Speaker 0: It's Tuesday May 31st 2011.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: two great warm-up games Rico and battle lines.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Warm today.
Speaker 0: Oh Mr..
Speaker 1: D.
Speaker 0: Even warmer today.
Speaker 1: actually it's the perfect warmness.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like it.
Speaker 0: It's good weather.
Speaker 1: I even I feel like you should only say warm today when it's so it actually is warmer.
Speaker 1: But you see if you're gonna turn on the air conditioner you can say warm today Just like you only say you only say woman if you're cold.
Speaker 1: I have the air conditioner on.
Speaker 0: I don't I've had my part.
Speaker 0: well the thing is my building for whatever reason just gets hotter.
Speaker 0: I think it's the like the big windows and all the rooms, but yeah if the AC is off It's like 80 something degrees in here.
Speaker 1: I only get pretty.
Speaker 1: I only get hot if Like all the electronic computers are on and the windows are closed.
Speaker 0: Oh well this room in particular the geek night studio.
Speaker 0: I basically shut the door and leave the AC on all the time.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm though a lot of you know Scott put up that counter-strike server the other day cuz mine has been out of commission for like Months yeah, but my internets was so it couldn't handle it, but we can't.
Speaker 1: it was just fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we can't swap PCs cuz it's not just a random PC.
Speaker 0: It's actually Scott's HD PC.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not gonna remove it I was just.
Speaker 1: you know it's the perfect computer to use for a counter-strike server cuz like it's not good.
Speaker 0: We're not home exactly.
Speaker 1: It's like if I'm not watching TV on it.
Speaker 0: I'm playing counter-strike.
Speaker 0: What else would I do right?
Speaker 1: So it's you know what better place what better computer to get dual purpose to?
Speaker 1: you know use it more efficiently and not waste.
Speaker 1: waste it then to use it as a gaming server when you're not watching something in your home theater, but My internet is so slow that when we got to like with ten players
Speaker 0: It was weird like we were playing okay, and then once we got to about eight players pings went up But it was still playable.
Speaker 0: my ping was like 20 instead of 10 yeah, but then ten players came in and Basically I didn't have any problems because I was on the gigabit Ethernet's on the same.
Speaker 0: Well, I had a ping of a thousand and I my ping is still five.
Speaker 1: I don't know why it's five to go across the room doubted me.
Speaker 0: I told you you need that anti griefing stuff installed because Scott's like.
Speaker 1: oh the game has its own built-in.
Speaker 0: It doesn't work.
Speaker 1: It does.
Speaker 1: It's if you team kill too soon, or if you team kill too many times You're automatically banned.
Speaker 0: It doesn't work that well.
Speaker 0: There are better ways to do it.
Speaker 1: I could have adjusted the numbers like have zero tolerance.
Speaker 1: like one team kill your band forever.
Speaker 0: No, because team kills happen And you want that.
Speaker 1: I know but it what it does.
Speaker 1: you can set a number of seconds where it's the start of the match And if anyone team kills in that frame it counts against.
Speaker 0: ah but team kill.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem.
Speaker 0: There's a good mod that handles this really well, and it while I generally like to play absolutely pure counter-strike I'm okay with a handful of mods that were on the the SMD server that I play it on all the time which get this.
Speaker 0: When you post in that thread like yeah, I gotta find a good counter-strike server.
Speaker 0: I've only played on one counter-strike server for like six or seven months.
Speaker 1: Send me the IP that shit.
Speaker 1: It's gone.
Speaker 0: Oh, I went in I went in and it wasn't in my favorites anymore.
Speaker 0: It's just not there.
Speaker 0: so I gotta find wherever it moved to and I couldn't find it so far.
Speaker 1: Well, if there are no people out there, right?
Speaker 1: I mean like, you know, I tend to play counter-strike in phases like I played a whole bunch I'm probably gonna play it tonight and then I don't play it and then I played a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: You know every months years whatever as much as I want to play it tonight I want to get to certain pony related thing done.
Speaker 1: Alright, but the other thing, you know, it's like, you know I think I've entered a counter-strike phase.
Speaker 0: Well, I think we played a lot more if we have a dedicated server because once Scott turned on the all talk and it was All listeners hanging out.
Speaker 0: It's pretty fun to play counter-strike with a bunch of people.
Speaker 0: it is.
Speaker 1: But the thing is is like if I if we pay for a dedicated server We pay for game server hosting which is 75 cents a slot at the cheapest for counter-strike source.
Speaker 0: How much per year per hour per?
Speaker 1: It's 75 cents if they based it on slots per month.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's actually not that bad because it's not.
Speaker 1: you have to pay more if you want like a like a 100 tick or 500 FPS server and then you pay per slot and you also pay more for counter-strike source than you do for regular counters like yeah six
Speaker 0: But it is kind of a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: These these game hosting things though What they do give you is they basically give you an easy web interface like enable mods and that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because base counter-strike vanilla counter-strike cake to run you just install like the Linux command-line dedicated server and it pretty much just works.
Speaker 0: It won't be great, but it'll just was really annoying.
Speaker 1: so I made a steam account and I opened up steam and I double clicked on server and Installed and then I double clicked on it to run it and it looked like it was running but it totally didn't work.
Speaker 1: So then I got the HLDS update tool for Windows, which basically lets you run the counter-strike server without steam.
Speaker 0: That's what you want and it totally worked.
Speaker 1: and I was like why the fuck don't they just make it work in steam?
Speaker 1: It was like the same GUI and everything.
Speaker 0: I was like what are the point mod developers for counter-strike servers?
Speaker 0: They're just the community is a little too hardcore old-school.
Speaker 0: So the tools are all really obtuse and pain in the ass to maintain.
Speaker 1: and yeah But if you get some of these game hose game server hosting places They say at least I can't tell how legit.
Speaker 1: they are from their websites, but they say like one-click mod installation.
Speaker 1: So I'm sure it's they've set up stuff to make it easier to administrate because that's their business.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, we'll put it this way.
Speaker 1: if they're legit I can't really tell.
Speaker 1: it seems like there's a bunch of them that are actually all the same Company on different domains with different looking sites.
Speaker 0: this week sometime I'll try to get my counter-strike server back up because I can host like 20 on 20 with the FiOS.
Speaker 1: just fine 20 on 20.
Speaker 0: I could do that.
Speaker 0: the computer step computers powerful enough for that computer might not be that powerful But the other computer is even more broken than this one.
Speaker 0: This one's an old computer, but I think it'll work.
Speaker 1: We just need 10 on 10.
Speaker 1: We don't need 20 on 20 Yeah, and then we just.
Speaker 1: we basically just need regular counter-strike.
Speaker 1: This is the thing is I didn't want to set up my own server But I couldn't find a server that had a regular map rotation.
Speaker 1: every server I found was either a a weird mod like gun game or surf and I like gun game but I don't want to play gun game all the time or they were 24/7 like dust to 24/7 office 24/7 and I was like sure if I want to play office But I don't want to play only office.
Speaker 1: I want to play all the maps in a rotation.
Speaker 1: all the default maps.
Speaker 1: No weird cut I do.
Speaker 0: there are a couple of non-standard maps that are fucking off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know which ones ones that are updates of the old maps that aren't in counter-strike stores.
Speaker 0: There are some original maps.
Speaker 0: I have a map pack.
Speaker 0: It was from the SMD server.
Speaker 0: They had a fantastic rotation.
Speaker 0: Basically the deal with them was that they had you know The admins and the people who were like kind of tight in that little community.
Speaker 0: They did for the for the clan what we used to do for AMVs back at RIT anime.
Speaker 0: They play every shitty ass map ever and they only put into the rotation the absolute most fun.
Speaker 0: best of the best Yeah.
Speaker 1: But the point is I want to.
Speaker 1: I want to play all the regular default maps that are built into the game and hardly Any server is.
Speaker 1: no server that I could find actually Ran a map rotation that included more than one of the default maps all Fox no items TMP only exactly It's like I want to play, you know assault or militia or whatever and this is the best.
Speaker 1: No one was running, you know, and I want to play like give me an update of oil rig or some shit.
Speaker 1: You know, I couldn't find anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's one map.
Speaker 0: You'll really like.
Speaker 0: it looks like one six, but it's in source called Westwood.
Speaker 0: It's just this totally old-school contrived Wild-west kind of village with the shootout and it's got all that kind of jank ass shit that you'd see plus this all those I want to play all the maps that no one remembers.
Speaker 1: mansion Arab mansion, you know, there's plenty old man or back alley.
Speaker 0: Do you remember how to make Gordon Freeman's ghost come out?
Speaker 0: I never succeeded to make those come out of the pool table but anyway or Vegas right I will admit that Gordon Freeman's goes coming out of the pool table Scared the ever-living shit out of me the first time it happened.
Speaker 1: The point is I want today I'm gonna try to play cs 1.6 and see if I find any server is doing a map.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna enjoy one six, why not cuz source is better.
Speaker 1: I'll find out.
Speaker 0: today is better.
Speaker 0: It's two more.
Speaker 0: that doesn't cost me anything to find out Yeah, but by the end of the week I'm gonna try to get cobble together and get my counter-strike server going again, but I'm not gonna do anything fancy with it.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna get it re-going and I'll post the IP once it's up.
Speaker 1: if that doesn't work or if it fails Somehow we should consider and we keep playing.
Speaker 1: we should consider paying for one if enough people like contribute.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well I'll set up because I can take Donations actually some or some but no some of these are.
Speaker 1: no these server places Actually have like clan donation things as part of the stuff.
Speaker 1: So it's like you can have it built into the server.
Speaker 1: the ability for people to help you pay for the server.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right We'll see.
Speaker 1: but like people donate money to you And I think it goes directly to the people you're paying for the hosting and adds credit to your account.
Speaker 0: Of course at the same time if I have a faster computer They've ever get it fixed or if I buy a new computer or whatever I could run a pretty badass counter-strike server here and I feel like if I pay someone to host anything I'm kind of wasting my FiOS Cuz it's wicked fast.
Speaker 0: Oh, yep Well, yeah this weekend.
Speaker 0: I was a mountain climbing.
Speaker 0: All right, I climb Mount Whiteface in the Adirondacks.
Speaker 1: Okay, I will.
Speaker 1: I will make the thing where I say I could make a joke and not make a joke about racism Racism.
Speaker 0: I thought you're gonna make some sort of semen joke white face.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway white face as opposed to black face Yeah, so I was carrying my burden up white face mountain And I won't.
Speaker 0: it was a fun hike.
Speaker 0: I mean you obviously don't care about mountain climbing.
Speaker 0: not really couldn't do it.
Speaker 0: you're worse.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: But we were gonna climb out Marcy, which is more than a mile up.
Speaker 0: But there was a thunderstorm and a lot of rain and to make a long story short We had to hike down white face many miles Basically going pretty much straight down over rocks with torrential rain and water just pouring over our feet and mud everywhere it was.
Speaker 0: It was intense and kind of grueling.
Speaker 0: Yeah great fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So speaking of counter-strike, I guess it's Tuesday.
Speaker 1: I guess yeah, let's see.
Speaker 1: There's not really actually a lot of gaming news.
Speaker 0: Ah, I Kind of disagree with that statement.
Speaker 1: But all right, like I couldn't find any gaming news We're talking about.
Speaker 0: so since you think it is a slow news day in the gaming world.
Speaker 0: What is your news?
Speaker 0: What is like the most exciting thing you found?
Speaker 1: Well, apparently right because the 3ds is out Even though the 3ds came out and there were like no games for it and there still aren't any games for it And no one's been talking about the 3ds.
Speaker 1: It's been.
Speaker 1: it's like it came out an explosion and then it's been quiet ever since didn't really explode.
Speaker 0: it kind of simmered.
Speaker 1: No, yeah, I know.
Speaker 1: It's it's not even simmered.
Speaker 1: It was like completely.
Speaker 1: What's the word for when you put out a fire?
Speaker 0: Doused now, well the Trump.
Speaker 0: think about this though when the GS was first announced, right?
Speaker 0: There were no games for it and other than hardcore people.
Speaker 0: No one bought it right away.
Speaker 1: But anyway, because the 3ds is out the DS light is gonna drop in price on June 5th Which is a few days from now to $99.
Speaker 1: if you don't already have a DS or DS light you should buy one.
Speaker 1: why as soon as the price goes down?
Speaker 1: because Because why it's something that's gonna last you Forever pretty much.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much it's gonna be.
Speaker 1: it's one of those things.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: I mean a GBA is still pretty damn good at this point a DS light Even if you buy it now, if you don't have one and you get one of those piracy cards You're gonna be rocking it for many years, right?
Speaker 1: I mean I got every NES every You know Gameboy every Gameboy Color game ever and a whole bunch of DS games and a whole bunch of GBA games.
Speaker 1: And you know, it's just this portable thing that can hold some Ridiculous number of games.
Speaker 0: and see this is why Nintendo's not making any money anymore.
Speaker 0: pirates like you pirating all their games.
Speaker 1: You know how many DS games I've bought a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah Actually, I think more important than owning the ones I pirate I would not have is owning a Gameboy Advance because that's the last one That'll play games all the way back to the beginning.
Speaker 1: Well, if you get an SP, then you can play games all the way back to the beginning.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, actually, did you remember this?
Speaker 1: I can't.
Speaker 1: I didn't realize remember that this existed until like a couple weeks ago the Gameboy player for the GV for the Gamecube.
Speaker 0: I Remember that pretty well because like I remember the super IT.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I remember the super Gameboy for the SNES.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, but the Gameboy player for the game.
Speaker 1: I totally forgot it existed until recently.
Speaker 0: I remember as a kid It's just there's something stupid about kids, but I really wanted the Gameboy player for the Super Nintendo.
Speaker 0: Like I'm the Super Gameboy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I really really wanted it.
Speaker 0: And when I think back I owned a Gameboy and I can't imagine why I would have wanted it because there was no game on the Gameboy I wanted to play at that point.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz what it did, right?
Speaker 1: So the Super Gameboy did two things.
Speaker 0: you have the background around.
Speaker 1: some know some of the games had built in Super Gameboy Enhancements that would put orders around the game on the TV and also you could choose from among three or four different color palettes.
Speaker 1: Right now the Gameboy color, right?
Speaker 1: This is interesting.
Speaker 1: When the Gameboy color turned on you could hold down different button combinations while it was booting to choose from amongst the Super Gameboy color Palette, but it did not add the borders Around it right the end.
Speaker 1: this Gameboy player for the Gamecube also didn't recognize the the Super Gameboy enhanced borders, right, but the Emulators that you can get for the you know, many Gameboy emulators do recognize those borders and display them properly.
Speaker 1: So it's kind of interesting like the only Nintendo product ever to recognize the Super Gameboy Enhanced Gameboy games was the Super Gameboy even though their their future products did not recognize, you know Like if you play it on a Gameboy SP some old Gameboy game that had you know The Super Gameboy enhancements you won't see those enhancements on there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess part of it was that most of the games I had in the Gameboy were not the kind of game You'd want to sit in front of a TV and play.
Speaker 1: Yeah the only Gameboy game that you really whatever.
Speaker 1: there's only a few that like were TV sit up like maybe Zelda and Maybe the Donkey Kong and that's not Gameboy Wars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you didn't have that shit.
Speaker 0: I had crystal warriors on my Gamegear.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I was I think the thing I was most Obsessed with throughout my entire childhood was hooking multiple Gameboys or Gamegears up to play a game Because none of my friends were interested in that.
Speaker 1: No, he had.
Speaker 1: people are interested in it.
Speaker 1: It's like you couldn't make it happen because you know one.
Speaker 0: I didn't know anyone else in the world who had a Gamegear.
Speaker 0: So there's no way I was ever gonna link that up.
Speaker 1: I never saw a Gamegear linkage, but I saw Gameboy linkage when we had Pokemon.
Speaker 1: There was a lot of Gameboy linkage going on with Pokemon like red and blue And also I remember on a field trip in elementary schools There were four kids who hooked up their game regular Gameboys to play f1 with the four-way.
Speaker 1: Yeah but other than that it was pretty rare because Pretty much the only way you could do it right is if there was a rich kid or a spoiled kid.
Speaker 1: then he would have.
Speaker 1: they get a Gameboy the necessary games and All the wires, but you needed to get lucky and have three other.
Speaker 1: they wouldn't have more than one Gameboy.
Speaker 1: So you need to have three other kids with Gameboys Who also had the game in the same place at the same time and that's pretty rare.
Speaker 1: It was one of those things.
Speaker 1: like the only people who were together enough you know in groups enough of gamers to make it happen on a regular basis were Nerds and kids and neither of them really had the money to buy all that stuff.
Speaker 1: Take a unique circumstance.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know your story about swords.
Speaker 1: You never had the desire for swords and the money for swords at the same time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, thankfully, but here's a thing That's actually a good thing not a waste like swords unless you're a sword person.
Speaker 0: Yeah At the same time the mystery you need but you need a combination to make it happen crystal warriors Which is kind of an advanced wars style like tactical fantasy grid based fighting game with magic and whatever Had multiplayer mode that I never saw.
Speaker 0: and because there was no good Sega equivalent of Nintendo power I couldn't live that vicariously.
Speaker 0: by reading Nintendo power could read game pro game pro didn't talk about GM didn't talk about crystal warriors.
Speaker 0: So I had like I saw a picture of One shot from the multiplayer game.
Speaker 0: to this day I don't know how it works because no one cares about fucking crystal warrior.
Speaker 1: That actually is something.
Speaker 1: right is if you go on say any website Gaming website say game spot right now game stop game spot Right and you look up like, you know Go through the list of new releases and you'll see.
Speaker 1: it'll show you every game that's gonna be released.
Speaker 1: and the hot games the big Games, right the ones that people know about.
Speaker 1: I'll have scores next to them and reviews.
Speaker 1: But all the other games all the shovelware doesn't have a review or anything.
Speaker 1: It's just like they have a bear information.
Speaker 0: Oh shit, son.
Speaker 0: Here's some video playthroughs of single-player only, right?
Speaker 1: But if you go if someone were to make a site that actually Seriously reviewed all the games that every other site ignored you could probably get a lot of traffic.
Speaker 1: Cuz pretty much anyone who searches for any of those, you know sub You know under-the-radar games is gonna end up at your site first as the number one result.
Speaker 1: And on top of that, you know It's there's so many of those games that you would be able to.
Speaker 1: you'd have to create a lot of content But you would get a lot of hits because it adds up in that long tail.
Speaker 1: true Especially on the sit like the portable systems.
Speaker 1: the vast majority like 80% of the games.
Speaker 0: Well, we really need to get rid of is the stupid game facts text-only culture.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, absolutely I'm so sick at game facts.
Speaker 1: and what the YouTube is much better for that.
Speaker 0: The fact that game facts even has a forum kind of amazes me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you want like some actual news that people care about I know you don't like the Call of Duty games.
Speaker 1: Not a fan of the duties
Speaker 0: duties duty Scott doesn't like duty especially the third one which is now yet but
Speaker 1: Many
Speaker 0: people have been commenting on the fact and apparently there was a press Blackout as in there are people in the press who know who aren't allowed to report on the details yet Which we've talked about that before and the BS around that.
Speaker 0: But there was an article and I think the New York Times and that a bunch of people were saying Yeah that are the Wall Street Journal.
Speaker 0: and then other people were saying that article wasn't actually accurate and I don't know the truth.
Speaker 0: I dug around enough and I found equal conflicting evidence for multiple versions.
Speaker 0: What Activision is doing with Call of Duty?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm the gist of it is and this is legit Activision is going to charge money a monthly fee Probably between four and eight dollars a month Which to quote them is comparable to something like Netflix.
Speaker 0: I mean if you'll play eight bucks a month for Netflix Then why wouldn't you pay four or five six bucks a month for Call of Duty's?
Speaker 1: Every Call of Duty or just the one Call of Duty?
Speaker 0: Oh, so Call of Duty?
Speaker 1: which Call of Duty they talking about?
Speaker 1: new like 20 of them, which is the new one?
Speaker 1: I guess the most popular one all of duty modern warfare 3.
Speaker 0: I just not out yet.
Speaker 1: All right, does that count?
Speaker 1: Is that on X?
Speaker 1: is this your Xbox or just PC?
Speaker 0: Multiple things.
Speaker 1: so you'd have to pay it even on top of your Xbox Live Gold.
Speaker 0: Uh, yes, but here's the thing.
Speaker 0: At first people reported that yeah, you can play just fine single-player But if you want to play multiplayer You gotta pay.
Speaker 0: and then that statement got retracted and replaced by a whole bunch of other things.
Speaker 0: So it's possible that they were testing the waters to see how people would react with like the incrementally less offensive options.
Speaker 0: But you're gonna be able to pay a monthly fee to be a member.
Speaker 0: Let's do
Speaker 1: a fucking survey
Speaker 0: Call of Duty Modern warfare 3 or modern warfare Elites and they won't say what this will entail other than that It will involve a social network that's directly like integrated into the game And maybe stat tracking like, you know, let's put it this way counter-strike.
Speaker 0: We play counter-strike right now say a new counter-strike came out like that tactical insertion game or counter-strike 3.
Speaker 0: Yes counter-strike 3 on the source 3 engine is coming out next month and they said alright The game itself is say I don't know 40 bucks forever.
Speaker 0: You just buy it and you have it.
Speaker 1: That's already kind of bullshit cuz I'm used to counter-strike being free.
Speaker 0: Alright, well say alright fine.
Speaker 0: Say it's free.
Speaker 1: Counter-Strike is a free mod.
Speaker 1: It's not I don't consider.
Speaker 1: You know, it was always a mod.
Speaker 1: I don't consider it to be a game You should have to pay for.
Speaker 0: but why?
Speaker 0: what if someone really I mean they made a new game from scratch That was just counter-strike better.
Speaker 1: Well, okay There's that there's one of the guys who originally made counter-strike.
Speaker 1: is sort of doing that.
Speaker 1: Let's forget what his game is called but pretend it's that game.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So say there were a month like of something that could be in the game But could only be in the game if they charged a monthly fee for it.
Speaker 0: Can you think of anything they could put into a game like this that you would pay a monthly permanent fee for to have access?
Speaker 0: To uh, I mean social network with clans and stuff built in.
Speaker 0: It's called to.
Speaker 0: did that by out of the box, but it's called steam and Xbox live.
Speaker 1: just integrate with that shit.
Speaker 1: Don't make your own shit.
Speaker 1: It's like everyone.
Speaker 1: everyone's fucking up.
Speaker 0: Nobody wants Scott Scott, then they can't charge you money for it.
Speaker 1: No kidding, but nobody wants your fucking separate bullshit.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna pay money for it.
Speaker 1: They want steam or and or Xbox live.
Speaker 1: Nobody wants anything else.
Speaker 1: All your any everything else other than those two things that has tried to do.
Speaker 1: this is fail.
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess the blow battle that battle net also is good.
Speaker 1: Those are the three successes.
Speaker 1: everything else that has tried to do that is fail.
Speaker 0: I would argue the tribes to stuff works just fine, but there was fail.
Speaker 0: What was fail about it.
Speaker 1: It really didn't work.
Speaker 0: Well, the fact that it didn't actually work was the only Surprise.
Speaker 0: had it worked it would have been okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because steam Xbox live and battle battle that existed but steam and Xbox live did not.
Speaker 0: but people are saying that one thing they might Offer is matte packs.
Speaker 0: But then the question is alright If you stop paying the monthly fee Do you lose access to the maps?
Speaker 0: if you don't pay like can you only play those maps with people who pay?
Speaker 0: so no one?
Speaker 0: Knows how that'll work.
Speaker 1: What if I just make my own map?
Speaker 1: Can I Everybody for free.
Speaker 0: Well, if they don't pay console games that making your own maps usually doesn't work.
Speaker 1: that well Yeah, but this is also a PC game.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right How about?
Speaker 0: maybe they get?
Speaker 0: let you run dedicated servers like you can already do for free on the PC.
Speaker 1: That should be free.
Speaker 0: Maybe people are saying they're gonna add detailed stat tracking.
Speaker 0: Oh, you mean like Counter-Strike does for free?
Speaker 1: Well me and any other people do for free with their third-party add-ons cuz it's open.
Speaker 0: I guess I can't imagine Anything they could offer that anyone would pay for.
Speaker 0: now I won't know.
Speaker 1: cuz like we were just talking about running our own counter-strike server and paying someone to run that server for us But that one alright, so one guy pays to run a server.
Speaker 0: Do the people who want to play on that custom server also have to pay?
Speaker 1: No, but what they could do right is this is actually wouldn't be a bad move is They could be you know, instead like the companies that are hosting that game servers calm Whatever that are offering counter-strike hosting.
Speaker 1: Why doesn't valve offer counter-strike server hosting directly so I could just go in steam?
Speaker 1: I would be.
Speaker 1: that would be so much more trustworthy.
Speaker 1: I'd be so much more willing to do it to then go into this shady company and just click and it's like you have bought A counter-strike server.
Speaker 1: Here's an easy GUI to configure it.
Speaker 1: It's totally standard You know, it's reliable because the people who make the game are running it.
Speaker 1: you have full control over it, though I'd pay for that Right, and then it would be really easy since integrating with the steam account to like turn it on and turn it off and charge By the hour, you know.
Speaker 1: some really low rate, you know, but 75 cents a slot a month.
Speaker 1: Well, just divide that by 30 and make it you know, two cents a slot a day or something like that You know.
Speaker 1: or one cent a slot for 12 hours, you know.
Speaker 1: So that way I could turn it on and off when I'm playing when I'm not playing you won't have to.
Speaker 1: but and the thing Is that'll solve a lot of your problems where you know, people can't get their firewalls working Yeah, or all this other bullshit.
Speaker 1: now At least you can also help you cheat that with cheat prevention because you're the only one run.
Speaker 1: Most of the servers will be run by the company, you know.
Speaker 1: So they'll have all this data from the servers to stop cheating.
Speaker 0: Yes, now many of the rumors before this news was kind of half-broken talked about how oh you have to pay to even play online.
Speaker 0: but they came out and basically said that's not true.
Speaker 0: and They definitely said that if you have Xbox Gold Xbox Live Gold You still have to pay for this on top of that to get access to the special features.
Speaker 1: That's a hundred bullshits.
Speaker 1: Yep, if you're paying for Xbox Live Gold, that means you should get all the stuff I mean now.
Speaker 1: why don't they just make it DLCs like look Street Fighter 4, right?
Speaker 1: They're coming they're doing it.
Speaker 1: Actually, I think I consider the right way or mostly the right way, you know considering the fact they do have business interests Right.
Speaker 1: So Street Fighter 4 arcade mode.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's out yet or it's coming very soon but the way it works is basically if Super Street Fighter 4 you want to add arcade mode basically gets you new characters and It gives you balanced.
Speaker 1: It changes the balance of the game and some other stuff, right?
Speaker 1: You have to pay for it.
Speaker 1: It's a DLC.
Speaker 1: It's a one-time cost.
Speaker 1: if you don't pay for it people who have paid for it can still fight against you in the old mode.
Speaker 1: So it's like this is backwards compatibility mode where you can still play with those people.
Speaker 1: You just don't have access to the new mode.
Speaker 1: It's totally a DLC, but it doesn't limit your online options really at all.
Speaker 0: Not a bad way to go about it.
Speaker 1: It's like they didn't dick over the people who refuse to pay and still want to play the old way.
Speaker 1: They just give you know an added bonus of the people who do pay for the arcade mode and it's a one-time DLC thing but it's not one of those DLCs like where they have.
Speaker 1: some of their DLCs are bullshit like pay for costumes.
Speaker 1: It's a real DLC.
Speaker 1: It gives you characters and you know stuff like that.
Speaker 1: So, you know if I played if I started playing Street Fighter again, I would probably pay for it.
Speaker 0: What really worries me is that here's a quote from one of the articles.
Speaker 0: another feature of the service will give Call of Duty players tools modeled on those from stock trading websites to analyze their performance within the game Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure what they mean by tools from stock trading websites.
Speaker 1: in other words It'll show you graphs of your stuff over time.
Speaker 0: Oh, you mean like counter-strike already does.
Speaker 0: I can see how often I hit with every individual gun that I've ever used since they Rolled this out.
Speaker 0: Yep already just free.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So we'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: I think the goal here is not so much to make money immediately but to get people used to the idea of paying monthly fees for games.
Speaker 0: because Rob Dyer said where's the quote about?
Speaker 0: he's very confident that other publishers will follow Activision's lead Quote.
Speaker 0: there's money to be made there.
Speaker 1: I think there's just a problem I'm seeing in all in pretty much all nerd industries across the board, right whether it's you know gaming or tabletop gaming or comics or anime.
Speaker 1: Right, all these people basically are.
Speaker 1: I consider the companies to be lazy, right?
Speaker 1: All they try to do is they say look we've sold a zillion copies of Call of Duty.
Speaker 1: Instead of trying to sell even more copies of Call of Duty Let's just try to get everyone's just trying to get more money out of the people they're already selling to right.
Speaker 1: Nintendo is the only one who didn't do that and now everyone hates them.
Speaker 1: But what they did is they said, oh, let's just try to sell them more people.
Speaker 0: Well, see it's got.
Speaker 0: here's the thing though You forget that I mean Call of Duty as a franchise.
Speaker 0: right now is the fourth and fifth most popular FPS on Steam.
Speaker 0: Oh Number one is still counter-strike - is also counter-strike.
Speaker 0: That's too bad.
Speaker 0: three is Team Fortress 2 and Left 4.
Speaker 0: Dead 2 is right.
Speaker 1: under both Call of Duty's Yeah, but it's like you don't see.
Speaker 1: valve has all those games Right to get and they're not charging shit.
Speaker 0: all the Call of Duty players online combined on Steam with PCs Which obviously is a skewed statistic.
Speaker 0: Don't get me wrong doesn't even add up to the number of counter-strike one six players?
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least right now as of six.
Speaker 0: fifty nine Eastern Daylight Time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so they got a lot to learn there.
Speaker 1: Maybe they should try to get as many players as counter-strike before they start trying, you know The thing is if you look at this is only gonna decrease the number of players I've got.
Speaker 0: if you look at consoles I mean how many people are playing counter-strike on their Xbox or their ps3?
Speaker 1: It was only on the Xbox one.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't think counter-strike was on the Xbox 60.
Speaker 0: so and if you pretend PC gaming doesn't exist which for the majority of gamers it effectively doesn't I Think it.
Speaker 1: I think actually PC gaming has made a huge come back.
Speaker 0: It has a huge comeback But I still think the majority.
Speaker 0: if you look at like a cross-section of video gamers as a whole people who self identify as video gamers I would guess that the majority do not have a dedicated gaming PC or Even play anything other than flash games on their PC.
Speaker 1: I think this will play Minecraft and I just think there's a surprising minority.
Speaker 0: You forget how many people have Xbox Live and play Call of Duty?
Speaker 0: We got of course, let's look all this up, of course, no one's playing Call of Duty on the PlayStation right now.
Speaker 1: I think that's fixed though.
Speaker 1: I don't from what I heard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not sure though because I haven't exactly cared to pay attention.
Speaker 0: We'll see where all this goes.
Speaker 0: We'll probably do a follow-up or maybe an episode on this kind of thing.
Speaker 1: So I can understand paying the monthly fee for the MMO like MMO Like.
Speaker 1: I don't like the game obviously but if I liked an MMO the Computer architecture of it pretty much demands that they have some huge centralized servers that are expensive.
Speaker 0: or for example What if you paid a monthly fee for a Final Fantasy 6 style game?
Speaker 0: Where you're paying a monthly fee and everyone else is playing a monthly fee and it's a pseudo art MMO Where there's just constant content being added all the time?
Speaker 1: Well, that's basically like it.
Speaker 1: That's the same thing as if there was a DLC every month and you paid.
Speaker 1: you bought a DLC every month But instead it's continuous.
Speaker 0: It's almost like an MMO.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they release they trickle the the the DLC instead of putting it in a blob.
Speaker 0: The subscription model is only really used now for MMOs as the industry defines MMO.
Speaker 0: I think we did a whole panel.
Speaker 0: We talked about how that's a stupid definition.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I think there are.
Speaker 0: I guess my point is there are games that really would warrant a subscription model.
Speaker 0: I just don't think that almost anyone in the gaming industry is making those games.
Speaker 1: Well, you know the thing is number one.
Speaker 1: They could if they wanted to write somebody could try really hard to make an MMO style game That does not have the centralized architecture.
Speaker 1: There's some sort of peer-to-peer architecture or something along those lines that was pretty advanced and then they could avoid having to charge the monthly fee, right?
Speaker 1: or Likewise someone can take a non MMO style game But figure out ways to improve it vastly by basing it on that centralized architecture and thus Validating the monthly fee.
Speaker 1: like imagine if there was some sort of Zelda game and there was a new dungeon every goddamn day, right?
Speaker 0: Maybe not every day everyone there'd be more dungeons than I could be.
Speaker 0: that's the point kind of like that stat recently.
Speaker 0: I think it's something like 48 hours of video or uploaded to YouTube every hour.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I mean the point, you know, it's like, you know If a game was just constantly growing or if there was like if there was you know, one minecraft world for everybody.
Speaker 0: You pay a monthly fee for that shit, I would probably pay a monthly fee for that.
Speaker 1: There's just one minecraft world dicks everywhere.
Speaker 1: Hey, just the gigantic.
Speaker 1: It'd be as big as like half the universe.
Speaker 1: Oh, that would be interesting if you added up all the minecraft worlds into one world and then Translated them to real size like based on the size of a real sheep.
Speaker 1: Right, how big?
Speaker 1: how much space in real space would it take up?
Speaker 1: It obviously probably bigger than earth.
Speaker 0: I remember I don't remember the stat anymore but when I was first getting into doom modding back in the day, you know, I used wadded and we didn't do and all that and D hacked to like mod doom and I made a bunch of cool stuff and a bunch of really amateurish maps.
Speaker 0: That didn't work so well in multiplayer because my cool concepts did not translate into games.
Speaker 0: But I remember when somewhat like just part of the dev manuals I had talked about how big the world is in terms in real terms relative to the perspective of the player.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Yeah, I don't really have anything to go with that other than that I saw a pretty scary my little pony fan thing someone did where they basically made a pinkie pie or Twilight Sparkle who was as big as a continent and I am under no illusions that that person did not make that by hand in Minecraft.
Speaker 1: No, I'm pretty sure they just made an editor.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Look at the people.
Speaker 0: look at what our forums doing.
Speaker 0: They I think enough people are enough crazy to make an entire continent size Twilight Sparkle.
Speaker 0: good job.
Speaker 0: So things of the day what do you got for me?
Speaker 1: So check this out.
Speaker 1: This is nothing to do with gaming.
Speaker 1: Nothing.
Speaker 1: I'm a fan of kinetic sculptures.
Speaker 1: They're pretty cool.
Speaker 0: I like ones where you can move something large in public.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those are good But this is one where you don't actually move anything But it is in public.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess it's.
Speaker 1: I think it's in a museum.
Speaker 1: It's at the truck gallery in Calgary, Alberta, right From June 3rd to the 30th, huh?
Speaker 1: And basically what it is is it's.
Speaker 1: it's a whole bunch of big long sticks right and they're all hooked up to cams that are all oriented differently and The sticks wave back and forth and it takes about 14 minutes for the pattern of waving back and forth to repeat itself.
Speaker 1: So it's like, you know, it's a totally different you know thing.
Speaker 1: it like you couldn't tell that it was repeating right a cycle and What it does is it sort of simulates grass Blowing in the wind right like big tall grasses and actually looks like tall grass is blowing in the wind.
Speaker 1: other Pokemon in there there might be But the point is it's sort of like hey, you know if there's ever a time when you know It's sort of like.
Speaker 1: it's called preserving the wind machine for preserving the wind.
Speaker 1: So it's like if there's a you know If there's no tall grasses or no winds or no both ever at a point in the future.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like hey, you know Get the idea it's like hey this thing simulates the feeling of looking at the tall grass is blowing in the wind.
Speaker 1: It's pretty impressive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we could talk a lot about preserve.
Speaker 0: I mean even you don't want to relate this to video games.
Speaker 0: We're already losing certain kinds of gaming experience.
Speaker 1: We've already lost lots of video games and we're losing more.
Speaker 1: not just but there's people in who are studying like they're only you know.
Speaker 1: They're basically working at colleges working hard to preserve games.
Speaker 0: I mean It's one thing like to emulate a game like it's a physical game like an electro mechanical game as it would be played if it Was in perfect working condition.
Speaker 0: but also I think there's value in emulating and Understanding the broken-down condition the condition that games actually were in for the majority of people who play them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, kind of like how.
Speaker 0: and if you had a video gaming museum There would have to be a Nintendo where the games would glitch out and you'd have to blow in them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly I imagine this far future where kids go to the science museum.
Speaker 0: You know They have all the shit out and you like poke at it like you at every station and move whatever thing they let you move And then they all get broken immediately.
Speaker 0: One of them will be an NES and an NES cartridge on a stick and it tells you to blow into it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Man, that could be.
Speaker 1: that's in a museum.
Speaker 1: But that's our childhoods in a museum next to the ancient Roman artifacts.
Speaker 1: Hey like that.
Speaker 1: And we're not even 30 yet.
Speaker 0: So this doesn't fit in the Continuity of the portal story, but it's cool.
Speaker 0: Nonetheless.
Speaker 0: Some people made a movie a short little film about Shell from portal and it kind of takes place after the events of portal.
Speaker 0: one Obviously not following on the events of portal to wait.
Speaker 1: So wait.
Speaker 1: So this is old.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's old or if they just started a long time ago and finished it too late.
Speaker 0: But it's cute and cool and very well shot.
Speaker 0: and about halfway through She uses portals and they actually look pretty good the way they render them.
Speaker 0: Mmm It's just a cute movie and I think everyone should watch it.
Speaker 0: No, it's not on College Humor.
Speaker 0: Oh Okay, so briefly in the meta moment the geek nights book club book is still Isaac Asimov's foundation.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll do that pretty soon.
Speaker 0: I think yeah, I got a burn through it.
Speaker 0: I kind of got distracted by all these game theory.
Speaker 1: I was also distracted by a lot of things.
Speaker 1: Let's do it in a few Thursday.
Speaker 1: Let's do it.
Speaker 0: if you think how far are you in the rereading of the Prince of nothing?
Speaker 1: I actually paused that also because I was distracted by Counter-Strike.
Speaker 0: my Yep join the forum, you know all that stuff.
Speaker 0: our forums rockin.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Check out the documentary.
Speaker 0: I'll just mention this because there's gonna be a screening of it at PAX, which is not that far away But going cardboard.
Speaker 0: we're in that and other cool people are in that as being made by a cool person.
Speaker 1: Everyone in it is cooler than us.
Speaker 0: It's about yeah, maybe 20% or so
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: and it's made by a cool person and I don't know what else I can say about it right now But there will be a Q&A and a screening of it at PAX Prime and we will very likely be at the Q&A to answer Questions.
Speaker 0: Yeah will be interesting.
Speaker 1: Saturday June 18th is nerd NYC recess.
Speaker 1: I may or may not be there But if you want to play tabletop games all day It's like 20 bucks and if you run a game in one of the two slots, then you can play the other slot for free.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm kind of leaning back on the nerd NYC's lately.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean not board game night now by recess though, even board game night.
Speaker 0: I do have the trouble and maybe I feel like this could turn into a show that I think we've.
Speaker 0: Let's do a show on it then a show how we've hardcore ourselves into a corner.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I think we've done that.
Speaker 0: Okay There's not that much else matter will be a pax prime.
Speaker 0: We will very likely be a pax dev.
Speaker 0: The New York comic-con is far off in the future and I can't say anything definite But there is a decent chance there will be gaming content that many of you who might not otherwise go to New York.
Speaker 0: comic cons in New York Might care about.
Speaker 1: and also Connecticut.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Also Connecticut's upcoming and I'll leave it at that though.
Speaker 0: We have one last thing.
Speaker 0: We usually don't beg for money.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna beg for money for someone else a good friend of ours Phil.
Speaker 0: He's the cool parkour guy who gave parkour lessons at Connecticut last year.
Speaker 0: So many of you might have actually seen him around.
Speaker 0: and he does this crazy-ass bike ride and they raise that crazy.
Speaker 0: It's pretty crazy.
Speaker 1: Could you do it if I wanted to?
Speaker 0: good?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you wanted to like you should do it That now it then we would need to raise even more monies.
Speaker 1: Cuz I asked him like how do you you know, he's like you.
Speaker 1: basically you need to.
Speaker 1: you need to give like hundreds of your Own money and they need to raise like thousands from donations.
Speaker 1: So it's a lot of money to get into it.
Speaker 0: But we have.
Speaker 0: we have listeners.
Speaker 0: I guess it's too late because we're gonna direct all of your charity to them.
Speaker 0: So it's not Child's Play season.
Speaker 1: So if you have money, it is always Child's Play season.
Speaker 0: actually Yeah, but it's not like the big Child's Play season where everyone's going.
Speaker 0: Oh shit Child's Play.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: So if you don't want to immediately donate money to Child's Play I will humbly recommend that you donate a small amount of money to Team easy riders because it's for Lou Gehrig's disease, which actually kind of sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't want that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean Lou Gehrig.
Speaker 1: He didn't want that either.
Speaker 0: No, he really didn't.
Speaker 1: But yeah, if you so if you know They basically need to raise this money to be able to do the bike ride in the first place.
Speaker 0: So, you know Yep, friend of ours cool guy and it if people do donate to him Maybe we'll get him on the show to talk about parkour or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's got a lot to talk about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's doing something really cool.
Speaker 0: Maybe he's walking around the world.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll talk about that later.
Speaker 1: We got a lot of friends who are full of awesome.
Speaker 1: That's more awesome than us, but they really have a hard time getting them on the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mostly because we're lazy and we live in New York and people are All the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right.
Speaker 0: So I guess it's time to review some games and we got two games for you Like you might have heard in the beginning there.
Speaker 0: They're both.
Speaker 0: they can both be played to player though One of them is obligatory to player and I don't know they're both really good warm-up games Like.
Speaker 0: they're the kind of game you play before you play a game.
Speaker 1: Yo dog Yeah, it seems like the thing.
Speaker 1: the thing is though lately we've only been playing warm-up games.
Speaker 1: No one wants to play real game.
Speaker 0: Well, this goes back into our we hardcore ourselves into a corner.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Guess we're gonna have to do hard quarter ourselves into a corner as a show then.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is good because we're working on Basically, we decided that since we can't come back from the event horizon we have passed beyond We can't play games with the world born anymore.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna lock ourselves in our Cathedral and play games with each other.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, so the first game is called battle line or battle lines.
Speaker 1: It's by Rainer Knizian.
Speaker 0: It is a direct simulation of a bunch of Greeks pushing against each other.
Speaker 1: Yeah rim loves that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I first played this game at PAX East.
Speaker 1: actually Alex got it from the PAX East game library brought it over we played it once and then he brought it he put it back and then I went to the To the gaming store looking for and I couldn't find it.
Speaker 1: But I went to the gaming store again and it was in a different section and I noticed it cuz rim was standing next to it.
Speaker 1: So I bought it and we played it a whole bunch more.
Speaker 1: basically, this is If you've ever played Rainer Knizia's What's it called?
Speaker 1: Why did the name of the the game just lost cities?
Speaker 0: I think that's the one.
Speaker 1: yeah lost cities.
Speaker 1: It's very similar to that right you're playing cards in different columns against the other players cards.
Speaker 1: He's also playing in columns and it's two player only.
Speaker 1: but the way it works is there are nine Columns and you play your Greek troops right that you're drawing from the deck into the different columns and When you have won a column as in the car you have three cards on your side of the column and there is no way Absolutely, no way the cards on the other side of that column can beat you.
Speaker 1: you win that column.
Speaker 0: now when we say no way It's in the way that you know, if you ever play hearts or Euchre you'll be you know experienced players.
Speaker 0: when they're playing with noobs the noobs will often get very confused.
Speaker 1: when about halfway through some guy just Opens his hand is like I take the rest.
Speaker 0: Yep, or everyone just throws down their cards like that's done Yep, and this game basically puts that into the rules.
Speaker 0: you only get something when you can say yes I've got it.
Speaker 1: Here's why now there are also So the way then you win if you win five out of nine columns or if you get three adjacent columns.
Speaker 0: So there's this little bit of posturing and fate.
Speaker 0: basically if I had to sum this game up It's very similar to a heart style game a trick-taking kind of game Except that one.
Speaker 0: it works really well with two player which most games like that don't.
Speaker 1: yeah They only need four player and two.
Speaker 0: it adds both some randomness Which we haven't talked about yet and some strategy to make a really fun experience even if it isn't the greatest game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean, you know, it's actually I think it's one of the best two-player games ever played Absolutely, but there's you know, there's not that you know other than actual war games Which will be you know.
Speaker 1: Then again two-player games are all sort of have the same flaws.
Speaker 1: that makes them not as good as real good.
Speaker 0: The thing is two-player games aren't as flawed as three-player games for skilled players, that's true.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the game also has these tactics cards that sort of you know have superpowers But you don't take them into account right unless they're already on the table.
Speaker 1: So it's like I could still win this column if I get this special card, but it's like well, that's a special card So it doesn't count.
Speaker 1: I win this column.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: So that's that's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I mean it basically if it were just that if it was just.
Speaker 0: you know The cards out and it's basically poker.
Speaker 0: There's six suits and there's numbers in this car And you know, it's like a straight flush is the most powerful Beats three of a kind which beats a flush which beats a straight which beats a high card Like some.
Speaker 1: yeah, so it's like, you know all the basically all the troops have numbers and colors and you know you like if I'm too away from a straight flush even if It's a low straight flush.
Speaker 0: and Scott has two cards.
Speaker 0: There are different colors.
Speaker 0: I can play the third part of my straight flush and I just get it immediately because there's no way any card Scott plays That aren't special could possibly make that column beat me.
Speaker 1: Yep, or let's say I've got you know, eight nine ten and they're all green in a column right rim has a seven.
Speaker 1: Well, there's no way that he can possibly win that column because there's no way.
Speaker 1: the best he can do would be seven eight.
Speaker 0: Actually, I would have won that column anyway, because if you play if you have an eight nine ten out anywhere Because if someone gets there first they win a tie.
Speaker 0: There is no way to beat that tunnel a column and you just get it immediately Even if the other person has never played a card there.
Speaker 1: There has to be a way for no because I could play It's nothing you could write that would beat it.
Speaker 1: eight nine ten is the best possible thing.
Speaker 0: It's only a nine ten.
Speaker 0: the other person loses even if you never if they never played a card That's true.
Speaker 1: But let's say I play seven eight nine in a column and you have a six.
Speaker 1: There's no way that you could possibly do You know anything that would tie or beat seven eight nine because you already have a six in that column.
Speaker 1: So I win the column.
Speaker 0: so the game comes down to a lot of posturing and fainting and like I see Scott played a six Seven but I have the eight in my hand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I know the only cut.
Speaker 0: there's only one card that'll fill that.
Speaker 0: so maybe I take a risk and I start building Just a three of a kind there instead or a flush there instead.
Speaker 1: But then maybe you know, he's even he's the inside card.
Speaker 1: you've got him But maybe he'll go for the low card or the high card.
Speaker 1: You know if he's got seven eight, he might do six seven eight or seven eight nine.
Speaker 1: You don't know which way he'll go.
Speaker 0: now the game crooks slightly.
Speaker 0: So in that there's two decks to draw from.
Speaker 0: yeah And this is this is kind of like the twist in the game that makes it.
Speaker 0: if it didn't have this twist It really would just be about the same level of strategy as a game like hearts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the special deck as all the special power cards in it and the regular deck is all the regular cards.
Speaker 1: So it's not like you get the special cards randomly.
Speaker 1: if you choose Are you gonna draw a regular card or a special one and you'll never have more cards in your hand?
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: You always have exactly seven in your hand period done.
Speaker 1: You cannot get more or less and you can.
Speaker 0: and there's a neat mechanic where if you play a special card You can basically never play More than n plus one special cards and being the number of special cards your opponent has played.
Speaker 1: So if rim has already played one special card, he can't play anymore.
Speaker 1: So he draws more.
Speaker 1: this basically fill up his hand and reduce his number of options because he can't play them.
Speaker 1: So there's really only if he's got three special cards in his hand one on the table and I have zero on the table He really only has four options for the turn instead of seven.
Speaker 1: Then as soon as I play a special card now he can play one again And you know.
Speaker 1: so as long you can only you there's no way to like say pile up the special cards and just play them all to destroy the other guy because that would be sort of pointless because everyone would grab all the special cards immediately be forced to Play them all really quickly and then the game would continue because they are much more powerful than the regular cards.
Speaker 1: So that that mechanic of not allowing you to play more special cards than your opponent or at least too many more than your opponent Really keeps the balance going.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, it would be kind of stupid.
Speaker 0: now the strategy is pretty good I mean if you ignore the special cards for a minute because remember they don't count in terms of Logically winning a column.
Speaker 0: so you can be in a situation where you know The other person can't win a column because you have the last card in your straight.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm in your hand ready to go anytime.
Speaker 0: But if the other person play you could be in a situation where maybe that card that'll win the straight is a special card.
Speaker 0: Then if the other player makes something else and he is guaranteed to win Except for your special card you lose it.
Speaker 0: So you're kind of forced to play special cards quickly in certain situations.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or you can lay out like I'll often.
Speaker 0: when I played with Scott I don't think it didn't work.
Speaker 0: But I tried to set up columns hoping that Scott would throw a special card into it To basically draw it out and then I jump over someone else and try to win.
Speaker 1: Yep But the thing about this game that really got me is that you really don't want to play a car every turn.
Speaker 0: I'm like, ah, I don't want to play any of these.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you play one in any column.
Speaker 0: You've committed that fucking column.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't take any cards back except for like a couple special cards that let you do stuff like that.
Speaker 1: So it's like you pretty much never want to play a card, but you have to play one on your turn.
Speaker 1: But then you have the satisfaction of knowing your opponent feels the same way.
Speaker 0: You pretty much have to throw cards away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got a couple of columns.
Speaker 1: There are a couple of columns that you just to give up on and sort of go for a lower Arrangement and hopefully, you know your if you want your opponent to go first.
Speaker 1: So if he if he commits a column to be a dumping column and he's played a second card on it and you know That his maximum formation for that column is really weak then you can go for that column with also a relatively low Formation that's just slightly better than his trash formation and win that column.
Speaker 1: and thus I also have a dumping ground for cards that you can't use in really high-powered formations.
Speaker 0: I almost always draw a special card first.
Speaker 0: Can you play one draw one?
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, you definitely want to get one right away because you start out with zero.
Speaker 0: so it's always good to have one Yeah, and I'll usually get a second one pretty early.
Speaker 0: So should I know what my options are cuz I'm not gonna see that many special cards throughout the game Yeah, and there aren't that many.
Speaker 0: so having two means.
Speaker 0: I know my opponent does not have those two.
Speaker 1: The thing is right is when we played we really held back on the special cards.
Speaker 1: Right either because we were held back by the other guy or because we were both holding.
Speaker 0: I hold back on purpose.
Speaker 0: I always want you or my opponent to get ahead in the game early with special cards because then they can't play anymore and I whip all mine out at the end and there's basically nothing the player can do about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like I wonder what would happen if both people let loose with the special cards and burn through that deck.
Speaker 0: He's run out and then the game would continue.
Speaker 1: I think the game would actually end much more quickly because I don't think it would.
Speaker 0: just very few of them will actually win one For you and some of them actually make you need more cards.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I think that the vast majority of you know If I was gonna play a special card It's because it was gonna lock a column in or two columns.
Speaker 0: But having too many special cards you won't have anything to lock a column with.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: The game you gotta sort of wait for like the first bit of the game to pass And the brain feel of this game kind of like, you know food critics talk about the mouth feel of a food.
Speaker 0: The brain feel of this game is very much like as I've said a million times hearts or Euchre or anything.
Speaker 0: I'm counting cards I'm counting straights.
Speaker 0: It's trickier because I can't use all the mnemonics I've built up over the years for you know games like hearts because there's six suits and there's ten cards per suit.
Speaker 0: So my card counting like.
Speaker 1: I actually fucked that up big time.
Speaker 1: There was a time in the game when I was looking around that I saw three twos in the table and a two in my hand And I was like, ah, there's no way rim has it too.
Speaker 0: And then I played two more twos And then he played two more twos.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh right this fucking six colors I totally fucked up the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all the mental equations I have don't work.
Speaker 0: So I got a wing it and I guess I'm happy that I was able to able to wing it pretty well and kind of fuzzy Logic my way through.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Now this game is actually a just a straight remake of an older kinesia game.
Speaker 0: shot and totin.
Speaker 0: I never heard of that shot and totin is the same game without special cards.
Speaker 1: Oh Interesting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so he basically said this game is pretty cool.
Speaker 0: He added the tactics cards added one more card to each suit and made a new game.
Speaker 1: Did it originally have the Greek theme?
Speaker 0: No, it's themed based on like mountain people.
Speaker 1: The Greek theme is much better Javelins and shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, I zoomed in more.
Speaker 0: It's based on Scotsman.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're all fighting.
Speaker 0: Okay, beating each other ahead with bagpipes.
Speaker 1: Nice.
Speaker 0: That's a bare ass right there.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: So there's another game that we played recently Yep, Rico, which we played at zenk icon randomly because a guy was there and he's like, it's cool game.
Speaker 0: Let's play Yep, and he taught us how to play and that's the thing.
Speaker 1: if you go to a convention This is just some random advice.
Speaker 1: right you go to the gaming library.
Speaker 1: There's always gonna be these weird games like you've never seen them before and they're just sort of sitting there like that hex bug game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you'll see a game that looks like a weird game.
Speaker 1: It's like what the fuck is this, right?
Speaker 1: You don't even.
Speaker 1: it's the kind of game you just overlook it cuz it's so inconspicuous And it doesn't stand out as being a big game or popular game or a fancy game.
Speaker 1: It's just sort of game.
Speaker 1: You don't recognize you never seen it before But it's hiding.
Speaker 1: play those games cuz.
Speaker 1: well, some of them suck.
Speaker 1: You're gonna find hidden gems in there All right, so Rico is one of those games just like an oddball, you know game that like was totally inconspicuous Didn't?
Speaker 1: wasn't popular?
Speaker 1: never heard of it before just sitting on the table.
Speaker 1: But we played it and we discovered something kind of good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's.
Speaker 0: it's another card kind of game Where you've got suits and you play cards, but the way it works, there's four colors four tiles for love You know for like it's for trash plants.
Speaker 0: So when you play cards from your hand, you can play any number of cards But you have to play at least one of one color.
Speaker 0: So if I have like four red and one green I could play one green or one two three or four red Yep, and you have to play it on the column that matches the color.
Speaker 1: So your red cards have to go in the red trash bin and your yellow cards is to go in the yellow trash bin.
Speaker 0: You then draw from that same pile like the same column on the other side of this middle card.
Speaker 0: Right the all the cards that are there and it's always replenished to be One plus the number of cards that are already on the top.
Speaker 1: So for example at the beginning of the game every trash bin has one card in it, which is a random card.
Speaker 1: So let's say the green trash bin has a blue card in it, right?
Speaker 1: I can play any number of green cards into the green trash bin.
Speaker 1: So I play two into the green trash bin.
Speaker 1: I then take that one blue card that's in there.
Speaker 1: now because there are two in the green trash bin We draw three at random.
Speaker 1: So the next person who puts any green cards in the green bin takes those three random cards that are now in there.
Speaker 0: Yep So you as you play closer to because basically once you hit four In.
Speaker 0: so if someone puts in a number of cards on a column that makes the total of cards that were put in by players Four or more.
Speaker 0: they all go away.
Speaker 0: They take a little token which has a number of victory points on it starting at zero.
Speaker 0: We'll save the numbers on them.
Speaker 0: But it's a number of victory points on it.
Speaker 0: you take that into your hand and then you take all the cards at the edge.
Speaker 1: So if you're the one who finishes off a particular trash plant and puts it over the top You get some victory points from the chips.
Speaker 1: But you're also probably gonna take a whole bunch of cards into your hand from the other side of it because it's close to full.
Speaker 1: So it's probably gonna have three at least three probably four cards in it.
Speaker 0: And thus the trick with this game Anytime you draw cards into your hand that are greater than five you have to discard down to five and every one you discard is Negative.
Speaker 0: one victory points.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: think about that right I play one card at the beginning of the game I play two and I draw one.
Speaker 1: so now I've decreased my hand size by one.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 1: Then I play.
Speaker 1: you know two and I probably draw like three.
Speaker 1: your hand size is growing for hand size grows over five.
Speaker 1: You lose points basically.
Speaker 1: so everyone pretty much poisons the well and makes all the trash plants super dangerous.
Speaker 1: So that way taking victory points is gonna actually cost you victory points because even though you get a chip That's worth points.
Speaker 1: You're also going to lose points.
Speaker 1: We're having too many cards at the same time.
Speaker 0: Yep, so you lose points a lot of points for illegally dumping.
Speaker 0: now if you manage to make through the whole game without ever Illegally dumping you get a pretty crazy bonus.
Speaker 1: Good luck with that shit.
Speaker 0: very rarely does anyone pull that ever.
Speaker 0: never.
Speaker 0: I've seen it, but it's pretty rare.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the other shit to the game Is that the time the tokens that get positive victory points on there's.
Speaker 0: there's a little pile on each column.
Speaker 0: The values go zero one two three three negative two four five.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: so if you take the zero or the one you're actually probably gonna be losing points in total or cut breaking even because even Though you took a chip you're gonna lose points from taking too many cards.
Speaker 1: So if you're the you know.
Speaker 1: if you take the zeros and the ones your score is actually going down.
Speaker 0: Typical end scores of this game are between negative four and three.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you're if you make it to the it's it's pretty.
Speaker 1: if you play good Well, you can get to the end of the game with scores of like zero, right?
Speaker 1: And then if you manage to be the one to take like the four or the five chip You're gonna get a lot.
Speaker 1: It's a lot of points right there and that will probably win you the game As soon as somebody takes a five chip the game of men ends immediately which makes it really really rough because This that's you know, there's 20 points worth of five chips But only five of those points actually get delivered to anybody.
Speaker 0: now the game's a little less strategic I would say than battle line because you have less information and you pretty much got to play it one turn at a time.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: This is a game where there are like it is it is partly random.
Speaker 0: It is mostly random.
Speaker 0: many times when I lose or win or Scott loses or wins it is obvious that there was no better decision The person could have made.
Speaker 0: But there are ways to optimize your play of this game one.
Speaker 0: You have to count cards religiously.
Speaker 0: You've got to know what's in everyone's hand.
Speaker 1: Remember?
Speaker 1: Nobody's drawing any cards that are face down.
Speaker 1: They're only drawing face-up cards other than their initial loadout other than their initial cards.
Speaker 1: But what if they do go over five?
Speaker 1: they discard some car?
Speaker 0: What they discarded.
Speaker 1: but you know what all the possibilities are.
Speaker 1: so it's possible to remember what's in everyone else's.
Speaker 0: No A human is probably not going to remember it exactly because that's kind of difficult to do.
Speaker 1: But all you really need to know is like does he have green?
Speaker 1: does he have to green?
Speaker 1: You know, that's all you really have to remember is like does he have this color?
Speaker 1: How many of that color does he have?
Speaker 1: you don't need to memorize this entire hand?
Speaker 0: So this is a good game for practicing these kind of deep strategies.
Speaker 0: So, you know buy this game.
Speaker 0: It's cheap.
Speaker 0: I bought these games.
Speaker 0: They're both pretty great if you can find them.
Speaker 0: But for Rico really played as a warm-up game to another game and while your friends will be good or bad or whatever The game is kind of random.
Speaker 0: It's a great game to practice some very important skills.
Speaker 0: pay attention and try to count cards learn mnemonics learn how to know Pretty reliably what's in everyone else's hands?
Speaker 0: Yep, and to count how many cards are already in play I've already come out.
Speaker 0: So, you know what's remaining in the deck what the statistical odds are of getting one card over another?
Speaker 0: and if you if you maximize those Skills you will slightly increase your chance of winning this game and you will greatly increase your chance of winning most other games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, for example, if the let's say the five point is open on the red on the red plant, right?
Speaker 1: I know that rim has two red cards.
Speaker 1: So I'm not gonna play two red cards because that would allow him to put it up to four and take the five.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna play one red card there.
Speaker 1: that way he can at best put it up to three Which means I'll be able to take the five if I have another red card.
Speaker 0: The second thing you need to do is and this game is almost identical Mathematically to a game I call sticks.
Speaker 0: people call it different things where you draw like five sticks three sticks and two sticks like lines On a piece of paper and you take turns crossing off any number of sticks in one row.
Speaker 0: Whoever picks up the last stick by crossing it off Loses and the game alternates effectively between stable and unstable states.
Speaker 0: an unstable state meaning one where someone can Push the game to ending.
Speaker 0: a stable state meaning it the game will continue.
Speaker 0: So you want the game to be in an unstable state because if it's in an unstable state and the other person messes up Or is forced to make a move then you win.
Speaker 0: So you want to make the game as unstable as possible when it's not your turn and as stable as possible when it is your Turn.
Speaker 1: yeah, so it's like aha no matter which pile you go into this turn You will lose points because they're all at minus two and they all have three cards in them.
Speaker 0: So you've got to learn Basically modulus math.
Speaker 0: while you're doing all this You've got to be able to count forward through the game iteratively and be able to say my turn his turn.
Speaker 0: He'll have to play something that will make one of those twos go away.
Speaker 0: his turn I'll be good and then from there you decide how much to stabilize or destabilize the game on your turn.
Speaker 0: Those are the only two skills in this game.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much you got to take turns poisoning the well and drinking from the well.
Speaker 1: Right, you're gonna drink poison and if somebody drinks from the well, there's no poison left because they drank it all.
Speaker 1: So it's like all right my turn I poison it.
Speaker 1: What are you gonna do on your turn?
Speaker 0: double poison double poison?
Speaker 1: All right, my turn I have to drink great now the zero poison.
Speaker 1: So what does room do on his turn?
Speaker 1: poison again?
Speaker 0: Oh Gertrude, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like you want to be the poison or not the drinker as much as possible but you're gonna drink the poison because Right, cuz eventually all the wells are poisoned and you're thirsty.
Speaker 0: So they're two great warm-up games and I recommend if you see them for cheap just pick them both up.
Speaker 1: Rico might be harder to find.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had some trouble getting it on Amazon and the first two vendors.
Speaker 0: I bought it from Apologetically emailed me later saying they couldn't actually find it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but battle line shouldn't be that hard from any board game.
Speaker 0: specialty shop Yeah, and you could make shot and taught and if you wanted to pretty easily for the deck of cards Yeah, you can just take a break.
Speaker 1: You just.
Speaker 1: you just need 60 cards 10 of each color and You know nine little two ponds and you could you could play the game.
Speaker 0: Yep This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.