Speaker 0: It's Thursday, January 27th, 2011.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nides.
Speaker 0: Tonight, it's burger time.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Which is happily nothing like Goofy Time.
Speaker 1: Hooray.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're back.
Speaker 0: We kind of didn't do shows after Magfest and kind of before Magfest for a bunch of reasons.
Speaker 1: Well, it's all, you know, we got incredible snowstorms, so it's not nice to go outside.
Speaker 1: Yeah, multiple blizzards.
Speaker 1: Evo is not snowing.
Speaker 1: It's really cold.
Speaker 1: You don't want to go outside.
Speaker 0: I've been skiing.
Speaker 0: We had Magfest.
Speaker 1: And Magfest, which is incredibly cold and you don't want to go outside.
Speaker 0: One thing I can say about Magfest is that, you know, aside from our Magfest show, a four-day convention, remember Otacon was like, "Hey, think we're going to do a four-day convention
Speaker 0: again?".
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Never.
Speaker 1: Whole no.
Speaker 0: It wrecked me about as much as it wrecks the staff, I think, going to a convention for four days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, four days is a bit much.
Speaker 0: Like, I remember.
Speaker 1: Especially 24/7 four days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like Saturday at Magfest.
Speaker 1: The thing is, it's like, you know, you can have a lot of extra fun on that one day.
Speaker 1: Even though we showed up late on the Thursday, there was still a lot of extra fun because, you know.
Speaker 0: We showed up late on that day, but it didn't matter because there was the 12-hour line.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, but, you know, you still, you get a lot of extra fun out of those hours, you know, because there's a lot more hours in there than you realize, but it's not worth an extra vacation day, right?
Speaker 0: It depends.
Speaker 1: The convention has to be ludicrously awesome for it to be worth.
Speaker 0: I would go to a four-day PAX.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean, what could they really put in that one more day?
Speaker 0: One more day of playing board games?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, but I had a day of playing board games at Magfest, you know?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time, we played board games with a lot of friends, and it was difficult to convince strangers to play.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: Different culture.
Speaker 0: But anyway, we're back.
Speaker 0: We're bad.
Speaker 0: The Geek Night schedule is resuming mostly, though we got a bunch of crazy stuff coming up, but we'll get to that.
Speaker 0: Mostly PAX.
Speaker 1: Yeah, PAX is coming, immediately followed by Zenkai Con, and then it's going to be a break, and then there's going to be more convention.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, you got any news?
Speaker 0: I mean, it's Thursday, and, you know, stuff's happening.
Speaker 0: There's chaos in the Middle East.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, there's been so much news since we last did a show that I had so much news to do, but all the news is I wanted to save for the other days of the week, so I'm like, "What
Speaker 1: news?"?
Speaker 1: You know, Thursday is the day where you can do a news that normally doesn't fit, so I got to find a news that doesn't fit.
Speaker 1: So, I figured, well, Thursday is the book club day.
Speaker 1: I'll do a book-related news.
Speaker 1: How good is that?
Speaker 1: So, apparently, you know, TED, Technology Education Design, who does all the TED Talks and the conferences and the TEDx's and all these things.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: You've seen the videos on the internet, I hope.
Speaker 1: If not, what the hell?
Speaker 1: They have now introduced TED Books, which is a line of books that have the TED logo on them, and, you know, featuring people who gave TED Talks and are TED-type people.
Speaker 1: And, you know, so, okay, so there's books with the TED logo on them.
Speaker 1: Big deal, right?
Speaker 1: Well, one of these books that they've already announced is particularly interesting is called "Beware Dangerism.
Speaker 1: Why we worry about the wrong things and what it's doing to our
Speaker 1: kids.".
Speaker 1: And this book obviously talks about how, you know, people, you know, mostly parents are like, "Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: Can't have a kid walking outside without me outside
Speaker 1: also.".
Speaker 0: I lived in Detroit, and I rode my little bike a quarter mile to get to the school.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, so it's like, you know, how.
Speaker 1: even, you know, even since we were kids, this "dangerism" mentality has increased a ton, and since my parents were kids, it's increased even more a ton.
Speaker 0: Well, Scott, as Pete taught us from playing danger patrol, the real answer is to maximize danger.
Speaker 1: Right, but I mean, you know, it's the thing is, right, is like, you know, like, for example, my mom used to just walk to school and she was way little, you know, and but now she is, right, you know, she has the "dangerism" mentality.
Speaker 1: She did it, but she wouldn't let me do it, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like, how does that happen?
Speaker 1: How do you go from doing something to that?
Speaker 0: Of course, many of those things have often been that way.
Speaker 0: I mean, how many people's parents smoked pot when they were young and would not let their children smoke pot?
Speaker 1: Right, but, you know, the thing is, is people have this impression that the world is more dangerous now than it was when the reality, statistically, is that the world is far, far less dangerous than it was.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, it's like people say, oh, there's so much more pedophilia now and like child kidnappings.
Speaker 1: No, there isn't.
Speaker 1: There was way more pedophilia back in the day.
Speaker 1: It's just now.
Speaker 1: whenever there's one pedophile, they make a huge story about it, whereas back in the day, it was like a pedophile.
Speaker 0: Well, there is a very telling statistic that was reported in the Dallas News last week about how in 1969, I believe 15 percent of children were driven to school by their parents.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Today, that number is over 75 percent.
Speaker 1: Whoa, that's a big change in the very 20, 30 years.
Speaker 0: Granted, my parents drove me to school every day until I was 16 and started driving myself.
Speaker 0: But the reason they did so was that the buses were just like, it was basically Mad Max and I didn't want to put up with that shit.
Speaker 1: I always took the bus.
Speaker 1: It was just fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my school district was Mad Max.
Speaker 0: At least in middle school.
Speaker 1: Was it really Mad Max?
Speaker 1: Because all those parents, those 75 percent of parents driving their kids to school, they're all going to say, "It's Mad Max on the bus.
Speaker 1: I got to drive my
Speaker 1: kid.".
Speaker 1: Or they're going to say, "It's not convenient to wait for the bus.
Speaker 1: I have to leave the house to get to
Speaker 1: work.".
Speaker 0: A lot of kids got broken noses on those buses.
Speaker 0: There were fights regularly.
Speaker 0: I was involved in some of the fights.
Speaker 1: I fought on the bus, but I kept going on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I broke a kid's nose when I was in middle school.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: That's what you're supposed to do on the bus.
Speaker 1: That was the problem.
Speaker 0: The other thing was the bus took for fucking ever.
Speaker 1: I didn't take that long.
Speaker 0: My bus took about 45 minutes to get me home because it made stops every five feet.
Speaker 1: On the way home, I was like, "The bus always gets you to school on time.
Speaker 1: It's not going to get you to school
Speaker 1: late.".
Speaker 1: Why was it never late on the way to school?
Speaker 1: I'd never been late to school on a school bus.
Speaker 0: Plus, the other kind of, I don't know, maybe conflating factor, at least with the bus thing, is that before I could drive myself, I did stuff after school.
Speaker 0: I was in clubs, and if you were in anything, if you were in school more than five minutes after school- You needed a ride home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was one bus that went to every part of the entire town, and it took two hours to get you home, so screw that.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow.
Speaker 1: I think our school had a ... I don't remember which school had it, but I think there was a late bus, but I don't remember if I ever successfully used it or not.
Speaker 0: See, part of it, too, was in high school, at least, where I grew up, there wasn't-
Speaker 1: On the late bus, and-
Speaker 0: Well, there wasn't a lot of demand for the busing, because once you were in high school, almost everyone had a friend who drove to school every day and would drive them, or would drive themselves.
Speaker 0: I mean, the school's parking lot was as big as IBM's parking lot was.
Speaker 1: School parking lot was always big troubles of fighting.
Speaker 1: There weren't enough spots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, ours was gigantic.
Speaker 0: The thing is, you'd have to park, I don't know, a mile away from the school if you got the late- So like RIT.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically.
Speaker 0: However, me being smart, which is get to school an hour early and then do all the homework that I didn't want to actually do, copying it off of other people in the band room before school- You were giving up sleep, though.
Speaker 0: I was giving up sleep, but then I made up for it in class.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I don't know, I feel like the dangerism thing is a valid concern, and most people say, "Oh, you're just saying that because you don't have any perspective
Speaker 0: anymore.".
Speaker 0: It always feels like things are different when you're older and you complain about it.
Speaker 1: I've looked at all these statistics.
Speaker 1: All the statistics are probably in this book, right?
Speaker 1: You don't have to take it from my word.
Speaker 0: Well, look at the evolution of the playground.
Speaker 0: When we were kids, our parents said, "Yeah, playgrounds were way more
Speaker 0: awesome.".
Speaker 0: And they could back that shit up by pointing out the dangerous shit that they used to do.
Speaker 1: I went on fast metal slides and metal jungle gyms.
Speaker 0: But think about this.
Speaker 0: Our parents said playgrounds were pussified.
Speaker 0: We now say playgrounds are pussified.
Speaker 0: I can point out things I used to do that are gone, and our parents can point out things they used to do that are gone.
Speaker 1: See-saws, spinny wheel thing.
Speaker 0: But I'm not that worried, because this is a pendulum, and I think it swings back and forth.
Speaker 0: Look, now there's a movement of reclaiming playgrounds.
Speaker 0: that's really moving.
Speaker 0: Have you seen the playground over in Vernon Jackson those kids play on?
Speaker 0: It is way more awesome than anything we had as kids.
Speaker 0: And it's super dangerous.
Speaker 1: Lava pit traps.
Speaker 0: Yeah, lava pit trap.
Speaker 1: Ah, shit.
Speaker 0: But while it's super dangerous, it makes up for that.
Speaker 1: Tarzan rope over the lava pit trap.
Speaker 0: With a piece of technology.
Speaker 0: That's greased.
Speaker 0: The surface?
Speaker 0: As a kid, you could basically jump off the top of the toppest thing, land on your head, and be mostly okay.
Speaker 0: I couldn't do that.
Speaker 0: I'd land on asphalt and break myself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you lived.
Speaker 1: I jumped off lots of tall things, and I was just fine.
Speaker 0: So, Ted Book?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Ted Book.
Speaker 0: That was your news?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, this is old news that for some reason is in the news again, but there were some recent movements on it.
Speaker 0: None of the movements were good.
Speaker 0: The old news thing.
Speaker 0: I don't want to talk about that much, other than the fact that it's weird how old news seems to come back from like two years ago, because two years ago everyone ignored it and suddenly everyone loses their shit.
Speaker 0: Even though it's the same news, same situation, nothing's changed.
Speaker 0: But anyway, courts have ruled that Dungeons and Dragons is not allowed in prisons because it threatens prison security.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: Quote, "It can mimic the organization of gangs and lead to the actual development
Speaker 0: thereof.".
Speaker 0: Hey, prisons.
Speaker 1: I got prisoners.
Speaker 1: If you're the kind of prisoner who plays D&D, and you just got your D&D taken away from you by the guards, send me an email or a letter, because I know you can write letters to people in prison, right?
Speaker 0: I'll mail you some burning wheel.
Speaker 1: I will mail you some burning wheel or some other RPG that is not D&D and it will be all good.
Speaker 0: Imagine they're sitting around playing D&D and here's what the warden hears.
Speaker 0: I shiv him.
Speaker 0: What do you mean you shiv him?
Speaker 0: I backstab him.
Speaker 1: Flurry of blows.
Speaker 1: That's for the shower room.
Speaker 0: But what bothers me is another statement from the ruling.
Speaker 0: Quote, "During D&D games, one player is denoted the dungeon master.
Speaker 0: The dungeon master is tasked with giving directions to other players, which the guy testified as saying, mimics the organization of a
Speaker 0: game.".
Speaker 0: Now, by that logic, education in prison mimics the organization of a gang.
Speaker 0: The warden mimics the organization of a gang.
Speaker 0: Pretty much anything mimics the organization of a gang, except-- Why do you keep saying "game"?
Speaker 0: Same gang.
Speaker 1: When you say "gang," you sound like you're saying
Speaker 1: "game."
Speaker 1: Gang.
Speaker 1: You need some more "ang," like
Speaker 1: "tang.".
Speaker 0: This bothers me on another level.
Speaker 0: A more fundamental problem is that role-playing is probably one of the more constructive things people in prison could be doing.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, they could be role-playing a bank heist.
Speaker 1: Even so, even so.
Speaker 1: And then practicing for the real deal.
Speaker 0: What is one of the most common causes of violent behavior in criminals, especially not that intelligent, kind of low-level criminals?
Speaker 0: A lot of studies show that it has to do with a lack of empathy and a lack of an ability to see things from other people's perspectives.
Speaker 0: What could help that more than telling someone to play someone else with different motivations?
Speaker 1: I don't think that's what they're doing, though.
Speaker 1: They're probably doing hack and slash D&D, which is miniature's game.
Speaker 0: Even then, even then, it's a constructive, harmless activity that keeps them busy.
Speaker 0: They have to do math, they gotta roll dice, they have to deal with failure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 1: It's just, you know, the judges have no idea what that is.
Speaker 1: It's just like when judges judge the technology, they don't know what they're talking about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it bothers me.
Speaker 1: And the lawyers don't go, no lawyer actually, you know, knows enough about D&D.
Speaker 1: And the one thing that really upsets me, right, is that, let's say, if I was Hasbro-Watsy, right, that's who's really to blame here.
Speaker 1: Because, I mean, lawyers don't know what D&D is, they're just doing their job.
Speaker 1: The lawyer doesn't know what it is, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, why hasn't Hasbro filed an amicus brief?
Speaker 1: Hasbro-Watsy, they gotta go in and gotta be like, "Look, you guys have it all wrong.
Speaker 1: This is what D&D is.
Speaker 1: We make D&D.
Speaker 1: Here's the
Speaker 1: truth.".
Speaker 0: I'd go one step further.
Speaker 0: I would try to sue someone under some sort of defamation grounds.
Speaker 1: Possibly.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you can, but not a lawyer.
Speaker 0: I would argue for it.
Speaker 0: I'd make a huge role-playing and prisons campaign.
Speaker 1: If I was Hasbro-Watsy, they definitely have their own lawyers.
Speaker 1: I would definitely be telling them to look into it.
Speaker 0: Plus, maybe not D&D.
Speaker 0: Take some other role-playing.
Speaker 0: In fact, I will bet that in the same prisons that have banned D&D, there are support groups and mandatory counseling sessions for maybe violent offenders that encourage role-playing.
Speaker 1: There might be.
Speaker 0: It bothers me that the prison system in the US is fucked up anyway.
Speaker 0: And on top of that, it's fucked up generally, it's fucked up at its core, it's fucked up at the top, it's fucked up conceptually, and it's fucked up in every individual detail.
Speaker 0: Like, every possible thing that could go wrong is going wrong.
Speaker 1: There are some details that are correct.
Speaker 0: A few.
Speaker 0: I mean, we don't just leave people to die in a gutter like they used to.
Speaker 0: I'll save this.
Speaker 0: I got a thing of the day about...
Speaker 1: We let them play basketball.
Speaker 0: I got a thing of the day about a prison... Yeah, but there's a referee.
Speaker 0: Gangs.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: Coach.
Speaker 0: Coach.
Speaker 0: I just, I can't get over... I picture a player now saying that...
Speaker 1: The coach is the gang leader.
Speaker 0: I picture a Luke Crane kind of gamer trying to run this game for like four hardened, And the guy's like, "He's not getting the sword.
Speaker 0: I shiv him.
Speaker 0: I shank
Speaker 0: him.".
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I just have this image.
Speaker 0: I feel like college humor should do a skit.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we should definitely send, you know, find one of those prison letter-sending things, and be like, hook them up with the indie RPGs.
Speaker 1: It could become a thing.
Speaker 0: Actually, one step further.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: And then, in fact, we could design a game, an RPG specifically for people in prison.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go one step further.
Speaker 1: And it could become so popular in the prisons, and then once this game is wicked popular in the prisons...
Speaker 0: It gets banned in the prisons.
Speaker 1: No, you sell it to the public as the game that is popular in prisons nationwide becomes a cool thing, right?
Speaker 1: Or banned in prisons across the US.
Speaker 1: Play this game.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: I think what I will do, because...
Speaker 1: And then when those guys come out of prison, they're gonna want to play it with their homies.
Speaker 0: I'm actually a long term shareholder in Hasbro.
Speaker 0: People who aspire to become prisoners.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna write a letter to Hasbro as a shareholder and say, look, you gotta get on this shit.
Speaker 1: And people who aspire to be prisoners will play the game practicing.
Speaker 0: I don't think that many people aspire to be prisoners anymore.
Speaker 1: All the people that are in gangs that aren't in prison.
Speaker 0: I don't think that's aspiration so much as the results of a failed shank check.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Or possibly a successful shank check that was linked into a failed prison check.
Speaker 1: People, you know, thugs who aspire to a life of crime, they will enjoy a game that is, you know, a prison kind of game.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should make a prison role-playing game where you play prisoners in jail.
Speaker 1: And the GM is the guards.
Speaker 1: Or maybe there's guards and prisoners and you do the role-playing game with rules.
Speaker 0: So things of the day.
Speaker 0: It's a college humor, but it's from the vault.
Speaker 1: It's always college humor.
Speaker 0: It's from the vault, and I wonder if anyone remembers it, but it's something really cool.
Speaker 0: It's not quite skiing, it's not quite hang gliding, it's hang glide skiing or Swiss ski flying.
Speaker 1: A little dangerous?
Speaker 0: It looks wicked dangerous.
Speaker 1: And is there a video of a guy doing it?
Speaker 0: There's a video of a guy doing it.
Speaker 1: Does he hurt himself?
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: There's a video of a guy doing it.
Speaker 1: Who wants to watch anything of the day?
Speaker 0: Not only is it a video of a guy doing it, but it's a video from the perspective of the guy following him also doing it.
Speaker 0: And I made this my thing of the day because I watched it and it made me make a decision.
Speaker 0: Because I ski, but I'm not a great skier.
Speaker 0: And I ski mostly just for fun.
Speaker 0: I think I've decided to get hardcore.
Speaker 0: I think I've decided to get real lessons and try to become a for real skier.
Speaker 1: So you're going to become a hang gliding skier?
Speaker 0: My goal, my literal goal, is to at some point in my life do what is in this video.
Speaker 1: Well, you will die.
Speaker 0: This might be shit talking or death talking.
Speaker 1: Death talking.
Speaker 0: But I'm going to go for it because I'm young enough to... This is pretty much my last shot.
Speaker 0: If I don't start toward an extreme sport now, it'll never happen.
Speaker 1: There's guys who do the extreme sports when they're older.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've got to train now.
Speaker 0: I'm at the last few years where my body might survive a serious injury.
Speaker 1: Call Red Bull.
Speaker 1: They'll help you.
Speaker 0: I'll just call Red Bull and be like, "Look, I want to get from what I am now to that.
Speaker 0: Will you sponsor
Speaker 0: me?".
Speaker 0: And I quit my job and do that.
Speaker 1: And start base jumping.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I'm going to do the ski flying.
Speaker 0: It looks less dangerous.
Speaker 1: Maybe less dangerous.
Speaker 0: It does look less dangerous.
Speaker 1: What could be less dangerous than base jumping?
Speaker 0: I get this impression.
Speaker 1: Base jumping is like the first extreme thing you have to do.
Speaker 0: This is a pretty crazy video.
Speaker 0: No, the first thing is bungee jumping.
Speaker 0: That's the lamest.
Speaker 0: That's like the bottom of the extreme scale.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: Same shit.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 1: So somebody made this thing.
Speaker 1: that is sort of an idea.
Speaker 1: that's sort of obvious, right?
Speaker 1: But they actually did it, which puts them on top.
Speaker 1: And also they found a way to do it on the way cheap.
Speaker 1: What they did is they made a thing called the pirate box.
Speaker 0: Is it full of gold?
Speaker 1: I wish.
Speaker 1: You go on Amazon.
Speaker 0: The Leprechaun universe is well and good.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: You have them in the pirate universe.
Speaker 1: So you buy a pirate lunchbox on Amazon, right?
Speaker 1: And then you buy a little wireless router thingy.
Speaker 1: You know, a little network card business.
Speaker 1: And you buy a little USB stick.
Speaker 1: And you buy, where's the list of stuff?
Speaker 1: You don't have to buy that much.
Speaker 1: It comes out to less than $100.
Speaker 0: So then I get a lunchbox with a pirate logo on it and some tech inside of it.
Speaker 1: And basically what happens is it's a wireless access point.
Speaker 1: It even has its own internal power.
Speaker 1: You buy a USB battery pack thing.
Speaker 1: And so then anyone who searches for wireless networks will see pirate box.
Speaker 1: And if they connect, right, this thing's running Linux.
Speaker 1: So what will happen is any website they try to go to, the website won't be there because there's no internet connection.
Speaker 1: It's just you connect it to a box in a lunch pail.
Speaker 1: And what you'll see is you'll see pirate box.
Speaker 1: And what the pirate box is is you just can upload files to it and download files from it.
Speaker 0: I'm surprised no one made a commodity version of this sooner.
Speaker 1: You didn't actually make a commodity version of it.
Speaker 1: You had to make your own by those instructions.
Speaker 0: Well, it can be made with commodity materials.
Speaker 0: Nerds can just make one and throw it out there.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I like this idea a lot.
Speaker 0: I feel like I should make one.
Speaker 1: I'm going to make one because we got conventions coming up real soon.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We're going to need it.
Speaker 0: We should know what we'll do.
Speaker 0: We'll bring it to every panel we do, point out its existence in the pre-talk before we actually do the panel, and just say, "Hey, anyone wants to put anything on here?
Speaker 0: You got a
Speaker 0: question?".
Speaker 1: Okay, so here's the things you need.
Speaker 1: You need a free agent doc star.
Speaker 1: You can also use a Go Flex or a Pogo plug, okay?
Speaker 1: You can use an Asus wireless router.
Speaker 0: Scott, I got it.
Speaker 0: This is what we'll do.
Speaker 1: A USB flash drive.
Speaker 0: Scott, I got it.
Speaker 1: A pirate lunch box.
Speaker 0: Let's both build one, right?
Speaker 1: Yes, we have two.
Speaker 0: And then once we've got them going, we will start a contest.
Speaker 0: Six months later, whoever has gotten the coolest thing uploaded onto theirs by someone other than themselves wins.
Speaker 1: Let's go for it.
Speaker 1: And then a rechargeable battery pack.
Speaker 0: I'm all about this.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to get into my whole.
Speaker 0: someday we'll have ubiquitous wireless internet.
Speaker 0: that then leads to some sort of cultural revolution.
Speaker 1: No, but the thing is, I think this is step one, right?
Speaker 1: For under 100 bucks, you can make one of these.
Speaker 1: The next step is to find a way to get some mesh networking going on with these.
Speaker 0: Yeah, where a pirate box finds another pirate box.
Speaker 1: Yeah, where the pirate boxes network with each other, and then you connect to one pirate box, and then you can request files.
Speaker 1: It'll be sort of like libraries.
Speaker 1: You can request a file from another pirate box.
Speaker 0: The third step would be if you could make a double pirate box that also gets an internet connection from somewhere.
Speaker 1: I think the point is that you don't want an internet connection because you want to make sure it's anonymous.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but you could make another one.
Speaker 0: that is basically you'd run a pirate node that a pirate box could connect to, and then people could tunnel through and do their nefarious evil deed, and then there's no record of how they got there.
Speaker 0: Because they ad hoc.
Speaker 0: They basically are behind seven pirate boxes.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I guess.
Speaker 1: Whatever, but yeah, I'm going to make one of these guys.
Speaker 0: So, very briefly, the meta moment.
Speaker 0: We were at MAGFest 9.
Speaker 1: It's over.
Speaker 0: If you were at MAGFest and you did not fill out the MAGFest 9 panel survey, you should do this honestly.
Speaker 0: We will go back to MAGFest if they invite us and pay for us like they did this time, and if no disaster happens between now and then, like MAGFest collapses or it's on the same week as PAX or something.
Speaker 1: Next upcoming convention is PAX East.
Speaker 1: Followed the week following is Zenkai Con.
Speaker 0: So PAX East, we are doing not one, not two, but daddy three panels.
Speaker 1: Oh, shit, three hard whirling panels.
Speaker 0: And our friends are doing a whole shit ton of panels.
Speaker 0: There is going to be this network of Geek Nights and Friends panels.
Speaker 0: You could basically plot a course through PAX.
Speaker 1: We're going to have to make a Geek Nights suggested programming list.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God, yes.
Speaker 0: But we are doing the triple threat, which is three short subjects in gaming.
Speaker 0: It's basically three 20-minute panels in one panel.
Speaker 0: Like bam, bam, bam.
Speaker 1: That have nothing to do with each other.
Speaker 1: We're not going to wrap them up or sum them together or anything like that.
Speaker 0: We're going to start the panel like it's a brand new panel.
Speaker 0: Stop it, pause, start another panel.
Speaker 0: It's going to be awesome.
Speaker 0: We're doing game mechanics and mechanism design again by popular demand.
Speaker 1: We only did it once at PAX West.
Speaker 0: And it's our best panel, hands down right now.
Speaker 1: And now it's PAX East.
Speaker 1: Who made that panel?
Speaker 0: Scott made that panel.
Speaker 1: That's right, Scott makes the best panel.
Speaker 0: And we're doing a brand new panel, one of my panels, totally brand new, we'll see how it goes, called Playing Games to Win or Winning Games.
Speaker 1: You should just call it Playing to Win the Game.
Speaker 0: I forget exactly what it's called.
Speaker 0: I got to look in the schedule.
Speaker 0: But basically it's the, you play to win the game panel.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: I'm looking forward to that one too.
Speaker 1: That's going to be good.
Speaker 0: Luke and Jared are doing some stuff.
Speaker 0: Going to be all up ins.
Speaker 1: Yep, lots of people.
Speaker 1: Anyway, also other news is.
Speaker 0: February 11th, upcoming Friday, there's a Nerd NYC board game night.
Speaker 0: There is also a Nerd night in Brooklyn.
Speaker 0: And we might go to that instead of the board game night because once we go to one of those, we already set it up.
Speaker 0: We're probably going to run some of our Geek Nights panels, shortened versions of them, at an upcoming Nerd night.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're trying to do a lot more New York kind of stuff, you know?
Speaker 0: Yep, so if you do anything and have a venue in the New York greater metropolitan area and you want Geek Nights, Raymond Scott, named Scott, to do a live show, email us, geeknightsatfrontrecoup.com.
Speaker 0: I'm not guaranteeing we'll come, but we will at least consider it.
Speaker 1: The book club selection is...
Speaker 0: Michio Kaku's Hyperspace.
Speaker 0: I'm about three quarters of the way through it.
Speaker 1: I also want to remember in the meta moment to mention you should go to frontrecruit.com, which is our website.
Speaker 1: A lot of people don't go there.
Speaker 1: Ever.
Speaker 1: You should.
Speaker 1: A lot of people don't follow us on Twitter.
Speaker 1: You can follow Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: You can follow me personally.
Speaker 1: You can follow Rym personally.
Speaker 0: We tweet out everything of the day.
Speaker 0: We also tweet out old episodes that you might have missed because the RSS feed only goes back like 100 episodes and we've been doing this shit since 2005.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: You can go to our forum, which you can get to from the website.
Speaker 0: Our forum is one of the best and least shit-cockery-filled forums on the entire internet.
Speaker 1: The forum has had a lot of new users lately and also some increased activity.
Speaker 1: Make sure when you apply to the forum that you type in in the box that says, "Why are you
Speaker 1: joining?".
Speaker 1: Just type in some actual English words.
Speaker 0: You have to prove that you're not a robot.
Speaker 0: I've denied a lot of people who were actually people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not going to use a captcha.
Speaker 0: You have to pass a Turing test.
Speaker 0: You've got one paragraph to pass a Turing test.
Speaker 1: You can write as little as one word, but you have to make sure that's a damn good word that proves that you're actually-- I think the cockboat would suffice.
Speaker 1: Remember, whatever you write in there, I am reading with my eyeballs or Rym is reading it, and if we are convinced based on that that you are a human, then we will say yes.
Speaker 1: It doesn't take much, but if you write something like, "I wanna," that's not enough.
Speaker 1: You have to write something like, "I'm a Geek Nights listener and I want to join the
Speaker 1: forum.".
Speaker 1: That would suffice.
Speaker 0: We're at the Five Napkin Burger, which opened up recently in Queens.
Speaker 0: It's a chain, but it's a good burger.
Speaker 0: I remembered how much I fucking love burgers.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, we always don't want to do a food show because it's sort of like the zombie show.
Speaker 1: It's so requested.
Speaker 1: I hate doing it, but the burger is perhaps the most important food in the United States, where we live.
Speaker 0: Let alone in New York City, where the burger joint is like this stanchion of society.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, New York, I guess, is still mostly known for its pizza, but I think because the burger was mostly relegated to fast food and also to barbecues in the summer, that more recently people have been able to make a lot of money by coming out with burger restaurants that serve high-quality burgers.
Speaker 1: Because you can get a high-quality burger.
Speaker 0: You can go to a Stuff on the Wall's place and get an okay burger.
Speaker 0: A lot of steak houses have really awesome burgers.
Speaker 1: But in recent years, the quality burger place, it's like fast food because you get a burger fast, but it's not actually a fast food piece of shit McDonald's burger.
Speaker 1: It's a real serious burger.
Speaker 1: It's become very popular, and in New York City, it's become so popular that there are so many choices in competing places that it's like a thing.
Speaker 1: Even Nerd NYC has a Nerd Burger event, where they go to a different burger place all the time to try them all out.
Speaker 0: A lot of people call us out and try to say that we're too harsh on Five Guys.
Speaker 0: They're like, "What do you mean you don't like Five Guys?
Speaker 0: Five Guys sucks
Speaker 0: balls.".
Speaker 1: Five Guys doesn't suck balls.
Speaker 0: I'm going to qualify that.
Speaker 0: Five Guys sucks balls, but there's an asterisk.
Speaker 0: Because we live in New York, Five Guys is like the bottom of the non-fast food burger.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing.
Speaker 1: Compared to, say, McDonald's or any fast food place-- Those aren't burgers.
Speaker 0: That's like saying Taco Bell's a taco.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying.
Speaker 1: Five Guys is better than all those by a lot.
Speaker 1: If you're in a suburb somewhere, and there aren't a million awesome burger places like New York City, Five Guys is probably way better than anything you're going to get other than your backyard.
Speaker 1: It's probably even better than what you're going to get at TGI Fridays or stuff on the walls.
Speaker 1: It's okay.
Speaker 0: Five Guys is the same level as a Bill Gray's burger.
Speaker 1: The thing I don't like about Five Guys is the default double burger.
Speaker 0: The thin little burger.
Speaker 1: The burger itself, even if you get double, is like this thin little sad kind of guy.
Speaker 0: That crappy McDonald's feeling bun.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, the bun is not the greatest bun.
Speaker 1: The french fries, they're all right.
Speaker 1: They're okay.
Speaker 1: And the peanut stick with the peanut oil stick.
Speaker 1: I can do--.
Speaker 0: However, I do not have enough non-okay french fry potato options.
Speaker 0: I need more carbohydrates at that place.
Speaker 1: Five Guys, if you want to beat out all-- It's basically the bottom of satisfactory.
Speaker 0: Well, I would say it's the bottom of still a burger.
Speaker 0: I mean, we got the Five Napkin right here, which I had never actually eaten at one before, and I'm recently very impressed with it.
Speaker 1: Well, Five Napkin, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, this is the thing, right?
Speaker 1: Is it really fair to compare a burger at a sit-down restaurant to a burger that you can take out?
Speaker 1: Because it's like, well, you know, I mean, they could, Five Napkin could make that same burger if you waited there to make it because they actually made it real fast.
Speaker 1: It came out right away and let you take it out with you.
Speaker 1: They could do that.
Speaker 0: By the same token, Capital Grill sometimes has burgers.
Speaker 0: Is that going to compete?
Speaker 0: I mean, is that fair?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think it's fair to compare a place that is a takeout specific place, you know, that might have a few tables for lunch people versus a place where it's only weight service.
Speaker 0: All right, so let's do just takeout then right now.
Speaker 1: All right, so just takeout?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Also, what kind of brought the interest back is Luke Burrage, our awesome courage Burrage juggling friend, was in the city for a while just hanging out, and he went on a quest to find the best kind of just burger joint in New York.
Speaker 0: He ate like every goddamn burger and everyone gave him recommendations.
Speaker 1: Well, not every, but he did eat a lot.
Speaker 0: I'm proud to say that my recommendation won.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's the thing, snippers, right?
Speaker 1: So let's look at snippers for a second.
Speaker 1: So snippers, you can get a takeout there, right?
Speaker 1: But it's not quite fast food takeout.
Speaker 1: You can sit at a table and put a little number up and they'll bring your burger to your table.
Speaker 0: Like it's a step down, but barely a step down from Five Napkin.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like this in-between kind of situation.
Speaker 1: It's not a sit down with weight service, but you can sit down there and they'll bring your burger to you.
Speaker 1: It's almost like the difference between McDonald's drive through and it's more akin to the '50s where you'd pull your car up and then a girl with roller skates would bring it to you.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, that reminds me, when I was a kid in Michigan, right, we still had A&W's.
Speaker 0: You basically go in, they had to drive through, they had the roller skating waitresses and everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are places like that still out there, just as many as there are driving through movie theaters.
Speaker 0: And you get a shitty-ass burger, the crappiest fries in the world, and a pretty damn good root beer float.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you can't mess up the root beer float.
Speaker 1: It's A&W, they make root beer, that's what they do.
Speaker 0: Granted, the root beer is high fructose corn syrup in here now.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it was when I was a kid or not.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I knew better.
Speaker 1: But do you think they're still using that corn syrup at the actual place?
Speaker 1: Probably.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, I miss those days hanging out at the A&W.
Speaker 0: Those are some shit burgers, let me tell you.
Speaker 1: But I mean, you've also got places in New York, now you get the burger trucks, right?
Speaker 1: And you've also got places that aren't specifically burger places.
Speaker 1: They're like generic deli.
Speaker 1: You can go in any generic deli place and ask for a burger.
Speaker 0: I'll make an okay burger.
Speaker 1: You can get one, and it's actually pretty cheap, usually a good deal.
Speaker 0: Way better than the default burger at a generic diner.
Speaker 1: That's for sure.
Speaker 1: So it's like you just go in a generic deli place that makes breakfast sandwiches and Boar's Head subs and everything and ask for a burger, and it'll be not bad.
Speaker 1: I've had it plenty of times.
Speaker 0: I've got to agree with the Luke Burge, though, that the Schnippers is the best kind of takeout-y burger there is in New York, at least.
Speaker 0: Like, it's the best one I've ever had.
Speaker 1: That you haven't had from this one truck, though, that I've been... I mean, the thing is, there are so many burger trucks, and I'm pretty sure some of them might be better than this one that I go to.
Speaker 0: There's one that was by Brian Park, like, a couple weeks ago.
Speaker 0: that was pretty damn good.
Speaker 1: Which one was it?
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: It was just a burger truck, and I was like, "Damn, I got a
Speaker 0: burger.".
Speaker 1: What did it say?
Speaker 1: What did it look like?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It was a burger truck.
Speaker 1: You don't even remember the name of it or what the truck looked like?
Speaker 1: What color was it?
Speaker 0: It was red, and it was one of those driving, like, the whole truck.
Speaker 0: It wasn't a cart.
Speaker 0: It was a proper big-ass truck.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: But anyway, yeah, the one that I go to is called Frites and Meats, right?
Speaker 1: And, you know, their meats are excellent meats.
Speaker 1: Very excellent meats.
Speaker 0: How about the Frites?
Speaker 1: The Frites are actually not that great.
Speaker 1: I'm not a big fan of the Frites, but...
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of places fuck that up.
Speaker 0: Like Good Burger has great burgers, crappy buns, and their fries are like McDonald's fries.
Speaker 1: So here's the thing right there.
Speaker 1: Buns are these unbelievable buns they get from, like, a fancy bakery downtown.
Speaker 1: Unbelievable.
Speaker 1: You get, like, the potato onion or the brioche.
Speaker 1: Oh, snap.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: Brioche burger is almost unfair.
Speaker 1: So then the cheese they get from the famous Murray's cheeses.
Speaker 1: You can get the Gruyere or whatever fancy cheese you want.
Speaker 0: What's with Gruyere?
Speaker 0: Like, coming up.
Speaker 1: It's popular lately.
Speaker 0: It's like the rising star of cheeses.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: I would have invested in a Gruyere dairy farm if I would have known.
Speaker 1: But, yeah, so they got, you know, awesome meats, awesome buns, awesome cheeses, right?
Speaker 1: The thing is, it's a little expensive, you know, for just a burger, right?
Speaker 0: Well, how expensive?
Speaker 1: Like eight, nine bucks.
Speaker 0: It's a good burger price.
Speaker 1: And the Frites are not, you know, they're not bad, but they're not amazing.
Speaker 1: They need to be a little more potato-y because, you know, they're actually Frites.
Speaker 1: They're not French fries, right?
Speaker 1: But the thing is, they give you these... You can get a little sauce for your Frites, 50 Cent.
Speaker 0: See, it's hard to impress me with that, though, because I can go full on and get poutine.
Speaker 1: Ah, shit.
Speaker 1: Where are you going to get it from?
Speaker 0: St.
Speaker 0: Mark's.
Speaker 0: There's like 10 poutine places right around there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's not near your work.
Speaker 0: No, not near my work.
Speaker 0: Nothing.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: They got this, like, garlic aioli you can get for your Frites or sun-dried tomato.
Speaker 0: The only thing I want more than some poutine in Midtown is a fucking Davella's.
Speaker 1: Davella's.
Speaker 1: We need that big day.
Speaker 1: But, yeah, so, like, there are some people that are just really kicking it out there.
Speaker 0: So, what's your burger?
Speaker 0: Like, what's your burger?
Speaker 0: Like, your go-to burger.
Speaker 1: Go-to?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I just... I don't really have a go-to burger.
Speaker 1: I get whatever I'm in the mood.
Speaker 1: I change my mood all the time.
Speaker 1: The main things that I care about, right, in terms of quality are how the bun holds up, right?
Speaker 1: Because I'm holding on to the bun to eat the burger, right?
Speaker 1: And if the bun doesn't become all soggy, you know, then it greatly, greatly enhances the burger eating experience.
Speaker 0: That's my main complaint, other than the fries with Good Burger.
Speaker 0: The bun basically, like, squeezes the burger out of it.
Speaker 0: Like, you touch it and it falls apart.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, you got to have a solid bun that holds the burger inside, because then the whole eating experience, I don't get my hands all greasy, and, oh, it becomes so much better, because then I'm able to eat it properly.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 0: I have found I like really messy burgers.
Speaker 0: Like, I kind of like things like pizza burgers, sloppy joes.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I like a pizza burger so much.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess it's all right.
Speaker 0: The thing is, most pizza burgers are shit, because they're either high school cafeteria tier, or they're at a diner where they're just a normal burger with some marinara.
Speaker 0: But a proper messy burger, you've got to eat it.
Speaker 0: You've basically got to go into that burger saying, "I am not going to wipe off my face or hands until I'm done.
Speaker 0: I am going to eat this, and I don't give a
Speaker 0: shit.".
Speaker 0: Then you can enjoy it, but only then.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, you're going to go bite.
Speaker 0: Napkin, napkin, napkin, napkin, napkin.
Speaker 0: Bite, napkin, napkin, napkin.
Speaker 0: You're going to whip out the knife and the fork, and it's not going to be a good time.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean, I like to go sometimes for just lettuce, tomato, onion.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: I like the onion.
Speaker 0: I like the pickle.
Speaker 1: I don't like the pickle.
Speaker 1: I'm not a pickle fan.
Speaker 0: It's very rare I'll get a burger without a pickle.
Speaker 1: I don't like pickle.
Speaker 1: I mean, I like pickles, but I only like certain kinds of pickles, which is usually not the kind that put in a burger.
Speaker 0: I like the pickle.
Speaker 1: Pickle on the burger doesn't make it good.
Speaker 1: It makes it worse.
Speaker 1: It's no good.
Speaker 0: I think my favorite, of all the burgers I've ever eaten, other than the burgers Lisa made that one time at James' house back at RIT.
Speaker 0: Oh my God, those burgers.
Speaker 0: Was that Banya burger down in Wildwood.
Speaker 1: Oh, shit.
Speaker 0: That Banya burger is so good.
Speaker 0: I forgot.
Speaker 1: I wasn't even thinking about the freaking alumni grill.
Speaker 1: I don't know if that can be beat.
Speaker 0: Because the Banya burger.
Speaker 1: I think alumni grill might be best ever.
Speaker 0: We brought this up on Geek Nights a couple of times.
Speaker 0: It is a thick burger on a good bun, and it has got this kind of like green pepper jalapeno sauce and cheese.
Speaker 0: But no, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: It's not just cheese.
Speaker 0: Cheese sticks.
Speaker 0: It's fried cheese sticks in the place of cheese.
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: Like, alumni grill, their meat isn't the best meat in the universe.
Speaker 1: And their bun isn't the best bun in the universe.
Speaker 1: But it's good.
Speaker 1: It's real good.
Speaker 0: The closest thing I've ever had to that is there's this one chili sauce burger at Schnippers.
Speaker 0: Other than the fact that it doesn't have cheese sticks, it is basically that burger.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, one of the burgers that I like to go for is the barbecue burger.
Speaker 1: And they got the barbecue burger, but it's half chicken, half burger in the same sandwich.
Speaker 1: That's too much.
Speaker 1: It's the best.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's so good.
Speaker 0: Usually the barbecue burger, I'm leery of, but then again, I usually get it.
Speaker 1: Why would you be leery?
Speaker 0: Because I always get it like a diner.
Speaker 1: Get some bacon and barbecue in there?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's always bacon, barbecue, and A1 or some BS like that.
Speaker 1: No, no, A1.
Speaker 1: Actual barbecue sauce.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You get in there.
Speaker 0: Of course, if you're going to get the barbecue, go one step further.
Speaker 0: Get the Wooster Burger.
Speaker 1: No, not really.
Speaker 0: I like the Wooster Burger.
Speaker 1: I'm not a big fan of Wooster's.
Speaker 0: Not a fan of mushrooms unless it's a big portabella.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, if it's a portabella, that replaces the burger.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess I don't like a burger that has like chopped mushrooms on it.
Speaker 1: No, not really.
Speaker 1: But a burger that is- I like mushrooms, just not a burger.
Speaker 0: But a burger that is a beef patty and then a portabella.
Speaker 0: Ah, ah, ah.
Speaker 1: No, you got to have just- You got to go double.
Speaker 1: If you got the big mushroom, you don't have the burgers out.
Speaker 1: Double.
Speaker 1: It replaces the meat.
Speaker 0: It's basically a double decker.
Speaker 1: No, I don't like a double decker.
Speaker 0: I like a double decker.
Speaker 1: No, two meats is too much meats.
Speaker 0: Because I like the patty melt.
Speaker 0: It's weird though.
Speaker 0: Or the patty melt club.
Speaker 1: It's weird though, right?
Speaker 1: See, here's the thing with the meats, right?
Speaker 1: If you actually get two burgers on there, even if they're small, right?
Speaker 1: So let's say you get two quarter pounders on the same bun, right?
Speaker 0: You get that extra half bun in the middle.
Speaker 1: Well, no.
Speaker 1: Even if there's no half bun in the middle, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: So you get two quarter pounders in there, right?
Speaker 1: The thing is, there's outside burger and inside burger.
Speaker 1: So really, you're doubling the surface area.
Speaker 1: So the outside charred part of the burger, you're getting a lot more of.
Speaker 1: And the inside part, you're getting a lot less of.
Speaker 1: So a double burger with two quarter pounders, I just can't even eat that.
Speaker 1: But, if you give me a single half pounder, right?
Speaker 1: That, I can go for.
Speaker 1: I can even do a single, well, maybe not three quarters of a pound, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, Fuddruckers has the one pounder, right?
Speaker 0: I ate a one pounder once.
Speaker 1: At Fuddruckers?
Speaker 1: The big thing that's as big as a personal pizza.
Speaker 0: I ate a one pound burger.
Speaker 0: And I was just fine.
Speaker 0: I was just fine.
Speaker 0: However.
Speaker 1: You didn't eat anything else?
Speaker 0: However, I was in high school when I could pull shit like that off.
Speaker 0: I mean, I think I've recounted the famous story where me and my friends were kicked out of a pizza hut for abusing the all you can eat buffet.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But, yeah.
Speaker 1: So, it's like, you know, because the half pound burger, right?
Speaker 1: Cooked properly.
Speaker 1: You know, the outside will be charred, the inside will be all juicy.
Speaker 1: So, it's not like you're eating a double burger.
Speaker 1: So, I can actually, I can stomach that.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: My favorite burger recently, though.
Speaker 1: Plus, too much charred food is going to give you pancreatic cancer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: I'm willing to put up with that risk.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: Kind of like how I occasionally still eat cooked sprouts.
Speaker 0: Even though I know it's dangerous.
Speaker 0: But every time I eat it now, I think.
Speaker 0: I think I'm basically skiing down a double black mountain of sprouts.
Speaker 0: Am I okay with this?
Speaker 1: Kind of.
Speaker 1: You're going to hang glide off the double black mountain.
Speaker 0: That's why I'm eating sprouts again.
Speaker 0: Because if I'm going to risk my life doing dangerous shit, sprouts can't be more dangerous than a double black diamond.
Speaker 1: Yes, they are.
Speaker 0: Depends.
Speaker 1: You'll die instantly.
Speaker 0: Pete will jump in.
Speaker 0: He'll yell at me.
Speaker 0: But, that five napkins.
Speaker 0: I'm worried because it's closer to my apartment than I thought.
Speaker 0: And it's also next to the movie theater.
Speaker 0: And they have this root beer.
Speaker 0: Well, it's actually like a ginger ale rum float.
Speaker 1: They actually serve the milkshake properly there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, with the malt thing.
Speaker 1: What do you mean malt thing?
Speaker 0: I used to go to malt shops when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: And the malt shops would bring you the milkshake in the shaker.
Speaker 1: That's what you call the shaker?
Speaker 1: It's a metal cup.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they called it the malt cup because they made malts in the malt cup.
Speaker 0: If you got a shake as opposed to a malt, they made it in a regular blender.
Speaker 0: If you got a malt, they made it in the milkshake blender.
Speaker 0: They called it the malter.
Speaker 0: Anyway, they bring you that cup.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, when you make anyone who buys a milkshake machine, it's this little thing that comes with mixers and these metal cups.
Speaker 1: And when you get a milkshake, they're supposed to give you the metal cup, pour a glass full of milkshake and leave the remaining, because the metal cup holds like 36, some ridiculous number of ounces.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: So they're supposed to leave the metal cup on your table so you can refill your milkshake glass.
Speaker 1: But a lot of places don't do that.
Speaker 1: They're cheap asses.
Speaker 1: And they just fill a little glass, probably a tapered glass, with like 16 ounces of milkshake, and that's all you get.
Speaker 0: Which is fine because I don't need that much milkshake.
Speaker 1: No, I need the whole thing.
Speaker 0: I don't need the whole thing.
Speaker 1: No, I'm paying for that because I'll charge you the same amount.
Speaker 0: I will pay more for less because I just want some milkshake.
Speaker 0: No, I want the whole fucking milkshake.
Speaker 1: No, it's exactly the right amount.
Speaker 0: Way too much.
Speaker 0: It's the right amount.
Speaker 0: You're not as much the appetizer guy as I am.
Speaker 0: Look, we went to Five Navkin, right?
Speaker 0: I wanted that milkshake and I got the milkshake, and I got my big ass burger, and I got fries.
Speaker 1: I got a lot of stuff.
Speaker 1: I got all the same stuff.
Speaker 1: I had the burger and the sweet potato fries.
Speaker 0: But lately I'm really feeling that default Five Navkin burger.
Speaker 1: It was pretty good.
Speaker 1: I liked it.
Speaker 0: But I'm also craving, because I haven't had him in like six or seven months, Sloppy Joe.
Speaker 0: I think it's time.
Speaker 1: Well, Sloppy Joe is not a burger.
Speaker 0: It's a burger.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: It's a burger-like device that I put in my mouth.
Speaker 0: It makes burger happen.
Speaker 1: No, listen.
Speaker 1: Sloppy Joe.
Speaker 1: I mean, you could make a Sloppy Joe a burger, but you put Sloppy Joe on top of a burger.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 1: But a hamburger needs to have a patty of ground beef that is then cooked.
Speaker 0: So is a patty melt a burger then?
Speaker 1: Does it have a patty of ground beef?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Is it then placed between two pieces of bread?
Speaker 0: It is placed between two rye bread toasts.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: Toasts.
Speaker 0: You said bread.
Speaker 0: You said pieces of bread.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: They have to be actual bun breads.
Speaker 0: What's the difference between bun and bread?
Speaker 0: Tell me right now.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you the difference right now.
Speaker 1: A bun, right, is simply a roll.
Speaker 0: And then you can't pull that bullshit with your brioche burger.
Speaker 0: A brioche?
Speaker 1: You can make a brioche roll and cut it in half.
Speaker 0: So what's the difference between a roll and a bun?
Speaker 1: A bun is a roll that's been cut in half.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: What's a hot cross bun?
Speaker 1: It's cut two times.
Speaker 0: Cut two times?
Speaker 0: It's not cut.
Speaker 0: It's just crossed.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: No, but it's a cross bun because the top of it has a little cross in it and it's hot because it's hot.
Speaker 1: It just came out of the oven.
Speaker 1: It's a hot cross bun.
Speaker 1: Anyway, if you use a rye bread, a rye bread is not a roll, right?
Speaker 1: Unless you take a whole loaf of rye bread and cut it in half or make a rye roll.
Speaker 1: I don't know how you'd make a rye roll.
Speaker 1: Make a really small rye bread and cut it in half?
Speaker 1: Because it's all about the crust, right?
Speaker 1: Because a roll is a whole bunch of crust in sort of a rounded shape.
Speaker 1: Whereas a rye bread, the crust would only be around the edges and you would actually have inner breads on the top and bottom.
Speaker 0: What if I take a rye bread and cut the top and bottom off and put a patty melt inside of it?
Speaker 1: Because you make a small rye bread in the shape of a roll, which would make it a rye roll.
Speaker 0: So is that okay?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So I make a patty melt like that.
Speaker 0: What about the patty melt?
Speaker 1: Would it still be a patty melt?
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: Would it?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, the trouble is a melt is basically make grilled cheese and put a burger in it.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: That's a melt.
Speaker 1: But grilled cheese doesn't go on a roll.
Speaker 1: Grilled cheese goes on two slices of bread.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but what if I make grilled cheese, but the back of each grilled cheese, the outside part, is the crust of a rye bread?
Speaker 0: Now I've got a patty melt burger.
Speaker 1: But then no, because it's not a grilled cheese if it's not two slices.
Speaker 1: It would then be a roll.
Speaker 0: It's two slices, but the backs of both slices are crust.
Speaker 1: No, those aren't slices if the backs are both crusts.
Speaker 0: But who says it has to be slices to be a grilled cheese?
Speaker 0: I've made grilled cheese with the ends before.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So then how about this, right?
Speaker 1: You buy a cheeseburger.
Speaker 1: Is a cheeseburger not a grilled cheese?
Speaker 1: There's cheese in there.
Speaker 1: It was grilled.
Speaker 0: No, because you have to grill the cheese.
Speaker 1: How is a cheeseburger a cheeseburger and not a grilled cheese with meat?
Speaker 0: It is a grilled cheese if you heat up the bun on a griddle with butter and melt cheese into it.
Speaker 1: They do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Then it is also a grilled cheese.
Speaker 0: If I'm eating this food, it now has the tags.
Speaker 0: It's like free market.
Speaker 0: Tag, burger.
Speaker 0: Tag, grilled cheese.
Speaker 1: Two tags.
Speaker 1: It can't be both.
Speaker 1: It can be both.
Speaker 1: It can't be a cheeseburger and be a grilled cheese sandwich.
Speaker 1: Because it's not just a grilled cheese.
Speaker 1: It's a grilled cheese sandwich.
Speaker 0: You're stuck in this old world nomenclature, this hierarchical bullshit.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, I'm using a hip modern tagging system.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: That's what it is.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: I'm so hungry.
Speaker 1: So we could talk about burgers for like a hundred years probably.
Speaker 0: I'll say this.
Speaker 0: I'm so hungry and in like five minutes I'm going down to Spin, which is like this high class ping pong club.
Speaker 1: You're going to Spin?
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Second time.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Company's paying too.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 1: Spin.
Speaker 1: For what?
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: Why was this occasion?
Speaker 0: Celebrating the fact that I still work there.
Speaker 1: Just for you?
Speaker 0: No, for my department that we all still work there.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Company president.
Speaker 0: Fancy affair.
Speaker 0: You know what they got there?
Speaker 1: They got sliders.
Speaker 0: They smell like they have that onion that White Castle has, but it's real goddamn meat.
Speaker 0: They're basically real meat, White Castle.
Speaker 1: Not a fan of the sliders.
Speaker 0: These are damn good sliders.
Speaker 0: These sliders have pickle, onion, lettuce, tomato, ketchup, mustard.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: First of all, I don't like mustard.
Speaker 0: Well, fuck you.
Speaker 1: Second of all, you know, the thing with sliders is a lot of, it's, they don't, you know- They're not burgers.
Speaker 0: They're sliders.
Speaker 0: I will give you that.
Speaker 1: It's just, they're just not, they can't replace a hamburger.
Speaker 0: No, they can't.
Speaker 0: But if you eat 10 of those things, you're not so good at ping pong anymore.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando Kay for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.