Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, November 29th, 2011.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Skye.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights Tonight, the 100%.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: I was cleaning out the junk drawer the other day.
Speaker 1: You know the junk drawer?
Speaker 1: Everyone has one, that drawer with shit in it.
Speaker 1: Like random stuff, there's nowhere to put it.
Speaker 1: Like what's this?
Speaker 1: Receipt or a key?
Speaker 1: I don't know who's key this is.
Speaker 1: Put it in the drawer, forget about it.
Speaker 1: Well, I cleaned that drawer out, and in that drawer I found a roll of film.
Speaker 1: Like, it was already rewound inside the little cylinder.
Speaker 1: So, it's been taken.
Speaker 1: Someone has taken pictures on it.
Speaker 1: It was like standard 35mm film, the kind I used to use like at RIT.
Speaker 1: The latest date...
Speaker 0: Was it that weird Advantix film?
Speaker 0: No, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: Okay, because that's the kind I had.
Speaker 1: The latest date this could be from, based on my estimations of the last time I used...
Speaker 0: 1999 or 2000.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is probably from high school, maybe...
Speaker 0: The year 2000, which was 11, 12 years ago.
Speaker 1: There is a tiny chance it is from our freshman year of RIT, but I kind of doubt that.
Speaker 1: I really wonder what's on it, and I gotta find someone to develop it.
Speaker 1: And once I do, as long as I'm not arrested, because there's pictures of like, I don't know, some dirty bomb terrorist plot and I just found this film.
Speaker 0: Yeah, wouldn't that suck?
Speaker 0: Like, you just find a roll of film and you're curious, you take it to be developed, and it's child porn.
Speaker 0: And then you're in jail.
Speaker 0: Because you found it on the street.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that would suck.
Speaker 1: It's one of the reasons why film sucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not like.
Speaker 1: if I find a USB stick on the ground, I gotta go to a techie and be like, "Can you develop this for
Speaker 1: me?".
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Actually, some people do.
Speaker 1: I can imagine someone giving me a USB stick like, "Yeah, there's stuff on here.
Speaker 0: Can you get it off for
Speaker 0: me?".
Speaker 0: I imagine though, the dumbest of the dumb people take their SD card to the drugstore and they plug it into that machine.
Speaker 1: And have the things print out or go onto a CD.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But I went to like four drugstores and I realized that, oh yeah, drugstores don't really develop film anymore.
Speaker 0: No, they just have those machines, like I just said.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I found a couple of places, but they're not near my work.
Speaker 1: So sometime in the next week, I'm gonna take this roll of film, probably the last film I will ever touch with my hands in the rest of my life.
Speaker 0: Well, you didn't even touch the film.
Speaker 0: The film's inside a plastic tube.
Speaker 1: I will never again touch the container.
Speaker 1: I will never again touch a container with film in it.
Speaker 1: Unless maybe I get the old 8mm videos from my parents' childhood.
Speaker 1: So we'll see what's on that thing.
Speaker 1: Most likely, awkward nerdy pictures of me in high school.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: I got nothing.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Okay, let's do news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we can do that.
Speaker 0: So check this out.
Speaker 0: The Humble Bundles.
Speaker 0: They're coming out, but a lot more bundles more frequently lately.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm less and less excited about each bundle.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is, a lot of the bundles, they just have shit you already got in them.
Speaker 0: It's like, come on guys, every bundle should be 100% consisting of things that have never been in any bundle ever.
Speaker 0: Now I can understand if there's some overlap between the Steam sale and the bundle, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like, this bundle's got shit that have been in bundles before.
Speaker 1: I sadly have a much more direct reason why I'm not so excited.
Speaker 0: I own a bunch of bundles and I've never played any of the games in them?
Speaker 1: I haven't played more than half of the games I own on Steam.
Speaker 1: Not even like, haven't played a lot.
Speaker 1: I mean, have never even double clicked on it.
Speaker 0: Yup, exactly.
Speaker 1: So, what do I do now?
Speaker 0: Right, exactly.
Speaker 0: I basically haven't been buying any games.
Speaker 0: The only game I bought was Zelda, which is pretty good.
Speaker 0: You should get it.
Speaker 1: Now Scott, why aren't we playing these games?
Speaker 1: Well, uh...
Speaker 0: Some of the games you play for like a minute and you realize they're not worth playing.
Speaker 1: I don't even get to that point.
Speaker 1: I don't even click on them.
Speaker 1: You know why?
Speaker 1: I'm going through, here's my Steam stats.
Speaker 1: 150 hours played of Counter-Strike Source since they started counting.
Speaker 1: Last played, yesterday.
Speaker 0: First played, the day came out.
Speaker 1: First played, before the P90.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the current bundle is the humble introversion bundle.
Speaker 0: And you know, introversion, those are the guys who made Uplink, Darwinia, Defcon, Multiwinnia.
Speaker 1: You mean all the games that had critical flaws?
Speaker 0: Uplink didn't really.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Uplink was okay.
Speaker 1: But Multiwinnia had critical flaws.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: And Darwinia wasn't flawed, but was single player.
Speaker 0: And Defcon is flawed, slightly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Defcon is a great concept, but the controls for Defcon...
Speaker 0: Well, the problem is that to win, you had to micromanage the airplanes and the submarines and such.
Speaker 1: I was fine with that.
Speaker 1: The only part that sucked was micromanaging the silos because you basically had to do an equivalent of kiting, where you have to coordinate all the silos to make sure 10 ICBMs are going to one place at the same time.
Speaker 1: And that was the least possible fun you could have playing that game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the fun, you know, they needed to make it more abstract, where the micromanagement of exactly where and when you clicked at what second didn't matter, as much as simply your decision of when to click, relatively speaking.
Speaker 1: Actually, the fleet movement and the submarine stuff, I love.
Speaker 0: The movement, yes, but the controlling of the anyway.
Speaker 1: Even that was fine.
Speaker 1: Literally, the only thing they needed to change is that the silos should fire intelligently if you give them a target, rather than basically defaulting to shoot a missile every time.
Speaker 1: I'm ready to be trivially shot down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, so that's the current bundle.
Speaker 0: If you haven't played those games, this bundle's well worth it, even just for uplink, because, I mean, like, you can pay whatever you want, right?
Speaker 0: So I think you can pay, like, a penny and get all this shit.
Speaker 1: And uplink is pretty fun.
Speaker 0: If you pay more than the average, right, which is currently $3.86, you get Aquaria, which I already have from some other bundle.
Speaker 1: I already have that as well.
Speaker 0: And Crayon Physics Deluxe, which I probably have from some other bundle.
Speaker 1: I actually don't have that.
Speaker 0: You'll also get Dungeons of Dreadmoor, which actually looks interesting, and I might buy the bundle just for that.
Speaker 0: You also get prototypes of two things that Introversion made, which is a subversion city generator and a voxel tech demo.
Speaker 0: Subversion was the game that they were gonna make.
Speaker 0: that was, like, the bank heist game, which I guess got shit-canned, I don't know.
Speaker 0: But, the most interesting thing of this whole bundle, and the re- The most interesting thing.
Speaker 0: The reason that I'm definitely gonna buy it for $3.87, or whatever, 1 cent above the average, maybe just 5 bucks to play it safe, right, is you get the source code to Darwinia, Multiwinia, Defcon, and uplink.
Speaker 1: I did not pay attention to the news enough to know that.
Speaker 0: That's pretty epic right there.
Speaker 0: Also, you know, they always show the top contributors for the bundle?
Speaker 0: Alright, who do you think made, 'cause remember, I think that for the first bundle, Notch gave the most monies, right?
Speaker 0: Who do you think is the number one contributor for this bundle?
Speaker 1: Number one contributor?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: It's another bundle.
Speaker 0: took their money and gave it to this bundle.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Humble Brony Bundle gave $12.50 to the Humble Introversion Bundle as the number one contributor.
Speaker 1: Wait, $12.50?
Speaker 0: No, $1250.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: But yeah, there's a Humble Brony Bundle.
Speaker 1: What, pray tell, is in the Humble Brony Bundle?
Speaker 1: Is that just all those kind of knock-off platformers that have a Rainbow Dash in them?
Speaker 0: Uh, ahem.
Speaker 0: Humble Brony Bundle.
Speaker 1: Or is it 10 Dating Sims?
Speaker 0: Hold on.
Speaker 1: And then some sort of, like, erotic dating sim.
Speaker 0: The Humble Brony Bundle is currently at $35.12, so $12.50 of that they gave to Humble Introversion Bundle, right?
Speaker 0: A-ta-ta.
Speaker 0: Humble Brony Bundle are packs of games, so Humble, we have ponies coming together to create a fun... Oh!
Speaker 0: It's a way for bronies to come together and create a fund to buy one big copy of the Humble Indie Bundle.
Speaker 1: So then!
Speaker 0: So there you have it.
Speaker 0: They pooled their money to buy the Humble Indie Bundle once, and they're at $35.12, they've only given $12.50 so far.
Speaker 1: That was sadly anti-climactic, because I know for a fact that people...
Speaker 0: I wish that they had a bundle of, like, something, but anyway...
Speaker 1: 'Cause if you've seen, there's this amazing trend of, you know, because people are really big into doing remixed stuff with the ponies, is that a ton of people think that they're gonna make, like, the next great game with ponies.
Speaker 1: There's, like, 10 different groups of people making, like, Dating Sims and platformers and quest games...
Speaker 0: Phoenix Wright 1, this MMOs...
Speaker 1: I don't know, as much as I would like to play one of those, I think Bobo's Big Adventure is what I'm waiting for.
Speaker 0: Bobo is definitely where it's at.
Speaker 0: Also, you know, plenty of the games that we've been waiting for for a long time are still not out yet.
Speaker 0: Retro City Rampage, Monaco, Spy Party... Come on, guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Monaco, I would pay a lot of money for just to be able to play right now.
Speaker 0: Seriously, those games, they're gonna be out probably within the next two years.
Speaker 1: The crappy, you know, not finished version I played at PAX a long time ago was enough for me to pay money.
Speaker 0: Right, so within the next two years, all three of those games will probably be out.
Speaker 0: And, yeah, that's it.
Speaker 1: Sadly, of all these games, right now, I'm most looking forward to a Bobo because it gives me everything that I like about Charles Barkley's Shut Up and Jam Gaiden without it being a JRPG.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: My thoughts.
Speaker 0: 100%.
Speaker 1: So, there's an article on Slashdot.
Speaker 1: It amazes me that articles like this get written or that anyone even... Rick Romero would be proud.
Speaker 1: Why it sucks to work at Zynga.
Speaker 0: Well, why wouldn't it suck to work at Zynga?
Speaker 1: Alright, so you work for a company that makes things that I would barely classify as games.
Speaker 0: They should make an article.
Speaker 0: why the good parts about working at Zynga?
Speaker 0: because I assumed that all the parts were bad, so it's like...
Speaker 1: According to the article, I actually read these articles and read some of the comments and everything.
Speaker 1: And the consensus seems to be that EA has much better working conditions.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine.
Speaker 1: Which is kind of amazing, but really Zynga is...
Speaker 0: Man, you know what?
Speaker 0: Foxconn has better working conditions.
Speaker 1: Zynga is perhaps the most destructive force in gaming the world has ever seen, but I can't blame them because they don't actually make games.
Speaker 1: It's like they're making a different product that the average person conflates with games.
Speaker 1: They think that, I don't know, Tribes 2-2 or Skyrim somehow on some level competes with a click on stuff to level it up game in Facebook.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, it takes people's time.
Speaker 0: There's people who do both.
Speaker 0: It's weird, right?
Speaker 0: Because with most games, at least, that aren't subscription-based, right?
Speaker 0: It's not about how much time someone spends.
Speaker 0: It doesn't correlate to how much money they make.
Speaker 0: It's just, did they buy the game or not?
Speaker 0: What do they fucking care if you play Skyrim?
Speaker 0: You bought it.
Speaker 0: They shouldn't even give a shit if you play it for one second or one year.
Speaker 1: Maybe they care because the designer likes you to enjoy the game or something, but that's not a business concern.
Speaker 0: Right, but in fact, they'd actually probably like it more if you didn't play the game so much because then you'd need something to occupy your time and you would buy a different game.
Speaker 0: If you were so obsessed with Skyrim that you played it for a long fucking time, you wouldn't be buying other games.
Speaker 1: No, then they'll make plenty of money off of you, Scott, because Horse Armor.
Speaker 1: They'll sell you DLC and you'll buy it gladly.
Speaker 0: Well, that's what they're doing now, right?
Speaker 0: But that's why they're doing that now.
Speaker 0: What instead they should do is they should make games that cost a dollar, but only occupy you for like five minutes so that you have to spend another dollar five minutes or now on a different game instead of a DLC for a big game.
Speaker 1: But it's weird because on one hand, I could argue that things like that, the things they make, on some level do compete with games.
Speaker 1: I'll bet that Nintendo is actually hurting from the fact that, you know, all things considered, in the end, the average really young child is going to have as much fun playing Diner Dash as he will playing a $50 first party Nintendo game on a DS.
Speaker 1: And they already probably have an iPhone for the kid.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand, at least when people, you know, gamers complain that Myst ruined gaming.
Speaker 1: Scott used to always say that because Myst was a game that came out that wasn't that great.
Speaker 0: Myst did create a large pile of crappy games and it did have a profound effect on gaming for many years.
Speaker 0: that has only recently worn off.
Speaker 0: And it was, if Myst had not come out in the way, in the fashion that it did, the gaming for the course of those years would have been significantly different.
Speaker 0: And I argue most likely better.
Speaker 1: Drew, I did not say you were wrong because Myst...
Speaker 0: For people who don't know, right, so here's the basic argument, right?
Speaker 0: Myst was a game that had graphics that were basically astounding for its time.
Speaker 1: But no, they were astounding to people who didn't know better because they were basically just stills.
Speaker 0: Right, they basically, they cheated.
Speaker 0: What they did is, right, when you have a computer, right, people always, you know, remember it wasn't Emily's boss who was like they wanted the game to look like Toy Story, right?
Speaker 0: The reason that Toy Story looks better than video games is because they render Toy Story very slowly.
Speaker 0: They can spend an hour rendering one frame if they want because after the frame is rendered, they just save it to a hard drive.
Speaker 0: And then you can watch the frames at, you know, 40, whatever, 30, 20, whatever frames a second.
Speaker 0: that, you know, the movie is.
Speaker 0: And you don't have to render them at, you know, the same speed that you're going to watch them.
Speaker 0: Video games, you need to render the frames as fast as the person is looking at them, which means you need to render at least 75 FPS if you have a 75 hertz display.
Speaker 0: Which means that you have to decrease the quality to be much less than Toy Story, which is rendering probably a frame a second at best.
Speaker 1: And Myst came out in an era, I mean, Myst had talking videos in it and that was an era when I was amazed that a MIDI file would play in a game.
Speaker 0: So Myst was a game that had all of its graphics pre-rendered and stored on a CD-ROM as opposed to being rendered in real time by a video card.
Speaker 0: So even for years after...
Speaker 1: Video card?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Back then?
Speaker 0: Video cards didn't exist then.
Speaker 1: That was video memory on your computer.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So in those days, it took years for it to be a game that looked as good as Myst.
Speaker 0: that wasn't also pre-rendered.
Speaker 0: And as a result, the standards for what people expected of video game graphics went way up.
Speaker 1: Kind of like the difference between, like, Rebel Assault, I think it was called, versus TIE Fighter.
Speaker 0: Also, people sold a shit ton of copies of Myst.
Speaker 0: It sold a ton of fucking copies for its day.
Speaker 0: Now at the same time, I would argue... Even among normal people, so...
Speaker 1: It wasn't Myst's fault, because...
Speaker 0: Well, you're saying that it was inevitable that someone was gonna do it?
Speaker 1: No, no, no, I'm saying that I think Myst was a pretty crap game and I think the puzzles were pretty arbitrary and crap.
Speaker 1: But, I understand why some people would like that game.
Speaker 1: The problem wasn't that Myst created these expectations.
Speaker 1: The problem was that the game industry, the people who made the decisions as to what games to make and what demographics to go after, saw Myst come out...
Speaker 0: That's exactly what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: And decided that that is the way to go.
Speaker 1: It wasn't Myst's fault.
Speaker 1: It was everyone else's fault but Myst.
Speaker 0: Well, no, but that's the thing.
Speaker 0: It was still Myst's fault, right?
Speaker 0: Myst had these pre-rendered graphics that were amazing.
Speaker 1: That's like blaming the kitten that Hitler tripped over for the genocide.
Speaker 0: They saw it sold incredibly well with these pre-rendered graphics.
Speaker 0: Thus, the people in the game industry saw that as the example and believed that good graphics were gonna sell a ton of copies.
Speaker 1: Ah, but here's the rub.
Speaker 0: So for years, they put graphics as a higher priority than everything else.
Speaker 0: Scott, they didn't think really about why it sold.
Speaker 0: And only recently have they realized their mistake.
Speaker 1: Because the graphics were part of it, but part of why it sold is a lot of the people who got into Myst were not gamers until Myst.
Speaker 1: They didn't play games.
Speaker 1: They didn't think of games.
Speaker 1: Gaming on a computer was not something they did.
Speaker 1: And Myst was kind of this thing that a lot of moms and a lot of non-gamers really got into, and that was great.
Speaker 1: But the rest of the industry said, "Oh, look at all these people buying this
Speaker 1: game.".
Speaker 1: And they were more interested in money than whatever demographic they might have been targeting in the past.
Speaker 1: So they decided to shift gears and all go after this one, new, poorly understood demographic all at once.
Speaker 1: I feel like the current game industry is doing the same thing.
Speaker 0: Right, only instead of it being graphics-based, it's angry birds-based.
Speaker 1: Except Angry Birds is a pretty good game.
Speaker 0: It's the best of them, yeah.
Speaker 0: It's playable.
Speaker 1: Angry Birds at least is a game.
Speaker 1: The majority of the Zynga stuff, I would argue, don't meet any reasonable definition of game.
Speaker 0: Anyway, Super Stickman Golf, let me tell you.
Speaker 0: That's the shit.
Speaker 0: You should get that if you got a phone.
Speaker 1: I saw you guys talking about that while I was in Japan.
Speaker 0: Super Stickman Golf is the business.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: I haven't used one of these in a while, and partly because they've passed.
Speaker 1: They've had their time.
Speaker 1: I used to love-- You've seen one.
Speaker 0: You've seen them all?
Speaker 1: Well, partly thanks to the internet, I think I have seen them all.
Speaker 0: I have also seen them all.
Speaker 1: It is very rare that I see a fail video.
Speaker 1: that is not just basically a retelling of a fail video I've already seen.
Speaker 1: And in those rare instances, I'm very surprised, but at the same time, I feel like my cup runneth over.
Speaker 1: I can only see so many people hit in the nuts by their own stupidity before I no longer care.
Speaker 1: So I present to you the fail collection of 2011.
Speaker 0: Well, it's the November, I think, specifically.
Speaker 1: Ah, it might be.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It was on CollegeHumor recently.
Speaker 1: If you have not watched fail videos before, many people I know have not.
Speaker 1: It was a thing that was actually surprisingly, in many ways, at least among my kind of crew, bigger ten years ago and kind of faded a little bit.
Speaker 1: Because there's no longer the mystique of like, "I got this video of a guy crashing a helicopter.
Speaker 1: Now it's all just on
Speaker 1: YouTube.".
Speaker 1: You can type in the specific kind of fail you want, and YouTube will give it to you.
Speaker 1: This, however, is a classical collection of fail, because unlike a lot of misnamed fail compilations, as far as I could see watching this, every single one of these was the result of a person taking an undue, unnecessary risk with improper equipment and/or being drunk.
Speaker 0: And deserving it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not like, you know, random guy gets, you know, like a helicopter falls on him.
Speaker 1: It's guy's a dumbass and pilot's a helicopter incorrectly.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: I present to you a fail video.
Speaker 0: So, one of the things that we hate the most, slow people on the sidewalks and the stairs and the platforms and the places where there are bottlenecks of humanity.
Speaker 1: I mean, I understand that they don't have anywhere to be, but I got places to be.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: So, at least walk single file and stay to the right so I can go past you like lightning.
Speaker 0: You won't even see me, like Rainbow Dash.
Speaker 0: Ah, shit.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Some guy in Japan, he has the same problem as us.
Speaker 0: He hates the slow walking people.
Speaker 0: He just wants to burn by them.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, Scott, when I was in Japan, I don't think you understand how slow people walk there.
Speaker 0: They were going so slow, right?
Speaker 0: So, this guy, being Japanese, where, you know, they have the skills to solve every problem known to humanity.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: Has solved the problem of the slow walking person.
Speaker 0: He took, well, just watch the video.
Speaker 1: Two problems.
Speaker 1: This would only work in Japan because of the way Japan is when it comes to laws about what constitutes a thing that is allowed to be on the sidewalk or not allowed to be on the sidewalk.
Speaker 1: Two, it only works because it's Japan and people pay attention to this thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this wouldn't work in New York or I would do it, no matter how awkward.
Speaker 1: Dude, I do do it.
Speaker 1: In New York, I use that device when I'm on the thing to which that device is usually attached.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: No one has ever responded to it, except once a guy turned around and flipped me off.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: But anyway, this guy is genius.
Speaker 1: In the meta moment, we will be at MagFest.
Speaker 1: We will be on two of the gaming intellectuals discussion round tables.
Speaker 1: One of those will have the Dr.
Speaker 1: Hazard on with us to ream us a new intellectual asshole.
Speaker 1: We will also be doing advanced Beyond Dungeons and Dragons 3.0.
Speaker 0: Why don't you just call it advanced Beyond Dungeons and Dragons and leave it at that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know what we're calling it.
Speaker 1: Basically, we're redoing the old Beyond D&D panel because that was the first panel we ever did at Apex, and I feel like we can do better now.
Speaker 1: Also, we've played a lot more indie RPGs since then.
Speaker 1: We are going to be at a nerd night on December 8th, giving a short version of Losing Should Be Fun.
Speaker 1: I'll post a link to the details and all that, so if you're in the area and you're okay with, I think, paying some money to see some geeky lectures.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't pay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't pay for anything.
Speaker 0: To see us, I wouldn't pay.
Speaker 1: Ah, it depends.
Speaker 0: I mean, this isn't like going to a convention where you're paying to get into PAX and you're giving us an hour of the PAX time.
Speaker 1: No, there's someone else doing a lecture before ours.
Speaker 1: I don't know, I didn't look.
Speaker 0: Are they better than us?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It might be about biology or something.
Speaker 0: Oh, so we're the last?
Speaker 0: It's just two people and that's it?
Speaker 1: I think it's just two lectures.
Speaker 0: And we're number two?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I barely know.
Speaker 1: I had email conversations.
Speaker 0: You don't even know what we're doing?
Speaker 0: Would we agree to a thing that we don't know what it is?
Speaker 0: It's Blues Brothers.
Speaker 1: I found us a gig, Scott.
Speaker 0: Dude, great.
Speaker 1: Got the band back together.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that, MAGFest, PAX East is coming up.
Speaker 1: If you haven't already bought your badge, well, you're a dumbass.
Speaker 1: Buy a badge.
Speaker 0: If you didn't get your hotel room, what the fuck?
Speaker 0: PAX East and MAGFest, if you're planning to go to either one of those, you should already have your badge and hotel right this instant.
Speaker 0: If you didn't get it yesterday, you fucked up.
Speaker 1: The current book club book is?
Speaker 0: A double book club.
Speaker 0: You have to read The Little Prince by Antoine de Saint-Ejupéry, which should take you about an hour or two.
Speaker 0: And then you have to read a real book, also by Antoine de Saint-Ejupéry, which is Winds, Sand, and Stars.
Speaker 0: It may have a different name in your country.
Speaker 0: Refer to Wikipedia for more details.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Also, go to the internets and look for Geek Nights on Twitter, Facebook, Google+, and FrontRecruit.com and all those places.
Speaker 1: In fact, most importantly, because I realized lately that- Whatever place is most convenient for you- The majority of you out there who listen to Geek Nights do not participate in our forum or anything on the website.
Speaker 1: So I figure I should tell you all that all of the lectures we did at PAX East last year are on YouTube in their entirety, and I'm uploading stuff that we did from PAX Prime this past year, and videos from BurningCon, and videos from the New York Comic Con, and basically the Geek Nights Rim YouTube channel has a fuck ton of videos of stuff that we have done.
Speaker 1: So Scott, what was the last game that you 100 percented?
Speaker 1: As in- Like, actually, really, 100 percented.
Speaker 0: Like, I got every single thing there was in the game to get- There is nothing left in that game for you to do.
Speaker 0: I can't even remember if I've ever- That is a tracked thing.
Speaker 0: I mean, I know I have 100 percent- I gotta go back to the- it's like I have to work my way forward, right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I know I 100 percented Mega Man 2.
Speaker 1: I did a Zelda 1 first quest.
Speaker 0: I know I have 100 percented Zelda 1.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure I 100 percented Zelda 1 second quest, but back then there weren't, you know, percent indicators, nor were there achievements.
Speaker 1: I have- I don't know if I got every "show me the door" charge or not.
Speaker 1: I assume I did.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, shit.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that counts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have not 100 percented Super Metroid or any Castlevania or anything like that.
Speaker 1: I- well, see, it's tricky because 100 percenting has- I 100 percented Pokemon Red.
Speaker 0: I caught all the Pokemons because my brother had Pokemon Blue and we were able to do it.
Speaker 1: Final Fantasy 1, 4, and 6.
Speaker 1: As in, I leveled up Rydia until she had Media.
Speaker 1: I also got all the, you know, broken, weird summons that you can get in the US version of the game.
Speaker 0: Pokemon Red, since then?
Speaker 0: I 100 percented Advance Wars, Advance Wars 2, Advance Wars DS, I 100 percented Mario Kart, Mario Kart Super Circuit, Mario Tennis 4, the Game Cube.
Speaker 1: You know, it's funny because I would say that I 100 percented Castlevania DS, the first Castlevania on the DS, but while I did get all the items in the game, I don't think I actually got- I don't know if I got, like, every monster.
Speaker 1: Like, I think there are some things I didn't actually get.
Speaker 0: I did all the Phoenix Wright games, except for the Edgeworth one.
Speaker 1: So, what does the 100 percenting actually mean?
Speaker 1: Because in the past, there was no way to know.
Speaker 1: There wasn't, like, an indicator.
Speaker 0: Well, Super Metroid, I think, was perhaps the first game with an indicator, I'm guessing.
Speaker 1: Yup, it just told you, you know, did you get everything or not?
Speaker 0: Right, because, I mean, you could beat the game without getting, say, all the energy packs, right?
Speaker 1: Now, Doom 2 had the percent meter where it'd tell you whether or not you got all the secrets.
Speaker 0: Doom 1 had that, too.
Speaker 0: Wolfenstein had that.
Speaker 1: Oh, I 100 percented both Dooms.
Speaker 0: Wolfenstein 3D.
Speaker 1: I did not 100 percent Final Doom or any of the other Dooms.
Speaker 0: Wait, did you really 100 percent?
Speaker 0: Doom, as in kill every bad guy, get every item, get every secret?
Speaker 1: As in every level.
Speaker 1: I beat every level of Doom 2 in Ultra-Violence, getting 100 percent on all the indicators.
Speaker 0: All three indicators, 100 percent, every single level?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: That means you killed every bad guy, and you got every item, and you opened every secret.
Speaker 1: Ever living fuck out of Doom 2.
Speaker 1: I don't think you understand how much of my life is dedicated- That's a little hard to believe.
Speaker 1: Scott, remember when we played Deathmatch in Doom 2?
Speaker 0: I'm just saying, it's hard to believe that you actually 100 percented all three categories in all the levels.
Speaker 0: It's easy to believe you beat all the levels, and that you maybe even got all the secrets.
Speaker 0: There may have been a level or two where- But to kill all the bad guys in every one of those levels- There may have been a level or two where it was actually impossible to do the 100 percent.
Speaker 1: I don't remember if that was true or not, because it's been-.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, is there enough ammo to kill all those guys?
Speaker 1: Oh, yes, trivially.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Scott, you realize I pretty much used the single shotgun through most of the game on most of the bad guys.
Speaker 0: Well, of course, that's what you use, period, in the game, no matter what.
Speaker 1: I also used the chainsaw a lot, because on cacodemons it worked pretty well.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, I guess there is always enough ammo if you use the chainsaw.
Speaker 1: Yeah, unless you forget to pick it up like a dumbass.
Speaker 0: It's like, you could even use theoretically, you could use the fist, and you could have enough ammo to beat the whole game.
Speaker 1: Scott, I got bored enough to where I made custom levels with like five cyberdemons and killed them with fists.
Speaker 0: I've killed a single cyberdemon with the fist.
Speaker 1: You had the rage power up though, didn't you?
Speaker 0: I don't know, I just run around behind him, punch him in the back till he turned around, and then run away and then get him in the back again.
Speaker 0: And keep doing that for a long fucking time.
Speaker 0: Doom 2.
Speaker 0: And you just dodge a lot, spend most of your time dodging rockets, 99% of the time dodging rockets, and 1% of the time punching him.
Speaker 1: Yep, Doom 2 feels way more difficult than it is.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I digress.
Speaker 1: I don't think Doom 2 100%ing was nearly as difficult as Advance Wars 1 100%ing.
Speaker 1: I mean, beating an Advance campaign with a perfect score.
Speaker 0: I didn't beat Advance Wars 1 on regular campaigns.
Speaker 0: I think I actually did eventually do that.
Speaker 1: I don't remember if it was the second to last, or the last mission of the Advance campaign.
Speaker 1: And remember, you had to beat the regular campaign with different directions and different decisions in order to get different characters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't even beat the fucking owl in the other ones.
Speaker 1: But it came down to, you had to move this transport with an inventory in it.
Speaker 1: I think you had one or two transport choppers with inventory, and there's nothing but fighter jets.
Speaker 1: You had to move every round the exact right position, with every single one of your units, every round.
Speaker 1: One mistake, game over.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna get the perfect score.
Speaker 0: Yep, 'cause that jet's gonna squ- boom!
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: I don't know what possessed me to do that.
Speaker 0: I don't know either.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But, uh, so what's the deal?
Speaker 1: Why don't we 100% games anymore?
Speaker 0: 'Cause it's not worth the fucking time.
Speaker 1: So why was it ever worth the time?
Speaker 0: 'Cause we had a shit ton of free time and nothing to do.
Speaker 1: Is that really it, or has the bar been moved in terms of what constitutes 100%ing?
Speaker 0: Well, I think both, right?
Speaker 0: So on the one hand, right?
Speaker 0: Take, for example, a game- you know, back in the day, I had time to beat a game.
Speaker 0: Such as, you know, a Zelda.
Speaker 0: But, because I had lots of free time, I didn't just rush for the Triforce.
Speaker 0: I would go around to, you know, and bomb all the walls in the dungeon, looking for goodies.
Speaker 0: 'Cause I had time, and I didn't have money to buy so many more games.
Speaker 0: So if I stopped playing that game, what other games were there?
Speaker 0: Well, there were a bunch of games that I also had played a bunch, and I wasn't getting new games constantly.
Speaker 0: I didn't have so many games in a bundle that I couldn't even play them all.
Speaker 0: So, you were gonna play the games that you had more.
Speaker 0: You were gonna go back to the bin and play a game you beat again.
Speaker 0: And if you were gonna play a game you've already beaten, to get more entertainment out of it, you're gonna start poking around.
Speaker 0: In addition to that, right?
Speaker 0: You have the fact that, you know, if you're 100%ing, say, something like Super Metroid, right?
Speaker 0: All the stuff that you would get by getting 100% was missile packs, energy packs, things that actually, you know, improved.
Speaker 0: You know, things that you wanted to get anyway.
Speaker 0: You know, even Pokemon, which 100%, you know, it's like, well, you know, you caught Pokemon.
Speaker 0: You were actually doing something for the game.
Speaker 1: I think you're onto something, because I feel like a lot of the 100%ing kind of meta.
Speaker 1: motivations in gamers today are just that.
Speaker 1: They're meta.
Speaker 1: They're not direct to the game.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, you got a thousand Baphomet dads throughout the game.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 0: Well, the perfect example is Super Smash Brothers.
Speaker 0: Congratulations, you collected all the little action figures for the gallery.
Speaker 1: Yup, or Minish Cap.
Speaker 1: Well, you used those shells to use the slot machine to get all the whatever the fuck they were.
Speaker 0: Right, it's like, that shit just doesn't mean anything.
Speaker 0: Now, in Super Smash Brothers, of course, you're gonna unlock all the maps and you're gonna unlock all the characters.
Speaker 0: And maybe even, you know, things that matter, all the items and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: But why unlock the stupid action figures if you have better shit to do?
Speaker 1: There was a time when 100%ing, even games that tracked it, that was all that mattered.
Speaker 1: There weren't so many meta things.
Speaker 1: Maybe there was, like, the one weird thing, like, find the item that doesn't do anything.
Speaker 0: My actual earliest memories of games that did this sort of thing were a lot of the early Game Boy Color games.
Speaker 0: Like, you look at something like Game & Watch Gallery, or even, I think, Super Mario Brothers Deluxe for the Game Boy Color, which is one of the best releases of Mario Brothers.
Speaker 0: there ever was, had, like, this stuff that you could, like, collect for Mario and shit.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, I think if you had, like, a Game Boy Printer, you could print out different stickers you collected and unlocked.
Speaker 0: It just had some shit like that in there, and it's, like, you had to beat levels collecting the coin, and it's, like, why even bother?
Speaker 0: It's, like, you beat the game, you play all the levels, you know, collecting all the coins, what does it get you?
Speaker 0: Some pictures show up?
Speaker 0: It's, like, what do I need these pictures for?
Speaker 0: I can go online and look at the pictures.
Speaker 0: Why do I need to spend my time unlocking useless pictures in a game?
Speaker 1: Yup, because when I think about it, every game I've 100%ed, it has been a game where I got some, like, contextual reward for doing that in the game.
Speaker 1: Like, I've got some power armor now or something.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: And it was also usually not a, like, the game wouldn't say, "Oh shit, you 100%ed me, I just kind of knew that I've got, like, the biggest, baddest
Speaker 1: thing.".
Speaker 1: Like, in Castlevania DS.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I actually 100%ed the game, I have to go take my DS card, I don't even know if I have it anymore or if I gave it to someone or whatever, but, uh, when I got Death's Axe, like, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the,
Speaker 0: the, the, the, the, the,
Speaker 1: the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the,
Speaker 0: the, the,
Speaker 1: the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the,
Speaker 0: the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the,
Speaker 1: the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the,
Speaker 0: the, the, the, the, the, the, the
Speaker 1: the, the, the, the, the, the the, the, the the, the the the the
Speaker 0: the the
Speaker 1: the the the the
Speaker 0: the
Speaker 1: the the
Speaker 0: the the
Speaker 1: the the the the the the the the
Speaker 0: the
Speaker 1: the
Speaker 0: the the the
Speaker 1: the the
Speaker 0: the.