Speaker 1: It's Wednesday April 27th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight the great comic castle waiting.
Speaker 1: Let's do this Been a while since we've done a show Too long God a little bit sick after anime Boston and didn't finish a Thursday show before anime Boston.
Speaker 0: I was actually you know way sick after and then actually yesterday.
Speaker 0: It was so good, but then this morning Sick again double sick slightly at least.
Speaker 0: it's just you know it's just the throat tickle.
Speaker 0: It's not like you know strep throat or anything.
Speaker 1: You know I have a full-on sore throat.
Speaker 1: I skipped two days of work.
Speaker 0: It's just like you know throat tickles discomfort while swallowing.
Speaker 0: You know that kind of situation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mine left a little.
Speaker 0: Rico law can't handle.
Speaker 1: I took pretty much Maximum number of drugs I could take to feel good until I take the minimum number of drugs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's how I roll.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what.
Speaker 1: how I roll doesn't hurt, and there's no harm done.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there is what harm.
Speaker 1: what harm does pseudoephedrine guaifenis in acetaminophen and?
Speaker 1: Benadryl do taken simultaneously?
Speaker 0: liver damage among other things.
Speaker 1: liver damage usually only occurs in the cases of overdose or chronic Use or in cases of people who are alcoholics.
Speaker 0: You being an alcoholic actually I see cirrhosis.
Speaker 0: Actually you guys got in my crystal ball.
Speaker 0: There's a capital C.
Speaker 1: I would just like to point out that I do drink quite a bit But by all measures by scientific measures of how much I drink I'm on the low end of moderate drinking.
Speaker 1: you have to drink A fuck ton of alcohol to be considered.
Speaker 0: That's like saying I don't do crack.
Speaker 0: I only do crack once a week.
Speaker 1: that other guy does crack every day, but I didn't say I don't do alcohol.
Speaker 1: I do alcohol in quantity.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm just saying you may not be technically an alcoholic.
Speaker 1: I'm not even a moderate drinker.
Speaker 0: Yes, but your liver is still damaged.
Speaker 1: actually no It's not.
Speaker 0: you realize you want to have a liver battle.
Speaker 1: I think my liver could win.
Speaker 0: my liver is probably gonna kick your liver's ass.
Speaker 1: Got you to realize that the liver is not damaged.
Speaker 1: if alcohol consumption is lower than the rate of alcohol Processing it's only when you consume too much in a short period or consume large amounts chronically.
Speaker 1: Do stupid things like taking a bunch of Tylenol so Discussed or take it's got a bunch of Tylenol is not one like Tylenol p.m.. One night.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's more than me.
Speaker 0: Okay, there's probably some cells in your liver that are damaged And you know how many of my liver damage?
Speaker 1: zero you know what?
Speaker 1: probably not and also we'll see who makes it to 90 You kidding.
Speaker 0: I'm making it to.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we were at anime Boston.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna really Extra liver cells gonna carry me the whole way cuz we've been to many anime Boston's where we got to see Clarissa and Gerald and Darryl.
Speaker 1: briefly Scott saw them slightly more than I did because he went to Jikoku.
Speaker 1: yep, I did not because I had to run a panel and while I went to Scott's hot steamy coup panel Which I had nothing to do with I even sat on stage doing nothing the whole time.
Speaker 0: So good of you to sit on stage and do nothing and be in the way.
Speaker 1: I was there for the introduction, and then I just sat there one five one point.
Speaker 1: I even gave up and just put my microphone down as watched.
Speaker 1: Well, uh yeah Scott went to anime hell while I had to run my anime openers panel all by myself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I was you know showing an example and obeying the golden rule.
Speaker 0: Golden rule yeah the real golden rule Yeah, no I Didn't want you to sit on stage and annoy me so I did not sit on stage.
Speaker 1: And you know you think is you would had fun annoying people in my panel.
Speaker 1: Even though I had to cut it short I barely finished because we had to cut all the panels down to like 45 minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you know.
Speaker 0: if they don't want to put they do.
Speaker 0: I understand.
Speaker 0: It's like there was some bad discussion of whether they would put gaps in the panels, and they decided not to write.
Speaker 0: But here's the thing.
Speaker 0: So let's say you got it you got a convention you're scheduling and you decide we're not gonna put gaps.
Speaker 0: So we'll make all the panels one hour, and we'll put them right up next up against each other, okay?
Speaker 0: So that means that the panel gets an hour And then you have to switch rooms and the next panel gets an hour right and everyone has to switch rooms basically instantly.
Speaker 0: But what they did is they basically stopped all the panels 45 15 minutes early.
Speaker 0: so the panels are only actually 45 minutes long.
Speaker 0: so why didn't they just schedule on the schedule the panels to be 45 minutes long and put 15 minute gaps there?
Speaker 0: At least then I would have known my panel was you know 45 minutes instead of.
Speaker 0: I had an hour panel And I tried to use my whole hour.
Speaker 0: It was cut short.
Speaker 1: well We'll see.
Speaker 1: I mean Lou is probably of all the anime cons We work with other than the professional.
Speaker 0: he told me that he wanted gaps, and he was shot down.
Speaker 1: well the smartest and most Competent of all anime con panel schedulers.
Speaker 1: I trust Lou and I know that he always tries to do the right thing.
Speaker 1: yeah But otherwise it went well.
Speaker 1: I mean I'm a boss.
Speaker 0: I got no other.
Speaker 1: no other complaint was another anime Boston.
Speaker 1: I have one complaint.
Speaker 1: Boston apparently can't handle any number of people with cell phones.
Speaker 1: I don't know what was up this weekend, but literally like my cell phone Just kept not getting signal.
Speaker 0: I had no problem.
Speaker 1: Ah, but a lot of people are having problems mostly sprinting Verizon people.
Speaker 0: Uh I had the wait.
Speaker 0: wait I had the evil AT&T and it worked just fine.
Speaker 1: You were complaining on Saturday at like five or six junctures about how you didn't have enough signal.
Speaker 1: the stuff was loading slowly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was trying to watch an HD movie on YouTube, and it was loading slowly on a cell phone.
Speaker 0: Gee there's a surprise.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: I think what hand at the top of a hotel.
Speaker 1: I think what was happening is that one Boston doesn't have a lot of tall buildings not to disparage Boston.
Speaker 1: It is one of the only cities I've ever spent any time.
Speaker 0: It's an okay city, but they're tall.
Speaker 0: buildings are not high.
Speaker 1: Consider living in like.
Speaker 1: if I couldn't live in New York for whatever reason I think I could deal with Boston.
Speaker 1: Boston is pretty chill Even though their subway doesn't run all the time and consist of tiny buses.
Speaker 1: but I Got about two stories up.
Speaker 1: suddenly cell service starts dropping off Rapidly.
Speaker 0: yeah, they didn't have a lot of tall buildings.
Speaker 1: So we're on the twister for Scott to take his laptop downstairs Load my little pony and then come all the way back up to the 21st floor to watch it.
Speaker 0: yep But you know whatever it worked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so my biggest complaint about anime Boston was that Boston cell service for sprinting Verizon sucks.
Speaker 1: Pretty good con.
Speaker 1: all right spend most of our time in the gaming area with our awesome.
Speaker 1: None of our like local posse went.
Speaker 1: we had none of the like core front row crew.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 0: they went to.
Speaker 0: they went to PAX and yeah, they don't go to every con like we do.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 1: So it was all like fans and formites, and it was pretty rockin time shoutouts to everyone We played games with.
Speaker 1: for also We've got two people are gonna help us do that show on wrestling that we keep saying we're gonna do.
Speaker 1: Okay, I learned a lot about wrestling talking to the hit man Right.
Speaker 0: so check this out.
Speaker 0: you know IDW the comic publisher.
Speaker 0: yeah most of the comics They put out are the licensed properties.
Speaker 0: remember.
Speaker 0: They were doing that that invasion thing that was Star Trek and transformers and Ghostbusters and right oh Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well apparently they put out a comic called it GI Joe a real American hero and basically what that was You know because they basically they put out so many different GI Joe and transformers comics that are all over the place right.
Speaker 0: some of Them are standalone like there was the steampunk one that I read and there was that all hell Megatron one.
Speaker 0: It was like standalone.
Speaker 0: things have nothing to do anything else, and then they got like.
Speaker 0: they got like freaking.
Speaker 0: you know Generation this and you know bad guy perspective that and then good Cyberstron this thing and it's all is like so many different things.
Speaker 0: you can't figure out how they go together Which one you want to read.
Speaker 0: right, but apparently this one comic they have called GI Joe a real American hero, and it picks up Exactly where the original GI Joe comics from Marvel left off.
Speaker 1: well like the original original right.
Speaker 0: so the Marvel GI Joe comics from the 80s right ended so that I read a whole bunch of those.
Speaker 0: So the first issue of GI Joe a real American hero picks up exactly where that last issue left off.
Speaker 0: There's a fan petition right To IDW.
Speaker 0: that's current at Monday evening.
Speaker 0: It was at twelve hundred and two signatures Right now.
Speaker 1: sorry just fan petitions always strike me as utterly hilarious.
Speaker 0: It's hilarious, but anyway the you know this is somewhat realistic.
Speaker 0: what they want?
Speaker 0: that what they want?
Speaker 1: I need a fan petition for My Little Pony.
Speaker 0: Yeah what they want IDW to do there was Is to make a Transformers comic that picks up where the Marvel Transformers comic left off.
Speaker 0: there were 80 issues of that comic right And that's pretty much like the core of Transformers.
Speaker 0: is that 80 issue Marvel comic?
Speaker 0: They want to make a new trend.
Speaker 0: they want IDW to make a new Transformers comic that were issued.
Speaker 0: number one is basically issue number 81.
Speaker 1: So I don't think this will happen.
Speaker 0: why not?
Speaker 0: they made a GI Joe one.
Speaker 0: Why wouldn't they make a part of this?
Speaker 1: because GI Joe the reboot you know the movie and every like GI Joe does not have the cachet in the industry right now that transformers does with all its movies and whatever The Transformers franchise I think if anything is gonna be closer and more based on the current live-action movies than I know
Speaker 0: There's only one.
Speaker 0: there's only one comic series.
Speaker 0: That's based on the movies all the.
Speaker 0: there's a whole bunch of them And only one of them has any to do with the movies.
Speaker 1: yeah, I know, but I'm saying going forward.
Speaker 1: I mean what were the sales and all those?
Speaker 1: I think they're more interested in driving the movie.
Speaker 0: friend I think you're thinking too hard about it because basically this is comics.
Speaker 0: No one gives a shit about comics.
Speaker 0: They do whatever they want.
Speaker 0: they've been making all sorts of weird guys.
Speaker 1: But at the same time when push comes to shove when someone says make a comic on something in anywhere in the toy industry The person saying that is usually thinking I have a movie and or some other property that I need to push.
Speaker 1: The comic is a trivial and cheap way to push that on.
Speaker 1: to nurse.
Speaker 0: Oh, but see that you see you're thinking about something like Hasbro right where Hasbro controls for example my little pony, right?
Speaker 1: Hasbro stop cocking up don't?
Speaker 1: don't?
Speaker 0: Anyway, and Hasbro also makes the My Little Pony toys right.
Speaker 0: Hasbro controls Transformers television movies and toys true, but the comics right.
Speaker 0: Transformers licensed to IDW.
Speaker 0: so basically they say IDW make the Transformers comics here you go You pay us money, and you can make Transformers comics with certain you know Restrictions or whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't know what they are because it's not like a public you know contract.
Speaker 0: So IDW you know.
Speaker 0: they make things like you know all hell Megatron and all sorts of whatever.
Speaker 1: all right.
Speaker 1: Here's my other my other rationale.
Speaker 0: They have been for a long time.
Speaker 0: They won't make it cuz and I don't think Hasbro even gives a shit cuz.
Speaker 0: it's comics.
Speaker 0: who cares?
Speaker 1: twelve hundred sales times Five bucks even isn't enough money No, but that's the thing they make.
Speaker 0: all sorts of other failing ones.
Speaker 0: Why not make this one?
Speaker 1: well How many failing ones can they make?
Speaker 1: I mean how do they make money?
Speaker 0: I think there's actually like five or six different Transformers series concurrently.
Speaker 0: I mean there's a lot of.
Speaker 1: here's the question do they make money and if so on what?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: That's what I'd like to know.
Speaker 0: Comics I don't know.
Speaker 1: I can't even tell anymore.
Speaker 1: It's even work like at least with the anime industry.
Speaker 1: There's the excuse of.
Speaker 1: there is no industry in the US anymore like what happened to this franchise?
Speaker 1: Oh, no one owns it, but with comics.
Speaker 1: We know who owns it, and we still don't know any information.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: so this isn't really news, but for anyone who's a fan of anime at all you should at least Be aware of the fact that Osamu Dezaki died.
Speaker 1: He is one of the important great legends of anime.
Speaker 1: He sadly died due to lung cancer probably because he was a chain smoker like a lot of Japanese people.
Speaker 0: It's actually one thing that makes me like not want to go to Japan.
Speaker 0: is that I know this basically smoking everywhere.
Speaker 1: Everyone I've ever talked to who's been to Japan said yeah You're gonna hate the fact that every jackass everywhere is smoking all the time on the site in the restaurants and this everywhere.
Speaker 1: I mean when I go down south and a restaurant is like smoking or not I'm like what and I'll.
Speaker 0: but at least there's a non right in Japan.
Speaker 0: is there even a non?
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: like is is there a such thing as a non smoking hotel room in Japan?
Speaker 1: now I could say a lot about Osamu Dezaki, but are people smoking in like the the?
Speaker 0: you know the Hot pond Springs, but I don't think they are there.
Speaker 1: the reason I'm not going to say a lot about Osamu Dezaki is that Mike tool said pretty much everything that needs to be said.
Speaker 1: so this is kind of a dual news because one if you don't know who this man is you Probably should.
Speaker 1: if you if you look at the list of anime he's done, and you don't recognize any of them You should watch several of them Particularly the Hajime no Ippo or Rosa Versailles.
Speaker 1: I haven't even watched Hajime no Ippo, and I know I should.
Speaker 1: yeah But you should not watch all of no just like how you don't read ambassador magma.
Speaker 1: You know of it.
Speaker 0: Why not read it?
Speaker 0: why not?
Speaker 1: Well you know what you read have you buddy, what is?
Speaker 0: you even know what ambassador magma is about and you know.
Speaker 1: Here's what I know about ambassador magma.
Speaker 1: I've been told by everyone that it is some of the worst that Osamu Dezaki has ever done.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, so that's you just so.
Speaker 0: basically you got in here say yeah, you have no idea.
Speaker 1: tell you what let's read.
Speaker 1: That'll be my next book club book.
Speaker 0: Where are you gonna get it in English?
Speaker 1: I'll get it all right I'll get it somehow.
Speaker 1: We'll read it in Japanese.
Speaker 1: It'll take a hundred years yeah, but seriously You know how we talk about the stereotypes of anime.
Speaker 1: We've done whole panels on this stuff.
Speaker 1: like Astro Boy Tezuka pioneered these certain kinds of ways of framing things and reusing footage to make anime happen and then later even when they were not Necessary anymore because the anime had bigger budgets they still did those things because they became iconic of anime.
Speaker 1: Dezaki is about as responsible for many of the tropes of anime today as Tezuka the two Osamu's I mean.
Speaker 1: I think the biggest hallmark of Dezaki is the sudden freeze-frame to a watercolor or kind of like Washed-out vision of what just happened like a highly detailed painting of the scene you just saw.
Speaker 1: Or the zoom up zoom up then zoom up a little bit slower on the same frame of animation.
Speaker 1: It's good stuff.
Speaker 1: and also You know you should really read Mike Tool's articles on the Mike Tool show on anime news network.
Speaker 1: They're actually really informative and really really well written, and if you can't get to a con and see Mike Tool do his Awesome panels.
Speaker 1: the only one I got to see at Anime Boston was a true story of Oda Nobunaga as told through anime.
Speaker 0: That was a good panel.
Speaker 1: That was a great panel.
Speaker 0: I liked all those different.
Speaker 0: Oda Nobunaga was a demon, but he was also a space robot and also has a mustache Yeah, but also does not have a man.
Speaker 1: sometimes always does is different Yeah, but he was a demon and we know that's true isn't he?
Speaker 0: woman also.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: He was a woman Not to be confused with Oda Nobunaga, but I digress mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: He's very ambitious.
Speaker 1: So things of the day I try to avoid doing you know the same old college humors every day because the secret would be if You want to see?
Speaker 1: Most of the worthwhile videos on the internet that aren't my little pony related.
Speaker 1: Pretty much college humor is gonna have them all within a few days So I really don't need to use those as things of the day.
Speaker 1: I assume you'll see them all.
Speaker 1: so instead I have for you from this pretty cool forum that is all about special effects like makeup masks creatures and all that kind of thing a silicone model of Bert a realistic Bert says me street Bert.
Speaker 0: It's horrifying.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just it's.
Speaker 0: that's pretty accurate.
Speaker 1: It's not even in the valley like it like you could conceive of a human who looked like this.
Speaker 1: It's just Really really detailed.
Speaker 1: and yeah, this is the stuff of nightmares.
Speaker 1: Yep, that's all I got.
Speaker 1: It's pretty.
Speaker 1: I thought it was cool.
Speaker 0: I got something I saw at anime hell.
Speaker 0: This is this is direct direct from hell, right?
Speaker 0: This is a clip from the 1970s television show Ding-dong roar where they sing a drug a song about not doing drugs.
Speaker 1: kids drugs are bad kids.
Speaker 1: That's actually in the orphanage.
Speaker 1: Yep Not gonna reveal what the real deal is.
Speaker 0: you're gonna know as soon as you click on.
Speaker 0: the link is in the title of the YouTube video.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you don't notice you'll know when that shit comes in before you throw it.
Speaker 0: Oh Prime in Seattle doing probably three panel special notice There was a tweet today from official pack saying that at the current rate Pax prime will sell out of badges in 15 days.
Speaker 1: So buy your goddamn badges.
Speaker 0: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: if you didn't listen to us before we said that you needed to buy the badge and get the hotel room Immediately I point out it's selling out faster Maybe because we're telling everyone to buy their badges.
Speaker 0: if people are listening to us and taking our advice good If you're not you're gonna be screwed.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Remember packs badges always sell out.
Speaker 1: point the first They are legally transferable.
Speaker 1: point the second In fact, that is condoned.
Speaker 0: point the third as long as you don't charge more than what you paid for.
Speaker 1: Yeah and even then if you do you can get away with that unless you're gonna be a Gigantic scalper jackass about it.
Speaker 1: If you do Robert cool probably finds you and trick you like he did that one year.
Speaker 1: Yes, so anyway the moral of this is even if you can't go to packs You should buy a badge anyway on the off chance that you do.
Speaker 1: and if you can't go and you're it's a week away I guarantee you'll be able to sell that badge for exactly what you paid for it and everything will work out.
Speaker 1: buying it.
Speaker 1: You're basically putting $60 or whatever aside to have the chance to go to packs.
Speaker 1: if it all works out Mm-hmm, and even if you don't get a good hotel, you can get a shitty hotel.
Speaker 1: There's plenty of shitty hotels still.
Speaker 0: Yep, they're just far away.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we'll be there.
Speaker 1: also packs dev was announced.
Speaker 1: So if you are a game developer or in any way involved in the game industry unless your press You should check out packs dev because it's kind of like if you can afford to spend a couple more days in Seattle if you Actually work for a game company.
Speaker 1: There's a good chance your company will pay for you to go.
Speaker 1: This is basically the deal with packs dev for people who haven't been paying attention.
Speaker 0: They want.
Speaker 0: they want to make a GDC that doesn't have press so it's basically by developers.
Speaker 1: for developers Yeah, the rules are basically if you register you do not talk about what happens at packs dev.
Speaker 1: You do not tweet.
Speaker 1: I mean happens at packs dev unless the speakers or the people you're talking to give you express permission.
Speaker 1: And if you don't it is not public what they will do to you if you violate this rule.
Speaker 1: But my guess is they will ban you from packs dev for life.
Speaker 0: Yeah which?
Speaker 1: imagine this?
Speaker 1: a world with no press game designers and people in the game industry in Basically a safe place for two days to go to panels that are inside baseball.
Speaker 1: Imagine someone who works for say Blizzard doing inside baseball panel on World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: Yep I don't know if that is what'll happen.
Speaker 0: Who knows can't say.
Speaker 0: I think that's what they hope will happen, right?
Speaker 0: Is it?
Speaker 0: developers will say all kinds of things that they wouldn't normally say because they don't want those things ending up in blogs and You know and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: now we may be there.
Speaker 1: We don't.
Speaker 1: we can't say anything about that yet, but there is a clause.
Speaker 1: There are people who are press but also have other hats.
Speaker 0: in the gaming industry for example Let's say you write game reviews, but you also make games like, you know penny arcade.
Speaker 0: They theoretically make games the least they did and they're also sort of press, right?
Speaker 1: They comment on the industry with their comics or for example say you are press like geek nights But at the same time you're doing a lecture on say game theory They have.
Speaker 0: and what if we make a game?
Speaker 1: Well, then we're doubly triple threat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the rule is if you have a press hat better take that fucker off before you come into PAX dev.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, you know, you're in trouble.
Speaker 1: same as we said before of course You know.
Speaker 0: if they they accept us and allow us to speak at PAX dev or some such, you know, which we don't know We would definitely allow people to spread the news about whatever we have to say.
Speaker 0: However,
Speaker 1: what I think we should do if we have time to take questions Like if we do a hardcore say a game theory panel and then we take questions I would actually want the questions to not be public because I would like people to be able to ask The inside baseball questions like we're making X game and here is our balance problem.
Speaker 0: That is fine with me because if it is not public that means that I can be a total jerk when I answer Yeah, I'll just get no one.
Speaker 0: I'll be like You don't know how to make games.
Speaker 0: That was a dumb question.
Speaker 0: You're stupid for even having asked it.
Speaker 0: We are all dumber.
Speaker 0: for me being in the room I award you no points.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got have mercy on your soul That's right.
Speaker 1: You realize I memorized that Adam Sandler speech for the day when we ever take questions again.
Speaker 1: All right Anyway, the book club book is Asimov's foundation, which you should have read.
Speaker 1: I have not read it because I'm a dumbass.
Speaker 1: I read part of it a lot halfway through it because I just finished the white luck warrior.
Speaker 1: I'll read it pretty soon And we're gonna be baby at Otacon.
Speaker 1: Like I said, we submitted our panels.
Speaker 1: if they accept them.
Speaker 1: We'll go and Let's see.
Speaker 1: There's not much else on our plate, you know board game nights all the usual stuff.
Speaker 1: We're going.
Speaker 0: bar camp NYC is open for registration.
Speaker 0: It's at bar camp.
Speaker 0: Just go to twitter.com.
Speaker 0: slash bar camp NYC or bar camp NYC org.
Speaker 1: Scott's helping out with that and you should check it out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you don't know what bar camps are you fail?
Speaker 1: Yep, also kinetic on which is an anime gaming slash steampunk slash furry slash art slash voice Fucking everything.
Speaker 1: convention everything geeky in Hartford, Connecticut.
Speaker 1: now if we count the way packs counts, it's like a 20,000 person convention.
Speaker 1: You know, it's about 7,000 people by unique bodies and it's in Hartford, Connecticut.
Speaker 1: we are the co-directors of panels and workshops for this convention for the last couple of years and It's actually a pretty goddamn rocking convention.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 0: It's got better.
Speaker 0: tape has a better tabletop gaming situation than anything even been any gaming con I have ever been to.
Speaker 0: with the possible exception of packs I think it's actually better than packs because the library is more expansive There's more tables available per person and they are better tables.
Speaker 0: That's the only reasons.
Speaker 0: the only thing packs cuz I mean it's not like how much can you make a tabletop better?
Speaker 0: you have games You have tables.
Speaker 0: Well, well packs has the same thing.
Speaker 0: two points has less games more tables.
Speaker 1: But what packs prime?
Speaker 1: in 2008 when they had the unfinished?
Speaker 1: Annex did not have as much space but because the space was organized into many many many small rooms It was a fucking awesome space, especially for role-playing games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was hand pecks east this past year in the BC EC while it was just one fucking gigantic room.
Speaker 1: That was a fucking gigantic room, right?
Speaker 0: But I'm saying is that number of table seats per person?
Speaker 0: the ratio at Connecticut is better than in either pack?
Speaker 1: Not if you count secret tabletop.
Speaker 0: I Can't count that.
Speaker 1: you can count that it's not.
Speaker 1: that was basically geek nights private tabletop anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so Connecticut the deadline is May 10th to register.
Speaker 1: if you want to run a panel or a workshop If you are a geek nights listener and you want to run a panel or workshop go to the link I'm going to put in this, you know moves post whatever.
Speaker 1: I am the one who approves your panels.
Speaker 1: Yeah Also, if you know of anyone who you think should do a panel let them know.
Speaker 1: give them a link to the forum, you know, whatever because We want to have some awesome panels and we were told last year the first year We were in charge that we in fact had the best list of panels Connecticut has ever had.
Speaker 1: Yep So yeah panels and your panel sucks submitted anyway And you'll get harshly rejected or you'll get accepted and then you'll get blacklisted Yep, and we do know pretty much everyone who accepts panels and every con in the East Coast.
Speaker 1: You'll get blackballed everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yep Anyway, anyway All right, so we don't we don't talk about comics quite that often.
Speaker 0: mostly cuz rim doesn't read him that off.
Speaker 1: I just read a whole bunch of comics that I have to give you to read and then we'll do shows on him so I Can finally mail him back to Timo.
Speaker 0: Why don't we just give him back to him at this point?
Speaker 1: Cuz you should read him.
Speaker 1: They're really good.
Speaker 0: No, I mean give him back as in in person.
Speaker 1: Yeah because the same reason I didn't give Aaron Clark his suit back in Person because if he flies out somewhere and I give him a big package to then fly back with versus just shipping it to him.
Speaker 0: Anyway anyway, so this is comic.
Speaker 0: I read it quite a while ago.
Speaker 0: It comes out very slowly issue by issue.
Speaker 0: But when they get enough issues, they release these really big hardcovers that are really fancy that even have the little ribbon in them.
Speaker 0: it's so awesome, right and I bought the first hardcover and it was so awesome and You know it was but no one else ever read it but me.
Speaker 0: So I was like I got no one to talk about this thing with and it's something that Almost nobody knows about but almost everybody will think is the best thing ever.
Speaker 1: It's pretty great.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna say straight up Yeah to head off the rest of the review.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so this is it's a comic is called castle waiting, right?
Speaker 0: It's got the word castle in it.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: It's by a girl named Linda Medley and Basically the deal with castle waiting is this it's like this whole fairy tale world right and Basically, you know you think oh, there's a whole bunch of fairy tale comics out there like fables and shit.
Speaker 0: Why do we?
Speaker 0: why do we need another one?
Speaker 0: Well, this this isn't like fables where it takes existing fairy tales and sort of retells them, right?
Speaker 0: It's not like Oh Rapunzel.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: It's its own.
Speaker 0: It's like a brand new fairy tale that never existed before.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's put up by fan of graphics.
Speaker 1: It's just you know, black and white comic book.
Speaker 1: The tomes are pretty great.
Speaker 1: They have the little like fancy ribbon.
Speaker 0: I said there was a ribbon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the ribbon bookmark built in is pretty fancy But if I had to say what it was briefly It's a slice of life set in a fantasy world that consists of a series of Semi-related Canterbury Tales almost styled fables just about all the people at this castle.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's really slice of life, right?
Speaker 0: I think there is.
Speaker 0: there is a core plot, right?
Speaker 0: So you have this this girl who is sort of a Sleeping Beauty ish Situation kind of sort of.
Speaker 1: we're gonna avoid spoiling a lot because it's just it's a pretty good comic and you should just read it.
Speaker 0: but basically the girl this girl's in this weird Sleeping Beauty kind of situation and Whatever it comes down to is she she's some sir.
Speaker 0: I think she's like a princess or who knows what she is or her dad was a merchant something like that.
Speaker 0: She is much older and she has a son.
Speaker 0: it was a little baby and the baby is obviously some kind of monster or something like a demon or who knows what.
Speaker 1: and She runs away and she ends up at this castle waiting Which is sort of not really a purgatory but like a sanctuary for all the dispossessed of the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like this castle that used to be a big fancy castle that had fairy tale shit going down.
Speaker 0: But you know everyone at that castle sort of event.
Speaker 0: Most of the people at that castle sort of evacuated.
Speaker 0: It's like she ran away from her home in the normal sort of medieval world And ended up in sort of like this hidden fantasy castle that there's only a few people living there now All right.
Speaker 1: See now I say there's a bit of slice of life because it's like half of this is a contiguous narrative.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I actually have to split up into thirds because a third of it is a continuous narrative of Like this main plot about the woman who's just joined with the baby.
Speaker 1: Yeah, another third of it is the tales of all the people who live there now and what their deal is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz well, I think what it does, right?
Speaker 0: She gets to this castle and you have to meet all the characters that already lived there which like sort of become her new Family, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz now she's living there with her baby So you meet all the people but then after that you really meet all the people, right?
Speaker 0: So there's the nun who lives there and then she's my second favorite and then they When they get then they basically they take that nun and they introduce you to her.
Speaker 0: So, you know her right.
Speaker 0: and then they come and they circle around back and they go off on this nuns whole history from like when she was a baby to her present day like that could cover the whole thing and it takes like half or more than half of a volume of Comic.
Speaker 1: that story is so engaging that you kind of forget the outside story and suddenly you're back in the modern time in the book And you're like, oh, whoa, whoa, wait
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like they go and they tell this whole character's story like it's a brand new comic and then they bring you back into the Main story of the girl who just showed up with her freaky baby, you know.
Speaker 0: And then I think they I think who knows right?
Speaker 0: Well, there's only two volumes so far and it comes out so slowly.
Speaker 0: But are they gonna do that for another character?
Speaker 0: They get to go off on the horse.
Speaker 0: guy and guys.
Speaker 0: my third favorite Let me guess your first favorite quiet guy the doctor.
Speaker 0: Oh you like the dog.
Speaker 0: I like the doctor.
Speaker 1: Oh, I like the quiet guy, but I like the doctor way more because he's Actually kind of cute in the way.
Speaker 1: He actually acts around people.
Speaker 0: He I don't know.
Speaker 1: He's very I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's this weird mix of shy.
Speaker 0: I actually kind of like the bird butler I mean everybody.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's nearly no unlikable characters going on here.
Speaker 1: I really like the horse too.
Speaker 1: I got just because he's so rainbow - he You know he is yeah But the all.
Speaker 1: the final third is really this slice of life.
Speaker 1: you get a lot of just these like this view of What day to day life is like in this castle.
Speaker 1: when there's no plot on the outside nothing going on It's just oh the fairies are up to shit again, and the roof is leaking and we got to fix it.
Speaker 1: And oh here's how we get gold and just all these kind of mundane Day-to-day happy stories.
Speaker 1: you feel like you're almost living there with this family of.
Speaker 0: really I don't think you know.
Speaker 0: I think that slice-of-life stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean It's not a significant percentage of.
Speaker 0: I think it is.
Speaker 1: I think it's a solid third.
Speaker 1: No, I mean you forget how much of the story is just.
Speaker 1: it's not like the backstory of like the full history of a character.
Speaker 1: It's just them going about their day-to-day BS.
Speaker 0: I think it's mostly just a lot of that stuff is just there because they're introducing you.
Speaker 0: They're sort of teaching you.
Speaker 0: here's how life at the castle works right so that you're not like well How do they freaking live out in the middle of nowhere alone?
Speaker 0: Where do they get money from?
Speaker 0: oh?
Speaker 0: That's what they get.
Speaker 0: I didn't say that's not Answering all these questions.
Speaker 1: I didn't say that's not the purpose of it.
Speaker 0: I would not I would not categorize it as slaves of life in any.
Speaker 1: that aspect of it is definitely slice of life Slice of the lives of these people.
Speaker 0: there's yeah gee and any story you see the slice of the lives of the characters gasps.
Speaker 0: That doesn't make it slice of.
Speaker 1: there's definitely a difference between when you see what's going on that either Establishes characters or furthers plot in some specific way versus this kind of just voyeuristic.
Speaker 1: ah check this out.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, no because all of those things they introduce are You know simply Chekhov's guns and/or explanations.
Speaker 0: I don't venture plots that follow.
Speaker 1: the leaky roof was not a Chekhov's gun for fucking anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah It was what I forget, but it was definitely in there.
Speaker 0: cuz what?
Speaker 0: cuz?
Speaker 0: then they started investigating like all the secret parts of the other Castle.
Speaker 1: they didn't.
Speaker 1: they did that because she wanted to move.
Speaker 1: yeah, I just read it.
Speaker 1: you read it a while ago.
Speaker 0: Point is stuff is in there for a reason.
Speaker 1: I don't think the leaky roof is in there for any reason other than to show you a slice of the lives of these characters Goony interactions they have with those sprites.
Speaker 0: anyway the point is the sprites are kind of great.
Speaker 0: It's not slice of life It is a fairy tale.
Speaker 1: I said one third of it is slice of life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no it is.
Speaker 1: You'll see when you read it.
Speaker 0: one third of everything is lies of life.
Speaker 1: But now now because there was no slice of life and the prince of nothing until it came in or us says Watha started shitting No That's some slice of life.
Speaker 0: so it's only slice of life.
Speaker 0: if the slice of life if there is a portion If there are characters doing things that are mundane if there if there is any portion of the story where characters are doing mundane things Suddenly that slice of life, but if they show you
Speaker 1: I'm saying
Speaker 0: when they're doing things that are not mundane and every day that is
Speaker 1: of the comic has at least a third of it about has many of the Characteristics of what you'd see in a typical slice of life story word.
Speaker 1: you could take all those apart from the overall plot and Separately completely apart from the detailed histories of all the characters and they would still be an interesting story.
Speaker 1: There's just no plot other than yay these people living their lives.
Speaker 1: check it out.
Speaker 0: But there is a plot other than that up in those parts.
Speaker 0: Not really there is.
Speaker 0: there's.
Speaker 0: the whole thing is a giant plot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there is an overarching plot.
Speaker 1: I'm saying that a third of the comic is very slice-of-life esque.
Speaker 0: Anyway, let's let's move on right.
Speaker 1: so I don't know why this is so hard for you to understand because it's not Anyway, so name any character from the comic?
Speaker 0: You know, I can't remember characters names shit Anyway, who can remember characters names?
Speaker 0: If you haven't read something yesterday, I mean, but you must Remember?
Speaker 1: No, you know you should eat some kiri.
Speaker 1: That'll fix you.
Speaker 0: Sure Anyway, so yeah the thing with castle waiting right is you've got so the camera.
Speaker 0: we didn't really go down the list of all The characters, right?
Speaker 0: So there's the girl who shows up with Her baby, that's a monster, right?
Speaker 1: He's a Leshy.
Speaker 0: I think yeah, he's some sort of monster Leshy something like that.
Speaker 1: I learned about Leshy's from quest for glory for no shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a. it's a fantasy thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're in there.
Speaker 1: There's this I saved one.
Speaker 0: There's this bird butler guy who's sort of like the mayor or like the head he takes care of all like, you know The business and the accounting and all that right.
Speaker 0: so he sort of makes sure that you know Everything is taken care of.
Speaker 0: he has a fangirl - yeah There's that the horse guy.
Speaker 0: he's actually a horse guy rainbow - yeah Oh, his name is like chest or something like that, right?
Speaker 1: Because there's basically the world is a fancy world where about a third a quarter of the people are animal people.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's the nun who is like from this weird, you know, they tell it you get the whole nun story Jesus.
Speaker 0: Yeah And she's like this.
Speaker 0: she has like this epic story of nunnage and it's like, you know, it's like the ultimate Feminist nuns of awesome.
Speaker 1: Don't forget her hanging out with a little demon guy.
Speaker 1: He was actually pretty chill.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Like she hangs out.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's right.
Speaker 0: There's like the evil demon who's like chasing the the baby who works for the witch in the woods.
Speaker 1: But you know the witch in the woods is really the only bitch we've met so far.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like.
Speaker 0: that's the only bad guy she gets hers.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like a witch.
Speaker 0: it is a witch in the woods and the imp that works for it and only the nun really knows the imp Is visiting and she talks to it, but no one else even knows.
Speaker 0: is there The store?
Speaker 1: the comic has a lot of those Semi like enemies who know each other and are actually kind of friends and they just kind of do the job of fighting with each Other.
Speaker 1: a lot of the characters have those kind of ripping on each other relationships.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there isn't really a whole lot of that You know, even though it's a fantasy thing.
Speaker 0: There's no Dragons and swords and actually like straight-up fighting or magical battles, at least not yet, right?
Speaker 0: I mean there probably aren't gonna be.
Speaker 0: it's mostly you know, there is a fantasy world.
Speaker 0: There is magic There is monsters and whatever but nobody's really having direct, you know, like fighting conflict.
Speaker 0: It's mostly sort of everyday social conflict and everyday problems.
Speaker 0: conflict like oh crap We need you know supplies.
Speaker 0: We went to town.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, all our money is gone You know, that's the kind of problems they run into not problems like, you know, oh crap the dragons trying to eat me.
Speaker 0: We must slay him you're not gonna you know There's none of that even though it's heavily implied that the world is full of that.
Speaker 0: There isn't any of that in this Castle waiting and I guess that's partially because castle waiting is sort of like the safe place, right?
Speaker 0: So anything like that sort of stays outside.
Speaker 1: I'm curious what would happen if the castle were actually besieged.
Speaker 0: I wonder if it could be besieged right?
Speaker 0: There's the hedge maze.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know but at the same time there's the path through the hedge maze.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's cuz.
Speaker 0: he clears it out all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which if the dragon was coming they just let it hedge in.
Speaker 1: How fast it hedges?
Speaker 1: we don't know these things, but it's a magical hedge maze.
Speaker 1: It might just close instantly Yeah, but if it closes instantly, then how is he constantly clearing it?
Speaker 0: I don't know either.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of.
Speaker 0: you know, sort of you know.
Speaker 0: A lot of the magic is sort of that quirky sort of you know, misbehaving nature stuff, right?
Speaker 1: It's like the dirty old water spirits pretty great dirty old just a naked old man.
Speaker 1: Who's totally lecherous.
Speaker 0: Yeah He lives in the well, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the stream?
Speaker 0: Oh, no, that's why the water was dropping from the ceiling.
Speaker 0: cuz that was the dirty old lecture getting into the thing.
Speaker 0: It wasn't actually rain or anything.
Speaker 1: He was just being a dick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there was actually a reason for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't say there was no reason for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then it served no plot purpose.
Speaker 0: It did.
Speaker 0: is it what to introduce you to the water?
Speaker 1: He was already introduced long time before to make a funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah But yeah castle waiting is like, you know, I don't it's.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: it's weird because it's like people know about it.
Speaker 0: It sells right and it's won awards and it's like so right but it's like you never hear anybody talk about it You know, it's like because I think it's cuz it just comes out so slowly.
Speaker 0: I mean it goes on hiatus.
Speaker 0: I mean this thing actually right according to Right the Linda Medley, right?
Speaker 0: She first thought of it in 1984 right and then They published seven issues.
Speaker 0: She self-published seven issues is according to Wikipedia in 1997 okay.
Speaker 0: And then in 1999 there was one hiatus issue, right?
Speaker 0: It's like oh my god.
Speaker 0: How many years is this?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: This is 1997 was how long ago?
Speaker 1: Long time 15 years, right?
Speaker 1: So they insult the xkcd.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so she published four issues in the year.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's like how many you know, she kept going and going it.
Speaker 0: few issues here few issues there and somehow in o6 They were able to.
Speaker 0: all the issues combined were enough to make the first hardcover and then in 2010 November last year They had the second hardcover.
Speaker 0: So and she's currently taking a break.
Speaker 0: So at this rate, let's see o6 and 2014 will get volume 3 Maybe 2015 something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah Which is kind of frustrating because you'll probably like this comic and read through it pretty quick and you'll hit the end of all the books that are out and then Waiting and it's like this is it's a continuing story.
Speaker 1: There is a plot right and rate at which it's being told there's gonna be like a hundred volumes But it's like gonna be preserved.
Speaker 0: Is it even gonna finish berserk?
Speaker 0: Yeah berserk.
Speaker 0: This is one of those things It's like, you know There is a continuing plot that'll probably never be resolved just because it gets published so slowly.
Speaker 1: Thing is it's worth reading.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I had great fun reading it and I look forward to eventually reading more of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the other thing is that you know The book does have a message right and it all.
Speaker 0: it's often like a feminist message, right?
Speaker 0: My favorite part was when You know the the story about the Miller.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and the Miller was like, oh, I need someone to work the mill, right?
Speaker 0: He's like, I don't have enough hands and the guys like what about those hands?
Speaker 0: and he points it like the Miller's wife or daughter Who isn't doing anything?
Speaker 0: And he's like, oh snap.
Speaker 1: He's got.
Speaker 1: how many coins did he throw in the shit?
Speaker 0: I forget.
Speaker 1: I don't remember that part.
Speaker 1: They owe the Miller like three gold coins.
Speaker 1: he tosses two into the shit and he's like well fish him out.
Speaker 1: Yeah Only two.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway, but but yeah this it's it's.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: It's a good kind of feminist message where it's like, you know, it's not it's not man-hating.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: you know, like, you know Scary women.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 1: what do you mean scary women?
Speaker 0: You know that kind of feminism that's like, you know women you You know the stuff is not really good fundamentals, but yeah, it's not the stereotypical Not real feminism of like, you know, he-man women-hating Amazon situation, right?
Speaker 0: It's it's like, you know actual feminism like.
Speaker 0: hey, you know men are cool You know, it doesn't portray men in any bad way, you know.
Speaker 0: But it portrays, you know women as an intelligent way.
Speaker 0: and the lesson is often You know feminist in nature and in most of the story moral in general of every story of Castle waiting seems to come down to.
Speaker 1: don't be a dick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much but it's usually women that are being dicked to you know in the stories, right?
Speaker 0: Because it's and that's I think that's part of why it's in sort of this medieval setting right because you have this sort of you know actual medieval Society, you know where they've got things like arranged marriages and You know All kinds of stuff like that, right?
Speaker 0: You know women can't work and all that sort of stuff that you would have medieval society.
Speaker 0: but in the fantasy medieval society by contrast, you've got like witches and princesses and You know like all that kind of stuff, right and it's the contrast between those things that is used to illustrate a lot of these morals.
Speaker 1: So, I mean in conclusion it's worth reading and you should read it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of people looking for you know indie comics in the in the you know If they're not coming out quickly enough for you to really fancy hardcover books easy to buy Can't go wrong.
Speaker 0: Totally awesome hidden treasure Right.
Speaker 0: What are you waiting for?
Speaker 0: I hope you're not waiting for a castle because you're Really?
Speaker 0: You're gonna be waiting for like a hundred years.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.