Speaker 1: It's Monday July 18th 2011.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: facial recognition technology and the federated cloud.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So now that I've given notice I can actually talk about this among people other than close friends.
Speaker 1: But I got a new job.
Speaker 0: You know when I was.
Speaker 0: I think I've said this before many times but it's like when I was a kid I used to look at like old people who had jobs and kept changing them all the Time to be like what's wrong with those people?
Speaker 0: Why can't they just keep their job?
Speaker 0: What's wrong with them?
Speaker 1: But now I never.
Speaker 1: I never thought that as a kid.
Speaker 0: I thought that now that I'm like, you know, whatever It's like I've changed jobs bunch.
Speaker 1: I mean as a kid I was the opposite.
Speaker 1: I thought man, how could you do the same thing for more than like a year?
Speaker 0: And now it's just like yeah Get bored of pretty much any job after a few years.
Speaker 1: RIT just ruined me that quarter system.
Speaker 1: I got so in tune to ten weeks something new plus the two-week break that It's kind of hard to get back into working.
Speaker 1: one thing for more than a year Let alone is just.
Speaker 0: you know You need a change of scenery and it's like it could be at the same job But usually the same job doesn't change or move quickly enough Depends.
Speaker 1: I've had rapidly changing jobs But in this case, I've actually worked where I'm working where I was working as of today when I gave notice that Almost four years That's the longest I've ever held a job in my entire life by far.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll be.
Speaker 0: I think I'm almost three years.
Speaker 0: I'm be approaching a Nexus.
Speaker 0: soon Sandworm will appear.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see what happens that the alliances are made or broken.
Speaker 1: my Anyway, my Nexus came and went and I am now the vice president of product management for a different company.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but how many people are in this company?
Speaker 0: Um enough I'll talk about it.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, but me it's a small company.
Speaker 0: So it's not like.
Speaker 0: it's not like your vice president of IBM It's like your vice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot of vice president.
Speaker 0: This is like, you know one room full of people your vice president.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but there's other vice presidents.
Speaker 1: Uh, I actually don't know who the other ones are if there are any and how many presidents are there one?
Speaker 0: So there's only one person the whole company above you.
Speaker 1: Uh, well, I report directly to the CEO.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah Yeah, but you know how many people are underneath the CEO like 20?
Speaker 1: Well, I'll talk about that more once it's all get situated.
Speaker 1: But basically this is this is pretty much the biggest job I've ever had and it's it's one of those things.
Speaker 0: every job That that's new is the biggest job you ever had.
Speaker 1: When I worked at the hospital that was far less of a big job than IBM.
Speaker 0: really you went you downgraded.
Speaker 1: No, just it wasn't wasn't it more money's it was more money.
Speaker 0: Well, then it's a bigger job.
Speaker 0: Nah, cuz money isn't really what drives me, but I didn't say it was a drive you just it's bigger.
Speaker 1: Well, I wouldn't say that's bigger.
Speaker 1: I could have made more money.
Speaker 1: I had a job offers at other places hospitals and things.
Speaker 1: I could Have made boatloads more money.
Speaker 1: This job just looks more fun.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean if you're making enough money, you're obviously gonna go to the fun place making more money than I need.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, I'm uh, I got a big career change and pretty much it's all on me.
Speaker 1: So if I cock anything up, there's nobody blame with me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not if you're a vice president It's not like there's the usual troubles of like bureaucracy and shit getting in the way for the company is small.
Speaker 1: Yeah if something even if it's big if you're if you're like your senior enough VP you can get stuff done.
Speaker 1: the VP of like the Technology group at IBM could pretty much get what she wanted and get what she needed.
Speaker 0: It's like in Robocop, right?
Speaker 0: There's all the V. You know, there's one VPS in charge of the Robo tech project and there's the other guys in charge of the other robot thing.
Speaker 1: Alright you watched a Robocop again recently.
Speaker 0: all the Robocop.
Speaker 1: Emily hasn't seen Robocop.
Speaker 1: We got to pick a night to watch it.
Speaker 0: I'm not watching again.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 1: We'll just watch it.
Speaker 1: You don't have to watch it.
Speaker 0: nerd note Robocop written by Frank Miller.
Speaker 0: Yes that Frank Miller as in Sparta and What's it called Verhoeven.
Speaker 0: no goddamn Batman no.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So, uh, there's kind of.
Speaker 1: it's not big news But it's news that Scott and I saw independently and had a lot to say about right away.
Speaker 1: This is yours.
Speaker 0: Oh my why are you introducing my news?
Speaker 0: You're confusing me.
Speaker 0: I thought you were stealing my news for a second.
Speaker 0: I was like you stealing my news.
Speaker 0: No, I let Scott have it.
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: So so if you don't know When Obama was elected president for the first time ever he appointed a federal CIO Which is a chief information officer, which is not the same thing as a CTO but sort of and basically his job Was not clearly defined so much but you know His name was Vivek Kundra, by the way, and he had to oversee.
Speaker 0: I think it was 80 billion Dollars in like federal spending on technology stuffs, right?
Speaker 0: So he is leaving his job in mid-mid August.
Speaker 0: So now that he's leaving much like rim he's got stuff to say about the job he's leaving as people do.
Speaker 0: yeah So pretty much the two things, you know, the two big things that he had to say.
Speaker 0: one was that you know He's all for like data openness, right?
Speaker 0: You know, we all want government data to be open but there's concerns obviously about security like real security.
Speaker 0: Not you know, not the issue of stuff is confidential for no reason.
Speaker 0: but you know issues like, you know The Nuclear Regulatory Commission.
Speaker 0: should we release this data?
Speaker 0: Hmm and they actually discussed it, you know for serious and it's like this is difficult.
Speaker 1: Well as opposed, you know just joking about it and then like right you're gone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: And then you know, there's also issues of.
Speaker 0: you know, the government knows combining databases especially if you combine the federal databases with say public information on Facebook and such that That's you know, not so good for privacy.
Speaker 0: and well, I don't believe in privacy.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna say I don't believe in privacy, but I do not agree that there's any real ethical argument You can make against taking publicly available information and aggregating it.
Speaker 0: Right, but the question is should you even make don't make the data publicly available in the first place?
Speaker 0: And then the question is, you know, this information is not publicly available, but it is government available.
Speaker 0: So if the government takes the publicly available information and combines it with the secret government information That is not public right now.
Speaker 0: Suddenly the government has now added Information that you know, perhaps under other circumstances it would have needed to warrant Ah, but at the same time that information was also available to average citizens.
Speaker 0: No wasn't Cuz?
Speaker 0: no because half of the information was you know government information that is in government databases Publicly available, but at the same time that information if they already have it they already have it, right?
Speaker 1: But they even if they already have it They're often evidential evidential rules about whether or not is admissible to pay in order.
Speaker 0: But anyway his you know That was one of his concerns was the opening of data and those.
Speaker 0: we could do a show on that maybe I know but anyway His other main concern which is I think more interesting right is the is pretty much the the airplane the air The airport food situation.
Speaker 1: I was gonna use the airport food situation as the example.
Speaker 0: that is story everyone tells.
Speaker 0: I forget.
Speaker 0: I wish I would have remembered where I first heard that story because I keep reusing that metaphor.
Speaker 0: But basically people don't know.
Speaker 0: you ever go to an airport and there's restaurants in the airport, right?
Speaker 0: But how come the restaurants in the airport aren't like McDonald's or TGI Fridays?
Speaker 1: They're always like weird things You've never heard of.
Speaker 1: they're like Sbarro.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: I've never seen this borrows.
Speaker 0: The Charlotte Airport is actually also a mall much like in Boston.
Speaker 0: the Heinz Convention Center is also a mall But the mall is actually sort of separated from the airport.
Speaker 0: It's not in the airport, right?
Speaker 0: But they're like the same building kinda.
Speaker 0: so it's like you can leave go through security go into the mall come back go through security.
Speaker 0: And you know, this is a mall food court out there, but most airports are on their own.
Speaker 0: So if you go to O'Hare in Chicago, right what restaurants are in there?
Speaker 0: It's not normal restaurants.
Speaker 0: You've heard of it's weird ones.
Speaker 0: So, how do those weird restaurants end up in there?
Speaker 0: Why aren't there normal restaurants people have heard of in there?
Speaker 0: Why isn't there a Capitol Grill in the airport, right?
Speaker 0: It's instead.
Speaker 0: it's like New York strip something that you never heard of.
Speaker 0: It's made up.
Speaker 0: It's only in that Airport.
Speaker 0: the reason is the companies that know how to manage the bureaucracy of the TSA.
Speaker 0: and You know the other, you know federal agencies involved in airports to get their restaurant in there are the ones that get in there.
Speaker 0: It's not based on food quality or anything like that.
Speaker 1: It's just if you're.
Speaker 1: the primary skill is I'm good at navigating the bureaucracy.
Speaker 0: So whatever restaurants whatever food service company knows how to do that paperwork is the food is the food service company That's gonna get those restaurants and make that money.
Speaker 0: So he's other major complaint besides the data openness was that in technology in the federal government?
Speaker 0: It's much the same way right is that?
Speaker 0: you know, they put out to you know Technology for the federal government and there's only a few people who know how to put in bids and deal with that bullshit.
Speaker 0: So these and they're not very good.
Speaker 0: They're really shitty tech companies, but they basically have permanent, you know employed.
Speaker 0: They're basically permanently employed by the federal government because they're the only people who know how to do this.
Speaker 1: I mean think of it how easy it would be for this to happen one a lot of people in the government don't know.
Speaker 1: like Really?
Speaker 1: What's up technology wise?
Speaker 1: To a limited number of bids come in because all the count like IBM doesn't know how to navigate this.
Speaker 1: maybe just to make up An example.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or at least the IBM is probably the ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but like other big tech companies are not.
Speaker 1: I mean Microsoft.
Speaker 1: probably by default people have to use Windows for stuff.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I mean if you need a guy to like set up routers or like pull cables or something You how many companies that do that are gonna apply to these bids to get those jobs?
Speaker 0: yeah, the other problem that he you know, the related problem is that the You know, there isn't like a technology committee in Congress or anything like that.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: technology is done very Vertically inside of each little division.
Speaker 0: So the government, you know has what is.
Speaker 0: there's a number here.
Speaker 0: It's like tons and tons of separate data centers and racks because basically every little government division has its own Technology budget and spending that it decides how to spend its technology and what to buy.
Speaker 0: So everyone has their own different systems, you know.
Speaker 0: It's like where the.
Speaker 0: you know, the NOAA has a website and then you know the the F the FTC has a website and FBI has a website and they're all separate.
Speaker 0: part of the.
Speaker 0: you know budgets for the individual.
Speaker 1: You know federal and no individual department whatever of their own volition give up their power over that tiny domain Even though economy of scale would save the government millions, right?
Speaker 0: So he says look the whole government could have three data centers.
Speaker 0: Right, probably because you want to have East Coast West Coast and middle and also safety of redundancy.
Speaker 1: real data centers.
Speaker 1: Have the concept of cages.
Speaker 1: so you have one data center economy of scale.
Speaker 1: and then one department say it has a cage I'm steel physical cage around.
Speaker 1: it's like 10 rats.
Speaker 0: But what he's saying is that there should be standardization, right?
Speaker 0: So there should.
Speaker 0: someone needs to spend the technology money Horizontally across departments and not within each department.
Speaker 0: So there should be one group.
Speaker 0: That's the technology group.
Speaker 0: That's like we're gonna make everyone's website and we're all gonna make all the websites the same way for every federal thing.
Speaker 0: There isn't gonna be separate websites and separate service.
Speaker 0: everyone are making the federal website system period for everybody, right?
Speaker 0: And you're all gonna go into.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be standard thing.
Speaker 1: that way when low sec hacks it they'll get everything.
Speaker 0: But be that way technology.
Speaker 0: people will be in charge of it and low sec won't get in.
Speaker 1: the thing is will they really be if That's the?
Speaker 0: if they get the other component of real technology companies with quality technology You know how to make bids as opposed to those people who got hacked by low sec making the bids right then You know the technology would be good.
Speaker 1: The process is just bad for getting government work and I don't know what to do.
Speaker 0: And it's also.
Speaker 0: it's also even if you could get a bid in it's potentially corrupt Right, like I might be able to put in a low bid and have better technology than the other bidders.
Speaker 0: But if the guy who's deciding doesn't know who I am The other guy.
Speaker 1: there are places in government where there's no corruption No, where there are laws saying that if you owe take bids, you must take the lowest bid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but how does that lead to pros and cons?
Speaker 0: You can't because some guy just puts in a dollar and he shows up with a power book.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: The problem with laws like that is that the lowest bidder is often not exactly who you want to be handling your important data.
Speaker 0: Right, but the point is I feel like if I could just find someone or do research and you figure out how to submit this paperwork I could probably do better technology and a lot of these other pretty much everyone else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you got to get a bunch of people to work for you and actually do it.
Speaker 1: art I mean you want to move down to DC and like pull cables.
Speaker 0: Yes the other problems You got to go to DC and do it.
Speaker 0: You can't do it in New York But maybe I could do it for New York State or the city, right?
Speaker 0: Like I could send in bids to new if it or how to get New York City tech contracts or New York State tech All right.
Speaker 0: So here's the thing.
Speaker 1: This is much like people who become businessmen I have a certain acumen and they're good at or want to do.
Speaker 1: or whatever reason do you want to turn your life into?
Speaker 1: Filing paperwork that you hate to people you don't care about.
Speaker 0: No, I get someone else to do the paperworks.
Speaker 0: Just I just want to get paid with tax money.
Speaker 1: Everybody who is good at technology has the same idea you do.
Speaker 1: who are you going to find?
Speaker 1: who will do that paperwork?
Speaker 0: There has to be someone who knows how to do it.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll just go to the companies that are doing it now Find the guy who's doing it now and just say hey Come work in this cool tech company in New York instead of for this permanently employed black crappy boring.
Speaker 0: So you're gonna do that in DC.
Speaker 1: You're gonna do that.
Speaker 0: I gotta find who the person is gonna start this company.
Speaker 1: Is this something you're planning to do?
Speaker 0: If I know just if I ever meet one of these people, I'll know I Don't know what to do about it.
Speaker 1: I feel like as much as I could be cynical and complain and say yeah Well, even if they standardized it, it'll still be a corrupt morass.
Speaker 0: I think there is an easy way.
Speaker 1: It would be better than the current system.
Speaker 0: Well, I think there's the one thing that needs to change.
Speaker 0: right is that you know The government the basically the wing government wants to spend money.
Speaker 0: It puts out a call.
Speaker 0: It's like who wants to do this and people say I'll do it.
Speaker 0: I'll do it.
Speaker 0: I'll do it and they pick someone right?
Speaker 0: Why doesn't the government instead go shopping right?
Speaker 0: It should go out and say Hey Google, can you do this?
Speaker 0: Hey Microsoft can you do this?
Speaker 0: So as some government contracts do go that way do they cuz I?
Speaker 0: yeah But how does that?
Speaker 0: how does the thing is I see while that could work better if the person doing the shopping is doing It well, like they're going at Amazon and picking the thing with the five stars like I do or going to Newegg
Speaker 1: Yeah, cause I was on a new egg or where the government's gonna get its stuff
Speaker 0: I'm just saying or is that person who's going shopping just going?
Speaker 0: hey best friend.
Speaker 0: You want to do this?
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 0: Corruption whatever Happens it happens all the time, but at least sometimes people do actually get fucked for that.
Speaker 0: the governor connected went to jail.
Speaker 0: Yeah Of course, he went to easy jail for like a year and he's out now and now he's making money again But it's still.
Speaker 0: I think it should be permanent jail.
Speaker 0: I think you know fucking corruption in the government should be much more serious.
Speaker 1: Well, I think maybe treason to back up a little bit.
Speaker 0: I tried to fuck the US government jail forever.
Speaker 1: We want to talk about a root problem.
Speaker 1: I mean look we got the airport.
Speaker 1: It's just that there's Bureaucracy.
Speaker 1: navigation.
Speaker 0: you fucked with the government.
Speaker 0: you tried to ruin you.
Speaker 0: very important.
Speaker 1: So that determines a lot of the future for a lot of things.
Speaker 1: I mean forget look at law.
Speaker 1: look at the bureaucracy You have to go through to like.
Speaker 1: if you're involved in a court case like all this kind of stuff You get it a lawyer to navigate it for you.
Speaker 1: There are whole like seas of information that normal people basically Can't navigate on their own.
Speaker 0: Do we exile people anymore at all?
Speaker 1: No, we don't exile people.
Speaker 0: Is that cruel and unusual or do you just don't?
Speaker 1: Where are we gonna exile him to?
Speaker 1: I don't Belgium.
Speaker 0: That's their fucking problem.
Speaker 0: It's exile.
Speaker 1: Usually you're exiled to a place and Elba would get pretty crowded pretty quickly.
Speaker 0: Where's Elba?
Speaker 1: You ever heard of a guy named Napoleon Bonaparte?
Speaker 1: Yeah, what happened to him after he lost after the Napoleonic Wars and his exile to a tiny island?
Speaker 0: was it named Elba?
Speaker 1: Maybe okay?
Speaker 0: Is that?
Speaker 0: it's like south of Spain, right?
Speaker 0: Mediterranean Google, I thought it was called something else.
Speaker 1: Well, you realize he was exiled to two different islands.
Speaker 1: because when he was exiled to his first island, right?
Speaker 1: He eventually escaped.
Speaker 1: I know that went back to France fuck shit up again And when they beat him again, they sent him to a further away shittier island.
Speaker 0: I did not know that.
Speaker 0: I thought he died on that.
Speaker 0: So what was the name of the first island?
Speaker 1: You can look this up.
Speaker 0: I think you don't know.
Speaker 0: So if I hear it, I would know it because I So Google.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: usually when they do stuff I'm like hells Yeah, but it's easy to forget the things Google does.
Speaker 1: that didn't work out so well.
Speaker 1: I mean wave did not quite work out the way we all wanted.
Speaker 0: Apache Foundation has it.
Speaker 0: You can still get it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not who's doing anything with it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna actually try to see if I can do something with it and Just wait.
Speaker 1: all the stuff that it did that mattered.
Speaker 1: It'll be in.
Speaker 0: G+ Exiled him to the island of Elba Saint Helena.
Speaker 1: There is exiled the second, you know how he died on the second island.
Speaker 0: just disease, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, we don't know the.
Speaker 1: there was arsenic in the paint and all sorts of crazy stuff about that.
Speaker 0: He arrived could only recommend pallidus.
Speaker 0: He died two days later after after confession, but he had to confess to Christian stuff.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I kind of kid.
Speaker 0: I thought he confessed like I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: I started I Dr.
Speaker 1: Lucky.
Speaker 1: I've got that game laying around somewhere.
Speaker 0: I have that game.
Speaker 1: I think I have one too cuz they're what like a dollar.
Speaker 1: so Google Has something called badges?
Speaker 1: badges for Google News.
Speaker 0: They news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so here's the deal.
Speaker 0: new Google News.
Speaker 0: What you read I can understand Google+ badges like achievements for like posting Achievements for news.
Speaker 1: you can work your way up from Browns to silver gold platinum and finally Ultimate.
Speaker 0: how does this fucking work?
Speaker 1: So you read articles on Google News about topic X and you start acquiring badges in topic X eventually branding you as an Ultimate in topic X. So if I read a whole bunch of articles on Casey Anthony I'll get a badge saying that I read a whole bunch of articles on Casey Anthony.
Speaker 0: Why would they want to encourage you to read a bunch of articles about the same thing as opposed to?
Speaker 0: Encouraging you to read a bunch of articles about a bunch of different?
Speaker 1: Well, if you do that, you'll get a whole bunch of different badges and level them all up.
Speaker 0: Well, but that'll be low-level cuz you won't read a 20. like you'll read 20 articles about f1 you read one.
Speaker 1: Maybe you'll read a whole bunch, but here's the deal.
Speaker 1: They're private by default, but they're there and already on.
Speaker 1: if you have Google web history set up Let me check this.
Speaker 1: but now you it might not work for you because you with ABS don't have Google profiles.
Speaker 0: yet I don't see anything about badges on my Google News.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because you probably don't have it.
Speaker 1: Okay, we're Google Apps.
Speaker 1: we're second-class citizens, that's right, so You can choose to share the badges and make them public.
Speaker 0: All right, what's the point of this?
Speaker 0: I read more news than you.
Speaker 0: Oh, they don't have a stated point, but I Can you can see all my friends know what news I'm informed about?
Speaker 1: No, they do.
Speaker 1: let you hide specific badges because I'm sure a lot of people will get a lot of surprisingly pornographic badges.
Speaker 0: Hey Scott, I see you read a whole bunch of stories about My little pony the Yankees, I thought you're a Mets fan.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I was reading how they suck kind of like how in latitude you can delete times.
Speaker 1: You can't like add but you can delete stuff from your history if you want to be like, yeah I don't want anyone to know.
Speaker 1: how is it scandals?
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna delete that.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: My phone was off around that time.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I Don't know why Google did this.
Speaker 1: I don't know what they're trying.
Speaker 0: sounds like someone is just doing nothing.
Speaker 1: It might be someone's internal project that they were like, oh, that's cool Let's turn it on.
Speaker 1: but it seems like this is the kind of mechanism design that leads toward disaster.
Speaker 1: yeah, because it encourages people to game a system and to read just click on news article.
Speaker 0: pretty much really gonna go to Google News and Just gonna click on a ton of articles.
Speaker 0: How does it know if you actually read them?
Speaker 0: Just have you visited them?
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: I didn't really dig into this that much but actually in a way Right that actually it helps Google out in one.
Speaker 0: Yeah Just click on a whole bunch of news articles to get these badges.
Speaker 1: Google's getting a lot of traffic referrals to those newspapers exactly.
Speaker 0: Google News is pretty great.
Speaker 1: But at the same time that's evil mechanism design.
Speaker 0: Google didn't really read those articles or look at the ads on those newspaper.
Speaker 1: That's evil.
Speaker 0: This is evil sort of evil.
Speaker 1: It is not a good thing.
Speaker 0: They're basically doing click fraud against other semi click fraud against other news Papers when they fight so hard to prevent people doing click fraud against them.
Speaker 0: That is if not evil hypocritical.
Speaker 1: Well, the interesting thing is if you forget those, you know arguments against it.
Speaker 1: there's also the problem that this is yet one more and it's Google and the internet are kind of pushing people toward.
Speaker 1: if you Want to you can basically shut out all information It doesn't agree with your worldview and focus your entire world around the things the bullshit that you believe whether or not it's true.
Speaker 0: Google do you know, here's what they could do.
Speaker 1: They do.
Speaker 0: instead of doing it badges like this.
Speaker 0: They should make a news game and then we can use game works like this.
Speaker 1: You've got to answer questions and prove exactly.
Speaker 0: it goes down the top news stories and it makes you read Like two or three articles about every news story from you know regular sources and also high brow sources and low brow sources of all shapes and sizes from all sorts of crazy conspiracy nuts to You know highly educated papers that are pages long, you know everything and then ask you questions and Gives you badges for answering, you know, there's some movie factual.
Speaker 0: So you'll get your badges based on the factual questions, but also ask you other questions that are sort of you know Interpreted market research.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and use that use that data to.
Speaker 0: you know Part of the to gauge the public opinion even to compare with to compete with say Gallup poll, right?
Speaker 0: They could be like.
Speaker 0: Google knows that X percent of Americans think rainbow - is the best.
Speaker 0: of course We're at best pony right with that.
Speaker 1: now another way they could go with these badges is If they the Google project like the cool technology project come up with a system that will read the news from Google News internally and Automatically generate the questions and the answers.
Speaker 0: Well, that's definitely the kind of thing Google can do.
Speaker 0: Yes That's definitely within their skills.
Speaker 1: You know people have accused me a couple of times in the past of being kind of Overtly pro Google and a lot of techie people accuse people of that sort of thing all the time.
Speaker 1: So right here I'm pointing out Google did some evil.
Speaker 1: This is bad.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's not the biggest evil night, but it's you know, they did pull out of China, but it is not good.
Speaker 1: This is it's not to look is so good.
Speaker 0: It's not a good thing.
Speaker 1: They should get rid of the stupid badges or they should do what we just said, which is much better.
Speaker 0: Well, it's also sort of evil right.
Speaker 0: suddenly Google knows that like X percent of Mets fans are you know, who Jews?
Speaker 0: How is that evil too?
Speaker 1: fine to root to reveal factual aggregated information?
Speaker 0: because now they're just.
Speaker 0: it's evil in the same way that say Right.
Speaker 0: How would Wikipedia be if Wikipedia was for profits basically making money off the backs of people's work, right?
Speaker 0: You know unplayed employees.
Speaker 0: So when Google takes data generated by you who is just you know Having fun on the Internet's and uses that for profit It's evil.
Speaker 0: in the same way a for-profit Wikipedia would be for evil.
Speaker 1: But at the same time the amount of work you're providing is voluntary and so trivial that it's worth zero in and of itself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this is why I have less of a problem with say Mechanical Turk, even though most of it is spam Because they're at least paying you one cent for your your tiny contribution to lawyer.
Speaker 1: they pay you with badges.
Speaker 0: That's not a baby.
Speaker 1: They could set it up with steam.
Speaker 1: You can convert the badges into hats.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll tell you what.
Speaker 0: now You know when I you want me to go and start the company that gets government contracts.
Speaker 0: Well, I find the person who knows how to do that paperwork.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna pay him in badges.
Speaker 1: They all say You pay them in badges.
Speaker 0: I'll pay him in bitcoins I'll take all the tax monies from the state fill my wallet use it to buy badges and give that day.
Speaker 0: Give that to the employees because they'll feed them things of the day.
Speaker 1: So when I was a kid watch a show called mask m dot a dot s dot K And it stands for.
Speaker 1: it stands for I forget.
Speaker 0: actually, you know, you don't remember.
Speaker 1: I don't remember I never.
Speaker 0: actually I'm gonna be honest, right?
Speaker 0: I watched a lot of 80 shows but I guess mask wasn't on in my area.
Speaker 0: So I never actually heard of it until I was in college and you remembered it.
Speaker 1: Well, I when I was little was obsessed with it partly because the show I I found on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Here's the first episode.
Speaker 1: I gotta watch it to see how well it holds up.
Speaker 1: Not for real.
Speaker 1: Probably not that well bad.
Speaker 1: It's animated surprisingly better than I expected slightly better.
Speaker 1: Like it's pretty good animation.
Speaker 0: This has to do with what it was later 80s, right?
Speaker 0: Not yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also it was pretty.
Speaker 1: it was higher budget than you'd think and there were comics and everything.
Speaker 1: but Say comics and toys say what you will about the respective merits of mask and say transformers Mask toys kick the shit out of transformers in terms of playability as a kid I don't know depends on the best.
Speaker 1: toys were so high quality.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: It's the mobile armored strike command, by the way Command.
Speaker 1: I had almost every single toy.
Speaker 1: I had Boulder Hill and everything.
Speaker 0: I might have seen some mass toys in my youth But like I didn't know they were mass because the show was never on on my TV.
Speaker 0: But yeah So what's your thing of the day?
Speaker 0: my thing of the day?
Speaker 0: Steal it from you by accident.
Speaker 1: We'll see when they whenever this gets taken down But it's the opening theme to mask and then the entire first season first episode.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's your thing today.
Speaker 0: Yeah Oh, so you're not gonna talk about the entire mass collection on DVD pre-order on Amazon for $60 Which is in fact what prompted me to make this my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: because you understand Transformers I bought the sent transformers season 1 DVD box set right and that was it long time ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah long time ago, but why didn't they just release all of transformers in one box period?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of episodes.
Speaker 1: you want to know why they can make more money doing it this way and the Ninja Turtles is even worse.
Speaker 0: You saw that on.
Speaker 0: yeah, but masks.
Speaker 0: they did it right.
Speaker 0: all of mask beer every single episode.
Speaker 1: You know why they did it that one box.
Speaker 1: They did it that way because Mask is not super well known Popular.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's gonna hold up.
Speaker 0: I think it's gonna be off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the animation is so much better than similar shows and the toys were so good.
Speaker 1: I kind of want the toys now anyway, so I would play with them.
Speaker 0: So one of our listeners tweeted this at me my thing of the day here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty amazing.
Speaker 0: But let me tell you so I got.
Speaker 0: I bought an SSD for my real computer Because I was having some problems with the disc being real slow and really slowing me down.
Speaker 1: big solid-state drive for you kids.
Speaker 0: Yes, I bought a solid-state drive and because right I was so smart and you don't know this in Windows If you go into your user folders, you just double click on your the folder that has your name on it.
Speaker 0: That's on the desktop Usually and all your other folders are inside of it like my videos my music my documents, right?
Speaker 0: All those are folders in your user folder.
Speaker 0: if you right-click on say for example your my documents folder and go to properties There'll be a tab that says location.
Speaker 0: So let's say you have a one hard drive in your computer.
Speaker 0: Everything is on C right unless you made partitions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but partitions are so old-school because drives are so cheap.
Speaker 0: So, of course you have two or three drives, right?
Speaker 0: So now you got two drives C and D. Let's say you want to move my documents to D. You can just right-click on my documents go to location and change it to D colon backslash documents and put up and push.
Speaker 0: Okay, it'll move your my documents folder to the other drive, but you'll still access it from that same place.
Speaker 1: So it's transparent, I mean I did that when I first built my computer and I bought a 32 gigabyte.
Speaker 0: as you can move all Your all of those folders I moved every single one of them I did as well to another hard drive and the only thing that will be on the C drive will be Windows itself and All the programs that you install.
Speaker 0: so higher, you know Firefox.
Speaker 1: now what I did very easily because I built my computer from the beginning with an SSD like that is I just let the Things that are fucked up and can't deal with another drive letter B on my SSD.
Speaker 1: It didn't hurt anything and I just made cuz I got the e drive e drive program files.
Speaker 0: I just installed everything that you move program files to a different drive, huh?
Speaker 0: Yep, so the thing with that is program files in a different drive as well and good But it has one bend a pirate universe.
Speaker 0: It has one flaw in that.
Speaker 0: one of the major advantages of the SSD right is the speed increase from loading Applications when you start them off, but I do that because I only had a 32 gigabyte SSD.
Speaker 0: I bought a 128 gigabyte SSD.
Speaker 1: that would not have been worth the money when I built my computer is 200 something dollars In fact.
Speaker 0: nowadays if I was building a brand new computer, I would get two of those bitches.
Speaker 0: I'll for the combine them into a single logical drive.
Speaker 1: Actually, I'm building a new HTPC.
Speaker 0: what I'm thinking Ssd for that.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: No what I'm thinking about doing is buying 128 gigabyte SSD and putting it in my current real computer.
Speaker 0: So the 32 gig in the HTPC and no other storage cuz everything he needs from a NAS cuz it doesn't need a big hard Drive, I'm not gonna buy an SS It's just gonna get all this bit media for the NAS.
Speaker 1: But the 32 gig SSD is useless to me if I take it out of my current computer.
Speaker 0: So yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: So anyway, that's my plan.
Speaker 0: So, of course I have a 128 gig so I want to leave as many program files as possible on that SSD until it gets full.
Speaker 0: obviously Because that way they'll start up faster.
Speaker 0: if I start Firefox I'll just start right up.
Speaker 0: But if Firefox is on another drive Well, it's you're right but the problem is a hundred.
Speaker 0: even 128 gigs even 256 gigs if I were to get two of them and combine them is not enough.
Speaker 0: if you have steam with a zillion games It is not big enough to hold all back to the old days.
Speaker 1: I remember I'd on the top of our giant computer desk.
Speaker 1: There was just every game box and when I wanted to play a game, I'd be like, all right What am I gonna uninstall?
Speaker 0: I need at least a 500 gig drive to hold to install all the steam games.
Speaker 1: Get like four SSDs.
Speaker 0: That is so much money.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it.
Speaker 0: So of course the steam games I play often I would like to leave those on the C Drive on the SSD so they can start up very quickly Especially games that have problems with loading times.
Speaker 0: Fuck you gloating time games that suck right?
Speaker 0: Fuck you.
Speaker 1: But games they're.
Speaker 0: they're a lot of single-player FPS.
Speaker 0: Actually, I organized all my steam games into categories and I noticed that I have a lot of single-player FPS is mostly due to the incomplete Yep, that I've been playing a bad company, which has a little bit of loading time, but not that much there.
Speaker 0: But anyway, but you're gonna SSD going on not for that.
Speaker 0: Okay, but anyway, so the thing is I do you know The steam games I play often.
Speaker 0: I want to leave on the SSD But the steam games that I might want to have installed but I play rarely but take up a lot of space I would like to move those to a different drive.
Speaker 1: So you want to have some games on the SSD but not all game.
Speaker 0: that is you know And that is a difficult thing to manage right.
Speaker 0: you'd have to constantly be making sim links and you might want to move games back And forth.
Speaker 0: you might be basically it's like going back to the DOS days.
Speaker 0: We had to delete a game to install a game, you know, it's it.
Speaker 0: fuck that Somebody made this amazing program.
Speaker 0: They actually posted it on the internet April 2nd 2010.
Speaker 0: I don't know if there's a newer version or if this even needs a newer version.
Speaker 0: It might just work.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean it already.
Speaker 1: can just scrape your credit card and passwords and send it in Nigerian sky.
Speaker 0: I have yet to test this out, but it's a program called steam mover, right?
Speaker 0: What steam mover does?
Speaker 0: you open it up and it you tell it where your steam folder is and it shows you a list of all your steam games and You give it a destination which is the alternate location for steam games.
Speaker 0: So you tell it.
Speaker 0: basically my steam games are in C colon backslash program files back Steam backslash site maps backslash common and I would like to put some steam games.
Speaker 0: That's my SSD on the left, right?
Speaker 0: I would like to put some of the games that I don't play so often on D colon backslash steam Which is the spare steam folder?
Speaker 0: Okay, then next to every steam game in the list is a blue arrow.
Speaker 0: you click the blue arrow.
Speaker 0: It moves it to the other drive.
Speaker 0: you click the blue arrow again.
Speaker 0: It moves it back where it came from.
Speaker 0: steam doesn't know the difference.
Speaker 1: Not too shabby is it?
Speaker 0: that is Pretty amazing right there and best of all it has a built-in Sort of.
Speaker 0: show me your moves Command where you can say I want to run the commands myself and it will show you the windows command line of what it's doing.
Speaker 0: It's basically uses xcopy Rd and Make link to move and sim link things back and forth.
Speaker 1: shit You know what I realized.
Speaker 1: so you will actually realize a lot of our listeners are probably just Amazed at the fact that you can make links in Windows.
Speaker 0: I know right but man it shows you on the command line what it's doing.
Speaker 0: so you can actually do it yourself.
Speaker 1: you realize kids You don't like doing stuff on top of stuff in Windows the same way you do in Linux.
Speaker 0: in new windows if all your drives Are NTFS.
Speaker 0: that's the only thing in this.
Speaker 0: all of your drives involved had to be NTFS partitions.
Speaker 1: It's fine.
Speaker 0: It is fun.
Speaker 1: I no longer bother with the whole dual boot to have the one virtual box.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's no reason It won't work with fat32 bla bla bla bla bla.
Speaker 0: It can only relocate folders not individual files.
Speaker 0: so Steam does have some really big files in it like GCF files that are in the steam apps folder itself that aren't actually part of A games in you know folder and you can't move those, but it's like well.
Speaker 0: I mean come on right You can leave those there, it's fine, but yeah steam mover is my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: You should check it out.
Speaker 0: if you have the SSD That's not so big.
Speaker 1: so in the meta moment the book club book that we just finished that will do a show on Shortly in its separate non Thursday episode stream with a new RSS feed and everything was Isaac Asimov's foundation Which we should have done the show on Thursday, but I hadn't finished it in time because I was busy.
Speaker 0: rim fail Yeah, but I just let it be on the record.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I got stuff to say about it.
Speaker 0: double fail you failed twice.
Speaker 1: Quite a lot to say about it.
Speaker 0: the next show on it.
Speaker 1: I don't know maybe not tonight.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of want to cook my dinner.
Speaker 1: We could do it Wednesday.
Speaker 0: Maybe we're doing another show.
Speaker 0: We're doing two shows Wednesday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or we could do it over the weekend.
Speaker 1: I'm sure we can find time.
Speaker 0: We gotta keep delaying this mother.
Speaker 0: Don't you I'm ready.
Speaker 1: It's just you want to do it right after this.
Speaker 0: I'll do it whenever I'm ready.
Speaker 1: I need to do a Wednesday right after we do that show on something or other.
Speaker 1: The penny arcade Expo in Seattle.
Speaker 1: we will be edits doing stuff.
Speaker 1: nice Kinetic on is passed and done.
Speaker 1: next year's kinetic on.
Speaker 1: many of you have already contacted us Asking about what it'll take to join our personal panels and workshops department.
Speaker 1: I will get back to all of you because I do in fact need you.
Speaker 1: The game katsu.
Speaker 1: people came out of the woodwork and we're like hey guys shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just so people know.
Speaker 0: New York comic-con a slash.
Speaker 0: New York anime festival October 13 14 15 and 16.
Speaker 1: Oh shit, we we should be there doing stuff, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that will be about a month and a half after packs.
Speaker 0: So that is that is coming up.
Speaker 0: Do not forget it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that'll hold us over until the next packs packs East we will be at doing a bunch of shit.
Speaker 0: I do not recommend doing this, but I feel it is my service to share this information.
Speaker 0: New York comic-con, you know, we like the conventions that have one price period right.
Speaker 0: so packs you buy a badge.
Speaker 0: It's a badge.
Speaker 0: Every badge is a badge end of store.
Speaker 0: You can go to anything with the badge as long as it's you know for that day, right?
Speaker 0: GenCon we don't like because they have individual ticketing for individual events.
Speaker 0: So if you want to play it you get.
Speaker 0: you buy a badge you get into GenCon and then you want to play in a game you gotta buy a ticket for that.
Speaker 1: and now there's the middle-of-the-road system.
Speaker 1: some gaming cons do.
Speaker 1: that's okay where you get Your badge and it comes with X tickets.
Speaker 1: That's all anyone can get.
Speaker 0: that's that's an okay.
Speaker 1: So that's just to you know, allocate these scarce resources.
Speaker 0: I don't like paying for more things once you're in the convention or having people have more or less privileges based on spending Money, right?
Speaker 0: So newer comic-con is against that philosophy.
Speaker 0: they sell fancy VIP badges for a lot of money and those badges get you swag and they let you cut lines and they let You see famous people and all that kind of bullshit.
Speaker 0: and I'm not a fan.
Speaker 0: So do not buy these.
Speaker 0: but I have to tell you they're gonna be sold out for this comic-con very soon.
Speaker 0: And also San Diego comic-con is like what very like this week Credibly soon.
Speaker 1: Oh two cons coming up.
Speaker 1: Not that we'll be there.
Speaker 0: But yes, let's see San Diego comic-con.
Speaker 0: Excuse me comic-con international right is July 21 through 24 so this weekend.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: and Otacon I believe is the weekend after that July 29 through 31st.
Speaker 0: It's convention season and the two biggest conventions east and west.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna be there.
Speaker 1: Yep Well, we won't be at Otacon because they don't like us anymore.
Speaker 0: But if you are they still like you.
Speaker 0: Otacon.
Speaker 0: Yeah for your treating of us doesn't mean we don't want to come.
Speaker 1: we offer to do panels and I kind of miss going to Otacon.
Speaker 0: but I'll go.
Speaker 1: just if you go to Otacon badly go see Makoto shinkai stuff.
Speaker 0: It's like having a girlfriend who's hot and you like her but she like beats you and it's like.
Speaker 0: It's like like I'm not gonna hang out with you while you beat me But if you stop beating me, I'd come back, but she does surreptitiously.
Speaker 1: It's like behind your back like you're like she doesn't answer your calls and then you go to bed.
Speaker 1: you wake up with the bruise.
Speaker 1: You're like what?
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: That's that's Otacon.
Speaker 0: Cut that shit out.
Speaker 0: We'll come back.
Speaker 1: if you were going to Otacon go see Makoto shinkai's panels.
Speaker 1: Not enough people.
Speaker 1: go see the actual creators.
Speaker 1: I mean we heard an anime next a long time ago.
Speaker 1: They just happen to have Rintaro.
Speaker 1: We're like, holy shit.
Speaker 0: It's Rintaro Yeah, and the room was like a quarter full and everyone's kind of sitting in there.
Speaker 1: He took questions like no one really had any questions for him.
Speaker 1: It was it was sad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's really sad.
Speaker 0: He seemed kind of happy though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he was like, whatever.
Speaker 0: anyway Actual show topic.
Speaker 1: Yeah show topic.
Speaker 1: So there is a story one of those things that you know would piss rim off.
Speaker 1: I have a whole like feed of things that pissed me off.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean there you must add ten a day of just reading Fark.
Speaker 1: Oh my god The thing is.
Speaker 1: it also makes me happy.
Speaker 1: That's why I don't read Fark because much of Fark is the story of people getting what?
Speaker 0: They deserve that's true.
Speaker 1: You try to you try to rob someplace and oh you got hit in the nuts.
Speaker 1: So anyway, this guy John H gasps Again.
Speaker 0: his name is gasps.
Speaker 0: just child must have been great.
Speaker 1: He lives in a masa who sits Okay, and he got his driver's license revoked.
Speaker 1: took him two weeks almost to get it back.
Speaker 0: Well, it was a revoked because he was driving shit.
Speaker 0: Lee was never had a ticket.
Speaker 0: Oh What the fuck.
Speaker 1: it was revoked automatically.
Speaker 1: He received a letter saying that it was revoked and it wouldn't even say why.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, so he not being able to drive had to go to the DMV and like regible I guess whatever they call it in masa who sits and event and you know do an inquiry and everything and eventually he found out That the reason his driver's license was revoked.
Speaker 1: Was that an anti-terrorism Facial recognition program that the state is running scanned a database of every picture of every driver's license and determined that he was likely a Fraudulent driver's license and a fake person copied from someone else's driver's license.
Speaker 0: But he's a real dude Mm-hmm, and how did he find out that his license was revoked?
Speaker 1: Oh, they sent him a letter.
Speaker 0: Okay Fake license in the database.
Speaker 0: Why would they send a letter to the fake address?
Speaker 1: Also, why don't they send the police to arrest the scammer?
Speaker 0: I don't get it.
Speaker 0: It makes no sense to me.
Speaker 1: So digging into this article more and more here's the gist of it.
Speaker 1: Governments are using this very powerful technology, which I'm gonna call a facial recognition.
Speaker 1: It does exactly what you think it does.
Speaker 1: it's it's been written.
Speaker 0: UK's been using it for years and years and years.
Speaker 1: It's been around for a long time, dude My camera the camera we use to film like our geek night stuff and our radio free equestria and all that It has really good facial recognition.
Speaker 1: I programmed in everyone in the crew and It just shows me their names in the viewfinder when it sees their faces.
Speaker 1: when I'm recording when I'm playing back I can look at tags and see who is in what scene when It'll even take a picture.
Speaker 1: anytime anyone on my smile list smiles on camera while I'm recording.
Speaker 1: you know, this stuff is already pretty consumer grade and Governments are using it for a lot of stuff Facebook Google.
Speaker 1: Everyone's gonna be using it.
Speaker 0: Well, they've been using.
Speaker 0: it's not new.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be using it like it's getting to the tipping point of super.
Speaker 0: It's been an iPhoto for a version or two.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, it's it's on every notes.
Speaker 1: But we're getting to the point of super cross linking.
Speaker 1: I mean right now Facebook still a lot of times you only show up in that embarrassing picture tag because someone tagged you in it.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: Imagine if Facebook just did facial recognition and every face you could figure out.
Speaker 0: it just auto tagged Yeah, but it would get some wrong, right?
Speaker 0: So and the problem is if someone tags you in a photo you can now see that photo.
Speaker 0: So what if I had a private photo of me naked?
Speaker 0: And then it tagged?
Speaker 0: it saw some other guy who looked like me?
Speaker 0: it automatically tagged because I wouldn't tag this private photo.
Speaker 0: What's the purpose of that right?
Speaker 0: I'm just using Facebook to store the photo and then it tags my face as this other guy and Then now he can see my naked photo.
Speaker 1: Well, Kenny, I don't know how it works.
Speaker 1: I don't have Facebook.
Speaker 0: that if I tag you in a photo you.
Speaker 1: but how would he know to tag you in a private photo?
Speaker 0: No, it automatically tags if the facial.
Speaker 1: so obviously unless they're idiots.
Speaker 1: It doesn't auto tag private photos.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying things like that are potential.
Speaker 1: but my point was that even if you've got say a Success rate that means that one out of a hundred photos is gonna be mistagged.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: And if we've got governments like Massa who sits Using this to deny people's like actual civic services.
Speaker 1: That's bullshit Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So this made me think a lot about facial recognition because I realized that I am mostly way for Ubiquitous facial recognition and even ubiquitous surveillance as long as it's relatively open.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, that's you know, that's the major thing, right?
Speaker 0: So the UK has had facial recognition on security cameras, you know for a long time.
Speaker 0: Basically, they have a huge system where they put facial.
Speaker 0: they put cameras all over the fucking place.
Speaker 0: You know more so than probably almost any country V for Vendetta style.
Speaker 0: Yes, exactly That's what they have.
Speaker 0: So and they have a huge database of faces and what they do is if you're walking down the street and your face It's caught in a camera They got a ton of computers that are gonna look you up and especially comparing you to like the wanted felons list.
Speaker 0: So if like, you know if the FBI is most wanted walks down the lit the street in London in a camera season It sets off a light somewhere where the people are watching and they'll go pick you up.
Speaker 0: That's what they do.
Speaker 0: theoretically Yeah, but they actually do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, how often does it work?
Speaker 1: How often do they actually respond?
Speaker 1: how many false positives?
Speaker 1: We don't know any of that We don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they definitely have this system and you know I'm actually in favor of that kind of system.
Speaker 0: as long as a the cameras are only in public places, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know you get but a camera in someone's house, let's just do right and be.
Speaker 0: you can't keep that video footage private.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: that video footage needs to be publicly accessible And there's no reason it couldn't be publicly accessible.
Speaker 0: immediately.
Speaker 0: I should be able to go and see a live view of whatever the camera outside my house is looking at
Speaker 1: or
Speaker 0: if I know There's a camera in London outside Big Ben I should be able to go online click on that camera and see what it sees in my web browser.
Speaker 0: Go to the entire archives and see what it saw.
Speaker 0: cuz maybe you know There's a Rodney King caught on that tape and I don't want the government destroying it.
Speaker 0: That needs to be a publicly accessible video.
Speaker 1: So arguments against that not not saying I agree with them would be that one makes it trivial to stalk people.
Speaker 0: If people are in public places, and I'm not physically chasing them I'm just watching them on cameras to stalk them.
Speaker 0: That's actually better cuz stalkers gonna start to start but it's not gonna stalk.
Speaker 0: Imagine this right?
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, I'm just saying imagine this.
Speaker 1: I'm just putting forth an idea.
Speaker 1: if we combine the ubiquitous cameras Which still require a lot of paying attention with ubiquitous and accurate facial recognition?
Speaker 1: I can auto stalk and then just have a database where eventually I'll know Pretty reliably where someone who has reasonably consistent habits will be.
Speaker 1: If you're a stalker you can know that anyway Yeah, but if you can't you might see if you if you're a stalker you have to go out and do the legwork So there's odds that someone will notice you, you know The creepy guys.
Speaker 0: the thing is I'm not saying that the facial recognition data and system has to be publicly accessible.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying oh, no I'm saying that the video footage has to be.
Speaker 1: and I'm saying that if the video footage is accessible Then they will.
Speaker 1: it will have a hundred percent facial recognition coverage because private people will have access to almost as good software.
Speaker 0: Maybe because the bit it'll happen.
Speaker 1: It'll definitely happen.
Speaker 1: I guarantee to you I mean already I think Picasa has a thing that'll like write tag people in your photos.
Speaker 0: Well, that's a photo.
Speaker 0: does yeah that a lot of them do that.
Speaker 0: It's mostly those are just for organization of photos.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but don't you can't tell me that within decade if not sooner people will have those capabilities for any video They have access to?
Speaker 1: I guess I mean what if YouTube did it?
Speaker 1: I personally would love it if I could go to YouTube and say here's a picture of me find any other YouTube videos that have.
Speaker 0: That'd be awesome.
Speaker 0: but at the same or you can take a picture of a person on the street with your phone and then get a list of All the YouTube videos.
Speaker 0: they're in and flicker photos.
Speaker 0: They're in and Facebook photos all aggregated.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: I should make that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, wouldn't that be awesome?
Speaker 0: if I made an app that did that I'd make so much monies.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: My take on all this is that I agree there are Pro societal problems that would come about in this future.
Speaker 1: I also argue that this future is inevitable and we we'd better deal with it now rather than later.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's you know.
Speaker 1: I think that's something we say all with it now when it's not yet a hundred percent ubiquitous.
Speaker 0: if we figure out as a society I'm like every other problem which we fail to deal with.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we always wait until the last second.
Speaker 0: No, we wait until ten years after the last.
Speaker 1: Oh, we have an economy based almost entirely on intellectual property That is trivially stolen untraceable.
Speaker 1: How long have people been able to do this?
Speaker 0: 20 years good job guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, but you know, it's we've said there's a lot of times you know, is that the Right?
Speaker 0: is that the government always goes to deal with some sort of you know New situation that is being brought about by technology?
Speaker 0: well after it has been brought about even though everyone saw it coming right and The technology is inevitable, right?
Speaker 0: A lot of times they try to fight the technology Itself after the fact that it's already out there in the wild, huh?
Speaker 0: Then they try to.
Speaker 0: they try to just ban it.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh shit.
Speaker 0: This technology is a problem for us now that it exists.
Speaker 0: Let's ban it.
Speaker 0: It's like well, no, what you have to do is you have to accept the technology because you can't fight it.
Speaker 0: It's unbeatable.
Speaker 0: It's like trying to slay the dragon.
Speaker 1: Is there not an example in the foundation of a nation that forgot how to use nuclear power and had an accident and banned nuclear Power because it was too dangerous?
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: It didn't turn out so well for them.
Speaker 0: Not at all, right?
Speaker 0: What you have to do is instead learn accept that the technology is gonna be there and instead change the things you can change.
Speaker 0: Remember technology is science.
Speaker 0: It's just the rules of the world.
Speaker 0: You can't fight the law of physics, right?
Speaker 0: We don't know how to do that yet.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll figure that out one day.
Speaker 0: not yet, right.
Speaker 0: but Society government law politics.
Speaker 0: These are completely artificial constructs just created by humans on paper.
Speaker 0: They're just words on papers.
Speaker 0: They're not.
Speaker 0: they're not laws of the universe.
Speaker 1: I am so amazed when people argue like strict constructionism of the US Constitution or anyone who even Bothers to debate the intention of the founding father, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I can't.
Speaker 1: tension of a guy a couple hundred years ago in terms of what he thought gun law should be is irrelevant To the modern world of guns.
Speaker 0: the law the laws of thermodynamics can't change him, right?
Speaker 0: Constitution just a piece of paper.
Speaker 0: we can make the rules whatever we fucking want them to be Right, so we should.
Speaker 0: you know We accept that we can't change the law of thermodynamics and instead we need to change the things we can change in our society to accept those facts.
Speaker 0: How the people who as opposed to trying to butt heads with them because then you're just asking for trouble funny.
Speaker 1: how.
Speaker 1: the people who most feel that the Constitution isn't just a piece of paper and it has some sort of mystical power and that the founding fathers were some sort of like God-emperor Kings enlightened among the masses who made everything perfect and foresaw every possible consequence of technology Are the same people who kind of don't believe in a lot of the fundamental laws of the universe?
Speaker 0: Funny that funny.
Speaker 1: but Government is impotent to deal with this.
Speaker 1: I'm not even gonna pretend.
Speaker 0: So what's government not impotent to deal with it's.
Speaker 1: I know one thing's really good at maintaining a general Status quo for a long.
Speaker 0: I know one thing the government is exceptionally good at wasting money.
Speaker 0: if there was a military invasion They would be really good at fending that off.
Speaker 1: Ah, not always though.
Speaker 1: historically a lot of government I mean read up on the Crimean War.
Speaker 0: I said the US government.
Speaker 0: right now if someone tried to invade the u.s Today they have that shit down.
Speaker 0: They have that shit.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying about all governments over all history I'm saying us government today.
Speaker 0: If somebody tried to invade us 1812 style.
Speaker 0: They know what to do.
Speaker 0: Yep They wouldn't even had to think about it.
Speaker 0: there wouldn't even be really a debate.
Speaker 0: They would they would just go.
Speaker 0: but anyway, I argue there isn't anyone who could do a better job.
Speaker 1: We agree that government cannot address the problems that society is going to face with facial recognition.
Speaker 1: No, because nobody you can't ban it.
Speaker 1: Everyone will have access to it eventually.
Speaker 1: and it was bum with a track phone.
Speaker 0: that track phone has facial And the government already has clearly shown as per your FARC article that they will clumsily try to use it clumsily.
Speaker 1: I think it's one step further.
Speaker 1: That's like an akimbo ham fist.
Speaker 1: It's like a man was genetically engineered to have two hands that are at in fact hams.
Speaker 1: Okay ham fists I amend my statement.
Speaker 0: they will derpily Try to use the technology that they cannot control.
Speaker 1: not quite herp to derpily because herp to derpily would have meant that this Database like crashed and destroyed all the driver's licenses.
Speaker 0: and then they're gonna get in the guillotine.
Speaker 1: That's kind of inside baseball.
Speaker 1: I Really I was at Emily and I went to this fancy French restaurant and we're like partying during best so One.
Speaker 1: the people in the restaurant are wearing the tricolor obviously Republican possibly Jacobins and They're drunk and singing with us.
Speaker 1: and you know They like keep giving us alcohol and screaming things in French and they got us up and made us dance around and they're pulling people in The street and kisses.
Speaker 1: it wasn't even Bastille day yet.
Speaker 1: It was before Bastille day.
Speaker 1: This is the.
Speaker 1: So I really really had to resist the urge to be like Viva la wa right after the saying the Marseille.
Speaker 1: They might have just killed me.
Speaker 0: why would they wouldn't have killed you Scott?
Speaker 1: they are clearly Jacobins.
Speaker 1: They had the tricolor pins on them.
Speaker 0: So they're not gonna murder you.
Speaker 1: they might.
Speaker 1: That's what the mobs did.
Speaker 1: Yeah dishes Oh, so anyway to get back to my point Which I kind of forgot what it was.
Speaker 1: Okay, government can't deal with this shit.
Speaker 0: la wa wants to use facial recognition to detect the derps.
Speaker 1: So I think the best way to handle this is for some enterprising individual or company Maybe Google maybe Facebook though Facebook would derp it too because Facebook's getting derpier derpier and derpier.
Speaker 1: You saw these tried to ban like Google+ ads and Facebook, I don't get.
Speaker 0: I don't get.
Speaker 1: it's like yeah If we don't tell them about Google+ they won't know it exists.
Speaker 1: They won't leave.
Speaker 0: Okay You know what Facebook really needs to do if they want to fight Google.
Speaker 0: They should just make Facebook email To fight Gmail.
Speaker 0: cuz right cuz like.
Speaker 0: even people who are using Facebook are also using Gmail.
Speaker 0: but if people it there but even if they're more heavily a Facebook person like they check their they check their email and Gmail and Then they go to Facebook for the rest of the day and they only go to.
Speaker 1: So they still chat in G talk even though they're on Facebook, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if they just had the Facebook chat work and they also made Facebook email.
Speaker 0: They could get people completely off of Google.
Speaker 1: I don't think they would.
Speaker 1: it's too late.
Speaker 0: I know it's too late.
Speaker 0: they're not gonna be able to do it, but they should.
Speaker 1: but someone either Google or Facebook or just some nerd like you said.
Speaker 1: just put it together yourself make the app or you take a picture of someone and it Finds everything about them in the world.
Speaker 1: stalker.
Speaker 1: Just call it stalker Because once you make the technology you've opened Pandora's box, they can't close it.
Speaker 0: Apple could ban it from the App Store.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then oh, you know what they're basically jailbreak.
Speaker 1: No, I'm gonna go back to an old analogy if you outlaw guns.
Speaker 0: But the thing is the problem.
Speaker 0: here's the thing as of today very today.
Speaker 0: if you were gonna set that up the way you would have to make it architecturally is The same way that Google does.
Speaker 0: their voice recognition on their keyboard is where someone takes the picture The photo is sent to your data center where it's processed and then the results are sent back You know asynchronously to the client and that's today.
Speaker 0: So if you set that up today You could be shut down because you would be required just by the laws of technology to have a centralized location in order to make This, you know be able to stand up against someone trying to shut you down.
Speaker 1: Local.
Speaker 0: it has to be at the point at where the cell phone or maybe you can plug it into your laptop or something.
Speaker 0: Well, here's enough horsepower Storage to hold the database Just on your person.
Speaker 1: Well, this is where I see the real future of personal computing.
Speaker 1: Remember your idea and a few technologies agree with us of everyone should have their own personal cloud.
Speaker 1: That's what I hope should be the result because then I have my phone Connects to my cloud my cloud interfaces with other clouds But I can shut that shit off if I need to.
Speaker 0: this is this is you know Something that is not a new idea, right?
Speaker 0: There's a thing called foaf friend of a friend.
Speaker 0: It's an XML schema.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: I know XML scheme was a kind of Blair these days But the way
Speaker 1: foam and there was a time when XML was the hot shit
Speaker 0: and the way foaf works You should look it up is that you made an XML document That was basically your social network profile and there were all these different extensions you could add to it.
Speaker 0: So anytime, you know, so it would start off with just like name address Whatever and let's say you wanted to add in like movie ratings.
Speaker 0: Well, there was an extension and it's like.
Speaker 0: well, this is how you add movie ratings to your you know in XML.
Speaker 0: And this is how you add, you know comments and this is how you add.
Speaker 0: You know hearts and all.
Speaker 0: you could basically add anything to it and all these different XML things Imagine
Speaker 1: like a super extensible modern version of the old like nerd tag
Speaker 0: Writing as writing a Facebook profile in XML and you could just add Anything you could come up with that you might want to be in your profile to it.
Speaker 1: as a pony Rainbow day exact.
Speaker 0: you could add a pony section.
Speaker 0: you could add, you know a graffiti wall any right?
Speaker 0: So and the idea was that you would host your foaf file on your website and you would have links in Your profile to other foaf files.
Speaker 0: So if I put my foaf XML file at Aprache.net/foaf.xml and it would be in the friends section.
Speaker 0: There would be a link.
Speaker 0: It was a friend rim Foaf location.
Speaker 0: You know rim.frontrowcrew.com/foaf.xml and rim would host his foaf.xml file at that location.
Speaker 0: So now everyone has their own web server hosting their own profiles, but they're all linked to each other.
Speaker 0: So you could still make on top of that a social networking app like Facebook, even though there's no central server Everyone is just hosting their own profile on their own server.
Speaker 0: So, you know the also jabber, right?
Speaker 0: So Gchat is jabber, but it's centralized but the idea of jabber is federated Chat, so everyone would have their own chat server, right?
Speaker 0: So we could have frontrowcrew.com chat server and then you would have users would have accounts on your chat server and you would chat With other servers.
Speaker 0: So instead of there just being one chat server like there is with say AOL aim this one server It's aim.
Speaker 0: Everyone would have their own chat server and if you chatted with other people on the same server as you Those chats wouldn't go over the Internet's they would just stay on that server.
Speaker 0: So if I was chatting with rim on the front crew.com server All our chats would be there and they wouldn't go anywhere else.
Speaker 0: So no one could spy on us.
Speaker 0: But if I wanted to chat with someone who has G chat then my server knows how to talk to G check because they both speak jabber and we could.
Speaker 0: it would the Servers.
Speaker 0: I would talk to my server He would talk to the G chat server and then the G chat server would talk to my server and send the chats back and forth.
Speaker 0: and that's Federation Identica which we used for a while also known as Laconica.
Speaker 0: I don't know what status.net is.
Speaker 0: what they're calling it These days is basically a Twitter that uses this architecture where everyone has their own Twitter server But then all the different Twitter servers know how to talk to each other.
Speaker 0: So you can just tweet and then the tweet will only go on your server.
Speaker 0: But if someone in another server is following you then your server knows to send your tweets to that server because you have a follower On it, but if there's a server out there, you don't have any followers.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna send your tweet to that one.
Speaker 0: It's only gonna send your tweets to the ones that needs to send it to.
Speaker 0: and So the ultimate goal here is that we can take down Facebook and Google and all these places and We could all have.
Speaker 0: everyone could have a server in their house and Microsoft is actually leading the way on this with Windows home.
Speaker 1: So actually though with Google we wouldn't have to take Google down.
Speaker 1: They could very easily have.
Speaker 1: they have a cloud that has its own.
Speaker 0: Yes, of course There are things there still room for these companies to exist and do things and provide many services But the point is is you would have your own server in your own house.
Speaker 0: You would put your photos and your videos and all your personal things on your own server Which is completely 100% under your control.
Speaker 0: You would decide what goes out and what goes in and if you needed to share with say your mom who has her own server In her house, you would just say share my photos with my mom her servers over there And when she wanted to look at your photos your server would send its photos to her server where she could look at them.
Speaker 1: Obviously, that's a a high level because the physical reality is you would need multiple locations for safety of data.
Speaker 0: Obviously, there's a lot of things going on there.
Speaker 0: But the other the reason that we can't have this nice thing right now mostly is because ISPs are dickwads.
Speaker 0: Yep And if ipv6 comes around well, you didn't have this.
Speaker 1: It's only relatively recently that a lot of people are doing two-way communication on the internet of any like so We're doing Any size like large quantities of data.
Speaker 1: in the early days Yes, they were because you couldn't send much data.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it was just two-way communication as bandwidth grew.
Speaker 1: notice how when cable modems came and everything bandwidth only grew downstream For a long time it did because and and I'm not gonna say conspiracy or anything, but very obviously media companies and technology companies and many companies do not really like the idea of People being their own publishers and their own distributors in addition to consuming data on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the internet is a web.
Speaker 0: I can send things directly from my computer to rim But if you've noticed whenever anyone's tried to set up networks with that structure, right?
Speaker 0: They've always been fought against by the man, right mighty Napster they fought, you know bit torrent is pretty much the only Surviving like peer-to-peer structured thing.
Speaker 1: now imagine a bit torn like thing for a web browser Browser was also a web server and you just you were publishing your shit Operas trying to do that.
Speaker 1: I know and that's that's what I would say web 3.0 is.
Speaker 0: but you know The thing is we got way off topic here.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: So that's fine.
Speaker 1: We've been a while we can actually a better topic.
Speaker 0: that you know, it's like we didn't have that show idea But that would have been a great show idea.
Speaker 0: We would have just started with that.
Speaker 1: I guess we got two topics we talked about.
Speaker 1: I guess since we're at the end though.
Speaker 1: I do want to.
Speaker 1: I Want to be able to walk home and the camera on my door lets me in.
Speaker 0: I don't know how much I would trust that but that's okay.
Speaker 1: I trusted if it got to the point where was trustable or better if My doors, that'd be okay.
Speaker 0: If it was just another factor in a multi-factor authentication or if my door still had a little however it locked.
Speaker 1: But the doorman I could give him a list of people who he you know when they walk in.
Speaker 1: it shows a little like like Like on his screen.
Speaker 1: it shows green like okay going to rims apartment.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So then he doesn't have to bother them.
Speaker 1: But yet someone I haven't put on the list.
Speaker 1: It's like like yellow don't know.
Speaker 0: well you could you can make face just one of like two or three factors and like it could be a password.
Speaker 0: you say like Imagine if you walked up to your door and it saw your face and you said open sesame and you had a thing Right, you know some sort of card swipe or something.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the saying not so great because people can hear what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's true.
Speaker 0: But you know just saying like, you know, and I did.
Speaker 0: that's an idea.
Speaker 0: You know a multi-factor door opener.
Speaker 0: and then what you could do is you could like if if everyone and let's say everyone had A car like it was a hotel.
Speaker 0: Right, I could come over to your house and I have a card that I used to open my house.
Speaker 0: So I could swipe the card at your house and you could say this card is allowed to open my house.
Speaker 0: No, no, I could say no one has a set of keys anymore.
Speaker 0: Everyone is exactly one key card for the world and you just add your your company when you go to work.
Speaker 0: They add your key card to the company's security system.
Speaker 0: So now you use your personal key card to go to work and if they fire you they remove you from it.
Speaker 1: So if I had this sort of multi pass, that would be the best thing ever Mmm, but imagine the like the potential you say.
Speaker 1: All right, Scott, you're allowed to open my door up until 10 p.m On weekdays.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could do that.
Speaker 1: Not a night though, cuz I'm sleeping most likely.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway, I also just really I want to go to a search engine like Google go to Google Images Upload a picture and find me on the Internet.
Speaker 0: Google Goggles does it.
Speaker 1: it does kind but not with idea.
Speaker 1: I took a picture of Adam and wasn't it like that monkey that came back.
Speaker 0: I took it at Connecticut.
Speaker 0: I took a picture of a oh at Nerd NYC board game night.
Speaker 0: Someone had a little tiny card game, but it was German.
Speaker 0: so I didn't know what the hell.
Speaker 0: I couldn't really understand what it said on the box.
Speaker 0: I took a picture of the box with my phone.
Speaker 0: Google Goggles Did.
Speaker 0: a Google search picked it up right away.
Speaker 0: bored young geek page showed up right top result.
Speaker 1: I just I want that to be a little bit further.
Speaker 1: I want to be able to search based on people like.
Speaker 1: I know who rim is.
Speaker 1: I want to search forever rim and whatever it is.
Speaker 1: I'm looking forward.
Speaker 1: see if I find incriminating videos Incriminating, of course.
Speaker 1: What else is anyone gonna search for?
Speaker 0: I don't have incriminating videos But you know, it'd be cool.
Speaker 0: Like if you're walking down and you see all your at PAX, you know Like.
Speaker 0: I know this guy click and it's like oh that guy.
Speaker 0: or if someone were to take a picture of me And then you know, they could find out my shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah or they could be watching a YouTube video and they could see me in the YouTube video.
Speaker 0: click on you and it goes to Your website.
Speaker 0: click on me and you click on my face.
Speaker 0: you highlight a box around it and then it does a search for my face Even though they just saw me in a YouTube.
Speaker 1: That's what I want and that's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.