Speaker 0: It's Thursday April 11th 2011 on rim, and this is geek nights Tonight SNMP and how nobody knows how to freakin use it.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So as I walk into work.
Speaker 0: There's a there's blue tape Covering the lock to the door to my suite.
Speaker 0: It's one of our many sweets, and there's just blue tape over it.
Speaker 1: I guess you're fired, so it's just open.
Speaker 0: It's holding it open.
Speaker 0: it prevented the door from locking.
Speaker 1: So I'm like hmm somebody forgot their key.
Speaker 0: So I look around and there's nobody around because it's you know the butt crack of dawn And I'm not really worried about thieves or anything because it's not your shit.
Speaker 0: Well no more because we have door men and it's actually a relatively secure building and very few people even have access to that floor Let alone you know anyway, so I go to my office.
Speaker 0: lights are off and I look around.
Speaker 0: There's nothing and Then I see an email.
Speaker 0: you know I go to complain to email the building and be like what the fuck dude Who left our door open?
Speaker 0: What are they doing?
Speaker 0: and?
Speaker 0: There's an email from the building, and they're like hey.
Speaker 0: We're uh busting into everyone's sweets to do surveys to Install sprinkler systems for fire suppression as has been mandated by New York City.
Speaker 0: all right.
Speaker 0: The fail there is that I now know that my building does not in fact have active fire suppression of any kind.
Speaker 1: All right, so that sucks.
Speaker 1: my apartment does.
Speaker 0: my apartment does too.
Speaker 1: So does the building I work in?
Speaker 0: the building I work in apparently does not.
Speaker 0: I didn't think that pre-war meant pre-world War One.
Speaker 1: no pre-war does mean pre-war.
Speaker 1: They're not talking about you know Persian Gulf.
Speaker 0: Well the joke I always make and I'll make it now is people always say like oh yeah The building's pre-war and I interject and say yes civil.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it means don't live there.
Speaker 0: Well, it was a double joke because until recently the building was named the Lincoln building mm-hmm But now it's named one grand Central Plaza because Lincoln had a bad connotation.
Speaker 0: Okay, yeah, I really don't like my building.
Speaker 1: sure I mean it's not like it was.
Speaker 0: What I do like is that it's like 70 degrees today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, except you know why could it?
Speaker 1: why is it gotta be trolling being like yeah?
Speaker 0: I get up in the morning shining the birds are singing.
Speaker 0: I'm like shit son ride my bike to work.
Speaker 1: no in the morning you wake up.
Speaker 1: It's like fucking fog.
Speaker 1: Look at the weather.
Speaker 1: It's like fucking rain.
Speaker 1: It's gonna rain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't look at the weather.
Speaker 0: You know what I looked at though.
Speaker 0: It was like 60 degrees.
Speaker 0: Yeah I can bike in the rain, but I'm not rollerblading in the rain.
Speaker 1: I can bike in tiny rain see like a couple because my building sucks ass.
Speaker 0: I can't ride my real bike cuz I have to leave it outside.
Speaker 0: I'm not leaving a multi-thousand dollar bike out on the street in Manhattan mm-hmm, so I'm getting my old.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: mountain bike Stolen in the past.
Speaker 0: re I'm fixing it, and I'm gonna ride that to work cuz someone steals it whatever It's already been stolen.
Speaker 0: the fact that I even have it is amazing mm-hmm And it can handle the rain pretty well because it's a goddamn mountain bike.
Speaker 1: Anyway, there was a. so for lunch today.
Speaker 1: right I go I'm walking around looking around walking around looking around looking around looking around for something to eat and There was this.
Speaker 0: that's what lunch usually is.
Speaker 1: yeah And there was a. there was a truck that was there that the last time this truck was there Had a huge line, but this time today Line was like non-existent, so I go to the truck.
Speaker 1: It's called Bien dang.
Speaker 1: It's Taiwanese food right and I got some chicken on top of rice all right, which is fried chicken, but also Next to it.
Speaker 1: they had dumplings.
Speaker 1: three dollars, so it was like ten dollar.
Speaker 1: gets you chicken and rice.
Speaker 0: How many dumplings for three dollars or not too bad Midtown?
Speaker 0: It's like seven dollars for three or four dumplings.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's actually a dumpling truck.
Speaker 1: the charges more than that.
Speaker 0: of course Emily's got it the best in Chinatown.
Speaker 0: It's like give me a dollar.
Speaker 0: I'll give you more dumplings than you can possibly eat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway the dumplings are pretty good.
Speaker 1: They had so you know dispense your own dumpling sauce whatever.
Speaker 1: But the chicken was also quite good.
Speaker 1: It was you know high quality fried chicken leg all right?
Speaker 0: I'm curious if it's going anywhere other than I ate it.
Speaker 0: a really good food truck.
Speaker 1: No But they not the best part of it right?
Speaker 1: was it the way they had prepared this?
Speaker 1: somehow?
Speaker 1: Alright with the chicken on top of the rice?
Speaker 1: is that the rice ended up absorbing all of this fried chicken grease?
Speaker 1: So it was like it wasn't sticky rice.
Speaker 1: right because it wasn't sticky.
Speaker 1: It was you know as sticky as rice is it was.
Speaker 1: it was so key rice, but the the the intense absorbed grease flavor.
Speaker 1: It tasted like sticky rice times two powers even though its stickiness was not at that level.
Speaker 0: I really suddenly want sticky rice, so it's like I ate some dumplings.
Speaker 1: I was like good dumplings.
Speaker 1: I ate some chicken.
Speaker 1: I was like all right good fried.
Speaker 0: It's like in that atomic, and then I eat the rice.
Speaker 1: I was like all right.
Speaker 1: It's not good.
Speaker 0: It's like when I was in that atomic trivia show and row was like yeah, Dave Riley Just said that he's eating chicken chicken.
Speaker 0: sure yeah, he's like chicken euros.
Speaker 0: He's like you all want them right now Don't you?
Speaker 0: chicken euros with tzatziki sauce?
Speaker 1: I had a falafel with everything last night, huh?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I ate at five napkin last night, huh, I really needed some burgers.
Speaker 1: They don't actually require five napkins now, but they require Talk about your false advertising.
Speaker 0: They really require 1.5 napkins.
Speaker 1: I can say that it would require Less than one napkin if they would just give you a bun that didn't suck.
Speaker 0: how come nobody can make buns that don't suck.
Speaker 1: even The burger truck that I go to has the excellent buns excellent really excellent, or just really good like the best.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's the best.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, I don't know best.
Speaker 0: I mean best is when you're getting into the territory of like custom Kaiser roll situation.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you what the truck is gonna be at 50-something Park.
Speaker 1: You can go over to it.
Speaker 0: I will go over to it.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you what you go follow it on Twitter, and you'll go over there.
Speaker 0: so not that long ago.
Speaker 0: I bought up Adobe CS4 well with Emily because I needed premiere as shitty as it is and I bought audition separately because Adobe was I knew better.
Speaker 1: I never pay for any Adobe product.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I needed audition, and I actually really did need Photoshop.
Speaker 1: It's gonna run the pirated shit inside of a virtual machine.
Speaker 0: I use Photoshop enough to where I kind of wanted it legit on my computer.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna pirate it inside a virtual machine mainly because the gimp Really actually sucks.
Speaker 0: You could use you use paint dotnet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because that also actually really sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it can.
Speaker 1: yeah, it can make funny Photoshop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not gonna make that impact font.
Speaker 1: It's all good.
Speaker 0: See I realized that the the line between professional like needing real software and not for drawing for me at least came down to CMYK.
Speaker 0: if I actually have to interface with printers anyone who's print stuff I really can't get away with anything open source because it just can't do it.
Speaker 1: only only send them PDFs.
Speaker 0: It'll always work And most people good printers won't accept anything like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if they do and what you're burning?
Speaker 0: uh no.
Speaker 0: and even if they do Usually they'll require the PDF to be in very specific Formats with Pantone colors and all this stuff that you just can't do with open source.
Speaker 0: pay someone else to do all your photoshopping Yeah, or and you know what places like that cost four to ten times as much.
Speaker 0: There's a reason I can buy like a thousand to five thousand full-color two-sided glossy postcards for like 30 bucks Because I do all the work Except the printing.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but they announced there's gonna be.
Speaker 0: see creative suite.
Speaker 1: 5 0.5 is wait.
Speaker 1: So you have four.
Speaker 0: I have full.
Speaker 1: five is already out.
Speaker 0: So five came out recently.
Speaker 0: I bought four near the end of its fucking life.
Speaker 0: Good job, which is fine because apparently there's some sort of amnesty thing where I can get an upgrade for cheap or whatever.
Speaker 0: I look into that.
Speaker 0: but so 5.5 introduces the subscription model, which is basically does that mean you?
Speaker 1: it's actually affordable.
Speaker 1: It's like 70 to 100 something a month forever a month forever Yeah, but that you for that amount of money you could just get it.
Speaker 1: What's the actual price per month?
Speaker 0: Fuck, uh, it depends on which one you get, you know, they have like a million different packages.
Speaker 0: Okay, Jesus Christ, I mean I have production can use this I needed like audition.
Speaker 1: and for me What if you?
Speaker 1: what if I just want?
Speaker 1: Photoshop is like five bucks a month.
Speaker 0: It's like 30 30 for 30.
Speaker 1: I can get like three $10 games on Steam forever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the subscription model is not.
Speaker 0: I'll give them $30 a year prices ignore what they're actually charging.
Speaker 0: Because of the fact the subscription model I think is a great idea for this kind of software because They're in a situation where you would like to make improvements.
Speaker 0: But the software is already good enough for the majority of its users to where they'll never buy it again
Speaker 1: Mmm,
Speaker 0: and they have a model currently where if you buy it again And you don't buy every iteration along the way you have to buy the whole thing again And it's a lot of money.
Speaker 0: So a lot of people I know we're still on cs2 or cs3 Mmm, so a subscription model would make sense because then you're basically paying Adobe Adobe to continually improve the product forever even if they don't make like these monumental improvements anymore.
Speaker 0: And you know you get support even though their support is kind of useless.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you don't actually need those improvements You could just buy a version and use it for 10 years and you'll actually save a lot of money.
Speaker 0: So occasionally you might need the improvements because like if you look at premiere from several versions, right?
Speaker 0: But you think it's like sucks more which is amazing.
Speaker 0: that that is possible, right?
Speaker 1: But do you really need the improvements?
Speaker 1: like obviously any improvement if you're actually doing real work We'll make things easier on you.
Speaker 0: Well, here's my thing.
Speaker 1: How do you get the job done without that improvement?
Speaker 1: and would that improvement help you enough to be worth the exorbitant price?
Speaker 1: You have to pay.
Speaker 0: here's the thing.
Speaker 0: one for enterprise.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, this will save you a half hour for $300 Scott One.
Speaker 0: you're forgetting that if you're a company if you're large if you're a company, of course just pay for everything.
Speaker 0: Who gives a shit even for individuals if you have money or you're like self-employed and generating revenue?
Speaker 0: It's really nice.
Speaker 1: if you're rich just buy everything duh.
Speaker 1: We're talking about people who aren't rich.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's all I'm saying is that you upgrade when there's a feature you need or you upgrade a lot.
Speaker 0: I learned this.
Speaker 0: a lot of people when I was tweeting were responding to me and emailing me.
Speaker 0: The main reason they keep upgrading is that they do design work for clients who themselves?
Speaker 0: Always always upgrade to the newest version immediately and then have backwards compatibility problems Mmm and forward compatibility for that on purpose.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they do.
Speaker 0: So basically Jackasses upgrade.
Speaker 0: so the people the designers who have to support the jackasses then have to upgrade even though neither one of them needed Anything in the upgrade Adobe made them made it purposefully incompatible with the previous versions that forced those cross upgrades.
Speaker 0: Yeah office is slightly better at that than Adobe.
Speaker 0: They're less evil though.
Speaker 0: I still disagree with anyway.
Speaker 0: What at least is good is that I had to buy audition separately about audition a long time ago because you know cool edit didn't So well anymore.
Speaker 0: on modern computers an audition is 90% the same as cool edit.
Speaker 0: I'm not really getting anything for my money.
Speaker 0: It costs a lot more than cool that it did.
Speaker 0: but They thought they had sound booth, which was basically if you're an idiot and know nothing about audio But you were required to interact with audio in order to make video or some other thing work.
Speaker 0: It was like the baby version of audition.
Speaker 1: You're better off using audacity Worse than audacity, but it cost.
Speaker 0: how much money like 70 bucks.
Speaker 0: Okay, Jesus wasn't that much money But for somebody $70 more than audacity They included it with all the sweets like.
Speaker 0: premier premium came with sound booth and audition was completely separate and didn't integrate at all Mm-hmm, which was stupid.
Speaker 0: and I remember reading on Adobe forums.
Speaker 0: A lot of people were like, yeah audition is gonna be end of life sound booth is so much better.
Speaker 0: Well, no actually sound booth is now end of life and gone because it was stupid.
Speaker 0: and now audition is the only audios software in Adobe land which is good.
Speaker 0: and for the first time in fuck ever they seem to have added a real feature Which I'm kind of amazed.
Speaker 1: what real feature could they possibly add?
Speaker 0: surround sound support, right?
Speaker 1: So they finally added a real feature something that they should have added ten years ago.
Speaker 0: So you say they should have added it.
Speaker 0: name any audio editing software That has surround sound support like real like.
Speaker 0: I can just do 5.1 and DTS and whatever.
Speaker 1: Some of the open source ones theoretically have it.
Speaker 1: if you're a god, you can make it work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's in there somewhere in the same way that latex is a 100% replacement for word.
Speaker 0: That's right Technically, correct the best kind of correct but they added a feature and For a second.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh surround sound.
Speaker 1: and then you know, no one has surround sound working properly except Scott Rubin.
Speaker 0: It doesn't buy you that much.
Speaker 1: he actually buys you a lot when it when you get something that's that, you know, correct.
Speaker 0: like what?
Speaker 1: You put a DVD with actual surround sound in my in the Xbox versus you know Watching something on Netflix streaming.
Speaker 1: big difference.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I watch everything on Netflix streaming.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like when you're in the movie theater and you know, the star is sure it comes from behind it works.
Speaker 1: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Of course you could do this.
Speaker 1: It's not the thing.
Speaker 1: is the thing with surround sound?
Speaker 1: you say there is a difference that how big is the difference?
Speaker 1: kind of big?
Speaker 1: It's not enormously big right, but it's big.
Speaker 1: The thing is it's just so cheap.
Speaker 1: It's not like, you know a 3d TV with the glasses.
Speaker 1: that'll cost you thousands.
Speaker 1: You can get surround sound working properly for like a couple hundreds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's.
Speaker 1: and if you don't have a sound system already, why the fuck not?
Speaker 1: Honestly, the only reason the main problem is that a lot of people actually do have surround sound But they don't actually know how it works and they hook it up wrong.
Speaker 0: Usually they have center channel coming out of all their speak or they don't set it up properly and it's it's actually this.
Speaker 1: You know, it takes knowing and doing to actually get it to work, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway, it's supported Which is interesting because that super HD camera that I have that we've been doing our videos with and actually records five audio tracks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but how does it record five audio tracks from one microphone up?
Speaker 0: It has five microphones really?
Speaker 0: Yeah directional now.
Speaker 1: But the thing is you would need five microphones two behind you and three in front of you.
Speaker 0: Uh, they just point in different directions.
Speaker 0: That's usually how you record surround sound.
Speaker 0: In fact, I can do stereo Scott stereo miking.
Speaker 0: What do I do?
Speaker 0: I take two mics and I put them in like an X.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's stereo.
Speaker 1: They were talking about surround.
Speaker 1: You got to get the front and the back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not.
Speaker 1: I point to what part of the camera is behind the thing that you're filming.
Speaker 0: Uh, Scott usually surround sound is relative to where the camera is But in the soundscape, but you know, the idea is that surround right you yes, so you'd it knows What was the audio coming to the front?
Speaker 0: What was the other coming from the back?
Speaker 0: If you master it, right, it's almost indistinguishable from having point sources in all those places.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you'll hear what's going on behind the camera where no one can see.
Speaker 1: the thing is you want the things that you know Are behind what you're looking at, but oh
Speaker 0: You're saying that what you want to do is make a pseudo Realistic acoustic environment to make the scene feel more realistic without doing actual Surround of what the real scene was like kind of like Foley where you make the fake sounds that sound more real than the Real sounds in a movie.
Speaker 1: That's what you can do with audition now Yeah, but I'm saying you can't do it with your camera, uh, if all the microphones are in the camera Scott because it doesn't matter It does man because you don't do that for movies or anything.
Speaker 0: you do that in the audio software.
Speaker 0: after the fact if I want to record surround sound with my camera What it does is it gets a surround picture that will translate into surround sound.
Speaker 0: So if I play it through a surround system I hear audio coming from behind me.
Speaker 0: that became from behind the camera and from in front of me.
Speaker 0: that came from in front of the And because of the amplitude of all these different things ain't all the different mics?
Speaker 0: It's as though I'm standing where the camera was right.
Speaker 1: But you don't want it to be as though you're standing where the camera was.
Speaker 1: you want it to sound like Where the character in the film is standing not where you.
Speaker 0: not always it depends on what you're doing It's true.
Speaker 1: But I mean for example though, right you're seeing the star destroyer come from up above?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Scott, but you don't want the sound.
Speaker 0: I'm not understanding what you're trying to argue because if I'm making a movie I'm just gonna do all the audio after the fact.
Speaker 0: anyway Cuz there isn't a real star destroyer coming over for me to have a microphone to pick up if you're pointing the video camera I don't need a microphone on Han Solo's butt because the Star Destroyer is not coming.
Speaker 0: There's no real Star Destroyer Scott.
Speaker 0: It's not real.
Speaker 1: if you say if you had you're pointing your video camera at a helicopter, right?
Speaker 1: You want sound from the helicopter to sound like, you know to come from behind and also the front but since the can't Helicopter is completely in front of Scott.
Speaker 0: Well, it's only hearing it from the front Usually if I'm pointing the camera at a helicopter it's because I'm showing a scene of a helicopter, right?
Speaker 0: Usually you want the audio coming from perspective perspective of the camera unless you're doing it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you wanted to come from where the person is standing, but there's no person There's a helicopter.
Speaker 1: the person in the house.
Speaker 0: Scott Have you ever watched a movie?
Speaker 0: if a helicopter flies by you hear the audio go left to right?
Speaker 0: Yeah in front of you not behind you.
Speaker 0: No, it would be straight on top of you But it's not straight on top of you.
Speaker 1: No, because even though you're looking at it on the screen it's whatever Scott you don't get it.
Speaker 0: No, I do get high.
Speaker 1: fighter comes over the top, right?
Speaker 1: You see the TIE fighter but it still sounds like it's behind you because it's still at the top of the movie screen.
Speaker 1: and then when it gets to the Bottom of the movie screen and it's all the way forward then it sounds like it's in front of you.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, so high fighter is still on screen.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry you but it still sounds like it's behind you because it's still on its way forward.
Speaker 0: yeah,
Speaker 1: and if you're all the if all the microphones are in the camera and the tie fighter comes over the top the TIE fighters already in front of you when that by the time it's at the top of your shot and that it already sounds like It's in front of you when it should still sound like it's behind you
Speaker 0: because that's fake effects as opposed to recording the action.
Speaker 1: That's why you surround sound for when you're awake in a movie.
Speaker 0: No Because this most consumer cameras are starting to have surround sound support because people record the actual immersive environment of the camera.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't want that.
Speaker 0: I just let you make a nature film.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure what you're trying to argue.
Speaker 1: So anyway, you don't want all the cameras in the microphone.
Speaker 0: Actually in most cases that anyone using a hand camera has I mean all the microphones in the camera now, yeah you do.
Speaker 1: No, you don't.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So do you have any news?
Speaker 1: I do have this excellent news.
Speaker 1: You ready for this is actually fascinating.
Speaker 1: All right, so 323 years ago This guy named William Molyneux.
Speaker 1: I don't know if he's related to Peter Molyneux, but doesn't matter, right?
Speaker 1: He wrote a letter to someone, you know, John Locke and he said hey John Locke.
Speaker 1: What's up?
Speaker 1: And John Locke was a good.
Speaker 1: What's going on?
Speaker 1: And he says hey Imagine there was a blind person right and this blind person Had a cube and a sphere and the blind person felt up the sphere real good with their hands and they felt up the cube Real good with their hands, right?
Speaker 1: so the blind person knows that his fear looks like and they know what a Sphere feels like and they know what a cube feels like.
Speaker 1: but they obviously don't know what they look like.
Speaker 1: They've been blind since birth.
Speaker 1: They'd never seen a sphere.
Speaker 1: They've never seen a cube.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right now imagine this blind person knows what a sphere looks like feels like and can identify a sphere.
Speaker 1: All right, they could.
Speaker 1: you could hand them an object and say what's this sphere or cube and they could say sphere by feeling You know, but not by looking because they're blind.
Speaker 1: They've always been blind.
Speaker 1: They've never seen one.
Speaker 1: then you give them their sight back.
Speaker 1: Okay, so now they can see again and you show them a sphere and a cube.
Speaker 1: you don't let them touch Right and you say which one is the sphere and which one is the cube they can see for the first time.
Speaker 0: Well, we know in modern times what happens.
Speaker 1: they've they felt a sphere and they felt a cube, but they've never seen them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right But now they got their sight back and you show them a sphere in a cube.
Speaker 1: Can they identify which one is the sphere and which one is the cube without touching?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: no because every study I've seen shows that people who regain sight who never had it before Really can't parse what they're seeing if they experience something that doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 1: Well, basically they no one actually had any idea.
Speaker 1: There was basically arguings of nature versus nurture and all sorts of night and nobody knew until Actually just now this study that just came out.
Speaker 1: and what they did is they they had a hard time finding Because it is possible to cure some kinds of blindness.
Speaker 1: But the problem is that a lot of the kinds of blindness that are from birth in the Western world Especially we cure them immediately, right?
Speaker 1: You know you when you're like a little baby so you can see at you know day two if you can paraphrase arguments We had all weekend.
Speaker 0: Skinner box is the answer, right?
Speaker 1: So what they did though is they actually went to poor places like in India and such and they found some people who are blind since birth but curable.
Speaker 1: and They did this and it turns out that no, they can't tell the sphere from the cube
Speaker 0: as expected
Speaker 1: but After like a very short amount of time like weeks, maybe a couple months They can tell huh,
Speaker 0: that makes sense even
Speaker 1: at even if they're actually pretty pretty old like eight to 17 years old, whatever
Speaker 0: Ancient.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, I mean that's that's a long time to be blind 17 years, right?
Speaker 1: They can figure they can you know, they can reconnect they're seeing to their feeling senses after just regaining their seeing senses after never having them ever and Then they can feel and see the cube and the sphere, you know at the same time Not bad.
Speaker 0: Now the question is can they walk in a straight line?
Speaker 1: No that the point.
Speaker 1: no, but the point is right.
Speaker 1: The reason it's so fascinating is because you know, there there are lots, you know for the longest time people kept thinking You know the brain stops developing, you know, it develops a whole bunch when you're young and then it doesn't you know It slows down.
Speaker 1: but more and more all the evidence is showing that like now the brain really doesn't stop It's it's going all the time.
Speaker 0: I read so far.
Speaker 1: You can learn stuff when you're old.
Speaker 0: Not that long ago that was talking about the fact that there's a strong correlation between how much sleep you feel that you need not so necessarily how much you get but how much you need and how much you're continuing to learn things.
Speaker 0: because generally people sleep a lot when they're young and it kind of peters off when they get older and old.
Speaker 0: like really old people often only sleep five six hours a night and There's a possibility that they need less sleep because they're learning less and the brain needs to do less at night.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 0: It was just a neat thing.
Speaker 0: I don't remember even where I read it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know This is like a lot of people.
Speaker 1: the other thing the article talks about is how you know A lot of people think that this is idea of when you're a child.
Speaker 1: There's these critical periods.
Speaker 1: So like if your brain is fucked up, it's like oh, that's it.
Speaker 1: You know We had this one chance where you had all this potential and you were.
Speaker 1: you were like clay and then you get hard.
Speaker 1: Well, that's really not nearly as true as it is.
Speaker 1: We thought it was, you know, your your brain is clay It doesn't.
Speaker 1: it's not like.
Speaker 1: there's no like period where up.
Speaker 1: It's in the kiln the game over.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That does not happen.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean let me know.
Speaker 0: I mean your brain is clearly wood as opposed to my magnificent marble brain.
Speaker 0: I'm sure.
Speaker 1: So I do want to talk about yes My wood brain that will continue to grow and get sunlight and water and your marble brain that is already Perfect and hard and will and small and smooth.
Speaker 1: Hey, no wrinkles in it and impenetrable and stubborn and non-growing and not adapting.
Speaker 0: so Google's algorithms lost a defamation lawsuit in the EU and this is Actually really disturbing and bad news for technology around the world and free speech.
Speaker 0: Basically what happened is that in the US we have libel and slander laws, but they're pretty weak.
Speaker 0: Well, they're.
Speaker 0: I think they're actually fairly strong, but then there were their weak relative.
Speaker 0: They're very strong in that they're well constructed because at its core libel and slander a primary solid defense against being accused of any of these in the courts is Truth, it's not liable if you're right and you can demonstrate it.
Speaker 0: It's not slander if the thing you said is true.
Speaker 0: I mean Scott has a tiny penis.
Speaker 1: It's a slander right there.
Speaker 1: now clearly if I go have measured.
Speaker 0: So if we go to court right and I've said Scott's penis is tiny and he says no, that's not true.
Speaker 0: It's slanderous when I demonstrate to the court that in fact it is tiny I get off.
Speaker 1: Yeah You get off on tiny penises we not getting off on mine.
Speaker 0: So in the EU especially in Britain this is not the case and I'm not a lawyer but everything I read indicates that libel and slander laws in most of Europe are just the worst there They're.
Speaker 1: I can't even describe how outrageous they are, but they balance off because they also have like, you know, the a lot more They balance out judicial discussion.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're litigious over there You're just gonna get fucked because you know, they got stuff like loser pays and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Whereas over here You know, we don't have.
Speaker 1: if we have Trade we got a trade.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the EU has you know safe harbor provisions where if I'm say a search engine and you find something slander is through me.
Speaker 0: It's not slander on my part.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's obviously the but Google had autocomplete autocomplete autocompleted someone's name with if you kept typing words like con man and fraud and as far as I can tell the person because a bunch of people Research is a con.
Speaker 0: Yes, there's no doubt so Google was sued under the grounds that because Google created that content as opposed to simply reporting it that they were liable for libel.
Speaker 1: Yeah lawyer doesn't know computers.
Speaker 0: Uh Well, the lawyer did know the law.
Speaker 0: judge didn't know computers as did the judge because the laws are stupid and because autocomplete was Supposedly information created by Google that did not exist on the internet itself That they are in fact guilty and they already lost the lawsuit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, they got an appeal or something And this is what I mean, it bothers me.
Speaker 1: the EU's just refuse to pay.
Speaker 1: What are they gonna do?
Speaker 0: Google has a corporate presence in the EU and a several that would be very difficult to shut down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so what are they gonna do?
Speaker 0: Uh, they're gonna have to pay giant fine.
Speaker 1: No, I mean, what if you just don't pay?
Speaker 1: What are they gonna do?
Speaker 0: Uh The same thing they do to anyone who doesn't pay which is uh, it's lost.
Speaker 0: these assets arrest people whatever Law, who can you arrest?
Speaker 1: It's a company.
Speaker 1: You got a wrestler page.
Speaker 0: They could shut down the company in Spain For example, they could issue an injunction against Google.
Speaker 1: So the thing is they don't actually need to be in Spain.
Speaker 1: They just have computers.
Speaker 0: They have people in Spain - you realize they just have all the people leave Spain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they could try to pull out all that, you know, shut down all of their presences in Europe.
Speaker 0: That's a stupid and laughable idea.
Speaker 1: No, you can keep the presence.
Speaker 0: Just keep move the computers out and the people out and then people in Europe still Google Yeah, but then you don't have a presence in the country for a lot of other useful reasons.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, it's a terrible idea.
Speaker 0: Scott is he follows Google.
Speaker 1: I would buy an island and just be like no one could touch me with any law.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what island are you going to buy and make an island?
Speaker 1: Uh-huh?
Speaker 0: So use the water for the trouble is the EU has been doing this a lot lately and there are tons of antitrust Lawsuits coming out of Europe against people like Google and Microsoft.
Speaker 0: that They're laughable.
Speaker 0: There's no other way to describe them.
Speaker 0: It's like Europe is collectively trying to stop any technological company for doing anything cool on the internet.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is right is look at what's going on, right?
Speaker 1: All the big tech companies are in the US Japan, right?
Speaker 1: Europe had what Nokia.
Speaker 1: it was just going to.
Speaker 0: We also despite the problems.
Speaker 0: We always complain about with the US increasingly becoming kind of draconian about the internet We have the freest internet of most of the world because we have
Speaker 1: any free internet
Speaker 0: because we have some of the strongest protections for free speech of any place in the world and Yet at the same time much of the rest of the world does not have these protections
Speaker 1: And their Internet's way faster.
Speaker 0: and because the internet is primarily a US thing We're starting to.
Speaker 1: our companies are starting to butt heads with you know, Europe and Australia Basically, I think they're basically just trying to tax US companies, you know, it's like they can't really.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like all these companies in the US.
Speaker 1: so, you know, Google Facebook everyone's over here.
Speaker 1: So we're making out and they're not making out so well, and we're kicking their asses, you know Apple destroying Nokia and everything.
Speaker 0: so anyway, this particular case is actually Italian though there was the Spanish one that was very similar recently and Technologically my take on is pretty simple Autocomplete is no different than doing a survey of people.
Speaker 0: if I was in Spain or Italy or the EU somewhere and I did a survey is Scott Does Scott have a tiny penis?
Speaker 0: and you know say 80% of respondents said yes.
Speaker 0: That's not really libelous of me who has done a scientific study or a poll.
Speaker 0: That's libelous.
Speaker 1: I should be able to sue all of you because they're all libelous the individual people who said yes Maybe all the people at once in a class action.
Speaker 0: There is no way you can convince me that Google's autocomplete is any different than a survey.
Speaker 1: No, the survey takers is off scot-free But I all the people who wrote the wrong thing on the survey knowing it was the results will be published Which now?
Speaker 0: this is why I love technology because alright the law should be that which is great because Individual people out there trying to shut them down would be like whack-a-mole Streisand effect and we win in the end.
Speaker 1: Anyway, well, how about this?
Speaker 1: Here's a good question, right?
Speaker 1: What if you you someone asks you, right?
Speaker 1: How much you know is something worth and you have no idea and you just guess and you guess wrong?
Speaker 1: is that libel?
Speaker 0: Well libel it would remember libel at least in the u.s Or slander requires malice and harm.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: No in Europe, it's basically right.
Speaker 1: so in Europe what if you don't, you know lie, but you just guess wrong I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm not a lawyer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because it's like that's basically what Google did.
Speaker 1: is they just?
Speaker 1: they just guess?
Speaker 1: they guessed, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like if you guess right or wrong, you know, it's like you're just guessing.
Speaker 1: can you be held liable for slander or libel?
Speaker 1: if you You know just guess as opposed to knowingly lie with intent to harm and such and such.
Speaker 0: I guess There is that EU.
Speaker 0: you're on notice.
Speaker 0: I'm watching you.
Speaker 0: I I tire of this bullshit.
Speaker 0: I like the EU in general and it has many benefits over say the United States.
Speaker 1: But when it comes to law as fucked up as our laws often are why isn't there just one at least one fucking country in The world where the shit is not fucked up, Scandinavia.
Speaker 0: It's still fucked up there this part of the EU Yeah, but I feel like it's less fucked up overall.
Speaker 1: I mean there are places that are less however, however But I'm saying why isn't there a single place that has no fuck-ups?
Speaker 0: Well Scott, here's my worst problem.
Speaker 0: The places with the least fuck-ups are also the coldest fucking places I know right.
Speaker 1: We need a tropical place with no fuck-up.
Speaker 0: I just need Manhattan in.
Speaker 1: I don't know the Bahamas and Manhattan should be its own country.
Speaker 0: Yes with internet.
Speaker 0: Yes, the internet in fact is in Manhattan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so things of the day we had friends out this weekend.
Speaker 0: Phil and she a were hanging out playing games and go to the mocha and everything but Phil showed us a video of Douglas Adams giving a speech and I had never seen this speech.
Speaker 0: I didn't know much about it.
Speaker 1: I'd never seen it either.
Speaker 0: it was a talk and it was also about one of his books that I'd never read.
Speaker 1: I'd never heard of.
Speaker 0: most people have only known of Douglas Adams because of the hitchhiker's guide And all the questions at the end of the video are horrible.
Speaker 0: I'll get to that.
Speaker 0: Parrots the universe and everything.
Speaker 0: This is just a fantastic talk by Douglas Adams about parrots the universe komodo dragons and Everything.
Speaker 0: trying to buy rubber rovers in China lemurs Hi eyes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just it's great.
Speaker 0: And the thing is I used to always say that Douglas Adams was a really good writer and I have to take that back.
Speaker 0: He is not a great writer.
Speaker 0: What he is is a great orator and his books are just writing down the things that he would have said.
Speaker 0: Yep, he is an amazing order.
Speaker 0: It's a very rarely.
Speaker 0: we try to watch TED talks often with the crew and we have people over and usually a Subset of the crew get bored pretty readily or don't want to watch something that's longer than 30 seconds.
Speaker 0: But uh, this held everyone's attention for a full hour.
Speaker 1: Well, there was nobody there.
Speaker 1: who was the the kind of person who would lose their attention?
Speaker 1: It wasn't like all those other people were there who are like.
Speaker 1: we can only watch things that are 10 minutes or are just really Lame and full of jokes every two seconds because our attention span.
Speaker 0: this is not a TED talk But it is effect.
Speaker 1: It is effect on the TED website.
Speaker 0: It's been like honored.
Speaker 0: It is now like an honorary TED talk.
Speaker 0: they're basically doing this best of the web like this is Basically as good as a TED talk if not better.
Speaker 1: It's better than any TED talks we have available and ready to post for you right now So we'll post that instead.
Speaker 0: when he stops talking Some questions happen and they're all retarded.
Speaker 0: if I were you I would watch the first two people who ask questions and listen to their questions because they nothing has changed in the last I don't know several decades because The questions are basically along the lines of.
Speaker 0: so you gave this talk and I didn't care about it at all.
Speaker 0: but what I really want to ask about is Some lame joke about the hitchhiker's guide towel towel towel.
Speaker 1: He It's like I'm.
Speaker 1: I give him props for not just being like shut up cuz that's what I do.
Speaker 1: I'm just like dude your question sucks goes nobody can ask questions like it amazes me.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna tell you all a secret.
Speaker 0: at every packs We have or any con where we have actually decided to take questions all of them suck.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, no, okay, we get good ones, but most of the time I can't hear you.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I literally just listen until I hear a proper mumble mumble mumble proper now And then I give an answer that is vaguely related to the proper noun Mm-hmm, and if you've heard me answering questions or Scott answering questions on stage, that'll probably explain a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but really this is amazing and the questions that are asked at the end are typical amazing me bad Alright, so yeah, so check this out.
Speaker 1: I don't know You know, I'm not really that OCD but you know, there are some times you get a little bit like, you know Some like.
Speaker 1: sometimes I'll step on cracks on the sidewalk.
Speaker 1: No problem.
Speaker 1: And sometimes I'll be like up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what do you what do you do if you're at someone's house and they put the toilet paper on the wrong way?
Speaker 0: Like it's just under?
Speaker 1: oh, you know, I don't know why people have this problem with the under over.
Speaker 1: I don't even notice whether it's under over really.
Speaker 0: we debated about that for about 40 minutes the other night.
Speaker 0: I don't even notice whether it's under over at all because here's the thing the vast majority of Americans do it over I know and it's mostly women who do it under uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I don't even like.
Speaker 1: when I put a new roll on there I just grab a roll put the thing through it and snap it on without even looking and when I grab for the toilet paper I don't even look at the.
Speaker 1: you know anyway, so if you're OCD or even just tiny bit OCD or really OCD here is Very reasonably priced $25 wooden cutting board.
Speaker 1: It looks to be a high-quality cutting board.
Speaker 1: it is 9 by 12, which is a good size for cutting board and It had.
Speaker 1: it is ruled very precisely with.
Speaker 1: you know Vertical and horizontal lines and measurements so you can cut your carrots or celery to exact specifications.
Speaker 1: If your knife is sharp, it's pretty great.
Speaker 1: It's pretty cool reasonably priced and also a cutting board.
Speaker 1: So if you need a cutting board Why not get this one?
Speaker 0: it's fun and nerdy and of course the meta moment.
Speaker 0: We will be at anime Boston April 22nd 23rd and 24th in fourth in Boston.
Speaker 1: That's coming up real soon.
Speaker 0: Yep, we're doing a bunch of panels all that stuff.
Speaker 0: Darryl Strad anime world order Gerald.
Speaker 0: I assume Clarissa I didn't actually ask them who's coming Like tools gonna beat their every nerd.
Speaker 1: it'll be nerd paradise.
Speaker 0: So if you are there aside from our panels if you want to just play board games We're gonna be doing a lot of that.
Speaker 1: Ah, we're gonna be anime.
Speaker 1: Boston does have a tabletop room.
Speaker 1: it is kind of small and usually kind of quiet.
Speaker 1: We will either be mostly kids playing Magic the Gathering and munchkin.
Speaker 0: We'll either be there or we'll get a posse and we'll go to the hotel like right in the area.
Speaker 0: Well, it's it's in the hotel.
Speaker 0: Yeah the tabletop, but we'll go to like the lobby of the Sheraton Yeah, and we'll play some games there.
Speaker 1: I think I think the tabletop room itself will be fine.
Speaker 0: It depends.
Speaker 0: it depends on how much of a posse we get.
Speaker 0: anyway The book club book was Michio Kaku cyberspace.
Speaker 0: the episode on that is up.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It is now foundation.
Speaker 0: foundation Should read foundation.
Speaker 0: I have not read foundation only the first one.
Speaker 1: There's like a bunch of them.
Speaker 1: make sure you get the first one.
Speaker 1: number one foundation.
Speaker 1: Any other metas?
Speaker 1: Oh, you should follow us on Twitter like go to twitter.com.
Speaker 1: slash geek nights because not enough people follow us on Twitter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess.
Speaker 1: and we supposed to post you when there's new episodes and it posts old episodes and things.
Speaker 0: But you gotta make this all high-energy like we're gonna be at anime Boston.
Speaker 0: Be sure to follow us on Twitter.
Speaker 1: What else are we gonna be at?
Speaker 1: We're going to PAX West the week before Labor Day.
Speaker 0: Been like if you enjoy geek guys, you should be following us at geek nights on Twitter.
Speaker 0: We have an awesome rockin forum.
Speaker 0: A lot of people have been joining lately.
Speaker 0: It's kind of an ivory tower of the internet.
Speaker 0: got to be very assertive like Fluttershy.
Speaker 0: So we did that show a little while ago on reading logs and the response as in the questions people emailed me and the questions people post in the forum made me realize that When we did a couple of shows on like system administration and the system administrators toolkit and like the things you need to know Like, you know grep or VI or you know reading logs var log Linux I think we have a lot more ground that needs to be covered.
Speaker 0: I don't think people actually know how to administer systems.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, yeah, but I mean how we could talk about that for years and years and years.
Speaker 1: But I think be kind of boring if you just be like, okay So this is how to use this command and this is how to use this command.
Speaker 1: But something is how to use this tool.
Speaker 0: what really bothered me what got me was someone in the forum and they had a good Question.
Speaker 0: they were like, yeah, I totally use logs to save the day.
Speaker 0: I'm paraphrasing and I'm not making fun of you dude because Most big companies in the world even tech companies don't even get to the point that you got of checking the logs.
Speaker 0: so, you know servers having trouble and they could like tech guy like couldn't figure it out.
Speaker 0: and finally someone thinks to look in the windows event log and they see that like one of the arrays like the raid had a disc that had failed and there was Fragmentation and a big problem.
Speaker 0: and oh shit.
Speaker 0: and they replaced it and fixed everything.
Speaker 0: and they're the heroes.
Speaker 0: but this of course raises the question that Why wouldn't you have known about this ahead of time?
Speaker 0: and I realized that Almost everyone I have ever met hardware guys software guys software engineers computer science versus IT.
Speaker 0: Nobody knows what SNMP is let alone how to use it.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean a lot of people have monitoring systems in place, right?
Speaker 1: But some of the monitoring systems are like, you know Most of them actually are prepackaged things that might use SNMP without exposing the user to the fact that it's being used.
Speaker 1: Oh and some of them actually use really stupid methods or you know Not completely useless but much dumber methods than SNMP like to make sure the server is up.
Speaker 1: Just ping it once every few seconds or make sure the website's up.
Speaker 1: So try to load the home page once every minute, you know.
Speaker 1: And then send an email if it doesn't load or if there's a server error.
Speaker 0: Yep Now the worst part is that most of the monitoring that people use out of the box like you buy a Dell server you get Dell OpenManage or Windows.
Speaker 0: it's I think RDM.
Speaker 0: I forget even because I only work with Dell stuff now So I forgot all the other proper nouns for all the other types of servers.
Speaker 0: But there's software that you install that can monitor everything.
Speaker 0: so like if there's a problem you log into the console through the web and you can see like oh the array has failed or That fan has died or say there's a lot of them IBM servers.
Speaker 0: I don't have this.
Speaker 0: they have an amber light on the front of the box That turns on if there's trouble and then you log into a management console to see what the trouble was.
Speaker 0: the lights kind of like the check engine light.
Speaker 0: and Even prepackaged software like that is almost always reactive or passive monitoring and that it doesn't tell you there's a problem.
Speaker 0: it's just there after you recognize there's a problem.
Speaker 0: and I want to talk very specifically about SNMP because unlike a lot of other things where There's a lot of theory I could cover and there's a lot of kind of very complex ground I can tell you in a few minutes how to use SNMP to trivially monitor anything in Linux.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know we have some monitoring stuff but like usually like for example if use Amazon You know Amazon Web Services, you can pay for CloudWatch Which is monitoring and it monitors your CPU usage and your memory usage and disk activity.
Speaker 1: So does it money just but from your perspective all it is is a bunch of graphs and you can set it with like.
Speaker 1: You know email me of CPU usage goes over 80% for more than a minute and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: And that's that's like the extent of the kind of monitoring most people have.
Speaker 0: maybe they're a little more advanced.
Speaker 0: They use like MRTG.
Speaker 0: they install that.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 1: MRTG is basically, you know, make your own graphs on your own server.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you can set thresholds on that.
Speaker 0: Like if the number of CRC errors goes.
Speaker 0: Oh wait It doesn't even do that by default.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so a lot of these things like Monet and nagios, right you basically That you run this.
Speaker 0: the nagio system is actually pretty pretty good.
Speaker 1: But you run these systems and then you have to go out and get scripts or you know modules that monitor different things.
Speaker 1: It's like I need the MySQL database monitoring module.
Speaker 1: So you go get it and configure it and say you know what those things actually work.
Speaker 0: really well.
Speaker 0: And that's all SNMP under the hood.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So if you just get nagios and install it and use it you're using SNMP and you're already half the battle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing with SNMP.
Speaker 1: It's like they're basically they're people.
Speaker 1: It seems like very very few places use it and know that they're using it.
Speaker 1: Oh even worse.
Speaker 0: so get this whenever I talk to vendors, right like ticketing systems.
Speaker 0: I was looking at ticketing systems I want to buy like a server that does something or anything.
Speaker 0: I always ask them questions like, you know, how does it install?
Speaker 0: What's the back-end database?
Speaker 0: Can I use it on a different database?
Speaker 0: do I have to use fucking Oracle or can I put it on postgres?
Speaker 0: and all these questions and by and large No vendor I have ever talked to for any product I've ever interacted with can answer any question I've ever asked them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but one of the questions I always ask is now first I throw him a bone.
Speaker 0: I will ask so how do we monitor this?
Speaker 0: just to give them you know, maybe they have some bullshit proprietary thing Maybe they've got something I give them the chance to say Oh, well, if you want to make sure it's up and they give me some stupid procedure Usually their response is okay.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: monitor it's up it's running I mean if it stops working they just have no idea.
Speaker 1: I need an email when it goes down if I'm not there and I'm not using it.
Speaker 0: My follow-up question is usually is there a MIB?
Speaker 0: And to this day only one company has ever responded with the words.
Speaker 1: Why yes, I Mean, you know and the thing is right.
Speaker 1: so people don't even know that this is a thing, right?
Speaker 1: But then there are some other people like me where it's like, you know SNMP exists, you know It's the simple network management protocol.
Speaker 0: That's very good.
Speaker 0: You're but it'll more than 99% of humans, right?
Speaker 1: But beyond that it's like it's this thing.
Speaker 1: It's I don't really know how it works or how to see it or use it.
Speaker 1: It's like you're coming sort of like how your computer has an I squared C bus And it's like what is that bus used for?
Speaker 1: people know about the USB.
Speaker 1: they know about the serial buses.
Speaker 1: They don't know anything about the I2C bus.
Speaker 1: your computer has one and it's there and there's some stuff on it But you have no idea and nor do you know how to read it.
Speaker 1: Yep, nor could you know?
Speaker 0: The thing is I wouldn't expect like a computer scientist a coder even a software engineer I would not expect you to really know the ins and out of SNMP unless you were writing Software that was big enough to where you wanted to make your own MIB to where it could be monitored directly
Speaker 1: or software That was actually doing monitoring.
Speaker 0: true like say for example you were going to write.
Speaker 0: I don't know a demon that does Like something for our forum like it does some cool real-time thing on our forum and you wanted to get stats out of it Directly.
Speaker 0: now a lot of developers would like write CSVs or XML to a place or have counters.
Speaker 0: you can get your database.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of different ways you could do that, but you could just provide a MIB and just extend it out through SNMP And then people can hit SNMP and get the data out of your program.
Speaker 0: That doesn't interest you at all does it?
Speaker 1: no not really because you know I mean Monitoring.
Speaker 1: you know I would use it if it was for data like you know.
Speaker 1: How much memory is the program currently using up and that sort of thing?
Speaker 0: how many calls are being addressed per hour?
Speaker 1: Yeah, stuff like that, but I never need that kind of information.
Speaker 1: the kind of information I need is actually usually the applications actual information right.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna write for example a content API.
Speaker 1: You know I'm gonna do that with HTTP and JSON, I'm not gonna do that with You know.
Speaker 0: this is why SNMP is important.
Speaker 1: with SNMP and at the same time right?
Speaker 1: HTTP and JSON I could also.
Speaker 1: it's so much easier to do than SNMP which would require learning.
Speaker 0: See now this.
Speaker 0: this is the beauty of it SNMP as its primary so much more accessible is basically Hardware and software agnostic.
Speaker 0: it runs it like like.
Speaker 0: technically it's a layer 7. you know in the OSI model application It is at the top, so it can't monitor anything below itself, so this is really it monitors things below really.
Speaker 1: So if there's a problem with Mac address Because it doesn't monitor anything SNMP is nothing more than a framework right, but that's exactly I'm saying is so you have something That's monitoring problems that you know level 3 and it finds a problem.
Speaker 1: And then it sends out SNMP the but SNMP doesn't get through because level 3 is broken.
Speaker 0: Uh so Scott think about your hierarchy of monitoring.
Speaker 0: if your server doesn't have any communication at all with the outside world if SNMP stops responding or TCP stops responding you set up monitoring such that if it doesn't respond.
Speaker 0: That's the most critical alarm the server is gone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we have lost contact with it.
Speaker 0: so at that point.
Speaker 0: That's the primary alarm.
Speaker 0: say There's 10 problems at the same time.
Speaker 0: say you're using 80% of your swap space when you don't expect above a threshold right and The motherboard caught fire and the server stopped running.
Speaker 0: uh-huh One of those problems is more important than the other one.
Speaker 0: it takes precedence?
Speaker 1: Yes, of course.
Speaker 1: so if there's a problem fires preventing you from finding out about the CPU Yes, there's a.
Speaker 0: but if there's no more about the CPU if there's a more fundamental problem that you would have caught and sent over SNMP But because some thing is broken on the way you can't even send that then your system is proper fucked right.
Speaker 1: But here's the thing right.
Speaker 1: what if the problem is between for example the monitoring server the one doing the monitoring and The machine that was going to email you the alert?
Speaker 1: it's like now there's alerts, but you don't know what they are and it could be more severe than the fact that you're Monitoring server can't email anybody Scott.
Speaker 0: That's just a trivial operational concern.
Speaker 0: That's just.
Speaker 0: I mean if you're smart you set up a secondary network.
Speaker 0: That's just for monitoring and backups.
Speaker 1: What if that network you know loses access?
Speaker 1: then it'll be like oh my god.
Speaker 1: Everything is down and really everything else is working.
Speaker 1: It's just the monitoring network is busted.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know what if you're not an idiot?
Speaker 0: if that would be obvious It can happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it can happen.
Speaker 1: It's really irrelevant, but the point is is that you know monitoring You know can't always be trusted completely.
Speaker 1: a lot of people they see monitoring.
Speaker 1: You're like that.
Speaker 1: you know they get an email.
Speaker 1: They're like oh, no everything's down.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: But really you gotta be intelligent.
Speaker 0: it actually can be trusted completely if it's set up in a intelligent reasonable matter.
Speaker 0: For example say a server goes down I get an alarm a critical red alarm immediately in all the consoles of all the productions of our people that basically says This server is no longer contactable via ICMP Meaning it is dead.
Speaker 0: it cannot be reached through anything ICMP or other protocols.
Speaker 0: so assumed Is that SNMP is also not responding.
Speaker 0: assumed is that no demon can respond now at the same time if?
Speaker 0: Every server on the network simultaneously has that problem.
Speaker 0: it collapses all those into one alarm.
Speaker 0: that entire network segment stopped responding Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: so if a network segment goes down I get a network segment alarm saying that whole segment is down.
Speaker 0: Every alarm that is subordinate to that alarm is suppressed.
Speaker 0: So I won't alarm on.
Speaker 0: I can't contact the postgres server on server a or server B or server C. I also can't ping server a or server.
Speaker 0: it collapses them all into one alarm.
Speaker 0: That's just kind of the semantic design of monitoring.
Speaker 1: I don't think anyone probably nowhere in the world except your company has the monitoring setup.
Speaker 1: so yes I can safely say I don't even know if Google and Facebook and big-time data centers have the most The path I've taken through IT.
Speaker 0: the hospital had shit for monitoring, but that aside IBM and the company I work for now Probably had what I would consider best-of-breed monitoring.
Speaker 0: as in.
Speaker 0: I do legitimately believe that the way I currently monitor my servers Which I think would be improved greatly is better than the vast majority of companies in the entire world monitor anything.
Speaker 0: I'm talking ours.
Speaker 0: I'm talking hospitals.
Speaker 0: I'm talking the financial sector.
Speaker 0: I'm talking technology Google Apple everyone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've never seen monitoring that level of sophistication.
Speaker 1: I just sort of assume that the big data centers and important places have it.
Speaker 1: they don't you know They know they don't Scott.
Speaker 0: Here's the example.
Speaker 1: I mean why node and play even like big hosting companies were really smart people work.
Speaker 1: They just have like the CPU alarm to not name any names.
Speaker 0: at some point in the last seven years I was at a data center Where I happen to have some stuff in a cage and a lot of other companies have stuff in other cages.
Speaker 0: I can't get into their cages, but I can see their racks.
Speaker 0: I can see their servers Point.
Speaker 0: the first nobody has fucking labels on anything except you know me - nobody really does cable management.
Speaker 0: very well by and large three.
Speaker 0: Almost every cage that I would walk past in data centers was a rat's nest.
Speaker 0: the servers have Lights like red lights like warning.
Speaker 0: this server has a problem on almost all the servers.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's the equivalent of walking through a yard where there's a bunch of cars running and they're all brand new powerful cars.
Speaker 0: And if you look in the windows of any of them checking all have the check engine light on.
Speaker 0: Some of them are blinking and maybe one of them is just smokes coming out of the exhaust When it's off.
Speaker 0: so yeah, nobody does what I do.
Speaker 0: But you know what you all want to and it is so trivial to set this stuff up.
Speaker 0: You wouldn't even believe it.
Speaker 1: and it's all.
Speaker 1: that's the funny stuff is like some of these things.
Speaker 1: They want to charge you monies for like but to see you can get the same thing for open source and free.
Speaker 1: That's just as good if not better.
Speaker 0: so very briefly an overview of SNMP the simple network management protocol.
Speaker 0: all it is is a hierarchy.
Speaker 0: a tree of Numbered notation is kind of like an IP address that point to data.
Speaker 0: so route like one dot three dot six dot one dot Oh dot one.
Speaker 0: that's kind of like the base route for sisutil.
Speaker 0: That's like where almost everything you ever do will be one three six one Oh one.
Speaker 0: now the MIB itself is not actually the number.
Speaker 0: the number is the OID which points at like a part place of the MIB.
Speaker 0: so think of it as like a giant IP address where if I if I query on a server this one Number all the way down it ends up pointing to like the amount of virtual memory that this Particular process is using at this time.
Speaker 1: So you got to ask for the number.
Speaker 1: you get like hey you server Yeah, what give me this number?
Speaker 0: Well, there's two ways to do it.
Speaker 0: now a MIB before I get into how you do that is kind of a directory.
Speaker 0: So it basically translates those numbers into names like DNS.
Speaker 0: So it'll be basically you'll do something like, you know, sisutil dot something dot something dot CPU.
Speaker 0: Give me this is like so it's like newsgroups Yep, and for monitoring software Usually you load a MIB and then if you tell it monitor that device.
Speaker 0: it knows which particular OID values in this giant hierarchy are relevant to that device Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So a lot of the underlying.
Speaker 1: Oh, so it's so for example, you have a router, right?
Speaker 1: Well, there's a zillion numbers, but you don't need to know for example a router how much hard drive space is left.
Speaker 1: Nope, right.
Speaker 1: So you don't you ignore those numbers on the router and there's a list of numbers that are the only numbers you care.
Speaker 0: what you Do on the router is you go to Cisco and you get the MIB.
Speaker 0: they have MIBs for just all their devices.
Speaker 0: And then you do an SNMP walk or use a MIB viewer to look at it.
Speaker 0: It shows you here are all the things you can monitor and here's the current values and all your servers Mm-hmm or all your routers or what?
Speaker 1: Here are the numbers you care about on this router and we have removed all the numbers that you might will never care about on This machine.
Speaker 0: and there's cool stuff like some of them.
Speaker 0: a lot of really complex systems and Cisco devices do this pretty well Will give you multiple counts like say for like number of I don't know CRC errors like errors on packets.
Speaker 0: One value gives you the current number, you know, like every five seconds like how many.
Speaker 1: there's only so much memory.
Speaker 1: So it's not good.
Speaker 1: You can't remember this number forever.
Speaker 0: Actually Cisco routers very specifically always remember things forever.
Speaker 0: They have counters that never get reset.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: What if they overflow though?
Speaker 0: Uh, I don't know.
Speaker 0: They're really big.
Speaker 0: I've never run into that.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying yeah, some people reset them whenever whenever there's a typical Cisco thing Is every here someone.
Speaker 0: this is IT tip of the day.
Speaker 0: Someone ever says yeah reset your counters and call me back if it keeps happening.
Speaker 0: What they mean is reset the error count on a device and then the next day see if there's a nonzero number in that counter.
Speaker 1: Because it's like if you haven't looked at the number in a while You don't know if that number went up today or a year ago.
Speaker 0: But like some will return the deltas and they'll reset every time you pull them.
Speaker 0: So I pulled it.
Speaker 0: it tells me how many since the last time I pulled it.
Speaker 1: So you got to know what which kind your device is.
Speaker 1: or can you change the mode or both?
Speaker 0: It depends on the device.
Speaker 0: SNMP is just a framework It's just so.
Speaker 1: this is the stance of.
Speaker 1: the standards are all kind of flaky and is it's not very consistent.
Speaker 1: You got to know.
Speaker 0: well, no because the MIB is kind of the contract.
Speaker 0: it tells you this is what is at this value Mm-hmm in excruciating detail oftentimes Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So there's two ways to do it.
Speaker 0: You can do polls or traps.
Speaker 0: a poll is I've got a server like Nagios that hits a no ID on a server.
Speaker 0: Say I have a thing that returns a one if postgres is running and a zero if postgres is not running.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So I have a watch that every you know five minutes or 30 seconds or whatever just hits that value and makes an alarm for me or sends me an email or whatever.
Speaker 0: if Anything other than a one is returned or a zero or whatever, you know exit codes.
Speaker 0: You can really have it do just about anything.
Speaker 1: So the SNMP doesn't broadcast.
Speaker 1: you have to keep pulling it.
Speaker 0: Yes Now that's poll based monitoring.
Speaker 0: There's also trap based.
Speaker 0: an SNMP trap is when a UDP packet is sent to a receiver.
Speaker 0: you could there's ways to do this with broadcast and everything But that sucks.
Speaker 0: basically device.
Speaker 1: you got a program on the device.
Speaker 1: Tell it where the receiver is.
Speaker 0: Yes, almost any device will have this if it's an old device any like a server hardware you buy like Dell boxes like the racks The open manages you can just type in like this IP address or this name and the community string.
Speaker 0: We'll get to that in a second.
Speaker 0: So you tell it send your traps here and then anytime it has a problem.
Speaker 0: or sometimes devices will send traps that are just Updates.
Speaker 0: like order came in order came in or I use the CPU You can pretty much do anything.
Speaker 0: So that's kind of more.
Speaker 0: It's still active monitoring but is active from the client.
Speaker 0: So obviously if the trap gets lost on the network, you don't get it.
Speaker 0: if The device fails before it can send a trap.
Speaker 0: You don't get the trap.
Speaker 0: So you trap monitoring would be more for event based things.
Speaker 0: Like you might want to get a trap if say You exceed a threshold of CPU usage.
Speaker 0: But you'd want to have a poll monitoring.
Speaker 0: say your database that tells you the database is now down.
Speaker 0: if you have the database server Send a trap before it goes down.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe it's egg faults and doesn't send a trap.
Speaker 1: No Or maybe it doesn't send the trap until after it's down in which case it went down and now it can't send the trap.
Speaker 1: Cuz it's down.
Speaker 0: Yep, and now you're fucked.
Speaker 1: No, you're fucked.
Speaker 1: So you got up both.
Speaker 0: so community string.
Speaker 0: There are three versions of SNMP as far as anyone would care.
Speaker 0: one two, and three.
Speaker 0: Everybody uses one Nobody uses to.
Speaker 1: wouldn't you use the newer one?
Speaker 0: Three is the best and nobody fucking uses or two supports it by and large.
Speaker 1: That's the way the world.
Speaker 0: Here's the main difference.
Speaker 0: one has basically no Authentication or security whatsoever.
Speaker 1: So you can just if you find a device in the world You can probably just pull all its SNMPs and get all kinds of information without any whatever.
Speaker 0: So you've got that.
Speaker 0: this is an operational concern.
Speaker 1: You've got to control that with firewalls with the community string Let me guess that's actually good that SNMPs at the high level so you can actually firewall it pretty easily.
Speaker 0: Yes It's very easy to firewall, but the community string in version one the way except, you know The SNMP of your firewall itself the way you do this by default.
Speaker 0: It's public on every device.
Speaker 0: Yeah you send a plain text string in your trap or Your server and then if you pull someone you give them this plain text string and if it matches what's on the server it responds.
Speaker 1: So that would prevent people from polling because they basically need to know the password Unless they can sniff other SNMPs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if they sniff the SNMP traffic then they can see the community string.
Speaker 0: Funnily enough because plain text which is kind of awesome because networks have become more and more switched and segregated It's actually made SNMP version one much more secure because it's actually more difficult to sniff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if it's completely switched and you can't get past the switch and it's not wireless But if you're not stupid you're monitoring the switch and if the switch goes down then you know all the devices behind the switch.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but think about this.
Speaker 0: notice how every concern you've raised.
Speaker 0: There's not a technological solution.
Speaker 0: There's just a logic solution a how do I want to monitor to my system?
Speaker 0: What's where?
Speaker 0: it's actually a very Non-technical problem to solve in terms of monitoring.
Speaker 0: the technical part is very small.
Speaker 0: So version 3 has real authentication, but no one uses it.
Speaker 0: No one supports it.
Speaker 0: Don't worry about it or Fucking.
Speaker 1: why people upgrade.
Speaker 0: come on even because SNMP you realize is one of those ass old protocols.
Speaker 0: you go to the net SNMP Website for Linux.
Speaker 1: Is there anyone even on?
Speaker 1: it's like even a community of people who even bother?
Speaker 1: You're the only one left in the world.
Speaker 0: It's very similar to the community around NTP.
Speaker 1: You're like the only people left.
Speaker 1: Yeah, three people who care.
Speaker 0: So if you want to get this going quick if you want to monitor a Linux server Make sure you have net SNMP installed and it'll give you a bunch of simple utilities like SNMP gets which you type SNMP get space and OID and an IP and In a community string and an SNMP version, you know, whatever data and you'll get back the value with that OID.
Speaker 0: It's just a command-line protocol.
Speaker 0: now You can do an SNMP walk which will walk down the MIB in an intelligent way.
Speaker 0: So you give it a no ID.
Speaker 0: It'll walk down everything under that OID every sub branch and it'll figure out all the sub branches based on the answers It gets along the way.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm It'll give you SNMP D and this is what you want to run.
Speaker 0: SNMP D is a demon that responds to SNMP queries and if you run it, there's Etsy SNMP D dot-com and Basically you can put lines in there where you say OID Script and a couple other parameters and all it'll do is if you hit that OID from the outside It'll run that script with the privileges of root effectively through SNMPs demon and Return whatever you want.
Speaker 1: that script to return sounds like gaping security hole to me.
Speaker 1: If one of those scripts has any problems in it whatsoever, I could hit you on that number with and run his route.
Speaker 0: Yes, that's why you have to not be an idiot.
Speaker 0: Now there are ways SNMP has a get.
Speaker 0: it also has a whole set system where you can change values like NTP.
Speaker 0: There's this whole mechanism for sending SNMP traps or polls to change values on your server.
Speaker 0: Do not use this.
Speaker 0: it is insecure and it sucks Hey computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah change the value of this parameter to slash temp slash exact whatever whatever, you know my root kit dot the.
Speaker 0: So if you want to monitor processes like say you run Apache Tomcat Which is a very common thing or my SQL Apache Tomcat.
Speaker 0: in my SQL That combination is probably run by more people out there than just about anything.
Speaker 0: so what you do is you install SNMP D and all that stuff and you run the demon and you edit the Etsy SNMP D Dot-com and you'll figure out this file.
Speaker 0: read the man page.
Speaker 0: You're not.
Speaker 0: you guys I assume are fairly intelligent and you'll just write a little script that does a PS and make sure That Apache is running and that also makes sure that my SQL is running and then extend that through the MIT.
Speaker 0: You know pick an OID that makes sense and just say, you know this OID corresponds to the script and then install nagios or something and point it at that OID and Then what it'll do is it'll pull that every 30 seconds every whatever.
Speaker 0: every time you pull it It'll run that script which does the PS figures out of the processes are running and it'll return all these sub OIDs.
Speaker 0: It'll return the string that the script returned.
Speaker 0: It'll return the exit code of the script.
Speaker 0: It'll return the system uptime and a million other things.
Speaker 0: So you just have your monitoring.
Speaker 0: say if that script ever returns a value that per the script I wrote indicates that my SQL and or Apache isn't running.
Speaker 0: That's an alarm.
Speaker 1: That's pretty good.
Speaker 1: That's actually kind of easy, but she's in.
Speaker 1: I thought it was.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: it's really easy.
Speaker 0: It's SNMP D dot-com in Etsy and SNMP D.
Speaker 1: but you got to write a lot of scripts Now or download them from the internet.
Speaker 0: nagios and things like that basically come with a million scripts You can just put on don't?
Speaker 1: they come with scripts for nagios.
Speaker 1: Do they don't you know?
Speaker 1: So they also come with scripts for SNMP D whatever.
Speaker 0: They're basically the same thing.
Speaker 0: Okay, I Mean I could go into more details and whatever but you guys are smart.
Speaker 0: You can figure it out and I think I have equipped you with the tools to Start to figure out how to monitor Linux.
Speaker 1: Can you bind SNMP D to just one of your ether?
Speaker 1: Interfaces trivially, okay, because a lot of times it's like you got the external interface.
Speaker 1: You don't want it to.
Speaker 1: you want anyone accessing your SNMP from the externally.
Speaker 0: actually, you know what Scott?
Speaker 1: I want it only on the internal interface.
Speaker 0: I feel like at some point down the road We don't want to do boring, you know.
Speaker 0: Actually teaching you stuff shows on a regular basis because people get bored.
Speaker 0: I feel like we might have to talk about how Networking works in Linux because I don't think many of our listeners know how to use IP tables or IP chains or any of That stuff.
Speaker 0: you read the instructions man, man IP tables.
Speaker 1: Well, you just go to Google type in IP tables.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how to IP tables?
Speaker 0: feck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but seriously SNMP is really easy to use and if You learn it if you learn it enough to where you can on a Linux server Monitor an arbitrary process and whether or not is running just that nothing more.
Speaker 1: I could do that already.
Speaker 0: You will be likened unto a wizard.
Speaker 0: You will be a god-among-men of IT because nobody fucking knows this stuff.
Speaker 0: I I'm amazed.
Speaker 1: I'm a CS guy I know it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just cuz I know Unix.
Speaker 1: Yeah And you just told me that there's a script and I just got to figure out what number to you.
Speaker 0: In fact SNPD is included by default in most most distros.
Speaker 0: look in your Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: I'll bet Etsy SNPD.com is already there.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know to be either honest either Are you do you have one open right now?
Speaker 0: We could check.
Speaker 1: No, I've.
Speaker 1: no I don't either.
Speaker 0: I'm actually using sent OS and scientific Linux more and more just a civic Linux.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what's what's in that?
Speaker 0: You should look into that.
Speaker 1: All right How scientific could it be?
Speaker 1: It's used by sciency people by and large, but does it come with like no No, MATLAB already installed.
Speaker 0: I wish I think we're done Unlike other episodes.
Speaker 0: actually if you guys have questions, I would recommend sending them to us.
Speaker 0: I could do a follow-up show like a special where I answer all your SNMP questions.
Speaker 0: I'll head one off at the pass.
Speaker 0: if you want to monitor windows Sucks, and basically you're gonna have to buy an agent and run it on the server and that will send the SNMP.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows Sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.