Speaker 0: It's Monday, January 10th, 2011.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, the death of the PC.
Speaker 0: Again, let's do this.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry that your listeners missed the last five minutes of our conversation before we started this shindig.
Speaker 1: Why would they want to hear that?
Speaker 0: Because it was pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: But, uh, sound day.
Speaker 0: Yesterday was a very important day.
Speaker 0: The annual, the tenth annual No Pants Day in New York City.
Speaker 1: Oh, we've only gone to two, though.
Speaker 1: So it's, for us, it's number two.
Speaker 1: Even though there was ten.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, we didn't live here, so what can you expect?
Speaker 1: We could have gone on any other subway.
Speaker 0: It would have been too much of a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: Plus, I did not know it happened until the year before we did it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is one thing I think Improv Everywhere needs to do, is they, it's like, you gotta check their website, or they have RSS.
Speaker 1: But I don't think they have, like, email reminders or anything.
Speaker 1: We need to, I need to figure out that whole thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, we totally missed the, uh, MP3 experiments.
Speaker 1: That happened, that basically blinked us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we happened to be doing a panel in the Kinokuniya, and then suddenly- Well, there's an episode of that, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think the entire crowd stands up and they're like,
Speaker 0: "What?".
Speaker 0: And they're looking behind us, we're like, "God damn it, turn
Speaker 0: around.".
Speaker 1: We've already, we've already discussed this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, on a show that Monday listeners probably don't listen to.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: No Pants is pretty much the same as the previous No Pants.
Speaker 1: I was kind of disappointed.
Speaker 0: It was, like, the first time it was fun, like, "Oh my God, we're doing
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: At this time, it was like, "Alright, I did
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think part of the problem was that, at least on my particular subway car, there were some people who were just, like, not- There were less people who were following instructions strictly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my whole team was just talking about it on the subway platform before we got on the car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and- I'm like, "Dudes, shut up.
Speaker 0: We don't know each
Speaker 0: other.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then, it's like, you know, not only that, but it's like one person not following instructions basically ruins one whole car, right?
Speaker 1: Even, you know, no matter how many other people do follow the instructions.
Speaker 0: The trouble is, to make it more complex would just introduce more people fucking it up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they can't really, you know, it's the law of nature, right?
Speaker 1: Is that if you want to get a group of people to do something, the bigger the group, the less they can do in unison without extreme practice, right?
Speaker 0: That's why it's the wave and not, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the only times that they can, you know, you get more complicated things, such as the soccer stadium singing a song, is because they all individually practiced and prepared the song.
Speaker 0: Practice and dedication.
Speaker 1: I mean, I practiced- Or when you see like, you know, people doing the card flips that are like animations, you know?
Speaker 0: I practiced taking my pants off to make sure I could do it quickly enough.
Speaker 1: It's because they coordinated and practiced a lot beforehand.
Speaker 1: So, with the No Pants Day, it's pretty much show up, ten minutes of getting talked at, and then doing it.
Speaker 0: Ah, but I think I identified the real problem.
Speaker 0: Last year, they gave much better and more detailed instruction at the individual group level.
Speaker 1: Well, at least at our particular group.
Speaker 0: This year, at our station, many of the group leaders did not really tell anyone what to do, and I kind of took over my group.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think one thing is.
Speaker 1: the one difference, I think, that made that happen, at least at our station, was that last year, the group leaders were given a piece of paper with instructions.
Speaker 1: This year, they were just sort of told instructions.
Speaker 0: I feel like next year, I'm gonna participate, but I'm not- Show up early and be the leader.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or I just won't participate with the group.
Speaker 0: We'll make our own group and do something more complex.
Speaker 1: What could you do that's more complex?
Speaker 0: I'll ride the seven fucking train.
Speaker 1: They already do ride the seven train.
Speaker 0: Ooh, I didn't say any seven train plan.
Speaker 1: If you go and start at the Unisphere, they ride the seven train.
Speaker 0: Ah, yeah, Unisphere.
Speaker 1: It's like, they already do all the trains.
Speaker 0: You know what they don't do?
Speaker 0: They don't do the G. No one's on the G.
Speaker 1: There's no one on the G.
Speaker 0: With no pants.
Speaker 1: You'll be on the G with no pants alone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, scare the conductor.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: You could take the G with no pants to the Brooklyn Williamsburg starting point, and then go with them, the hipsters.
Speaker 1: I think what would be better if I just- The hipsters are probably more eccentric with their no pants.
Speaker 0: If I just, the next time I'm going to Manhattan for something like a Saturday, I just do it on my own.
Speaker 1: I just take my pants off.
Speaker 1: That's all you.
Speaker 1: Someone might come up to you and be like, "Hey, you're
Speaker 1: late.".
Speaker 0: The other trouble is that too many people, not on my car, but I saw a lot of other cars where the general public knew what was going on right away.
Speaker 0: They're like, "It's that fucking pants thing
Speaker 0: again.".
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They're also, I think the police were alerted, because there were police on my subway car and in Astoria and Union Square and in Times Square.
Speaker 1: It's like the police were alerted and they weren't making any trouble.
Speaker 1: They were just about.
Speaker 1: They had their eyes open.
Speaker 0: If you want a real flash mob, you've got to have a group.
Speaker 0: 4chan, Anonymous, they do it well.
Speaker 0: You announce something like today to do tomorrow, and regular world people cannot react fast enough.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: No pants day has been scheduled for months.
Speaker 1: It's like because you said it the day before, only people who check the internet every day will see it, or people who are on the Twitter or something like that will see it and be able to react in time, and local people only also.
Speaker 1: As a result, the people will be more willing and more able to execute the instructions properly and more dedicated.
Speaker 0: Of course, at the same time, despite all that, I was very happy that I am totally seriously sure that I convinced the nice old lady who offered me a seat next to her that I did in fact lose my pants and I don't know what all these other people are doing.
Speaker 1: Is she senile?
Speaker 0: I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: She's
Speaker 0: asking me where I work and I was like, "Yeah, I just left my pants at work and I'm just trying to get home and I think there's this thing, all these other people, She's like, "Yeah, there's some kind of no pants thing, but you just got lucky I
Speaker 0: guess.".
Speaker 0: She was totally, I'm pretty sure I got her.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the one funny thing I saw was, well, first of all, in the Astoria train, one guy was freaking out.
Speaker 1: He was just laughing hysterically.
Speaker 0: Was he one of us or just some guy?
Speaker 1: Just some guy.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's good.
Speaker 1: Then in the train, once we got... Oh, I forget.
Speaker 1: No, whatever.
Speaker 1: There was a guy sitting in the corner of the subway car.
Speaker 1: He was sleeping and snoring.
Speaker 1: He was not a no pants guy.
Speaker 0: So he woke up and then no pants?
Speaker 1: He was just sleeping the entire time.
Speaker 1: I did not see him wake up.
Speaker 1: He slept past Union Square.
Speaker 0: What I was at least happy with, I got off at 30th Avenue and where I happened to get off was right at the top of the stairs.
Speaker 0: So I just stood there kind of pantsless and that was where I got all the kind of interesting reactions.
Speaker 0: On the cars, I really didn't get anyone because everyone was like, "All right, there's a bunch of people with no pants.
Speaker 0: There's something going
Speaker 0: on.".
Speaker 1: Maybe they'll reformulate.
Speaker 1: The thing is the formula they have is still so good because you get multiple, you get two platforms and you get two cars.
Speaker 0: And you get this kind of quick, like it's too fast for most people to figure it out and react with other people.
Speaker 1: It's like you get all these platforms and you get multiple trains.
Speaker 1: Basically, you have the effect on two trains of this gradual.
Speaker 1: what the fuck, right?
Speaker 1: Because one guy does it weird.
Speaker 1: Two guys, four guys, eight guys.
Speaker 1: And then the second train comes in and it's one, two, four.
Speaker 1: So you get the build up on two different trains.
Speaker 0: And then people getting off in Union Square are just like, "What the
Speaker 0: fuck?".
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at that point, I think it's kind of silly because it's just like everybody has no pants.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well at that point, what's most fun is, I mean, we got away right away and we walked north and we kept the pants off.
Speaker 0: The reactions were much better when it's just four-pantsless people walking into a bakery to get some hot chocolate because it's cold.
Speaker 1: The thing is in New York, the people who are employees of a retail place never freak out about anything.
Speaker 0: Nah, because they're like, "Oh, you're not wearing pants?
Speaker 0: A homeless guy came in and pooped all over the table four minutes ago.
Speaker 0: You're not phasing
Speaker 0: me.".
Speaker 1: I went to the bank and got two-dollar bills and so far, I've had no trouble whatsoever using them.
Speaker 0: You had to go way upstate and find a Taco Bell.
Speaker 1: There's a Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: If you look up two-dollar bills on the internet, this is one story about a guy.
Speaker 0: The Park one, yeah, the Taco Bell, two dollars.
Speaker 1: No, this is the Best Buy one.
Speaker 0: Basically, a guy- Oh, separate story.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically the story, I found it in like ten different places on the internet.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it was just copied from one source, though.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure if it's true, either.
Speaker 1: But basically, a guy had a car stereo installation at Best Buy and they decided that it wasn't a free installation, even though it was supposed to be a free installation.
Speaker 1: He wanted to protest the fact that they were trying to charge him for the supposedly free installation.
Speaker 1: He went and it was $158 or something like that.
Speaker 1: He paid it with 57 two-dollar bills or whatever it comes out to, right?
Speaker 1: As a protest, because he worked for some tour group that had two-dollar bills.
Speaker 1: because he used the two-dollar bills so that the people on tours could use them to buy lunch because it was fun.
Speaker 1: So he had so many of them and they were sequential or whatever.
Speaker 0: I was going to say he had to have a reason because otherwise- Because he got them from the bank all the time.
Speaker 0: If you're doing the protest payment, it's pennies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, he got it from the bank all the time because he used them at his job.
Speaker 0: You've got to be like Kramer with that sack of change.
Speaker 1: So as a protest, he paid with these 50 pile of two-dollar bills he got from the bank.
Speaker 0: I take it this ends with police?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, he was arrested.
Speaker 1: Well, he wasn't arrested.
Speaker 1: I don't know if maybe he was arrested.
Speaker 1: He was handcuffed to a pole in the police station, right?
Speaker 1: And he was like, "Are you
Speaker 1: serious?".
Speaker 1: And then the Secret Service, of course, came and was like, "No, these are
Speaker 1: fine.".
Speaker 0: You guys are dumbasses.
Speaker 1: You guys are dumbasses.
Speaker 1: Let him go.
Speaker 0: So you're unfamiliar then with the most famous two-dollar bill story of all.
Speaker 0: The Fark two dollars.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to tell it- If this Best Buy story was ever in the news, I'm pretty sure it would have been posted to Fark.
Speaker 0: It probably has been, but it's usually a footnote to the Fark story of a guy who uses a two-dollar bill at a Taco Bell.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to tell it.
Speaker 0: Just Google it.
Speaker 0: There's an internet.
Speaker 0: You can get the original story, not my bastardization of it.
Speaker 1: Okay, so let's move on.
Speaker 1: Last year, when there was CES, we didn't have any Monday ideas.
Speaker 1: We did a Monday CES news show.
Speaker 0: This year- Wait, wait, my whole news is CES.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of boring tablets, 3D TVs, and a bunch of phones that no one cares about.
Speaker 1: Anything else?
Speaker 1: That's it?
Speaker 0: No one is really talking about it.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen anything that really stands out.
Speaker 1: Well, you've got to read Engadget.com.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm on Engadget, and everything looks- Everything is tablet, tablet, tablet, tablet, phone, tablet, phone, phone, car- It's all like, "Hey, we made an Android tablet.
Speaker 0: It's different from all the other ones in no way
Speaker 0: whatsoever.".
Speaker 1: No meaningful way, at least.
Speaker 1: I mean, basically, what's really upsetting is that I know for a fact that the CES is gigantic, right?
Speaker 1: And that I'm sure while the vast majority of things that would get traffic to a site like Engadget are things like Android tablets and other things that have very good search terms in them, right?
Speaker 1: But I'm also confident that if I was actually at the CES, there'd be a bunch of weird booths of things that no one thinks about that no one cares about, so they're not going to be posted to Engadget, but are probably interesting, and we will not see them.
Speaker 0: You've got to find some nerd blogger and read whatever he writes, some guy who went.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe we- you know, the thing is- Trivial amounts of journalism would figure this out.
Speaker 1: The thing is all the tech journalists talk about how they hate going to CES, so I'm like, "Huh, do I really want to go to it, or not, you know, if I
Speaker 1: go?".
Speaker 0: Wait, wait, wait.
Speaker 0: So you're a tech journalist, and you hate doing your job.
Speaker 1: Well, they talk about how, like, "Why should I, you know-".
Speaker 0: "Why should I
Speaker 0: journalize?".
Speaker 1: Well, these are not the journalists that go- That I'm looking for?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Engadget guys go because they're taking pictures and saying, "Look at this thing.
Speaker 1: Look at this thing.
Speaker 1: Look at this thing," right?
Speaker 1: But really, most of what they're doing amounts to regurgitating the press releases to the masses, right?
Speaker 1: They're taking this message that is being broadcast in a very small place and broadcasting it to the internet.
Speaker 1: A lot of the other- the tech journalists that hate going are the kind of guys who opine, you know?
Speaker 1: They say, "Oh, the iPhone, it is- will do
Speaker 1: badly.".
Speaker 1: You know, they don't need to actually be there.
Speaker 1: They can just read Engadget and then opine, like us!
Speaker 1: They basically do what we're doing right now for a living.
Speaker 1: They don't want to go.
Speaker 1: But anyway- I'll go.
Speaker 0: I'll take your job.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll go at least once to see what it's about, and if it's good, I'll go again.
Speaker 1: And if it sucks, I won't go again, you know?
Speaker 0: I don't know how much fun we'd actually have there when I think about it, though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: I've hated pretty much every trade convention I've ever been to.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just a- it's not-.
Speaker 1: the thing is, the only thing I think that saves CES from being just a room full of boobs is that it's like 10 rooms and 30 hotels full of boobs.
Speaker 1: At the very least, you can always go to a new place with new boobs and maybe meet somebody, you know?
Speaker 0: But it seems like 3D TVs and tablets are, like, the big thing, and every tablet looks like an iPad.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Have you noticed all these, like, phones that look like the iPhone?
Speaker 0: Except they don't work like the iPhone.
Speaker 1: No kidding.
Speaker 0: If only the iPhone were on some other carrier, I'd probably have one.
Speaker 0: But that'll never happen.
Speaker 1: Oh, sure?
Speaker 1: Never.
Speaker 1: It'll never happen.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about that in a couple weeks.
Speaker 0: That thing that won't happen?
Speaker 1: Tomorrow, actually.
Speaker 0: That won't happen tomorrow?
Speaker 1: Or today, if you're listening to this tomorrow.
Speaker 0: If you're listening to it tomorrow, you can't- by definition, if you're listening to it, it's today.
Speaker 1: No, because today is the day that I am saying this, not the day you're listening to it.
Speaker 0: Scott, this is much like the bar that has the clever sign in the window that says "Free Beer
Speaker 0: Tomorrow.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 0: So, is there any news to talk about at all?
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually, this news is not related to the CES.
Speaker 1: So, whether or not you knew this or not, or not, or not, VLC is a program that allows you to watch videos and also listen to audios.
Speaker 1: And it actually does a whole bunch of other video audio related stuff, too, if you can figure out how to make it do that.
Speaker 1: And the one thing about VLC is that, you know, it can play pretty much anything.
Speaker 0: It's very popular among Mac users, and it's very popular in general among people who can't get MPlayer to work.
Speaker 0: Because it's slower, but it just works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like it has a GUI, right?
Speaker 0: That GUI's like half there.
Speaker 1: It's a bad GUI.
Speaker 0: So, it's like people who- Granted, there is that GUI- Well, there's that GUI for MPlayer.
Speaker 0: that's way worse than the VLC GUI.
Speaker 1: Well, actually, there's one good GUI for MPlayer.
Speaker 1: is the MPlayer OS X Extended, right?
Speaker 1: Ah, yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like the MPlayer++ that's on the Mac.
Speaker 1: But there's no good MPlayer GUIs for Windows or Linux or anything.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so VLC was actually released for iTunes in the iTunes store for the iPhone and iPad, I guess.
Speaker 1: I don't know for the iPad, but definitely for the iPhone.
Speaker 1: And people were like, "What?
Speaker 1: It's GPL.
Speaker 1: That means you have to be open with the source and you can't add DRMs because it's GPL 3 and how is it-" you know.
Speaker 1: So, basically, they added it to the store and it was accepted, but they did it mostly as an experiment to then challenge.
Speaker 1: To be like, "Okay, there's a GPL thing in the store.
Speaker 1: Now, Apple, obey the
Speaker 1: GPL.".
Speaker 0: So, a bunch of nerds were like, "Let's make some trouble and then complain about the trouble we
Speaker 0: made.".
Speaker 1: Well, no.
Speaker 1: I think what it was is more like they knew that pretty much what was going to happen is they were going to remove VLC from the store.
Speaker 1: And that is the news.
Speaker 1: That is what happened.
Speaker 1: Apple removed VLC from the store and that's that.
Speaker 0: But all the news I see of people talking about it is saying, "Evil Apple removed VLC when everyone watched
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 1: That's because people don't know the whole story.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because really the story is- Right.
Speaker 1: The real story is basically what they did.
Speaker 1: is they said, "Okay, Apple, look.
Speaker 1: We're going to give you- here's a chance for you to be awesome to the open source, cool people, right?
Speaker 1: Here is your opportunity to make good.
Speaker 1: We know that odds are you're just going to make bad because that's how you do and that's what everything of history of your behavior has told us.
Speaker 1: But look, we're going to give you a chance to make good.
Speaker 1: Here's your chance to make
Speaker 1: good.".
Speaker 1: And they didn't make good, so it's like,
Speaker 1: "Ah.".
Speaker 0: What's funny is that they accepted the app.
Speaker 0: They were like, "All right, let's
Speaker 0: play.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then- Now you must obey the GPL.
Speaker 1: No, we're going to remove the app rather than obey the GPL.
Speaker 1: So?
Speaker 0: Effectively obeying the GPL.
Speaker 1: I know, but the thing is it's so weird because there's a lot of people out there who say things.
Speaker 1: They try to praise Apple for its open source-ness, right?
Speaker 1: They'd be like, "Oh, look.
Speaker 1: Apple open sourced Darwin kernel and Apple open sourced the- what's it
Speaker 1: called?".
Speaker 0: Well, Apple is very good at open sourcing the things- The LLVM, right?
Speaker 0: That don't matter.
Speaker 1: Apple open sourced- well, the LLVM kind of matters, but the point is they try to praise Apple for being so open source friendly compared to the evil closed source Microsoft, but it's like, "Well, look.
Speaker 1: Here was their chance to be open source friendly and they were
Speaker 1: dickheads.".
Speaker 0: But at the same time, that's their proprietary DRM distribution system.
Speaker 0: You can just download and install VLC.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: what they could have done though is all they really could have done to make this work is they could have just kept VLC in the store with no DRM on it.
Speaker 1: That would have sufficed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time, why bother?
Speaker 0: People who want VLC will just know where to get it anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but not for your iPhone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but do you need it on your iPhone?
Speaker 0: What can your iPhone not play?
Speaker 1: The iPhone can only play two video codecs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and for people who use iPhones?
Speaker 1: It can only play flash videos if they're from YouTube.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, it can only play H.264s and that's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: So, what percentage?
Speaker 0: Here's the operative question.
Speaker 0: We care because we're people who care about this sort of thing.
Speaker 0: How many people out there would ever even realize this is a problem?
Speaker 1: I think there are actually quite a few people who they do handbrakes or they have videos that they've made that they want to watch on their iPhones or iPads.
Speaker 0: I see most of the people I see complaining online.
Speaker 1: What happens is these people are now currently, they're not complaining because they're re-encoding the videos.
Speaker 1: They're converting them and it takes a while, but they don't mind because they don't know any better.
Speaker 1: But if they realized, "Aha, there was a way to do this without spending all this time re-encoding," they would be very happy, but they don't know that, so they just re-encode not knowing there's a better world.
Speaker 0: But most of the people I see complaining about this sort of thing are basically, they're one step before that.
Speaker 0: They're much less technical and they're people who basically say, "Yeah, these videos just are broken.
Speaker 0: They won't play on my Apple
Speaker 0: stuff.".
Speaker 0: And they don't even get past that point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you could tell them, "If you use the VLC, then they work," they'd be like, "Oh, all right," and they'd be good.
Speaker 0: But now you can't tell them that.
Speaker 0: This kind of segues right into the main topic because there's two, the diametric worlds of, and it's weird because Linux, for most people who use it...
Speaker 1: Don't segue to the main topic when you've got a piece of the day.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll get to that in the next half of the show because it's time for things of the day.
Speaker 0: So we were watching these.
Speaker 0: Chie, our good friend, told us about these a while ago, and we were reminded of them over the crazy front row crew New Year's party.
Speaker 1: I don't know why you're saying we.
Speaker 1: I never saw this before.
Speaker 1: you just showed it to me.
Speaker 1: You were in the room.
Speaker 1: I was probably playing a game in a different room.
Speaker 0: We were all watching these.
Speaker 0: You were definitely in the room.
Speaker 1: I did not watch.
Speaker 0: You definitely were there.
Speaker 1: I did not see.
Speaker 0: I'll agree.
Speaker 0: You did not see.
Speaker 1: I was in a different room or I was in a different apartment.
Speaker 0: But we watched them multiple times, in fact.
Speaker 0: But this is Sundance, some videos, green porno.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Isabella Rossellini basically tells you how different animals have sex in hilarious paper mache cardboard cutout form.
Speaker 0: The B one is the best one, at least for getting an introduction to what this sort of thing is like.
Speaker 1: Oh, why did you show me the best one first?
Speaker 1: Because now the other one's going to be meh.
Speaker 0: Uh, no.
Speaker 0: They're all pretty much like 99% as good as the B one.
Speaker 1: I'm going to tell you something, though.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I'm not a B.
Speaker 0: Just for the line at the end where he's like, "Now I will die without my
Speaker 0: penis.".
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: Who does that?
Speaker 1: It sounds like someone I know.
Speaker 0: You may know him.
Speaker 1: I think you might know him.
Speaker 0: So, that's it.
Speaker 0: There's like a million videos.
Speaker 0: They're all short.
Speaker 0: They're incredibly worth watching.
Speaker 0: The show is called Seduce Me.
Speaker 0: You might have seen this.
Speaker 0: I think one Daily Show way back showed one about bedbugs.
Speaker 0: And one of the worst words, well, combination of words I've ever heard in my life, traumatic insemination.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, how about ducks with their friggin'- Ducks.
Speaker 0: Ducks are motherfucking rapists.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you what.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: Watch out.
Speaker 1: Donald's coming to get you.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So, check this out, right?
Speaker 0: I'm checking.
Speaker 1: If you take someone to a big open field or perhaps, I don't know, salt flats- And what, rape them like a duck?
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: And then you put a blindfold on them and you just say, "All right, listen.
Speaker 1: You can't see anything, but walk in a straight
Speaker 1: line.".
Speaker 1: And they're not cheating.
Speaker 1: They're not peeking out of the blindfold.
Speaker 1: Maybe just put a sack over their heads so they really can't see.
Speaker 1: And you say, "All right, you're blindfolded.
Speaker 1: Walk in a straight
Speaker 1: line.".
Speaker 1: People think they're walking in a straight line, but really, no matter how many times you do this experiment, people always walk in sort of like a corkscrew circle.
Speaker 1: They veer to the right.
Speaker 0: It seems to always be to the right.
Speaker 0: That's the weirdest part.
Speaker 1: And people have tried it swimming.
Speaker 1: They've tried it with different- Driving.
Speaker 1: They've tried it with different genders.
Speaker 1: They've tried it with different heights.
Speaker 1: They've tried it with left-handed, right-handed, ambidextrous people.
Speaker 0: What about wheelchairs?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but they've tried just about everything.
Speaker 1: Because if I just hold forward on my motorized wheelchair- They're still trying, and they still can't figure it out, but what they do know is that if you have some sort of point of reference, you can walk straight.
Speaker 1: But if you don't have one, people cannot walk straight, no matter how much they think they're walking straight.
Speaker 1: They'll start to walk in a circle.
Speaker 1: It does make sense, because I remember as a kid, one of the things you learn- We know that this is what happens, but we don't know why.
Speaker 0: One of the things you learn when you're camping, and if you've ever spent a lot of time in the outdoors, is that you cannot trust your own sense of direction in a forest.
Speaker 0: You will go in circles if you try to just walk straight.
Speaker 1: Imagine the path or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but even then, you'll lose the path, and then you'll go in a circle, and you'll find the path again, and then you'll go in the same circle.
Speaker 0: In fact, the path often makes it worse, because you'll be on the path, veer off the path onto a deer trail, come full circle, you'll find the path again like, "Yes, I got
Speaker 0: it!"
Speaker 0: And you'll be right back where you started.
Speaker 1: This is why you need a compass.
Speaker 0: The thing is, I feel like, with the knowledge of how this study worked, if I did this myself ten times and figured out how much I tend to veer, I would stop every hundred steps, turn a little bit to the left, and then continue.
Speaker 1: See, the thing is, I don't know why the car one failed, because if I had a car in the salt flats, I'd basically just step on the gas and not touch the wheel.
Speaker 0: It's got alignment shifts.
Speaker 0: You hit any bump, and now you're going a different direction.
Speaker 1: It's a salt flat.
Speaker 0: It's not perfectly flat, Scott.
Speaker 1: The salt flat is perfectly flat.
Speaker 1: That's why they do the test drives there.
Speaker 0: It's pretty flat, but there are imperfections you are likely to run into.
Speaker 1: Alright, I would hold the wheel and not move my hand.
Speaker 1: Right in the middle.
Speaker 0: I'll bet you would subconsciously move it a little bit.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: And not realize it.
Speaker 1: I can hold it right in the middle.
Speaker 0: Scott, try to hold your hand perfectly straight and not move it at all.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: Alright, on something that can move.
Speaker 0: A wheel of some kind.
Speaker 0: Just in the air.
Speaker 1: My knee can move, but...
Speaker 0: Your knee has more resistance, and I see you moving.
Speaker 1: I can just put my knee up against the wheel.
Speaker 1: I do not move it.
Speaker 1: I think it will.
Speaker 0: So you think that all these studies... total bullshit, because no one's smarter than you.
Speaker 1: I think I could do it.
Speaker 0: You think you could do it.
Speaker 1: I could do it.
Speaker 0: Tell you what.
Speaker 0: You rent a car.
Speaker 0: Let's get out on the Queensborough Bridge.
Speaker 0: Let's try this.
Speaker 1: Why don't we do it somewhere safe?
Speaker 1: Where there's a lot of straightness.
Speaker 0: But I thought you could do it.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a straight road.
Speaker 1: Because then I would be blindfolded, so I wouldn't see the cars in front of me stopping.
Speaker 0: So we'll go like 2 a.m.
Speaker 0: when there's no cars.
Speaker 1: There are cars at 2 a.m.
Speaker 0: Not so much on the Queensborough Bridge.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of cars at 2 a.m If you go at 5 miles an hour, you won't run into anyone.
Speaker 1: Instead, they'll come up and smash into my ass and honk like hell.
Speaker 1: And then I'll know what direction I'm going in for sure.
Speaker 1: Because we'll be honking, which is a point of reference.
Speaker 1: It needs to be quiet.
Speaker 0: So very briefly, the meta moment.
Speaker 0: This weekend, we will be at MAGFest.
Speaker 1: MAGFest.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: I don't think you're very good at it.
Speaker 0: I'm not very good at it.
Speaker 0: Neither are you.
Speaker 0: Me too.
Speaker 1: I'm great.
Speaker 0: We'll wait until we get there and hear other people doing it.
Speaker 0: It's more like a... Like he charges up.
Speaker 1: You're trying too hard.
Speaker 1: That's better.
Speaker 1: You're enunciating too much.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we'll be at MAGFest doing 3 panels.
Speaker 0: We got the schedule.
Speaker 0: I put it in the link.
Speaker 0: So if you want to know when our panels are, if you're going to be at MAGFest, outside of those, we'll just be chilling, hanging out.
Speaker 1: There are some panels in the schedule that look like they would be our panels, but they're someone else's panels.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm curious.
Speaker 0: I might go to some of these panels.
Speaker 1: There's a match game.
Speaker 1: There's like a storytelling and tabletop role-playing game.
Speaker 0: I've never seen anyone else do a match game at the cons we've ever been to.
Speaker 0: I'm curious to see if they do it well.
Speaker 1: Actually, some of the events are pretty creative, like the Iron Chef, where they're actually going to cook with a George Foreman in a microwave.
Speaker 0: I wonder how they're getting away with that, because there's no way we could get away with that at like Kinetic Con.
Speaker 1: Where would we get enough George Foremans in enough microwaves?
Speaker 0: Where are we going to get the hotel to say, "Yeah, you can plug 10 George Foremans into this
Speaker 0: room.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can plug in 10 microwaves.
Speaker 1: No trouble here.
Speaker 1: Run them all simultaneously.
Speaker 0: MAGFest seems like a con that gets in vague trouble with a hotel every year.
Speaker 0: I'm just getting that impression.
Speaker 1: Maybe they found a hotel that like loves that shit.
Speaker 0: It's possible.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's a hotel that no one else uses.
Speaker 0: They're just desperate.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: They hate them, but they have nothing they can do about it.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We'll see, but MAGFest is going to be pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: We got other cons coming up, like PAX East and everything.
Speaker 0: Book Club book is Michio Kaku's Hyperspace.
Speaker 1: I started reading.
Speaker 1: I read the introduction.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a good book.
Speaker 0: Yeah?
Speaker 0: You're saying it's not?
Speaker 0: Are you going to prejudge this amazing book?
Speaker 1: No, I'm just saying I read the introduction.
Speaker 1: I can't really say either way.
Speaker 0: How was the introduction on a scale of 1 to 10 of introductions?
Speaker 1: It wasn't really a good introduction because it wasn't Neil Gaiman, who is the greatest introduction writer of all time.
Speaker 0: I would love to see a book that is a coffee table book, just introductions by Neil Gaiman.
Speaker 1: That was my idea.
Speaker 0: In fact, he should write the introduction to his own book.
Speaker 1: That was my idea for that to happen, but I tried to tell him that idea.
Speaker 1: He didn't say anything.
Speaker 1: He wasn't reading his tweets.
Speaker 1: That day.
Speaker 0: You should have told him at PenguinCon 2.
Speaker 1: I didn't have the idea then.
Speaker 1: I had the idea more recently.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll write him a letter on paper.
Speaker 1: He'll read that.
Speaker 0: I remember back in, I don't know, 1996, give or take?
Speaker 1: '97 or '98.
Speaker 0: If I may.
Speaker 0: That was a different time, you understand.
Speaker 0: That Oracle was one of many companies saying that the desktop was dead and that it was going to be a short span of time before everyone is using thin clients, proprietary thin clients, everything is going to be up in a cluster, going to be up in a cloud of some kind, and PCs are going to be dead.
Speaker 0: Part of this was to lock down the experience.
Speaker 1: DRM, Oracle was way ahead of its time for being evil.
Speaker 1: They weren't thinking about the evil DRMs at that point, right?
Speaker 0: They were thinking about the lockdown, the support, verified code.
Speaker 0: You don't need any local data store because trust us, we've got it.
Speaker 1: What they were thinking about was mostly, "Look, you had to keep giving us money even after you bought the computer because we actually have the computer and you
Speaker 1: don't.".
Speaker 1: That's mostly the core of what they were thinking about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there was a lot of talk about protected data streams.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, part of the reason for that was they wanted to be, it was like, "Well, look, this benefits the customer because their computer will just always work and it will be cheaper to buy the computer even though they'll have to pay us
Speaker 1: monthly.".
Speaker 0: Now, the nerds said no.
Speaker 1: And it'll be so secure.
Speaker 0: The nerds said, "I want the power to run whatever code I want and have whatever data I want with no one else having access to it.
Speaker 0: I can handle
Speaker 0: that.".
Speaker 0: And things went around for a while.
Speaker 0: When I was at IBM, I--.
Speaker 1: Well, I think mostly the reason that that didn't work at the time wasn't due to lack of trying.
Speaker 1: It was that the desktops had caught on mostly because of the Apple II and what came after it and the IBM PC and what came after it.
Speaker 1: It had caught on already.
Speaker 1: There was an existing base of software and things that people did with computers and that was the platform.
Speaker 1: It was the PC platform.
Speaker 1: It was locked in.
Speaker 1: Games are coming out for it, right?
Speaker 1: So you couldn't really compete with it because you didn't have the network bandwidth to the house to compete with it.
Speaker 0: Well, see, for the home user, I don't think that was on the horizon yet because where this was expected to happen was in business.
Speaker 0: If you hadn't interrupted my anecdote, when I worked at IBM, which was 2003, give or take, I came into possession of several thousand thin clients that were designed to connect to a thin client server and do all that stuff.
Speaker 0: They had RAM.
Speaker 0: They had a little CPU that was just strong enough to get the data and do whatever it needed to do, a little bit of local processing power, and a network card, and almost nothing else, an output for a serial port and keyboard inputs and everything.
Speaker 1: There's a place on the fourth floor of the building I work in and the whole middle of the room is just all these thin clients.
Speaker 0: So you know why we got these?
Speaker 0: Because nobody wanted them because they were completely useless.
Speaker 0: They were so slow and so obsolete, so fast.
Speaker 0: It was amazing.
Speaker 0: This was in enterprise environments where we did have the bandwidth.
Speaker 0: We had plenty of bandwidth.
Speaker 0: Bandwidth was not the limiting factor.
Speaker 0: The limiting factor ended up being that, one, the servers weren't fast enough to deal with all these clients.
Speaker 0: Two, the local clients were slow as balls.
Speaker 1: Thin clients are a little better now for business purposes.
Speaker 1: There's actually plenty of businesses, mostly where they have a bunch of workers doing the same exact task with a simple interface.
Speaker 1: For example, the place on the fourth floor of my building is an apartment place.
Speaker 1: All anyone does in any of those computers is search for apartments in a little browser.
Speaker 1: They have just a field of thin clients.
Speaker 1: People just search and that's all they do.
Speaker 0: But what brand?
Speaker 0: Are they actually thin clients?
Speaker 0: Or are they data-less clients?
Speaker 1: No, they're those YA's things.
Speaker 0: But most people use, when they call thin clients, they're actually data-less clients.
Speaker 0: They're usually a Linux box with a hard drive and a CPU.
Speaker 1: These are one of those things where you turn it on and you get ghetto windows.
Speaker 1: All it has in the ghetto windows is some sort of Windows remote desktop kind of client thing.
Speaker 0: Most thin clients in the older days used Citrix-like things and would even get the desktop from afar.
Speaker 0: They had nothing locally.
Speaker 0: If there's anything local, it's not technically a thin client.
Speaker 0: It's a data-less client in that it has a minimal system to do what you need locally and has local processing power, but all the application logic and all the data is stored somewhere else.
Speaker 1: This is basically a situation where you have either a VMware server or a Windows server, whatever, and all the actual computing happens on this server or cluster of servers and people just remote into it with remote desktop kind of situations, and that's how it works.
Speaker 0: I got rid of those thin clients, and you know what I replaced them with?
Speaker 0: Linux PCs, because they were cheaper and easier to maintain and a thousand times more powerful.
Speaker 0: And the best part is, what a lot of people didn't foresee that I think was really the death of that old south thin client was web apps.
Speaker 0: Web apps meant that it didn't matter what was on the end, because when you had these thin clients, you had to have all this kind of specialized software.
Speaker 0: There was no open, general framework.
Speaker 0: Everyone had their own proprietary bullshit solution.
Speaker 0: With a web app, you really literally didn't care.
Speaker 0: As long as they had IE3 or up, it just worked.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's the one thing.
Speaker 1: The web started out as just sort of like mostly an information thing.
Speaker 1: It was almost like an encyclopedia where anyone could make a page or edit pages.
Speaker 1: People weren't thinking of it being an application platform, so other things like the Citrix.
Speaker 1: It's like, well, an application runs in the desktop, and if you need to serve an application over the network, you need something like exporting or remote desktop.
Speaker 1: You need something.
Speaker 1: But only because the browsers and the JavaScript and everything became more powerful did web apps actually happen.
Speaker 1: It's like, no, shit, everything's in the browser now.
Speaker 1: So we got to the same place they were thinking.
Speaker 1: We just didn't take the route that they were expecting to get there.
Speaker 0: But there was definitely this aspect of the media.
Speaker 0: People talked a lot about how eventually no one will have a local PC anymore.
Speaker 0: They will just have some sort of client that gets them to the data that we host, and no one will run their own applications, no one will write their own applications, no one will have local storage.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, people are also thinking about this general idea.
Speaker 1: It's like the idea of the appliance computer.
Speaker 1: That's what they wanted back in the day, at least.
Speaker 1: They were like, why are we giving normal people these computers that are actually full-on computers?
Speaker 1: Normal people want a toaster.
Speaker 1: They should have an appliance that's as easy to use as a microwave.
Speaker 1: You know, push a button that says play game, and push a button that says, you know, read encyclopedia, and push a button that says, you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: And there were a ton of attempts at things like that.
Speaker 1: They all failed until the iPhone.
Speaker 0: Well, there were some early -- remember the original iMacs?
Speaker 1: That was not an appliance.
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't, but it was close.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, it ran OS X. It was not an appliance in any way.
Speaker 0: But the way they were presented to people -- In fact, it didn't run OS X.
Speaker 1: It ran OS 9.
Speaker 0: But the way they were presented to people, and the way they were bundled, they were bought by people with the expectation that they would work mostly like an appliance.
Speaker 0: They had their big buttons, and they do very simple, focused things.
Speaker 1: It was -- no, it didn't have these soft -- you know, I mean, it was -- hardware-wise, it was all-in-one, you know, thing, but that was nothing new.
Speaker 1: The original Mac was all-in-one, right?
Speaker 1: It'd be appliance --.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was like lost precursor technology to most computer users by then.
Speaker 1: But the true idea of an appliance computer that actually succeeded, that people actually bought in any number was, you know, the first iPhone, which, you know -- Well, that's way later.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm talking about the old days.
Speaker 0: This was basically a first step.
Speaker 0: It was a move in that direction, not to the data-less PC or the thin client, but to the appliance PC, which was a very different direction from what Oracle and a lot of people really wanted to push the industry.
Speaker 0: But nerds from the start were like, "Fuck you.
Speaker 0: I'm not letting you touch my data.
Speaker 0: It's mine.
Speaker 1: Damn
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: And they pretty much lost, and PCs really took over.
Speaker 0: Everyone had PCs.
Speaker 0: There was a whole era where the whole thing was like every nerd was building their own PC.
Speaker 0: There was like Renaissance of PC building.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there was Dell and Gateway and all those things.
Speaker 0: Remember, like, CompUSA?
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: And basically, everyone forgot about this argument, and suddenly it's coming back again, and I don't think anyone forgot about it.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of people forgot about it.
Speaker 1: No, I think it's just that it's finally -- you know, a big movement came much too quickly, right?
Speaker 1: It was like the App Store, and then it exploded before people realized, "Aw, shit, the appliance appeared when we were least
Speaker 1: looking.".
Speaker 0: There it is.
Speaker 0: See, outside of tech circles, no one was even thinking about that.
Speaker 0: They'd already forgotten about the whole movement.
Speaker 0: They had their PC.
Speaker 0: They upgraded it every few years, and they just never thought about it.
Speaker 0: And then suddenly, iPads and iPhones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that, you know, the main problem here is you get this argument that goes on, and the argument goes something like this, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, "Oh, this is so great because now my computer is easy to use, and it never breaks, and it's secure, and my grandma can even use it.
Speaker 1: It's so
Speaker 1: easy.".
Speaker 1: But then the nerd says -- And it does everything that I want it to do.
Speaker 0: The nerd, you know, like me, says, "But I want to do this particular thing, and I don't want to have anyone else control whether or not I do that
Speaker 0: thing.".
Speaker 1: Well, you can still use your hard-to-use computer, but no one else needs to use that hard-to-use computer.
Speaker 1: Everyone else can live happy with their managed computer experience.
Speaker 0: Of course, one interesting way to look at this is look at the difference between a Windows PC, where if I want an application, I go to, you know, thisismalware.ru, and I download an .exe file, and I run it, and it installs it on my PC.
Speaker 0: Because you're a moron.
Speaker 0: But in Linux, when I wanted something, I'm just like, "App get install this thing," and I have this repository that just handles it.
Speaker 0: And yet, with the iPad model, it's a very similar thing.
Speaker 0: I want an application that does X. I go into the "repository" -- I'm making quote marks -- and I just get it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the problem -- the key differences are, number one, that repository, not everything in there is free.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Number two, when you get something from that repository, you can get the source code to it also.
Speaker 1: And three, you can just put things in the repository.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: No matter what it is.
Speaker 0: But then again, there are the quote-unquote "approved" repositories.
Speaker 0: Like, if you just install an Ubuntu or CentOS or something, you get a kind of certified, vetted, you-trust-these-people repository.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they only check to make sure something works.
Speaker 1: They don't check to make sure they like it or not.
Speaker 1: And also, you can just add any repository you want.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but that's the fundamental difference, that the iTunes repository is it.
Speaker 0: I can't add the iTunes.ru repository.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, and the main thing is, you know, the first argument that, like, you know -- I try to argue that these things are bad, and people say, "Ah, they're not bad,
Speaker 1: blah.".
Speaker 0: We can do this pretty simply.
Speaker 0: You make the argument that it's bad, and I'll make the argument that it's good.
Speaker 0: It's pretty easy to take turns on this.
Speaker 1: All right, so the first reason that it's bad, right, is if people, you know, have a computer that is too easy to use, there will be much less incentive for them to learn how to actually use a computer, and basically, there will be this tyranny of the people who are programming over the people who are just using iPads.
Speaker 0: Ah, but Scott, do we not have a tyranny of mechanics and a tyranny of civil engineers?
Speaker 0: that people only need to know the specialized tools for their specialized jobs, and for every other realm of their life, they really just need an appliance?
Speaker 0: Shouldn't we trust the experts to take care of the expert work?
Speaker 1: We do indeed have a tyranny of mechanics, and I wish more people would know how their car works so they wouldn't be getting ripped off and such.
Speaker 1: But here's the problem, right?
Speaker 1: Even more so than the car, the computer is integrated into every part of life.
Speaker 1: You use your car for transportation, which is a major part of life, which is why I think you should know how your car works, even if you're not personally capable of fixing it, right?
Speaker 1: You should at least know more than most people know.
Speaker 1: But a computer is everything.
Speaker 1: If you don't know how to handle your computer, basically, as the world progresses to where more and more things are handled by computers, the computers will now own your life, and thus the people who control the computers now control you.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, do you not-- As opposed to just controlling your transportation.
Speaker 0: Even with the car, do you not need a license to drive?
Speaker 0: And if someone is incapable of driving safely without harming themselves and others, do we not force them to not drive and have someone else drive them around?
Speaker 0: Is the iPad/iPhone model not an expert?
Speaker 0: makes the people who can never figure it out drive themselves in this controlled, safe environment on these rails, and the smart people will just use something else?
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: The people who are incapable of driving, it's basically a car that drives itself for those people who cannot drive themselves.
Speaker 1: And now it enables those people to get around, and that is a good thing.
Speaker 1: However, think about the harm-- At least, it's not necessarily harm, but opportunity cost of this happening.
Speaker 1: And the opportunity cost is, think about how the world has-- We have been able to change the world because of our control over our own computers, right?
Speaker 1: The fact that the web exists at all is because people all had computers that they could control.
Speaker 0: Ah, so Scott, so Scott, but this was a tyranny of the ultra-elite technorati.
Speaker 0: The vast majority of people are not contributing to the internet in that regard.
Speaker 0: They are contributing information.
Speaker 0: They are contributing on a meta-high level, like they're contributing way above.
Speaker 0: They're adding to Facebook.
Speaker 0: They're writing content.
Speaker 0: But below the level of putting words and videos into the stream, they are not doing anything.
Speaker 1: You need to think farther into the past.
Speaker 1: Think of this, right?
Speaker 1: In the '90s, there was AOL, and AOL was dominating, right?
Speaker 1: And why were we able to escape AOL?
Speaker 1: Yes, there were technorati and programmers who were able to make up the Apache web server and to make Netscape Navigator and to make these tools for escaping AOL.
Speaker 1: That made people want to leave AOL.
Speaker 1: But it was because people were able to control the software on their own machines that even-- You think, "Oh, everyone's
Speaker 1: ignorant.".
Speaker 1: Well, they somehow managed to install Netscape and then get out of AOL.
Speaker 1: They managed to do it, no matter how ignorant they were, because they had control over their computers.
Speaker 1: They had this choice.
Speaker 1: But at the same time-- And if they had all had iPads or AOL pads in the late '90s, AOL would still be conquering the world today.
Speaker 1: There would have been no change.
Speaker 0: But then at the same time, will there not simply be a dichotomy between the people who don't understand how any of the technology they use works, who just use the appliance, and the technorati who live in a different internet world?
Speaker 1: There will be that dichotomy.
Speaker 1: But what I'm saying is that if these people who are ignorant and don't know how their stuff works, if they lose their ability to have choice, then that takes power to change the world away from open-source people like us, because we can't get anything into their hands.
Speaker 1: And the only power to change the world through technology will be in the hands of technology companies with money who can get their software onto these closed platforms.
Speaker 0: Ah, but at the same time, despite the openness of the PC platform, people were very resistant to even leaving AOL.
Speaker 0: And much of what caused this shift was industries very much pushing and promoting their own agendas to get people away from AOL into an open marketplace where they could then compete, and in the end, they win due to the fact that people still didn't really have any choice.
Speaker 1: Well, all companies, right, they seem to follow this model of where when they're falling behind, they push for the open way, because when it's open, then they can compete.
Speaker 1: But then once you're ahead, you want to close it up, because you've got the most people, and then you lock them all into you, right?
Speaker 1: That seems to be the business model that flows back and forth, right?
Speaker 1: If you're winning in some department, right, you want that department to be closed, so nobody leaves you because you have the most customers right now, you have the most market share, and if you close it down, all those people have to stick with you.
Speaker 1: If everyone's got iPods, you want to lock that shit down so they can't go switch to Zunes that easily.
Speaker 1: It's very hard to switch to Zune because you're locked in the iTunes library.
Speaker 1: But, what do you do if everybody's using Windows, right, that's the majority winner.
Speaker 1: You need people to switch to Mac, which means you need to make stuff like Safari, and all this other stuff so that it's, you know, make it as compatible as possible.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, we can open up Microsoft Word documents.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we can do, you know, you want everything opened up so that people can easily transfer over to you.
Speaker 1: But you know, one day, OS X is on top of Windows and market share, they're going to close that shit down, and it's going to be much harder to switch back the other direction.
Speaker 0: Let's look at the AOL days versus the current days.
Speaker 0: Most people who are using their computers, they recognize that the iPad, at least to them, is just better.
Speaker 0: It just has a much better and more intuitive interface.
Speaker 0: And unlike the AOL days, back then, they started to move from AOL when they realized they'd see people outside of AOL doing things that they themselves could not do.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: What is there that open source is doing better right now that normal people care about than the iPad and the iPhone?
Speaker 0: Name a phone that is better than the iPhone.
Speaker 1: Right now, there is nothing.
Speaker 0: Name anything related to media that is better than iTunes doing what people want it to do.
Speaker 1: Right now, there is nothing, right?
Speaker 1: Not at this very moment.
Speaker 1: And that is the reason why the iPad and the iPhone and such are winning at this very moment because there is no such thing.
Speaker 1: However, if they win too much, if they get too far ahead, then the potential for there to be such a thing in the future will disappear.
Speaker 1: In the olden days, that thing was Napster that appeared, that everyone installed.
Speaker 1: Now, if you invented Napster today, it could not take foothold because there are not enough... If too many people had these lockdown devices, Napster would never get on those devices.
Speaker 0: The industry has a vested interest in locking these things down to prevent anything like Napster from ever happening again.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: In fact, there is probably a great...
Speaker 1: But that is horrible as the worst thing for the world and the progress of human society.
Speaker 0: But it is a good thing for grandma who will never get a virus again.
Speaker 1: It is not good for grandma.
Speaker 1: You think it is good for grandma when you are only looking at that one grandma and her personal experience.
Speaker 1: But I think the future, the progress of technology in the world as a whole is better for grandma.
Speaker 1: Even though she does not know it.
Speaker 0: Are you saying that it is bad that old grandmas now have easy to use computers?
Speaker 1: I am saying there is more to it than that.
Speaker 1: There is a good part and a bad part to everything.
Speaker 0: Why do we have to choose, Scott, between computers that are easy to use and just work and computers that are impossible to use but are open?
Speaker 1: We do not have to choose.
Speaker 1: I have a very simple solution to this problem.
Speaker 1: Oh, do you?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Solution number one.
Speaker 1: Somebody needs to hire a good designer that is not going to work at Apple.
Speaker 0: Can you honestly argue to me that Google, which has effectively infinite resources, is unable to do so?
Speaker 1: They have hired tons of designers and apparently they are all sucking if you have not looked at Google shit lately.
Speaker 0: So are there good designers?
Speaker 1: That is a problem.
Speaker 1: Get to design school kids.
Speaker 1: Stop going to work at magazines and fashion and work on industrial design.
Speaker 0: But how come it has not happened?
Speaker 0: How come there is no one?
Speaker 1: I do not know.
Speaker 1: It is frightening.
Speaker 0: And of course, open source.
Speaker 0: X windows is fantastic.
Speaker 1: Actually, X windows is going out the door but it is another episode.
Speaker 1: I have an argument actually.
Speaker 0: I am going to make a separate argument.
Speaker 1: Here is a second part of the solution.
Speaker 1: We just need to make a law that says, look, if you buy it, you own it, you can do whatever you want to it.
Speaker 1: You have to include -- you cannot completely lock it down.
Speaker 1: Grandma would get the iPad, she would not know the difference.
Speaker 1: But if I get an iPad, there has got to be an option somewhere for me to -- remember in the olden days, you would buy stereo and it would come with a schematic?
Speaker 1: You just need to put that in law so that a computer comes with a nerd document with it.
Speaker 1: Your car has to come with a service manual.
Speaker 0: In the modern world, cars do not come with a service manual.
Speaker 1: I know, it is bullshit.
Speaker 1: I buy the car, you should give me the fucking layout.
Speaker 0: The only realms -- and this is where I think we are going with the PC.
Speaker 0: I was playing the devil's advocate the whole way.
Speaker 0: I point out, Scott, that it was increasingly difficult to make an argument that did not boil down to.
Speaker 0: I am evil and have the power to do what I want so you are fucked anyway.
Speaker 1: If you have a car, you worry, if I give up the service manual, some other company can make the same car.
Speaker 1: They can just take apart your car.
Speaker 1: There are no secrets in the car.
Speaker 1: There are no secrets in anything.
Speaker 0: But no, Scott, you are not letting me finish.
Speaker 0: The PC is going to move into a realm, the actual physical PC that many other things have moved into.
Speaker 0: When I buy a Radio Shack whatever, like a Radio Shack microphone or something, it is just a shitty microphone that just works.
Speaker 0: If I buy a real compressor or a real mixer or a real microphone, it comes with a schematic, it comes with diagrams, full technical documentation, a warranty, and support.
Speaker 0: If I buy a regular car, just some Ford car or whatever, I do not get the real service manual.
Speaker 0: And I have to go to the dealer and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: I am sure if you buy a Ferrari, you get the real deal.
Speaker 0: The PC is going the way of every other thing that has ever come out in the history of the world.
Speaker 0: If you are a professional or a contractor or an expert, you will get the hardware that gives you the freedom, openness, and documentation that you need.
Speaker 0: The future is going to be computer.
Speaker 0: experts will have actual PCs that they run whatever the hell they want on.
Speaker 0: And everybody else is going to be using an appliance.
Speaker 1: But those people with PCs because computers have infiltrated every part of our society?
Speaker 0: Yes, we are going to be mechanic wizards.
Speaker 1: And the thing is, but we are benevolent.
Speaker 1: I am saying, "Look, you people, I do not want to rule you like an evil god.
Speaker 1: Do not let me.
Speaker 1: Learn to use a
Speaker 1: computer.".
Speaker 0: Scott, and they will look up at you and say, "Do you have
Speaker 0: circuses?".
Speaker 1: And I will say, "Yes, watch all these video games I can play that you
Speaker 1: can't.".
Speaker 0: And they will say, "Those video games are difficult and I do not want to play
Speaker 0: them.".
Speaker 0: I will continue playing Farm-Iville-Pad-Frontier-Town.
Speaker 1: And I will say, "No, people are stupid and I could not save
Speaker 1: them.".
Speaker 0: And they will say, "Look ye mighty upon my
Speaker 0: farm.".
Speaker 1: I will say, "Look ye mighty...".
Speaker 1: See, what would really... Upon my penis.
Speaker 0: The only way to fix this is we have to hack into Zynga's servers, right?
Speaker 0: And corrupt Farmville.
Speaker 1: Farmville teaches you to... Teaches you to see?
Speaker 0: Teaches you to be like, "Look, Farmville broke because of
Speaker 0: DRM.".
Speaker 0: Just lie, straight up.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: I do not know.
Speaker 0: But really, I think the future of the PC is that the majority of people, like it or not, are not going to have PCs in the next 20 years.
Speaker 0: They will have phones, tablets, screens, devices that...
Speaker 1: TVs with computers built into them.
Speaker 0: And they will have data in the cloud and they will use this in their day-to-day lives.
Speaker 0: The only people who will need processing power and stuff are the experts.
Speaker 1: I mean, look at me.
Speaker 1: If I didn't... I could even see people...
Speaker 0: If I didn't play games and I didn't do podcasts and video, I would not need a desktop PC.
Speaker 1: The thing is, I even see... Right now, we're looking mostly at multimedia people, media creators, and programmers, right?
Speaker 1: I could even see the multimedia creators being shut out to where there's some sort of... Right?
Speaker 1: But then, instead of the iMac or the Mac Pro, it'll just be the art machine.
Speaker 1: And all it does is run the art programs and that's it.
Speaker 1: And it doesn't do anything else.
Speaker 1: And all the art people will buy it.
Speaker 1: It has a Wacom built into it or whatever.
Speaker 0: Now, that's a dangerous future for me because way back in the Napster days, and many of the people who actually understood what was going on... I remember people were saying, "Yeah,
Speaker 0: Napster.".
Speaker 0: And I was like, "Napster?
Speaker 0: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Just go to MP3
Speaker 0: sites."
Speaker 0: Sites.
Speaker 0: And then, that night, I was like, "Oh, what's
Speaker 0: Napster?".
Speaker 0: And actually, once I realized what it was...
Speaker 1: I was like, "Oh,
Speaker 1: shit.".
Speaker 0: I realized that the danger is not that we will event... The law will come down on people who violate intellectual property and they'll stop people who pirate stuff.
Speaker 0: Piracy is not the danger to all the people out there who want control.
Speaker 0: Piracy is just awesome.
Speaker 0: The danger to them is that people who have control over their own hardware can make their own stuff.
Speaker 0: That they can make their own movie and distribute it, and nobody can stop them, and nobody can compete with them, and there's no barrier to entry anymore to anything.
Speaker 0: And the lockdown world is going to try to prevent that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because not only...
Speaker 0: Look at iTunes.
Speaker 0: People like to use iTunes to get geek nights.
Speaker 0: Even iTunes dropped all of our individual episode feeds, and they only kept our main feed.
Speaker 0: We have no way to contest that.
Speaker 0: We have no control over that.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: You have to go side routes to say, "I want to use this URL for a particular RSS
Speaker 0: feed.".
Speaker 0: They basically said, "Fuck you
Speaker 0: guys.".
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's dangerous, I think, to the future of media distribution.
Speaker 1: It's very dangerous.
Speaker 1: What's even more dangerous is that when you have a closed platform, the tools of production are also controlled, right?
Speaker 0: Well, they're controlled now by the fact that Adobe sucks.
Speaker 1: It's like, "Look, you got an iPad.
Speaker 1: Well, look, you can take photos and you can draw doodles and you can write.
Speaker 1: It's like you can create these
Speaker 1: things.".
Speaker 1: But really, you don't have the full tools of production, right?
Speaker 1: That's why people always... There's this old argument that why you can't have freedom if you have communism, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, "I want to go and
Speaker 1: protest.".
Speaker 1: "All right, we'll let you protest.
Speaker 1: Go
Speaker 1: ahead.".
Speaker 1: "All right, let's go make some
Speaker 1: signs.".
Speaker 1: "All right, we got to go to paper to make all the
Speaker 1: "All right, let's go to the paper
Speaker 1: factory.".
Speaker 1: The state-run paper factory, right?
Speaker 1: "All right, I want to complain and I'm going to make a piece of software that's going to put Apple out of business using my Apple computer with Apple tools because it's the only computer.
Speaker 1: Shit, I can't make this thing on this Apple device because it's not possible.
Speaker 1: They would not make a tool that allowed me to put them out of business with their own
Speaker 1: tool.".
Speaker 0: We also have the argument that's much more tricky.
Speaker 0: Like with video games, I learned most of what I know about computers today because when I was a kid, I wanted to play computer games and that was goddamn impossible and I had to learn
Speaker 1: IRQs
Speaker 0: and DMAs and I would go into DOS and load drivers and futz with stuff and boot disks and that taught me like I'm a better person and a better gamer because of that and I'm a computer professional.
Speaker 0: I make boatloads of money, but at the same time, I could never justify going back to that shitty old medieval world of computing.
Speaker 1: No, but I think the thing is.
Speaker 1: I think that it is necessary for people to learn and that is the way that I learn, but I think there needs to be a way for new people to learn and perhaps intentionally suffering by choice or simulated suffering or something.
Speaker 1: Well, what
Speaker 0: I always say, and I think we've talked about this on Geek Nights, I don't want to get into a lot of detail, is that what we need is one, computer science and coding should be as important as math and reading and social studies in all levels of primary education.
Speaker 1: K through 12, fifth subject, every day, you know, every day you have math class.
Speaker 1: Kids should just learn C++.
Speaker 0: They should learn object-oriented programming alongside algebra.
Speaker 1: No, they should learn starting at the bottom.
Speaker 1: You should learn how a computer works.
Speaker 1: Then you got to learn how to program a computer.
Speaker 1: You know, you got to learn every possible level.
Speaker 1: You should know everything there is to know.
Speaker 1: K through 12, if you're going to computer class every day, you can learn everything from, you know, the electron on up to the C code.
Speaker 0: People don't necessarily, you know, there are people who are not good at math, but you know what, they still have to take math in high school and maybe they get C's.
Speaker 1: And they're not going to be mathematicians.
Speaker 0: And they don't take calculus.
Speaker 1: And they're just going to be a writer and they're never going to use math except to pay their bills.
Speaker 0: But at least they got as high in math as they were willing and capable of getting.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: But we don't give any kid the opportunity to do that in technology.
Speaker 0: The only people who learn technology.
Speaker 1: They can't even afford to pay teachers.
Speaker 1: How are they going to pay us to be teachers?
Speaker 1: The only people in this modern world.
Speaker 1: Our salary, they had to pay us as much as three teachers.
Speaker 0: Scott, do you agree that the only people who learn technology to any degree in the modern world are the people who are self-motivated and do it on their own?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well it's also people who have some external motivation.
Speaker 1: For example, you know, I care mostly about gaming, but I have to learn technology to do the gaming, so I do it.
Speaker 1: But as if computers get too easy, then that motivator goes away.
Speaker 1: I want to do art.
Speaker 1: I don't have to learn computers to do art because it's so easy.
Speaker 1: Ta-da!
Speaker 1: Now that person who would have learned computers and become a great person at computers 10, 20 years ago will not any longer.
Speaker 1: So the, you know, the number of people who have the possibility to, you know, control and manipulate technology is going to have a decreasing return as time goes on.
Speaker 0: Well, I think for one, the future is, just as I- It's already decreased pretty heavily.
Speaker 0: Just as I described, PCs are going to be an expert tool, much like an audio compressor is.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So at CES, there was this one news which brought this episode on.
Speaker 1: that makes the situation more dire, right?
Speaker 1: And ooh, dire.
Speaker 1: Ooh.
Speaker 1: Dire bear.
Speaker 1: Gar.
Speaker 1: Okay, so.
Speaker 1: Basically what the new- the biggest news at CES, I think, right, was that they announced that Windows 8 will run on an ARM CPU, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know how much technical detail I want to explain about this right now, but there is a big difference, you know, Intel CPUs are all x86.
Speaker 1: So are the AMDs.
Speaker 1: That's the CPU architecture.
Speaker 1: Didn't we do a CPU architecture episode?
Speaker 0: I think so.
Speaker 1: Go listen to that episode.
Speaker 1: Anyway, ARM CPUs, right, follow a completely different business model than the Intel x86 CPUs, right?
Speaker 1: You know, obviously the architecture of ARM, it's a better instruction set, it's all these other things, right?
Speaker 1: But here's the most important thing that matters to this discussion.
Speaker 1: The way Intel's business model works is that they pack in the transistors as tight as they can with the maximum density Moore's law, and they crank out the exact same CPU as much as they possibly can in high quantity, and they keep making it more and more powerful, and they charge a lot of money for the CPU itself, right?
Speaker 1: But all that CPU does is CPU.
Speaker 1: It doesn't really do anything else.
Speaker 1: So you build, when you make systems using these CPUs, you build everything around them.
Speaker 1: That's why you have a sound card.
Speaker 1: That's why you have a video card, right?
Speaker 1: Because it's not in there.
Speaker 1: I mean, some of them have video cards in them now, but it's not a good video.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to get into it, right?
Speaker 1: But that's the Intel business model.
Speaker 1: The ARM business model is completely different.
Speaker 1: They make what is called the system on a chip, right?
Speaker 1: If you're making a device, let's say me and Rem decide we want to make a tablet.
Speaker 1: Okay, Rem, we're going to make a tablet tomorrow.
Speaker 1: What do we want this tablet to have?
Speaker 1: We want it to have a 12-inch touch screen.
Speaker 1: We want it to be able to play MP3s.
Speaker 1: We want it to be able to have some wireless networking.
Speaker 1: We don't need any wired networking, and we're going to have a USB port, but we're not going to have any firewall, right?
Speaker 1: We make the list of all the things we're going to have, and then you go out, and you get someone to make you an ARM CPU.
Speaker 1: that has just those things and no other things.
Speaker 1: It's not about Moore's law.
Speaker 1: They can pack in so many transistors that they've got plenty of space, so they don't even pack it in as tight as they could to make it as fast as they could.
Speaker 0: So here's the TL;DR of that.
Speaker 1: They just make the custom system for that one device into that.
Speaker 0: The TL;DR of that is that it takes the power out of the programmers who have... I mean, it doesn't take resources to write code.
Speaker 0: It takes resources to make a chip to figure out a proprietary chip to do something on it.
Speaker 1: An ARM chip isn't proprietary.
Speaker 1: Linux runs on ARM.
Speaker 0: But a phone device has the particular limitations of what that phone can do.
Speaker 1: That is the problem, right?
Speaker 1: With an Intel CPU, all it does is CPU.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: So you put it in this motherboard, and you can add features, and you can do anything that is possible with computer technology by adding onto it.
Speaker 1: When you have the system-on-a-chip model, where this CPU, although it is ARM, and although you can program it easily enough, it is still unique to this one piece of hardware, or this line of hardware, and it only has these limited features.
Speaker 1: You really can't add to it that easily.
Speaker 1: The system is on the chip.
Speaker 1: It's not a system around the chip.
Speaker 1: So you can't be going like, "Oh shit, this thing doesn't play.
Speaker 1: It's got an MP3 decoder in it, and that's how it plays
Speaker 1: MP3s.".
Speaker 1: So I can't suddenly, if I try to make it play a different codec, I'll have to do that with the CPU.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have a hardware decoder, and it's not powerful enough that it drains the battery life, and that's that.
Speaker 1: So when you have a PC, even if it's not Intel x86 architecture, but your ability to do new things is limitless.
Speaker 1: When you have a system-on-a-chip, you are far more constrained just with the hardware.
Speaker 1: Even if it was open, you could put any code on there you wanted.
Speaker 1: You really couldn't do everything that you could think of, because you can't go adding stuff to it.
Speaker 1: You can't go, "Oh man, I should do
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's nothing on the chip to help you with that.
Speaker 0: So I think this is just part of the divergence between the expert system, the tool of the master, and the generic commodity appliance.
Speaker 1: And the thing is, I think that what you're going to see, you see Windows 8 is going to be on ARM.
Speaker 1: ARM is already number one, whether you realize it or not.
Speaker 1: It's going to become even more number one, and Intel and AMD are going to be hurting big, big time in the next year.
Speaker 1: Huge hurting, because the benefits of ARM, you'll see every DS has an ARM, by the way, two arms.
Speaker 0: Well, what's really going to end this?
Speaker 1: The main benefit is that you have incredible battery life, all these things that matter to the end user when they're on a closed system, just everything is better as far as they can tell.
Speaker 0: What's really going to end this, the big next step will be, because right now, one driver, it's a surprisingly large industry in terms of money, even though it's a relatively small segment of the population.
Speaker 0: PC gamers are going to eventually converge on Xbox between the two, and once all the things that PC, either PC gamers disappear, or the things that PC gamers like to do are done on more specialized hardware away from the generic PC, that's one of the last nails in the PC coffin for anyone who isn't a super computer expert.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know, it's kind of a murky gray area.
Speaker 1: It's like, well, are they going to make Xbox things run on the PC?
Speaker 1: Are they going to make on Xbox PC?
Speaker 0: I don't think Microsoft has decided what direction they're going.
Speaker 1: It's like, that's what Microsoft used to be pushing for.
Speaker 0: They were pushing forever for commodity hardware, and then you just run games on whichever console.
Speaker 1: A lot of people have tried that.
Speaker 1: Atari, well, I don't know if Atari did it on purpose.
Speaker 1: But 3DO was like, anyone who wants to can make a 3DO, and you just have to pay us money, and then people who make 3DO games did not work, did not work well at all.
Speaker 1: But Microsoft wanted that.
Speaker 1: They wanted to be like, all right, look, let's make a common gaming platform that anyone can make games for, and let it be one.
Speaker 0: That is the future.
Speaker 0: It's just, they tried to do it, at least they tried to push for it too soon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I can see them now coming out with the Xbox PC.
Speaker 0: The Xbox is basically just a Windows PC, kind of specialized.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It could be scary if you want to play computer games.
Speaker 1: and basically, what's Steam going to do?
Speaker 1: If Windows 8 is basically just an Xbox on your desk.
Speaker 0: It depends.
Speaker 0: Were I Steam, I would be talking to Microsoft and keeping negotiation channels open 24/7.
Speaker 1: If I were Microsoft, I would buy Valve.
Speaker 0: Oh, in a heartbeat.
Speaker 1: And then I would mix it all together, and then I would be the king.
Speaker 0: I would sell the gaming box.
Speaker 1: I would merge the Steam and Xbox networks together, and then because I was the king, I wouldn't need to charge for Xbox Live Gold.
Speaker 1: I'd just give everyone the free gold.
Speaker 0: That would basically shut PlayStation out, because then what would happen- PlayStation isn't shut out already?
Speaker 0: They're still there.
Speaker 0: I think the PlayStation line would die if that happened.
Speaker 0: I think Nintendo would continue on, but Nintendo is basically making the gaming appliance.
Speaker 1: I'm wary about Nintendo, because there's news that the 3DS is going to have five hours of battery life.
Speaker 1: Because it's basically running three screens, because you need two screens for the top, which is 3D.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's going to be rough.
Speaker 0: At the same time, their demographic has shifted quite a bit in the last few years.
Speaker 1: I'm also worried.
Speaker 1: It comes with a charging dock.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Do you have to hold the dock if you want to play it while charging?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm holding off.
Speaker 0: I'm basically not a Nintendo gamer anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: But that's a whole separate discussion.
Speaker 1: Oh, and if you're still thinking, "Oh, no.
Speaker 1: ARM's not going to take
Speaker 1: over."
Speaker 1: Well, look.
Speaker 1: Apple switched to Intel, but now they're switching to making their own CPUs.
Speaker 0: Well, look at the laptop market.
Speaker 0: How much the laptop market changed when the netbook appeared.
Speaker 0: Most people said, "I just need to get on the internet.
Speaker 0: I need the cheapest possible
Speaker 0: computer.".
Speaker 0: And now the netbook market is being destroyed by tablets and phones, because people realize they don't even need to type that much.
Speaker 1: Chrome OS is interesting.
Speaker 1: I got one of those Chrome laptops, but it's- It's not there.
Speaker 1: Well, it is.
Speaker 1: It's that managed experience.
Speaker 1: Here you go.
Speaker 1: It's a browser, but it's open.
Speaker 1: You can do anything as long as it's in the browser.
Speaker 1: And anyone can write a Chrome extension.
Speaker 1: You just can't write a Chrome extension on a Chrome laptop.
Speaker 1: You need a different one, unless there's something I don't know about.
Speaker 1: Maybe some sort of in-browser coder text editor program.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I guess you can find an in-browser SSH client to another machine somewhere.
Speaker 1: But basically, it's a web browser, so it's as easy to use as Chrome, because it's just Chrome.
Speaker 1: You log in with your Google account.
Speaker 1: All your data is stored safely, no matter what, in the clouds.
Speaker 1: It's not a thin client you're processing locally that actually has storage locally.
Speaker 1: It explodes, you can pick up another one just like it, and it'll look like exactly where you left off, 100%.
Speaker 1: It's completely secure, and it's actually architected software-wise, basically perfectly, in terms of being safe and secure, and not going to crash, and booting quickly, and all these things.
Speaker 1: But that's all it does, is browse the web.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not going to be editing my video on it.
Speaker 1: You can't install Napster on it unless you can get, as in a Chrome extension, Napster.
Speaker 1: Even if you could, you'd get some music onto it, and then it doesn't have much space.
Speaker 1: You have to store all your music on Google servers, and then if you want to listen to your music, you have to stream it down to listen.
Speaker 1: It can only do a codec if Chrome has the decoder, or you can get a... I don't know, I haven't found a way to install plugins.
Speaker 1: You can install Chrome extensions, and it comes with a Flash plugin already, but I can't find a way to add more plugins.
Speaker 1: You couldn't add more codecs unless you could add more plugins, or you could find a way to get that in extension.
Speaker 0: I think because we've gone on long enough, the short version of all this, is the PC dying?
Speaker 0: Yeah, kind of.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's not so good in some ways.
Speaker 1: A lot of people might, in their small, narrow view, think it's great.
Speaker 1: "Oh, these appliance PCs.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's so great.
Speaker 1: Everyone can use
Speaker 1: computers.".
Speaker 1: But in the wide world view, it may bring... there are some dystopian possibilities.
Speaker 0: Or it will make people like us God Kings.
Speaker 1: That's dystopian!
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: Well, Scott, because phallic is a cylinder, anything vaguely cylindrical is a phallic.
Speaker 1: Exactly my point.
Speaker 0: There are holes everywhere.
Speaker 1: Where are there holes?
Speaker 1: I don't see any holes.
Speaker 1: It's a rectangle.
Speaker 0: In fact, Scott, your computer has more vaginas than penises.
Speaker 0: Look at all those vaginas.
Speaker 1: If you find me a vagina that's a rectangle with sharp edges, I don't want to go near that vagina.