Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, May 17th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm sky and this is geek nights tonight in the year 2011.
Speaker 0: We talked about the game diplomacy from.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: All in all I'm very happy with my real phone as opposed to my free.
Speaker 0: They really couldn't do anything.
Speaker 1: Well, you know the pre had a nice interface.
Speaker 1: It was a good size has a better interface than either droid or iPhone by and you know when they first announced it I was like, oh shit.
Speaker 1: Look at this real competition.
Speaker 1: It was pretty excited and most I would have got if it had gone the wet, you know, it had fulfilled its potential.
Speaker 1: I probably would have been interested in generation to.
Speaker 0: most of the problems I had with it came down to the fact that it was you know Two-year-old hardware and there was no like like.
Speaker 0: there were never any updates for you.
Speaker 1: And I really liked how it integrated all the instant messaging and the text messaging together.
Speaker 1: Yeah, droid doesn't all the email together.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but one of the things like it was functional as a smartphone Except for Google Maps.
Speaker 0: because Google Maps it didn't have the new vector version.
Speaker 0: So basically if you didn't have great internet wherever you were it just wouldn't load Google Maps at all.
Speaker 0: But one thing that I'd overlooked.
Speaker 0: I didn't really think about games on the phone because the pre had no games None.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's actually games on droid and I actually played a couple of games.
Speaker 0: And all I have to say is Angry Birds is mildly entertaining.
Speaker 0: It is a three out of five flash game at best.
Speaker 1: That's you know, that's sort of the point, right?
Speaker 1: You're not gonna get any games on your phone that are gonna be like, oh my god.
Speaker 1: This game is amazing.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but what's what amazes me?
Speaker 0: I guess it doesn't amaze me.
Speaker 0: I should expect this but it interests me that of all the Similar level of flash game out there all the similar level of game you can make on a phone Angry Birds is the one that has such like cultural cachet.
Speaker 0: The reason is because the birds are cute.
Speaker 0: it's a dollar and then it was the free version.
Speaker 1: the birds are cute and It has fun noises.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the bird and the noises they make are pretty good and it's you know, I mean like hey You know, I agree three out of five is pretty much what I would give it.
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 1: I beat the whole thing.
Speaker 1: I even bought Angry Birds seasons.
Speaker 1: I paid two dollars to get every Angry Bird there is because you know It's not like I'm sitting there at home playing Angry Birds if I'm standing on the subway, you know Do look out the window.
Speaker 0: Based on total enjoyment over like over time like average unit enjoyment per unit time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can also rate them in total enjoyment overall.
Speaker 0: Because look at a game like QWOP.
Speaker 0: QWOP cannot be played for more than about a minute or two, that's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: but QWOP that minute or two was solid goddamn gold.
Speaker 0: primarily because there are other people watching.
Speaker 0: you try to play.
Speaker 1: Yep, but yeah, you know, there's all these cell phone games.
Speaker 1: mostly, you know, I got quite a few of them.
Speaker 1: They're pretty much mild entertainment that you know.
Speaker 1: The only reason that it's beneficial in any way is because you can play it very quickly.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of great DS games, you know, but the problem with DS games, you know It's their real games is that they're real games Which means you usually can't play them like in five minutes on the subway, you know You need like.
Speaker 1: I'll play.
Speaker 1: I play my DS primarily when I'm about to go to sleep and not when I'm on the subway.
Speaker 0: That's when I typically play Advance Wars every day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, you know, it's like, okay I read books or I'm about.
Speaker 1: I'm you know, I'm gonna play DS and then read a book or vice versa.
Speaker 1: You know cuz I'm laying in bed.
Speaker 1: I don't have a TV in front of me.
Speaker 1: That's when the DS comes in because it provides that middle ground of gaming.
Speaker 1: but you know game on the phone It's because you have your phone no matter what.
Speaker 1: sometimes you're stuck somewhere a waiting room Something and you just wanna.
Speaker 1: you can't really do anything productive.
Speaker 1: So at least occupy your mind with the blackbird dinner.
Speaker 0: Well, you can't just sit and think I Already did my sit and thinking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 1: I also sit and think while playing, you know Plus some of the you know, there are some games you can get.
Speaker 1: there was like when I first played bejeweled blitz on the phone.
Speaker 1: I really said all this is a game of randomness is basically if you get a really easy board You're gonna get a high score.
Speaker 1: But then week after week I noticed that other people are getting half a million and I never got half.
Speaker 1: And I was like there's more to this game.
Speaker 1: So I looked online At some but you'll wait.
Speaker 0: Wait, so it wasn't.
Speaker 0: so I tried to get better at the game.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 0: I looked online.
Speaker 1: So I looked online at what people are doing in bejeweled blitz.
Speaker 1: It is there is some advanced fucking play in bejeweled blitz.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you I could see that it is like.
Speaker 1: I thought I Wrongly judged the game thinking it was a game of luck Just getting an easy board.
Speaker 1: that would give you a high score and there is some of that right.
Speaker 1: if you get an easy board You're gonna get a higher score no matter how good you are, you know, yeah, but At the same time, you know, there are someone who's good is gonna get us, you know consistently higher score.
Speaker 1: There's significant speed factor going on, you know, if you can go fast You can get a high score on.
Speaker 1: you know, every time no matter what the board is.
Speaker 0: So we did Recently go to the no quarter exhibit the second of two in New York at the NYU gaming center.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was.
Speaker 1: it was small than I expected but you know, it was worth the trip over there.
Speaker 0: I mean it was neat to see.
Speaker 0: it was kind of like a series of exhibits.
Speaker 0: They had one really good game.
Speaker 0: It was basically this kind of ultra simplistic like in the style that we've been liking lately that we may or may not be doing A pax panel on that sort of game.
Speaker 0: Yep, or at least aspects of games like that Reminded me of you ever play American gladiators today.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that was actually a pretty damn good game.
Speaker 1: Well, it's parts of it.
Speaker 1: But yeah, the wall was hot.
Speaker 1: But you remember the one where you go?
Speaker 1: you're in the safe zone.
Speaker 1: You can get a. you get a ball in the safe zone and have to run into the danger zone where the gladiators are And put the ball in the baskets.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was sort of like that only maybe reversed.
Speaker 1: ish this one ball and you have to hold the ball in the goal zone.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: It was a lot like soccer for the Atari 2600.
Speaker 0: I didn't play that.
Speaker 0: really I've got it over there.
Speaker 1: No, let's go try it.
Speaker 0: It's a lot like it.
Speaker 0: Let's try it not as fun as Wizards of War or outlaw.
Speaker 0: Yeah The only.
Speaker 0: it's kind of a decide.
Speaker 0: the NYU Game Center I think is a great thing and clearly the people who are involved in it Really know their stuff and really enjoy being there.
Speaker 0: But in general I've noticed that there is a. it's not a trend.
Speaker 0: This is probably always been this way but being in the city and going to events like this Almost universally an event that provides free food and especially free beer doesn't have much else going on.
Speaker 0: I Mean this place was basically so crowded so fast that you could kind of just stand there in the crowd eating and drinking But you couldn't interact with any Game Center people or actually play any of the games.
Speaker 0: I have noticed this that they're you know, they're well like all those startup meetups or tech meetups or hacker meetups in the city.
Speaker 0: They're all the same.
Speaker 1: Well, no, that's why I was see the one that you went to right like that Like NY hacker.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those are all the same thing, right?
Speaker 1: But I was going for a time.
Speaker 1: I guess it.
Speaker 1: I don't know what happened to it, right?
Speaker 1: It just sort of.
Speaker 1: I missed one meeting and then I haven't heard about it since I'll guess I'll subscribe to it.
Speaker 1: But hack and tell was actually you have to go and someone who made something gives a you know A five-minute presentation and then another person goes another.
Speaker 1: so they were actually there was something happening at hack and tell which is why I liked It and I kept going to.
Speaker 0: I think what it comes down to is that event had an agenda.
Speaker 0: Yeah Many things do not have agendas and
Speaker 1: that's why I did stopped going to the NY hacker Town halls because it was pretty much stand around this free pizza and talk to people and it's like yeah Okay, I can network with people but the thing is I you know What a lot of the people who go to these things will also want to network, you know.
Speaker 1: And what do they have to sell?
Speaker 1: they're trying to hire you.
Speaker 1: they're trying to get you to use their product.
Speaker 1: They're trying to sell you on something right?
Speaker 1: It's like all I got to bring here is geek nights.
Speaker 1: It's like hey, you want to listen to geek nights?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know that works.
Speaker 1: if I'm given a panel It doesn't really work if you just walk up to someone to talk to them and especially when they're only interested in you know software because
Speaker 0: as much as I thought it works pretty well, but Unintentionally because what it ends up getting you is the guys like oh, yeah, you can interview me about my thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah but you know the thing is It's as much as we look down and like all these we go to anime cons and we're always confused about how the anime kids Don't care about games or technology The technology people.
Speaker 1: they actually do sort of care about video games in a shallow way because they all play them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they they also.
Speaker 1: they care about tech like 90% and they don't care about Any and this is the primary thing of geek nights.
Speaker 1: You should care about all the geekeries from cars to sports to technology.
Speaker 0: I would say more that you should have multiple areas of interest.
Speaker 1: Yes many as many as possible You know, even if something is not your area of interest if you see the lot of people are interested in it at least You know, what does it take?
Speaker 1: five minutes while you're bored at work?
Speaker 1: You know to learn the basics of some hobby that you have nothing to do with like.
Speaker 1: remember we were at the park and we Saw the people doing like the the mini remote control boats.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I read a couple web pages about remote control boats.
Speaker 1: It's not like I'm gonna get one or that I know enough to talk about it But I read because I was just interested to see what the deal is.
Speaker 0: So what's one interesting thing you learned about?
Speaker 0: remote-controlled boat hobbyists?
Speaker 1: Well bait like the way it steers is there's actually like a little spinning thing.
Speaker 1: It's tied to the string and when you under remote control You basically move the sail back and forth as opposed to like a rudder underneath the water.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I knew that.
Speaker 0: That's how those sailboats work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know that was like, oh I didn't realize But I don't have any advanced knowledge, right I mean, I basically have any.
Speaker 1: you know, I know I know but next to nothing but I know more than nothing.
Speaker 1: Which is you know, it's good to know Yeah And then if I meet someone and they happen to be into remote control boating I can have an okay conversation with them.
Speaker 0: So there's not a terrible amount of video game news That's really worth talking about right now and we're kind of in a lull of games being announced.
Speaker 0: 3ds is selling as well as it's gonna sell.
Speaker 0: So I kind of want to talk about because we've already talked about Nintendo's future in the 3ds and why we're not buying them Nintendo is transitioned from a buy sight unseen Company for us to a wait-and-see Company.
Speaker 1: only thing from Nintendo that I plan to buy is they're gonna come out with the skyward sword for the Wii, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I'm gonna get that because it's a Zelda game for the Wii But actually I have an expectation that it won't be so great.
Speaker 1: I think it'll be less good than was it Twilight Princess.
Speaker 0: Was that the Never even finished Twilight Princess?
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: it's just weird because I know that if you say whenever you had the word Twilight and Prince our goal I just get confused princess.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Celestia and I also get confused with like the vampire thing and Twilight struggle.
Speaker 1: There's too much going on there.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I think it'll be less good than that.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm actually downgrading my expectation of Nintendo in general because you know We talked already about a lot of the reasons why Nintendo's having trouble lately So I don't need to get into all of those.
Speaker 0: but to summarize then I'll call attention to two articles.
Speaker 0: Nintendo for one is really Really stepping up the region slash DRM situation.
Speaker 1: we knew this already when the 3ds came out.
Speaker 1: people read the terms of service and it said You know, we can break your 3ds if you like use an r4 or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is old people who were calling in Nintendo basically confirmed that no warranty like there's no way back if it gets brick.
Speaker 0: They said yeah, we'll say there might not be a way to recover.
Speaker 0: You might have to buy a new one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think they're you know, they're gonna.
Speaker 1: pretty much so.
Speaker 1: that's why I'm keeping on glad I got a DS lite not a DS I or anything like that.
Speaker 0: It also turns out according to this article that if you read the terms of service Nintendo pretty much collects and owns the rights to Any user-generated content that is generated with the device.
Speaker 1: That's incredible news to me.
Speaker 1: I was not aware at all.
Speaker 1: So that's like if you bought a camera from Nikon and you're a photographer and you take wedding photos.
Speaker 1: Nikon doesn't own those photos.
Speaker 0: I mean one.
Speaker 0: Nintendo reserves the right to collect all the user content Which they define as comments messages images photos movies information data.
Speaker 1: really all the penises of pictochat now belong to Nintendo.
Speaker 1: Yeah The world's largest database of penis doodles.
Speaker 0: that users grant Nintendo a worldwide royalty-free irrevocable perpetual non-exclusive and fully sub license of a license to use reproduce modify adapt publish translate create derivative works from distribute perform and display Your user content in whole or in part and to incorporate your user content into other works in any form media or technology Now known or later developed including other promotional or marketing purposes,
Speaker 1: man It's gonna be so great with like some
Speaker 0: parents Nintendo
Speaker 1: takes pictures of their kids on the 3ds and then the next thing they know it's you know, human centipod.
Speaker 0: when I Think the greatest thing.
Speaker 0: I mean, this is a great thing for consumers now Unlike any other time in history the entire world will see my balls.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I'm going to take pictures of nothing bought my balls.
Speaker 0: Yeah But independent of this I was reminded the other day that the 3ds is also region locked which Basically fucks one kind of person people who speak Japanese and English and are actually willing to pay for games.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean if you if the DS was any indication Right and actually now that I have an entire library of Game Boy and Game Boy Color and GBA games It's really it's been true since the Game Boy Is that the chip.
Speaker 1: in terms of portable games Japan has all the better games.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, I mean they've had all the better games in the past forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah forever.
Speaker 1: There's been tons of awesome games that they've had.
Speaker 1: that we have not had but it's actually been decreasing over time.
Speaker 1: They've had less cool exclusive Japanese games over time like in the Saturn era.
Speaker 1: They were like there was that one game.
Speaker 1: I forget what it was called But I could.
Speaker 1: I could if you had the cover of the game I could tell.
Speaker 0: but at the same time It might be that you're not looking for because I was in book off the other day with Emily Yeah, and I was looking through all the Japanese DS games In the portable realm right?
Speaker 1: There's just.
Speaker 1: it was like Game Boy Game Boy Color GBA DS.
Speaker 1: They have all these amazing games.
Speaker 1: We don't have right.
Speaker 1: it was even a miracle that we even got the Etrian odysseys over here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not that those are that great But still that's what I just I don't get.
Speaker 0: why like I really I tried to understand and I've come up with a bunch of Rationalizations, but I can understand why Nintendo's dr.
Speaker 0: Emming because you pirate every goddamn game now Yeah, but the thing is none of the.
Speaker 1: I can honestly say none of the games that I have pirated for the DS Right are games that I would have paid for If the piracy was not an option.
Speaker 1: and in fact, there are still games that I went out and bought like, you know I went out and bought.
Speaker 1: Even after I had the piracy card.
Speaker 1: I still bought games such as Miles Edgeworth investigations.
Speaker 0: What about Golden Sun DS?
Speaker 0: What about that might magic game?
Speaker 1: I'm buying that on the 360.
Speaker 1: I never would have bought the DS one.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I bought it.
Speaker 0: I played it.
Speaker 0: It was great.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna buy the Xbox one but I just Every rationale I can come up with for why Nintendo is actually for the first time region locking a portable console Doesn't actually make sense.
Speaker 0: If you assume that Nintendo actually wants to achieve the goal that I'm.
Speaker 0: assuming they're trying to achieve any goal I come up with it runs counter because the people who want to buy a Japanese game are the only people Who actually will buy a game and if they put DRM on it and prevent, you know They have region locking.
Speaker 1: those people really have two options pirate or not buy or buy two 3ds Japanese one and an English or because just by a Japanese one because isn't any game is gonna be in both.
Speaker 1: So if you can read both languages, what American game do you need?
Speaker 0: Ah, but then you run into trouble of trying to lend games to people.
Speaker 1: Nintendo has always had a history and actually It's sort of good and sort of bad right ever since the NES even earlier.
Speaker 1: I guess there is nothing earlier.
Speaker 1: Game and watch.
Speaker 0: Yeah game and watch.
Speaker 0: Are there Hanafuda cards?
Speaker 1: Nintendo has always always Attempted to make their games impossible to pirate, right?
Speaker 1: That's why the n64 used cartridges and that's why you know The like the GameCube.
Speaker 1: the discs were tiny and on the Wii, I think the disc spin backwards.
Speaker 0: Let's go back in time, but they don't do it.
Speaker 0: Let's go back in time.
Speaker 0: Imagine a world Where when Sony and square said hey, we want to use CD Nintendo said hells.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, if they hadn't failed There would be no PlayStation.
Speaker 1: Nintendo would still be the king.
Speaker 1: there might not even be an Xbox.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there might not have been an.
Speaker 0: I think there would have been an Xbox anyway But I don't think it would have been as big of a success Console the only console game in town to be Nintendo because there would have been no PlayStation.
Speaker 1: It would just been Nintendo Nintendo Nintendo.
Speaker 0: It's not like Neo Geo was gonna go anyway But it was an arcade game in your house.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was.
Speaker 0: Of course Nintendo is also right along these lines, you know The cafe project cafe the Wii successor is gonna have HD.
Speaker 0: So I guess they've decided you gotta have that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you have to.
Speaker 1: now they got that one wrong.
Speaker 0: I still say no I think in when the Wii came out it was fine to not have HD Yeah, but that was.
Speaker 1: that was true at that exact moment in time.
Speaker 1: But what they did not anticipate was that both halfway through the Wii's lifetime It would be unacceptable and which means that you know, it's sort of like, okay when the Wii came out We've life spent.
Speaker 0: they'd already sold all the wheeze.
Speaker 0: Who care course?
Speaker 0: and the people who bought them after that point are not the people who care about HD.
Speaker 0: Those were you know moms who heard about this.
Speaker 1: we spot as a result, right?
Speaker 1: It's killing.
Speaker 1: the lack of HD Caught forced them to not get a bunch of the cross-platform games, right that are on Platform games don't sell well on the Nintendo console.
Speaker 1: Oh, but maybe they would have.
Speaker 0: You know, I think one of the only ones that sold better on the Nintendo was a Soulcalibur 2 maybe No, that was the GameCube.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Thank you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but on the Wii, I mean what what?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean you could have gotten you know Street Fighter on the Wii or you could have gotten, you know.
Speaker 0: But even if the weed been HD, it would have been powerful enough to do the game.
Speaker 1: Anyway, why not?
Speaker 0: Because the Wii wasn't that powerful.
Speaker 1: I'm saying is that if the Wii was HD obviously would have been more power had they made it more powerful.
Speaker 0: It would have been more than $200 It's also true.
Speaker 0: and then they're brilliant.
Speaker 0: plan of selling just wheeze and one game would not have succeeded Mmm, but they're not gonna have a hard drive and they're having a relatively small amount of splash space supposedly in project cafe.
Speaker 0: So they're definitely committed to.
Speaker 1: it's all rumors, though You don't know that my true this is but even so that definitely makes a lot of sense.
Speaker 0: This is from tatilo.
Speaker 0: Okay Yeah, I'll trust him on this.
Speaker 0: All right But basically and we'll see what happens at e3 when they you know and you and they're actually going to reveal all this stuff.
Speaker 0: but Nintendo is pretty committed to only selling little games and retro games at high prices Online and they're really gonna focus on you buying discs.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I mean they've always done that right is they?
Speaker 1: they do everything they can they don't want to do.
Speaker 1: They don't do DRM in the way that Apple does DRM where you encrypt something and have a key.
Speaker 1: They do DRM where they physically make their technology Non-standard so and in and not interoperable to make it physically difficult to pirate the game.
Speaker 0: You couldn't on the PlayStation just you know, it was just a CD but you couldn't just copy it Wouldn't work.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: You had to mod the PlayStation to play a copy game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, but I mean it's like, you know, it's much more difficult to do these kinds of things on.
Speaker 1: you know The GameCube right?
Speaker 1: I mean people to put mod chips in the Wii because you know you we discs.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, you could pirate.
Speaker 0: we did games put them on an SD card Be any easier to pirate a game on the Xbox despite slightly more standard media because the Xbox is far more complicated.
Speaker 0: it's not like the old days when I took a chip a relatively simple chip that I bought overseas and Soldered it into the breadboard of my PlayStation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the way the Xbox Catches you right is that they go the route that Nintendo doesn't go which is a lot more internet control.
Speaker 1: the Xbox live you know, so if you start partying things on your Xbox the Xbox live cuts you off and your Xbox is now basically worthless because Online actually works.
Speaker 1: Nintendo doesn't have working online.
Speaker 1: So they can't threaten you with that.
Speaker 0: Why don't they have working online?
Speaker 1: Oh Nope they're retarded.
Speaker 0: so I'm downgrading personally my forecast of Nintendo's success in the future Mine was already downgraded.
Speaker 0: I was at like a three out of five.
Speaker 0: I was at a wait until they release a game I want and now I'm mad, you know, hope they release a game I want okay.
Speaker 1: So what if they come out with 3d advanced or so 3ds?
Speaker 0: I would wait till it came out and see what people said and try it somewhere before I'd buy it.
Speaker 1: But you'd buy a 3d.
Speaker 1: what if it was the only game that ever came out for 3ds, but it was great.
Speaker 1: Would you buy a 3ds and the game just for that?
Speaker 0: for that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: I Really need a new advanced wars game, right?
Speaker 0: Like it's it's pretty bad I think.
Speaker 1: you know, I think we've got to work now.
Speaker 0: You want to play some advanced wars?
Speaker 1: No, I think what we got to do is we have to work on making I think you were talking about with the couch TV.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well get this easy online advanced wars.
Speaker 1: ish clone nobody needs to buy it.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: I'm doing all.
Speaker 0: next week my c++ Two-week boot camp got pushed back to like July because I was apparently the only student.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, but I got a week-long like hardcore become a Python badass boot camp and I get to skip work all week.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: How about that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so right after that, let's get cracking.
Speaker 1: All right We get it.
Speaker 1: We get to design the thing first.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I already got some ideas to infantry.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I'll make up I'll make a proof of concept with just two inventories and then once we have that foundation Then we can design all the units and all that crap.
Speaker 0: and with the design I will use because we're you know Pecs dev is coming up.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about in the meta, but you know what?
Speaker 0: We'll talk about in the meta.
Speaker 0: What do you got in the news?
Speaker 1: What do I don't have a news?
Speaker 1: Oh, I do have a geek bite though So you may remember a long time ago is the thing of the day.
Speaker 1: the codex of a chemical engineering is a flash game.
Speaker 0: It's basically a game that tricks you into writing code.
Speaker 1: It's a programming game.
Speaker 1: That doesn't look like a programming game, right?
Speaker 1: It's flash.
Speaker 1: If you haven't played that you should go and play.
Speaker 0: it's great.
Speaker 0: There's a non programmers.
Speaker 0: It's great.
Speaker 1: Yes, the guy who made it Zach from Zach Tronics industries is basically a gaming design genius.
Speaker 0: We should get him on the show.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: Come on.
Speaker 0: I will make it happen.
Speaker 1: He's a genius Like oh my god, he's genius.
Speaker 1: Anyway, he made a game Couple months ago called space chem right and he came out and I was like, oh look at that It's another game from the Zach Tronic that genius guy on Steam.
Speaker 0: I bought it side unseen.
Speaker 0: I haven't played it yet, right?
Speaker 1: It's $15 on Steam because or 15 euros Yeah, which is a ripoff.
Speaker 1: but last week it was 750 on sale, which is when I bought it and that was a good price.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I'd buy it for 15, but it's basically codex level chemical engineering on double crack.
Speaker 1: It is oh my god the most amazing and basically the way this game what this game is about actually has a story.
Speaker 1: You're in space and you need to do chemistry, you know, it was really hard to not.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah basically, you know, it's.
Speaker 1: it's like Codex of a chemical engineering where you had to make you know machines that will take apart Elements and put them together into other elements, but he's instead of using alchemy like mercury and such he's using actual chemistry.
Speaker 1: So here's a carbon with four hydrogens attached to it.
Speaker 1: It's a methane.
Speaker 1: remove the hydrogens and then put them over here and put the carbon in the hydrogen over there You know and then make a carbon monoxide and an acetylene something over here and it's like oh my god How am I gonna do this?
Speaker 1: and then somehow you manage to do it?
Speaker 1: But you actually get to make multiple machines and link them together with pipes.
Speaker 1: So it's it's even more like programming because you can actually sort of write functions.
Speaker 1: You know each machine being you know a function and then you know and at the same time He also added the synchronized command.
Speaker 1: So you've actually you know I think if I remember correctly in codex civil chemical engineering all you did was write a program down the left-hand side.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and this one you actually on any given machine You have a red and a blue sort of worker that each have their own programs.
Speaker 1: You can have actually two programs running together just to make the machine work.
Speaker 0: Oh shit multi-threaded.
Speaker 1: and There is a a synchronized, you know command Signaling.
Speaker 1: so what if a?
Speaker 1: if a machine hits a synchronized command it'll wait there until the other machine hits a synchronized command And then both of them will resume.
Speaker 0: moving from that point I mean, it's rare that I can take a game and give you such a direct correlation to a real-life valuable skill.
Speaker 0: I mean war games.
Speaker 0: teach you abstract game theory to a degree, but that doesn't apply directly to your life in an obvious way.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean there are some things like I remember this guy wrote this article about how his kid was playing Pokemon cards And at first he was like a waste of money collecting.
Speaker 1: But then he noticed that the one thing his kid did learn from the Pokemon trading card game was the ability to do Arithmetic very quickly because you had to be like BAM 20 damage my debt.
Speaker 1: My health is now 80 and now I need three energy to do it, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, but it wasn't obvious in that that was kind of a side effect of the game.
Speaker 0: Of course wasn't a math game?
Speaker 0: Yes, of course, but this is the case where I mean what you just described is multi-threaded.
Speaker 1: You play space care.
Speaker 1: you like space cam like you really like it.
Speaker 1: you can't get enough of it.
Speaker 1: You should go into computer science because that's what you'll be doing all day every day.
Speaker 0: And if you hate this game, you really should not be going into computers.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, which is sucky because everyone needs to know computers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, really, but yeah, so yeah Even if you don't like it You should play space cam anyway so that you can stay up to date with the real world and not fall behind and be like a caveman Luddite.
Speaker 0: So things of the day as you all know this weekend is the rapture.
Speaker 0: Jesus coming back to kick our asses.
Speaker 0: the end Get ready.
Speaker 1: I have prepared many anti-jesus.
Speaker 0: I have pestered the people in Grand Central every day for the past several weeks.
Speaker 0: I every day ask them for their wallet.
Speaker 0: I asked him if they want to meet me on the 22nd.
Speaker 0: I asked him if I can have their house.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So I've got some anti-jesus weaponry prepared just in case.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we got.
Speaker 1: we got some upside-down crosses.
Speaker 1: obviously we got some.
Speaker 1: we got some.
Speaker 0: you know I feel like Jesus might be more afraid of a right-side-up cross.
Speaker 1: Well, we got.
Speaker 1: Really you think you?
Speaker 1: you think he'd rather be.
Speaker 1: Wouldn't it be so much worse if you're upside-down?
Speaker 0: But at the same time he was gotten by her eyesight up.
Speaker 0: one have some bad memories, right?
Speaker 1: So now it'd be like this time we're gonna hang you upside down.
Speaker 0: Of course my lookout to say that wouldn't really fit me.
Speaker 0: Oh upside down Yeah We got.
Speaker 1: we got some Works.
Speaker 1: no garlic works on vampires.
Speaker 1: You got vamp.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I gotta have actual vampires to fight against Jesus.
Speaker 0: Is he not undead?
Speaker 0: and one wouldn't you just turn on dead at like level 30?
Speaker 0: I Don't think.
Speaker 1: and we have some sharks because Jesus loves fish and sharks eat fish Scott.
Speaker 0: I have a much more powerful weapon.
Speaker 0: All right Socrates.
Speaker 0: Oh But Anonymous and I now speak on behalf of anonymous here by right now.
Speaker 1: No, you don't because everyone knows who you are.
Speaker 0: You're not speaking anonymously On behalf of them, but I'm not a member.
Speaker 1: There's a chain of custody that is broken whatever say what you got to say.
Speaker 0: So Anonymous is once again doing a call to arms and Anyone who's about to say how do you know it's really anonymous if you have to ask that question?
Speaker 0: You don't understand what anonymous is.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: They've decided to pull a worldwide prank and they're being pretty open about it on the internet because they figure People who are on the internet enough to notice this before it happens are not the people that they're going to target.
Speaker 1: That's correct.
Speaker 0: They're targeting local news and crackpots.
Speaker 0: Yep, basically on May 22nd 8 p.m.
Speaker 0: Eastern Daylight Time.
Speaker 1: I will be.
Speaker 1: this is a Sunday if I'm not mistaken.
Speaker 0: Yes It is this Sunday at 8 o'clock at night.
Speaker 1: Yes, I actually would probably will be home from bar camp But I'll be incredibly tired.
Speaker 1: I don't think I'll be able to participate due to physical You know disability.
Speaker 0: but I do wish I would participate because I am or call Your outlet of choice, maybe a local newspaper Maybe a crackpot conspiracy theorist blog, maybe your crazy friend who believes in Ron Paul You know, what are any of those people?
Speaker 0: maybe multiple if you're ambitious?
Speaker 0: Yeah and report that you're.
Speaker 0: you've seen a Triangle of eight or so yellow lights in the sky and has everyone see?
Speaker 1: it would be one thing if people started reporting UFOs.
Speaker 1: But if everyone all around the whole country starts reporting the same exact UFO I'm going to call local New York one from Skype, you know, New York one is actually.
Speaker 1: It's like people don't know this.
Speaker 1: it aren't from New York.
Speaker 1: New York one is this TV channel that you can only watch on Time Warner I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: And it's like the most boring Generic news.
Speaker 0: the temperatures 57 degrees, right?
Speaker 1: but the thing is because it's.
Speaker 1: it's because it's so boring.
Speaker 1: it actually kicks the shit out of say the Fox News's and the other all Sensational news is because it's just so.
Speaker 1: it's just normal news like Is in the city today giving a speech about X opposite side of the street parking has been suspended.
Speaker 1: If you're new if you're a New York person, it's actually pretty useful.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because no human can on their own know the actual rules of where you can and cannot park.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not you know, but there's a lot of things.
Speaker 1: the subway isn't working.
Speaker 1: There has been a you know, there's all sorts of.
Speaker 1: when you're in a city like New York There's a whole bunch of news that matters only to New York people.
Speaker 1: that doesn't mean anything to the rest of the country at all The rest of the world and New York one is a pretty good way to get that news.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna call them and I'm gonna email some crackpot that Scott Johnson knows.
Speaker 1: probably I would just go down the list of all the all the local TV where you know wherever you live.
Speaker 1: go down the list of all your local TV stations get your ABC CBS NBC Fox and Then call your local newspapers, you know and in like, you know Younger and puncher and not an adult who has responsibilities.
Speaker 0: I would call the police.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's ballsy I would go for it.
Speaker 1: Would you call the 911 or just 9-1-1?
Speaker 0: I'd call the local cops.
Speaker 1: Okay, you can do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I Guess they could get me for something and if I was 17, oh, yeah Yeah, anyway, that's my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Let's go for it.
Speaker 1: Okay So, oh, you want to think of the day - I do Chicken chicken.
Speaker 1: taking chicken chicken chicken chicken chicken chicken chicken chicken chicken chicken chicken chicken chicken chicken chicken chicken Chicken chicken chicken chicken chicken chicken chicken.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: This is pretty much the best present.
Speaker 1: I wanted to leave it at that, but I guess you ruined it.
Speaker 1: Wow But yeah, this guy he was at some sort of let's see This was presented at the triple-a s humor session in 2007. right Some sort of science, you know jokey thing sort of like the ignoble Awards.
Speaker 1: ish, right?
Speaker 1: basically, he went and gave this presentation PowerPoint and all he said during the whole thing was chicken and It was actually pretty hilarious is one of the best presentations I ever seen better than any of our panels.
Speaker 0: I have one very important thing to note.
Speaker 0: He took questions.
Speaker 0: He did take questions and only two questions were asked.
Speaker 1: They were might have seen this already because it has about a million YouTube views.
Speaker 0: they were without Exception the best question best questions.
Speaker 0: I've ever seen an audience member ever asked at any presentation I've ever seen in my entire life.
Speaker 0: That is true and That saddens me immensely.
Speaker 1: You gotta watch this video is great.
Speaker 1: And if you want to do panels at conventions or be a public speaker of any kind learn from this man.
Speaker 1: He has a valuable lesson to teach you.
Speaker 1: In fact, he has many valuable lessons to teach you.
Speaker 0: So very briefly in the meta moment bar camp is this weekend Saturday ends.
Speaker 1: Sunday.
Speaker 0: bar camp NYC Scott's a big part of it.
Speaker 0: You should also be a big part of it.
Speaker 1: I'll be there very tired on Saturday.
Speaker 1: Hopefully Sunday, I'll be okay, but the which is the must less attended day.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be calm for a while.
Speaker 0: No big conventions coming up.
Speaker 0: Connecticut submissions for panels are closed and I'm Desperately sorting through them and scheduling them and everything before the deadlines in front of me.
Speaker 0: The next big concept we'll be going to that you Tuesday folks will care about will be packs and probably packs dev and Along those lines I do want to say because Scott noticed all the books I got accused me of cheating because I kind of am cheating.
Speaker 0: We're up in the ante.
Speaker 0: We're gonna have at least one panel that's going to go way beyond what we've gone to before in terms of game theory Yeah, which means we have to learn it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm really up in the ante.
Speaker 0: on the math I'm actually working on specific actual Mathematical week solutions to some of the board games we've gotten.
Speaker 1: so when you feel when you finish up one of those books Give me it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Book is still Foundation Isaac Asimov.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's a classic.
Speaker 1: So I don't even read it, but it's a classic.
Speaker 1: so I picked it.
Speaker 1: You know, it's out.
Speaker 1: It's the kind of book that's like.
Speaker 1: oh, that's got to be a must read, right?
Speaker 1: Also, I do want to remind people how many t-shirts do we have left like six?
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are still six geek nice t-shirts in a box somewhere around here.
Speaker 1: You can buy them.
Speaker 1: if you go to front recruit calm and click on shop.
Speaker 1: You could buy one of those six t-shirts.
Speaker 1: They could be yours.
Speaker 0: There's not.
Speaker 1: on Europa They.
Speaker 0: someone ordered a shirt relatively recently and I forgot to ship it to you.
Speaker 0: So you'll get an email from me.
Speaker 1: Good job Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah rim is the one responsible for all the e-commerce thing.
Speaker 1: So if you're from a foreign country and you can't buy one I figured out how to handle that blame rim and they.
Speaker 0: I got an email from someone and soon as soon as I figure out The invoicing system I can take international orders by email or phone.
Speaker 1: Well, that'll probably take care of the six remaining shirts.
Speaker 0: I think so cuz we have at least six listeners overseas who want shirts and one.
Speaker 0: Yeah If you're the dude who didn't get your shirt because you ordered it and I forgot I'm gonna cut the price in like half when I ship it to you.
Speaker 0: Yeah Just just put some money in the box cuz we already made all the money a long time ago on those shirts.
Speaker 1: But we are gonna as soon as they run out We're gonna get more merch of some kind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got some stickers lined up.
Speaker 1: I was actually thinking there there's got to be some place that we can go right that give us like a whole merch Package like shirts and stickers shitty cafe, press.
Speaker 0: no I'm not like that to pay to code that we're not.
Speaker 0: we don't sell enough stuff to go to.
Speaker 1: No, like, you know like because when people are doing like promotions for the business, right?
Speaker 1: They'll have like shirts and pens and stickers and buttons and like a whole.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah a bunch of crap.
Speaker 0: I can get all that stuff from the place.
Speaker 0: I ordered the shirts from.
Speaker 1: yeah There's got to be a place that offers like a package deal as opposed to having to order each thing separately Like I want to order each thing separately would cost about the same.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you think there's no one who offers like a package deal where you don't think about it.
Speaker 0: I've done a lot of research on these fronts.
Speaker 0: I have really good really cheap suppliers.
Speaker 0: The only reason we don't have more merch is laziness coupled with a lack of artistic ability.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's really it All right.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, we're gonna work on it.
Speaker 0: So this weekend this past weekend we invited number of people over to play a board game from 1959 Mm-hmm board game took called diplomacy a game incredibly famous game.
Speaker 0: I'd always known I would argue It is not famous but infamous is both much like.
Speaker 0: well no, it is a game that many people is not obscure will refer to as the friend breaker that I think most gamers have heard of But few have actually ever played.
Speaker 0: it's a game that people talk about playing.
Speaker 0: They talk about that friend who played it.
Speaker 0: Maybe they saw a game of it at their local gaming con.
Speaker 0: I have known Maybe ten people in my life including the five people from this weekend who have actually played a game of diplomacy.
Speaker 1: to conclusion Yeah, I've never actually played diplomacy before but I knew you know, I had known that it was a game that existed.
Speaker 0: I had played once and I didn't finish that game at our way.
Speaker 1: I knew generally what it was about, but I didn't actually know the rules Specifically until very recently.
Speaker 0: so like months the internet said that the game takes about four hours to play.
Speaker 0: Wikipedia says the game takes at minimum four hours to play.
Speaker 1: All right, and the box box does not say all right That's weird.
Speaker 1: A box usually gives a time estimate.
Speaker 0: This is a game from It's right now.
Speaker 0: it's put out by Wiz ads of the coast used to be Avalon Hill Designed by Allen B. Kalhamer.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about him and I'm not gonna talk about the history of the game.
Speaker 0: Diplomacy is a game that you've got to really be committed to if you want to play.
Speaker 0: Diplomacy is an asshole game with ass old rules.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is clear.
Speaker 1: You know, it is not elegantly.
Speaker 1: I mean some things about it are clever right, but mostly the game is not elegant.
Speaker 1: It has many flaws The rules have many gotchas and errata's and it is not a smooth production and by any means.
Speaker 0: Well, it seemed simple until the second round of the game when immediately Everyone just made moves that created this circular clusterfuck.
Speaker 0: that took us like 20 minutes to unravel Yeah, only to determine that the end result was nothing.
Speaker 1: Well, we think it was nothing.
Speaker 1: I still can't get a clarify.
Speaker 0: I want to play again by mail, but I want to play again by computer.
Speaker 0: We talked about how diplomacy works.
Speaker 0: It's on the surface level.
Speaker 0: It is a simulation of a World War one esque conflict like a Franco-Prussian war something something in that era.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and all the players are basically were you know leaders of countries great power dictators great powers.
Speaker 0: So, you know Britain France Austria Turkey Russia turns out.
Speaker 0: none of my friends know what the fucking Russian flag looks like except me.
Speaker 1: I do now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you do now everyone does now everyone.
Speaker 0: I was like, alright, you think you know all the old flags, right?
Speaker 0: What's this one France?
Speaker 1: Nope Come on, it's red white and blue.
Speaker 0: Doesn't anyone know that the white is in the middle to symbolize that the royalty was splitting the nation in two?
Speaker 1: No, I won't.
Speaker 1: I do now.
Speaker 1: but yeah, my problem was that it's like, you know from you know, most of my life The Soviet flag was a flag that was so.
Speaker 1: be it flag the Soviet I know because Scott I knew that the Soviet flag was not the Russian flag, but it's just.
Speaker 1: I rarely saw the Russian flag.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, nobody knew Austria or Italy or anything.
Speaker 0: it was kind of amazing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I used to know flags more than I know them now.
Speaker 0: actually if you believe me It is actually a very apt simulation of the diplomacy surrounding World War one because we played for five hours and 28 minutes and at the end of that time It was a five-way draw.
Speaker 0: Yep, and everyone was dissatisfied with the result and Basically saying if we played more rounds I would have invaded X.
Speaker 1: Yeah leading directly into World War two Alright, so basically the way the game works and the thing that's clever about it Right is that everyone has units and every unit is worth exactly one.
Speaker 1: It's not like risk where you can get a numbers game like a high.
Speaker 1: I've got 40 attacking your five I win.
Speaker 1: it's you got one.
Speaker 0: you can have at most one unit per space and no army has a power Different from one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if I attack Scott in Silesia and he's in Silesia, it's one-on-one.
Speaker 0: I bounced back.
Speaker 0: nothing happens.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: No one gets defeated.
Speaker 0: No one gets destroyed Just nothing.
Speaker 1: now what he could do is he could attack with two which would then eject me, but it doesn't kill me It just makes me retreat to a different open country nearby.
Speaker 1: The only way I would die is if there was no open country nearby and I was trapped.
Speaker 1: then I would die.
Speaker 1: And the thing is you start the game with only what three units and Russia gets for Russia gets force You have barely any units and you control supply centers in your home country.
Speaker 0: And if you control one at the end, you know you to every other turn You'll get units so that you all lose units so that you have a number of units equal to the number of supply centers You control but said reinforcements can only come out of where you originally started.
Speaker 0: So even if I control 17 of those fuckers, I can only get new units in my home country.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty.
Speaker 1: basically the game makes it such that Unless you're already dominating like unless I've already taken someone over and now I've got two countries, you know worth of guys.
Speaker 1: My you know the ability.
Speaker 1: my ability to influence the game just based on my own decisions of where I'm gonna move my units and what orders I'm gonna give them is Basically nil.
Speaker 1: you can't do anything on your own because you have so few units and they're all equally powerful to everyone else's units You can't do anything.
Speaker 1: So you can't win the game just by sitting there making decisions like you do in every other board game.
Speaker 0: so here's where the game departs radically from what most people expect from a war game because it is really a Negotiation game a diplomacy game.
Speaker 0: Hence the title diplomacy.
Speaker 0: Yep one Everybody has your 15 minutes between every turn to talk.
Speaker 0: go walk away.
Speaker 1: You can do it every one.
Speaker 0: go out on the balcony go into the bathroom.
Speaker 0: Go outside.
Speaker 0: SMS someone doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: at the end of that time before the end of that time You have to have written down the orders for all your moves and put them in the hat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or box or whatever.
Speaker 0: The orders are all revealed and done simultaneously after the fact.
Speaker 0: Now secondary to this There are no Binding agreements in the game.
Speaker 0: The game is a non-cooperative game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can make all the agreements in the world, but nothing buying couldn't write up treaties.
Speaker 1: You can pretend to have a UN.
Speaker 1: you can do all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 0: We did form a League of Nations and had two meetings in the court in the context of the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah to decide the future of Europe after we the the inevitable horrid Stalemate.
Speaker 0: Yeah until I eventually betrayed my allies Russia and Turkey.
Speaker 0: Yeah You deserved it.
Speaker 1: Turkey I wasn't gonna be ineffectual completely ineffectual.
Speaker 1: I was ineffectual.
Speaker 1: I was very good.
Speaker 0: No, you weren't you.
Speaker 0: But Basically the other big thing about the game aside from the you know Aside from what I just told you is that the only way to really get anywhere is to coordinate your moves Very exactly.
Speaker 1: Yes, for example, let's say I want to attack rim here, right and I'm attacking him from Constantinople to You know Budapest, right and that's the move I'm gonna make and I need some help for my buddy in Russia.
Speaker 1: My buddy in Russia wants to support my attack on Budapest.
Speaker 0: He has to have a unit adjacent to the place Scott is going to attack and he has to script not attack But support and then the unit he is supporting and where it is going.
Speaker 1: So on his sheet.
Speaker 1: in order for him to actually help me win and attack rim and hurt rim He has to write on his sheet unit in Whatever place he's in supports attack from Constantinople to Budapest that's he has to write that which means he needs to know that I am going to make an attack from Constantinople to Budapest which means I need to tell him that and He needs to.
Speaker 1: so now I'm giving him information.
Speaker 1: That means I need to not lie to him and he needs to actually be faithful with our alliance or go through with it.
Speaker 0: He already talked to me and said look I'm really on your side.
Speaker 0: Let's eliminate everyone else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's figure out where is Scott's either going to attack in this place or that place.
Speaker 1: I'll pretend I'm gonna help him.
Speaker 1: We'll figure out which one of those two places is.
Speaker 1: then we'll know to support the defense of that place.
Speaker 0: I'll support an attack to cut off the support and dislodge the supporting unit.
Speaker 0: That's causing the attack to bounce back and messing up all your plans.
Speaker 1: We have to coordinate all that in the span of the 15 minutes And if you do that were to cut off the support, it'll make it look like that Russia did.
Speaker 1: it was trying to help me
Speaker 0: And It's complicated if I'm trying to coordinate this with my ally and my allies trying to fake out Scott I mean you only got 15 minutes and if I go off to talk to him on the balcony all secret Like
Speaker 1: Scott's gonna know something's up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can just look around the room and you know You've got all all that met all this stuff.
Speaker 1: that's meta in other games, right?
Speaker 1: Like oh, I see how you're holding your cards.
Speaker 1: That means you that stuff is meta in most games in diplomacy.
Speaker 1: That is the game.
Speaker 0: at one point I wrote down I will betray Scott this turn and I put it in the Hat and I was gonna hand the Hat to the people I needed to communicate this to.
Speaker 0: You know were supposedly on the opposite alliance and that was the best way I could come up with you.
Speaker 0: not let Scott and Richard Know that I was about to betray the ever-living fuck out of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one time so people tried to attempt to hide the Hat.
Speaker 1: that was that was clever.
Speaker 0: That was clever and hilarious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it didn't work.
Speaker 0: I mean the rules are if you just if you're not back You don't put your orders in all your units hold they just sit there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean my orders were complete went by the time ran out and did just because the Hat wasn't there.
Speaker 1: That does that doesn't mean that you know, yeah, just like punch the guy like yeah, that was the thing I was thinking.
Speaker 1: I was like, why don't we just punch people and tie people down?
Speaker 1: and it's like.
Speaker 1: well The thing is if you do that, then the game really is just beat doesn't?
Speaker 1: it's not diplomacy more just boxing.
Speaker 0: It's who is the fifth strongest man on Europe Island?
Speaker 1: Yes, you sort of have to be like, alright Nobody can break real laws while playing the game because otherwise it just breaks down and there's no point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know you're not gonna.
Speaker 1: you can't lock someone in a room or knock someone unconscious or drug someone.
Speaker 0: Oh the final important aspect of the game is that at any time any all the players?
Speaker 1: No, there's two aspects aspect.
Speaker 0: Number one is at any time any player can quit Yeah, you can quit which is something talked about in our panel.
Speaker 0: losing should be fun.
Speaker 0: Within the rules you could games have an ability for a player who's not having fun to just leave.
Speaker 1: you can just leave if it's Too much for you.
Speaker 1: if you're if you're tired of it Maybe you got hosed and you're ineffectual and no one likes you anymore and you don't have it in you to try to make someone.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like I'm not powerful enough So no one even wants my help.
Speaker 1: Right and this data?
Speaker 1: there's really nothing I can do to help them and I'm so weak that I can't be effectual on my own I might as well quit.
Speaker 0: you can quit gracefully the game allows for it, but you don't want to because The only way to end the game is either one person has to control 18 supply centers you start with three.
Speaker 1: that is basically impossible unless other people just let you.
Speaker 1: or if you have an ally you Roll and you keep playing for a long time.
Speaker 1: You could eventually get there but the instruction book even says the official instruction book says if you win that way you were playing it Wrong, or you're playing it right and all your friends is stupid.
Speaker 1: That's possible.
Speaker 0: So the way to end the game really is a vote among all players who have any number of military units still on the board.
Speaker 1: even if you have one unit left on the board you get the same number of votes as everyone else even a Unanimous vote.
Speaker 0: you end the game and everyone who voted shares the draw.
Speaker 0: Everyone who did not vote because they were not on the board loses.
Speaker 1: So even if you've got one unit left and some other guy has 17 another guy is seven.
Speaker 1: Basically, everyone has 17 or less and you have one and you all vote.
Speaker 1: you win just as much as those guys with 17.
Speaker 0: Now we were playing you understand for the championship belt which is a thing now in the crew dating back to the time of the vision and the bamboo.
Speaker 1: that's correct.
Speaker 0: and We ended up taking a picture of all five of us holding the belt.
Speaker 0: and what really happened was Five and a half hours into the game You know, we come down to an alliance of three and an alliance of two and the alliance of two was doing really well But they couldn't.
Speaker 0: they didn't have the momentum to push through and beat the alliance of three Even though they had a huge advantage due to early game stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, we actually you know operation invade Italy probably would have succeeded in significantly damaging the the alliance of two If you hadn't betrayed me on that vital turn, ah, but you could have waited one more turn.
Speaker 0: Invade Italy was going very well.
Speaker 0: you realize that France's operation invade Austria was about to begin and had I can followed through - I would have taken Italy and Lost Austria thus losing my ability to make new unit.
Speaker 0: That's fine and dandy by Turkey Yeah, and then you would have lost an ally and you would have been done.
Speaker 1: No, cuz down it once I once we had Italy we could have then retaken Austria on the next turn.
Speaker 0: I don't think you could have.
Speaker 1: you were thinking too short-term.
Speaker 0: also, I Was pretty much the most powerful person in my triple alliance because of the nature of the game had significant power.
Speaker 0: I just couldn't extend my power In a more centralized place and a more secure border, the only real threat to me was France.
Speaker 1: I had oh, I've actually had more units than you at many points in the game.
Speaker 0: My problem was that early on the geography of Turkey made it incredibly difficult to exert my force over great You know what early on in the game when you had more units than me that's when I was allied with you Yeah, and I was okay with that.
Speaker 0: Notice how soon as I had more units than you.
Speaker 0: betrayal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, jerk.
Speaker 0: part of it was that Russia was doing the best possible thing.
Speaker 0: It just turned out that Russia and England were very expertly countering each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they're basically at a stalemate.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile Turkey was at a stalemate coming around Greece and I was at a stalemate.
Speaker 1: France was incredibly too strong and me and rim had to team up to even hold him back and we were starting to Make a little bit of progress pushing him back But it was so slow and in the process of doing so we almost took Italy.
Speaker 1: if we had one more turn But in order to take that Italy rim was gonna leave his Austria open.
Speaker 0: and you realize that the double Alliance the Allies had been constantly offering me Great benefits to turn over power to them and join their Alliance.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but basically that was another problem.
Speaker 1: right is that you know?
Speaker 1: England and France teamed up.
Speaker 0: a hundred percent had absolutely no betray as they as is the smart thing to do in this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they were a complete lock together Absolutely, never betrayed each other.
Speaker 1: They left their backs open to each other and not once did they attack each other in the fatigueable.
Speaker 0: now You know why I betrayed you because remember two rounds before that we had our brilliant plan.
Speaker 0: It was our last ditch.
Speaker 0: I had that one army that was gonna try to scoot all over the bottom of Europe and pop out behind him.
Speaker 0: just conquer like Work.
Speaker 0: yeah, that didn't work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then I betrayed you but they the two of them were an equal counterbalance for the three of us.
Speaker 0: So I decided that if I join them we could roll you and then the game would end and the three of us would share victory, uh-huh Here's where the fundamental problem with the game of diplomacy the to to fundamental problems.
Speaker 0: three fanatical devotion comfy chair problem.
Speaker 0: the one at At minimum Not at minimum at maximum every turn takes 15 minutes plus resolving.
Speaker 0: So about 20 minutes total.
Speaker 0: Yep Say I had joined them in their Alliance and it's three.
Speaker 0: on to the three strongest players against the two weakest players.
Speaker 0: Victory is assured But it was gonna take us about Four to five turns to actually get into a position to eliminate Turkey and then Russia which would then you could have voted unanimously for a three-way victory Which would have been preferable to a five-way.
Speaker 0: So five turns to take out Turkey two more to finish off Russia.
Speaker 0: seven turns times minutes Because Scott and Richard Russia and Turkey being intelligent rather than quitting if their utility is to share victory would wait 14 minutes and 59 seconds every round to turn in their orders of support support hold.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: And it would have been incredibly difficult because of the geography involved for you to actually break those support hole.
Speaker 1: No, it would have been pretty easy because there weren't enough adjacent territories.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there were.
Speaker 1: you'd have to take them pretty much one or two at a time Yep, so you couldn't take like five in a big sweep no matter how close the problem war weariness is simulated Brilliantly in this game.
Speaker 0: hmm war weariness Actually happens because at five and a half hours.
Speaker 0: We were actually literally weary of the war Extremely.
Speaker 0: the people who were winning voted to share victory with Scott Because it wasn't worth another two or three hours of our lives to destroy him.
Speaker 1: I mean it would have been worth it if it was gonna be like, you know If someone who was close to scoring an individual victory on their own Might have been worth it to spend another hour to eliminate all remaining four players could have but to get basically 2/5 more victory divided amongst three people.
Speaker 1: so two fifths divided So two eighths.
Speaker 1: an extra court 25% of I don't know is not a lot of extra victory.
Speaker 0: But at the same time this is part of the reason why I think the game is in many ways brilliant.
Speaker 0: It just by us playing played out almost exactly the way World War one played.
Speaker 0: Absolutely.
Speaker 0: It fought to a stalemate.
Speaker 0: Eventually, everybody gave up.
Speaker 0: there was there were some nominal winners and nominal losers But every single nation thought in their minds if I just had the chance to continue the war I would totally win.
Speaker 1: World War two is coming up soon.
Speaker 1: Don't worry out.
Speaker 1: This is a sequel.
Speaker 1: So the other thing that is.
Speaker 0: second problem with the game.
Speaker 1: Yep the rules suck are.
Speaker 0: just Say it took us about a turn to run into very difficult to resolve situations and in the instruction book They have all these different examples of things that can happen.
Speaker 1: that might cause you know Conflicts where you won't know what to do and it tells you what to do if they happen.
Speaker 1: the thing that happened Immediately was not in those rules and I was like what the fuck.
Speaker 1: there's so many possible Arad is here and ways to handle weird situations.
Speaker 1: How did we so quickly in our first game on the second turn get a weird situation that is not in the book What the fuck and we didn't know what to do.
Speaker 1: So we just sort of you know, sort of figured.
Speaker 1: we should you know Let it be a standstill because it sort of made sense and it probably that may have been very well The correct thing to do in that situation.
Speaker 1: But I can't be a hundred percent sure and that drives me crazy in a board game where I'm trying to figure out the rules And I don't have a solid answer puts an asterisk on the whole thing.
Speaker 1: It's like ah, oh my god.
Speaker 0: but To be fair every gamer should play.
Speaker 0: if you're a board gamer.
Speaker 0: You should play diplomacy.
Speaker 1: You've got to know if you can find people who play with.
Speaker 0: you have got to get friends to play.
Speaker 0: get a full seven people Schedule a day and be like we're playing this motherfucking game.
Speaker 1: now A lot of people say it's like the friend killer.
Speaker 1: Someone won't be friends with you blah blah blah and in a way that is you know at first, you know Before I played the game.
Speaker 1: I was like, alright, you know anyone who thinks that obviously is such a shallow person About Illuminati.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly You know, I thought it was like, okay, you say it as a joke, you know, but it's like I was playing the game.
Speaker 1: It was you know at times I was a little bit grumbly.
Speaker 0: It's just like uh, you know She always actually like.
Speaker 0: I think you felt a little betrayed because no one saw my betrayal coming which well I did I point out.
Speaker 1: actually during that turn while you know I noticed that that was one turn where you had not let me see any part of your order sheet.
Speaker 1: Also, you were sort of looking around and poking and not saying much so I was like.
Speaker 1: I was guessing I'm like.
Speaker 1: Oh, is he gonna betray right now?
Speaker 1: So when you did I wasn't at all surprised.
Speaker 1: I was just sort of like oh he did.
Speaker 1: Yeah Had to happen, but it wasn't that.
Speaker 1: you know, I was grumbly before then.
Speaker 1: I just didn't because the game makes you feel grumbly because you're so ineffective all the time that it's not that you know It.
Speaker 0: just prance and britain were terribly effective.
Speaker 0: They were but I was.
Speaker 1: no we weren't.
Speaker 1: so I just the game can put you in an unpleasant mood very easily I would.
Speaker 1: I would do think though It's only a friend killer if you're really not friends to begin with yeah, and you're really immature and sad.
Speaker 1: Another thing about the particular game that we played is we only had five people.
Speaker 0: because we someone Make it two ponies didn't show up.
Speaker 0: So one of the ponies really should have come.
Speaker 0: you would had a good time Yeah, so there are two.
Speaker 1: basically it when you don't have six people right only what Germany Italy's empty Italy.
Speaker 0: if you play six Players Italy is neutral and all its units.
Speaker 1: I think that would have been.
Speaker 1: that would have been okay.
Speaker 1: But the major problem was that Germany and Italy were both neutral with a five player game would have been fine.
Speaker 1: Except what happened was the unit the unified alliance of France and Britain went straight east and just destroyed Italy and Germany and swept them.
Speaker 1: but meanwhile Russia and Austria rim.
Speaker 1: right day I went straight for you.
Speaker 1: they went straight for me in the bottom right corner Which made it much easier for France and England to come straight to the right unopposed and there wasn't anything pushing back on them Because nobody was playing as Germany or Italy.
Speaker 1: as a result in over the first two turns they got significantly more power.
Speaker 0: No, they got their power.
Speaker 0: They didn't actually take Germany or Italy in that time.
Speaker 0: They took it way later.
Speaker 0: They got all their power from taking Africa and Spain Yeah Which were completely empty.
Speaker 1: and you know no one was able to stop the baby.
Speaker 0: some pony had been able to get a fleet out There.
Speaker 0: I was.
Speaker 1: I supposed to get a fleet out there?
Speaker 1: I had to use my fleets to defend against you and Russia.
Speaker 1: you.
Speaker 0: I went down to get my fleet out there and your jackass Attacks from behind kept me from getting out.
Speaker 1: You might your attack my text from behind because you know if you just left your back unopened I wouldn't have taken it cuz I'm all honest and not evil, but I need to tell the third time To have my access out through the Adriatic Sea.
Speaker 1: and this is the thing.
Speaker 1: the geography of the game is real Geography is real geography, which makes it incredibly difficult and painful.
Speaker 1: quite often, you know and a lot of games Geography is often convenient.
Speaker 0: It's like alright you got geography is very convenient if you're Britain.
Speaker 1: But no think of a game like Vinci right and Vinci.
Speaker 1: the geography is often extremely convenient.
Speaker 1: It rarely causes you trouble, right?
Speaker 1: It's always like, you know some is better than others But it's like there's a mountain there when you need it to be a mountain and there's a. you know There's always a good spot right in diplomacy.
Speaker 1: There's only one spot and it's awful all the time.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's that bad.
Speaker 0: I think it's just more realistic.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: It's incredibly realistic.
Speaker 1: geography is awful Which is you know, the other games have maps where the geography is, you know designed for a game and is not awful.
Speaker 0: So at least in our game somewhat ironically Italy and Germany were partitioned by the greater powers.
Speaker 0: Mmm I just found that kind of beautiful in a way.
Speaker 0: It was really fun.
Speaker 0: as Exhausting as it was it was really fun.
Speaker 0: And I do want to play it again.
Speaker 1: I think I would only play.
Speaker 0: I want to play what it has to be.
Speaker 1: seven has to be seven.
Speaker 1: I can't play with the five.
Speaker 1: That's not gonna happen again I do.
Speaker 0: I want to play it at least one more time.
Speaker 0: also.
Speaker 1: Person we do think it's fairest to choose your starting countries randomly, but I really did not like being Turkey.
Speaker 0: I would have rather have been Turkey than Austria.
Speaker 1: You probably also would not like to be Austria.
Speaker 0: I would much rather seven player game.
Speaker 0: I would love to be Austria.
Speaker 1: I would.
Speaker 0: I would much rather because I would ally with Germany and Italy and we just go all out.
Speaker 0: That's possible.
Speaker 1: I would like to be France or Russia.
Speaker 1: If I had it, I wanted to be Russia or Britain.
Speaker 0: to be honest Britain I might.
Speaker 1: I might.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't mind being you know, we could do this.
Speaker 1: I do sort of feel though that like Britain is just the opposite Turkey.
Speaker 0: Yeah, here's how we do it.
Speaker 0: Everybody writes down the country.
Speaker 0: They want to be Secretly.
Speaker 0: we reveal them.
Speaker 0: if no one else wrote the country where you want it you get it and then for the people who contend We set up a system where they can't get the one they wanted.
Speaker 1: So anyone who wrote down a country that someone else wrote down they have to write down another country.
Speaker 0: They can't be the one they just wrote down two seconds ago Yep, and then we have to have an exception for it comes down to two people Coin.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that would work pretty well actually.
Speaker 1: But if it comes down to two people that means it's two free countries Unless they both want the same one, which is maybe unlikely who knows.
Speaker 1: but yeah, definitely I would only play again with seven people.
Speaker 0: So what I'm gonna do?
Speaker 1: one probably said there aren't all these easy pickings.
Speaker 1: and the worst part I think what made it more frustrating?
Speaker 1: or is it being Turkey?
Speaker 1: all the easy pickings were not adjacent to me.
Speaker 0: They were.
Speaker 0: if you'd gotten a fleet out.
Speaker 1: No, I had to I would have had to go through you to get to Italy or tunis.
Speaker 1: That's not.
Speaker 1: I'm not talking about the easy pickings that were just empty land.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about the easy pickings of Italy in Germany were not that easy But they weren't you.
Speaker 1: you were adjacent to them and I couldn't get there.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: To attack them.
Speaker 0: Well France and UK sure did yeah later After they'd already conquered the entire Western world.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, well anyway, yeah.
Speaker 0: But I think what I'm gonna do is I posted a link to the that online diplomacy.
Speaker 0: that looks pretty good.
Speaker 0: So after I sort out a bunch of geek nights work I have to do I'm gonna start up a seven player play by Internet game with like 48 hours for turns or something like something ludicrous.
Speaker 0: It'll be a long-term game where everyone who wants to play can play idly.
Speaker 1: I think that'll work better than what.
Speaker 1: what's that other game?
Speaker 1: We played Neptune's pride.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, is Neptune's pride was a lot of how often do you check it?
Speaker 1: And it was a lot of numbers.
Speaker 0: God Johnson always would brilliantly attack people at like 3 in the morning.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean that is the one thing about diplomacy right?
Speaker 1: is other games You know give you the option to ally or think, you know make deals and things like that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: and or trade.
Speaker 1: and you know, like risk or you know, shogun samurai sword shogun.
Speaker 0: Well, remember there's two kinds of games.
Speaker 0: There are cooperative games where deals are a part of the game like dune.
Speaker 0: Yep, and Those are not that realistic from a war standpoint.
Speaker 0: They're only realistic if you're doing like a commerce simulation
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 0: but non cooperative games like risk where there's no way to make a binding deal are More fun and more realistic from certain perspectives, but at the same time Because it's a game and not the real world Everyone's gonna get their ass betrayed in the end.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing with Rick the thing is right.
Speaker 1: so dune has binding deals Right, which means that you use the in-game mechanics to enforce your alliances is a cooperative game.
Speaker 1: You don't need to diplomacy.
Speaker 1: You don't need to actually do real diplomacy stuff, right?
Speaker 1: You don't need to because it's in the game.
Speaker 1: the worm comes up.
Speaker 1: You can ally with someone and you're good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not really diplomacy if you can prove that what you're doing is what you did.
Speaker 1: Yes at the same time risk.
Speaker 1: while you can make deals freeform and risk the same way you do in diplomacy and they're non binding You can enforce.
Speaker 1: basically there's a numbers game in risk that beats.
Speaker 1: that totally dominates any deals that you make.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't merely matter what deals you make in risk because numbers win.
Speaker 1: I got ten friggin units here.
Speaker 1: You got one that doesn't deals.
Speaker 1: don't matter because I could win just with the game mechanics.
Speaker 1: I don't need to win.
Speaker 0: Well more importantly means that if I want to enforce deals I have to one be a shrewd diplomat and to Have the ability to enforce the deals or punish people who renege on the deals within the context of the game.
Speaker 0: Yes, like if I make a deal with Scott like we are now a double Alliance.
Speaker 0: We're going to do X and Scott betrays me.
Speaker 0: I Or convince the rest of the world to help me like sanction him.
Speaker 1: Yeah but in diplomacy Right because every all units are equal.
Speaker 1: so you can't win with the game mechanics alone and the deals are non binding.
Speaker 1: You actually have to legitimately actually convince people in the real world for real in order to make any progress Which few other games have that?
Speaker 0: or you have to not convince them but can but have trick them into thinking That you have convinced that you have to think that you have convinced them when really, you know They're going to betray you and you betray them what basically by any means necessary.
Speaker 1: You need to get them to write orders on their order sheet.
Speaker 1: that are the orders that you want them to write on their order Sheet.
Speaker 0: no matter what that means is and I also know several times Multiple people cocked up complicated orders.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is actually pretty accurate to real warfare, especially in that era.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Napoleon tells Marat to go somewhere and that's the wrong place.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm the wrong place.
Speaker 1: At the same, you know, it's it reminds me a lot of traders of Genoa now just called Genoa Which is a game where you can trade anything for anything, you know.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of games that have trading like settlers, you know encoded in the rules.
Speaker 1: But in trades of Genoa, you can trade anything for anything using any means you want.
Speaker 1: you can make futures markets You can you can come up with any scheme you want and do it which is you know sort of like diplomacy where you can diplomacy in any way you want and There's not too many games that actually pull that off very well.
Speaker 1: So diplomacy.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's it's a game that you should play especially if you have an interest in game theory World War one.
Speaker 1: diplomacy Yeah, it's very.
Speaker 1: it's a very important game historically.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't I don't know how if you should, you know invest a whole bunch of your life into it But you should definitely play it once or twice learn about it Know the rules as much as they can be known.
Speaker 0: some people do some people get way into it.
Speaker 1: There's some people do Huge Tournaments, but you know, it's important to know, you know the way that you know, Star Wars is important for a film person to know.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.