Speaker 2: It's Tuesday November 8th 2011.
Speaker 2: I'm rim and this is geek nights.
Speaker 2: tonight We have Luke crane to talk about burning apocalypse car.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 2: So we're here with the the right honorable Luke crane.
Speaker 0: That's right, I've Right honorable.
Speaker 0: What what does that mean?
Speaker 0: I don't know what it like.
Speaker 0: what how do you get that title?
Speaker 2: I mean, maybe as opposed to wrong.
Speaker 1: I think it's for judges right.
Speaker 1: the wrong Judges are right honorable, right?
Speaker 0: So right.
Speaker 0: Do I wear the robes?
Speaker 0: Am I wearing robes right now guys?
Speaker 2: Oh, yes, you could be.
Speaker 2: I have just right in that closet.
Speaker 1: No, you have a like Close enough to nothing like.
Speaker 1: it's nothing like a judge's robe.
Speaker 1: It's not even close.
Speaker 2: It's very close Not even almost the same.
Speaker 0: Yeah any someone who calling this meeting to order?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 2: So the reason we brought her eyes we brought Luke in here is partly because I'm actually in Japan right now But and we needed a Tuesday show filler.
Speaker 2: more importantly burning apocalypse con is actually nigh.
Speaker 2: In fact, I'm gonna get back from Japan and then go to that the next weekend.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've mentioned this in the show many times.
Speaker 1: Burning apocalypse con is 11 11 11.
Speaker 1: I guess that's the date, you know.
Speaker 1: And it's not just burning.
Speaker 1: It's also apocalypse, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Last year for those of you who might remember last year On 10 10 10 it already feels like that was more than a year ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, it was a little bit was about.
Speaker 1: Okay, I guess it was but it feels like three years.
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: so yeah last year during cuz comic-con camped on my date, but anyway Last year at the weekend of 10 10 10 we ran a small con out here in a story.
Speaker 0: It was about 50 people and we played only burning wheel Mouse Guard Then burning empires through the whole weekend and it was really.
Speaker 0: it was way more fun than it should have been.
Speaker 2: It was pretty intense.
Speaker 2: I had not played burning wheel and that like concentration ever in my life.
Speaker 0: Yeah So I think that was the case for most people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like usually go to a con you're lucky to play once little load and five or six times.
Speaker 0: yeah, so it kind of.
Speaker 0: and we we developed a like a priority system for getting into games and And we had people come from all over the world and it just had a good feel to it.
Speaker 0: So as Everyone knows your second album always sells worse than your.
Speaker 0: So I was trying to think of a way to To do the second year and give it a boost rather than just kind of be like, oh, I've already done that I don't you know, I don't need to do that again.
Speaker 0: So I invited my friend Vincent Baker who is the author and designer of dogs in the vineyard Kill puppies for Satan a bunch of other games and apocalypse world and I said hey, let's so.
Speaker 0: so these like.
Speaker 0: so the convention is now like curated.
Speaker 0: This is the new hip word.
Speaker 0: It's it's a curated.
Speaker 0: basically you run.
Speaker 0: You know, you can only run a selection of these games.
Speaker 0: There's like, you know, ten games that you can run it though I know you put an other option.
Speaker 2: So of course I immediately submitted with a game that wasn't on any of the lists that was made by Jared Just for fun to see if you'd accept it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, so when?
Speaker 0: and it's.
Speaker 0: I didn't want the other option in there But my programmer because programmers just don't listen they always put another they do it.
Speaker 0: So he put it up there but he's vindicated.
Speaker 0: today somebody submitted a game that I didn't think of.
Speaker 0: Somebody submitted Rock of Tahamut, which is one of Vincent's small experimental games.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 0: So that's really cool.
Speaker 0: So now we have a rock of Tom out of.
Speaker 0: would it be okay to play?
Speaker 1: Arabian nice.
Speaker 1: didn't his wife make that?
Speaker 0: that is a Megway Baker game.
Speaker 0: Not a Vincent Baker game.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: There you go Vincent's name.
Speaker 0: basically his name has to be in the design credits for it.
Speaker 0: Like somebody wanted to play dungeon your name or my name, right?
Speaker 0: Somebody wanted to play dungeon world, which is a hack of one of his games But his name isn't in the design credits.
Speaker 0: like he didn't actually work on the design.
Speaker 2: Well the fact that you even got to the point of thinking about that case that scenario of the mod of the game Someone probably submitted it right?
Speaker 0: That's probably why well someone asked right away, but I mean I had thought about it beforehand like yeah Your name's gonna be in the credit.
Speaker 0: So So Yeah, so we're gonna have probably between 70 and 80 people this time in man, Manhattan.
Speaker 0: Okay, you're at 440 studios right 40 the same place that they do recess.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Yeah, we're gonna do a party on November 11th and then November 12th and 13th, we'll have games all day Down there, so we'll have five slots of games and just like last year you run one session and you play four sessions And it's gonna be a good time
Speaker 1: All right, so what would you say to someone who is like, you know, maybe not familiar with you know Luke crane or Vincent Baker like should they even come now the game now?
Speaker 0: No, straight up don't don't show us just chill out go go to recess or something.
Speaker 0: There are other other events.
Speaker 0: It's not a good environment for someone who doesn't know what they want to walk into.
Speaker 0: I mean unless they're just really outgoing really forward really, you know interested in this stuff, but Because you got to run a game So it's hardcore on purpose.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, and you just you want it that way and you're fine with it.
Speaker 1: You're not going forget as many people to show up as possible.
Speaker 0: I don't want people to come to this to slouch and just be like.
Speaker 0: I want people to come to this and be challenged, right?
Speaker 0: I want them to be challenged and stand like just to Raise themselves up to run a game.
Speaker 0: I mean I had this last year.
Speaker 0: I was totally right.
Speaker 0: I demanded people run games and that that were like, I don't know I don't know and they did and they had a great time and they learned a lot.
Speaker 0: And like there's this whole mystique about running a game that it's hard or that it's required special skills.
Speaker 0: It's such a bullshit.
Speaker 0: And people I get this all the time people tell me about your gming.
Speaker 0: Why do you do this?
Speaker 0: How do you GM?
Speaker 0: I'm like, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I just run games.
Speaker 0: You should run games.
Speaker 1: Well, I think I think that's you know, the problem I've seen in GM I mean at least you know personally is like in order to get good at it You have to do it a lot, but it to do it a lot starting from never having done it You have to do it a lot badly first.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which means people have to suffer in your crappy games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not like if you're if you're a bad to get art it to be an artist.
Speaker 1: you draw a bunch of crappy drawings But no one else is to suffer them Right, but it did to be a GM to get your practice.
Speaker 1: other people have to you know.
Speaker 1: So it's the people who started GM in high school could win.
Speaker 1: when your high school friends didn't care about your bad GMing that got good at it.
Speaker 2: Oh, they cared that.
Speaker 2: I'm an infamous GM from high school, right?
Speaker 1: But if you start when you're older, you know, 20 30 year old people aren't gonna put up with this first time GM.
Speaker 1: They don't have time for that.
Speaker 0: So so yeah, I definitely see what you're saying.
Speaker 0: And you know just like any skill you start younger earlier and you keep practicing it.
Speaker 0: You're gonna be good at it You're better at it.
Speaker 0: but in this the environment that we have here where everyone knows that everyone has to run a game and That most people are familiar with most of the games you get great players supporting You know kind of timid GMs and you can and they can.
Speaker 0: they help them.
Speaker 0: They they drive the games forward and they they raise the quality of the whole event.
Speaker 0: That is something
Speaker 2: I see when I see people playing burning wheel that I never saw with D&D Where the game master flubs a rule or doesn't really know what to do and the players make suggestions like oh You should make him roll this or no, that's clearly Whatever skill as opposed to jump because he's doing this one thing and the GM's often go along with it because it makes sense.
Speaker 2: Yeah, you never see that in D&D.
Speaker 2: No It's like.
Speaker 1: I mean this, you know, well that happens to us all the times like that's not sword That's it.
Speaker 1: that happens to us pretty much every time we've been playing recently.
Speaker 2: No, that happens to us because you and are basically the backseat game master.
Speaker 1: Well, no, but we're always like.
Speaker 1: we're always like what skills should we use?
Speaker 1: and we're like It's the game of what skill and it's like.
Speaker 1: well, how about this one?
Speaker 1: You know, is that really composition?
Speaker 2: I mean, she's just trying to write for someone.
Speaker 1: right that just happened.
Speaker 1: It was composition or writing.
Speaker 2: Yeah, we had a failed write test followed by a failed read test.
Speaker 2: It was awesome.
Speaker 0: Those are good ones.
Speaker 0: yeah, burning wheels a little skilly but and I do the same thing and we we.
Speaker 0: So I'll usually keep my mouth shut up to a point until because I because if I speak up everyone like listens Which is oh you have life, but that's what we want.
Speaker 0: We want you to write.
Speaker 0: No, no one should listen to me Just play the goddamn game as I wrote it.
Speaker 0: so But but we'll do that in my group too.
Speaker 0: We'll make suggestions and and so right because the rules are meant to be transparent and it's just it's.
Speaker 0: there's not meant to be Any mystique to it?
Speaker 0: So the Yeah, there's not.
Speaker 0: it's not like the GM has this kind of final say or anything like that.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna burp and And So.
Speaker 0: so anyway, so you you just get You you get games in public which are better for it, you know especially if everyone's kind of open to input because
Speaker 1: if I don't know what skill to use this someone at the next table who maybe knows
Speaker 0: sure but also like Like we expect the GM to say hey, well, you're stuck for an idea.
Speaker 0: Why don't you do this?
Speaker 0: I see no reason why the you know, the GM stuck for an idea.
Speaker 0: the players can't say Hey, you know, why not try this?
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: yeah, I'm actually you know, since the con is gonna be so hardcore I'm actually kind of got to do a lot of reading because I own all the Vincent's games But I actually don't know how to play almost any Doing some reading
Speaker 2: to bring them up at conventions like we'll do a panel like hey all the indie RPGs We always mention all his games and all your games and
Speaker 1: it's like I own.
Speaker 2: I give him the two-sentence summary of each one But I haven't.
Speaker 1: it's like I own apocalypse world.
Speaker 1: I've haven't I don't think I've read a single page of it.
Speaker 2: I've never run enough free market.
Speaker 2: Even I've only played it with you.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got it.
Speaker 1: We got to work on that.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I think that's great.
Speaker 0: I think that we're all gonna challenge myself included.
Speaker 0: I have not yet sat down to play apocalypse world.
Speaker 0: I read it and I you know, I'd love to play it.
Speaker 0: I love the genre.
Speaker 0: So You know there and we have a good mix of games right now.
Speaker 0: We have you know, four or five free market games.
Speaker 0: We have No, well a bunch of a bunch of burning wheel a bunch apocalypse world some, you know mouse guard one burning empires game.
Speaker 0: Whoa Yeah, I'm excited the the scenario That he pitched me is really good.
Speaker 0: So And then just a smattering of other stuff a couple dogs games a couple in a wicked age games.
Speaker 1: I Never even heard of any wicked agent.
Speaker 1: I got something to buy.
Speaker 0: That's one of his.
Speaker 0: yeah He'll you can buy it at the con.
Speaker 0: He'll have a lot of stuff there.
Speaker 0: So yeah, one more thing I wanted to talk about for 11 11 11 for the the burning apocalypse con is that Tragically one of our really close friends one of the editors of the burning wheel books and one of the GM's for burning apocalypse con had a severe stroke and He is been hospitalized for the past two weeks and will be hospitalized For probably a couple more.
Speaker 0: he's recovering and he's and they're saying he's gonna make a full recovery.
Speaker 0: But no, it's a rather traumatic experience.
Speaker 0: He was a key for the past two weeks.
Speaker 0: He's been paralyzed, you know the left side of his body.
Speaker 0: so I wanted to let everyone know that for 11 11 11 we're going to Use it as a fundraising event to help him try to pay his bills and that I'm gonna produce a custom mouse guard hack Hopefully for 11 11 11 if not then shortly thereafter Since there's a lot of planning to do in addition to writing.
Speaker 2: pretty sure if you don't make it by 11 11 11 You'll be able to take pledges and I'm pretty sure people will commit to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I'm gonna make a custom hack and then the proceeds from that will.
Speaker 0: we will split them between My friend and myself.
Speaker 1: now that the hack isn't gonna be only available at 11 11 level though You know, no, no internet for everybody.
Speaker 0: It'll be up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean at 11 11 11 It's gonna be a pile of notes.
Speaker 2: So at the very end you got to take that pile of notes and then sell that at a charity auction at like magfest.
Speaker 2: That's not bad, I mean the rape clock went for like 700.
Speaker 1: You just make sure make sure that when you put it up there That you let it instead, you know Don't set a price.
Speaker 1: make it like pay what you want because there'll be people who will give more.
Speaker 1: right if you make it five Bucks someone's like, oh, you know rather than buy two for ten bucks.
Speaker 1: They'll just want to give you 20 for the one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, I was thinking that basically yeah, it's gonna be a pay what you want.
Speaker 0: scheme for the hack.
Speaker 2: Yeah Yeah, well, I mean even non charity purely commercial ventures that do that tend to go do very well Right, right.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I figured you guys would want to know and your listeners might want to know too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so yeah if you like the way burning wheel books are edited if you like the fact that the lists are alphabetized and All the weapon stats are you know, correct and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: It's this.
Speaker 0: this is the guy that does all that editing.
Speaker 0: he's the guy who does the really niche II stuff that make sure everything's in order and The stuff that most people don't think about.
Speaker 2: you guys now surprisingly important to my life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the the stuff that that you would be surprised you'd think that Luke Crane could do that.
Speaker 1: No All right, so I guess enough about you.
Speaker 1: Let's do fun stuff.
Speaker 1: So have you heard about this risk legacy game that's coming out?
Speaker 1: I want I want to know your opinions.
Speaker 0: I have only heard the vaguest of things about this.
Speaker 1: Okay, so there's a new risk coming out.
Speaker 1: It was designed by Rob Davia and someone else whose name I could get from board game geek if I wanted to.
Speaker 1: Sorry, sorry other guy And basically it's a risk.
Speaker 1: right you roll dice you attack countries.
Speaker 1: the Ukraine is weak the whole thing, right?
Speaker 1: But I think it's.
Speaker 1: I think it's a future sci-fi with different races And the most important thing which is strangely revolutionary is that it's persistent, right?
Speaker 1: So I haven't read the rules completely but what it looks like is When you start the game Like you pick a race and you choose one of two powers and you tear up the card and throw it away And then like well the
Speaker 2: board itself you write you put
Speaker 1: five stickers on the board You write the names of cities on and territories on the board.
Speaker 1: That is crazy, right?
Speaker 1: So it but it's like, you know, it's weird in that in video games Persistence is something that's been around since muds.
Speaker 2: It's also something that usually pisses me off.
Speaker 2: They take a stateless game like counter-strike to add persistence.
Speaker 2: I'm mad.
Speaker 2: Yeah, we're mad about it too.
Speaker 1: that like ruin the game, but it's something that's always been in RPGs, right?
Speaker 1: You level up your character is persistent right to take the persistence and put it into the the regular old board game.
Speaker 1: It's strange that it hasn't been done earlier.
Speaker 0: That's cool.
Speaker 2: Like as soon as I heard about it, I was just dumbfounded that I hadn't thought of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well cuz I mean my first impulse would be like nobody would pay for that Nobody would play that game, but then you would get collectors who would buy it and then that would be it Which is cool in and of its own right, but that's excuse me.
Speaker 0: That sounds very very cool.
Speaker 1: I definitely think hardcore people would probably buy to Not put the stickers on the board.
Speaker 1: They would just sort of cut the sticker out maybe and sort of put it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're gonna get all sorts of weird Contortion print out.
Speaker 1: so people just put all the disposable stuff aside and print out their own copies to use to play.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, yeah, you know with maybe post-it notes and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: But but mo like the whatever mainstream families out there, you know who buy it will play it and probably hate each other afterwards Because you're gonna be tearing up card.
Speaker 0: Like can you imagine your Christmas present is that?
Speaker 0: and you either that I get it and you you're taking immediately tearing it up and writing.
Speaker 0: I know that.
Speaker 2: what if like your dad tears up your card because he's nuked you and now that's on the board forever.
Speaker 0: That's Amazing.
Speaker 0: I love that to death.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I can see tears.
Speaker 0: I see tears in the future.
Speaker 2: Interestingly the price point is at the upper end of German board game price.
Speaker 2: It's like 60 bucks something like that.
Speaker 1: It's expensive.
Speaker 2: Well, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, they must have us some kind of like reusable components in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah Basically from what I understand is you can you play it X number of times like 12 13 times and every time you play it You something changes.
Speaker 1: you're still modifying the game, but we're rich the world in some way, right?
Speaker 1: But when you're all done with those 13 playthroughs or however many it is Then you can still play risk on that board with all the modifications that have happened to it.
Speaker 1: But you just don't modify it anymore and you're playing.
Speaker 1: sentence.
Speaker 1: Now that set is set in stone.
Speaker 2: It might actually be different from another set that is done plan because you're playing in rims world the winner at the very end Names the world Wow and writes it on the board with.
Speaker 2: I'm so jealous Yeah, so like we got to make some games to do this now because it's definitely opened up a whole new world I think I think it's gonna do the same thing that Dominion did.
Speaker 2: that Dominion came out and then there's a million Dominion clones.
Speaker 2: I was tricked by Thunderstone.
Speaker 2: I was like, oh dungeon crawl Dominion.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was the second one, right?
Speaker 1: It's terrible.
Speaker 1: I usually the.
Speaker 1: have you seen quarryers.
Speaker 1: It's Nice building game my card.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's a dice building.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: So you say instead of buying cards for your deck you buy dice.
Speaker 1: you put them in a bag.
Speaker 1: You draw five dice out of the bag and you roll them.
Speaker 1: So you need Dominion.
Speaker 1: you buy a card.
Speaker 1: the card always does what it does But in quarryers you buy a die.
Speaker 1: There's a chance.
Speaker 1: it might do one thing as a chance.
Speaker 1: It might do another thing because you roll it every time you play it.
Speaker 1: I Think that's the most clever one I've seen.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we got it.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking dungeon crawl like, you know Raven law hero quest hero quest where you put stickers on the board Breaking dies or doesn't die and then that you know, you open the envelope.
Speaker 2: It's like the king died.
Speaker 2: Oh shit Like.
Speaker 2: maybe there's one scary envelope.
Speaker 2: the whole game.
Speaker 2: It's like if Rowan dies, you even know who Rowan is.
Speaker 2: when you start playing The game like you see you find Rowan and then everyone's like him.
Speaker 1: That's the coolest thing at the envelopes with like rules in them that you don't open until the time is right.
Speaker 0: Ah, that's so cool.
Speaker 0: Wow, well good job guys.
Speaker 0: I mean, I was really jealous.
Speaker 2: I was really surprised like I did not expect that this to happen like this kind of game Especially for risk to be the game that they're doing it with Because risk is like Monopoly.
Speaker 2: It's kind of like this venerable game that everyone played as a kid and hates.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's the thing.
Speaker 0: It's like a template.
Speaker 0: It's these you know, this kind of raw squishy template like much like D&D that you can Then start banging and hacking around into other stuff.
Speaker 0: I I have I have hacked up risk a little bit.
Speaker 0: when I was developing a Napoleonic version of burning wheel I was looking at Down with that.
Speaker 2: I love that shit But I was trying to make my own mod of it to run a ship game where everyone's on like a British Navy vessel Mmm, like a quarter way through that and I gave up.
Speaker 0: I had I have ship combat rules somewhere in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had like you my ship combat rules are fun, too.
Speaker 0: Like you could pretty much grab any object and use it as a ship, right so you could play it on any surface.
Speaker 0: Use anything you like, you know, we would have had paper cutouts or something like that.
Speaker 0: But that but we also.
Speaker 0: but the the system of measurement was relative.
Speaker 0: It was lengths.
Speaker 0: So it was lengths of x-ship lengths of a bar.
Speaker 0: So so right, so whatever you if you had a pencil as a ship then you move that pencil, you know It moved ten lengths as it moved two pencils forward.
Speaker 1: But if so, if I've got a pencil and you've got a penny then you're in trouble.
Speaker 0: Well that you would move pencil links you whatever like when you set the lengths of not It's not.
Speaker 0: you would move lengths of your ship.
Speaker 1: You would like you could set the length at anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then the yeah, you're right because you don't need to all have rulers and warhead.
Speaker 2: I don't bring.
Speaker 2: my pencil is longer than your pencils.
Speaker 2: I have a better pencil.
Speaker 0: So What the hell.
Speaker 0: why did I just talk about that?
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 2: No, no, I want it.
Speaker 2: I really want it.
Speaker 0: So we I one of the things I was working on those I was I was gonna cannibalize a risk set to be the like warfare mechanic Cuz because one of the versions of risk had cannons horsemen.
Speaker 2: Yep It's right there on the corner.
Speaker 2: I've got it.
Speaker 2: It has that mod with the Ottomans and the cat the bases The castles.
Speaker 1: No, I think the one is the one I had which is slow But that's the one newer that.
Speaker 2: but that set also has the cannons and the horses not just the little try whatever right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, the just they pretty still like around ten years ago.
Speaker 2: So when was the last time you played a game of risk all the way through?
Speaker 2: It ended in victory as opposed to the table being flipped Vericon At a con.
Speaker 0: No, no, it was after Vericon in maybe 2004 okay.
Speaker 1: That's actually pretty reason.
Speaker 2: That's about 14 does five and it was When we had our risk tournament at RIT that one time maybe.
Speaker 0: yeah, it was one of the.
Speaker 0: it was a very Informative night of play And I well, I realized it always I you know, I had This revelations about why I didn't like risk.
Speaker 0: I won't go so far as to say that why risk is fucking broken but why say that?
Speaker 0: because the My friend was winning and he was quite happy about winning, but he wouldn't win Mmm purpose on purpose.
Speaker 2: Oh Yeah, so there and there's one thing we couldn't like you're holed up in Australia and he just can't break through.
Speaker 0: Oh, I was holed up in Australia was it was that scenario, but there was no like.
Speaker 0: there was nothing I could do.
Speaker 0: There was no like.
Speaker 0: I didn't have any cards.
Speaker 0: I only had this many troops on the table Like I couldn't.
Speaker 0: you know, I you know the.
Speaker 0: for my turn I would have to like attack him and like, you know Do one round of combat and then stop or whatever like because it was nothing to be done.
Speaker 0: But he wouldn't he would just he would do the same thing.
Speaker 0: He wouldn't Actually win he would just play around and then just like basically he was just dumping units on the board To try to get up to whatever the maximum unit level is.
Speaker 0: and you know, even though I had four territories There's nothing I could do.
Speaker 0: And it was very very informative like wow, there's something going on here.
Speaker 0: There's something wrong the fact that this is a game about world conquest and and it has to come to this inevitable conclusion.
Speaker 0: But there's nothing here driving play toward that conclusion.
Speaker 0: It's you know, it could continue like this indefinitely And that is problematic.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I mean look in his case his utility was get stuff on the board.
Speaker 2: piss off Luke.
Speaker 0: Yes Yeah, yeah, absolutely, right, which is interesting from a kind of sociological anthropological standpoint Not so interesting from a gameplay standpoint.
Speaker 1: So so what games have you played recently like, you know?
Speaker 1: Have you played a game recently?
Speaker 0: Oh Lord what well my my funny that you mentioned Napoleonic.
Speaker 0: so my love.
Speaker 0: this year This past year has been the commanding colors Napoleonic Which.
Speaker 0: so that's the guys who made memoir.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's free on Steam now, you can just play it.
Speaker 2: remember out 44 online.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's cool.
Speaker 0: So So that was That I've had that.
Speaker 0: I haven't played it nearly enough but I really enjoy that.
Speaker 2: Don't be tricked into getting battle lore.
Speaker 0: No, I I played battle or a couple times and I just couldn't deal My battle or said yeah, you can have it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I really I played it like once that all my friends I know they played it like once.
Speaker 0: they don't like it.
Speaker 0: So So Napoleonic I've also been playing.
Speaker 0: some of you.
Speaker 0: your listeners might have heard me interview about With with genocides Jen about Greg Stafford's Pendragon.
Speaker 2: Yeah We're gonna play that I think after Scott Spends a year or two training.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I was like how much like how much Arthurian stuff?
Speaker 1: Do I need to know because I started reading it and it was like, you know It's like I don't know anything about heraldry.
Speaker 1: So how much like heraldry do I have to learn in real world in order to do you have the just the rulebook?
Speaker 0: Pendragon.
Speaker 1: I have to get the other one though like the campaign one, right?
Speaker 0: The campaign will walk you through everything.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't have to go and read like more to Arthur to learn.
Speaker 0: You should because it's cool anyway, but the point no, no the great Pendragon campaign has everything is exhaustive So me but it's like.
Speaker 1: so if I'm gonna run this do I have to read that entire?
Speaker 1: Campaign or can I just turn to page one and sort of begin the campaign that you totally it's on rails, dude You don't need to read ahead.
Speaker 1: You don't need to read ahead.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's like you can read ahead for like the next week or whatever, but it's totally on rails.
Speaker 1: So it's pretty much just read the rule book then open up the big book and start playing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean obviously I read like the first, you know bunch of pages in the big one to know what it's coming up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, otherwise the camp.
Speaker 1: it would be a little weird if we're sitting there playing again, but I'm reading a whole page.
Speaker 1: Let people wait.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, don't do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you really want to familiarize yourself with the the basic mechanics.
Speaker 0: They're gonna be a little bit different than what you're used to.
Speaker 0: No kidding Like how you get bonuses how you apply like and apply them How you make contested tests like how you make an uncontested test like it's just a little bit different.
Speaker 0: I have you played hero quest whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay, so so then you're.
Speaker 0: then you're good.
Speaker 0: You're good for that the I was gonna say passions.
Speaker 0: You're gonna want to learn how to how passions work and how traits work and and you're you're going to have to pick out like you're gonna figure out kind of what the authority level of the GM is in the game.
Speaker 0: like when you can make someone make a passion test one you can make them make a trait test, you know.
Speaker 0: when you can just you know fuck with them in other ways because there's The.
Speaker 0: the GM has some kind of really hard sticks that he can hit the players with In addition.
Speaker 1: so if you hit too often then well, no you hard no you need to hit.
Speaker 0: You need to every time the players cross that line.
Speaker 0: You need to hit them with the stick in the game.
Speaker 0: Otherwise the game breaks down.
Speaker 0: Otherwise if it's like parenting it's like if you're inconsistent like oh you did that once but it was fine then.
Speaker 0: but now no BAM It'll drive those people crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's actually harder though because it's like You know something that I always have a problem with a running burning wheel and other things like.
Speaker 1: I forget to do the steel test You know, you just don't remember right, you know, or you forget to do a dwarven greed test.
Speaker 1: So forgetting to hit with the stick, you know, if that's very important there.
Speaker 0: It's yeah, but it's uh, the game's a lot more Confined to these things than it is.
Speaker 0: then burning wheel is it's not a quite as a man So, you know for people have no idea where it's at.
Speaker 1: Well, like what is what is the game like?
Speaker 1: It's obviously a king Arthur Arthurian legend.
Speaker 2: It was described to me by Scott as I was giving it somehow just as awesome.
Speaker 1: It's like I gave him like a second hand description based on a half reading of the rules and listening to you on another podcast.
Speaker 2: So he's like, you don't make any decisions.
Speaker 2: You have no control.
Speaker 2: I just tell you what happens and it sounds awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: It's a really amazing game design.
Speaker 0: It's it's unique For a role-playing game.
Speaker 0: One of if I'm not mistaken one of Greg Stafford's priorities when designing it was to take Control away from the players and put it and so make to make the character a little less Controllable so that the players couldn't simply walk up to can't walk up to Uther and just knife him, right?
Speaker 0: You can't be like I'll take Arthur ha ha ha You can't do any of that stuff because your your character has these these traits and passions and all these kind of Rules that it that the character must abide by.
Speaker 0: and the thing is they're not just simply strictures laid down of.
Speaker 0: no You can't do that.
Speaker 0: It's All built into the fiction of the game.
Speaker 0: to like it all makes sense.
Speaker 0: your character Basically, if you push him too far in one direction, he'll start to act like a knight in that period.
Speaker 0: he'll start to behave like In that manner and and you basically you the player will be confronted with okay, you have to behave in that manner.
Speaker 0: What do you do now?
Speaker 0: It doesn't say exactly what you have to do.
Speaker 0: It doesn't say like you must do X but it says okay, you hate Saxons.
Speaker 0: the Saxons are asking you for emissary.
Speaker 0: What do you do?
Speaker 0: You have to hate them.
Speaker 0: You have to figure out some way to manifest that hatred here.
Speaker 0: And so it's.
Speaker 0: it's hard.
Speaker 0: It's really challenging on the players But it's amazing how it Produces, you know, it does what it says it's supposed to do.
Speaker 0: It's really neat.
Speaker 2: So by the end you've basically played out the entire Arthurian legend Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So how long have you been playing this?
Speaker 0: We played about 14 sessions.
Speaker 0: We're on hiatus right now because we pretty much Knifed each other.
Speaker 1: Okay How far along through the big book did you get?
Speaker 1: and we're in the session where the anarchy?
Speaker 0: Period where I think at four nine nine nine or five hundred.
Speaker 1: Well, how many pages like how you know percentage wise?
Speaker 0: Oh, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm not the GM.
Speaker 1: How many sessions would it take to get to the end?
Speaker 1: You know It goes off to the end.
Speaker 1: It's over.
Speaker 0: It's like two or two and a half years of play or something.
Speaker 1: Okay playing every month every week every every week.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow.
Speaker 2: So in other words like eight to ten years Our burning wheel game is lucky if it's every other week.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, it's a. it's a really amazing piece of work.
Speaker 0: how he's taken the mythology and made this game out of it.
Speaker 0: and The one of the frustrating things for us is that you weren't.
Speaker 0: you're not important in the mythology In any.
Speaker 1: you're not playing as Arthur Lancelot right there.
Speaker 0: No can you cannot.
Speaker 1: yeah, you have to be sir dicks a lot or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yep, I am sir gee.
Speaker 0: I Can't remember my last my manner like a French.
Speaker 0: Whatever Sir guy I'm sir gee of sir gee.
Speaker 0: the cruel is my character.
Speaker 0: Are you actually cruel?
Speaker 0: I am the cruelest man in all of Britain.
Speaker 1: So why are you allowed to be a knight if you're so mean?
Speaker 0: cruelty is not Cruelty and mercy that their opposites are not important.
Speaker 1: See your peasants are just pissed.
Speaker 1: They hate you.
Speaker 0: No, I'm actually really loyal to my pens.
Speaker 0: I'm actually the most loyal man in all of Britain as well.
Speaker 1: Oh, so I'm cruel to the people who try to fuck with your oh my god Like if say if I come and they know I'm trying to like I will take you into my basement and torture you.
Speaker 0: This is this is how I did.
Speaker 2: He start out that cruel.
Speaker 0: He started out a little less cruel.
Speaker 0: I decided my last character died.
Speaker 0: I played kind of a a knight who was more interested in intrigue in court and stuff like that and I got a lance through my chest.
Speaker 0: So in a joust or just or in court ending in a joust Okay with another night, which I got at court and I have the same lance skill as him.
Speaker 0: So yeah prepare to die a lot.
Speaker 0: So I decided to play a man more of the age and since the age is about fighting and killing shit I made a guy who was a little bit better at being At fighting killing shit and I just wanted to play against hype for this.
Speaker 0: I'm actually hurting myself by playing a cruel night.
Speaker 0: You can because you can be.
Speaker 0: You can be Like a virtuous night and you can be religious right?
Speaker 1: So the cruel night is not gonna get the Holy Grail, right?
Speaker 1: It's just not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think so the but so I'm.
Speaker 0: I lose out on a hundred glory a year, which is a big deal because Yeah, which is a really big deal because I've amped my cruelty up so high
Speaker 1: that seems to be from reading the rules Like the number one thing is just get as much glory
Speaker 0: as possible.
Speaker 0: The game is weird and its priorities like it's actual gameplay priorities like the kind of the behavior that it rewards because there's all these great ways that it sculpts your behavior and makes you behave like a You know like a knight in this age and the Knights in this age are complicated creatures.
Speaker 0: They're violent, you know angry But you know religious.
Speaker 0: but also they're loyal and honorable and tolerant.
Speaker 0: and you know, it's weird It's cool, you know, so that the characters have a lot of nuance to them.
Speaker 0: but You in order to survive the the rigors of the age the perils of the age You have to acquire glory.
Speaker 0: and in order to acquire glory, you need to be hungrier.
Speaker 0: hungrier than a fucking fifth-level magic user.
Speaker 0: So Yeah, you really need to be gunning for those points all the time and you need to be like pushing aside your fellow players.
Speaker 0: I mean like no No I will speak to with her and you know I will lead the charge.
Speaker 0: and like every time you need to be like climbing over each other for glory.
Speaker 1: hmm Ready to fight for glory instead of what you believe?
Speaker 2: Well Give it a year.
Speaker 2: Do you studying?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll start off maybe by the time I'm 50 maybe actually, you know That's another thing is I look forward to.
Speaker 1: you know, we haven't yet had like the group of like retired nerds.
Speaker 1: All right If you're retired and you're a nerd you can write that two and a half years.
Speaker 1: suddenly you're not playing every week You're playing every day Maybe every day for three hours.
Speaker 0: You're I think I would not be friends with my friends if I play that game.
Speaker 1: But Yeah, you can get it done in a few months.
Speaker 1: that way right sure All right.
Speaker 1: All right Anything else?
Speaker 1: Is there anything else you want to talk about anything fun?
Speaker 1: You've been doing lately?
Speaker 0: So I well, so just related to that I Apparently I'm going to be on the genocides again With Greg Stafford the author of Pendragon.
Speaker 1: All right, I definitely tweet that out so I can.
Speaker 0: so I can get I will.
Speaker 0: I will I'll put it on the Twitter.
Speaker 0: But yes, that will be after the 11 11 11 con.
Speaker 1: so also I guess to be Tangential the new burning wheel is out To you.
Speaker 2: since then we have not even talked about burning wheel gold.
Speaker 2: We have not actually played it.
Speaker 2: Our game is still burning wheel revised.
Speaker 2: We haven't done one version.
Speaker 0: Oh cool Yeah, I think you guys will like it.
Speaker 0: Everyone says that It's smoother more, you know more streamlined easier to reference and whatnot.
Speaker 2: So what's that?
Speaker 2: What's the guiding philosophy of burning wheel gold?
Speaker 2: Like what was the like your main intent in?
Speaker 2: Creating it as opposed to revise.
Speaker 2: Do you have a mission statement?
Speaker 2: or was it just let's fix this.
Speaker 2: Let's fix this.
Speaker 0: It was ARG.
Speaker 0: shut the fuck up.
Speaker 0: Stop arguing about that.
Speaker 1: So what were people arguing about?
Speaker 0: at least the major thing one of the things that drove me nuts.
Speaker 0: Burning wheel gold's been in the works for years, but you know just to what extent it was gonna come in at and Was up in the air.
Speaker 0: It's one of the things that that one of the the defining moments was.
Speaker 0: on the forums there was like a 20 page debate about positioning and You know, I like ranging cover positioning or fight positioning both Fight positioning and I. I like those rules and they you know, they're they're fun.
Speaker 0: But I was like, I'm reading the stuff.
Speaker 0: I'm like, this isn't what my game is about.
Speaker 0: My game does not.
Speaker 0: I just don't care and no one should care this much about the.
Speaker 0: you know If you have a spear and you're at lunging and you you know, how do you withdraw?
Speaker 2: I feel like sometimes I cared and sometimes I didn't.
Speaker 2: Okay, well it depended on what kind of game it was and what was going on in the game at the time.
Speaker 2: sure.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean burning wheels flexible like that too.
Speaker 0: Like you don't.
Speaker 0: sometimes you just don't have to care about the fight rules That's fine.
Speaker 0: But there just was way too much energy being expended on that shit.
Speaker 0: so You know, I was like, alright, I know I can just tweak this.
Speaker 0: Of course now all of those same people are like but but but but so don't play the old game still exists.
Speaker 0: No, it's not that they love the new rules, but they're just they have to question every Iota of the new rules.
Speaker 0: and I'm just like, oh god.
Speaker 0: So So I just wanted to to clean things up but also was economical was Putting everyone's like, oh god, it's so cheap.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, actually the two books with the bellyband way more expensive than doing one a single hardcover.
Speaker 1: So I So rather than print more of the you know, the old ones print a new one.
Speaker 1: save money, right?
Speaker 0: You know, yeah, and so right we were.
Speaker 1: if you're gonna print a new one might as well update it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: and yeah, right it was just was the you know, good timing that things are going out of print.
Speaker 0: we had time Yeah, and there were some stuff.
Speaker 0: I wanted to fix it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I was also just sick of sorcerers whining Incessant whining from everyone around source.
Speaker 0: So I mean I just I just there was whining.
Speaker 1: even after the magic burner came out.
Speaker 1: They're still whining.
Speaker 0: Oh god.
Speaker 0: I hate magic.
Speaker 0: I Hate.
Speaker 1: I know you didn't like magic because it wasn't in there to begin with.
Speaker 0: I mean not really anyway, so I took some dice away from sorcerers and it's just It's better overall.
Speaker 0: They I just brought them kind of in line with the advancement system and brought them you know in line with just the skill check system and like everything.
Speaker 0: so they They aren't quite as special anymore.
Speaker 0: They can still whatever pew boom.
Speaker 2: You're dead, but it's all about shards.
Speaker 0: it's charts is a good one, but there's a. There's fewer dice in play and you know, so the range is is tighter.
Speaker 0: The statistical range is tighter, which is nice Less madness.
Speaker 2: So I found to be the insane killing machine That's unstoppable have to be like the gray shade elf now and not the human sorcerer.
Speaker 0: I mean Starting off, you know, if you want to be a human sorcerer like burning wheels kind of like agnostic to this like whatever.
Speaker 0: Do whatever you want you know if you want to be a burning wheel sorcerer with your B6 sorcery and a bunch of forks and your white fire and your turn aside the blade whatever and that's it.
Speaker 0: You're just naked running around me.
Speaker 0: If that's your kind of game like I want you to play it I want you to have fun with it.
Speaker 0: But you know, I'm you're not playing that in my game But I ultimately The elf will always be more powerful.
Speaker 0: Like if you're gonna if you like you want to go toe-to-toe all the way out to the top Maybe it maybe a dwarf would be the most dark elf.
Speaker 2: definitely That seems to be something people always like like when we show people burning wheel to replay it.
Speaker 2: They like the fact that it's not balanced because I think they've gotten the point with Dungeons & Dragons where it's too balanced right door.
Speaker 2: no matter what you are, you're all Exactly equally powerful in all generic situations.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I was just never into that.
Speaker 0: I like it's not.
Speaker 0: It's not really necessary from a role-playing game standpoint because role-playing games aren't competitive.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: it's not really necessary from a narrative standpoint because in a narrative Characters have different statures, but you know also in a narrative all characters have the same weight, but whatever the the but but characters Like it's in a narrative seemingly have all these different You know power levels whatever.
Speaker 0: so I just you know, I took took that shit out from the very beginning.
Speaker 0: I was like, I don't care just make what you want to make, you know.
Speaker 0: but that's the thing.
Speaker 0: you once you do that once you It's cool like you take the brakes off you like or that kind of like the Kind of like moral limits like.
Speaker 0: no, you must be balanced.
Speaker 0: No, you know you must this and you say okay guys No, you guys can choose and you have to figure it out amongst yourselves and kind of make each other happy.
Speaker 0: It just it's great.
Speaker 0: It just adds a lot to the game where you know, you have to you can't just sit there being like And there's tweaking up a character.
Speaker 0: you you have to actually talk to your friends and be like, hey I think I would like to play a stupid munchkin.
Speaker 0: Your friends go.
Speaker 0: no, you always play that.
Speaker 0: we let you play that lesson.
Speaker 2: Well, I'm not gonna play anymore great That's what I was enjoyed reading there at least reading the revised burning wheels our little notes and for some of the really powerful Stuff and said things like this is only okay if everyone at the table agrees to it, right?
Speaker 2: But you didn't exclude it.
Speaker 2: You didn't say no you can't do this.
Speaker 2: You said everyone's got to be cool with it.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's just like the spirit of role-playing.
Speaker 2: Right?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: All right, ultimately what like Vincent says it's role-playing sir, uh role-playing games are games of permissions and expectations and so the permission comes not from Religion or on high it's from you know, everybody at the table.
Speaker 2: Sorry.
Speaker 2: I laughed.
Speaker 2: I was realizing that BDSM is the exact same.
Speaker 1: They do a lot of role-playing permissions and expectations cachao, so So Yes in my you know I don't know if you know this but I get a box of comics in the mail every month from DCB service.
Speaker 1: calm It's actually pretty cool.
Speaker 1: You pre-order two months in advance and everything is like a ludicrous discount.
Speaker 1: So the box was unusually large Last month because there was a very large box within the box.
Speaker 1: Would you would you know about this other box mouse card?
Speaker 1: Yeah Maybe that one had a bunch of had a bunch of dice in it and like statues and yeah kinds of crazy crap.
Speaker 1: I mean you guys and the map which was the most cuz I've heard the original hardcover Like you'd be opening the back of the book to use the map.
Speaker 1: That was like in right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah mapping ponds and dice and cards and all the cards.
Speaker 1: I forgot about the cards.
Speaker 0: Yeah yeah, that was.
Speaker 0: uh That was a long time coming that that the mouse card box set was debuted at Gen Con and Which is in August and it was we sold.
Speaker 0: very very well Nice, and I'm hoping that someday I will see some money from it.
Speaker 0: But I'm very happy with it overall.
Speaker 0: There are of course always things I would tweak but it's very exciting.
Speaker 0: It's very popular.
Speaker 0: people seem to enjoy it.
Speaker 1: I Didn't really look too closely at it, but it's it's the exact same game.
Speaker 1: I just has a whole bunch of extra fancy stuff in the or.
Speaker 1: were there any edits to it?
Speaker 0: There's some.
Speaker 0: well we corrected some errata in it.
Speaker 1: Okay, that's good.
Speaker 0: I probably introduced some as well as I tend to do but we corrected some errata in the rulebook and And the superficial changes are the addition of the cards and the dice.
Speaker 0: and so the dice are custom dice.
Speaker 0: So you have three symbols you have snakes swords and axes on the dice rather than one to six numbers.
Speaker 0: And then so the character sheets reference the custom dice and the GM screen references the custom dice rather than traditional dice.
Speaker 0: So it's superficial stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean you can still use regular dice with it.
Speaker 1: But remember a six is an axe a four and a five is a.
Speaker 2: so that could actually help.
Speaker 2: because I it's weird running Role-playing games.
Speaker 2: I'm sure you've seen this before.
Speaker 2: people who have never played a role-playing game ever before versus people who know anything about them.
Speaker 2: It's like night and day like the things you think people would assume or be obvious Just don't make any sense to the other people across the board.
Speaker 2: They won't like even burning wheel.
Speaker 2: I see people who don't just can't understand that a four or five or six is a success like they can't like.
Speaker 2: Right deal with it.
Speaker 2: Right like but it's a five.
Speaker 2: I got all fives.
Speaker 2: Isn't that better than fours?
Speaker 2: Like they don't right.
Speaker 2: I can't get convince them that it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so right.
Speaker 0: So now you those would be swords.
Speaker 0: you have all swords awesome rockin.
Speaker 0: and now you have all axes.
Speaker 0: that is better.
Speaker 0: Alright, so.
Speaker 0: But speaking of people who have never played role-playing games before you know, what's going on.
Speaker 0: This is total tangent.
Speaker 0: Okay, my mom who my dear dear old mom who took my role-playing games books away from me when I was a kid It has is starting a role-playing game club at her high school in High Point, North Carolina.
Speaker 1: Oh, so she's like a teacher there.
Speaker 0: She's a teacher.
Speaker 0: She's been a teacher her whole life.
Speaker 0: So So Yeah, so she's starting a role-playing game club and this is it's.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna loop this back in.
Speaker 0: and so I had this really interesting experience in the last year with my mom where I sent her free market and she was like Wow, this is really cool.
Speaker 0: and she had a completely different reaction to it than she had to any of my other stuff.
Speaker 0: like You know, she gets the books that have scary orcs on it.
Speaker 0: Well, she I don't know no dice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she gets the book and she's like oh nice you made another book it looks nice.
Speaker 0: She got to the free market and she's like wow, this is really cool.
Speaker 0: and she said something she'd never said to me before.
Speaker 0: She's like, can I play this?
Speaker 0: and I said, yes, that's what they're for.
Speaker 0: Yes, you can mom She can I play this with my students.
Speaker 0: I was like, yeah, sit down with a few of them You're gonna one of you's gonna have to read the rule book.
Speaker 0: But aside from that go for it.
Speaker 0: So a couple months later, you know, I send her a copy.
Speaker 0: This is actually in August.
Speaker 0: I sent her a copy of the mouse card box set uh straight from Gen Con I think and And She calls me up and she's like Freaking out.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: This is amazing.
Speaker 0: Ah, I want to.
Speaker 0: I want to play this with my students.
Speaker 0: I'm like, what is going on here?
Speaker 0: What's happening?
Speaker 0: And I realized it's because the box sets are games to to moms Around the world.
Speaker 0: a box set would.
Speaker 0: that includes everything you need to play is a game.
Speaker 0: a book is something you read.
Speaker 0: Right a book isn't something you play.
Speaker 0: cuz I get that reaction.
Speaker 0: people all the time like what's that?
Speaker 0: Oh, it's a game and they look at me, but it's a book.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: It's a game like choose your own adventure like no, you know, right cuz like a book that contains rules that you use.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's cool.
Speaker 0: I love role-playing games and I love and role-playing game books, but But her watching her reaction to mouse card was really profound like she saw it as a game and she is.
Speaker 0: so she's doing it.
Speaker 0: She's starting a role-playing game club at her high school And she
Speaker 1: so this is when you first said I thought it was one of those cases were like The students wanted to make a club and they needed an advisor and you're you know, no This is like your mom is trying to get the students together.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she's trying to see she she's at a 1400 kid High school so it's pretty big.
Speaker 0: That's big.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, it's it's pretty big and she is She's caught.
Speaker 0: she asked me she's like, how do I do this?
Speaker 1: She actually know who all the nerds are.
Speaker 0: Well, but I was like you're gonna have chest have like up the founding meeting or something right
Speaker 1: make a charter and
Speaker 0: So I was like you're gonna get a couple kids in the back mom who Are shy and kind of awkward and you need to approach them very gently Because they're probably who you need to get this club going.
Speaker 0: it's like you like you know and you need to kind of let them know that you're here to support them and that you're here not to kind of tease them out and then flay them for the thing that they love but you're actually here to Tell them that what they love to do is awesome and that you need their help to spread the word.
Speaker 0: And and she's like, you know, she's like, okay I'm like, I'm like mom.
Speaker 0: you raised someone.
Speaker 0: It's in your blood.
Speaker 1: Look for the little lukes out there.
Speaker 0: So she's really good.
Speaker 0: Like she's she's.
Speaker 0: she's pretty smart lady So I have faith in her.
Speaker 0: But yeah, so I'm gonna Donate some games down there, too.
Speaker 0: If I ever get my author's copies of the mouse card box set I will send more.
Speaker 2: Well, I was planning that I want to send them to Child's Play because I think that'll get a lot of gamers going I mean but Child's Play tends to only want what they already want, right?
Speaker 1: It's like what the hospitals ask for.
Speaker 2: Hospitals like you send them weird stuff and I know because I used to work in hospitals in the Bronx and I saw like the Like Montefiore actually is one of the Child's Play recipients.
Speaker 2: Yeah and I saw the kind of stuff that the nurses would get excited about and it was the interesting weird stuff like that Not the stuff that the kids or the hospital itself had asked for that the nurses be like, oh wow And then they'd really get the kids engaged.
Speaker 0: I tried to donate burning wheel books to Child's Play and they told me that they they were thankful and they were polite.
Speaker 0: But they basically they said that they couldn't like Sanitize them.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's why they only accept new things.
Speaker 1: They don't accept used things and they only accept things that come in like a package, you know You can't just send a book.
Speaker 1: It has to be something that's like sealed.
Speaker 1: So actually a shrink-wrap mouse guard box set would work out right because it's a sealed thing.
Speaker 1: But some you know, but a book that's just already open, you know, it might is that you know They can't take anything that's used.
Speaker 1: So if you have an action figure on its own no good, but an action figure on a card with the plastic bubble Totally awesome You know because it goes to hospitals where everything's got to be clean, right?
Speaker 1: They don't.
Speaker 1: that's why they don't accept used things.
Speaker 1: So you think the hospital would love if they could take the used things?
Speaker 1: They would love to take the used things for the sick kids.
Speaker 2: I know we have like six Gameboy Advances, right?
Speaker 1: So that's why they use things.
Speaker 1: go to toys for you know to the to the poor kids and the new things go to the Sick kids.
Speaker 1: That's how it works.
Speaker 0: Interesting.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah make sense.
Speaker 1: So yeah, if you just maybe if you shrink wrap some burning wheels, then it might I don't know We'll see.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll get them some copies of Mouse Guard.
Speaker 2: Yeah, that's sort of what's the next step with Mouse Guard?
Speaker 2: I mean, it sounds like it's just getting it out getting people to play it.
Speaker 1: There was a rumor of a dark crystal RPG.
Speaker 1: Is that true?
Speaker 0: That is a rumor.
Speaker 1: Okay, it is a rumor.
Speaker 0: it is a rumor but it's not.
Speaker 1: it is not a confirmed thing.
Speaker 0: Okay, oh you can google it.
Speaker 0: It's all over the internet and I will tell you it's a rumor.
Speaker 1: All right Because I know you know our.
Speaker 1: it is a weird thing because you know at least from my understanding Right.
Speaker 1: Arkaya has some of these Jim Henson properties such as Fraggle Rock Muppets and you know dark crystal and such right?
Speaker 1: Yep, but I think they got though that license before Disney bought Marvel if I if it's I'm remembering correctly,
Speaker 0: okay
Speaker 1: And which means you know, and it seems like boom studios I think is another comic publisher who had Disney licenses You know before Disney bought Marvel and it seems like what's going on is they're just sort of letting the licenses Expire and like Disney or I think Marvel is already gonna put out like some Pixar comics Like as they're as the licenses are expiring from boom.
Speaker 1: Okay, so if this rumor is true like I'm wondering, you know, you if you might have to do it very quickly I don't know.
Speaker 0: Disney doesn't own those licenses.
Speaker 1: Oh, they don't because Disney does own all the Jim Henson stuff.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, you are you are conflating two different things.
Speaker 0: Jim Henson sold Disney the Muppets at some point in his over didn't sell him any of the other stuff, correct?
Speaker 0: He was interesting He was.
Speaker 0: he felt like he was done with it and wanted to move on and do other things more elaborate things like labyrinth In the Dark Crystal, so he sold them the Muppets.
Speaker 0: And yeah, Jim Henson also does not own Sesame Street or whatever.
Speaker 0: They are contracted to do the puppeteering for The children's theater workshop stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, interesting.
Speaker 0: So so yeah, there are three separate entities that are involved with the Muppeteering.
Speaker 1: I've learned something today.
Speaker 1: I'm happy to So sin knowing that dude if it's true make Frogger Rock next cuz.
Speaker 1: oh my god I just want to go around.
Speaker 1: I won't be dozer and Scott.
Speaker 2: that would have to be a food based RPG.
Speaker 1: I that is that is fun.
Speaker 1: I I have would be the best.
Speaker 0: I've definitely Pitched people the Frogger Rock RPG really a Friday game.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: just make it Anyway, just give it to me and don't worry about anyone else.
Speaker 0: It's interesting that you're interested in that because they don't think that They don't think there's any interest in that.
Speaker 2: Well, I mean my experience is that no one seems to think that anything that that's popular should be popular will be popular Would hit any demographic.
Speaker 1: and you think even you know, archaea is a lot more smart and savvy than say a Hasbro.
Speaker 1: But even then, you know, it's still not, you know, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Anyway, if if if it's possible, I will try for it.
Speaker 0: All right, you awesome That's all.
Speaker 0: that's the best I can say.
Speaker 2: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 2: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 2: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and my comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.