Speaker 0: Hey, it's Monday January 31st, 2011.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: Egypt versus the Internet's spoiler.
Speaker 0: the Internet wins.
Speaker 1: Let's do this When skiing.
Speaker 0: this weekend, I'm feeling good about skiing.
Speaker 0: remember I'd you fall down.
Speaker 0: I did not fall down one goddamn time.
Speaker 1: Did you see you stayed in the bunny slip the whole time?
Speaker 1: No, not even the bunny slip.
Speaker 1: You were just skate.
Speaker 1: You're just going around the lodge.
Speaker 0: Actually, I went for it.
Speaker 0: I went for some pretty tough runs and Any like evil ten black dive and I didn't do any double black die.
Speaker 1: You didn't do any six ninja star.
Speaker 0: now you didn't do.
Speaker 1: you didn't do the course.
Speaker 1: That's so dangerous.
Speaker 1: It doesn't even have a sign next to it because they don't want you to go down there.
Speaker 0: I saw a guy who was going off that way.
Speaker 0: I was skiing.
Speaker 1: really there was no sign.
Speaker 1: So there wasn't an official course what it is.
Speaker 1: He just went right off the edge.
Speaker 0: So there's one trail where there's kind of this like there's a fence.
Speaker 0: That's like don't go past this and the snow is up against the fence.
Speaker 0: And there was a guy standing at the top of that snow because the fence is so deep in this one spot that you can Only see like five inches of the fence.
Speaker 1: Oh, so the fence was such a shallow fence.
Speaker 1: If you're on top of the snow.
Speaker 1: No, this is like six feet tall It's just there's like there is six feet of snow so you can get over the fence really easily.
Speaker 0: So he's just standing there looking down and there's no trail there.
Speaker 0: It's just trees and snow rocks.
Speaker 0: There's some rocks.
Speaker 1: How steep is it?
Speaker 0: It's about like this like a 70-degree angle.
Speaker 1: So it's not ultra dangerous.
Speaker 0: That's pretty damn dangerous.
Speaker 1: But it's not ultra dangerous like YouTube.
Speaker 0: dangerous Captain you've never skied before.
Speaker 1: Red Bull sponsored dangerous.
Speaker 0: Usually the more dangerous slopes are not the straight down ones They're the rocky ones.
Speaker 1: I think free falling straight down like a few hundred feet is most dangerous.
Speaker 1: What's more most dangerous than that especially if this jacket rocks?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's got you saying oh, that's not dangerous.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying it's not dangerous.
Speaker 1: I'm saying it's not as dangerous.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like yeah, nobody's as good a fighter as Kenshiro.
Speaker 0: But what it's like?
Speaker 1: that I'm saying what that guy was doing was very dangerous.
Speaker 1: It wasn't most.
Speaker 0: Yeah Scott It's the difference between 90% and 91%.
Speaker 1: No, it's more like 80% dangerous.
Speaker 0: That's way more.
Speaker 1: remember skiing skiing.
Speaker 1: The bunny hill is already 50% danger Are you kidding?
Speaker 0: You can't hurt yourself on the bunny hill Unless it's a freak accident.
Speaker 0: You're more likely to get hurt by a car.
Speaker 0: You can definitely break your brittle old man hip on the bunny sloop if you're a brittle old man if you're a 30 year old Successful normal person with a reasonable amount of body strength.
Speaker 1: You're kidding.
Speaker 1: You're gonna get a ski pole right through your eye.
Speaker 0: It's pretty hard to hurt yourself Severely.
Speaker 1: someone skis gonna go snap off and then go right through your neck and that'll be the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're more likely to get hit by a car in your apartment than have that happen Not on the third floor, but on the first.
Speaker 1: on the first floor you are right, but not on the third floor.
Speaker 0: So anyway, I tried a lot of serious stuff.
Speaker 0: And the one thing I was really practicing was jumping.
Speaker 0: I did some the most air I got I have out.
Speaker 1: Did they have a ski trampoline?
Speaker 1: No, we shouldn't invent that.
Speaker 0: basically There was this like set of like three moguls on the way to one of the cliffs that I would ski off of.
Speaker 0: So I would jump all three of those and I was going for air.
Speaker 0: I got about four and a half five feet high off of like one foot mogul.
Speaker 1: I can jump four feet in the air just standing still.
Speaker 0: I Don't know if you can my mate.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean technically right?
Speaker 1: Well, it depends how you measure it.
Speaker 0: because like if you want to measure if does not measure does your foot your both of Your feet get more than four feet off the ground.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could do that I don't know.
Speaker 1: The thing is right.
Speaker 1: my head would not go out four feet off the ground.
Speaker 0: Most of it would just be yes got my head was going four feet off the ground.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that's a little different.
Speaker 0: Yes And I was doing little baby jumps.
Speaker 1: cuz I just busy pick my legs up and I think that's already like two and a half.
Speaker 1: So I just need to get two feet of push, you know, and my head would actually only go two feet up.
Speaker 0: But you say yeah, I'm just I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'd like to see you do a jump.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should do some.
Speaker 0: we get an HD camera.
Speaker 0: We could set up an event.
Speaker 1: We need a ruler plus.
Speaker 1: I would use spring shoes.
Speaker 0: You think spring shoes are gonna help from a standing jump?
Speaker 0: Yeah without a bounce.
Speaker 1: Well, I start wiggling a little bit.
Speaker 1: and then you know, you got one good spring.
Speaker 0: You can use the spring shoes.
Speaker 0: I'll use a trampoline.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna use a. use a trampoline.
Speaker 0: I'll use a trampoline with the double jump.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna use a trampoline with a pogo stick.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: I'll jump out of a building Like those Russians, it doesn't count.
Speaker 0: All right, it's Monday, so what do you got for me?
Speaker 1: No, so a lot of people on the Internet's lately people on the Internet's, you know So reliable great sources of news is gonna be one of those.
Speaker 0: some guy on the internet says that.
Speaker 1: well This is actually a lot of guys in the internet.
Speaker 1: But I think it was more of a meme like one guy's wrote a blog post about it So other got into other people's heads and they believed it and whatever.
Speaker 1: But basically they were all complaining that Google search results as of late are very much more spammy and full of bullshit.
Speaker 1: sites That are just you know content farms or all right sites that scrape other sites to get high in search rankings.
Speaker 0: before we talk About all that.
Speaker 0: I have two kind of Assides.
Speaker 0: the first one is that you goddamn kids have no idea how good you have it.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: think those search results are bad.
Speaker 0: You think those are bad.
Speaker 0: go back to 1997 and search for anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a you know, people sort of take it for granted URL into Yahoo and you will not find that website.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: people take it for granted.
Speaker 1: Now that Google works as well as it does.
Speaker 1: they did not live through the era When you would use Alta Vista and then you'd use webcrawler and then you just dogpile which would search every search engine all at once.
Speaker 0: You had two choices.
Speaker 1: all the search engines were so shitty that you just couldn't find fuck-fuck.
Speaker 0: The choices were that basically Alta Vista would find five sites that were spammy or completely unrelated to what you were looking for.
Speaker 0: Yahoo would find three sites that were that had the information you wanted.
Speaker 0: that for our Ford That.
Speaker 0: that was pretty much it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the best way to find stuff back then was still like web rings Oh god, or link.
Speaker 0: remember everyone had a links page.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: The other thing I have to say is that Every time I've seen someone like an actual human Who who's trying to search for something and they can't find it and they complain that they're finding spammy bullshit I look at what they searched for and they clearly just don't understand boolean logic and Don't know how to search for things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they type like people don't know how to search for shit.
Speaker 0: It's like they need to know how to like what kind of food to feed their baby cat like their kitten and they'll search for like cat.
Speaker 0: But Yeah, that that's not gonna find but there's gonna find.
Speaker 1: the Wikipedia article on cats, you know It's it's like I have.
Speaker 1: you know just from searching even from the days before there was Google's or Alta Vista's right from using like CD-rom encyclopedias like my searching, you know and using like oars and ends to find stuff in them.
Speaker 0: There was an event when I was in middle school in the Science Olympiad like the National Science Olympiad thing.
Speaker 0: That was basically search the goddamn internet and they would give you a bunch of questions and you had and you had access to the Internet.
Speaker 0: you had to answer them.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, and uh people Goddamn morons.
Speaker 0: This was like 1998.
Speaker 0: I think Yeah, no, this was earlier than that.
Speaker 0: This is like 1995.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I'm really good at searching and most people are not so I think part of the red.
Speaker 1: I'm not denying that there are none of these bad results in Google at all because I've definitely seen them in my time.
Speaker 1: Yep But usually they come up when you search for something that there really aren't any pages that have that information.
Speaker 0: Usually where I see the most problem and I think this is where most people who have complaints are searching They search for in quotes.
Speaker 0: Usually well, they don't use quotes because they're stupid.
Speaker 0: a specific error message.
Speaker 0: They got from something and they find a million people asking the same question in a million forums and no one answers it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then there's like the expert sex change link and then they eventually go there.
Speaker 0: They can't find what they want.
Speaker 1: It's actually semi related to the problem of people not knowing where to go to do things, right?
Speaker 1: It's like for example, let's say something happens in our forum a lot, right?
Speaker 1: Somebody's in the geek nights forum They're part of our community.
Speaker 1: That's like their number one internet community or maybe number two internet community, right and they have a question about some programming something.
Speaker 1: So they come and ask it there and it's like alright, you know that I'm in this forum And you know, I might know the answer but really you probably should ask this question in Stack Overflow.
Speaker 1: We're all the programmers in the world might answer it.
Speaker 1: Why are you asking it here?
Speaker 1: This is not.
Speaker 1: this is not a question for this location, you know.
Speaker 1: People just don't know to go to the right place to type in the right thing.
Speaker 0: Also people don't know that you can type site colon URL and then it'll only search that site.
Speaker 1: I know I use that every day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean that's often how I'll search not experts exchange but server fault or Stack Overflow.
Speaker 1: If you're not like if you if you have an experience where you search Google and you don't find exactly what you want on the first Try every time you need to improve your Google skills.
Speaker 1: So I suggest you go and you read about Google search and Practice Google searching and study Google search and how to use it better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean quotes versus not quotes.
Speaker 0: Making, you know selective statements picking one site Excluding a term.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: God I just remembered the old days when I would search for something I'd be like I want like pictures of tenchi muyo characters because I wanted to do something with that.
Speaker 0: I'd search for like pictures.
Speaker 0: tenchi muyo Minus porn minus sex minus sex porn minus dildo.
Speaker 1: Here's a good example from the other day.
Speaker 1: This is a perfect example.
Speaker 1: So, you know curl right C URL Which is the library and command line program you use to do HTTP requests and look at headers and these sorts of things.
Speaker 1: Right, so I was using that and I wanted to add a header.
Speaker 1: So I was like, you know I couldn't the man page was too big and I couldn't find what I was looking for.
Speaker 1: So I was like, how do I add you know this XML header to with using curl, right?
Speaker 1: And I was looking for the command line.
Speaker 1: curl was what I was looking for and all the results I got were for the PHP curl library.
Speaker 1: So I was like I need to know this, you know, this isn't helping me.
Speaker 1: So I did.
Speaker 1: I kept my same search query and I put in minus PHP and I pressed enter and what I wanted was a top result perfect done.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so all these people are complaining that the Google search result is not as good and they're saying that you should use a different Engine like duck.
Speaker 1: duck go or is very popular.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Try one of those things shit.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna find anything better.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know 90% there.
Speaker 1: the thing is those things kind of work, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you could get by with those but it's like really that's what you're gonna use.
Speaker 1: They Google is searching the internet so fast and crawling everything with such an army of computers That even if someone else might have a better result in a term or two They just can't compete as a whole.
Speaker 1: this is really no way.
Speaker 1: they don't have the hardware and software resources.
Speaker 1: They you know, and they're not putting that amount of power towards the problem that Google is.
Speaker 1: I mean Google came out today with real-time audio translation of Spanish and English Like you could talk to.
Speaker 1: you could talk in Spanish and it will start talking may know as chocolate.
Speaker 1: You know, it's not Anyway.
Speaker 1: So people a lot of people are complaining about Google shitty search results You know.
Speaker 1: and there's a guy actually at Google named Matt cuts who's one of the people at Google you can actually talk to I?
Speaker 1: think that's his job is talking and he's is pretty much job is search spam and he's basically constantly working to make it better.
Speaker 1: and he did make it better and he's making it better all the time and People are complaining and trying to be like anti-google.
Speaker 1: It's like what the fuck is wrong with you.
Speaker 0: now There is the trouble Google has is that a lot of there are a lot of content farms or if you make a bad Search query or you search for something where nobody had like.
Speaker 0: there is nothing worthwhile on the internet You're gonna find the same forum post repeated on a billion bullshit ad revenue generating blogs And Google could do better to block that out, but no other search engine doesn't have that problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah So, I don't know what I would do.
Speaker 0: a very simple solution.
Speaker 0: Google had this and it kind of went away.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they ever added it back.
Speaker 0: I haven't looked too hard because I rarely have problems for my own cuz I you know I'm logged into Google all the time.
Speaker 0: It would be cool if I could you know have an option next to any domain and just blacklisted from my own Google searches forever.
Speaker 1: Well, actually they had a thing.
Speaker 1: they used to have Google search wiki, right?
Speaker 1: Which is where you could sort of add and remove and customize the results for a different query.
Speaker 1: They removed Google search wiki.
Speaker 1: that feature is gone.
Speaker 1: However, if you did Google search wiki while it was enabled For your account then all those things that you did are still in your account.
Speaker 1: So it's like your settings are saved but you can't change them because
Speaker 0: remember back in the day before we had good ad blocking I had a program that basically you'd right-click on an ad and it would pop up at the full uri of the ad and You could turn it new regular expression and it would block.
Speaker 1: that's basically how ad block still works.
Speaker 1: The only difference is that now your ad block also subscribes to the easy list.
Speaker 1: You automatically get all these regular expressions that are automatically maintained by someone else.
Speaker 0: I would like to do the same thing for Google because I have a feeling that if I eliminated About 20 or 25 top-level not top-level domains, but it's like domains in dot-com and org That would eliminate 99% of the spam I ever seen.
Speaker 1: good because they've got a lot of those content farms are gonna be a Bunch of websites all hosted at the same IP address or they're gonna be a bunch of.
Speaker 1: you know, here's the real trick though.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of hosts out there that specialize in like spam bad hosting and what they do is they get a bunch of servers And they get is a bunch of IP addresses that are all over the place that are all pointing at the same thing.
Speaker 1: So it's like they could have one hosting company with so many wacky IPS all over that.
Speaker 1: It's really hard to block them.
Speaker 1: So with those guys is just a matter of time.
Speaker 1: But the thing is because IP before those guys are gonna run out of IPs.
Speaker 1: the trouble comes when we get IP v6.
Speaker 1: Then what the fuck are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: Yep, like.
Speaker 0: here's an example Like I just did a search for because this is something I had to show someone to work how to do recently You know an SSL.
Speaker 0: when you have run have a chain certificate.
Speaker 0: like you have the real SSL certificate and then a chain certificate that goes to the root authority.
Speaker 0: Yep I just show someone how to set that up.
Speaker 0: So I look for a web page.
Speaker 1: I don't even know how to set that.
Speaker 0: I know it's pretty straightforward.
Speaker 0: Just cat it can catnip them both to get anyway.
Speaker 0: Okay, a Firefox actually doesn't give a shit.
Speaker 0: And even if you do it wrong Firefox will say the search.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway If you just Google for SSL chain certificate almost every single response is either Hey want to buy an SSL certificate or a bunch of stupid Forums where people are saying hey, I can't get my chain certificate to work and people don't give answers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that that is a problem is when you search for something that can have two possible Verb, you know actions right is how do I get a chain certificate to work?
Speaker 1: What is a chain certificate?
Speaker 1: I want to buy a chain certificate, right?
Speaker 1: So you actually when you search for that you literally have to type in more than just chain certificate.
Speaker 1: You have to type in.
Speaker 1: I want to you know, where can I buy a chain certificate or chain certificate prices?
Speaker 1: You know, if you're looking to how do I set one up?
Speaker 1: you had to go yet You might even have to not use Google.
Speaker 1: You might have to go straight to Stack Overflow or server fault or Wikipedia there, you know to read specifically about it.
Speaker 0: Whoa, whoa Whoa, so the top link Was looked like one of those spammy forum things and it look it's the side looks like a spammy bullshit forum site.
Speaker 0: It has the right answer.
Speaker 1: So Did it scrape the right answer from stack?
Speaker 0: I think it's great the right answer from someone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's possible that happens a lot, too Well, but it's really hard, you know, that's the problem that they're working on is, you know, someone scraped something from a different site.
Speaker 1: Well, how do you know which site was the original site?
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: I think what they need to do And it'd be nice to do some sort of aggregation where if you notice the same content on a bunch of places Come up with algorithms that determine the fitness to either try to determine the source
Speaker 1: They already have that they use it on Google News.
Speaker 0: Yeah So we have to do something similar for Google search results.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing Google News knows how to group news articles together when they're all about the same thing But it doesn't know what the first source of that news was, right?
Speaker 1: So if there's an AP story and the AP story gets in like 30 newspapers Which newspaper shows up on top is like the most popular one, you know most linked to or something It's not their original story, which would be AP link as opposed to Chicago.
Speaker 1: something link, right?
Speaker 1: Anyway, but yeah Google search results are just fine.
Speaker 1: It's not really a problem.
Speaker 0: So the Golden Gate Bridge is Finally in 2012 if Quetzalcoatl doesn't fuck it all up.
Speaker 0: Get all electronic toll collection.
Speaker 1: Yes 34 job.
Speaker 0: Wait, wait, no 34 jobs.
Speaker 1: Do they already have an easy pass kind of thing?
Speaker 0: I have no idea, but they're going all electric.
Speaker 0: So get this going.
Speaker 0: all electric means 34 jobs get eliminated good 34 and they save 19.2 million dollars for the first eight years Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah gasps and The only thing I have to say about that is why is there anywhere in this country where I still pay a toll?
Speaker 1: With money is we need more jobs not less jobs?
Speaker 1: if we actually made things efficient like I say they were you know, it's.
Speaker 0: That's a good argument except for the fact that this was 34 jobs.
Speaker 0: it's not enough job.
Speaker 1: No, no I mean This is the thing that I always say.
Speaker 1: right if you go to an economist and you say because people were worried when computers were First invented right that the computers would eliminate jobs Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna said replace on your statement and the Weaver the loom Steam power.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but people are always.
Speaker 1: we're always worried that technology would eliminate jobs and economists would say no historically that hasn't happened.
Speaker 1: But the truth is and I at least I believe the truth is that it's not the fact that technology won't eliminate jobs.
Speaker 1: Is that we don't extract the full potential of technology?
Speaker 1: And if we did we would eliminate jobs.
Speaker 0: I was about to say there are only 30 toll workers on that one bridge 34.
Speaker 1: there's 34 toll workers on that one bridge in the whole country.
Speaker 1: There's thousands of toll workers.
Speaker 0: Oh thousands Oh, that's not enough jobs to care.
Speaker 1: Okay, so in every office in this country, there's people working on spreadsheets.
Speaker 1: I could eliminate all of them at least, you know, five people per office with a single MySQL computer.
Speaker 0: So here is my corollary argument that that's millions.
Speaker 0: My argument will get halfway toward refuting you but then it's gonna refute itself.
Speaker 0: All right, so hear me out Every other like.
Speaker 0: when the Industrial Revolution happened what we saw was that in the very near term Many jobs were eliminated.
Speaker 0: You don't need a shit shoveler when you have an automated shit shoveling machine.
Speaker 0: That's right, except when shit shovelers are still cheaper than automated shit shoveling machine maintenance.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: However Most of the jobs that the US has today It is not cheaper to hire a person mostly because of health care costs and fair labor practices and things like that.
Speaker 0: So we can automate all the shit shoveling jobs like McDonald's.
Speaker 0: we can just have a fully automated McDonald's.
Speaker 0: The only reason they don't is that a minimum wage punk kid is way cheaper than the automatic burger making machine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but a full-time person is way more money, but in white-collar world where you can't easily like basically Automating all the jobs would save money like getting rid of.
Speaker 1: well any job where decisions are made can't be eliminated Unless you can get like if there are two decision-makers You can just get one person to make all those decisions.
Speaker 0: But you could automate most of the spreadsheet ladies who are so-called office experts with a database and some PHP.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you need.
Speaker 1: the thing is you need one computer guy.
Speaker 1: So here's my argument and it's not enough computer guy.
Speaker 0: during the Industrial Revolution million tons of jobs disappeared and there were many people out of work, but the savings to the world By removing all this excess labor that needed to be done Created more jobs in the long run because it created all these kind of new jobs that couldn't exist before.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're supported by the industrial wait.
Speaker 0: Wait, wait, wait, you can get me finished.
Speaker 0: I said I'm gonna review myself.
Speaker 0: All right, and I think that was the case with every major technological change up until this point.
Speaker 0: I think the difference now is that the jobs that are being created by the destruction of jobs due to technology are Beyond the reach of the vast People.
Speaker 1: I was going to say that exact same thing unlike previous times where those people were retrained.
Speaker 0: we're not seeing that due to a combination of shitty schooling lack of respect for technology work lack of understanding of technology work and the fact that technology is moving faster than government education Politics everything combined can react.
Speaker 0: all those things together are creating almost a Kurzweil Ian singularity out of which we're fucked.
Speaker 1: for That is true.
Speaker 1: when they replaced, you know, the the factory where it's just an assembly line by hand with the conveyor belt You know people were you.
Speaker 1: when they replaced the horse and buggy with the car people were retrained.
Speaker 0: It's not just retrained It's that once we replaced, you know guys weaving with factories Then we build a million more factories.
Speaker 0: that's all.
Speaker 1: but now the thing is when you get computers involved you make less and The people who worked in the thing the computers are replacing.
Speaker 1: you're a spreadsheet guy.
Speaker 1: You work with Excel all day.
Speaker 1: if I replace your Excel with a web app that just does all your work for you.
Speaker 1: So now you what do you do now?
Speaker 1: There's nothing to do.
Speaker 1: you're done.
Speaker 0: No, this would be fine.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do.
Speaker 1: learn programming.
Speaker 0: This would be fine If education was somehow keeping up with technology to it.
Speaker 0: if kids in school today or learning object oriented programming from kindergarten onward Then they would be entering the workforce ready to be the workers who take these brand new jobs that were created.
Speaker 0: We'd be fine.
Speaker 0: But instead it's like education just falling further and further away from practical skills.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but I want to go back to this bridge for a second, right?
Speaker 1: All right, so the bridge did it have easy pass like technology before or if I know okay.
Speaker 1: So let's so.
Speaker 1: basically you expect me to be a journalist But anyway, the bridge is now be effectively all easy pass only, right?
Speaker 1: So if you go through and you have an easy pass, you're good, right?
Speaker 1: But what if you do?
Speaker 1: what if I'm from out of town and I don't have an easy pass and I drive over the bridge?
Speaker 1: What then?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm actually trying to figure that out right now.
Speaker 0: He didn't give me enough stalling time to figure it out.
Speaker 0: But look at New York right now where it works and on the throughway and they're doing this more and more Jersey even especially on The way to Wildwood they have the just keep driving easy passes.
Speaker 0: Gotcha lanes all over the place.
Speaker 0: Yeah They do and if you do not have an easy pass You've got to get off the goddamn exit and go to this one toll booth like the last one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 1: But the thing is the toll booth is still there.
Speaker 1: This is what they're talking about here.
Speaker 1: I read some of it was that the basically there's.
Speaker 1: no there's no cash lane at all.
Speaker 0: Okay, they have an existing system called fast track.
Speaker 0: That's much like easy pass.
Speaker 0: All right, and Alright I did some journalism just there and it just so happens that the way this works is if you don't have the fast Track whatever system they just take a picture your license plate and mail you the bill.
Speaker 1: All right, that's that's pretty good.
Speaker 1: But I got some questions about that.
Speaker 1: What if I'm driving my friend's car through the toll?
Speaker 0: then he owes the toll.
Speaker 0: What if he shouldn't have given you his car?
Speaker 0: same thing happens if you borrow my car.
Speaker 1: I got my easy pass.
Speaker 1: What if I drive so fast?
Speaker 1: the camera fucks up?
Speaker 0: So apparently that's not likely and I'm reading some follow-up articles here.
Speaker 1: What if I drive so fast?
Speaker 1: it photos me twice.
Speaker 1: So guys, let's wait so slow.
Speaker 1: It gets me twice.
Speaker 0: then basically what I'm reading here.
Speaker 0: Is that the way it works If it misses a couple percent of people and doesn't find them?
Speaker 0: don't not find them.
Speaker 0: It doesn't told them the cost savings are so much as who cares.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: What if I'm in a rented car?
Speaker 1: Won't they rent a car place get the bill?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and rental cars are registered and they'll probably just pass the bill on to you.
Speaker 1: How would they know?
Speaker 0: because they know who rented the car when they rented it, but I don't have to pay.
Speaker 0: I've already given the car back I don't Scott Nate have you found a rental place that'll let you rent a car without giving them either a bank account or a credit card number?
Speaker 0: Most rental places now anyway, they have an easy pass just in the car.
Speaker 0: They just bill you.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So what if I Buy a brand new car and it's got the paper plates on it.
Speaker 0: It looks like you can take a picture of it.
Speaker 1: I buy a brand new car and I've got dealer plates.
Speaker 1: is a dealer gonna get the bill.
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably ha.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you borrow a car to test drive it then yeah, you're responsible for the tolls So the license plate owners responsible for the toll.
Speaker 0: what I'm fine with that.
Speaker 1: Okay, I got one more.
Speaker 1: I saw this once.
Speaker 1: this is real.
Speaker 1: this guy who is a illegal ricer speeding kind of type of guy modified his car as the button that changes the.
Speaker 1: He's got a button that slides a cover down over the license plate completely obscuring.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: All right 0.1% of people get away with it.
Speaker 1: Yes I'm gonna totally.
Speaker 1: if I live there I would totally get a button right.
Speaker 0: what I would do?
Speaker 1: I would push it.
Speaker 1: it would cover the license plates.
Speaker 1: I drive through the toll and push it again.
Speaker 0: what I would do if I were the programmers of the system?
Speaker 0: Any car where it can't figure out?
Speaker 0: What for whatever reason what the license plate is to bill?
Speaker 0: It just logs it and then after you know a month or so or running it We just have humans look at all the ones that couldn't do and see what's the cause like.
Speaker 0: maybe I can't read Delaware license plate.
Speaker 0: Maybe there's people pulling bullshit like you.
Speaker 1: they see a generic not fancy car going through the toll with obscured life.
Speaker 0: All right, you live in this area.
Speaker 0: This is happening on a regular basis.
Speaker 1: So all right, is it?
Speaker 1: maybe I don't live there?
Speaker 0: All right, then you did all this work to get away with a getting out of like a $15 toll once.
Speaker 0: good on you Do it more than once.
Speaker 0: eventually they're gonna just have a cop.
Speaker 1: They're like, all right Now they've got a cop there which means they've only saved.
Speaker 0: No, because the cops not always there.
Speaker 0: what I would do is unless I can find a clear You know that the people who maintain the system unless there is a clear trend of increasing Violations of people not having to pay that is adversely affecting the cost-benefit ratio.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't give a shit if it's adversely affecting it.
Speaker 0: a cop sits there once and pulls over every goddamn guy with the machine And then I charge you with so many felonies.
Speaker 0: You couldn't even believe that felony fraud.
Speaker 1: It's not fraud.
Speaker 0: It's illegal to drive without a valid license plate.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 1: they could suspend my license.
Speaker 0: They can also get you with.
Speaker 0: you know, you're committing fraud by avoid toll evasion.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's fraud.
Speaker 1: You can probably argue fraud.
Speaker 1: I think it's toll evasion and it's you know Driving on that license plates properly displayed.
Speaker 0: Yep, and you know, whatever else you could pro conspiracy to commit Yeah, it is because you built it.
Speaker 0: you have the device installed in your car.
Speaker 0: be pretty easy.
Speaker 1: I need a bunch of people.
Speaker 1: it would have to be like no Conspiracy just means conspiring to xxx.
Speaker 1: But then I can't understand how that would be illegal.
Speaker 1: if what?
Speaker 1: if I conspire to do it and then don't do it Can you still and you prove that I did that conspiring without the doing?
Speaker 1: it depends on you then that's bullshit.
Speaker 0: They recently arrested a guy for buying this.
Speaker 0: There's a fart story about this.
Speaker 0: I don't know where it'll end up.
Speaker 0: He bought a whole bunch of matches a whole bunch of fuel and Suda Fedron Rested him for conspiracy to make meth amphetamines.
Speaker 1: He was think but did he make the meth?
Speaker 1: No, then he.
Speaker 1: how could?
Speaker 1: that's bullshit felony bullshit felony.
Speaker 1: I call bullshit.
Speaker 1: I call felony innocent to proven guilty.
Speaker 1: He didn't do.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying what's right or wrong.
Speaker 0: I'm saying what I would do to you.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you what, mr James Bond I'm thinking about making meth right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm thinking about it.
Speaker 0: I think they got him on some sort of having the will and the means and Follow-up story and Fark pointed out that they found an old story saying that the same guy was arrested for making meth a couple of Times in the past.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying the guy was definitely gonna make math.
Speaker 0: There's no but I Don't know.
Speaker 0: All I'm saying Scott is that if there's a will there's a way to get a felony conviction.
Speaker 1: What if I go to the store and I buy a but you sound like men who were like, oh You want to implement this fancy technology?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: What if I'm an old man, and I can't figure it out.
Speaker 0: Where's your technology now?
Speaker 1: No, this isn't what if I'm an old man?
Speaker 1: I'm on.
Speaker 1: figure out It's what if I'm a young man and your technology doesn't work on speakers.
Speaker 0: They got away with shit for a while That's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna be toll freakers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a Much better strategies.
Speaker 0: have a license plate that turns the.
Speaker 1: oh, oh, I got a better idea.
Speaker 1: We hack the system to where it takes a picture.
Speaker 1: But you actually like you.
Speaker 1: you actually just put in the database a picture of like a penis don't see?
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like the cock boat license plate.
Speaker 0: exactly Things of the day.
Speaker 0: so if you like X cop or Dr.
Speaker 0: McNinja, who doesn't?
Speaker 0: you will like the other of both of those?
Speaker 1: Who doesn't?
Speaker 0: and if you like best karate for the gentleman?
Speaker 0: You'll probably like both of them as well.
Speaker 0: There's this kind of.
Speaker 0: if you if the title of any of those three things Sounds like a thing you would like you will like all three of those things.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day is that X cop which is a wonderful comic about a cop who finds an axe and becomes X cop Someone made a short fan film.
Speaker 0: It's more of a kind of a trailer for what would be the X cop movie.
Speaker 0: The guy they got looks exactly like X guys a little smaller though But otherwise, he looks exactly like a smaller X cop is like 40 feet tall and made of radiation.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: It's pretty damn good and pretty high production value.
Speaker 1: No, except for dinosaur cops mask.
Speaker 0: Actually, I'm gonna email these guys and be like what HD camera do you use?
Speaker 0: Can I buy?
Speaker 0: should I just buy that one?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah you people in the forum I've been looking for an HD camera.
Speaker 0: But anyway, that's inside.
Speaker 1: All right It's been a while since we've used a hockey fight as a thing and remember hockey fight week.
Speaker 1: So here on a January 26, which is just a few days ago Zach's door teeny and Chris Bartsch of the Dallas Stars and Edmonton Oilers got into a big fight down in Dallas.
Speaker 0: Now the my favorite part until I noticed the part that's Scott's real thing of the day was that Basically, they turn to each other and then as soon as they start to fight there is an explosion of gloves.
Speaker 1: I love that.
Speaker 0: just BAM in all directions.
Speaker 1: That's the greatest.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so there's a glove explosion.
Speaker 1: that good old hockey fight and quite a good, you know, very very good hockey fight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they keep going at it.
Speaker 1: They're getting real tired.
Speaker 0: guy in the black jersey is clearly winning this thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, the thing is about this fight is there's some music playing right do Do and if you are a nerd you will know exactly what music this is.
Speaker 0: it is.
Speaker 0: In fact the NSM be theme song.
Speaker 0: Yes Anyway, that's that's some inside baseball for you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you're listening to this to the song going on.
Speaker 1: But what's really interesting is that at first I thought this music was being added after the fact by YouTube.
Speaker 1: Right because you watch anything on YouTube and there's always music, you know overlaid this music.
Speaker 1: I guarantee you I know for a fact is being played in the arena, you know somewhere there's an intern in Dallas in Dallas Who had that?
Speaker 0: mp3.
Speaker 0: just Waiting and waiting and waiting for a fight.
Speaker 0: that was long enough and worthy enough of it and he had play on that thing And he sat there arms crossed.
Speaker 1: That was probably the highlight of his year and every nerd in the Dallas hockey arena watching stars fan was like, oh fuck.
Speaker 0: Yes Actually, this is a self-serving thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I gotta find the old audio but remember at RIT when I made that clip from the Beavis and Butthead movie And I gave it to the corner crew guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then they played it during the shutout game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was my crowning glory.
Speaker 0: The only thing we never got him to play was the tiger tiger song.
Speaker 0: that's right, so yeah.
Speaker 0: So before we get into it the meta moment the book club book is Michio Kaku's hyperspace Which I just I'm 90% through it and I'm 10%.
Speaker 0: I can say one thing hyperspace.
Speaker 1: I've been playing DS games.
Speaker 0: I hadn't read it since I was a little kid.
Speaker 0: It's talks about the fourth dimension.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like Carl Sagan.
Speaker 0: Yay science, but it's all about Multidimensional string theory quantum mechanics.
Speaker 1: The only thing I want to know is like this book is kind of.
Speaker 1: it's not old old But it's you know, it's it's years old.
Speaker 1: It means how is this still mostly what you you know theoretical physicists think?
Speaker 0: or is there new things that say Right, I was looking online and a lot of it is still pretty solid.
Speaker 0: All right, a lot of it.
Speaker 0: But anyway, we'll talk about it when we talk.
Speaker 1: I would like I would like for someone Timo someone who is a physicist to tell us which parts are not solid.
Speaker 0: thing is a lot of his history like after a while It's like alright, so you're with us on this, you know Einstein stuff.
Speaker 0: All right, what all quantum mechanics?
Speaker 0: That's just a big fat middle finger to Einstein.
Speaker 0: What about now?
Speaker 0: what now?
Speaker 0: Doesn't this go against everything we're talking about?
Speaker 0: So the book goes a lot of good directions But I mentioned it only because I made it my book club book and now having read it again It is scary how much that book influenced my young science interest.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Almost everything I cared about as a kid came from hyperspace.
Speaker 1: That's interesting.
Speaker 1: Yeah Also in meta news PAX East is very soon.
Speaker 0: We are doing not one not two not three But five panels.
Speaker 1: only three of them are combined into one.
Speaker 1: So it's really three.
Speaker 0: We're doing game mechanics and mechanism design again due to popular.
Speaker 1: Do you really need to list them all?
Speaker 0: We'll list them all later.
Speaker 0: We'll list them on Tuesday.
Speaker 1: We should go to PAX East but the week following PAX East is Zenkai con in Pennsylvania somewhere.
Speaker 0: It's a growing anime con.
Speaker 0: We'll be there doing a whole bunch of stuff.
Speaker 1: It's sort of the kazukan replacement for us.
Speaker 0: Yep Also, uh that the weekend coming up two weekends from now February 10th or February 11th on Friday is a nerd NYC board game night.
Speaker 0: We will be there Playing board games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we have a lot of listeners showing up.
Speaker 0: It's turning into more and more of a geek nights meet up.
Speaker 1: So if you it's like every week there's like one listener.
Speaker 1: There's like whoa weird.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's always a different listener, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: so if you want to meet us and you live in the greater New York City area and you come to think coffee on Fridays when they had their nerd NYC board game nights We are there playing board games and you can totally play a board game with us unless you smell.
Speaker 1: Also, we have a website for our crew.
Speaker 1: calm go to it.
Speaker 1: We have an email address geek nights a front recruit.
Speaker 1: calm email us.
Speaker 1: We have Twitter.
Speaker 1: geek nights.
Speaker 0: We have a forum that has a sort of forum explosion going on yet again, right?
Speaker 1: And also the people in the forum have made their own unofficial geek nights IRC channel, which is on free node.
Speaker 0: It is unsanctioned, but I give it my thumbs up.
Speaker 0: wink and nod.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz people always like Scott, you know, we need a. you know, why don't you make like a geek nights wiki?
Speaker 1: I'm like, why don't you make you dance wiki?
Speaker 1: So they're like Scott.
Speaker 1: We want a geek nice chat room.
Speaker 1: Like why do you make a nice chair?
Speaker 1: So they finally did.
Speaker 0: I mean I made the geek nights Counter-Strike server But why do I have to make everything?
Speaker 0: the server powered itself off and won't power back on?
Speaker 0: I won't.
Speaker 1: I won't say it's official but I mean it does.
Speaker 1: so there's not an official chat room But it's a geek nice chat room.
Speaker 0: Yeah If you want to chat one of you listeners makes a geek nights thing.
Speaker 0: that is super popular and we decide to make the for real thing.
Speaker 0: Obviously you will be the moderator and administrator of it if you want.
Speaker 1: Because the main reason I don't want to make an official thing is cuz that means I got to take care of Unofficial, I don't got to do shit.
Speaker 0: It's like I said the geek nights Counter-Strike server powered off like a couple weeks ago and won't boot and I got to figure out What's wrong with it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think the power supply died.
Speaker 1: Yeah, feel free to make as many unofficial geek nights things or front row crew things as you want as long as they're unofficial.
Speaker 1: You know, I don't really care.
Speaker 0: Well that by nature could not be official.
Speaker 1: unless we officialize then I mean think you know, that's what every community on the internet does right.
Speaker 1: if you go to say something awful forums There's a something awful minecraft server.
Speaker 1: I'm sure but that's not run by something awful It's just by people in the community.
Speaker 1: make the something awful, you know community minecraft servers, you know, that's how it works.
Speaker 0: Do note however that we retain all trademark rights to geek nights and front row crew.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just as an aside if you get big enough, we're gonna make you sign a licensing agreement.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think we can sue an IRC channel for using pound geek nights as its channel name.
Speaker 0: Cover my bases because I'm not a lawyer and I don't want to do most.
Speaker 1: at the worst-case scenario We could write the free node an email and then they would give.
Speaker 1: make us the op of the channel instead of them.
Speaker 0: So Egypt we're not gonna talk about Egypt just yet We could.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling once this has resolved itself somewhat We will do a Thursday show on Egypt because I have a lot of say that I've been following this pretty much continuously.
Speaker 0: I'm very interested in the outcome.
Speaker 0: I'm with those kids, but Independently one very specific issue came up that resonated throughout geekly circles because a very similar issue at least on the surface has been Making the rounds in America among nerds and people are afraid of it.
Speaker 0: So remember when Obama and the administration and the government kept saying we need an a quote internet kill switch.
Speaker 1: Well, they still want one up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they want one pretty badly and there's debate as to what internet kill switch means.
Speaker 0: But we have seen the what an internet kill switch could be in Egypt because Egypt for those of you don't know This is a largely popular movement that kind of came out of social media and hit the real world.
Speaker 0: Because the youth are not stupid and that you know, they can communicate and say we're done at this bullshit.
Speaker 0: Let's get together.
Speaker 1: Yeah, every time I look at footage of any Egyptian protests or anything there are more cell phone.
Speaker 1: Everyone's got blackberries and cell phones taking pictures of everything uploading the videos to YouTube Everybody's all over that shit tweet in Facebook and everything.
Speaker 1: right now granted There's a lot of fake Facebook in it, but this plenty is.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of real.
Speaker 0: so Egypt basically Couldn't deal with these protests.
Speaker 0: and shortly after all this began they shut down everything they Madagascar to the internet.
Speaker 0: They literally turned off telecommunications in almost the entire nation of Egypt, but here's the thing is.
Speaker 1: not only did they turn off the Internets, but they turned it off phones.
Speaker 1: They turned it off in a really clever way.
Speaker 1: like they managed to turn it off like, you know They're apparently I was reading there are some other countries that route their traffic through Egypt.
Speaker 1: They're still routing to them.
Speaker 1: Like this was something.
Speaker 1: had smart Cisco people do this, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe they paid Cisco themselves to do it because Cisco well has no problems doing that kind of shit.
Speaker 0: You're interested in that.
Speaker 0: pay attention to anonymous because at least one group claiming to be anonymous which means they are effectively anonymous is Trying to piece together all the technology that they used to then Scream how far and wide at the companies who allowed this bullshit to take
Speaker 1: all Cisco does the same?
Speaker 1: does the bullshit in China?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's probably you know them but it basically they were modifying routing tables and this sorts of stuff.
Speaker 1: They weren't.
Speaker 1: just you know, some other country or probably just go and cut all the cables and that would be that right?
Speaker 0: But but think about this.
Speaker 0: this is kind of an aside.
Speaker 0: but Egypt the government that was probably the worst miscalculation they could ever have made because they saw that social media was really driving this and They turned off the internet and then that actually made the protests bigger not smaller.
Speaker 1: This is the one mistake that I always keep pointing out.
Speaker 1: is like everyone all these countries are so stupid.
Speaker 1: They take the 1984 approach and the problem with the 1984 approach is that it is obvious everyone can see it.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know You look at like pictures of like Al Jazeera versus Egyptian state television where it shows like no one protesting and just cops standing at an empty street.
Speaker 1: and it's like yeah Captain obvious we see what you did there, right?
Speaker 1: You're not fooling anybody.
Speaker 0: if you want to fool everyone you have to do the u.s Trick which is have all the free speech you want.
Speaker 1: Hahaha.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter You don't actually doesn't amount to anything.
Speaker 0: but think about this from a more direct level.
Speaker 0: So there's a large angry growing movement demanding the downfall of the government and democracy and all this stuff.
Speaker 0: So they turn off the biggest circus in the world to a nation that already doesn't have enough bread.
Speaker 1: no bread No circuses.
Speaker 1: All right, we're gonna even less circuses.
Speaker 1: No, that was stupid.
Speaker 1: You gotta add if you added bread or circuses, that would make when you turn off phones and the internet Even grandma's getting pissed now.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: There was another country.
Speaker 1: I read that.
Speaker 1: well, I gave money to everybody.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I forget what it was.
Speaker 1: I don't know it might have not been true, but I read something about some country giving money to everybody Because you know or something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was something in Kuwait, let me look it up.
Speaker 1: you keep talking.
Speaker 0: are you sure it was something?
Speaker 0: are you sure it wasn't Nothing.
Speaker 0: Hold on.
Speaker 1: I'm looking it up.
Speaker 1: you talk.
Speaker 0: All right, so they tried to shut down the whole internet and they succeeded and It had no effect on the protests effectively.
Speaker 0: But at the same time that is a really I don't believe that the US government should have any ability to Dictate any sort of internet thing like that.
Speaker 0: The government should have no way to shut down our internet because I cannot imagine any Possible way that that could protect us more than individual entity entities Working to protect their own networks in the event of some sort of scary so-called cyber attack.
Speaker 1: I can't actually find a an actual news article about this.
Speaker 1: quite things.
Speaker 1: It was probably just a tweet or something.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, wait wait for it.
Speaker 1: Oh, no Ron.
Speaker 1: Nevermind regard was probably bullshit But yeah, if you want people to stop protesting you had to be nice to them.
Speaker 1: You can't be obviously mean to them.
Speaker 1: This is gonna make them angrier and it definitely that's what happened.
Speaker 1: I could have told you that it's the other thing.
Speaker 0: I have a more kind of wide aspect of this kind of a wider view because well I want to talk about technologies.
Speaker 1: Like what do you do when they cut off the Internet?
Speaker 0: Well, I was thinking about this from Egypt.
Speaker 0: What did they do?
Speaker 0: They already had critical mass So the mass just coordinated itself with the good old-fashioned means of posters and flyers and Sneaker-net and walking around and shouting from the rooftops.
Speaker 1: Yeah megaphones, right?
Speaker 1: But you know that doesn't replace internet.
Speaker 0: Well in an urban culture It can and can for this.
Speaker 0: if you've gotten to the point of going out into the streets and not leaving then You don't need the internet anymore Especially if you're having multiple simultaneous demonstration plus
Speaker 1: anything that you're gonna record is gonna be You can put it on the internet later and
Speaker 0: you can't stop satellite.
Speaker 0: Someone's gonna get the signal out because look they cut off the internet.
Speaker 0: We still know what's going on.
Speaker 0: The rest of the world knows you can't hide this shit.
Speaker 1: satellite dishes can't be V Ham radio ham radio can't be V. Yeah, you know plus look even in for example, North Korea, right geography.
Speaker 1: So you go to the border near China and you can pick up a cell tower.
Speaker 1: There's actually cell towers there on purpose.
Speaker 0: Look at what happened in Cuba.
Speaker 0: There's a black market and USB sticks with copies of Wikipedia on them.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I think I made that a thing of the day a long time ago.
Speaker 1: That's awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, USB underground.
Speaker 0: and in North Korea There's supposedly a USB underground of South Korean pop dramas.
Speaker 1: plus, you know You look at my thing of the day from last Thursday, right the pirate box Which we're gonna be making use of very soon.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I'm excited about my pirate box.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know you set some of those up and suddenly you've got a you know a wireless Egyptian Intranet and then as soon as there's internet again You just get those pirate boxes on the internet and then I'll snap.
Speaker 0: the pirate box is just the first salvo.
Speaker 0: and what will eventually?
Speaker 0: Be the thing that I talk about all the time.
Speaker 0: what if we could make for the same money that we're making this pirate box now a Pirate box that also has the option of just finding other pirate boxes making a mesh communications network?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean this already is sort of small mesh networking, right?
Speaker 1: And we can.
Speaker 1: there's sort of like this ham radio packet routing that you can do if you buy these device.
Speaker 0: All that stuff is slow as shit.
Speaker 0: However in a situation like this getting video out and getting you know video around and the kind of internet stuff We do as important as that is What's actually important to a movement or a resistance is?
Speaker 0: Text and we can send a lot of text with very low bandwidth.
Speaker 1: The other thing we can do, right?
Speaker 0: Serval Wireless networking mechanism.
Speaker 0: There
Speaker 1: have been plenty of instances of nerds setting up their own GSM network So we could easily get all the AT&T and T-Mobile phones at least You know texting each other for free on some sort of you know, nerd network of kinds
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: and the other thing is right.
Speaker 1: if you're talking about a situation where they turned off the internet, right?
Speaker 1: This is likely there is a lot less is a lawless situation, you know or much much less law.
Speaker 0: Forget all that America.
Speaker 0: It's pretty easy to get around this in the long run.
Speaker 0: Yeah one of the.
Speaker 0: imagine if the internet got shut down like right now like we're sitting here and suddenly there's no internet at All and like I can't.
Speaker 0: my cell phone doesn't get an internet anything So I call some of my friends and and I can't get through to anyone After about a day of that and me, you know using sneaker net to find out that Nobody has internet like only the Northeast power outage and I found out through hook and crook that nobody had power.
Speaker 0: Once I figure out that that is due to the government I am in the streets.
Speaker 1: No, but what I'm saying here is that you know The main thing that keeps us from having our own internet right now that it's not controlled by any government or company.
Speaker 1: Right is the FCC which regulates and controls which frequency Situation.
Speaker 1: that shit don't matter.
Speaker 1: So up go big ass antennas go to the grocery store empty out the food cans make the cantanas.
Speaker 0: That's why what I would advocate is that nerds should make one of the RFC.
Speaker 1: Every nerd should make big antennas that are illegal now and get and just test them out Make sure you don't get busted and then put them in the closet and then if shit ever happens Bust out your antenna.
Speaker 0: now the good nerds need to get together and make RFCs and come up with protocols.
Speaker 0: and means that basically assuming Mad Max or at least assuming internet Mad Max What like?
Speaker 0: how quickly can the nerds make radio free world?
Speaker 0: here's how you do your free earth.
Speaker 1: Here's how you do it.
Speaker 1: ready.
Speaker 1: You take the DD wrt firmware.
Speaker 1: you add you know mesh network end of the world mode to it and You know, you can.
Speaker 1: you basically pop the antennas off your router attach your cantanas or whatever other badass antenna you're gonna make.
Speaker 0: That's a pretty gross oversimplification.
Speaker 0: You need something more robust because if you use barely commodity stuff like that It'd be pretty trivial for a government that was pissed off enough to just block everything.
Speaker 0: what you both at least block.
Speaker 1: you What you know, obviously we can make more advanced stuff too, but you need to have something that any nerd can do.
Speaker 0: nerds need to write a protocol and come up with an open standard that would be totally illegal to actually use but would work.
Speaker 0: some Sort of spread spectrum high-powered.
Speaker 0: We don't give a shit about what else we screw up radio system that if it's running is Basically, it's mutually assured destruction for the government to jam it.
Speaker 0: they would have to jam everything including themselves including the numbers stations.
Speaker 0: the numbers stations.
Speaker 0: Nerd should make some numbers stations, but that's a pretty sure nerds do make.
Speaker 1: the numbers.
Speaker 0: take one one one one But zoom out a little bit because we could get into the specific tech and that would almost be a separate show of like.
Speaker 0: very Specifically, how would we route around?
Speaker 0: but the wider issue is that look what's happening in the Middle East?
Speaker 0: these isolated protests spread throughout numerous countries and the only common theme is that there are people who want Liberalized political systems, even if they do not want liberalism They don't necessarily want to have this kind of open free Western society But they want political freedom.
Speaker 0: and that's this kind of core meme that's spread in a way They could never spread before.
Speaker 0: social media I think caused all of this.
Speaker 0: hmm the same level of dissidents would not cause this in many nations simultaneously a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I think what it is is that you know, I have the feeling, you know people anyone in America no matter which side They're on right all of us whether you're right or left or up or down or sideways everyone's dissatisfied about something and Dissatisfaction always outweighs the satisfaction.
Speaker 1: because they take.
Speaker 1: four people tend to take for granted the things they're satisfied about right?
Speaker 1: But the things they're dissatisfied about, you know, if the only problem we had in the entire United States that the DMV had long lines.
Speaker 1: People would just be like on Fox News or whatever news station.
Speaker 1: They would be like the long line of the DMV to be reporters day with cameras.
Speaker 1: you know everything else in the country is perfect.
Speaker 0: or at Maslow's Pyramid if the if the thing Like if there is a thing that's broken that's low enough level to where everybody no matter how much they hate each other all agree.
Speaker 0: I mean look Islamic extremists and Liberal secular youths all agree that the current regime has to go right.
Speaker 1: But the thing is people are generally always pissed off at government no matter how perfect the government is, right?
Speaker 1: There's no way.
Speaker 1: everyone is always.
Speaker 1: no one likes any government no matter what the government is.
Speaker 1: Find me a place time in history country where people are going.
Speaker 1: Yay.
Speaker 1: Our government is so great.
Speaker 1: We love living here.
Speaker 1: This is wonderful.
Speaker 1: There's no problem.
Speaker 1: I don't hate any politicians or presidents.
Speaker 1: I want all.
Speaker 1: I want to vote for all of them over again and again.
Speaker 1: Everything is great.
Speaker 1: Never happened.
Speaker 1: Never will happen.
Speaker 0: Are you talking about?
Speaker 0: in Cuba?
Speaker 0: I mean 90% they're.
Speaker 0: just there's landslide elections.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so in Egypt - yeah, everyone's happy same kind.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the fact is is that why if that's the case that people are always dissatisfied.
Speaker 1: People would always be in revolution right because everyone's pissed off.
Speaker 1: So they would have a revolution and then as soon as they're pissed off again, which wouldn't be that long Revolution again, right?
Speaker 1: Why doesn't that happen?
Speaker 1: It's because people aren't angry enough degree of anger Not to get mad.
Speaker 1: and also how much do you believe that the revolution will work and it's worth your effort Right, which a lot of that has to do with unemployment also?
Speaker 1: Yeah well if you don't have to go to work then you can be in a revolution.
Speaker 0: if you have a job you're not going to sell tales back in what I was saying because look the thing Tunisia had its rising up and it was relatively successful and Discontents in neighboring nations basically were like we can do that too.
Speaker 0: We might win.
Speaker 1: So what the thing is is that People did not believe that a revolution would work.
Speaker 1: But as you get the power of technology right coming in the power of the people is enhanced.
Speaker 1: You need an arm course, not it.
Speaker 0: people were not armed.
Speaker 0: Note that China is blocking the ever-living shit out of any news about Egypt or Tunisia.
Speaker 1: That's true, right?
Speaker 1: That's with good reason, but at least if you're you know want China to stay the way it is, right?
Speaker 1: It's you know, if you suddenly gave a whole country of angry people guns They would there's.
Speaker 1: they would suddenly have a revolution.
Speaker 1: cuz now it's like we can take on the army.
Speaker 1: We got guns.
Speaker 0: on The Daily Show There was this graphic Johnston was talking about the Egyptian thing.
Speaker 0: when it first started he was like blah blah blah the nation of Egypt which Sits on top of and he puts up this graphic the world's largest untapped reserve of Islamist rage.
Speaker 0: And he had this graphic of like sand bedrock oil Islamist rage.
Speaker 0: and it was just this pissed off looking guy.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: So anyway instead of giving these people guns we gave them all cell phones and internets Which is almost as powerful a weapon as guns Especially since it looks like the guns that are there.
Speaker 1: the army isn't shooting them so they don't need guns.
Speaker 0: Well think about they got all the weapons a very different situation.
Speaker 1: since it's not a violent conflict They don't need weapons.
Speaker 1: The cell phone is the most powerful weapon they have.
Speaker 1: So taking away the internet was basically equivalent of gun control here.
Speaker 0: Well part of it was.
Speaker 1: that's what made the people powerful enough to for them to believe that their revolution would work was seeing that It worked elsewhere and seeing that they could do the same thing.
Speaker 0: of course part of the difference here Was that like in Iran with the attempted Green Revolution?
Speaker 0: They could basically get people from the rural areas ban them together and just drive them in to quash it.
Speaker 0: But in Egypt the military is much more modern and the people in the military are much more Similar to the people who are protesting, you know, that's another thing is the Egyptian military is not made up You know, it's like the people in the military are also be.
Speaker 1: it's like America.
Speaker 0: Imagine if the the US, you know, New York City's in riots like we're in the streets Military comes out against the New Yorkers who are mad because there's no internet.
Speaker 0: and They're those people.
Speaker 0: they're from Wyoming and they also don't have internet.
Speaker 1: They're also yeah, they're just they're not they're us.
Speaker 1: They're not like this other group of people.
Speaker 1: that's you know, usually when you have militaries going against the people It's because you have a military class that is sort of above the regular people.
Speaker 1: They got better privileges They don't you know, they're not like the other people.
Speaker 1: So the military people are happy and well-fed and well-paid while the regular people are in the shitter.
Speaker 1: That's when you get militaries that are being all bad say Khmer Rouge kind of situation.
Speaker 0: that's why I'm excited about this.
Speaker 0: whole.
Speaker 0: technical outlets is the way the technology assisted this because Egypt's reaction is very much kind of Their admission that this kind of regime is fucked worldwide in the long run.
Speaker 0: Mmm, because you can't I mean you can't stop nerds Nope Unless you stop them all.
Speaker 0: and if you think is it's happening now There's no outside world for them to get the signal out to it might have petered out.
Speaker 0: It's happening now.
Speaker 1: and the places where there is less stability like Tunisia But our total control of the government or more anger right like Egypt, right?
Speaker 1: So as time goes on right the bar is only going to get lower.
Speaker 1: So places that are only kind of angry are gonna be like, oh, we're kind of angry, but we can totally go.
Speaker 1: Let's do it and it's only a matter of time before, you know, maybe in our lifetimes with the?
Speaker 1: u.s.
Speaker 0: My take on it is more that throughout the Arab world I I'm starting to believe that there is in many places a silent majority that even if they're not necessarily Liberal or have any of our Western ideals and freedoms and maybe not want those things fully.
Speaker 0: They definitely want more political freedom and are generally dissatisfied with the brutal regimes that are on top of them.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot of brutal regime is probably I mean, I imagine there are a lot of people who are kind of in public Yeah, sharia law and privately like man fuck this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you think you know Saudi Arabia.
Speaker 1: It's like you really think all those people like, you know love being ruled by a bunch of princes Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and look at Egypt.
Speaker 0: I mean look at the stereotype of Egyptians to come over here in the clubs hanging out.
Speaker 0: look at Egyptian nightclubs in Egypt.
Speaker 0: Those kids don't want to live under Sharia law.
Speaker 0: hell no, but I feel like there's this kind of silent or frightened majority in much of the Arab world that Technology bit by bit is going to show those people.
Speaker 0: You know what.
Speaker 0: you don't have to put up for this bullshit.
Speaker 0: Look in all those other countries.
Speaker 0: those people stop putting up for the bullshit.
Speaker 0: Mmm, and Iran has the interesting situation that There's this huge gap in generations because of the Iran-Iraq war and all the people who died Very rapidly.
Speaker 0: all the people in power with the very conservative values are going to die of old age or become too old to maintain Power and then there's gonna be a huge gap and then a very large angry youth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, look at we're waiting for the old people to die so we can use computers, right?
Speaker 0: They're waiting.
Speaker 1: they're waiting for the old people to die because the old people are too religious.
Speaker 0: And even when they're religious, well, we'll see I think we've gone on long enough But I don't know.
Speaker 0: the moral of this is you can't stop the signal and the pirate box is the first step toward Liberating the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we need to everyone.
Speaker 1: we need to start working on You know some sort of antenna system that totally breaks all kinds of laws in the FCC, but we don't actually implement.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't use it until the time is right.
Speaker 0: So when the time is right everyone puts their antennas up or make the the separate internet or we make the Pirate boxes that do that that make the mesh network and then we do a Michael Moore thing.
Speaker 0: I remember Michael Moore air dropped all those TVs over Afghanistan.
Speaker 0: No, it was a long time ago It was a publicity stunt.
Speaker 0: but imagine a day when you know Iran the youth rise up again and We like mass the Western nation start mass producing.
Speaker 0: just nerds.
Speaker 0: every every five nerds get together and make one Mesh pirate box and just kind of ship it over and try to get it smuggled into Iran And then eventually the the nerds of Iran have their own network.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see that thing is if we tried to like mail these things to say Egypt, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, you mail plans and parts in streams that they can't cut off without cutting off.
Speaker 1: Right, but the thing is like if you tried to mail something to Egypt now, it's not getting there.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: So you start smuggling these things into places like North Korea over time?
Speaker 1: Hmm North Korea's already had plenty of smuggled in.
Speaker 1: yep, those people are watching South Korean dramas on VHS.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they just arrested a lot of people for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah badly.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.