Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, September 28th, 2011.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, the Geek Nights worst webcomic contest of 2011.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, you know, we're in New York City.
Speaker 0: We are.
Speaker 1: You can get any food you want in the universe.
Speaker 0: Pretty much anything.
Speaker 0: I had, uh, for lunch I had Mexican food, and last night for dinner I had curry.
Speaker 0: And the previous day I had Mexican food.
Speaker 0: And the day before that I had Mexican food.
Speaker 1: Good job with the Mexican food.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I really hadn't had a burger in like a few weeks.
Speaker 1: I was like, "I'm getting a burger for lunch,
Speaker 1: bitches.".
Speaker 0: The thing is, New York, it's like the burger is one of our things.
Speaker 0: The burger joint.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the problem.
Speaker 1: There are no burger places close enough to my work, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I could go to the Shake Shack on Broadway, but I think it's on 8th, near the Port Authority.
Speaker 0: If you go to Schnippers, it's not that far from you.
Speaker 1: Schnippers, that's still kind of far to go to Schnippers, which is even, which is a couple blocks further than Shake Shack.
Speaker 0: Scott, I used to walk to Schnippers from my office.
Speaker 1: You're crazy.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: I walk about a mile to get a good burger.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's, you know, there was a, you know, I can go to McDonald's.
Speaker 1: Fuck that, it doesn't even count.
Speaker 1: Five Guys doesn't even count.
Speaker 1: There's Island Burger, which is amazing.
Speaker 1: But you gotta sit, you gotta sit down at the Island Burger.
Speaker 1: It's not, you know, you don't want to take out from the Island Burger.
Speaker 0: So there's a place near me, I don't know what it's called, but it's not a chain of any kind.
Speaker 0: It's just a burger joint.
Speaker 0: They have burgers, fries, and sweet potato fries, and very little else.
Speaker 1: So one of my co-workers suggested this place that was still kind of far, called Le Parker Meridian.
Speaker 1: Now, here's the deal.
Speaker 1: He suggested it, and it was sort of iffy, and I was like, if not now, then when?
Speaker 1: So we went.
Speaker 1: So if you go to Carnegie Hall, alright, then you go east, right?
Speaker 1: Remember where we went?
Speaker 0: This means nothing to the majority of our listeners.
Speaker 1: Remember we went to see Summer Wars and the Directors Guild?
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: Immediately next door to that are some glass sliding doors.
Speaker 1: And on those glass sliding doors is the tree symbol.
Speaker 1: that is the symbol used on private property when it's open to the public.
Speaker 0: Yup, you get a text brick for that shit.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So that symbol was sort of embossed by like a laser on these glass automatic doors.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, what the fuck is this?
Speaker 1: Well, what it is, is you go in there, and there's like a fancy hotel bar, ultra fancy, with music playing, and it's like, whoa.
Speaker 1: Why is there the open to the public sign on those doors, followed by a hotel bar?
Speaker 0: For the tax break.
Speaker 1: There's a hotel called Le Parker Meridian that is le fancy.
Speaker 1: Very le fancy, right?
Speaker 1: It's on 109 West 56th Street, New York.
Speaker 1: And the entrance to the hotel is on the southern street, the 56th.
Speaker 0: Alright Scott, so give it to me straight.
Speaker 0: On a scale of 0 to 10, 0 being the minimally edible burger, so already above 5 guys.
Speaker 1: You're not, let me finish.
Speaker 1: the most important part of the story, is not the burger.
Speaker 1: You go into this hotel, it's ultra fancy.
Speaker 1: You walk through the hotel bar.
Speaker 1: You go in, and it's like another hotel seating area, sort of like a hotel lobby.
Speaker 1: And it's way fancy, all sorts of crazy modernish styling, right?
Speaker 1: And you're looking around, and you go to the concierge, big long concierge desk, it's made of stone, right?
Speaker 1: And you look to the right of the concierge desk, and there's a big red curtain.
Speaker 1: And then there's a seating area in front of the red curtain.
Speaker 1: There is a tiny, tiny, tiny area in between the red curtain and the concierge desk.
Speaker 1: Like, narrow enough for one person.
Speaker 1: You'd think it was just the way to go into the back behind the concierge desk.
Speaker 1: But if you look...
Speaker 0: Is that the burger joint?
Speaker 1: If you look in this narrow hallway, there is a neon sign, a very small one, and it is neon bent into the shape of a burger.
Speaker 1: Two yellow circles of neon with a little green and a brown and a red neon in the middle of it.
Speaker 0: You know, if this were an anime, this would take you to the burger dimension.
Speaker 1: Maybe six, maybe like six inches square, six inches on each side square neon.
Speaker 0: Scott, did this take you to the burger dimension?
Speaker 1: You go down this hallway, and you make a right turn, and suddenly you're in like this normal burger place with stuff written all over the walls, and like movie posters, and a big long line, and people crowded in to a room about the side, maybe twice.
Speaker 1: your living room is behind, is hidden in this little hotel.
Speaker 1: It totally is not fancy in any way whatsoever.
Speaker 0: So, Scott, the burger.
Speaker 0: How's the burger?
Speaker 1: It was about the same as Shake Shack.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: But, you know, it was...
Speaker 0: It gets points for style.
Speaker 1: The style of being hidden behind the curtain in an incredibly fancy, open to the public hotel, lobby-ish area.
Speaker 1: But, yeah, for being so hidden, a lot of people fucking know where it is because it was a line out the door.
Speaker 1: And they do shakes, and they got a sign, and the sign is like, you know, "Here's how to order.
Speaker 1: If you don't order right, we're sending it to the back of the
Speaker 1: line.".
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Super Nazi style?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you have to go, and they're like, "Here's how to order a burger.
Speaker 1: Hamburger or cheeseburger.
Speaker 1: Then, you know, medium, rare, well, whatever.
Speaker 1: Then, lettuce, tomato, onion, whatever.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, if you don't do it just right, back of the line.
Speaker 1: You're taking too
Speaker 1: long.".
Speaker 1: I'm thinking they go there, like, on a weekend, and the fries, well, they look like McDonald's fries, and they were that same style.
Speaker 1: They actually had a pretty good flavor to them.
Speaker 1: I think they put something extra on them.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: I might be up that way for a meeting on Friday, so I might take a late lunch.
Speaker 1: Don't expect, you know, a fucking amazing burger.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: I'm expecting a good, solid New York burger joint burger.
Speaker 1: It's about the experience of going into the fancy hotel, and there's a secret burger place hidden behind the curtain.
Speaker 0: Perhaps behind a secret tunnel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the reason to go.
Speaker 1: Plus, I got a cheeseburger and fries, and it was 12 bucks.
Speaker 0: So, yeah.
Speaker 0: So, as you all know, there's the Thundercats animation.
Speaker 0: Oh!
Speaker 0: It's kind of an anime, except it's made for American audiences, and is in English.
Speaker 1: Hey, spirits of evil.
Speaker 0: I've been watching it.
Speaker 0: I watched the first three episodes.
Speaker 1: No, watch the first one episode.
Speaker 0: It's okay.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: My Geek Bite of it, the best I can say is okay.
Speaker 0: It has... It's really well animated.
Speaker 0: Like, it looks really good.
Speaker 0: I really like the character designs.
Speaker 0: And I like the kind of aesthetic and where it's going.
Speaker 1: I didn't see enough Mumrah yet.
Speaker 1: Mumrah's my man.
Speaker 0: Mumrah looked really kind of not scary and pathetic when he was out in the sunlight.
Speaker 1: Oh, that sucks.
Speaker 1: I had the best Mumrah toy.
Speaker 0: So, when he's inside, he's some scary shit.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: But then he gets knocked through a wall into the outside, and then he just looks like an old man.
Speaker 1: Like, ah!
Speaker 1: Well, that's how Mumrah was.
Speaker 1: So, they're actually being true to the original Mumrah.
Speaker 1: But I had the best Mumrah toy.
Speaker 1: It was like, I had the full-size action figure of Mumrah the Everliving.
Speaker 0: Whoa, I had like no Thundercats toys.
Speaker 1: I had a lot.
Speaker 1: I had the big castle and everything.
Speaker 1: And then I had this little Mumrah toy.
Speaker 1: It was like a three-inch Mumrah, but it actually came in both forms.
Speaker 1: And it was a little tiny playset where you could spin him around.
Speaker 1: You could spin it around inside the playset to transform his decayed form with ancient spirits.
Speaker 1: And it came with a tiny mommutt also.
Speaker 0: So, I guess what bothers me about it is that the writing is actually kind of derpy in terms of dialogue.
Speaker 1: The dialogue was a little bit derpy in that first episode.
Speaker 0: It does not get less derpy.
Speaker 0: Now, couple this with the fact that if you did not know this was an American cartoon, like on American TV, and you listened to it, this is one of the things I always say about anime dubs.
Speaker 1: You think it was an anime English dub?
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you listen to any anime dub, except for perhaps the Disney ones and maybe Cowboy Bebop, not knowing it's anime, and I would just take a random person off the street and be like, "Listen to this audio.
Speaker 0: What is this
Speaker 0: from?".
Speaker 0: And they'll know immediately if it's anime because anime dubs kind of suck.
Speaker 0: But it's not the actor's fault because I know for a fact that a lot of these actors that are in some shit dubs are really good when they're doing something in English that was originally in English.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or even voice acting.
Speaker 0: I don't want to say not real acting, but not also face acting.
Speaker 0: So I think it just comes down to a combination of bad script writing and bad direction that makes these anime dubs all bad.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you look, the people who do the voices in Ponies have done a bunch of not as good voices in other things, but in Ponies, there's some damn fine voice acting going on there.
Speaker 0: Oh, My Little Pony has some of the best voice acting I've seen in a long time from anything.
Speaker 0: But yet, somehow, despite the fact that this Thundercats is Studio 4C and looks amazing, it sounds like a crappy 90s anime dub.
Speaker 0: And it really takes away from the epicness of it because the characters just kind of say derpy, overdramatic things out of nowhere all the time with that kind of inflection that anime dubs always have.
Speaker 1: My theory is that it has to do with doing it together, the different styles of doing it, right?
Speaker 1: Everyone in the same room doing it before the animation is done.
Speaker 0: Ah, but many good things in America are done in the not cool style of, you know, everyone in the room.
Speaker 0: They're done it with everyone individually in their own private room.
Speaker 1: But I do, I think that from what I heard, I'm not 100% sure.
Speaker 1: I think the Ponies is done with everyone in the same room before they animate the mouths.
Speaker 0: I am guessing it is because I'm pretty sure that Futurama was done that way as well.
Speaker 1: I think Futurama was also done that way because if you look on the DVDs, you can actually, when they show the voice actors in the extras, yeah, they're always in the same room together.
Speaker 1: And I think that that style has a significant impact.
Speaker 0: The way to find out for sure, I gotta know if the Archer dubbing is done that way or not.
Speaker 0: Because Archer is also some fantastic 100% grade A voice acting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm still not, I don't think the show is funny, but the voice acting is pretty good.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 0: I usually understand where you're coming from.
Speaker 0: I know why you don't like Firefly.
Speaker 0: I can understand that.
Speaker 0: I know why you don't like, you wouldn't want to own a dog, for example.
Speaker 0: I know why you don't like Star Trek.
Speaker 0: I cannot understand why you don't like Archer.
Speaker 0: I don't get what you don't like about it.
Speaker 1: It's not funny.
Speaker 0: What's not funny about it?
Speaker 1: What's funny about it?
Speaker 0: The comedic timing of Archer and just all the other characters and the way they deliver, they're kind of realistic about as witty as real people are banter.
Speaker 1: They're not as witty as real people.
Speaker 0: I would say that they're wittier than the average person.
Speaker 0: It's like Meowshwitz in there.
Speaker 0: Whatever, Archer is the funniest show to come out on TV.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Ever.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the Thundercats TV show, take it or leave it.
Speaker 0: I might keep watching it because the animation is really good and the plot's okay.
Speaker 1: And you got nothing else to watch.
Speaker 0: But I guess the problem is, the fundamental problem, I recently watched Madoka Magica and fresh in my mind is the memory of what it feels like to watch something that's fucking awesome grade A. So watching this, it's like, I got to watch the next episode, I guess.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So speaking of Madoka Magica, here's something that's barely news, but I just want to make a point about it real quick because the rest of this episode isn't going to go long.
Speaker 1: In Japan, there was a grocery store called Lawson or some kind of convenience store or something, convenience store chain Lawson, and they had a Madoka promotion.
Speaker 1: And the way the promotion works is you would get points by being a customer and you could use the points to get exclusive Madoka Magica items.
Speaker 1: And one of the items was a poster and there was only 10 of them, period.
Speaker 1: So it's good to get enough points for the poster and you get the points before anyone else.
Speaker 0: That is a really good poster though.
Speaker 1: So the poster is pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's like a fancy 3D poster was assigned by the voice actresses and it's got the Madoka characters standing in front of Lawson wearing Lawson uniforms, I guess.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like you're basically buying an advertisement for the whatever.
Speaker 1: So I don't know.
Speaker 1: So this poster was sold on Japanese eBay, right?
Speaker 1: Equivalent, basically.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: For 501,000 yen, that's 6,600 American dollars.
Speaker 1: Oh, Yahoo Japan auction site.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I mean...
Speaker 1: Even as the best poster in the universe, and there's only one of them, and for getting God rubbed his dick on it, I'm not paying $6,600 for it.
Speaker 1: I'd pay $6,600 for...
Speaker 0: Scott, here's what I would do.
Speaker 0: I would buy it for that much money.
Speaker 0: I would then illegally make prints and sell them for $100 each.
Speaker 1: The thing is, it's some kind of 3D poster with autographs is sort of the, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the thing is, a lot of people would probably be okay with the print.
Speaker 1: I would pay $6,600 for a real arts, like Mona Lisa on the wall type of situation.
Speaker 1: I'd pay a lot more than $6,600 for that, but you can see the point, right?
Speaker 1: For a poster, I'm not paying.
Speaker 0: So very briefly, things of the day.
Speaker 0: We're talking about animation on these Wednesday nights most often.
Speaker 0: We were just talking about an anime that has great animation and derpy voice acting, and another show that has great animation and great voice acting.
Speaker 0: I submit to you a third example of great animation and also great voice acting, though they're cheating because it's an announcer narrating stuff.
Speaker 0: We've talked about these off and on, but if you have not seen all of the Goofy's Guide to Some Sport from the 40s and 50s Disney, you should watch all of them.
Speaker 0: So I picked a semi-random one.
Speaker 0: I was going to show you Goofy Gymnastics, but Scott insisted that it be changed to Goofy the Olympic Champ.
Speaker 1: No, I just said that Track and Field is my favorite one, and that I kept asking to watch it, and you kept watching different ones.
Speaker 1: Because the other ones are better.
Speaker 0: The best ones are, in order, The Art of Skiing, Goofy Gymnastics, and the Boxing one.
Speaker 1: I like the Olympic one.
Speaker 0: I do like the Olympic one.
Speaker 0: It's okay.
Speaker 0: I like how this era of Disney very often has the image of a stick of some kind that has burned down or a match or something, and it's that little black charred thing with the bulb at the top kind of bent over.
Speaker 0: Like that particular icon is in so many Disney cartoons from that era.
Speaker 0: It's kind of funny.
Speaker 0: Now that I point that out, you'll see it everywhere, but this is Goofy showing you what it's like to be an Olympic champion in 1942.
Speaker 0: A Goofy Olympic champion.
Speaker 1: So check this out.
Speaker 1: This is another, right?
Speaker 1: You all know the Daikon animation.
Speaker 1: If you don't, get out of here.
Speaker 1: This is something that I saw a tweet about.
Speaker 1: Basically, someone made a fan animation a long time ago combining Matt Cross, which is my favorite, with Minky Momo, which I don't know really that much about.
Speaker 1: I just know it's a magical girl show.
Speaker 1: So they combined Minky Momo and Matt Cross into this animation a zillion years ago.
Speaker 1: And, you know, it's not the highest quality.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of still frames.
Speaker 1: The voice acting is over non-moving mouths and whatever, but very impressive for people who did not have computers.
Speaker 1: Incredibly impressive.
Speaker 1: In fact, it's better than a lot of things people make now that they do have computers.
Speaker 1: So if you are sitting around doing nothing and just playing WoW all day or whatever, shame!
Speaker 1: And if you're out there making stuff, then here's some cool stuff.
Speaker 1: That's cool and old and kind of interesting.
Speaker 0: So before we get to the main bit, very briefly in the meta moment, if you want to see us at the New York Comic Con, tell us you're going.
Speaker 0: We'll be there at various times doing press-related stuff.
Speaker 0: MAGFest is coming up.
Speaker 0: You should probably get a hotel room and register for MAGFest soon before it sells out.
Speaker 0: It almost definitely is going to sell out.
Speaker 1: Burning Apocalypse Con 1111?
Speaker 0: Burning Apocalypse Con 1111 will probably also sell out.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And that's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: The worst webcomic contest is done because we're judging it right the fuck now.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: And the Book Club book, which we will do an episode on next Thursday.
Speaker 1: The Ear, The Eye, The Arm.
Speaker 1: But are we doing them not on Thursdays?
Speaker 0: It's up to you.
Speaker 1: I thought we already decided that.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: We will put it up at some point in the next week or two.
Speaker 0: Our review of The Ear, The Eye, The Arm by Nancy Farmer.
Speaker 0: And its sequel, The Throat.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: I was going to make a joke there.
Speaker 1: The throat, the crotch, the foot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so here's my trouble.
Speaker 0: For some reason, I could not come up with any other body parts except genitalia.
Speaker 0: So I kind of paused there and gave up.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Alright, so.
Speaker 1: Worst webcomic contest.
Speaker 1: Let's get this over with.
Speaker 0: So we were talking just a moment ago about how you should get off your ass and create something.
Speaker 0: So I want to make something very clear.
Speaker 0: Every single entry that we're about to talk about.
Speaker 1: Not every single, but most of the entries.
Speaker 1: The majority.
Speaker 0: The ones that aren't just GoDaddy squatting pages.
Speaker 0: Are the people who do them, if you are not creating something and they did this comic, no matter how horrible, they are on some level better than you.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: Because at least they made something.
Speaker 0: And no matter how bad something is, I mean, you know what?
Speaker 0: Go listen to Geek Nights from 2005.
Speaker 0: We would not have been winning the best contest, best podcast contest.
Speaker 1: Go look at the first Penny Arcade.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Still funny though.
Speaker 0: So we're going to go through a good number of the submissions here.
Speaker 1: All of them.
Speaker 0: Now, we had some very specific criteria for this contest.
Speaker 0: We did.
Speaker 0: You know, people had to submit the name of the comic and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: But we have some objective aspects of worst-ness that we wanted people to check off.
Speaker 0: So that we could kind of categorize these comics.
Speaker 0: And I think this covers pretty much everything.
Speaker 0: The categories were bad art, bad writing, racist, sexist, tries to be funny and fails, tries to be serious and fails, never gets better as time goes on, fap comic that tries to pretend it isn't, and the author is crazy independent of the comic itself.
Speaker 0: That last one counts for a lot.
Speaker 1: Well, we are going to judge these entirely subjectively.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Scott and I just have to come to some sort of consensus.
Speaker 0: I only have up the list of the comics, not who submitted them.
Speaker 0: I have the full list.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm not looking at the names of the people.
Speaker 0: They're scrolled off to the right.
Speaker 1: Well, we're just going to go in order of submission.
Speaker 1: So the first one and actually the second one that were submitted were the exact same ones submitted by two different people.
Speaker 0: Well, it's technically, there's two different comics there, but they're by the same person and they're basically the same.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're going to put, if it's on the same website, I count it as the same webcomic, right?
Speaker 1: Like there was a last second entry that I didn't even really get enough time to look at.
Speaker 0: I looked at it.
Speaker 0: It's pretty bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but, you know, it seemed to be a website with a whole bunch of comics done by the same, you know, the same crew of people.
Speaker 1: And it's like, dudes, that, you know, that counts as one comic, right?
Speaker 1: It's, you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So mama is and/or Hathor the cow goddess.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: So this comic, basically the deal here is that some lady who, she is a geek of breastfeeding.
Speaker 1: That is the thing she is into.
Speaker 0: I do not think she is a geek.
Speaker 0: She is a nerd of breastfeeding.
Speaker 0: Indeed.
Speaker 0: Because I do not, I think that breast, her knowledge and interest in breastfeeding is very deep.
Speaker 0: But I do not detect many other interests.
Speaker 1: Well, she, you know, you get an idea of like what this person, you know, believes.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know, obviously she believes in breastfeeding, but on the other hand, she takes it way too far.
Speaker 0: And also, how can you take it too far?
Speaker 0: I mean, breastfeeding like a boss on Deborah's desk.
Speaker 1: No, you know, like militant breastfeeding, like everybody, you know, it's like if you're a vegetarian, you're just like, I don't eat meat versus you don't eat meat, die in hell.
Speaker 1: No, I'll say, I mean, you do eat meat, die in hell.
Speaker 0: I do agree with the sentiment that Barbara shouldn't be illegal and breastfeeding should be okay.
Speaker 0: The only places breastfeeding should not be okay are the same places that eating is not okay.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: But the point, you know, this person, you know, they suggested that she was crazy, at least in her, in the submissions.
Speaker 1: And it's like, well, she's partially crazy, right?
Speaker 0: I think she's a little crazy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Like on the one hand, she's got some good ideas.
Speaker 1: Like she's into free range kids and she's got, there was some comics there that depicted like a cage around the playground and she was like, no good.
Speaker 1: You know?
Speaker 1: And I was like, yeah, you tell them.
Speaker 1: And then, but there were some other ones that were, I was like, uh, you, yeah.
Speaker 0: I think part of what makes it odd is that, well here, I'll read the description that one of the people submitted.
Speaker 0: Heather, the cow goddess features an ultra liberal cow headed, breasted as you can tell because every other comic features her breasts.
Speaker 0: Woman who does nothing but espouse the benefits of breastfeeding.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: Home birth.
Speaker 0: Home school.
Speaker 1: Home birth is not a good idea.
Speaker 0: Home schooling.
Speaker 1: Not a good idea.
Speaker 0: Unschooling.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: While mocking such absurd things as science, medical technology and actual structured education.
Speaker 1: Uh, not good.
Speaker 1: Now it's like one of those people who basically believes, you know, I guess the set of things, some of which are right and some of which are wrong.
Speaker 0: Now that's fine.
Speaker 1: I'm not, I don't think that, I am personally not going to judge someone's comic based on how much I personally agree or disagree with their things.
Speaker 1: I'm just going to, you know, but I am going to judge the person based on how crazy they are.
Speaker 1: Someone could completely agree with me on everything and still be a nut.
Speaker 1: Someone could also disagree with me on everything and be perfectly sane.
Speaker 0: Well, for example, I was at the, uh, the Jon Stewart rally and there's this one guy and we're, you know, we're all talking and he's like, yeah.
Speaker 0: He's making all these good points about, you know, the general liberal intelligent politics that we espouse.
Speaker 0: And then he looks up and he's like, you see that?
Speaker 0: That's a chem trail.
Speaker 0: And I was like, okay, we're done here.
Speaker 0: I was like, you believe, don't even talk to me.
Speaker 0: And I just, I gave up on him.
Speaker 0: So I got to back up here.
Speaker 0: I think that this comment got trolled almost down.
Speaker 0: I feel like this woman probably had to put up with a lot of the internet hate machine.
Speaker 1: Probably.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Because I go back, uh, ultra liberal cowheaded, you know, breasted woman, literally cowheaded.
Speaker 0: The art is just kind of a normal human mother with this sort of cow mask face.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The art is really not so great.
Speaker 0: It's not that bad though.
Speaker 0: It's kind of cute.
Speaker 1: It's better than I can draw.
Speaker 0: It's better than some web comics I have read for a long time.
Speaker 1: It's true.
Speaker 1: It doesn't improve that much over time, but it does improve slightly.
Speaker 1: My main problem with it, when she's very bad with the speech bubbles and putting the words in the right place.
Speaker 1: The lettering is just awful.
Speaker 0: She obviously has like, oh, this is my idea.
Speaker 0: And it just kind of, uh, shirotasms all over the page.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: A lot of the comics actually have this problem of awful lettering, right?
Speaker 1: It's like when you read, when you get a Marvel comic or a DC comic, they have, you know, penciler, writer, penciler, colorist, inker, and letterer.
Speaker 1: And lettering is like the last thing a lot of web convicts care about.
Speaker 1: Like some of them never even try to improve lettering, you know, if they're just concentrating on art.
Speaker 1: They just sort of, you know, make a speech bubble and fill it in.
Speaker 1: And it's like, yeah, it's a bad idea.
Speaker 1: Penny Arcade on the other hand, excellent lettering.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know, offhand, I'm just going to rate them on craziness.
Speaker 0: This gets five.
Speaker 0: I'm not, I don't know what the scale is, but I'm going to set it at five.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know what the scale is, but I mean, this is definitely, you know, I'm not going to read this.
Speaker 1: It's a bad web comic.
Speaker 1: But I'm not going to make, this is not the worst web comic.
Speaker 0: It's, you know, it's weird.
Speaker 0: There's like this line.
Speaker 0: Like there's this whole scale of web comics.
Speaker 0: And then there's this line below with, below which is like the untouchables.
Speaker 0: It's well above that.
Speaker 0: Like below that line is almost undifferentiated from white noise.
Speaker 1: So yeah, so mama is slash cow classic cow goddess.
Speaker 1: In fact, you know what, I'm going to say right now.
Speaker 1: Submitted by Colby and also fat 101, you did not win.
Speaker 1: No, because- But at the same time, winning is losing in this contest.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is, this is great in that this is why it can't win.
Speaker 0: It's weird enough to where anyone who is on the internet should find it and go, what?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's actually, it's not worth reading every day, obviously, but just go to it once so you know it exists and see what it's about.
Speaker 0: So we're not going to talk about every time it got submitted, but control delete was the next submission.
Speaker 1: Gasp.
Speaker 1: And the first person to submit it was no name, no email address.
Speaker 0: It got submitted a bunch more times.
Speaker 1: So control all delete wins the award for- We're only going to discuss it once right now, but we'll count.
Speaker 1: We're going to go down the list sequentially of order of submission.
Speaker 1: So we'll mention every time there's another control delete submission and have a final tally at the end.
Speaker 0: Control all delete wins the award for being control all delete.
Speaker 0: I don't know what I can say.
Speaker 0: I hadn't actually really read it until it got submitted in our contest.
Speaker 0: Like I had always kind of ignored it.
Speaker 1: I knew it existed, obviously, for a long time.
Speaker 1: And I, you know, I had seen the guy who made it at conventions, and I heard many stories about him of various vagueness and, you know, things.
Speaker 1: And I knew that he was sort of crazy and weird actually reading his comic.
Speaker 1: You know, for comics that were incredibly long, I just sort of read like the earliest comics, some random ones in the middle, and then the latest comics.
Speaker 1: A, what was interesting about this is the art progressed, but it didn't progress that much considering the age of it.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: It's like there was a significant improvement, but considering the time period, the improvement was not congruent with the time period.
Speaker 1: It should have improved much, much more.
Speaker 0: Like I hit a random comic here and it's from 2005.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And it looks kind of like Penny Arcade from a similar era.
Speaker 1: Well, that's something else I was going to say, right?
Speaker 1: Is that a lot of the jokes, like I picked a bunch of random comics in the middle.
Speaker 1: Almost all of them appeared to be stealing or, you know, leaning on jokes from other things.
Speaker 1: Like he was just retelling jokes that belonged to other people.
Speaker 1: Now, maybe he invented those jokes and I read the retelling somewhere else.
Speaker 1: It's definitely possible.
Speaker 1: But for there to be so many of them, right?
Speaker 1: It's like how come this, you know, either everyone is stealing this guy's jokes or this guy is stealing everyone's jokes, which is more likely, right?
Speaker 1: So it seemed like he wasn't even really writing it.
Speaker 1: He was just finding the joke on the internet of the day and making a comic that says the same exact joke of what he found.
Speaker 0: Well, it felt more like it was, I don't want to say it was stealing from Penny Arcade specifically, but it was...
Speaker 1: There were some, I do remember one or two instances of Penny Arcade stealing specifically.
Speaker 0: It was just a lot of the same kind of humor, but done in four frames instead of three.
Speaker 0: Which, that's, you know, we have some old comics we could talk about, but they weren't submitted, so we won't.
Speaker 0: Where we had a, basically the comic would be hilarious and then one of the co-creators would always add like one extra panel that ruined it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so what else about control, delete?
Speaker 1: It's not actually funny.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, I've clicked on three random ones in a row and they're lit like the exact same joke as a Penny Arcade from a similar time.
Speaker 0: That's what I was saying.
Speaker 0: I know, but I'm just literally like clicking random here.
Speaker 0: I know, that's what I did too.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 0: I don't, I can't, I don't want to say control, delete didn't win yet because the comic itself is not that bad.
Speaker 0: It's just kind of really mediocre and just goes on for a long time.
Speaker 0: But the author is kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, if you believe the stories about the guy.
Speaker 0: There's too many of them for me to discount all of them from so many different sources.
Speaker 1: No, I don't discount them.
Speaker 1: I know he's crazy, but I, you know, I'm trying to judge the comics.
Speaker 1: I mean, I am taking craziness into account, no doubt, but I am trying to judge the comics more than the craziness.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if you, you know, you multiply comic badness by say 10 and craziness by 0.05, still a closely run affair.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think he's pretty much equally crazy to the cow goddess lady.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is the cow goddess lady feels a lot more benign.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: Like, like I feel like if you criticized her, her response would be, I do what I do for the people who like it.
Speaker 0: And I feel like Tim Buckley would spittle on me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he definitely seems like there's a lot of drama going on.
Speaker 0: Maybe he's an Andy Kaufman, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's just, especially because I talked to a lot of people who know him more directly.
Speaker 1: If he was an Andy Kaufman, then he should win best upcoming.
Speaker 0: Yes, absolutely.
Speaker 0: The thing is, people talk about that plot twist that I actually didn't read that part and didn't find it randomly and didn't bother to take the time to find it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is something is if you, you know, people who submitted comics that were very long, just due to the nature of them and the nature of this contest, I could judge all the parts of the comic with my method of beginning, middle, end, but I couldn't judge the long term plot.
Speaker 1: That's just impossible for me to look at.
Speaker 1: So if, you know, I know Control Delete does have sort of this long term plot, but I couldn't really bring that into account in my subjective decision making because I had no way to experience it properly.
Speaker 1: Even I could read a summary of Cliff's notes of it, but that doesn't do anything for you.
Speaker 1: But I did notice that pretty much the newest comics and the oldest comics, it doesn't seem like there's been a lot of progression.
Speaker 1: It seems like it's, you know, you could read the first few comics to introduce you to the characters and then start reading the new ones and skip the whole middle and you wouldn't be too lost.
Speaker 0: It's just like, the Cowyotus one, if I say, hey, check this out, people will go, whoa, and remember it.
Speaker 0: If I tell someone random just to read Control Delete, they'll probably just kind of stop reading it and forget about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think so.
Speaker 1: So maybe if you've never read web comics before and you come across this, you know, you haven't heard these jokes before elsewhere, then it might work on you if you're, you know, because a lot of people like a lot of crap.
Speaker 0: But seriously, dude who submitted it, you did not need to check fap comic that tries to pretend it isn't.
Speaker 1: Okay, next choice.
Speaker 0: I actually... Oh, this one wins.
Speaker 0: Fuck this comic.
Speaker 0: It's terrible.
Speaker 1: I read this entire comic as it was coming out right up to the end.
Speaker 0: And even from the beginning at RIT, Scott and I barely fucking knew each other.
Speaker 0: And he's like, you know, we're really getting into web comics because that's when they were like really exploding with Mega Tokyo and then Penny Arcade and everything.
Speaker 0: And Scott's the only one in the crew who liked Bob and George.
Speaker 0: I guess Greg liked it too.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I liked Bob and George.
Speaker 0: And to this day, none of us can understand why.
Speaker 0: I just didn't... It wasn't funny.
Speaker 1: So here's the deal with this comic.
Speaker 1: This guy originally wanted to draw web comics.
Speaker 1: He started out drawing a web comic about Bob and George.
Speaker 1: And he had the worst arts in the universe because he was just starting.
Speaker 1: But he was so bad, his room for improvement, if he would have kept it up for a long time, would have been vast.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: He started with like barely stick figures.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: That's my new favorite insult.
Speaker 0: Given time, your capability for improvement is vast.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: But he quickly gave up on that and went into sprite comic territory.
Speaker 1: And he was pretty much the first and premiere sprite comic to go into the Mega Man zone.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: You know, 8-Bit Theater is pretty much the only good sprite comic, I'm guessing.
Speaker 0: I'll stand by that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But, you know...
Speaker 0: Well, 8-Bit Theater, it amazes me how well he integrated those little sprites into personalities that to this day... As strong as ponies.
Speaker 0: I see a black mage and that character is... There is no way to dissociate that character.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, so Bob and George, you know, he did it with Mega Man.
Speaker 1: And he started by progressing through the Mega Man games.
Speaker 1: One, two, three, right?
Speaker 1: And he had some funny jokes in there.
Speaker 1: My favorite of which, which I still remember, is Flash Man.
Speaker 1: And he's like, "Flash Man, what do you
Speaker 1: do?".
Speaker 1: And he's like,
Speaker 1: "No!"
Speaker 1: Because he's going to flash him with, like, you know, a trench coat.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I never found any of the jokes funny.
Speaker 1: I thought that was funny.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I like Mega Man a lot.
Speaker 0: It was just... Yeah, but that's just not a good webcomic make.
Speaker 1: It's better than the other previous two.
Speaker 0: Name another funny one other than the Flash Man one.
Speaker 1: There were ones that were funny because I kept reading it and I laughed occasionally.
Speaker 1: But I can't remember what they were because it was a zillion years ago.
Speaker 1: The thing is, after he sort of finishes up with the Mega Man games...
Speaker 0: Okay, this one's okay kind of funny.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: He goes on sort of a crazy plot, like, involving Bob and George and all these other characters.
Speaker 1: And it's sort of incomprehensible.
Speaker 1: and there's some, like, self-insertion and time travel.
Speaker 0: Ah, the problem with many webcomics.
Speaker 0: Many of which were not entered, so I will not talk about them.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Where you have a funny comic and then you try to get all plotty.
Speaker 0: And instead of making a new comic for that plot with characters for that plot, you just keep making the same fucking comic forever and try to mash all your plots onto it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But eventually, he did end the comic at some point.
Speaker 1: It did end.
Speaker 1: And he sort of weirdly brought the original fact that he was, you know, the true origin was.
Speaker 1: he was trying to draw and he failed and switched to sprites, but he managed to tie that back in somehow.
Speaker 1: It's relatively incomprehensible.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't actually suggest anyone read it.
Speaker 1: But, you know, it's not the worst.
Speaker 1: It's far from the worst.
Speaker 1: It's better than Control Delete.
Speaker 1: It's better than any of the ones so far.
Speaker 1: So far it's the least bad of our three comics that we've gone over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I must say, and I cannot stress this enough, it has never made me actually laugh.
Speaker 0: I read a whole bunch of it a long time ago because Scott just wouldn't fucking shut up about it.
Speaker 1: I don't remember not shutting up about it.
Speaker 1: I just remember you saying it.
Speaker 0: Because you'd always be like, "Hey, Rem.
Speaker 0: Flashman.".
Speaker 0: And I'd be like, "I'm not gonna read Bob and
Speaker 0: George.".
Speaker 0: And you're like, "You gotta read Bob and George.
Speaker 0: It's
Speaker 0: great.".
Speaker 0: In fact, we've had this same conversation many times for the past decade.
Speaker 0: "I don't like Bob and
Speaker 0: George.".
Speaker 1: It's not the worst.
Speaker 1: You know, there's ten billion webcomics out there just as good as it, with the same Mary Sue kind of sprite fan of something stuff.
Speaker 1: And this one actually has a little bit of funniness to it, which puts it above those.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying it's Penny Arcade or anything.
Speaker 0: Alright, so someone submitted a comic that I'd never heard of called The Freckled Finger.
Speaker 1: Right, so I took a look at this one.
Speaker 0: I want to read the submission.
Speaker 0: The artist clearly puts a lot of work into this comic.
Speaker 0: What sort of makes the fact that it is unbelievably offensive even worse.
Speaker 0: The guy is clearly trolling.
Speaker 0: However, the racism, sexism, and general horribleness does not at all feel like the sort of parody racism that people trying to be edgy, et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 0: It wasn't as offensive as I expected it to be.
Speaker 0: But then again, I've seen some pretty offensive things in my time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, some of these comics, right?
Speaker 1: First of all, the art's actually kind of good.
Speaker 1: This didn't have awful art like all the other ones.
Speaker 0: Some of them are funny in the same way that some of the parking lot is full.
Speaker 0: comics were funny.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: They weren't all that offensive.
Speaker 1: For example, there was one that's like, "How does a sadomasochist propose to a
Speaker 1: cutter?".
Speaker 1: And it's like, you see this guy with all these tattoos proposing to some girl, and then he takes a razor blade and cuts her finger.
Speaker 1: It's like, "Okay, I'm not laughing out loud at
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 1: But it's like, you know, this guy's trying.
Speaker 1: He comes up with an original sort of clever idea each time.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you can see what he was going for even if it didn't work out.
Speaker 1: It's like he's trying.
Speaker 1: He's got some sort of spark.
Speaker 1: He just doesn't have any fire.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, the other thing is I feel like he too often did fall back on, "I'll just do something really
Speaker 0: offensive."
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: And that's where edgy comedy fails when you do it.
Speaker 0: It is just offensive, but there's no cleverness.
Speaker 0: For example, the NSMB is offensive, but it's just clever enough to where you can laugh at it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So look at, for example, Penny Arcade or South Park are offensive, but they're not primarily trying to be offensive.
Speaker 1: The offensiveness is the side effect of the original joke that they are telling.
Speaker 1: It's just they don't hold back, so they end up being offensive with a dick wolf or some such.
Speaker 1: Whereas if you aim for offensiveness first, then you have no joke.
Speaker 1: You're just being extreme and out there with nothing to go by.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: But yeah, the art on this is actually pretty good.
Speaker 1: He has a bunch of different styles.
Speaker 1: He does a Calvin and Hobbes one at one point.
Speaker 0: I was looking at that one right now.
Speaker 0: It's actually kind of funny.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, so this is actually, I don't know if I'd read this just because it's not funny, but this is actually well above average in the webcomics world if you take every webcomic that ever existed into an account.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The person who submitted this named Derek, I guess, just really didn't like it or was really offended by it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it is offensive.
Speaker 0: Don't get me wrong.
Speaker 1: Well, he says while he's in the submission, he said the guy was trolling.
Speaker 0: No, I don't take that as an excuse.
Speaker 1: I don't think he's trolling.
Speaker 0: I think he's just trying to be funny.
Speaker 1: He's just trying to be funny by being offensive.
Speaker 0: But seriously, if you want an offensive webcomic, you should read The Parking Lot Is Full.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: And/or The Thin H Line, which was renamed Sexy Losers later.
Speaker 1: Say A Freckled Finger?
Speaker 1: Not the worst webcomic.
Speaker 0: Sarah Zero.
Speaker 0: I didn't read this one.
Speaker 0: I must have missed it by accident.
Speaker 1: So Sarah Zero is less of a webcomic and more of like an illustrated sort of action sci-fi thing, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like each comic, it's got this fancy kind of website that's also sort of hard to navigate.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm going through it now.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The lettering is actually great.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, I was just complaining about lettering on the other comic.
Speaker 1: The lettering on this is like most of what it has going for it.
Speaker 1: Like if you go to like a few comics back from the newest one, like someone's like whacking someone on the side of the head and then it's like snowplow.
Speaker 1: It's like there's a bullet in the word snowplow is behind it with all the blood coming out of the person's head.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean, it's you know, it's an action sci-fi kind of thing.
Speaker 1: There's a whole bunch of comics.
Speaker 1: Here's one where there's a car that's pretty well rendered driving down the road with an explosion behind it.
Speaker 1: And on the front of the car is a plow.
Speaker 1: And on the plow in reverse, it says slow traffic, keep right.
Speaker 1: It's like, ah, you know, it's fairly incomprehensible.
Speaker 1: But yeah, that's that's the problem with it is that you cannot even if you start at the beginning and read it one at a time.
Speaker 1: You know, it's more of a well-lettered illustrated thing than a comic, I guess.
Speaker 1: But it's you can't figure out what's going on at all.
Speaker 1: It's like who are these characters?
Speaker 0: The person is trying to do something neat.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't really.
Speaker 0: I can't say it's bad because it's far from bad.
Speaker 0: I again wouldn't read it because I can't tell what's going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't you.
Speaker 1: it's like you can't care about it.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: you can look at a single strip or panel and just be like, oh, that's I see what you did there with that lettering around the shape of the person's face.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, but there's no reason to read it because you can't tell what the fuck is going on.
Speaker 0: But then again, there was no reason to retry gun for the same reason.
Speaker 1: That's correct.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So actually, I'd say this is about equal to Try Gun manga, which is not which is very far away from the worst web comic ever.
Speaker 1: But still, Try Gun manga is not good.
Speaker 1: Don't read it.
Speaker 0: OK, so here's where we get on the rabbit.
Speaker 0: Oh, God.
Speaker 0: It updated.
Speaker 0: There's there's.
Speaker 0: there's some furry sex.
Speaker 1: Kitten K. Voodle.
Speaker 0: So I heard of Kitten K. Voodle many times.
Speaker 1: You know, how do you know?
Speaker 1: we met the guy who makes this right?
Speaker 0: Did we?
Speaker 1: At Connecticut.
Speaker 1: Oh, shit.
Speaker 1: We were at Connecticut and sitting there in it was an early Connecticut.
Speaker 1: The first or second one we were at, we were sitting around talking.
Speaker 1: This guy with this fat, smelly guy who had bad B.O.
Speaker 1: wanted to show us his arts.
Speaker 1: And it was this comic.
Speaker 1: And then when I saw this comic, I was like, oh, I've seen this before.
Speaker 1: It's that guy who showed me all this furry porn that he draws at Connecticut.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You don't have to shoot it at me in reference to semen from.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Pretty much it.
Speaker 0: I want to read the submission here because it does literally explain exactly what we're talking about.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: This comic is famous among furries.
Speaker 0: So there's these two furry characters, Kit and K. Voodle, married couple.
Speaker 0: They moved to a town called Yiffberg, which indicates strongly which direction this is going.
Speaker 0: They find they have a massive crop of Boink Berries, a berry that keeps one's Nice.
Speaker 1: Let's move there.
Speaker 1: They decide only people are allowed, no animals.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Cat girls are cool.
Speaker 0: Maybe a fox girl.
Speaker 0: I could live with that.
Speaker 1: It's all you.
Speaker 0: There is nothing wrong with anthropomorphic art or any of that stuff.
Speaker 0: When I say furry, I'm going to say this right now.
Speaker 0: I mean, people on the Internet who like anthropomorphic art and have a persecution complex.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, Goofy was anthropomorphic art, but that was a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's just if if you have a chip on your shoulder about Is Goofy a furry?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Is Mickey Mouse furry?
Speaker 0: It requires the chip on the shoulder.
Speaker 0: It has to be the biggest chip ever.
Speaker 1: Is Bugs Bunny furry?
Speaker 0: Well, anyway.
Speaker 1: Roger Rabbit?
Speaker 1: Furry?
Speaker 0: So, yeah, it's just them having sex and this weird like government, I guess, trying to stop people from having sex.
Speaker 0: To quote the last sentence in the review, it's just like the most bizarre author track you've ever read.
Speaker 0: Like a Jack Chick track for furry comics.
Speaker 1: Now, you know, for example, in the earliest part of the comic, it's that, you know, Kit and Kay Boodle get stuck in a hole in the ground, literally like a rabbit hole.
Speaker 1: They can't get out and, you know, they do it.
Speaker 1: And then their explosion from doing it causes them to be shot out of the hole, or at least it causes Kay to be shot out of the hole.
Speaker 1: And I guess she saves Kit with a rope or whatever later.
Speaker 1: But, you know, basically the art on this actually is not bad, except for the fact that it's drawing what is drawings of.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, there we go.
Speaker 0: I've been going backtracking and I finally found one that did not have semen in it.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: But, yeah, you know, the art is actually good at arts, kind of.
Speaker 1: You know, it's pretty typical, like newspaper quality, you know, anthropomorphic arts.
Speaker 1: It just happens to be art of animal people having sex and doing all sorts of nasty shit.
Speaker 1: Other than that, it's good arts.
Speaker 1: If he drew a non-furry comic, it probably would be pretty well done if someone else wrote it.
Speaker 0: Actually, I would argue that his earlier, sketchier art looks better than the later color art.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, he definitely has a different style.
Speaker 1: It's not really a matter of, you know, I don't know.
Speaker 1: But the guy can draw, regardless.
Speaker 1: A lot better than most people.
Speaker 0: But it's not, for what it is, it's not a bad comic.
Speaker 0: Because remember the category I said very specifically was "fap comic that tries to pretend it
Speaker 0: isn't.".
Speaker 0: This is a fap comic that does not make any bones about the fact that it's not bony.
Speaker 0: That's exactly right.
Speaker 1: Like, even though it's furry and it's not my thing and it's not most people's thing, right?
Speaker 1: He's not even, like, trying to be shy about it.
Speaker 1: This guy is just like, "Fucking animals, fucking hell, yeah.
Speaker 1: This turns me on.
Speaker 1: It's
Speaker 1: awesome.".
Speaker 1: And I'm like, "More power to you,
Speaker 1: man.".
Speaker 0: You know, it's almost as though he's not a furry because you have to have that chip on your shoulder or you don't count.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this guy has no chip.
Speaker 1: He's just like, "Animals with dicks?
Speaker 1: Fucking, let's get it on.
Speaker 1: Semen
Speaker 1: everywhere.".
Speaker 0: Granted, the comic itself has some of that persecution plot in it.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: And I don't know if that bleeds over into his real life.
Speaker 1: But it's like, you know, like, in the very first comic, like, he just sex all over the place and he's like, "Here's what you're in for.
Speaker 1: Just so you
Speaker 1: know.".
Speaker 0: So this is definitely not the worst webcomic.
Speaker 1: And while the guy, when I met him, was, you know, had bad B.O.
Speaker 1: and was fat, he wasn't actually, like, you know, offensive personality-wise.
Speaker 1: Except for the fact that he's like, "Hey, check out my furry
Speaker 1: porn.".
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: I'd rather hang out with- But at least he wasn't ashamed of, like, "Here, check out my furry
Speaker 1: porn.".
Speaker 0: I'm much happier hanging out with Mr.
Speaker 0: "Hey, look at my furry porn" than "Hey, check out my disembowelment hentai guy at
Speaker 0: RIT.".
Speaker 1: So, Kitten K. Poodle, I'm not reading it.
Speaker 1: If you're not a furry, you shouldn't read it.
Speaker 1: But actually, if you're a furry, this is probably the best webcomic in the world for you.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: I mean, come on.
Speaker 0: So, The Watch, which I already knew about because it's kind of famous for being a poster child of Mary Sues.
Speaker 1: Is it now?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I can't- There's a whole TV Tropes page, I don't know if it's still there, on this comic.
Speaker 0: In fact, I believe they have a syndrome like The Watch Syndrome.
Speaker 0: It's kind of got a- I don't know, it's a- This is the archetypical fap comic that tries to pretend it isn't.
Speaker 1: Is The Watch really that- I never heard of it before, ever.
Speaker 0: It's famous among people who care about drama on the internet.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: I'll find the TV Tropes page.
Speaker 0: You can start talking about your reviews.
Speaker 0: I knew a little bit more about it than you did.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, first of all, the art starts out as, like, you know- The first comics look basically about the same as the first Penny arcades, maybe a little bit worse.
Speaker 1: The newest ones look only slightly better.
Speaker 1: Like, the level of improvement was not much at all, really.
Speaker 1: You could have improved a lot more there.
Speaker 1: The other thing is that it's like, I read the first few strips, and it's like, how the hell does this get to be where it is in the newest ones?
Speaker 1: It's like, I had to do a whole lot of reading to figure out what the hell's going on here, and I am not doing that at all.
Speaker 0: Apparently there are spin-offs of The Watch.
Speaker 0: So, here's the deal.
Speaker 0: One, it's basically a comic for people who have certain oddly specific fetishes and want something to titillate them.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: Based on the way people talk about it, and the content.
Speaker 1: But it's like, from the- I looked at a bunch of strips, and I couldn't find anything that was, you know, fat fish or weird like that.
Speaker 0: Well, 'cause it's not- you realize there's a whole community of people on the internet who are really into this sort of gender transformation-y stuff.
Speaker 1: I did see some of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot of that.
Speaker 0: Maybe we read different parts of this comic.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 1: But it's like, it mostly just looked like, you know, pretty average webcomic.
Speaker 1: Like, okay, there's like a magical girl, and there's some, you know- But think about the plot.
Speaker 1: She's in high school.
Speaker 0: Basically, the main character girl is basically better than everyone else, more powerful than everyone else, fixes everything no matter what, everyone else is kind of pointless.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, it's not like it's, you know- It reeks of Mary Sue.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not well plotted or structured or anything like that, but it's just, it's not like painfully awful, like oh god, this is the worst thing I've ever read.
Speaker 0: Well here, I'll read the description again from submission.
Speaker 1: Is that a lot of people coming to these comics, right, is they brought in like the community or the meta around the comics, you know, and they, because they know about the comics.
Speaker 0: Ah, true, for example.
Speaker 1: That's why they submit them, but me, I'm coming to this, never even heard of this before.
Speaker 0: So here's a good example.
Speaker 1: So I don't get any of that.
Speaker 0: Say, you know, there is pornography of Pokemon out there.
Speaker 0: It's true.
Speaker 0: But you can't say that that makes Pokemon bad.
Speaker 0: Right, it's like- That people are turned on by Pikachu.
Speaker 1: Exactly, it's like if you, you know, there's a world of Pokemon stuff, so if you ask me about Pokemon, there's a whole bunch of stuff that comes to mind, like the third movie for instance.
Speaker 1: But if you just give someone the first Pokemon game and play that and that's all they know of Pokemon is what's in that, actually in that game, their judgment is going to be completely different from say someone who reads the forums of the watch or knows the history of the watch or the person who writes and draws the watch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, for example, I for a long time read a comic called College Roomies from Hell and it's one of these kind of general mediocre- Talk about art doesn't improve.
Speaker 0: It actually does.
Speaker 0: It looks way better than it used to.
Speaker 1: Barely.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot better.
Speaker 1: Maybe about the same as the watch.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the submission I present to you, quote, I present to thee the watch, a comic with so much potential that it's squandering of its legacy.
Speaker 1: I present to thee a comic- Squandering, that it's squandering of it is legendary.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: I present to thee a comic that barely improved its art despite existing for as long as it has, despite the artist working alongside someone whose art is identical to her only with actual effort.
Speaker 0: A comic that has much body horror, an explanation of what body horror is, horrifying, fascinating.
Speaker 0: No, it's fat material.
Speaker 0: At least according to the submitter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in what I read I couldn't find any fat material.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's because I read the descriptions of every submission before I actually read the comics.
Speaker 0: So, you know, the submission talks a lot about why it's fat material for this stuff.
Speaker 0: So I found a lot of stuff on the internet about body horror fetishism.
Speaker 0: People who like the idea of being turned to stone, like they'll probably watch My Little Pony when the cockatrice gets fluttershy and ah shit son.
Speaker 1: Uh huh.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: So it is possible that this comic is catering to that demographic.
Speaker 1: Possible.
Speaker 1: That's fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's not the worst webcomic.
Speaker 1: I'm not judging you on your demographic.
Speaker 0: Even if someone actually tries to cater to that demographic?
Speaker 1: I mean look, am I going to say that Penny Arcade is good because it caters to people like us and it's bad because it doesn't cater to little kids?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Am I going to say that Gronk by Katie Cook, which is awesome by the way, is bad because it caters to little kids and doesn't cater to me?
Speaker 1: So what does it matter if it caters to a sexual deviancy as opposed to an age group?
Speaker 0: I mean we just spent more minutes than I ever thought I would in my life defending furry porn.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But to read the end here because I was talking about the Mary Sue stuff, our titular watch named Annie Anonymous is a person who can do no wrong and if she does do wrong it's waved away and she suffers no consequences.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the thing.
Speaker 1: He's complaining about the long term plot which I do agree should be part of the determination of the worst webcomic.
Speaker 1: if the comic has a long term plot.
Speaker 1: But it can't be reasonably expected for anyone to judge it if they haven't read the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, every random page I read was someone being turned into something and some kind of episodic humor about that.
Speaker 1: There was a whole chapter about like clones doing something that was weird.
Speaker 0: Doing something, eh?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Eh, eh.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So yeah, the watch, just another mediocre webcomic really.
Speaker 1: I don't see what the big deal is.
Speaker 0: It doesn't delve into the realm of worst.
Speaker 0: Control alt delete.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Control alt delete.
Speaker 1: Oh no, you skipped over Electric Retard.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Electric Retard looks like it was drawn with the MS Paint and I think it was.
Speaker 1: But this is basically another one of those try to be offensive on purpose with MS Paint.
Speaker 1: Sort of the same way the other one was.
Speaker 1: Only the art in this is much worse.
Speaker 1: But while the art is worse, the design is actually better.
Speaker 1: It's like his whole sight is drawn with MS Paint and the same sort of almost crayon MS Paint style.
Speaker 1: The comic, everything.
Speaker 1: So while it's bad.
Speaker 0: He's got his own MS Paint ad.
Speaker 0: With Adolf Hitler on it.
Speaker 0: So you know what you're getting into.
Speaker 0: And uh.
Speaker 0: It's pretty bad though.
Speaker 1: It is pretty bad.
Speaker 1: And it's pretty much like, you know, like the offensiveness.
Speaker 1: Like the other one was like trying to make a joke with the offensiveness.
Speaker 0: This one is just offensive.
Speaker 1: This one is pretty much just show you something extreme with no joke.
Speaker 1: Like the second comic.
Speaker 1: Is it the second one?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the second comic and the whole thing.
Speaker 1: There's only like a 40th or something of them.
Speaker 1: You can read them all.
Speaker 1: The second one was called First Born Son.
Speaker 1: And it's like a mom in the hospital with the baby and the dad.
Speaker 1: And the dad's like, wow, my first born son.
Speaker 1: Can I hold him, honey?
Speaker 1: Here you go.
Speaker 1: So then some criminal shows up with a jail, you know, black and white stripe jailbird shirt.
Speaker 1: He grabs the dad.
Speaker 1: The baby falls on the floor with his head bleeding.
Speaker 1: The dude drives a wood chipper into the room.
Speaker 1: And then he jerks off while the dad is going through the wood chipper.
Speaker 1: It's like, it's like, dude, that's it.
Speaker 0: I mean, the parking lot is full, was clever in its horrifyingness.
Speaker 0: This is just, this is just, you know, the worst one is titled Pimp.
Speaker 1: Uh, which number is that?
Speaker 0: So here's the plot.
Speaker 0: There is a, there is a black man who is in fact a pimp, a pretty style and pimp.
Speaker 0: He's walking.
Speaker 1: I see him.
Speaker 0: Another black man appears with a gun with a gun and the pimp man raises his fist and says pimp style and transforms into pimp man.
Speaker 0: Bullets do not hurt him.
Speaker 0: He stops this bad guy.
Speaker 0: A white man sees him and says the words brown up, turns into clan man.
Speaker 0: They have a fight that involves a whip and a gigantic black man's penis being wielded like a urine spewing whip.
Speaker 0: And it ends with him being lynched.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 0: That was a joke.
Speaker 0: That was, that was fantastic.
Speaker 1: He's not lynched.
Speaker 1: He was burned on a cross.
Speaker 0: I guess he's crucified and then burned.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, it's just offensive.
Speaker 0: Like at no point is there a punchline.
Speaker 0: It's just horrible.
Speaker 1: Uh, it's pretty bad.
Speaker 1: This is maybe the worst yet ish.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I think this so far is the worst comic we've actually talked about because it has no redeeming qualities.
Speaker 0: No improvement.
Speaker 1: The only good thing about it is the design, the graphic design as a whole, the unification of the site and the comic is the only good thing going for it.
Speaker 0: So his fact is basically like I'm banned in Germany, which is probably true.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Uh, you can't contact me.
Speaker 0: There's no contact info.
Speaker 0: I draw it all myself.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Uh, you can't take me down.
Speaker 0: People try all the time.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So I would imagine the sole purpose of this comic is to instill outrage and then enjoy said outrage.
Speaker 1: If this guy is trolling, then he's the best web comic ever.
Speaker 0: No, because he doesn't, most people would avoid it.
Speaker 1: The fact that I did not know about it is a significant redemption if he's trolling.
Speaker 0: The fact that I did not know about it until it was submitted to us means that he's failing.
Speaker 0: Also, if you want offensive comics, read the parking lot is full.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So we already mentioned that.
Speaker 1: That's so don't add an extra one.
Speaker 1: We re round a bit.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So what's this one?
Speaker 1: Oh boy.
Speaker 1: I don't even remember this one.
Speaker 1: I got loaded up.
Speaker 0: It's got good art.
Speaker 0: Like it's okay.
Speaker 0: Art.
Speaker 1: I'm waiting for it to load.
Speaker 0: I don't remember this one either.
Speaker 0: Actually.
Speaker 1: No, I remember.
Speaker 1: I just don't remember it by name.
Speaker 1: I definitely remember reading it cause I remember one that was called.
Speaker 1: So you're a cartoonist.
Speaker 0: I mean the arts, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, this one.
Speaker 1: This one's okay.
Speaker 0: I didn't have anything like terrible to say about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The only thing about this one is that it just, there was no funniness.
Speaker 1: It's like it wasn't a joke.
Speaker 1: I didn't, I didn't laugh at any of them.
Speaker 0: It's almost more like pages from a book that itself is a single comic as opposed to a web comic.
Speaker 0: Like each individual page doesn't really do much for you on its own.
Speaker 1: It's almost like someone who was in, you know, was like in art school and had like an assignment to draw a web comic and they had to keep drawing the web comic as long as they were in school.
Speaker 1: That was their like job, you know, like they had to do it.
Speaker 1: And they weren't very good at writing or telling jokes, but you know, their art is actually, you know, it's art.
Speaker 1: It's way better than a lot of, 90% of the other ones that were submitted, you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's nowhere near the worst web comic.
Speaker 1: Not even remotely close to the worst web comic.
Speaker 1: What did the submissions say?
Speaker 1: Why did they say it was the worst?
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: Tom Preston is a terrible writer whose every comic says it's tearing down, oh it's the raw, yeah, it's tearing down straw men.
Speaker 1: That I didn't get.
Speaker 1: I didn't get that.
Speaker 0: Because of all the random strips I read, I didn't see a straw man.
Speaker 0: I'm going to try to look for a straw man while you read the rest of that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You're a cartoonist is basically a compilation of every misused Garfield punchline every one.
Speaker 1: His best comic couldn't be as good as all of Jim Davis worst comics.
Speaker 1: Actually, the art is better than the more recent digital Garfields.
Speaker 1: You know, I like the older Garfield art a lot better.
Speaker 1: And it's about equal and funniness to Garfield, which is not funny at all.
Speaker 1: Maybe if we did, so you're a cartoonist minus something, it would be hilarious.
Speaker 1: Let's see, here's one that might be tearing down straw men.
Speaker 1: Things that make me want to head desk.
Speaker 0: I was just looking at that one.
Speaker 1: Confusing the word animation, confusing Disney with other companies.
Speaker 1: The main, the anti-pony mentality.
Speaker 1: When was this done?
Speaker 1: Was this done in the pony times?
Speaker 1: What's the date on this comic?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: MLP fim.
Speaker 1: He likes, he's a pony guy.
Speaker 1: This is a recent comic.
Speaker 0: Anyone who likes ponies can't be bad.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: It's automatically not the worst comic because a guy likes ponies.
Speaker 1: Uh, okay boys.
Speaker 1: I don't see what's wrong with this.
Speaker 1: He's got a troll in the last panel.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I didn't find anything offensive to my sensibilities in this comic.
Speaker 1: I did not either.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think that a lot of people submitted comics that were just personally offensive to them, right?
Speaker 1: Like, you know, someone submitted furries cause they are really, you know, can't, they.
Speaker 0: I think they submitted furries because they just wanted to force us to refer to them.
Speaker 1: That also.
Speaker 1: But like, you know, someone submitted, you know, Mama Is cause.
Speaker 1: you know, Mama Is is way crazy lefty and they're probably somewhat righty.
Speaker 0: Or it's just because it's so crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm glad it was submitted cause I never would have seen that otherwise.
Speaker 1: Me either.
Speaker 1: Um, well, you know, I'm not glad anything was submitted.
Speaker 1: But you know, I think a lot of people submitted things that were just personally offensive to them and their own sensibilities and therefore judged it as the worst web comic as opposed to judging it as a web comic.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Here's a random funny one.
Speaker 1: More impartial criteria.
Speaker 0: Two people are at a convention and one of the older guys like, excuse me a moment, hot chick at three o'clock, he disappears.
Speaker 0: He comes back disturbed and the main character says, I didn't know you had a thing for Sephiroth.
Speaker 0: And the old guy's like, I don't even know what that is.
Speaker 1: It's not bad.
Speaker 0: So this is far from a terrible comic.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to read it, but it's not bad.
Speaker 0: I mean, can put this side by side with electric retard and uh, yeah, right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Electric retard is currently winning.
Speaker 1: The next one.
Speaker 1: This actually of all the ones that were submitted, I actually liked this one the most.
Speaker 0: It's actually kind of cute and funny.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The modest Medusa.
Speaker 1: So basically the story is there's a dude.
Speaker 1: He lives in a house, right?
Speaker 1: And the beginning art awful.
Speaker 1: And the more recent art significantly improved from the oldest art in this comic.
Speaker 0: It's not, I would not call the beginning art awful.
Speaker 1: It's pretty bad.
Speaker 0: Uh, you've seen electric retard.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, but the dude basically just comes home and finds his Medusa, little cute Medusa girl in his closet.
Speaker 1: And it's kind of cute and funny.
Speaker 1: It's like cute Medusa girl.
Speaker 1: Yay.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And she has, I love it when her snakes eat things and she's like trying to eat something and it's, she always wants to eat with the choco something you have in the snakes like steal it from her.
Speaker 1: She wants to eat choco dials and then the snakes on her head eat the choco dial and then she cries.
Speaker 0: So let's see.
Speaker 0: Why did, why was it submitted?
Speaker 1: I mean, it is moe, you know, pure straight up.
Speaker 0: It is moe.
Speaker 0: But so let's read the quote.
Speaker 0: It seems an almost cute fantasy comic in the guy gets saddled with a kid vein until you realize the cute monster is his fat fantasy and the first thing he does is pee on her.
Speaker 1: So I read reading that I had to go forward to find, you know, I read until I got to the.
Speaker 0: I was reading the whole comic thinking, when does this turn into child porn?
Speaker 1: Basically she's in the toilet because it's water in there and she's a snake and then he goes to the bathroom not realizing she's in there and it's not porny in any way.
Speaker 1: Now this might be, might be right.
Speaker 0: One of those ones where, you know, that comic that pretends it's not exactly right.
Speaker 1: But it's the thing is it's done in the same way as an asamanga dao or a yotsuba or a pre time skip, you know, bunny drop right to where there are many redeeming.
Speaker 1: There are many redeeming qualities, right?
Speaker 1: Even though it is cute with a little Medusa girl and the fapness will not enter into it compared to, say, a chubra or a kiss excess or many other things, you know, even a love Hina to where, you know, that there is sort of this implied, you know, porniness that they're sort of hiding, sort of not.
Speaker 1: It's like it's not even implied.
Speaker 1: It's only added in the minds of the reader 100 percent.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Maybe also the writer, but it's not in the comic is my point.
Speaker 0: It's just I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's not the worst comic.
Speaker 1: I actually kind of want to read it because it's cute.
Speaker 0: It is cute.
Speaker 1: It's very cute.
Speaker 0: So I guess I can see why someone might say that comic.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of sad.
Speaker 0: And how much?
Speaker 0: why is every?
Speaker 0: I just noticed the previous control of the lead submission also says that comic that pretends it isn't right.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: No one's faffing it's all delete.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you that much.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about the next one because someone tried to be a jerk, but this guy's wrong and I can argue it pretty succinctly.
Speaker 1: I'll let you handle this then.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to read his whole submission because he's he's impinging on XKCD.
Speaker 0: And I feel like his criticisms are actually objectively wrong.
Speaker 1: Well, so far he submitted the best comic yet.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: In fact, one of my top 10 Webcomics anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know XKCD is a favorite of scrims.
Speaker 0: But yeah.
Speaker 1: Then why are you trying to?
Speaker 1: you're not going to.
Speaker 1: you know, you're not going to win the contest with this.
Speaker 0: You got balls, kid.
Speaker 0: I'll give you that, Ben.
Speaker 0: But I'm going to buck the trend here.
Speaker 0: XKCD is a lackluster, tryhard comic that panders to the pseudo nerdy demographic by playing on entry level science jokes that anyone with a high school education could get.
Speaker 0: The author writes the comics in such a fashion that readers with even a basic grasp of mathematics and pat themselves on the back, lengthen to friends and pretend they are intelligent.
Speaker 0: In short, the math and science humor is shallow and pretentious.
Speaker 0: There's more, but I don't know why you would say that humor is shallow and pretentious just because it's presented in an accessible fashion.
Speaker 1: Also, while the math and science in XKCD is presentable and comprehensible by nerds such as us, you have a great overestimation of the science and math knowledge of anyone who's graduated from high school, at least the United States.
Speaker 1: Most people would not understand even the simplest of pie jokes in XKCD.
Speaker 0: Never mind the fact you do not yet know this.
Speaker 1: This submitter clearly does not yet know how stupid the world is.
Speaker 1: And you are lucky, my good sir.
Speaker 0: Never mind the fact that the comic, you know, XKCD does a really good job, I think, of making some very difficult to understand concepts very accessible to people.
Speaker 0: I mean, half the time, what's his comic?
Speaker 0: It's a really interesting infographic that is pretty well researched.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it takes, you know, while it sticks in lines most of the time, you know, he actually gets more expression out of those stick figures that half these comics we've gone over get out of full color everything.
Speaker 0: Oh, let's let's go on because he continues his rant.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: There is no significant improvement in the art style.
Speaker 0: in the many years XKCD has been running from stick figures to stick figures.
Speaker 0: Now, you know what, dude, that's wrong.
Speaker 0: Look at the early comics.
Speaker 0: They're really poorly drawn stick figures.
Speaker 1: They're much better drawn now, not to mention some of the comics where it isn't just sticks.
Speaker 1: There are quite a few where there will be, you know, sort of like backgrounds.
Speaker 1: There's some.
Speaker 1: there was a few night comics with a starry sky that were quite, you know, much more than just sticks.
Speaker 1: But also the infographics, you know, especially, you know, he definitely goes all out with with clever constructions of, you know, information design, let alone the art itself.
Speaker 0: The art has improved markedly.
Speaker 0: And if you can't see that because you're looking at the surface level of saying it's still a stick figure, then you shouldn't read Order of the Stick either.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: Because Order of the Stick, same deal.
Speaker 0: The character designs are very simple and you look at it now and say, wow, that hasn't progressed.
Speaker 0: Then you look at the first comic and realize how far it's come and how subtle improvements make these very simple characters very expressive.
Speaker 0: These are some of the most expressive stick figures I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: XKCD is one of my favorite and most heartwarming comic comics.
Speaker 0: And I think your criticism of the art and the accessibility is very misplaced.
Speaker 1: So the last thing he says is that he says he's hope he's made a decent case showing why it's his least favorite.
Speaker 1: Your case is not decent.
Speaker 0: You can say that it's your least favorite.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but he said he hoped he made a decent case and no, he did not.
Speaker 0: Well, no, he made a decent case.
Speaker 0: as to why he doesn't like it, because many people will look at simple art and the triggers like this logic in the brain of this is simple art, therefore it is bad or has not improved from some earlier state as opposed to looking at the simple art and saying, wow,
Speaker 1: this is
Speaker 0: very elegantly designed simple art.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So somebody thought they'd be funny and submitted a worst webcomic called worst webcomic.
Speaker 1: It's even at worst webcomic dot com.
Speaker 1: So you think that this would just win straight up.
Speaker 1: But actually, no, it's really you know, it's another one of those ones where it's like, why does this guy think it's the worst?
Speaker 1: Because, I mean, it's not funny at all.
Speaker 1: I did not laugh at a single one of these.
Speaker 1: And he tends to use this trick where he takes some existing graphic and put some words on it like he does some Cookie Monster.
Speaker 1: He does some the two most recent ones.
Speaker 1: He's got a Cookie Monster who's depressed with a psychiatrist and he's got a Tootsie Roll Pop, you know, as Mr.
Speaker 1: Owl.
Speaker 1: But it's a dolphin and the dolphins a dick.
Speaker 1: But none of the comics are actually funny.
Speaker 0: Some of them are OK.
Speaker 0: They're not.
Speaker 1: I didn't even so much as like smile or chuckle or even feel an internal laugh.
Speaker 0: OK, here's one guy's asking a chemist or something.
Speaker 0: So what happens to all the used chemicals from the lab?
Speaker 0: And the chemist is like, well, it's actually a very complicated process.
Speaker 0: First, you have to classify the chemicals in terms of acidity, composition, reaction with other chemicals, flammability, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 0: You have from the organization and the guy interrupts.
Speaker 0: He's like, you just throw them all away, don't you?
Speaker 0: He's like between two a.m.
Speaker 0: and four a.m.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Well, here look at this one.
Speaker 1: It's like you've seen the latest episode of Teen Mom.
Speaker 1: No, me either.
Speaker 1: It's like what?
Speaker 0: It's not even he's clearly making fun of the fact that Teen Mom is not a liked or known show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, your webcomic is not liked or known either.
Speaker 1: You know, up with this, you know, this isn't the worst, but there's really nothing.
Speaker 1: It's not that there's nothing good about memorable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's.
Speaker 1: it's as black as black can be, I think.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I really just had so much to say about it.
Speaker 1: So, Blair.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is, here's why I'm saying it's black, dude.
Speaker 0: I'm going to let you in a little secret.
Speaker 0: The guy who submitted it and never mind.
Speaker 0: Never mind.
Speaker 0: I got nothing.
Speaker 1: We're just going to skip that one because it's so bland.
Speaker 1: Has nothing to go on.
Speaker 0: I got nothing to say about the next one.
Speaker 1: I liked a lot, actually.
Speaker 1: I liked it just about as much as I like.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: This one.
Speaker 0: I actually did like this one, too, just because the art is actually really.
Speaker 1: it's savage chickens and it's Post-it notes, but not always a single Post-it note.
Speaker 1: It's you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: sometimes it's a it's basically yellow background, really.
Speaker 1: Sometimes it's more than one Post-it note long and is cute.
Speaker 1: chickens with sort of far side ish jokes.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Like endangered species that nobody cares about.
Speaker 1: The crinkly bag at the movies, Tiger.
Speaker 0: Once upon a the abruptly ending story.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I feel like everyone wants a piece of me and it's a pie that's talking.
Speaker 1: I get I don't know.
Speaker 0: This is far from the worst webcomic.
Speaker 0: It's actually pretty OK.
Speaker 1: I think it's cute.
Speaker 1: I'm actually read it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: What do you say?
Speaker 0: He's basically the guy submitted.
Speaker 0: It says it isn't funny.
Speaker 0: Let me make sure he didn't say it was a fap comic.
Speaker 0: I feel like that.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: He did not say it was a fap comic.
Speaker 1: He said that bad art tries to be funny and fails, never improves or get better.
Speaker 1: Time goes on.
Speaker 1: That is true is that it's basically the same for its whole length and it is quite long.
Speaker 1: Pretty simple idea.
Speaker 1: Try chickens on post-it notes.
Speaker 1: Hilarity ensues.
Speaker 1: Unfortunately, there appears to be a step missing at humor.
Speaker 1: So I think it was funny.
Speaker 1: Kinda.
Speaker 0: I think we might have a winner.
Speaker 1: It's about as funny as every newspaper strip that's in the newspaper today.
Speaker 0: It is funnier than any newspaper strip that is in the newspaper today.
Speaker 1: This might actually be in some newspapers.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 0: Actually, you know what?
Speaker 0: It should be in some newspapers about that level.
Speaker 0: So here we come to something that stands out.
Speaker 0: This is a cut above the rest.
Speaker 1: This is definitely the worst so far of what we have gone through.
Speaker 1: It may hold out till the end and be the worst webcomic.
Speaker 0: To quote the entry, this is a man who has been so broken as to the point where he thinks that an abhorrent act of racism and anti-Semitism is liberal.
Speaker 0: What were the categories?
Speaker 0: The aspects of worstness, bad art, bad writing, racist, sexist, tries to be funny and fails, never gets better.
Speaker 0: The author is crazy.
Speaker 0: And it's all of those.
Speaker 0: It's called Billy the Heretic.
Speaker 0: I don't even know where to begin.
Speaker 0: The website looks like those kinds of websites.
Speaker 0: What where Jack Chick style craziness appears.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know how some people are racist, but they're not just overtly racist, right?
Speaker 1: They're not just like, you know, kill all Jews, right?
Speaker 1: This guy is like, kill all Jews straight up like he's not even trying.
Speaker 1: He's like he thinks he's just OK.
Speaker 0: Well, here I'll read a comic, Billy the Heretic.
Speaker 0: There's a plane that's flying and the father is like, happy birthday, son.
Speaker 0: For your surprise, just tell the captain anywhere in the world you want to go.
Speaker 0: So he says to the captain, quote, Captain, please land in the nearest black city that is generally safe, clean.
Speaker 0: Any country is fine.
Speaker 0: And there's nowhere for the plane to land, that's the joke.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that is probably one of the least offensive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let me let me pick another one.
Speaker 0: Oh, the Anne Frank ones are pretty bad.
Speaker 0: I don't think he believes that the Holocaust happened.
Speaker 1: Probably not.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: Anne Frank was a Jewish girl who was gassed to death at a death camp called Auschwitz.
Speaker 1: Miss tell Eli didn't Anne Frank leave Auschwitz alive?
Speaker 1: Well, the evil Nazis took her somewhere and gassed her to death.
Speaker 1: Then please instruct the class as to how she died of typhus during a typhus epidemic that killed thousands of other innocent Germans.
Speaker 1: You knew it didn't happen.
Speaker 1: Gassing Jews is hate, hate.
Speaker 1: Do you hear me?
Speaker 1: It is hate, hate, hate.
Speaker 1: Isn't it true that you... Isn't true that you hate, hate and I mean, really hate?
Speaker 0: He seems to be against interracial marriage, against black people, right?
Speaker 0: Against women, against Jews, against liberals.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this guy now, you know, we may disagree with him and someone could write an equally crazy left comic easily.
Speaker 1: So we can't, you know, obviously we disagree with him.
Speaker 1: But and it's racist and horrible.
Speaker 1: But that's not the only thing that makes it horrible.
Speaker 1: Is that not even the racist jokes are funny and they're not not even actively grown and painful, but they're also like many of them.
Speaker 0: end on this point where it's obvious that the author is trying to be clever.
Speaker 0: Like he thinks like, aha, look at this witty balmo.
Speaker 0: I have showed those liberals that there was no wittiness whatsoever.
Speaker 1: None.
Speaker 1: It was minus wittiness.
Speaker 1: It's just overt with no subtlety to it at all.
Speaker 1: It's just blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: Kill all Jews, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: Black people are sucky.
Speaker 1: It's like, what?
Speaker 1: That's all you got?
Speaker 0: He's got a fact up.
Speaker 1: What's the fact?
Speaker 0: OK, what the fuck is up with this website?
Speaker 0: I made this site to teach people about the Jewish community.
Speaker 1: Gay.
Speaker 0: Do you hate Jews?
Speaker 0: No, but I find them hypocritical.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Were you really adopted by Jews?
Speaker 0: I know it sounds crazy, but it's true.
Speaker 0: Apparently he was adopted by a Jewish family and resented it.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, yeah, it's just awful.
Speaker 1: All the website was also awful.
Speaker 1: Everything about this is awful.
Speaker 1: There is not one good thing about it.
Speaker 1: It is it is nine minus a billion.
Speaker 1: It might win, which means which means it would lose.
Speaker 0: I don't even know what else I can say like it.
Speaker 1: I'm dumbfounded by it, it's because it's basically a crazy conspiracy website.
Speaker 1: It looks like it just in the happens to be a Webcomic.
Speaker 1: It's like if time it was it was Jew Cube, the comic, but it's so offensive and crazy.
Speaker 0: But I get the impression that there's no trolling going on here.
Speaker 1: And this guy is serious.
Speaker 0: This guy is.
Speaker 1: He believes this one hundred percent.
Speaker 1: He's not trolling.
Speaker 1: There is no way that he does not believe this is a one hundred percent legitimate for real Webcomic.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, Billy the heretic sure is heretical, that's for sure.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Let's blow through the rest of these, because I think we have a winner.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we still got to go through all of them.
Speaker 0: We do spicy tornado.
Speaker 1: So the deal with spicy tornado, right, is.
Speaker 1: I looked into this and it was submitted mostly because of the meta around this comic.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So you look at it and it's basically sort of cute, simple ish M.S.
Speaker 1: Paint comics that are not really funny at all.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it's going somewhere.
Speaker 1: It's almost like actually the one with the sperm and the shopping cart in the car, the golf cart.
Speaker 0: And that's actually pretty good.
Speaker 1: That was all right.
Speaker 1: It's got a good joke, at least.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like this guy is going somewhere with his simple joke telling slightly, you know, as he's like a kid who can tell a good joke once in a while.
Speaker 1: What's sad about this is that in the meta I read about this, this guy like quit his job to do this comic, thinking he's going to make a bunch of money.
Speaker 1: Basically, the kid or whoever made this comic or is making this comic, you know, it's like my mom told me it was great.
Speaker 1: And it's like I'm thinking is the guy who is making this.
Speaker 1: It must be like the dude bro guy who is playing Imagine Babies fashion.
Speaker 1: Like it's just someone who is so naive, you know, and so unworldly.
Speaker 1: Maybe his home school.
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Just someone who has no idea about the world and like, you know, thinks my mom says my comic is great.
Speaker 1: It's the best comic ever was.
Speaker 1: Like, have you seen another webcomic?
Speaker 0: I actually did not know any of that.
Speaker 1: That was what was in the submission.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So the submission was like.
Speaker 0: I didn't read this mission on this one.
Speaker 1: The submission says it received a lot of very strong criticism at face punch.
Speaker 1: Decided to sign him sign up himself and ask what was wrong with it.
Speaker 1: He left plenty of pearlers there.
Speaker 1: The fun begins here.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: His posts speak for themselves.
Speaker 1: Learn about the man behind the comic is tragically hilarious and frankly, an important part of this mission.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And there's not a lot of strips.
Speaker 1: I looked at them all.
Speaker 1: I didn't actually read every word of every one of them.
Speaker 1: But it's like.
Speaker 1: basically the reason the comic this was submitted is the worst is because it's just so sad that the guy making it might maybe he's like even as down syndrome or something.
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: You know, but it's like just the guy making it is so sad that like he's it's like imagine if.
Speaker 0: But see, I can't make this one win because I know I don't think it's actually the worst.
Speaker 0: No, it's just sad.
Speaker 0: But that's the meta is sad.
Speaker 1: It's not bad.
Speaker 1: It's just sad.
Speaker 0: Sad, bad man.
Speaker 0: You know, that's why I couldn't if I picked a winner here that made by Brad, I'm not getting me sad to think about.
Speaker 0: That makes me a bad person.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's got to make me mad or perhaps glad.
Speaker 1: The comic's not bad.
Speaker 1: Just the meta of it is a sad story of someone who believe like quit their job and believes they're going to make money with.
Speaker 1: really not anywhere even close to you can make money.
Speaker 0: Scott, if you like, if we quit our jobs and make geek nights full time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but geek nights is better than this comic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we still wouldn't make enough money.
Speaker 1: That's for fucking sure.
Speaker 1: All right, let's move on.
Speaker 0: So station three station V three.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is the one like the cute little buddy guys.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So it's the thing that really bothered me about this.
Speaker 1: one is it's been going on for a while and I read the beginning and the end and not so much of the middle is the other one.
Speaker 0: I have no idea what if there's a plot.
Speaker 1: And it seems like if there is a plot, there's been no progression of it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: it seems like there is a continuity, but it hasn't moved.
Speaker 1: It's like it's still mostly where it started, even though it's been a while.
Speaker 0: Well, it has story arcs in the classic old style of webcomics in a dropdown box.
Speaker 0: And there's like 50 of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you read them and it's like each story, it must be so decompressed, as they say, as to where you pass over like a minute of time in comic time in each story arc, and also you look at the art now in the beginning art and it's mostly the same, except he's using the bucket tool to color it, you know, it's like he hasn't changed the art except for coloring it with the bucket tool.
Speaker 1: And so, I mean, in terms of improvement of art, I'd say this is the least improvement over time of any of them that had this stretch to cover.
Speaker 0: But again, it doesn't stand out as being particularly bad.
Speaker 1: No, I mean, some of the alien things are cute.
Speaker 1: You know, like little things that buzz along the wall with two eyeballs.
Speaker 0: It's already more enjoyable than Garfield.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, you know, nothing seems to really happen or tell any jokes, but already good jokes that make you have any humor.
Speaker 1: But it's not the worst webcomic, not even close.
Speaker 0: Just kind of goes on.
Speaker 0: The little blobby guys.
Speaker 1: Billy the heretic is still winning.
Speaker 0: I kind of like the little blobby guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the blobby.
Speaker 1: I like anything blobby.
Speaker 1: That's that's going to hurt you if you tried to tell me something.
Speaker 1: blobby is the worst.
Speaker 1: A guy in his monkey dot com is a 404 GoDaddy squatting site.
Speaker 1: Good game.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So there you go.
Speaker 1: The next submission was chick.com, which is ChickTracks.
Speaker 0: But they are technically online.
Speaker 1: Making them webcomics.
Speaker 0: The website for Chick looks surprisingly at first glance, not nearly as crazy as you'd expect.
Speaker 1: No, it's like it's a. it's basically a cookie cutter e-commerce site.
Speaker 0: He clearly paid someone for it.
Speaker 1: No, it looks like he downloaded or either downloaded or basically got a, you know, a roll your own e-commerce site using magenta or one or, you know, open cart or one of those thingies.
Speaker 1: So e-commerce and made it site to sell ChickTracks.
Speaker 0: Here's the question, because the submitter even, you know, kind of addresses this.
Speaker 0: Is it fair to put the ChickTracks in the same running because they're special?
Speaker 1: Even if you put the ChickTracks in the same running, Billy, the heretic is still worse.
Speaker 0: True.
Speaker 0: And I think the reason why is so.
Speaker 0: when I read a ChickTrack, I usually laugh.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because it's like it's so wrong that it's laughable.
Speaker 1: It's like it's like Time Cube.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: If you take Time Cube as a joke and not as a serious thing, you know, in that way.
Speaker 1: And it's like it has such a the meta of ChickTracks because everyone knows them.
Speaker 1: It's like you can't.
Speaker 1: you can't not.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's actually really cheap to order the ChickTrack like that's why, you know, you see the crazy people handing them out.
Speaker 1: because they can get them for almost nothing.
Speaker 0: We should make some.
Speaker 0: I know people have made nerdy ChickTracks before.
Speaker 0: we should make our own and just put them out there.
Speaker 1: People have done that.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Ponies.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: Control delete was submitted again.
Speaker 1: Now here comes something special.
Speaker 1: This is maybe the best submission there was.
Speaker 0: I was I was surprised by this when I was going through and I actually looked at it.
Speaker 1: Someone made a comic called Geek Nights Comic One or Geek Night's Comic One.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a comic about us straight up.
Speaker 1: It's all inside jokes you'll only get if you listen to Geek Nights or go to the forum.
Speaker 0: It's made by taking our Creative Commons licensed videos and pictures of us and putting speech bubbles on them.
Speaker 1: It's they're actually really funny.
Speaker 1: If you know us, they're not funny at all.
Speaker 0: If you don't know what is really interesting to me and why I want we're going to have a new contest now.
Speaker 0: This inspired me.
Speaker 1: And the newest issue, the comic, though, was just made with sticks and didn't use photos of us.
Speaker 0: Dude, whoever is making this, I didn't really look.
Speaker 0: make more because I kind of like it.
Speaker 1: I also like it.
Speaker 1: Keep making it, but not just because it is ego stroking because legitimately funny.
Speaker 0: What I find really interesting, though, is that reading something like this, they're funny to us.
Speaker 0: But yet you the listeners out there, you don't know, you know, the real rim and the real Scott, you know, the kind of persona we put on on Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Our friends often laugh when you about certain, I don't know, things you believe about the two of us that are very far off the mark.
Speaker 0: But as far as our persona, personas on Geek Nights are, that's how we are like the meet.
Speaker 0: the US, you know, is not the US we really are.
Speaker 0: But the US, you know, is actually kind of funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There's also a double meta in, I think, the third comic where it's like, here, let me read this to you.
Speaker 1: So here, let let you have it open.
Speaker 0: Yes, I have the third one, the one that's you want to read our parts.
Speaker 0: Yes, the lettering is really bad.
Speaker 1: So I'll start because I'm the one for talking first.
Speaker 1: So, you know, we're in this webcomic, right?
Speaker 0: The wine helps me forget, but I'm not there yet.
Speaker 0: Why do you ask?
Speaker 1: Do you think it was created just to be an entry in the worst webcomic contest?
Speaker 0: I expect so.
Speaker 0: It's certainly a bad webcomic.
Speaker 0: Come on, dude.
Speaker 0: When we said we should feel bad about not creating anything, we didn't mean you should make shit just to feel good about yourself.
Speaker 0: Put some effort into it.
Speaker 1: And then the narrator says, all right, how about some of those adventures?
Speaker 1: I promised.
Speaker 1: Who do you want to meet?
Speaker 1: Then I say Rainbow Dash.
Speaker 0: How about Kellis?
Speaker 0: Can you get us a character from a book or do you not read at all?
Speaker 1: Narrator says those are not public domain.
Speaker 0: Creative Commons, you mean?
Speaker 1: Narrator says the point is I can't draw them in this comic.
Speaker 0: You actually just can't draw.
Speaker 0: Full stop.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: They made good use of our facial expression.
Speaker 1: This is probably the best webcomic you can make with Riven.
Speaker 1: Scott is characters.
Speaker 1: And I salute you.
Speaker 1: Good job.
Speaker 1: Keep it up.
Speaker 0: Keep it up in a big way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're a winner.
Speaker 1: And you made something.
Speaker 0: Whoo.
Speaker 0: Oh, you skipped one.
Speaker 1: Did I?
Speaker 1: The control delete, we mentioned it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we did.
Speaker 0: Never mind.
Speaker 1: We're mentioning them all twice because you keep going back into them.
Speaker 1: Divide the number of times you mentioned control delete by half.
Speaker 1: So the next submission, someone linked to spreadsheets at Google dot com and it was like, hey, share the spreadsheet of submissions of the worst webcomic.
Speaker 1: No, no.
Speaker 1: The next one is actually another control delete because.
Speaker 0: But because.
Speaker 0: But I think at this point people were just taking the piss.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: OK, the next one, M.G.
Speaker 1: Comics, Akuma something.
Speaker 0: So according to the submission, it's one of the, quote, shittiest sprite comics he's ever read.
Speaker 0: But apparently it's held up as one of the best sonic sprite comics in existence.
Speaker 0: Now, one, the fact that you would have a category for best sprite comics and inside of that, you have a category for best sonic sprite comics.
Speaker 0: And related to that, you know that this is held up as the best of those.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Sprite comics suck.
Speaker 1: All of them basically except 8-bit theater.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: This comic is basically, you know, it's about.
Speaker 1: it's less than Bob and George, I would say.
Speaker 1: But it's for sonic fans, basically, you know, and that's all there is to it.
Speaker 1: It's pretty awful.
Speaker 1: Which, you know, the thing that makes it really awful is that even worse than Bob and George is it's hard to read just because everything is so small.
Speaker 1: It's like the guy didn't doesn't format the comic properly.
Speaker 1: So you can't even read the letters in there.
Speaker 1: It's like you need a magnifying glass and some of these strips.
Speaker 1: in some of them you can read, but some of them it's like you need a magnifying glass to know what's going on in this comic.
Speaker 1: And it's just, you know, it's basically a mediocre sonic fanfic with sprites.
Speaker 1: Instead of just being a fanfic.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, again, meh, but not bad, bad, not worse.
Speaker 1: I give it one bad, not two bads.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 1: Another submission for Control Delete.
Speaker 0: It's a comic about computer aided design, I think.
Speaker 1: Another submission of the Geek Nights comic that featured us.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Sorry, dude.
Speaker 0: Someone already submitted it.
Speaker 1: Another submission of Control Delete.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: And then one that we didn't see until just now.
Speaker 1: It was submitted yesterday, so I didn't see it until just now.
Speaker 0: So I'm not sure what to make of this one because it's pretty bad.
Speaker 0: But Billy the Heretic really beat you to the punch.
Speaker 0: Whoever made this comic.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, this comic obviously was submitted because it's extreme Fox News, right wingish kind of thing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So whoever submitted it really disagreed with it.
Speaker 0: Bad political views alone do not a bad webcomic make.
Speaker 0: You could probably make a really good right wing comic, though I've never seen one.
Speaker 1: But I mean, you know, like the ones that actually are more are less right wingish, but still right wing.
Speaker 1: But make it to the newspaper.
Speaker 1: Like what's the one with the duck?
Speaker 0: Oh, Mallard.
Speaker 0: What's it?
Speaker 0: It's terrible.
Speaker 1: It's terrible, but it's not as bad as this.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, that's why that's in the newspaper.
Speaker 0: And this isn't right.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So anyway, to quote the submitter, it's a horrible and racist and sexist and all that, especially with its super hot, comically huge boob, half Asian, half Swedish token game girl.
Speaker 0: Oh, and she's a virgin and conservative.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: And they call Obama a Nazi or something.
Speaker 1: They probably do.
Speaker 0: There is apparently some some more author drama, though.
Speaker 0: OK, so according to the submitter, I did not verify this at all.
Speaker 0: The webcomic author claimed that he was in foreclosure because of, quote, liberal banks.
Speaker 0: that forced him to take a loan.
Speaker 0: he couldn't afford to pay.
Speaker 0: So he raised money, forced him to take a loan.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: So he raised money.
Speaker 1: Whatever your right wing.
Speaker 1: What happened to a personal responsibility?
Speaker 0: Oh, but he was forced to buy the evil liberals.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: So he apparently attempted to raise money from his fans, raise some money and then lost it in a Ponzi scheme.
Speaker 0: I don't know, I read through it and it wasn't.
Speaker 0: Offensive is so much is just, again, immemorable.
Speaker 1: There's offensive stuff like, did you see the one with the?
Speaker 1: he's got a Chinese guy with huge buck teeth and you know, like on purpose.
Speaker 0: there it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: The word faggots actually coming up a lot now that I'm going through.
Speaker 1: these are the guy he's pretty just blatantly right.
Speaker 1: I mean, here is the one that's like fascism.
Speaker 1: You can believe it.
Speaker 1: It's got Obama's face.
Speaker 0: Oh, I must have picked the wrong random ones to read.
Speaker 0: This is way more.
Speaker 0: OK, I was reading like these bible ones that were just kind of.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're.
Speaker 1: no, they're bible ones.
Speaker 1: There's all kinds.
Speaker 1: It's like it's comic strip club, right?
Speaker 1: It's like a club.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of different comics.
Speaker 1: is red eye.
Speaker 1: Name this strip evolve with guy.
Speaker 0: There's also the the with Mika and fascist Obama rip off of the Republicans and the Democrat with the same art.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, actually, the art in this is one hundred times better than Billy the heretic.
Speaker 0: A hundred thousand.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Even though it's crazy right wing, it's just Fox News right wing and not Billy the heretic right wing.
Speaker 1: It's not like kill all the Jews.
Speaker 1: He's actually saying Obama's a Nazi, like it's a bad thing.
Speaker 1: I always find that funny, like you will act like Obama's a Nazi.
Speaker 1: That's a bad thing.
Speaker 1: that he's a Nazi.
Speaker 1: But you also you're the one who hates the Jews.
Speaker 1: So what's your right.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling that the billy the heretic guy has.
Speaker 1: it's like they hate Jews and then they use Nazi as an insult.
Speaker 1: It's like what it's like.
Speaker 1: Are you kidding me?
Speaker 0: Well, I love the fact that they usually can Nazi, Nazism, screw the black people, fascism, the Nazis, kill the Nazis and racism, sexism and somehow socialism.
Speaker 0: Like all those things are somehow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you don't like socialism or fascism.
Speaker 1: But wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: It's people like don't know what the words mean clearly.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: This is you know, if you're a leftist person, this is going to be incredibly offensive to you.
Speaker 1: But it's but it's not the worst webcomic because it's again, mediocre, immemorable.
Speaker 0: I'm going to forget.
Speaker 1: I think a significant number of these entries people just put in because, you know, they personally had a strong disagreement with the views of the author, which is, you know, as you can see in Billy the Heretic, a significant contributing factor.
Speaker 1: But it's like the rest of the comic, if you would just change the views, if you took this comic strip club and you made it, you know, not about politics, you made it about video games.
Speaker 1: And instead of hating blacks, they hated platformers.
Speaker 1: And instead of, you know, hating Obama, they hated FPSs and they really like PlayStation.
Speaker 1: It's like this would be an average mediocre webcomic.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't be, you know.
Speaker 1: So of all the submissions, that's all the submissions, how many controlled deletes do we have?
Speaker 1: Oh, one, one, two, three, four, five, six, six, six submissions of controlled delete out of 30 submissions.
Speaker 1: So like a fifth of the submissions were controlled delete.
Speaker 1: So you win the use.
Speaker 1: the Voters Choice Award for worst webcomic, actual worst webcomic, I think is Billy the Heretic, because Billy the Heretic combines all of the aspects other than I don't think it was checked.
Speaker 0: No, it is not as pretends to be a fab comic, but isn't.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: Pretends not to be a fab comic, but it is.
Speaker 1: It also was just in all of the qualities.
Speaker 1: How bad was the art?
Speaker 0: The art is awful.
Speaker 0: The writing is awful.
Speaker 1: The worst.
Speaker 0: The message awful.
Speaker 0: The author crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everything in all those other categories.
Speaker 1: It was off the charts in terms of how bad it was.
Speaker 1: Maximum craziness, maximum bad art, maximum badness.
Speaker 0: Billy the Heretic is kind of like the real world.
Speaker 0: Like a lot of these comics are like a generic schlubby guy that you pass on the street.
Speaker 0: You don't even notice him.
Speaker 0: Some of them were like awesome celebrities walking by.
Speaker 0: And I don't know why you guys didn't like them.
Speaker 0: But Billy the Heretic is the smelly, angry hobo who physically accosts you when you try to walk by him.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: And that is why it is the worst of webcomics.
Speaker 0: So I guess we have our winner who submitted this one.
Speaker 0: Who did submit Billy the Heretic?
Speaker 1: Chance, you win something.
Speaker 0: We'll send you a prize.
Speaker 0: We will email you with details.
Speaker 1: You can email us.
Speaker 1: Maybe let us know what kind of prize you want.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're welcome to read all these other webcomics.
Speaker 1: Yeah, put links to all the webcomics.
Speaker 0: I will put links to all the other webcomics.
Speaker 1: You only need to link control delete once, though.
Speaker 0: I got to link to it five times.
Speaker 1: But it was submitted six times.
Speaker 1: And I don't know if you have any ideas for other worst contests we could do in this fashion.
Speaker 1: Let us know.
Speaker 0: I feel like the worst podcast contest was more fun because I could just play examples in the show.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: We can't really show examples unless we did video.
Speaker 0: The contest I want to do.
Speaker 0: next, I actually want to do something good.
Speaker 0: I want to have a mashup contest.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Like some sort of like.
Speaker 0: I haven't decided the rules yet, but I want to.
Speaker 0: I want to get someone else in on it, like Geek Nights, Front Row Crew and someone else that does creative stuff.
Speaker 1: The thing is, anytime we do a contest where people make stuff, we never get enough submissions.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: We only got a handful of submissions of the Geek Nights advertising contest.
Speaker 1: We only got a handful of submissions of Cornucopia.
Speaker 0: That is why we want to involve two separate fan communities of things and say, mash up any combination of these two things.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: That'll get at least double the submissions.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: Maybe also in anime world order.
Speaker 1: What are we going to mash up?
Speaker 0: I don't know, audio, video, I guess they don't have enough video.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they've got audio, though.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: You got to come up with a better idea than the vague idea.
Speaker 1: You got a real idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just want to get people to mash stuff up.
Speaker 0: And I refuse to do a pony contest.
Speaker 0: Don't even ask.
Speaker 1: The pony contest has already been won.
Speaker 0: Yay.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.