Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, I'm Luke and this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight I talk about the German competitive puzzle games called Ricochet Robots and Set.
Speaker 0: This is a special episode of Geek Nights while Wim and Scott are away.
Speaker 0: They said, "Hey, send in some of your guest podcasts," and so I thought I might as well make one.
Speaker 0: They're actually away doing, I guess, anime conventions and video conventions and board game conventions.
Speaker 0: So if you're listening to this Geek Nights for the first time, maybe you met them at a convention or saw them on a panel or something like that and they said, "Check out our podcast,".
Speaker 0: and so you're checking it out.
Speaker 0: But this is not the best introduction to Geek Nights Tuesdays, so instead what you should do is stop this episode, download pretty much any other episode in the feed as long as it doesn't have the word "special" in the title.
Speaker 0: Just find something that you're interested in, listen to Wim and Scott talk about it in the normal podcast and you get a much better idea of what Geek Nights is really all about.
Speaker 0: Also in this podcast, I'm not going to stick with the usual format, I'm going to skip the news and the things of the day because I don't know when this episode is going to be released.
Speaker 0: So the news will be old news and maybe the things of the day will be like everyone had seen it by the time I finished with that.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to move straight on with the main meat of the matter.
Speaker 0: Oh, by the way, I'm Luke.
Speaker 0: I'm a podcaster.
Speaker 0: I'm also a professional juggler.
Speaker 0: One of my podcasts is actually called The Juggling Podcast, which you probably won't be interested in.
Speaker 0: Another one is called the Science Fiction Book Review Podcast, where I review science fiction books.
Speaker 0: All of the science fiction books that I read, I review, so check that out if you want.
Speaker 0: More importantly, a bit more about me, I live in Germany and I like German board games, which is actually, you know, put those two facts together, is actually really quite handy because I have access to lots of German board games and I have access to many German people who also like to play board games.
Speaker 0: Many of my friends are much, much, much, much more into board games than I am, but then I have a life as well.
Speaker 0: I can't spend all of it playing board games, although me and my girlfriend, we do spend a lot of time.
Speaker 0: We just got turn and taxes a few weeks ago and had a lot of fun with that.
Speaker 0: And also, yeah, we go away because, you know, a lot of my friends, they go away for a few times a year, sort of rent a venue, maybe a school or something where they can sleep and feed themselves and have like a mini board game convention for three or four days, maybe 50 people there or something like that.
Speaker 0: I've done that a few times as well, both here in Germany and in the UK, and it's really good fun, of course.
Speaker 0: Also on top of that, because I'm a juggler, I go to juggling conventions and the games that I'm going to discuss today are ones that we don't play, like.
Speaker 0: this is not going to be one of the classics like Settlers and Carcassonne, they're going to be games that I don't play with other gamers, more other jugglers, because every time you go to a juggling convention, there'll be two games, two games specifically that people play most often, and they are ricochet robots and set.
Speaker 0: They're by far the most popular, and I think they're the most popular because, well, they've got a few things in common.
Speaker 0: First of all, it's a puzzle game, so, you know, when you get good at it, of course you get better at it, and there's nothing random about them, or there is actually randomness in both games, because it sort of sets up a random puzzle, and you've got to solve them.
Speaker 0: Both of these games, ricochet robots and set, do this.
Speaker 0: But for all the players involved, you know, everyone, once they look at the board or look at the cards, equal setup, you know, and then it's the difference in skill that get it, which I really like about that.
Speaker 0: Too much randomness of drawing cards and rolling dice is never that cool.
Speaker 0: The next thing that they've both got in common is that you don't have to have a set number of players to play it with.
Speaker 0: So you can play with two players, or up to five, six, seven, twenty players.
Speaker 0: However many people you can fit around a table, that's how many people can play these games.
Speaker 0: Of course, you can play it by yourself, but then you're just sort of training and practicing and things like that.
Speaker 0: The next thing that they've both got in common is that you don't have to be there for the beginning or the end of the game.
Speaker 0: You can turn up any time you want throughout the game and start playing.
Speaker 0: You just sort of look over and go, three, or set, or whatever you're going to call up, and you know, so you start a game like you and two other people.
Speaker 0: By the end of the game, ten more people could have turned up, but it doesn't spoil the game in any way, because you're still playing against the board, you're still playing along the other people, and you're still trying to win.
Speaker 0: And of course the same thing happens too.
Speaker 0: If you turn up, or if you're there at the beginning of the game, you can leave, go get a drink at the bar, get some food, come back, return, nobody's going to miss you at all.
Speaker 0: Another thing they've both got in common is that, of course the good players are always going to win, but winning is not the only goal, because it's a point system, so maybe a new player will come along, and they'll have a goal like, okay, I know I'm not going to win, I may not even get a single point, but you know, I'm going to get the solution to one of these, you know, before or as it's called by another player, and before it's been explained, and then the next goal can be, oh, I'm going to get a single point.
Speaker 0: And the next is going to be, I'm not going to come last, or then I'm going to come second, or then I'm going to try and take a few points away from the main one, then maybe I'm going to win.
Speaker 0: So lots and lots of different things you can do this.
Speaker 0: You can sit there and play a long time, and you can see new players come in, and then they suddenly get that first point, and they're like, yes, and it could be two games in, and then it could be another game before they get a next point, but it's still just as enjoyable.
Speaker 0: So all of these factors make these games perfect for informal gatherings, you know, at the often at the side of a hall, in a juggling convention, a game will start up, and the game will continue for maybe four, five hours in a row, but of course, the people at the beginning won't be there at the end, and the people at the end have maybe only come half an hour before, but the session will still be going, and you can just leave them running, and they sort of sweep up people, and yeah, it's just generally a really nice diversion for when you're not doing anything else.
Speaker 0: Finally, both games you can actually play by yourself as a puzzle game, like you say, to practice.
Speaker 0: Not only that, but they can actually be played on various places online, and I'll include the links to the games where you can play Set and Ricochet Robots online.
Speaker 0: I don't actually do this very much, but there's a group of friends from the UK, you're living in Germany, they're in the UK, but we have a chat room that one of the guys coded up, and every day we chat there, and every day the Set and Ricochet Robot comes online, and every day, at one time during the day, all the chat suddenly disappears, and then people start posting their daily results, like 14, 14, 12, 12, 12, 9, 12, yeah, 9, thought so, got a 9, 2/8, 2/8, got something like that, and that's it, so you know, it just kills the chat room for a day while at least 20 people go in there and play Ricochet Robots and Set and some other games at the same time.
Speaker 0: Again, links in the show notes.
Speaker 0: So I'll start with Set, I guess talking a bit more in depth about Set, because it's a little bit easier than the other one to explain.
Speaker 0: Set is not a board game, it's actually a card game, and you've got a deck of cards and they're all unique, and you set them out 12 at a time, and if you see three cards that match into a set, you shout
Speaker 0: "Set!"
Speaker 0: and you scoop up the set, and that means you've got one point, you've got one set, and then three more cards are dealt face-up in their place, and the game continues with people calling Set till there's no more cards left, or there's no more cards left, or there's no more sets left to get, and if there's a set, you know, if 12 cards are out there and there's no sets being called for a while, you put out a 13th card and then a 14th card until Set is called, and of course at the end of the game, whoever has the most sets wins.
Speaker 0: So it sounds a bit like Snap, and it is a bit like Snap in a way, but it's like a really hard kind.
Speaker 0: Like I said, every card is unique, but there's four different ways a card can be different from another card.
Speaker 0: So each card shows one of three symbols, an oval, a diamond, or a squiggle.
Speaker 0: Also, these three symbols, there can be different numbers of them, so one, two, or three symbols.
Speaker 0: Also, each card has symbols that are either green, red, or purple, and on top of that, each card has the symbols either as sort of like a red outline or green outline and purple outline, or they're sort of shaded in slightly, or they're sort of a full block of colour.
Speaker 0: So to call a set, you must pick out three cards, which in all four of these different ways of these different values are either the same, or completely different from each other, on each card.
Speaker 0: Again, it sounds a bit complicated, I'll just give an example, I guess is probably the best way to sort this out.
Speaker 0: So card one can be one solid red diamond, card two, one solid red oval, and card three, one solid red squiggle.
Speaker 0: And all cards, you know, have one symbol, all cards are solid, all are red, but then they have three different symbols.
Speaker 0: You can't have one solid red diamond, one solid red diamond, one solid red oval, of course you can't because all cards are unique, but you can never have two of one thing and one of another in one of the values where they have to either be all the same or different.
Speaker 0: Another example could be you get one solid red diamond, two red solid ovals, and three red solid squiggles.
Speaker 0: So you know, you get red solid, all of them are red and solid, but then each three of them have a different number and a different symbol.
Speaker 0: And of course you can then have sort of one, I've got to think about this one, one solid red diamond, two shaded green oval, and three outlined purple squiggles.
Speaker 0: So in that case, all cards are different in all of the values, but it doesn't really happen that often when you get that, but when it does happen, you know, it's like woohoo, all three different, and everyone high fives each other, actually they don't, they're getting on with the game and shouting set, but I guess the human brain spots similarities a bit quicker than they do the differences in the cards, so you know, the more similar the three cards have been moored in more ways, the quicker someone will shout set and scoop them up.
Speaker 0: So I actually first learned this game maybe six or seven years ago, and I started playing with other people, you know, other jugglers and things like that in the UK who are also new to the game, and I got to the point where I could win a lot of the games, you know, and you know, each game only lasts a few minutes, set is actually quite a quick game before you start again and start the next round, so I'd play a lot.
Speaker 0: The thing is, like I said, I lived in England at the time, and I'd only played against other English people, or British people, or Albionic as it's known here on Geek Nights, funny story about that, actually I was just on stage at the European Juggling Convention, and there's about, you know, I'm hosting the show, so maybe 1,500 people in front of me, and I say this next act is from London, and everyone goes reeee, or the London people go reeee, and I'm like cool, so who here's from London?
Speaker 0: More people go reeee, who here's from England?
Speaker 0: More people go reeee, and then I said, who's here from the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, and less people went reeee, and I was like haha, some people don't know their own nationality as it appears on their passports, so yeah, it's not just people outside of England, Britain, the UK, who get confused about it, so yeah, Albionic.
Speaker 0: Anyway, where was I?
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, I'd only played against English people.
Speaker 0: So I met this German girl who moved to the UK, and anyway, we sat down, and the dealer started dealing, Annette, the German girl, she just said set, and none of us had even started looking at the cards yet, and she got a set, and the game continued, and it was like Annette, set, and everyone else was, dammit, and then set, and everyone else, dammit, and set, and everyone else, oh fuck, Annette set, and it just carried on like this, and she just dominated the game, I think one other person got one set, and she got all the other sets, and it turns out that unless you're German, you really suck at this game, it's just that simple.
Speaker 0: Germans absolutely dominate this game, as I said I was just at the EJC, the European Juggling Convention, and there was a set tournament took place, and they organised it and played it, and I actually watched one of the games later on in the tournament, and it really, really put me in my place, because the game lasted like less than a minute, it was just like set, set, set, set, set, set, set, and they had to have a dedicated dealer to actually put the cards out there, because if one person is dealing, and the other person is just looking and calling sets, sometimes the other person can have a bit of an advantage there.
Speaker 0: So this game is actually really good fun, like I say, it really, like, it doesn't take long to play, and you can play with any number of players, and I really think you should get a copy of this and just give it a go, or at least play it for a few days online, or just try it out online and sort of get used to it.
Speaker 0: As I said, I thought I was actually good at this once, but it turns out against Germans.
Speaker 0: I'm really, really not that good.
Speaker 0: Anyway, moving on to Ricochet Robots, this game is a bit more complicated, so to set it out you've got a board, this is a proper board game this time, you've got a board with four quarters which are printed on both sides, which is cool because you can arrange the board sort of randomly in many, many different ways of playing, so each game has a different board, up to however long it's going to be before you get round to that next, or that first way of playing again, and so the four quarters fit together to form a kind of maze, but it's like a very open maze with a border around the edge, so you can't go off the edge, and there's lots of little L-shaped walls in the interior, and it's got this cool industrial sci-fi kind of styling which is pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Anyway, within the maze there's like 16 goals within little L-shaped bits of walls, and each goal is a different colour, I think there's red, blue, green and yellow, and there's four different kinds of symbols, so there's 16 goals, I think there's like a triangle, there's a planet, a swirly something, and I can't remember what the other one is, but at the end of the maze is called robots, because they look a little bit like circular robots, and they've each got one of the four colours too, and you set them at random, and there's the beginning of the game, and you sort of just, you know, you drop tiles onto the board to see where they're going to be, so next, someone turns over one of the small circular tiles, and again there's 16 of these, or 17, because there's one sort of joker where you go anywhere, and on it is a colour and a symbol, or a symbol of a certain colour matching one of the goals of the board, and that begins the round, so the idea now is to bounce the robots around the board until the robot matching the colour on the selected tile arrives at the goal on the tile, so the robots start moving in one direction, you hold onto the blue and you go.
Speaker 0: okay I'm going to move the blue left, and it keeps moving in a straight line until it bumps into wall, and then it stops, and that's one move, and then you go.
Speaker 0: okay now I need to move it up, so you move it up, and it hits the edge of the board and it stops there, and then you move it right, and it hits a robot and it stops there, so that would be like three moves to get there, so everyone actually looks at the board and they've got to sort of mentally track in their brain the shortest route possible that they can get the blue robot onto the blue triangle goal, for example, so you're thinking right, up, across, down, left, right, and bingo, you're there, seven moves, so you think seven moves and you call out seven, and once you call out, or once the first person calls out seven, that's the first call, so an egg timer is flipped over and everyone else has a minute to find a shorter route and call a lower number, and if someone calls a lower number, and they say six, and everyone goes, oh yeah, six, someone will go five, and oh five, great, stuff like that, so then once the time is up, the person shows their route around and everyone goes yep, very good, very good, like that, and the lowest number of course is the one that wins, and they get the tile and they get one point, of course if you call five, and then you go, oh no six, your five doesn't count, that's your lowest bid, and then you're out, you know, unless you can actually find a five, which normally you can't, and the best thing about this game is when you get a blue robot, you don't have to just move the blue robot to get to the blue destination, you can move, say, the red robot and then bounce the blue robot off the red robot, and use the yellow robot to stop the red one and stuff like that, so you can maybe get somewhere with twelve moves by just moving the blue, but if you move the green, just sort of about there, and then bounce the blue off it there, you can get there in eight, of course you say eight, and then someone calls out seven, because they've used the red and the yellow to get to the same place, so around will go something like this, fifteen, fourteen, oh yeah, fourteen, fourteen, ten, ten, ten, ten, like that, and it just goes on down the numbers, down the numbers and stuff, and the best thing is about it, at the end, you get some really really creative solutions to the puzzle, because the board is different all the time, and every situation is going to be different, no two ricochet robot games will ever be the same, I guess it's like going that way, the amount of things that can happen means that every game is totally different, the robots will always be in different places, and the board will always be in different configurations.
Speaker 0: when you flip over one of the tiles, so one person will go, oh here's ten, and everyone will go, way ten, really cool like that, and they show them, it's like really cool, and then someone will say, oh but I had another ten that looked a bit like this, and they'll show it and it's a different solution, but this one will say, hey look at my twelve, and they show the twelve and they actually bounce all of the robots off each other three times in every different part of the board and get there, so again the stylish solutions get a lot more kudos, but they won't win you the game, but sometimes if you just, you know, it's really cool at the end of the game just to share.
Speaker 0: And the cool thing is again, I was just talking to a German friend of mine who lives down the street in Berlin, and he has the biggest collection of board games of anybody else I ever known, and he actually told a similar story to mine, because he played ricochet robots at home with his girlfriend, and he thought he did quite well, and then he sat down with some English players at the EJC last week, and it turns out English players play it a whole lot more than Germans, this ricochet robots game, and he didn't manage to win a single point in the first few games he played, because it turns out the English, especially the London jugglers, and some others, they just play this all the time whenever they meet up, and yeah, they are really, really shit hot.
Speaker 0: There's a few variations to help new players I guess in ricochet robots, but I'm not sure if they're official or if they're house rules or anything like that, and one is to let, say a new player comes along, if they manage, say the best thing that anybody else calls out is "ten", and within that minute the new player can also call out ten, and they don't have a piece yet, they get that point, if they can find within a minute the lowest call.
Speaker 0: The thing is, I don't really normally play like that, because we normally try and make it a bit harder, because you know, we're all good at it, you don't really, of course the new players they can come along, they can do that, but we make it different by saying no solution can be under five moves, so if you get there, say, like you turn over the blue triangle, and you can get there with the blue thing in two moves, so instead of just calling out two, and then the new player going "oh, oh yeah, two, I can see that", and them getting the point, and it just being a waste of a tile, or a waste of that part of the game, we made a rule that if it's under five moves, it can't be under five moves, and you've got to come up with a new lowest number of moves to win, but that's five or over.
Speaker 0: Then the solution itself can't contain the lowest solution entirely, so if the solution is sort of like blue goes up, left, down, you can't have up, left, right, left, down.
Speaker 0: That's not allowed, you know, you've got to come up with something where you don't go across all of the gaps that the lowest solution solves.
Speaker 0: Again, that's maybe a bit tricky to explain.
Speaker 0: And there's also some official ricochet robots expansions.
Speaker 0: There's one with a silver robot, and one with diagonal walls in the maze, and things like that.
Speaker 0: I've not really played them much.
Speaker 0: I've played them a bit, and they're alright, but I actually just like the normal game itself, the original game itself.
Speaker 0: Once I did actually come up with my own expansion, which is called the ramp piece, because the silver robot, what happens is that you just use it like another robot, but you never have to move it to any destination, and there's the diagonal walls, which you can bounce off, like you can ricochet off, but it only counts as one move, because you can't stop there, you actually bounce off the one.
Speaker 0: The ramp move, or the ramp piece that I made, was that it moves like a robot, but when it's in front of a wall, and another robot goes into it, it jumps over the ramp, over the wall behind it, and then lands on the next empty square, and then keeps going on until it hits another wall or robot.
Speaker 0: And again, it's just a little expansion which works just as well as the official expansions and actually costs nothing extra.
Speaker 0: In fact, the silver robot expansion doesn't cost anything extra, just use a chess piece of some kind, I guess.
Speaker 0: So, playing ricochet robots is actually quite a strange experience, and actually like a full game of set, even though the full game of set only lasts a few minutes, and playing a single round of ricochet robots takes maybe about a minute or so as well.
Speaker 0: But between the tile of ricochet robots, you turn over a tile, and then everything just goes exactly silent, and everyone just sits there.
Speaker 0: And then someone turns, you know, someone calls them out and the timer is turned, and there's nothing but motionless players, sort of eyes flicking about the board, you know, and sort of like lower numbers being said quietly, sort of five, five, five, four, four, well it can't do that actually in our rules, but there you go, it just keeps going down and down and down.
Speaker 0: And then as soon as the timer runs out, there's a big explosion of activity with people chatting and discussing and getting up and leaving and coming back and then, you know, talking about it and sharing the different solutions, and then suddenly someone will flick a tile over and there's back to silence.
Speaker 0: And nothing at all is happening.
Speaker 0: As I said, set is quite the same, but the chatting and activity normally happens at the end of each game rather than at the end of each round within one game.
Speaker 0: So ricochet robots is a damn good game, I'd give it four stars out of five, however I know a lot of people who really, really hate the game, they just look at it and they just can't get into it at all.
Speaker 0: And also at juggling conventions you have sort of ricochet robot widows and stuff, like with the guys going over to play the game and leaving the girlfriends just sitting there chatting and things like that.
Speaker 0: So maybe this is all genetic, I don't know, maybe people can just do puzzle games like this and some people can't.
Speaker 0: I can, but I know that compared to most people I'm just not so good at this.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that's about it really, I guess these discussions of ricochet robots and set really maybe help you decide if you want to buy them, if they're good for you or not.
Speaker 0: Again, you don't sit down and play them as a normal card game or as a normal board game, you can do, but it's pretty much a great game to have.
Speaker 0: Maybe if you're at a board gaming meetup or some other kind of meetup, just set it on a table and just leave it there and when people want to come along you need like minimum two players to be on each of these games.
Speaker 0: Just sort of leave it set up.
Speaker 0: so if someone's waiting for another game to start or they've been, you know, they've been eliminated from a game or from a tournament, they can just go over there, sit there, play ricochet robots, people can come and go.
Speaker 0: And yeah, it's just one of those cool casual games that you can just pick up and people can come and go and that's why I'd recommend it, these group puzzle solving kind of games.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I'm waffling on now.
Speaker 0: I guess I'm going to catch you later.
Speaker 0: My name's Luke Bewitch, I hope you've enjoyed me here.
Speaker 0: filling in for Rim and Scott, a short little show, but that's all I'm going to do.
Speaker 0: See you later.
Speaker 2: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 2: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 2: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 2: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 2: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Speaker 2: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Speaker 2: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 2: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial Share-A-Like 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.