Speaker 1: It's Tuesday April 5th 2011.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek night tonight the card game.
Speaker 0: Yo me Mario let's do this.
Speaker 1: Over the weekend I was in Racha Chah cold Actually, it was warmer there than it is here right now.
Speaker 0: Fuck them right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah But got to eat some de bella's and I got to say they have a brand new de bella's like the old one's gone.
Speaker 1: That shopping plaza over there is like the former CompUSA one.
Speaker 1: There are so many empty big-box stores around there.
Speaker 1: It's kind of crazy.
Speaker 0: How many what's left?
Speaker 0: is the computer Renaissance still there?
Speaker 1: No But the de bella's is like where did it move to?
Speaker 1: it's right on Jefferson now like right by all the other stuff like near where the Bruggers used to be and everything.
Speaker 1: Okay, but anyway this de bella's is freaking gigantic Like two stories tall on the inside.
Speaker 0: go upstairs inside of it.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: It's just a gigantic tall ceiling.
Speaker 0: Oh, it always had a pretty tall ceiling.
Speaker 1: It's way taller.
Speaker 1: think twice as tall 20% cooler, but I got to have some de bella's and you know what it's kind of like rewatching Ava every time.
Speaker 1: I think you know what that gay.
Speaker 1: that wasn't as good as What.
Speaker 0: are you stupid or like when?
Speaker 1: I would you know not that long ago?
Speaker 1: I was like playing Zelda 1 again, and I remembered oh wait one of the best games ever.
Speaker 0: You just don't learn your lesson.
Speaker 0: Dude.
Speaker 1: Yeah, de bella's pretty much has the best subs in the world.
Speaker 1: I Don't know about the world Best subs I have ever had short of occasional one-off subs.
Speaker 1: Yeah made by experts.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: I mean but on the way back, uh Feel a little ooky not from de bella's because I shared de bella's with many other people who did not get sick.
Speaker 0: Maybe it was.
Speaker 0: was there an ingredient in your de bella's that was not in it?
Speaker 1: Exact same de bella made by the same person that someone else had and they were fine.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, and Emily had a different de bella that someone else also had.
Speaker 1: neither one of them got sick All right, so I yeah horrible food poison.
Speaker 0: What did you eat before the de bella?
Speaker 1: Uh a whole bunch of different things.
Speaker 1: I can't really.
Speaker 1: Maybe it was the raw sprouts mixed with uncooked eggs.
Speaker 0: That's it?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: That's the one.
Speaker 1: but yeah Horrible food poisoning didn't go to work yesterday.
Speaker 1: the best part of this is I like rock climb and Ski and bike and rollerblade and I do all this stuff and I'm trying to learn parkour and I'm kind of an active guy.
Speaker 1: You'd think when I injure myself the inevitable day when I seriously injure myself It will be because I was doing something dangerous.
Speaker 1: No, in fact, I threw my back out so bad I couldn't walk on Sunday in the course of vomiting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I vomited so violently I threw out my back.
Speaker 0: that'll happen.
Speaker 1: The worst part is and think about this I vomit in the course of vomiting.
Speaker 1: I throw out my back.
Speaker 1: I fall over backwards and proceed to continue vomiting.
Speaker 1: That was that was my lowest moment There.
Speaker 1: there is very much a little lower than that.
Speaker 1: He didn't suffocate on the vomit because at least the last time I got horrible food poisoning I was hospitalized before I fell over backwards vomiting.
Speaker 0: You seem to have a trend here.
Speaker 1: my body's first my go-to thing.
Speaker 1: if there's any trouble my body's like What do we do?
Speaker 1: vomit?
Speaker 0: I'll resist bargaining until the end of days.
Speaker 1: I will too.
Speaker 1: My body has other ideas.
Speaker 1: It's expert system is like is there a problem?
Speaker 1: Can this be solved by vomiting vomit?
Speaker 0: Anyway, my streak is now very long.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, that was awesome man, I missed work good job and today I feel great But I think that's because I ate solid food for the first time in two days.
Speaker 0: That's a good thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's all also.
Speaker 1: no fucking my little pony on Friday.
Speaker 0: No, maybe this Friday.
Speaker 1: It better be There better be I don't know I don't know what I'll do.
Speaker 1: send an angry letter to Hasbro.
Speaker 1: I've already talked to them.
Speaker 1: They have no interest in.
Speaker 0: it says here a bird in the hoof April 8th.
Speaker 1: Now I wonder is Celestia Purposefully neglecting her bird?
Speaker 0: or is she angry that they intervene such that they have to cover Tries to help the princess sick bird without her permission and the ponies help smooth it over?
Speaker 0: Yeah, smooth it over.
Speaker 1: that.
Speaker 1: that implies that Celestia might not be a hundred percent on the up-and-up.
Speaker 0: I think it's one of those situations where she doesn't mind that she helped the bird.
Speaker 0: It's that she broke some other rule in the course of helping the bird like going into a forbidden area.
Speaker 1: Ah, you know the forbidden gulag where Luna's locked up.
Speaker 1: Yes anyway, so Because I had food poisoning and I couldn't even lie down because I also hurt my back.
Speaker 1: I Sat on the couch poking to my xbox all day.
Speaker 1: So I bought shadow complex and played a whole bunch of it.
Speaker 1: It was pretty good.
Speaker 1: Like you said it's kind of But it's not long enough now, which is fine because I don't have the patience.
Speaker 0: if it was longer I would have had the patience for if it was longer.
Speaker 0: But I don't have the patience to play the same game to get a hundred percent completion in the same areas over and over again.
Speaker 1: I think it's more that I have more patience for a very long game like that.
Speaker 1: if it's not a portable like Castlevania I'll pretty much play that forever.
Speaker 1: I could have play an infinite Castlevania and never get bored with it because I can play it like on the subway.
Speaker 1: But if I'm at home, I have so many more things I can do that.
Speaker 1: I really don't have patience for Metroidvania Mm-hmm, but I also noticed that the demo for the new Russian attack was there so I played that all the way through and There is not nearly enough rushing Coupled with the fact that the attacking is not so fun.
Speaker 1: Really It's basically a shitty version of casual castle crashers with no 3d.
Speaker 1: It's just 2d.
Speaker 1: So you walk up to a guy and it's like heavy attack light attack block.
Speaker 0: But the original Russian attack people don't know that game, but that was like some great game.
Speaker 0: You just you couldn't stop rushing.
Speaker 0: It's just rush.
Speaker 0: and it was constant attacking and if you didn't constantly attack there was dying.
Speaker 0: Yeah a lot of it.
Speaker 1: For me that game was basically rushing to the game genie.
Speaker 1: I Never beat it legit.
Speaker 1: I never even got close to beating it legit.
Speaker 1: Fuck that game.
Speaker 1: But Russian attack.
Speaker 1: expatriate tried to make a plot like a for serious plot.
Speaker 0: That is basically Why do you need a plot?
Speaker 0: Here's the plot.
Speaker 0: you ready?
Speaker 1: Go go go.
Speaker 1: Russian attack the Russians.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the game.
Speaker 1: go go go No, but basically there's no Go.
Speaker 1: so tell me if you see.
Speaker 1: tell me if you've heard this plot.
Speaker 1: before a meteor strikes somewhere in Russia It causes a crystal to grow.
Speaker 1: that crystal is mad energy.
Speaker 1: the Russians harvest it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've heard that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the plot.
Speaker 1: All right, and then I'm in a prison and there's all this dialogue I just don't care about.
Speaker 1: and then they let me out of the prison.
Speaker 0: Why is there dialogue?
Speaker 0: the game should consist of nothing but rushing and also attack.
Speaker 1: so I stab motherfuckers ending No, stopping no walking and in the course of stabbing motherfuckers I have two choices at all junctures stealth or not stealth.
Speaker 0: Why is there stealth?
Speaker 0: It's not hide and attack It's rush.
Speaker 1: The game is pretty much like yeah, you want to hide everywhere.
Speaker 1: We're gonna give you like a thousand different hide buttons and only to stab motherfucker buttons.
Speaker 0: What the fuck.
Speaker 0: who made this game?
Speaker 0: I found a grenade.
Speaker 0: really someone just took the name Russian attack and made some other game that was not Russian.
Speaker 0: It's a.
Speaker 1: they really focused on Russians as in the nationality as opposed to like that, but it's not Russian.
Speaker 0: Are you SS?
Speaker 0: I a N?
Speaker 0: do they read it wrong?
Speaker 0: Because it's.
Speaker 0: are you SS?
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: are you sh?
Speaker 0: Apostrophe n?
Speaker 0: yes in you are rushing.
Speaker 0: I'm an American soldier in a gulag Stabbing motherfuckers in Russia as in rush and like, you know toys are us.
Speaker 0: is his rush and attack?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you really don't run a rush because then you get caught by bad guys.
Speaker 1: You really want to crouch down and sneak and hide in the hole.
Speaker 1: If you want to hide in the door you hit up but if you want to hide in the hole you hit.
Speaker 1: why?
Speaker 0: yeah I'm not playing this now.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah health packs - but you know what?
Speaker 1: I will play packs that you have to use explicitly within d-pad.
Speaker 0: You know what though?
Speaker 1: I got every night vision that basically you turn it on when you need it and you turn it off When you don't need it, and it doesn't do anything interesting.
Speaker 0: I got ROMs of every NES Gameboy and Gameboy color game ever on my DS piracy card.
Speaker 1: I should really get a DS piracy car and now I can play Russian attack.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I am so not impressed with Russian attack.
Speaker 1: expatriate that I. it's difficult to describe to you how Uncomfortably bad it would.
Speaker 1: not bad not bad.
Speaker 1: if it was bad it would be more fun.
Speaker 1: It's just so desperately mediocre.
Speaker 1: To quote Wikipedia players will be able to perform shank combos in addition to the stealth kills.
Speaker 0: Why the stealth kills?
Speaker 1: the game is all about shanking.
Speaker 1: you realize you just have a knife and you have like a thousand ways.
Speaker 0: But in Russian attack didn't you have like a rocket launchers and machine guns and all sorts of ridiculous.
Speaker 1: Well until you run out of ammo and then it's knives till the end.
Speaker 0: I know that but I'm saying there were rocket launchers and machine guns available to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so screw this game All right.
Speaker 1: Just if you want a game like this play Bionic Commando rearmed.
Speaker 1: if you didn't that game is why everything you want.
Speaker 0: I get it better.
Speaker 0: Do you?
Speaker 0: why don't you play Russian attack for the NES?
Speaker 1: Why don't you play Bionic Commando for the NES?
Speaker 0: I played some bad commander for the Gameboy.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you.
Speaker 1: So what do you got for me?
Speaker 0: so You know Jane McGonagall right.
Speaker 0: she did the keynote.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, she did.
Speaker 0: she made this game.
Speaker 0: And if you're in New York, you can play this game bark ball.
Speaker 1: No Chicken bowling.
Speaker 0: No, it's called find the future and you play it at the library the New York Public Library the big one.
Speaker 1: Do I research science and try to better the world?
Speaker 0: I don't know what the hell you do but you basically go to the library and you go to this website and you you do whatever it says.
Speaker 0: and then 500 people.
Speaker 0: on May 20th 2011 Which is in 44 days 9 hours 23 minutes and some seconds from now at the time of this recording Smart listeners you can figure out exactly when we recorded gig nights.
Speaker 0: 500 people Are gonna stay overnight at the Stephen a Schwartzman building and become the first in the world to play a new game.
Speaker 0: Find the future.
Speaker 1: Oh, wait a minute New York Public Library.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I work right next to that I know.
Speaker 0: so if you have to go to the library and You know do this play the game.
Speaker 0: That's on the website.
Speaker 0: submit your entry and then 500 people who enter are gonna play the game again the real game I guess on May 20th, okay Overnight at the library.
Speaker 1: I'm spending my lunch over there to tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Yes, this is looking pretty good to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: also as a random aside if you weren't at PAX or if you were stupid didn't go to the keynote I'll try to find a link to it.
Speaker 1: You should be able to find her keynote from PAX.
Speaker 1: It was pretty damn amazing.
Speaker 0: You had a lot of crossover with her TED talk though If you've seen that it did but in her book if you've read that but it was obvious a lot of the people in the audience Had not.
Speaker 1: what scares me is how many people at our panels did not go to the keynote.
Speaker 1: Yeah Despite the fact that there was a simulcast.
Speaker 1: So while the keynote filled up like you couldn't get in as far as I can tell there was plenty of space in the figure.
Speaker 0: Anyone who was there that wasn't at the keynote was one of those expo hall type of people.
Speaker 0: or they had some other Conflicting panel that they cared more about.
Speaker 0: so they were not, you know, or they were playing games So they weren't likely to watch a simulcast.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, anyway, so things of the day it turns out now.
Speaker 1: I didn't read the study behind this.
Speaker 1: I am quoting an article that is talking about an article from the Journal of experimental social psychology.
Speaker 1: but supposedly there is evidence that if you are thinking about Being high as in physically higher than some arbitrary reference point You are more likely to cooperate and be altruistic in general.
Speaker 1: So if you put say a Salvation Army bin at the top of an escalator or stairway people are 50% more likely to give than if you put it at the bottom of an escalator or elevator or stairs or ramp or Anything.
Speaker 1: it even applies to showing people a video of flying versus a video of walking or driving.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I bring this up on a Tuesday because one of the panels we did at PAX was game mechanics and mechanism design.
Speaker 1: You know the whole idea that you can design a game that will cause certain behaviors in the play.
Speaker 0: You should put the in-game charity bucket at the top of the in-game escalator.
Speaker 1: No, you should have a picture of the sky at the end of your demo with a button that says buy the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you get people go up the stairs at the end of the game before you give them the part You know the buy full version button.
Speaker 0: That's a good idea.
Speaker 1: There appears to be evidence that that would probably work.
Speaker 0: Probably so I make sure there's birds going.
Speaker 1: Now think about this for everything cookie Brigade.
Speaker 1: You got to be at the top of every one of those escalators.
Speaker 0: Just well, I mean the cookie braid already sells all the cookies.
Speaker 1: true true, but they could possibly get more money.
Speaker 1: Oh If you need a player to play diplomacy with you get them into the game at the top of an escalator.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you should be looking for game.
Speaker 0: People should be at the top of escalators and stairs being like one play one play one play.
Speaker 1: I wonder if we can apply this.
Speaker 1: we're thinking about doing a show on it because you know out there your German board game players.
Speaker 1: There's the problem where nobody wants to play a wooden cube game Until they play it and then they love it.
Speaker 1: I Feel like we need to use this like shit like walk up to someone show them a picture of an airplane.
Speaker 1: They'd be like do you want to play a wooden cube game?
Speaker 0: Maybe we should just try wooden cube games that have themes of sky and airplanes and such while playing that song sky-high from dance dance revolution.
Speaker 1: Maybe this is why we like Rainbow Dash so much, too.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, I thought this was cool and you know It's kind of a reminder that psychology and game mechanics and mechanism design and games are all Pretty much cut from the same cloth.
Speaker 1: The only difference is that mechanism design uses a lot more math All right.
Speaker 0: So have you ever heard of a person named Peter Edkison?
Speaker 1: Uh My brain says yes, but yeah, he's an important person.
Speaker 0: He was the founder and first CEO of wizards of the coast.
Speaker 0: he's also currently the president Gen Con or the owner of Gen Con.
Speaker 0: CEO and owner of Gen Con and He you know, he was responsible for uniting D&D and Magic the Gathering under Wizards of the Coast and selling it to Hasbro.
Speaker 1: so remember back in the day all the conspiracy people who were like Wizards of the Coast is gonna turn D&D into Magic the Gathering and ruin it But anyway little did they know they would turn it into World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: He's currently the CEO of hidden city games where they make the Bellis era.
Speaker 0: I remember where Luke and Jared were.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, who would want to play a game about horses on anyway anyway?
Speaker 0: But here is a very interesting interview with this man where he discusses many things such as purchasing Hasbro and Regretting losing the Pokemon card game license and such-and-such using Hasbro.
Speaker 1: You mean being purchased by Hasbro, right?
Speaker 0: exactly?
Speaker 0: There was.
Speaker 0: there is an interesting.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna give you just one question and answer here.
Speaker 0: That's in the middle of the interview.
Speaker 0: that makes it kind of funny, right?
Speaker 0: Someone says define fantasy in 25 words or less that the interviewer said that That question has been asked of many people before.
Speaker 0: so he says I looked at fantasy for entertaining stories about heroes their beliefs how those beliefs are challenged and dealt with And how that changes the hero.
Speaker 1: There's might be a role-playing system he might enjoy.
Speaker 0: perhaps perhaps he has heard of it.
Speaker 0: perhaps perhaps he employed the creator.
Speaker 0: You Should.
Speaker 0: I is a good interview worth reading if you are someone who cares about tabletop things.
Speaker 0: He also even mentions here the best thing Hasbro has done in the last 10 years.
Speaker 0: big IMO caveat here Is the joint venture with discovery kids to create its own hub children's television channel.
Speaker 0: if Hasbro and Wizards can figure out how to leverage The hub together, that would be awesome.
Speaker 0: You know what I.
Speaker 1: In case anyone is unaware out there, you know new listeners, maybe they don't listen to the other shows.
Speaker 0: If they this is a man, this is a man who owns a company that makes a horsey trade card and you try card Trading card game.
Speaker 1: if they gave up on the girls and they and they made D&D related shows and just put them on the hub Well D&D comics do real that badly actually I think and they're actually I think it's Paul.
Speaker 0: so because they're awful.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that's the problem.
Speaker 1: I feel like there's a way to tap that.
Speaker 0: but look at how sorry people who make D&D comics.
Speaker 0: But if you don't suck you're doing a sucky job.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling I mean look at a penny arcade For example at PAX when they did that we're gonna play D&D on stage.
Speaker 1: how crazily popular that stuff is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I feel like you could turn that into a show probably.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah attack in the darkness and such.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway the meta moment.
Speaker 1: we are going to be at anime Boston upcoming in a few weeks doing a whole bunch of panels.
Speaker 1: We are going to be at the mocha this weekend.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not doing any panels, but we'll be interviewing people our friends.
Speaker 1: you going enough.
Speaker 1: Johnny.
Speaker 1: Wander will have a table.
Speaker 0: They're having a table.
Speaker 1: Whoa Finally after like five years of us saying they should get a table.
Speaker 1: They have a table Oh snap, so you should go find them and pester them.
Speaker 1: We should come up with something weird for you to say to them.
Speaker 0: Everyone should go up and do the same thing to them.
Speaker 0: Like what's the thing?
Speaker 0: It has to be something Weird enough to where I gotta get you go to draw ponies as many ponies as possible.
Speaker 1: That's that's self-interested.
Speaker 1: All right, guys Your mission is to trick.
Speaker 1: you go and enough into drawing pictures of ponies and then scan them in and give them to us.
Speaker 0: We need to you go and on mocha pony collection.
Speaker 0: As many my little ponies as you know.
Speaker 1: You cannot tell them that we put you up to that.
Speaker 1: Just tell them that you really want them to and that a little bird told you that they were just be like.
Speaker 0: just say that You're a huge fan of my little ponies and then you know that.
Speaker 0: you know with her art style She would you know that we she would draw an amazing one.
Speaker 1: This will also tell us if they listen to gig nights in a timely manner or not.
Speaker 0: I don't think they did Occasionally, I believe they do.
Speaker 1: I don't know our friends listen far less than all of you know The book club book which we'll be talking about on Thursday was Michio Kaku's hyperspace.
Speaker 0: many of you is probably tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Yes Also on May 1st, it is outdoor fucking day.
Speaker 1: You got something.
Speaker 0: come on, yeah, I can't get the page to load.
Speaker 1: we submitted our panels for Otacon So we'll see if we're going there.
Speaker 1: Pax prime is Five months or so away.
Speaker 1: We will be doing panels at it.
Speaker 1: There is also I'm going to say a word.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to say anything about it because I can't.
Speaker 1: Pax dev.
Speaker 0: we don't know what that is.
Speaker 1: We don't know what that is, but it is something.
Speaker 1: All right, it is something that it might happen someday.
Speaker 0: It might never happen.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: It's a word that I heard.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything else about the world.
Speaker 1: The word was passed to us some time ago with no further information.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I'm a. do you say enemy Boston already?
Speaker 0: Yes, okay on May 21st and 22nd in New York City There is going to be bar camp.
Speaker 0: So the registration information will appear at some point.
Speaker 0: But if you go to the bar camp NYC Twitter account There is a link to where you can sign up to be notified of when you'll be able to register.
Speaker 0: So do that if you are New York City person you want to go to bar camp.
Speaker 0: I'm helping organize it.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be good.
Speaker 1: So I enjoyed Street Fighter and RTS's and you know fighting games, but what are the?
Speaker 1: Well, they're the same thing basically Just a higher level, but I think they're mostly the same.
Speaker 1: They're more Execution matters more than strategy at the low levels in some of the games Yes, and at the high level strategy matters only because execution is perfect.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: But I am ass at these games.
Speaker 1: I am so bad at Street Fighter that despite spending a lot of time Practicing and trying to become good.
Speaker 0: I'm trivially dispatched by even what I would consider low ranking players Yeah, I mean there there are games, you know such as jungle speed which are pure execution, right?
Speaker 0: No strategy jungle speed.
Speaker 1: Well, there is technically the strategy strategy.
Speaker 0: Here's the strategy execute perfectly.
Speaker 1: if I match someone else.
Speaker 1: I will grab the totem before they do.
Speaker 0: There's no.
Speaker 0: but this there is no.
Speaker 0: no one has any different strategies.
Speaker 0: Everyone has the optimal strategy.
Speaker 1: I do have a secondary strategy that not everyone has colors.
Speaker 1: colors match.
Speaker 1: It's a match match.
Speaker 0: The point is that a game like jungle speed.
Speaker 1: There's no talking in jungle.
Speaker 0: Execution is everything and the winner is determined purely by execute.
Speaker 1: I mean, I have a strategy in hockey I take the biscuit and I put it in the bed as much as I can.
Speaker 0: in other games, right?
Speaker 0: There it strategy dominates right?
Speaker 0: So, you know in diplomacy there pretty much is no execution.
Speaker 0: Yeah whatsoever.
Speaker 1: It's all Strategy, actually, I would argue that diplomacy is nothing but execution of applied psychology.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: the point is that there it's not you know a sport or Locking the door before Scott Johnson gets back to put in his order.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: Whatever right other games, right?
Speaker 0: I have a mixture of the two.
Speaker 0: for example football Is the foot?
Speaker 0: is the strategy and the execution mixed together, however?
Speaker 0: In some games right where there were even when the two factors are present, right?
Speaker 0: One of the factors has been mastered.
Speaker 0: For example, there are many games Where for example baseball there is execution and strategy in baseball But people have mastered the strategy such that only the execution matters at high levels of play.
Speaker 0: At low levels of play people still haven't mastered the strategy.
Speaker 0: So both things still matter right but at high levels.
Speaker 0: in Major League Baseball only execution really matters.
Speaker 0: Right and such in like fighting games like Street Fighter, right?
Speaker 0: There is execution and strategy.
Speaker 0: both come into effect.
Speaker 0: however at the highest levels Execution has largely been perfected and only the strategy Mostly matters.
Speaker 0: at the highest levels right of things like Street Fighter and RTS is right Whereas on the low levels of Street Fighter and RTS is both Execution and strategy matter because neither one of them have been mastered.
Speaker 1: now imagine if you took Street Fighter 4, let's say championship edition and Championship edition.
Speaker 1: Yeah super super And made it where execution didn't matter where I input my string of moves and we take turns And you can take as long as you want.
Speaker 0: Yep, like alright I'm gonna throw a Hadoken and if you don't tell the guy that before you do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if he comes near me I'm gonna hit.
Speaker 1: So Yomi is basically that it's Street Fighter.
Speaker 1: the card game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it's made by this guy named Sirlin who has a. he's made he's making a bunch of games.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: I made this puzzle game with the chips right with something that people are talking about.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah They were playing that at zinc icon.
Speaker 1: yeah,
Speaker 0: and basically I kept hearing about this Yomi game and people just kept talking about it and talking about it and then I Saw some people play it once and I noticed that it was also a real deck of cards like, you know Two three four five Jack Queen puzzle
Speaker 1: strike.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the other one.
Speaker 0: All right, then this guy also has on his website He wrote a book about playing to win the game.
Speaker 0: So we like this guy, but this guy Sirlin I think he's also if I'm not mistaken like, you know a master of mechanism design.
Speaker 1: His site shows at the top your shopping bag is empty and there's a sad looking shopping bag looking at you with big eyes like Yep, and if you put something in it, he's happy.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but anyway, yeah, this guy knows what he's going on.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure he's like a semi professional fighting game guy, but he's yeah,
Speaker 1: well
Speaker 0: like us He was always upset that pretty much, you know, he's gonna beat the hell out of us at fighting games, but He still was always bothered by the fact that you know, he couldn't execute You know perfectly along with you know The highest highest level guys, even though he felt that he was strategically on the same level or higher level than them He couldn't beat them.
Speaker 1: because execution now that is not a flaw in any game because I am of the mind that Execution and elegance of execution is a very fine form of competition.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's fantastic the strategy of hockey whatever but the execution of hitting a guy into the boards as hard as you can without doing A penalty matters to me quite a bit.
Speaker 1: I enjoy watching such interplay But there is a place for both and I like the fact that he's considered how to take a game like Street Fighter and bring it down to the low level.
Speaker 1: So someone who does not have the execution abilities can enjoy the high-level strategy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, but basically there is a strategy in Street Fighter But you you can't really access that strategy unless you get really really good at the execution.
Speaker 0: and not many people can do that Even many even though many people play Street Fighter.
Speaker 0: very few people experience the strategy of Street Fighter because it's inaccessible to them.
Speaker 0: They need to be masters of the joystick before they can get there.
Speaker 1: So he's made a game before you can master the joystick.
Speaker 1: You must first master yourself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he made a game called Yomi which is a card game which has the exact same or nearly the exact same strategic elements and play as Street Fighter or most fighting games.
Speaker 1: you've got your power.
Speaker 1: bar your life Yeah, with none of the execution.
Speaker 0: so it doesn't matter if you can't use a joystick for poop.
Speaker 1: You can get the same Street Fighter experience unless you're good at close-up magic and you just cheat with the cards.
Speaker 0: Yes, we're assuming no cheating because I've been practicing.
Speaker 1: I think I can fairly effectively reveal a card in either direction.
Speaker 0: We'll just play the digital version Hack it.
Speaker 0: There's a real digital version.
Speaker 0: It's official on the website.
Speaker 0: It's in beta.
Speaker 0: I'll hack it Anyway, so what's Yomi all about?
Speaker 0: so Yomi is a non collectible card game, right?
Speaker 0: Where each deck of there's decks of cards is ten of them and you can buy sets of two or you can buy the full Set.
Speaker 0: the full sets really expensive.
Speaker 0: It's like a hundred something dollars.
Speaker 0: Right, but the individual like, you know to buy just two decks is like 20 something.
Speaker 1: my suggestion to distribute the cost and to make sure you like it is do what we did and buy one set of two and play the Game a couple times.
Speaker 1: if you're intrigued at all trick one of your idiot friends into buying a set of two different characters.
Speaker 0: No, it's non collectible non customizable.
Speaker 0: It's not magically gathering.
Speaker 0: It's not yugioh It's not Pokemon, but each individual deck is a different character.
Speaker 0: So think of it like, you know This deck is guile and this deck is M bison.
Speaker 0: in this deck is Chun Li and originally I'm pretty sure he wanted the street Fighter license, but he couldn't get it.
Speaker 0: So he just made up characters and the first set is fantasy strike And I think the next set is gonna be something else, right?
Speaker 0: So each set is gonna be a different, you know setting with different characters.
Speaker 0: So when the next set comes out you have you know Ten more characters.
Speaker 0: next that comes out your ten more characters.
Speaker 1: It has all the aesthetics of a video fight as the stupid plot of a fighting game.
Speaker 1: It has the characters and the backstory.
Speaker 1: the characters are all kind of absurd.
Speaker 1: It is everything you would expect.
Speaker 0: Yep, it is.
Speaker 0: It is exactly like a fighting game in every way.
Speaker 0: Here's how the game works, right?
Speaker 0: You take your deck of cards, which is also a regular deck of cards, you know, 52 plus 2 jokers, right?
Speaker 0: You shuffle it up You draw seven and every turn you play rock-paper-scissors and the rock-paper-scissors is pretty much either attack throw or block dodge.
Speaker 0: Right, so block dodge beats attack Attack beats throw and throw beats block and dodge, right?
Speaker 1: So you play rock-paper-scissors Kind of like a fighting game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just like a fighting game and if you win the rock-paper-scissors, then you get to do a bunch of damage possibly.
Speaker 0: but First if before you do a combo, right?
Speaker 0: Which is how you would do even more damage the other person gets to bluff.
Speaker 0: They can put a card face down and bluff which is like a ha ha Right, and that ha ha ha is pretty much like either.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay, you can risk doing a combo But if I'm not bluffing your combos gonna be a waste.
Speaker 1: The best part though is that it the dynamics are like a fighting game.
Speaker 1: attacks have speed If two if attack hits attack the faster one gets through.
Speaker 1: and you have this combo system where if you hit someone once You know, I poke M bison with my jab, I then lay in with the combo into my ender that knocks him down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if he was bluffing that combo is just gonna be a big waste and he'll block the rest of the combo even though The first or if I dodge I get to counter.
Speaker 1: but if I block then I get other things.
Speaker 0: But but if you block a special attack, you still take a little bit of chip damage Yeah, and some characters they're.
Speaker 1: the damage that goes through the block is substantial.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and every character has different attacks different special abilities, right certain cards.
Speaker 0: You know every card actually has two abilities on it, right so you play.
Speaker 1: we pick which way you want it to face And like one sides attack one sides dodge.
Speaker 0: Yep and special attack.
Speaker 0: Some of them are the same thing on both sides, but some of them have two different abilities like, you know The fish man, he can either do a bubble shield or you can do like some crazy attack with the other side of the same Card.
Speaker 1: it's a complete information game and that you know the full.
Speaker 0: No, you don't know what the other part Scott.
Speaker 1: Yes, it's not a perfect information game.
Speaker 1: It is a complete information game because you know the entirety of the strategies available to both characters.
Speaker 0: No, cuz you don't know what cards he has in his hand.
Speaker 0: You don't know is a block even possible for him this turn?
Speaker 1: But you know the total array of possible strategies and you know.
Speaker 0: what you know Is that the certain strategy might be impossible if he does at that time, but it is theoretically possible at any point.
Speaker 1: Theoretically, it's not perfect information.
Speaker 0: Well, you think you'd have to know what's in his hands got.
Speaker 1: complete information simply means you basically means that you know The rules of the game and you know the rules both players are playing by.
Speaker 0: you do know the rules Perfect information.
Speaker 0: you look to the other guy's deck and know all his.
Speaker 1: yes means that you know Every decision that has been made up to this point and there are no simultaneous decisions Mm-hmm, and this game is nothing but simultaneous decisions.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: And there's also lots of hidden cards and Pretty much that's it.
Speaker 1: I mean the characters all have neat powers like Lum the gambling panda.
Speaker 1: It's just like we only have four the characters.
Speaker 0: So I don't know about the other six, you know But the ones we have.
Speaker 0: we got the regular people the red and blue this.
Speaker 0: they seem to be like the main and we have Lizard man equivalents the weirdo characters.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: It's a random panda.
Speaker 0: and the defensive fish man Who is?
Speaker 1: I love the defensive fish man.
Speaker 0: fish man's pretty good.
Speaker 0: He does two damage every single round no matter what unless he's knocked down.
Speaker 1: My only worry is that we played a whole bunch of times and the blue guy and the first deck you bought is so far Is undefeated by a wide margin?
Speaker 0: No, I think the the red girl won once when I played at board game night.
Speaker 0: Ah How about that?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah The blue guy is that one combo that does like 45 damage.
Speaker 0: Well, no, it's one move that does 45 damage, but you need to have three aces, right?
Speaker 0: That's another cool thing about.
Speaker 0: the game is like it has all these mechanics that so Perfectly represent mechanics and fighting games, right?
Speaker 0: If you do a combo of regular attacks Then you get to search your deck to get aces which are always your best attack.
Speaker 0: You can discard pairs three of a kind and four of a kind to go search for aces.
Speaker 0: You can do all these things to go get aces out of your deck and that's basically the equivalent of powering up the EX meter At the bottom of the screen in any fighting game, right, you know.
Speaker 0: And that way even though you might have used all your cards already You can go dig for the aces to get you know to get more so you can keep unleashing your best attack.
Speaker 0: You know your ultra your super or whatever, even though you've already used it.
Speaker 1: You also draw aces if you chain together long combos.
Speaker 1: I said that already but the bet the big part is that different characters have different limits on combos.
Speaker 1: Like the panda only has four.
Speaker 1: the fish man has three.
Speaker 1: one character has like five or six.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that some of the characters, you know Every character has a particular strategy is Valerie has more than anyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the thing is Some of the characters right are just pretty from what I hear.
Speaker 0: they're just win against other characters.
Speaker 0: You know It's sort of like a rock versus before you even start.
Speaker 0: Like if you take the guy who's all about blocking and you take the other guy who's all about getting through blocks Well, guess who's gonna win most of the time?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what?
Speaker 1: It's kind of like a fighting game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is kind of.
Speaker 0: you know If you see the other guy chooses a character and you see what character he chooses you can pick a character.
Speaker 1: that's strong against Character but then they'll pick a different character and it's the same problem.
Speaker 1: and I wonder what would happen.
Speaker 1: It's like a fighting game panda vs.
Speaker 1: Panda.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you got two decks, I see no reason why you couldn't do that.
Speaker 0: You know, you just had to get.
Speaker 0: even if you think is you can't even do that You buy the full set.
Speaker 0: you did buy two full sets to do that.
Speaker 1: That's why I'm saying just everyone who cares about this game If your friends like it is get each one of them to buy one of the sets of two.
Speaker 0: Well, if I all go in and buy the box and split it up The box does come with like mats to play on and life counters and that sort of extra stuff if you want it.
Speaker 0: So it's not a total waste to get the to get the fancy full box.
Speaker 1: The mats are stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, I don't even know why you need mats.
Speaker 0: But you know life counters would be good because we keep using paper to count life.
Speaker 0: or you know cell phone cell phones And it's not the most convenient thing.
Speaker 0: counters.
Speaker 0: you know 2d 10 is what you really want to get to count your life in this game because every character basically has a.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't mind just playing it on a smartphone The whole game on a smartphone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I see no reason why they couldn't do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah That'd be pretty cool.
Speaker 1: They would.
Speaker 0: and one of the one of the things I don't like about this game though I guess it's sort of mandatory.
Speaker 0: I said it's two-player, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I sort of wish it was more than two players somehow.
Speaker 0: That would be totally cool.
Speaker 1: It would be possible if they made another set which obviously is probably gonna happen to have rules for like Alright - on - and like here's.
Speaker 0: you can have tournaments that you know.
Speaker 0: You could take any of the Street Fighter multi-play modes Johnny Cage versus Johnny Cage.
Speaker 0: He could have knockout mode where.
Speaker 0: basically, you know You have.
Speaker 0: you know You have two teams and the team's the weakest guy in each team fights and the winner fights the next guy or you play where?
Speaker 1: You both have two characters and just have a make up a rule where you tag out.
Speaker 1: We mean tag out like I tag out to my other character by spending an action The car you the other guy.
Speaker 0: so you play it more like more tomorrow versus cap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you keep track of the three hip HP's of the characters separately of three decks.
Speaker 0: Yeah Three discard piles and three hands and you guys least you can only use one at a time at any given turn.
Speaker 0: I could dig that but what do you have?
Speaker 0: but you would just tag you.
Speaker 0: tagging out doesn't cost you anything.
Speaker 1: Well, you got to come up with a good way to do it or wait for an official version Which will probably come.
Speaker 1: that does stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would make it like discard two cards to tag out or you know, something like that Yep, or you have to successfully dodge or block.
Speaker 0: Yeah something like, you know.
Speaker 0: Or maybe like.
Speaker 0: if you tag out then you you you know, you cannot You must attack or throw you, you know, you can't.
Speaker 0: you know some sort of restriction like that?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the game has knockdowns.
Speaker 0: it's got.
Speaker 0: you know, it's got some weird.
Speaker 0: are some weird rules like the?
Speaker 0: if you get knocked down then you can't be blocked by Like something mix-ups.
Speaker 0: It's like why it's kind of weird, but it's it explains it pretty clearly on one of the cards To help you out.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I mean it's once you learn it.
Speaker 1: It's actually really straightforward.
Speaker 1: The rules are just like I'll fold out.
Speaker 1: magic is way harder than this.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I mean, it's not.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't say it's like the greatest game in the world But it's a two-player game, which is rare, right?
Speaker 1: You can just rip it out.
Speaker 0: It's got a lot of replay value.
Speaker 0: You can play it very quickly.
Speaker 0: I mean if you play it with people who know the rules, it's as quick as a round of fighting.
Speaker 0: You know of Street Fighter, which is pretty great You know, the only things is that it is no fooling.
Speaker 1: pretty much rock paper scissors plus randomness determines Which of course, I mean Scott and I played two rounds earlier.
Speaker 1: I barely won the second one and I Scott got a flawless victory on the first one.
Speaker 1: I literally lost every paper rock scissor the whole time.
Speaker 1: I do dodge.
Speaker 1: He does throw I do attack He does block like it was just perfect.
Speaker 1: Perfect.
Speaker 1: There was nothing I could do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you lose the right paper scissors every time you lose.
Speaker 0: that's just how it goes Right and that may you know.
Speaker 0: and the thing is that's what fighting games are at the highest level is rock paper scissors With some randomness, right?
Speaker 1: Well all games break down to either arbitrary random or solvable.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's no solvable because you're against a human opponent.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna solve?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: You don't.
Speaker 0: he could push any button.
Speaker 1: Ah, I Play tic-tac-toe against a human opponent.
Speaker 0: No, no, but I mean there's.
Speaker 0: there's so many possible attacks that it's not a solvable thing Right, yeah in a fighting game now unless you you you're trying to defend it could be a broken fighting game.
Speaker 0: where it's like Aha, this unblockable combo over and over again will win and that's a solution.
Speaker 1: That's basically why Kenshiro wins every fight.
Speaker 0: Yeah But but non-broken one attack that in non broken fighting games when you've mastered the execution it comes down to rock paper scissors Plus a little bit of randomness.
Speaker 0: All right, and that's what Yomi is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well or you know Bushido blade came down to.
Speaker 1: I know how to do the throw and no one else does.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but think about it.
Speaker 0: It's like okay I'm by sitting your guile and we're playing Street Fighter where we're both masters, right?
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna go and try to do this attack You know and people always talk about like you try to trick the other guy into doing a move to leave himself open.
Speaker 0: You know, that's that's all.
Speaker 0: that's exactly what it's all about in Yomi.
Speaker 1: It's like the old samurai fights where you know I will open myself up to let him hit me knowing that he will hit me on mortally, but I will hit him mortally.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I sort of like this idea though.
Speaker 0: I wish that it would expand to more areas, right?
Speaker 0: Like maybe what we should do is go in both directions, right?
Speaker 1: You know wait, so we take an RTS and make it turn based.
Speaker 0: No like a turn It's not what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: So in Street Fighter, right?
Speaker 0: they took out the execution component so that people who couldn't execute could learn and appreciate the Strategic component.
Speaker 0: and maybe some of those people will go back and play fighting games and maybe some fighting game people will play Yomi And it'll cross over right?
Speaker 0: Maybe what we need to do is take some other games, you know and remove a component that people can't get past right and cross them over for those games that skill right.
Speaker 0: or We can do is we can take games Scott.
Speaker 1: They did that her first-person shooters They made Halo.
Speaker 0: All right, but I'm talking about we can take say Puerto Rico add an execution component You know and keep the same strategy as Puerto Rico, but at execution make it a video game.
Speaker 0: You've got a crocodile your brown guys into the plantations exact something, you know something along those lines You know.
Speaker 0: you take this, you know.
Speaker 0: Take a game that has a strategy and an execution remove one or the other take a game that only has one add the other You know.
Speaker 0: try to get crossover because I feel like this is how even though these these two different games will have the same strategy Or same execution component at least no crossover between the community
Speaker 1: when I imagine board games Like I'm playing Puerto Rico a whole bunch and I think about man.
Speaker 1: What kind of game do I want?
Speaker 1: It's always take Puerto Rico and add one additional component or remove one fundamental component Or replace one component and it's basically that yeah I mean you look, you know, some people are sort of doing it.
Speaker 0: Like you look at Le Havre is pretty much Calus plus Agricola.
Speaker 0: Yeah Mine is as much in the inside is a theme.
Speaker 1: the theme of Le Havre is basically boats get victory point pictures of boats get points.
Speaker 1: how Abstractions.
Speaker 0: at least Calus has a real theme.
Speaker 1: Yeah put stuff in the castle.
Speaker 0: I played a game of Calus board game.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, I want to play Calus again.
Speaker 1: real bad crushed it because you went into the castle Castle.
Speaker 0: this other guy did all gold and he was using second place But but he didn't castle at all.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I lost a bunch of points and this other guy was way behind like dead last But he caught up to second place in the last in the final round, but I won the dungeon and the walls.
Speaker 0: He won the tower and I still did pretty good in the towers and no one can catch.
Speaker 1: You know kids if you'd gone to our how to win a games panel We told you all how to win Calus.
Speaker 0: direct path to big.
Speaker 1: just go to the castle correct.
Speaker 0: bad favors favors favors Bottom bottom favor track to get free buildings.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I built a blue building.
Speaker 0: No one else built a blue building.
Speaker 0: I won.
Speaker 1: Yep buildings and victory points.
Speaker 0: Yep No one can stop me.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: But yeah, yo me is fun.
Speaker 0: I even made a mistake.
Speaker 0: I probably could have had two blue buildings because I forgot the gold mine existed and I didn't.
Speaker 0: I could have chosen the green building Favor one more time.
Speaker 1: Nah, but anyway God I really want to play Calus now.
Speaker 1: Yes, like real bad.
Speaker 0: Let's do it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so yo me yo me is the new hotness.
Speaker 0: Everyone's talking about it and not with no reason.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not the greatest but it's good.
Speaker 1: I posit because we've had a worth your worth your money.
Speaker 0: We have
Speaker 1: had a renaissance like a study really a renaissance but a surge of this kind of game lately in our crew at Conventions 10
Speaker 0: billion times better than munchkin
Speaker 1: because there are two times when we need a game that we can whip out Relatively quickly without a lot of fuss and mess.
Speaker 1: that can be taught easily and played to completion before the line moves standing in line for something or Warming up while we're waiting for everyone to finish their business to play a real game?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and spot it.
Speaker 1: jungle speed and yo me are like the three best games for the M banana grams.
Speaker 0: Yeah the problem I keep having though is that People play these games and then these games dominate like people just sit there playing spot it for an hour.
Speaker 0: It's like no You're supposed to spot it for like a minute while someone sets up the cube game And once the cube game is set up stop playing spots.
Speaker 1: the fundamental problem of the cube game.
Speaker 1: We got to play the cube game up in that hallway above the expo hall instead of down in the bottom of the expo.
Speaker 1: Haha.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway with Rainbow Dash This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.