Speaker 0:
Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, June 8th, 2011.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight's double feature, Wakfu and Hippy-a-ra.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So did you see Steve Jobs?
Speaker 0: He was all going to the Cupertino town council and showing him the building he wants to build to put all his people in.
Speaker 1: I did not see that.
Speaker 0: Oh, because basically what happened there, right, is the Apple's got too many people now for their campus, right?
Speaker 0: So HP is leaving to go to a different town.
Speaker 0: So they basically, HP's moving out and he's buying HP's land and he wants to build this gigantic 12,000 person circular building.
Speaker 0: Actually looks pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Oh, you realize that's one RIT.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, and it's actually a pretty good plan.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh dude, that's sweet, right?
Speaker 1: Alright, but there's clearly a but here.
Speaker 0: So my office is doing a similar situation, right?
Speaker 0: Where it's like, basically this, you know, a company bought us and they have another office in town, but our office is better, so they want to move their people in their other office in town into our office.
Speaker 1: We did a similar thing before where we basically bought as much of our floor as we could.
Speaker 1: We have like most of the floor.
Speaker 1: And then we were doing all this renovations, we needed all this space, and then now that we laid off a quarter of the company, we don't need that space anymore.
Speaker 1: So now, after a long time, they're kind of down renovating.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so for like months, there have been people coming in, because we work in an area of the office that was sort of empty, and it was just us and a bunch of empty space.
Speaker 0: So that was clearly the space to be renovated.
Speaker 1: I mean, it was like that in the IBM.
Speaker 1: I mean, my hallway was like half empty.
Speaker 1: in the building and the floor under us, there were just like empty locked rooms.
Speaker 0: Right, so, you know, that's the space they were going to move into, so people have been walking around us and whispering and all this kind of, you know, and like, we've noticed people walking around with measuring tapes and blueprints and all sorts of stuff for months and weeks, but no one told us dick.
Speaker 0: And it's like, uh...
Speaker 1: I'm starting to get sick of, it's weird how all the smaller companies I've worked for are like, they're so secretive about everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I really want to talk about, right?
Speaker 0: Because basically, you know, we found out, you know, I don't care what they decide, put me in a tiny box, put me in a big office, I don't really care, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like, they just wait till the last second to tell you anything, and they're just so discourteous and secretive for no reason.
Speaker 0: But look at Steve Jobs, the most secretive guy in the universe, right?
Speaker 0: He doesn't want anyone to know anything, but he'll go to the town council, a public forum, and see, here's the giant building I want to build, here's the blueprints, here's what we want to do, right?
Speaker 0: He's out about it, you know, stuff like that, stuff that affects the employees.
Speaker 0: He's going to tell the employee what the employee needs to know, and the people in the town what they need to know.
Speaker 0: He's not going to, you know, keep things secret just for no reason.
Speaker 0: He has at least what he thinks is the reason most of the time.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's a more general problem.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of, I'm feeling like secrets are one of the biggest problems we've got right now, because secrets cause corruption.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we talk all about the time, mostly what we talk about is that government unnecessarily keeps too many things confidential.
Speaker 0: But it's not just government that has a problem with secrets, and it's not just companies either, it's just people in general keep things secret unnecessarily for no reason and often cause more harm than, you know, that didn't need to be caused.
Speaker 0: If they would just share information, basically people follow a policy of keep everything secret except for what you absolutely can't keep secret, where what you should do is keep everything public except for what you absolutely cannot make public.
Speaker 0: That is the policy you need to follow.
Speaker 1: But specifically with the corporate stuff, like in jobs, it's really weird to me that the mundane stuff is usually a better kept secret.
Speaker 1: Like, I didn't even know about the layoffs back when we had all the layoffs until the day it happened.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean, that's an HR thing.
Speaker 0: There's sometimes legal reasons you have to keep that secret.
Speaker 1: But simultaneously, there's a corporate move.
Speaker 1: To this day, I don't officially know that we're moving offices and they're moving stuff around.
Speaker 1: I know no, because I know shit, but I don't officially know.
Speaker 1: No one has officially informed me of anything.
Speaker 1: It's annoying.
Speaker 0: It is, it's very annoying.
Speaker 1: Much like how the anime industry is super secretive about everything for no reason.
Speaker 0: And it's totally, you know, in a situation like I'm in where it's like, I'm working here, you're someone who's moving in, this affects me and the people I'm working with, and it's just, you know, it's just discourteous not to tell us.
Speaker 1: At the same time.
Speaker 0: It's like, you're not obligated to tell me.
Speaker 0: You don't need to make me a part of the decision making process.
Speaker 1: More than once.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: But the fact that you don't tell me makes me think you're a jerk.
Speaker 0: It's like, the only really harm you've done is make me hate the upper management and think they're all jerks.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, are you not simply a mercenary?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean, the point is, you know.
Speaker 1: I mean, you don't tell the mercenaries the strategy.
Speaker 1: You don't care.
Speaker 0: But if they just told me, I wouldn't think they were jerks.
Speaker 0: I would like them.
Speaker 1: Ah, but does you thinking someone's a jerk in any way materially impact anything?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it makes me want to get out of there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you- And they don't want me to leave.
Speaker 1: Ah, we'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: The other thing, right, the other situation is, right, is like when a big higher up guy, right, gets a gigantic office and everyone else is stuck in tiny cubes, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like, okay, you're the highest up guy.
Speaker 0: You have a right to do that, right?
Speaker 0: That is your privilege for being, you know, the top CEO or whatever you are.
Speaker 1: Or I can understand situations where there are people who have enough responsibility to where they need kind of a private large office with just space to have meetings and do stuff in.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't need to host private meetings often enough to have my own dedicated space.
Speaker 1: I can go, you know, check out one of the conference rooms.
Speaker 0: Of course, but by doing so, right, by having an excessively large office, what message did that send to the rest of the employees, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like.
Speaker 0: basically you're saying, I'm a big jerk.
Speaker 0: Who cares about myself?
Speaker 0: Fuck you all.
Speaker 0: Get in the tiny cube.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like you have a right to put me in a tiny cube.
Speaker 1: What if it's meritocracy, Scott?
Speaker 1: What if it's where the people whose jobs are most important have the nicest offices?
Speaker 0: I'm just saying.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, what if?
Speaker 1: Would you be mad if it was a meritocracy?
Speaker 0: You know, it depends.
Speaker 1: I mean, the people who are better get paid more.
Speaker 1: How is that different than having a bigger office?
Speaker 0: Actually, I think that it shouldn't be secret when people get paid either.
Speaker 1: I'm very open about what I get paid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, me too.
Speaker 1: Except at work because everyone's like, well, actually everyone I know outside of like the geek community and outside of like, you know, my circle of friends, people are super cagey and really don't want other people to know what they make.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's actually that is sort of a conspiracy by companies.
Speaker 0: They don't what they want.
Speaker 0: They someone intentionally back in the day wanted some company wanted to make it a stigma to let people know what you made.
Speaker 1: because not to not to name names, companies I have worked for or may currently work for have stipulations in contracts stating that I cannot disclose to other employees how much I make.
Speaker 1: Or other benefits that I have.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: Like, for example, I have stock options in my company, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Most of my co-workers don't even know stock options were an option.
Speaker 1: And I'm not allowed to tell them that I have them.
Speaker 0: It's only a benefit to employees to know what your fellow employees make.
Speaker 0: If you all shared, if everyone told everyone else what you made, then, you know, you might.
Speaker 0: someone might be upset at finding out that they're being paid a lot less than someone else.
Speaker 0: But since everyone knows how much everyone's contributing, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if I get paid a little less than this other guy who does more work than me, it's like we look at each other and we're like, yeah, all right, you do more work.
Speaker 1: But usually what happens is a company has someone who's been there a long time.
Speaker 1: They need them.
Speaker 1: So they're giving them increasing salaries to keep them around.
Speaker 1: And then they hire someone new.
Speaker 1: And because that person might not be familiar with the pay grades of that industry, they pay them the minimum possible.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So sharing information, someone might be upset at finding out the truth.
Speaker 0: But then if you actually had balls and would go to the people who make the decisions to be like, hey, we've discovered this is unfair.
Speaker 0: Fix it, asshole.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Then suddenly they're in the ones who are in the deep shit and the employees become empowered, even without unionizing.
Speaker 0: Just by sharing information, you could empower yourselves and get more money for everyone.
Speaker 0: You're not going to get less money for anyone.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You're just going to get more money by sharing this information at the expense of, you know, some people who are really sensitive, you know, being upset.
Speaker 0: But I'm sure they won't be upset if they had the balls to go and fight for their money.
Speaker 1: But I foresee the people who are most likely to be upset are the ones who aren't paid that much and who probably don't have any sway to be paid anymore.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So then it's just, hey, you know, you've there was a truth that you aren't really worth that much to us.
Speaker 0: And now it is revealed.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And your choice is to continue working here or not get a job somewhere else because you suck.
Speaker 1: I will at least for now continue to make my one hundred and thirty five thousand dollars a year.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I make 70 something.
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: I make almost double what you make.
Speaker 1: And yet you probably do more work than me.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: But you're going to watch out.
Speaker 0: I'm going to fight next.
Speaker 0: Because the thing is, I'm so I'm too nice.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: As much as I say the balls to fight for whatever.
Speaker 1: I've been thinking about that lately because I know my problem.
Speaker 1: I've been seriously debate doing the same.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I think that's that's what you know, how we always talk about, you know, the nerds who could be the most dangerous, who could bring society crashing down or too nice.
Speaker 0: That's why we don't do terrorism, even though we could.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's the same thing.
Speaker 0: It's like I'm a nerd.
Speaker 0: I'm too nice.
Speaker 0: I don't go in there and be like, give me more money.
Speaker 0: Asshole.
Speaker 1: It depends.
Speaker 1: It depends on how much you care.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'll be honest.
Speaker 1: When I worked at my previous job hospital, I went into my boss and I was like, look, unless you give me a hundred percent raise, I'm going to give you my two weeks notice.
Speaker 1: And then, yeah, the guy was like, yeah, that was me.
Speaker 0: That was quitting.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That wasn't actually negotiating.
Speaker 1: Well, I gave.
Speaker 1: I gave an ultimatum because had he doubled my salary, I might I probably would have stuck around a little while longer than quit anyway after I had a pile of money.
Speaker 1: But that's a separate problem.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But the point is, I'm too nice.
Speaker 0: I've never once actually negotiated or fought because everyone who's ever paid me has paid me enough to live.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I'm paying the rent.
Speaker 0: I'm buying everything I could possibly want to buy, you know, giant boxes of comic books every month, computers, anything I need an Amazon.
Speaker 0: I just buy it without thinking I pay the rent, I pay all the bills and my bank account balance just keeps going up.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, I'm so non greedy.
Speaker 0: I'm just like, whatever.
Speaker 0: So I never fight for more money or anything.
Speaker 0: But next time I decide, you know, it's been too long.
Speaker 0: I realize you don't get anywhere without fighting.
Speaker 0: So now I'm going to fight the next time I get a chance when there's a review or whatever there is that ever.
Speaker 1: Ah, my company is very smart about that.
Speaker 1: They stopped giving reviews years ago.
Speaker 0: So that's a genius move.
Speaker 1: So that way.
Speaker 1: Because think about this.
Speaker 1: No one ever asks you anymore.
Speaker 1: Hey, are you happy?
Speaker 1: What's going on?
Speaker 1: So you never have an excuse to be like, yeah, I'm kind of bored.
Speaker 0: But it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: There is going to be some sort of H.R.
Speaker 0: event at some point.
Speaker 0: that will give me an opportunity to negotiate in some form.
Speaker 0: But when that comes, I'm basically going to be like, look, I want 30 vacation days.
Speaker 0: I know I've been joking about 30 vacation days, but now I'm actually serious.
Speaker 0: I want 30 vacation days.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm not getting if you don't give me 30 vacation.
Speaker 1: Well, your logic is sound because to summarize it, you basically pointed out that, all right, you could make more money elsewhere.
Speaker 1: Both of us could.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But, you know, it's a pain in the ass to switch jobs and all that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: And anyone can just offer more money.
Speaker 1: So there's no benefit to fighting for more money one place versus another place.
Speaker 1: But nobody, for some reason, the American like industry system is fucked up to where nobody gives anybody shit for vacation days.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Even me.
Speaker 0: But in Europe.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's 30 days minimum and no one has any jobs.
Speaker 0: There are some places where it's like 60 days minimum.
Speaker 1: Scott, most people have three hundred and sixty five days.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, you know, the so the idly wealthy and the unemployed.
Speaker 1: So because no one gives anyone vacation days, I mean, I don't even get as many as I want.
Speaker 0: If they gave me 30 vacation days, I basically would have to stay there for less pay.
Speaker 0: for, you know, as long as I could do to come to gave me 30 actual vacation days going anywhere else would reset me to 10.
Speaker 1: Well, the biggest thing I realize the real problem here is pretty fundamental.
Speaker 1: I would take a 50 percent pay cut to work 50 percent of the time.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And that would be awesome for me.
Speaker 1: And no one is going to pay me seventy thousand dollars a year to only work six months out of the year.
Speaker 0: No, but here's the other.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So they could give me more money.
Speaker 0: But like I said, even at my current pay, my bank account is increasing because I'm so frugal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because you're so great.
Speaker 1: We're so rich and we're just rubbing it into all the listeners faces.
Speaker 0: Listen, if you guys go and study computer science and are good at it, you can end up in the same way, too.
Speaker 1: But you also got to be lucky and for, you know, you want to the real secret.
Speaker 1: But then what we should get onto the actual show, you know, and the real secret is one, actually be smart to learn computers, because that's where you make all the money.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There are a few other specialty fields you can make equal money in, but three live in New York computers.
Speaker 1: The ones that we know.
Speaker 1: you don't have to live in New York for a major city.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But the biggest thing, too, is you've got to be willing and able to sell yourself.
Speaker 1: You've got like everyone I see when I interview people to hire, like to work for me, they're like they're so cookie cutter, like I don't remember their names, like everyone looks the same, talks the same, wears the same suit with the same like color, like the power tie and the earth tone.
Speaker 1: The resume is all like identical.
Speaker 1: It's like nobody stands out.
Speaker 1: No one's willing to let their real personality show through.
Speaker 1: In an interview, everyone always acts the way they expect corporations to expect them to act.
Speaker 1: You realize every interview I've ever done, I act like me.
Speaker 0: That's like the other day when I was in the.
Speaker 1: I'm like, yeah, I do a podcast called Geek Knives about nerdy shit.
Speaker 0: We usually eat in the park outside of Barclays, which is, you know, it's one of those public private parks like they own it, but it's public.
Speaker 0: Oh, speaking of which, and there were these guys walking around with name tags.
Speaker 0: They're all wearing the same suit.
Speaker 0: And it was like I was like, oh, my God, I'm so glad we're not those guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's actually the fact that my company doesn't have a dress code because I wear suits like every day.
Speaker 1: But now that it's warm today and I was biking to work until my fucking bike got stolen, I stopped wearing suits and started wearing just T-shirts.
Speaker 1: And I kind of don't want to go back to wearing suits ever again, even though I really like wearing suits because I get, you know, it'll never get cold again.
Speaker 1: It's going to be warm like this forever.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so anime, manga, comics, news.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Oh, you want some news?
Speaker 1: I think we should actually talk about.
Speaker 1: we don't want to be Dave and Joel here.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So there was a gigantic comics news.
Speaker 0: I don't know if we've talked about it on the show.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure we haven't.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much the biggest comics news ever.
Speaker 0: DC Comics is going to relaunch.
Speaker 0: Some people are saying reboot, but the official word is relaunch.
Speaker 1: That's the distinction.
Speaker 1: there matters a lot to people who care.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: So about this is this is actually what is happening.
Speaker 0: They're going to.
Speaker 0: in a couple of months, every comic, every single DC comic will end.
Speaker 0: And instead, there will be fifty two new DC comics that will all be number one in the same month.
Speaker 0: And those will be the DC Comics.
Speaker 0: There'll be fifty two of them.
Speaker 0: They will start with number one all over again.
Speaker 0: The thing is, it's a relaunch.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know, they're restarting, but they're not completely restarting right from nothing.
Speaker 0: But they're sort of restarting.
Speaker 0: So it's like theoretically, if you've never read the comic before, you should be able to read this comic.
Speaker 0: But that's not like they're throwing all the history away in the incinerator.
Speaker 0: At the same time, they're doing something else.
Speaker 0: And I'm not even going to bother talking about like which titles or who's drawing and writing which ones.
Speaker 0: The only one that I think is a big deal is the Jeff Johns, who I hate, and Jim Lee, who I like, are doing Justice League, which I think is like the big one.
Speaker 0: they're trying to push.
Speaker 0: But anyway, they're going to also make every comic digital available on the same exact day that it's available on the newsstand.
Speaker 1: Oh, shit, son.
Speaker 0: For the same price.
Speaker 0: But there's no more details than that.
Speaker 0: There's probably going to be all sorts of DRM and whatever.
Speaker 1: This would have been a stupid idea a long time ago, but there are enough iPads and high resolution phones out to where you can look at color images like that and do OK.
Speaker 0: But anyway, and then like a couple of weeks after the comic comes out, it's going to go down from because the comics are going to be three dollars and so with the digital ones.
Speaker 0: But a couple of weeks when the comic becomes old, the digital one will go down in price to two dollars.
Speaker 0: So this is like it's.
Speaker 0: it's yet another example.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Of comic, you know, company that is was didn't update his business model for the digital age when it should have in nineteen ninety nine.
Speaker 0: It's currently twenty eleven.
Speaker 0: They're they're, you know, eleven years, twelve years too late.
Speaker 0: But most companies, the mistake they make is they dip the toe in the water.
Speaker 0: They say, oh, it didn't work.
Speaker 0: And they pull the toe out of the wall.
Speaker 1: You realize the reason they do this is not because they're incompetent on that front, they're incompetent, but not in this specific way.
Speaker 1: It's not like they think these forays into the digital world, these toe dippings are going to work.
Speaker 1: They know they're going to fail.
Speaker 1: They're engineered to fail.
Speaker 1: They set them up to where they tip in a little bit and then it fails.
Speaker 1: And they can go back to all the people who matter and say, look, it doesn't work.
Speaker 1: Nobody can do this.
Speaker 1: And they're trying to make sure that nobody ever does it except steam.
Speaker 0: iTunes all do it just fine.
Speaker 1: What superhero comics are doing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But but anyway, the point is this.
Speaker 0: I got to commend them while simultaneously admonishing them.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I commend them because this is not a toe dip.
Speaker 0: This is a foot dip.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Or maybe a down to the knee.
Speaker 0: It's like maybe you're sitting on the edge of the pool and you put both feet in and you're you're thinking about sliding off the edge.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it's like they're making a bigger move for the modern world than anyone has ever done before.
Speaker 0: They're resetting everything to number one.
Speaker 0: That's you know, I like that.
Speaker 0: Making the comics more accessible, if not completely accessible.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They're making it digital, available on the same day.
Speaker 0: That's all great.
Speaker 0: But I can still have to admonish them because it's not far enough.
Speaker 0: Here's what they should do.
Speaker 0: Ready?
Speaker 0: Number one, forget about the frickin issues entirely.
Speaker 0: Only digital comics.
Speaker 1: They should try it out now.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: Because they're going to make money off of it from the nerd trades only.
Speaker 1: Why not just make the money off the nerds?
Speaker 1: It doesn't cost you anything to do.
Speaker 1: It's just guaranteed profit.
Speaker 0: Because they don't make that much money off the nerds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they make something.
Speaker 1: The other the other rationale they probably will come up with is that that would end all comic book stores.
Speaker 0: That's a tough shipper.
Speaker 0: That doesn't matter to DC.
Speaker 0: This is already crushing the comic book stores, because every single person who switches away from comics to digital is now giving their three dollars directly to DC, bypassing the retailer.
Speaker 0: This already really hurts comic book stores.
Speaker 1: I don't think it does, because the primary audience currently of comic books are people who buy them because they're collecting.
Speaker 0: But then why the reset to number one?
Speaker 0: Clearly, that is an appeal to the masses.
Speaker 1: It is, perhaps, but I don't know how successful it will be.
Speaker 0: And plus resetting to number one like this.
Speaker 0: If you look online at the sort of the fan reactions on many forums, I've looked at two or three and I've looked at comment threads on a couple of comic news sites.
Speaker 0: It's really mixed.
Speaker 0: Like you can't even measure it.
Speaker 0: There's some people who are like, well, I'm done reading DC Comics now.
Speaker 0: And there's other people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: And then other people.
Speaker 1: Dude in your Green Lantern underwear and Green Lantern sheets, who has every Green Lantern ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is what drove you to quit.
Speaker 1: I'm sure.
Speaker 0: But you know, the thing is, you'd be surprised.
Speaker 0: These people do actually, right?
Speaker 0: When Spider-Man...
Speaker 1: No, they don't.
Speaker 1: They keep buying it.
Speaker 0: No, you'd be surprised when Spider-Man had that thing a while ago where they took away, where they, you know, revealed who he was and then unrevealed who he was.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The sales on Spider-Man, there are tons of fanboys stopped buying it and other people started buying it.
Speaker 0: It was like this big shift.
Speaker 0: And it's like, you know, the new people are going to come in and start reading it and other people are going to stop reading it.
Speaker 0: And there are the fanboys who keep reading it no matter what.
Speaker 0: But there are a lot of half fanboys who, you know, they can, they change what they do.
Speaker 0: Maybe they'll stop buying one comic, start buying another.
Speaker 0: You know, they're buying, they're going to buy a comic.
Speaker 0: But what comic they buy is up in the air, right?
Speaker 1: I do think the loser in all this in the long run, though, will be the comic book stores.
Speaker 0: Oh, definitely.
Speaker 0: Comic book stores lose no matter what.
Speaker 1: The thing is, comic book stores and gaming stores are in the same boot.
Speaker 1: In that boat.
Speaker 1: Das Boot.
Speaker 1: In that neither one of them is getting the presence it used to, partly because people are buying stuff online.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't buy board games digitally.
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 1: Amazon is cheaper than any gaming store I've ever been into.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: What if, you know, if Wii U was something that you were going to buy?
Speaker 0: We'll talk about Wii U and some Tuesday in the future.
Speaker 1: Oh, Wii U.
Speaker 0: And what if there were actual real board games on Wii U?
Speaker 0: Would that hurt sales of physical board games?
Speaker 1: See, it's hard to say because that's just an example.
Speaker 1: Because board games are kind of the same thing as comics.
Speaker 1: The people who care about European style, you know, hardcore German board games are the same kind of nerd, like the same type as the hardcore comic book fans.
Speaker 0: All I'm saying is that if they don't want any admonishment from Scott Rubin, what they have to do is they have to make the reset an actual reset.
Speaker 0: Throw away all of the history of all of the superheroes and never, ever, ever, ever go back to it.
Speaker 0: Make it completely gone, set on fire.
Speaker 0: Not, OK, we'll change the costumes and we'll change some things and keep it familiar.
Speaker 0: No, get rid of it entirely.
Speaker 0: So it never comes back.
Speaker 0: Number two thing they have to do to remove all admonishment.
Speaker 0: Don't charge me three dollars for a fucking digital comic.
Speaker 0: Netflix pricing, right?
Speaker 0: At the current pricing, three dollars a comic.
Speaker 1: Oh, duh.
Speaker 1: If there was a Netflix of comics, you just subscribe to Spider-Man for twelve bucks a year or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: For even if I wait and buy these digital comics at two dollars each.
Speaker 0: Fuck it.
Speaker 0: If they have fifty two titles, I would pay ten bucks a month, one hundred and twenty dollars a year.
Speaker 0: If that meant that I could read every DC comic ever, whenever I wanted it, any device ever with no DRMs, I would pay one hundred and twenty dollars a year.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: I'm paying them zero right now.
Speaker 0: That's one hundred and twenty.
Speaker 1: I'd go a little further.
Speaker 0: It doesn't cost them anything because they're only giving me digital copies, which cost them nothing.
Speaker 0: Now, if I were that many people would pay that one hundred and twenty dollars, I guarantee at least a million people would pay one hundred and twenty dollars a year.
Speaker 0: That's a hundred and twenty million dollars a year.
Speaker 1: And I would basically what I would do is, you know, the new comics, I'll go into this, but I'd make the price a little a lot higher, maybe double, triple, but I'd sell it on digitizing the entire backlog and putting all of those up for free.
Speaker 0: See, I was just talking one hundred and twenty dollars a year for starting at these number ones.
Speaker 0: If you're going to give me the entire history of DC Comics, all the way back to Action Comics number one or even earlier and all the new stuff, I pay two, three hundred a year.
Speaker 0: If that meant always have all the access to everything forever, you know, like that forever, forever.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Unless I don't pay my three hundred dollars, then you can cut me off.
Speaker 0: But you know the point.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But yeah, they need to do that.
Speaker 0: Then I'll be impressed.
Speaker 1: So speaking of comic book shops being driven out of business, Kevin Smith wants to do something and I'm going to quote the article.
Speaker 0: He owns some comic shops, doesn't he?
Speaker 1: So he wants to do, and it looks like he is doing, they did a casting call.
Speaker 1: Everything's pretty much going along.
Speaker 1: Reality show.
Speaker 0: You mean game show?
Speaker 1: About a comic book store.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: What's it about?
Speaker 1: The day to day goings on of a comic book store.
Speaker 0: Oh, so it's not.
Speaker 0: it is actually a reality show.
Speaker 0: It's just going to be like, watch what happens in this comic book store.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Watch what happens in this comic book store.
Speaker 1: Now, I can I can spoil the first season of this because I've been in comic book stores.
Speaker 1: It's mostly very quiet.
Speaker 0: But but the thing is, it's going to be his comic book store probably.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Which is actually a pretty nice shop.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like, yeah, it's sort of like Midtown Comics.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's very nice.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Or Forbidden Planet.
Speaker 1: You've been to Midtown Comics.
Speaker 1: What's usually going on in there?
Speaker 1: It's quiet and there's like 20 nerds looking at stuff quietly.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But the thing is, because this is going to be a TV show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're going to get.
Speaker 1: they're going to get personalities in there and they're going to get them to argue about stuff and do, you know.
Speaker 0: Plus, nerds will go in there intentionally thinking they're going to be on TV.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 0: And when this event's like a free comic book day, stuff will happen.
Speaker 1: I'm just I'm not there.
Speaker 0: Imagine gathering tournaments.
Speaker 1: I'm not feeling this too much.
Speaker 0: Plus, they're going to stage a lot of things to happen in there.
Speaker 0: You know, they'll have creators coming to do signings and they'll be.
Speaker 0: they'll talk to people, you know, they'll.
Speaker 0: they'll interview people about what they're buying.
Speaker 0: You could you could do this for 12 episodes, I think.
Speaker 1: The thing is, this would be better off not being on TV, being a YouTube show.
Speaker 0: Actually, there is a web comic if I written by a guy who works in a comic shop.
Speaker 0: And basically whenever a customer says something really stupid, he makes a like a one or one panel or three panel comic of whatever stupid thing the customer said.
Speaker 0: It is hilarious.
Speaker 0: I forget what it is, but I'm going to try to find it and get a link out there.
Speaker 0: But that is what the the reality show should be.
Speaker 0: If you show all the moronic customers saying stupid shit like they say in that comic, that'll be a winner because to actually see the people's faces and to see them saying that while the camera's pointed at them.
Speaker 0: That's awesome.
Speaker 0: That would double the hilarity.
Speaker 0: And the comic is already literally, laugh out loud, hilarious.
Speaker 1: Now, to quote the article, because this really sums up what this is all about.
Speaker 1: I'm just quoting the last sentence here.
Speaker 1: Regardless, it'll be nice to see Smith pushes boundaries and get out of his comfort zone by finally doing a project centering on a couple of dudes making pop culture references.
Speaker 1: So I got one more little thing that I just happen to see.
Speaker 1: You know, there's this whole foreskin circumcision debate going on, San Diego campaign to ban it and whatever.
Speaker 0: But I'm indifferent on that whole issue.
Speaker 0: I abstain.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm not indifferent.
Speaker 1: I'm actually yeah, I'm torn.
Speaker 0: I abstain.
Speaker 1: I'm ambivalent, but weakly ambivalent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because ambivalent implies, you know, ambivalent that I've got like you like you could be ambivalent by having two very powerful opposing opinions that you can't reconcile.
Speaker 1: But in this case, I'm ambivalent in that I have like one weak argument for and like one weak argument against.
Speaker 0: I've got I've got like medium arguments on both sides and they're not.
Speaker 0: they're not principles that I hold very close to, like far away principles.
Speaker 1: So I noticed this article is anti circumcision comic, anti Semitic.
Speaker 1: There's a comic force within it, so there's a comic foreskin man.
Speaker 1: that's about this debate.
Speaker 1: I was going to fight to save people's foreskin.
Speaker 1: And this article, you know, I just saw that like the headline and I saw like a first sentence or so of it and I'm like, all right, probably not.
Speaker 1: It's probably just pro foreskin and someone's making a leap that, yeah, because a Jewish tradition is to circumcise boys, that obviously it's anti Semitic.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: And I was going to brush it off.
Speaker 1: So then I click on the article and you know what's on the cover of the second one.
Speaker 1: So here's foreskin man, Aryan, beautiful, blonde hair, chiseled behind him is what I can only describe as the stereotypical Jew with horrible razor blades ready to circumcise a baby against the wishes of the mother.
Speaker 1: And there's like the Jewish Hasidic mafia behind him.
Speaker 0: So it is.
Speaker 0: Then why is there even a?
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, usually when the title of the article is is X anti Semitic, you expect to see something that's questionable.
Speaker 1: like if a headline ever says is X, Y, that headline is bullshit and that article is bullshit.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: But the point is, is except in this case with a headline like that, you would think it would be a questionable situation.
Speaker 0: It's like it's like, huh, is this gay?
Speaker 0: And you open it up and the show tunes and penises and, you know, it's like, gee, no, I don't know.
Speaker 0: But now look at this picture.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 1: OK, it's it's pretty great.
Speaker 1: So I'll leave it at that.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: This comic probably is a little anti Semitic.
Speaker 0: The name of the web comic about the comic book shop, which is still updated as recently as today, is called Our Valued Customers and I will link to it.
Speaker 1: So things of the day, it's, you know, summer.
Speaker 1: ish.
Speaker 1: This is right around that time of year when a lot of high school seniors and people like that skip school to go to amusement parks, ride some roller coasters.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And I thought we'd done a show on roller coasters.
Speaker 0: I thought we did also.
Speaker 1: I could not find it after like 10 minutes of digging around our listeners.
Speaker 0: Go tell us if we did one.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling it might have been a show you recorded and did not post.
Speaker 1: That's possible.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or the search is broken.
Speaker 0: Less likely.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, you know, we were talking to in the forum recently about geekeries that you grow out of.
Speaker 1: And there's a whole debate there.
Speaker 1: But one geekery I kind of grew out of, partly just because I am an adult and have access to much more exciting and worldly things because I have more money.
Speaker 1: But when I was a kid, you know, middle school, high school, I was a suit like I would consider myself a roller coaster nerd.
Speaker 1: Like I knew the intimate motherfucking details about roller coasters.
Speaker 1: You take me to Cedar Point.
Speaker 1: I can tell you when the roller coasters were built.
Speaker 1: I can tell you about like, well, that's technically, you know, that's a wooden looking coaster, but technically it's a steel coaster because the rails are like this.
Speaker 1: And yeah, so really into roller coasters.
Speaker 1: And I was looking around online trying to figure out, like, all right, it's been about a decade since I've ridden a real roller coaster.
Speaker 0: You got to go to international roller coaster database.
Speaker 1: Except for that one roller coaster we rode that one year in Wildwood, which was OK.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean, it was OK for not having ridden a roller coaster in a long time.
Speaker 1: It was like a three out of 10 roller coaster that got a plus five bonus for the fact that I had ridden a roller coaster in half a decade.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And minus one hundred bonus from costing ten bucks to ride one minus another one, because remember that year that was when I had Lyme disease and didn't know it yet.
Speaker 1: So I had a wicked headache the whole time.
Speaker 0: It's only minus one, but the ten bucks was more minus.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Ten bucks back then meant a lot to me.
Speaker 1: So my thing of the day is a POV of what I consider to this day, there may be a better roller coaster, at least a better contiguous roller coaster.
Speaker 0: The best roller coaster you've ridden.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Now, I argue this partly because people have made taller and faster roller coasters, but this is a contiguous closed circuit steel coaster as opposed to the kind of BS cheating coaster that's really big, but basically shoots you up one big thing and over it.
Speaker 1: And that's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, it's sort of like, you know, it's like a drag, you know, some cars.
Speaker 0: It's funny.
Speaker 0: Isn't the name of that real dragster drag?
Speaker 0: It's like a drag racing car.
Speaker 0: It's like let's make a car that goes straight really fast.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 0: But it can't turn.
Speaker 0: An F1 car is much more impressive, right?
Speaker 0: Even though it might not have a top speed as high as the drag car, it can turn and it's useful.
Speaker 1: But there are many different styles of roller coasters and like wooden coasters and steel coasters and different kinds of steel, whatever.
Speaker 1: But the Millennium Force at Cedar Point is a particular kind of steel coaster.
Speaker 1: A similar coasters would be like the Magnum XL 200, which was also at Cedar Point.
Speaker 1: The steel coaster that has one very tall, very straight hill, and then it has a lot of very high up and downs, not doesn't go upside down and a lot of turn left and rights.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But usually the turn left and right is minimized.
Speaker 1: And the biggest thing is it'll have like three huge hills and rapid succession.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe it's a combination of hills and turns and banked turns.
Speaker 1: Their primary benefits are high top speed, coupled with very strong sideways and top wise Gs, especially at the peak of the second hill of a coaster like this, you'll pretty much like if you don't have your seatbelt on, you're dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Those are my favorite types of roller coasters, hands down.
Speaker 1: Because now I used to be, you know, it's too bad there's no YouTube.
Speaker 0: I actually want a really good one.
Speaker 0: It's not as high or as fast, but there is a Superman roller coaster at Six Flags New England.
Speaker 1: I've heard Superman's OK.
Speaker 0: It is it is quite good.
Speaker 0: It's about 100 feet less than the Millennium Force.
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: the Millennium Force has been voted so many times by various kind of international and national roller coaster organizations as the best steel coaster in the world that I find it hard for anyone to argue to me that there is, in fact, a better roller coaster, at least a better contiguous closed loop steel rail coaster, which
Speaker 0: is my favorite kind.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: So the Millennium Force POV, if anyone knows of a better coaster, I dare you to tell me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are higher there.
Speaker 0: Look at this.
Speaker 0: But they do not have as much action.
Speaker 1: When this was built, it was the tallest and fastest roller coaster in the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And when it was built, its third peak, the third highest part of it was taller than the Magnum XL two hundred's highest peak.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a pretty damn good coaster is to this day the longest steel roller coaster in the world as well.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I got a really good thing today.
Speaker 0: You do?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's hockey related.
Speaker 0: So we tend to look down on people who are sort of the drunken frat guys.
Speaker 1: Only because, you know, the only reason I ever looked down on someone like that because you're fucking loud.
Speaker 0: But they're also pretty much the opposite of geeks.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But at least these guys, how do you know they're not geeks like they're really into how you know, they're not at home with like three different red solo cups, like training and practicing because beer pong.
Speaker 0: If this game of beer pong odds are one guy is actually a beer pong geek and the other guys are just want to get drunk.
Speaker 0: And, you know, you could be a getting drunk geek, but you know what?
Speaker 0: If you're doing it with Bud Light, you're not a getting drunk geek.
Speaker 1: No, you're getting drunk geek, but you're not a beer geek.
Speaker 0: That's like saying you're a video game geek and all you ever play is Mario.
Speaker 1: You're not even getting drunk geek because getting drunk geeks know that Vodak is the way to go.
Speaker 0: I know that.
Speaker 0: Or perhaps gin.
Speaker 0: The point is, here is an epic tale of some hockey Canadian hockey geeks who are fans of the Vancouver Canucks.
Speaker 0: This is one of the most epic tales I've ever read.
Speaker 0: It involves, I'm not going to tell you the story because then what's the point?
Speaker 0: You have to read it for yourself to get the full effect.
Speaker 0: But it involves, right, a one thousand mile road trip from Vancouver to L.A.
Speaker 0: to see a hockey game or San Jose to see a hockey game.
Speaker 0: Sorry.
Speaker 0: The Sharks and Jose getting so drunk, you end up in the hospital drinking some of those alcoholic beverages with the owner of the Canucks and his hot ladies going back to Vancouver, escaping the hospital and many other epic things happening.
Speaker 0: It is so epic and it's all true.
Speaker 0: One hundred percent true photo evidence, not Snopes, not bullshit.
Speaker 0: It really happened, as is told in this article.
Speaker 0: One hundred percent.
Speaker 0: I confirmed it.
Speaker 0: It's for real.
Speaker 0: It's awesome.
Speaker 1: It's the kind of thing that you'd see in a movie and you would be like, oh, that's a stupid movie.
Speaker 1: It's like contrived.
Speaker 0: Similar things have happened to us.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like, oh, remember that, you know, when we were driving back from Otacon and we needed to get off the highway in the dark to get gas, you know, and like, this is like one of those stories times a hundred.
Speaker 1: Our midget hookers playing settlers really doesn't even come close.
Speaker 0: It's like that times 20.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's that awesome.
Speaker 0: So check out this story of epic epicness.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment, the Geek Nights Book Club book is still Isaac Asimov's foundation.
Speaker 1: The unofficial book club book is still all of the R. Scout Backer, Prince of Nothing books.
Speaker 1: We will not be at Otacon because they didn't invite us back.
Speaker 1: So you can tell them if you want us to be there.
Speaker 1: PEX will be at Connecticut is coming up.
Speaker 1: We'll be there running the panel's department.
Speaker 0: E-commerce room.
Speaker 1: that's coming along.
Speaker 0: We're pretty sure.
Speaker 0: you said you were going to mail the things tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, and the only new update on the e-commerce is that we're almost out of shirts.
Speaker 0: But I thought you said after a previous show that you were going to mail something the following day.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Did you do that?
Speaker 0: Oh, OK.
Speaker 0: What do you?
Speaker 1: that's why it's not a news.
Speaker 0: I'm just verifying that you mailed like you said you would.
Speaker 0: There was a non shit talk.
Speaker 0: That is a news when it comes to RIV.
Speaker 0: A non shit talk.
Speaker 0: Oh, my gosh.
Speaker 1: Speaking of non shit talks, you might have noticed we launched a new spin off front row.
Speaker 1: Crew geek night show called Radio Free Equestria.
Speaker 1: It is about nothing but my little pony friendship is magic and the intimate Gandalf girthings that are going on there in.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I think it's a pretty good show, actually, and it's going to go up pretty much weekly for a while, at least pilots.
Speaker 0: Brony seemed to like it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well, I was I was worried.
Speaker 0: I was you know, I didn't know what the reaction was going to be, but Brony's actually were excited for more.
Speaker 0: I was like, really?
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 1: The reaction was pretty overwhelming, actually.
Speaker 0: From Brony's.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't know about normal people.
Speaker 1: We have more list, more viewers of this at its start than geek nights had for like the first year.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, it's it's a targeted community effort.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We got to do more targeted community efforts.
Speaker 0: Well, that was always the strategy.
Speaker 0: We just haven't found enough communities that are ripe for targeting.
Speaker 1: So to put another thing out there, like I said before, there is a another a third thing that we are working on.
Speaker 1: I don't know when it'll be up, but it's it's coming.
Speaker 1: We have a third show unrelated to ponies and not directly related to geek nights that will also be on YouTube.
Speaker 1: So keep an eye out on my YouTube channel, Geek Nights Rim.
Speaker 1: So we got two shows for you, but one of them we haven't seen a lot of.
Speaker 1: And we're going to talk about fairly briefly, just because it's something kind of different and cute and neat.
Speaker 1: And we're always a big fan of those kind of short, cute anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're big on the the animes that are, you know, made up a lot of short tiny episodes like Damakoto and such, because it doesn't take that much effort to watch them.
Speaker 0: And if you have a short attention span, you can totally burn through it really quick.
Speaker 0: And, you know, risky safety really got us hooked.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So Hippyra, the little vampire, or I guess vampire.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not.
Speaker 0: You know, I know vampires are a thing lately, but it, you know, which sort of, you know, it's annoying like, oh, another vampire thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're mad because someone else likes something.
Speaker 1: This bothers you that someone else is a fan of something.
Speaker 0: No, I'm just saying it's like, you know, when they're seen, there was like a zombie.
Speaker 1: Vampires were cool before other people were into.
Speaker 0: No, I'm just saying there was a zombie glut and then there was a vampire glut.
Speaker 0: And it's and it's like, well, you would you would think, oh, it's.
Speaker 0: you think, right, maybe if there's another when any new thing comes out during a glut.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it wasn't the thing that inspired the glut or kicked it off like Walking Dead kicked off the zombie glut.
Speaker 0: But so a lot of other things just came in from the side.
Speaker 0: And it's like, OK, obviously you didn't put a lot of effort into this.
Speaker 0: You're just trying to ride the wave.
Speaker 0: So you would think a new vampire thing coming out in a vampire glut is just trying to ride the wave.
Speaker 0: But you'd be skeptical that it actually has merit.
Speaker 1: There's one thing that makes this kind of stand out, a little one tidbit that you might not notice.
Speaker 1: The story is done by one Katsuhiro Otomo.
Speaker 0: Oh, the Akira guy?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Akira guy.
Speaker 0: Yes, he just wrote the story, though he didn't animate it or anything else.
Speaker 1: It was directed by some other guy, not a huge cast of people working on it, because it's a short, cute little show about a little vampire boy in a place where the sun never rises.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically it's.
Speaker 0: it's a vampire town named like Salta.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And he's a cute little vampire guy.
Speaker 0: He lives in the cute little vampire town.
Speaker 0: All the little vampires.
Speaker 1: He has a friend that's a soul because one of his one of the adults in the village collected hundreds of thousands of human souls and tried to mash them together into something he could bite so he could go to hell, because hell is heaven for vampires.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: And he fucked it up.
Speaker 1: And one little leg of his soul popped out and is hanging around with Hippy Ra.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And there's not much else to say.
Speaker 1: It's just kind of cute, goonie.
Speaker 0: And yeah, it's not.
Speaker 0: it's usually the shows that are really short like this have just really intense, strong jokes.
Speaker 0: They they come hitting hard with the comedy nonstop because they've only got like five minutes.
Speaker 1: This is more slice of life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is a little quieter.
Speaker 1: I guess slice of death.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, undeath.
Speaker 0: But it's like cute, funny.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And all the funniness is just like seeing how the cute vampire world works.
Speaker 0: It's like, oh, I got myself some blood orange juice.
Speaker 0: It's like, lol, blood orange juice.
Speaker 0: OK, it's cute.
Speaker 0: Oh, we got to take biting lessons in school.
Speaker 1: I love taking biting lessons.
Speaker 0: You know, it's stuff like that.
Speaker 1: It's not like or like the subway pulls up and there's some people sitting and then there's some people who are bats hanging from the straps.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's all environmental.
Speaker 0: Like what would happen in a friendly vampire town?
Speaker 0: Funny.
Speaker 0: It's not like Domic Adobutu where they come hitting hard with drunk unicorns.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Drunk unicorns.
Speaker 1: It's just sort of, you know, someone's got to mash up My Little Pony and Domic Adobutu.
Speaker 0: Not a bad choice.
Speaker 0: But anyway, you know, the show is really short.
Speaker 0: It's all CG, but it's pretty good.
Speaker 0: But the download, the quality of the downloads hurts it quite a bit.
Speaker 0: You have to find in higher resolution downloads than we had.
Speaker 0: But then again, the Mac Mini was pretty weak.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Cor Solo.
Speaker 1: You can find it.
Speaker 1: It's cute.
Speaker 1: But our main topic tonight is the thing that, you know, after ponies ended in the Fur Roku forum, there's about how many thousand posts in that thread.
Speaker 1: But there's one other thread that's been kind of plugging along.
Speaker 1: There's like a hundred posts in it about wakfu.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, hey, there's a show that I've never heard of that has all these posts in a thread.
Speaker 0: I mean, maybe it's worth checking out.
Speaker 1: On Geek Nights a while ago, because I've been watching it with Emily and I've seen a decent amount of it.
Speaker 0: I've seen three or four episodes.
Speaker 1: It's OK.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, like people made a thread about it.
Speaker 0: So I said, oh, I got to check that out to see what the deal is.
Speaker 0: So I checked it out and I was like, you know, I was like, well, it wasn't bad.
Speaker 0: But why are people getting so incredibly excited about it?
Speaker 1: Are they getting so incredibly excited about it?
Speaker 1: I don't think they are.
Speaker 1: I think they're excited about it at the same level that, say, people are like when we're watching Slayers way back.
Speaker 1: We just, oh, let's watch some more Slayers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Slayers is way better than wakfu.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're similar genre at least.
Speaker 0: They are similar in genre.
Speaker 1: Is one of those like might as well be a game?
Speaker 1: Oh, well, it is a game, but we'll skip that for now.
Speaker 1: It's basically a generic JRPG style plot of a hero and his party going on adventures in a world that is surprisingly video game like.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So here's the deal.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: There was a game called Dofus, which is a Flash based MMO.
Speaker 1: It's the thing that Scott never noticed at all the gaming cons.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And then.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And that Dofus game had some sort of world that they created for.
Speaker 0: So Wakfu was another.
Speaker 0: It was basically Wakfu is an MMO Final Fantasy Tactics game.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That was in the same world as Dofus.
Speaker 0: So there's a video game that created a world.
Speaker 0: Then there was another video game, Wakfu, that took place in the same world.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So he's the same universe for two video games.
Speaker 0: And then what we're talking about today is an animated series based on.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The Wakfu game, which is placed in the same world as the Dofus game.
Speaker 0: So the first season of 26 episodes began airing in '08, according to Wikipedia, and new episodes continued into January 2010.
Speaker 0: And it's French.
Speaker 0: That's the thing.
Speaker 0: is all this stuff is French.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The video games, all this stuff were made by French people.
Speaker 0: I think Square Enix actually is helping them publish.
Speaker 0: All of the production for the TV show was done in Flash in France, except for I think two episodes are done in Japan, whatever that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Isn't that important?
Speaker 0: But yeah.
Speaker 0: And they're coming out with a season two.
Speaker 0: So the thing that's really impressive about the show is that it's all done in Flash.
Speaker 0: My Little Pony is also all done in Flash, but My Little Pony looks really impressive.
Speaker 0: Wakfu, if you just look at still shots, looks way more impressive than My Little Pony.
Speaker 0: It's like you look at My Little Pony and you're like, oh, my God, that's the best thing, the highest quality Flash animation I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: But Wakfu is even better, except for the fact that he's personally, while the art and visual imagery is way better than ponies.
Speaker 0: I actually think the animation, the movement is a little jerky.
Speaker 1: Well, there's two things going on, because I've noticed it's like 50/50 some aspects of the animation, especially when there's some sort of CG thing like flying by action, action, super well animated.
Speaker 1: But when when a character is like turned into another character to talk, it's it's like they they're like it's almost like stop motion like it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's strange, like for action scenes or fighting or casting magic spells or anything like that.
Speaker 0: The animation is super awesome.
Speaker 0: And it's like, whoa, this is really done in Flash.
Speaker 0: You shitting me, right?
Speaker 0: You'd expect them to use, you know, whatever they use for like, you know, all the other digitally animated shows.
Speaker 1: But Flash is surprisingly used more often than you think.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but when somebody is just sitting there talking like their head, it moves in weird sort of jerky ways.
Speaker 1: Well, it moves exactly the way you see characters move in JRPGs.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Or the way that like people move in like old crappy FMV's and old PlayStation video games or really old CG movies that were done really poorly before technology was good.
Speaker 0: And, you know, but it's only the movement like the character still looks amazing.
Speaker 0: It's just the movement of the character in the scenes where they're just talking is often kind of weird.
Speaker 0: It's almost like uncanny valley, but not I don't know.
Speaker 1: So it follows the plot of a young boy named Hugo, who has the portal gun in his hands.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And is the descendant of dragons or something.
Speaker 1: We don't know what the deal is, but it opens.
Speaker 0: He's the magical mystery dude.
Speaker 1: There's.
Speaker 1: there's definitely some homage because the whole show opens right with like a flash of magic in this village, this random village and this lone wolf and cub looking duo walks out of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Just guy who looks super dangerous pushing a carriage with a baby in it.
Speaker 1: And something attacks him and he totally kicks its ass because he's lone wolf.
Speaker 1: I guess he's a dragon.
Speaker 1: And the thing that attacks him is like, oh, he's so full of walk through.
Speaker 1: I want to eat it.
Speaker 0: You know, walk through is like the generic life energy that everyone, you know, the bad guys want to collect.
Speaker 0: And, you know, as an aside, this show and the bad guy is some sort of walk through powered robot who can travel.
Speaker 1: Definitely some sort of precursor technology situation going on in this world.
Speaker 1: I love shit like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But there's this maybe magic tech.
Speaker 1: They like the Prince of Nothing has a lot of proper nouns, made up gobbledygook, proper noun.
Speaker 1: that's just there.
Speaker 1: You know, that's high, don't you?
Speaker 0: And then, you know, the difference between the nursery and the in the in the Keonene Beach of a wookie chigra.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But and I understand more French than I expected watching this because it's in French and French is something I studied in like high school.
Speaker 1: And at RIT.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I'm hampered by the fact that they use a lot of silly made up proper nouns.
Speaker 0: And, you know, I've noticed a lot of them are very Marduk and Gardakhan.
Speaker 0: Have you noticed that?
Speaker 1: Marduk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they are.
Speaker 0: That's hilarious for me because of because of that other the names to Princess Amalia Charan-Charmes.
Speaker 1: Sir Sedleygrove Persedal.
Speaker 0: And Senor Gardakhan.
Speaker 0: Rubillax and Boba Fett.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but yeah, the thing is, you know, it's not it's.
Speaker 0: you know, it's not bad.
Speaker 0: It's like, hey, it's it's a fantasy plot, right?
Speaker 0: It's fun.
Speaker 1: It's cute.
Speaker 1: The main character totally just goes for it.
Speaker 0: But it's so generic in its fantasy plot.
Speaker 0: Is it like?
Speaker 0: it doesn't have anything special that makes it stand out above all the other JRPG fantasy plots in the universe.
Speaker 1: Characters are all fun.
Speaker 1: Like I like the individual characters, but they're not great characters, at least not yet.
Speaker 1: I've seen a lot of episodes, but it doesn't grab me as much as other things have grabbed me.
Speaker 0: It's like what makes this JRPG story better or different than a JRPG story from any Dragon Quest, Final Fantasy, Valkyrie profile, Xenogears, Chrono Trigger story?
Speaker 1: Of course, it does get points for being very JRPG.
Speaker 1: Like early on when they're good, they go to the shop to try to buy a, quote, world map.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the map is pretty cool.
Speaker 1: And actually, I like that episode because one, the cat girl and her husband were pretty funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were right.
Speaker 1: And while the twist at the end was pretty obvious at the same time.
Speaker 0: It was Captain Obvious.
Speaker 1: It was also kind of funny.
Speaker 0: It was OK.
Speaker 1: Though the way it resolved at the end when he's like, how do you think I'm going to keep getting stuff for the shop?
Speaker 1: And she's like, darling.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the thing is, it's not, you know, it's like.
Speaker 0: it's not like ecstatically funny.
Speaker 0: It's just sort of like ha ha funny, you know, a little bit ha ha.
Speaker 0: It's not like.
Speaker 0: it's not like, oh, my God, I need to watch more of this so bad.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That's how you know.
Speaker 0: when something's good is when you absolutely cannot resist watching the next one.
Speaker 1: I know I often forget that, like because I watched.
Speaker 1: there's this era from like 2003, 2004, when there was we were watching a lot of kind of generic anime because we almost felt obligated to, you know, anime club and everything like scryed and all that shit.
Speaker 1: And I just remember I'd be watching like a lot of anime and it'd be like, it's sure like, oh, no, I'll watch one more episode, then I'll go do something real and something actually fun.
Speaker 1: And then not that long ago, we were hanging out at someone's house a few years ago and maybe a year ago.
Speaker 1: And someone there hadn't seen Cowboy Bebop.
Speaker 1: So like, oh, just put on the first couple episodes.
Speaker 1: And then I thought, oh, I'll half ignore it because I've seen Cowboy Bebop three times.
Speaker 1: I'll just play a board game.
Speaker 1: Now, I watched every second of Cowboy Bebop and desperately wanted to watch all of it immediately.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, Hajime no Ippo, I started, you know, I picked it up because it was in my queue and I burned through it like, you know, I don't know, phosphoric sulfuric acid.
Speaker 1: My little pony, I watched as soon as I could.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: As soon as the new pony episode came out, I was desperate to go and watch it.
Speaker 0: You know, Full Metal Alchemist, when it was coming out, we did that.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: When Full Metal Alchemist was coming out, it was like the mad rush to see you could get it first.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, so that's how, you know, something's really good.
Speaker 0: Wakfu, I've watched a handful of episodes and really I would be just fine not watching any more ever.
Speaker 0: Like, if one was on, I would watch it.
Speaker 0: But it's not like.
Speaker 0: I don't have this desperate need to see more, which puts it, you know, it's like, well, I'll just go to.
Speaker 0: I'll definitely go to something else before I go to Wakfu.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Not that it's not bad, but it's just not.
Speaker 0: it's not great.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It doesn't stand out.
Speaker 0: It's not amazing.
Speaker 0: It's interesting.
Speaker 0: It's just another JRPG plot.
Speaker 1: You probably won't be happy.
Speaker 1: It gives me the same level of enjoyment as an individual episode of, say, Fist of the North Star.
Speaker 1: Individual episode for individual episode.
Speaker 1: Now, the overall enjoyment of Fist of the North Star is higher because there's this compounding as you watch more episodes.
Speaker 0: That is the thing.
Speaker 0: I think what Wakfu could have done to make me more interested, right, was to actually bring more heat on that initial plot.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Because it's that typical JRPG stuff where, you know, there's a hidden great power and we give you a hint of it at the beginning and then it's hidden away.
Speaker 0: And as the episodes go on, it won't be revealed until the very end.
Speaker 0: And then it will come back.
Speaker 0: You know, every JRPG does that.
Speaker 0: And it always bothers me.
Speaker 0: The worst one of those is Luffy.
Speaker 0: You ever play Luffy?
Speaker 1: I tried to play Luffy.
Speaker 0: At the very beginning of Luffy, you are right.
Speaker 0: The great, heroic, epic party of legend in your super high level.
Speaker 0: And you go and you play out basically the legend.
Speaker 0: It would be like if there was a pony RPG and level one was like, you are Celestia, use the elements of harmony to stop Nightmare Moon.
Speaker 0: And then as soon as you beat that first level, you're like the great, you know, descendant of that party's leader.
Speaker 0: And you're just some punk kid with nothing.
Speaker 0: And it's like, oh, what the fuck?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it takes until the end of the game to get back to the epic shit.
Speaker 0: It's like, give me something that's epic the whole goddamn time, asshole.
Speaker 0: See, look at Fist of the North Star.
Speaker 0: It's epic the whole time.
Speaker 0: You don't get to start, you don't see the nuclear war that much, but you see it's always Kenshiro and Kenshiro is the guy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's not like the real guy was Kenshiro's ancestor and Kenshiro is just sort of...
Speaker 1: See, you don't always need epic.
Speaker 1: Look at Cowboy Bebop.
Speaker 1: There's no epic plot.
Speaker 0: Look, I'm on heroin here.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Your methadone ain't going to work.
Speaker 0: I need that big shit all the time.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Don't give me the dragon in the first episode and then not give me the dragon in the fourth episode.
Speaker 1: I want more dragon stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, don't bring out the time shifting bad guy in episode one and two and then hide him away until later.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Bring him out.
Speaker 0: I want to, you know, let's see what he's up to.
Speaker 1: But seriously, like if you enjoy shows like Slayers or Goku-Do, you know, any of those...
Speaker 0: I think it's exactly equal to Goku-Do, I think.
Speaker 0: That's exactly right.
Speaker 1: Because Goku-Do was a little like it had his great moments, but overall it started to peter out.
Speaker 1: It wasn't quite as good as Slayers.
Speaker 1: And also, I got to qualify.
Speaker 1: I really like Slayers.
Speaker 1: It is a great show, but simultaneously has its problems.
Speaker 0: Slayers is not perfect.
Speaker 1: Slayers actually has a surprising amount of shounen style fighting Dragon Ball Z where people stand there going, "Oh, is he going to use this power?
Speaker 1: Is he going to use that
Speaker 1: power?".
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it doesn't last more than an episode.
Speaker 0: It's within the episode.
Speaker 1: And it always cuts to, you know, someone praying to Zormo Gooster.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Zormo Gooster.
Speaker 1: I love Zormo Gooster.
Speaker 1: The best guy.
Speaker 0: Zormo Gooster is better than all of Wakfu added together.
Speaker 1: Zormo Gooster is pretty much the god of the gods.
Speaker 0: Zormo Gooster could beat Kenshiro.
Speaker 1: Oh, easily.
Speaker 1: Easily.
Speaker 1: But Kenshiro could definitely beat Gov, the Demon Dragon King.
Speaker 0: Well, that's not even a contest.
Speaker 1: In fact, the Demon Dragon King, Gov, is already dead.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but yeah, if you're the kind of person, you know, because I know those people exist, where it's like you can't get enough of JRPGs.
Speaker 0: Like, a JRPG comes out and you just play it like crazy, you know, and you just get hooked into every old JRPG on the planet or anything with that kind of story.
Speaker 0: Or, you know.
Speaker 1: Or if you like procedural adventurer drama.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like if adventurers are going on a fantasy quest, you just really can't get enough of that.
Speaker 0: Then you can't get, then Wakfu is another one of those for you.
Speaker 0: And the best part is you don't have to press A to, you know, to fight random encounters.
Speaker 0: You just get the story part.
Speaker 0: The only, I think the real weakness of Wakfu is that the characters, they're okay, but they're not like, they're not really strong, you know?
Speaker 0: It's like, they have their personalities, right?
Speaker 0: But they're not strong personalities in one direction or another, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, this money guy, the main character is really, like, has no personality whatsoever.
Speaker 0: He's so nothing.
Speaker 0: You know, there's the, actually the best of the whole main characters is the little sword that the knight has to fight with.
Speaker 0: Oh, the shabu, I forget what the demons are called.
Speaker 0: The knight is pretty boring, but his sword is actually pretty cool.
Speaker 1: George just wants to fuck shit up, that's all he cares about.
Speaker 1: He's like, come on, come on, let me take over, it'll be fine.
Speaker 0: And the two princesses, you know, the princess and her assistant, it's like, they're all right.
Speaker 0: And they have, you know, they're, you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: But they're not, like, strong.
Speaker 0: Look at the ponies, the ponies are strong characters, right?
Speaker 0: It's like Twilight Sparkle, the nerd, right?
Speaker 1: Also the Jean Grey, but we'll talk about that later.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well that's why people always compare it to, like, Team Fortress 2, which also has the strong personalities in the characters, you know?
Speaker 0: And that's, you know, I guess that just works for me, when the characters are like that.
Speaker 0: How'd you mean if it was the same thing, right?
Speaker 1: Oh my god, I was looking for it.
Speaker 1: The best Gardakhan name in Wakafu is Grogologran.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: G-R-O-U-G-A-L-O-R-A-G-R-A-N.
Speaker 1: That's pretty great.
Speaker 0: It's Grogologran.
Speaker 1: Grogologran.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's even better than Gardakhan, or Marduk.
Speaker 1: Noximilian is pretty good, too.
Speaker 0: There's also, right underneath that, is Cabrock.
Speaker 0: Cabrock is very Marduk.
Speaker 1: You're looking at the Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: So are you.
Speaker 0: Master Goldtard, yeah.
Speaker 1: Breadnaught.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're done with this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're done with that.
Speaker 1: But, you know, it's a fine show.
Speaker 1: It's like a solid B. I'd say B- because I consider Scrap Princess to be a solid B. I have a pretty nice scale.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: I think it's equal to Scrap Princess.
Speaker 1: No, Scrap Princess is better.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Because Scrap Princess is a better animation.
Speaker 1: And I think better characters.
Speaker 1: And actually was a pretty great show.
Speaker 1: Except for the fact that Scrap Princess pulled the biggest "Let's figure it all out" at the end I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: Even worse than Paranoid Agent, which is a great show.
Speaker 0: I'll agree with your B- rating.
Speaker 1: Because Scrap Princess, the entire plot is revealed after the eye catch in the last episode.
Speaker 0: Not as bad as Alien 9.
Speaker 1: Where the big-?
Speaker 1: well, because Alien 9 was kind of like in media res.
Speaker 1: You gotta give it that.
Speaker 0: Uhhh... no.
Speaker 1: Plus, that wasn't even a plot.
Speaker 1: It was just, "Oh, if you happened to watch the credits, that poor girl
Speaker 1: died.".
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 0: By getting squished in a very Wicked City kind of way.
Speaker 1: Alien 9 is pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: I feel like we should watch it and review it.
Speaker 1: Because I haven't seen it since we used to hang out with Luke.
Speaker 0: I only saw it because I was in a room when someone else was watching it.
Speaker 1: Gaby was watching it and then we went to play board games.
Speaker 0: I didn't actually watch it.
Speaker 0: I was just in a room when it was being watched.
Speaker 1: I have a manga from it, too, laying around.
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 1: I don't know where I got it.
Speaker 0: I can't even remember this shit.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.