Speaker 1: It's Thursday, November 17th, 2011.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: Emily, and I talked about our trip to Japan.
Speaker 2: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: I guess we're back to kind of our normal schedule.
Speaker 2: I know it's bullshit because next week is gonna be Thanksgiving.
Speaker 1: ah shit, and then there's gonna be wait Monday Wednesday.
Speaker 1: We can do it.
Speaker 2: I'm just saying there's gonna be some mad holidays.
Speaker 1: I will manage unless I get sent to Turkey and then there's gonna be no geek nights for a while.
Speaker 2: well And then right so I'm off work from Christmas through mag fest.
Speaker 2: Oh, yeah, so I go into work until after mag fest once.
Speaker 1: so Scott What are you going to do in that time?
Speaker 2: shit talk?
Speaker 2: Perhaps some of it will actually be shit, but most of it talk.
Speaker 2: Yeah, read a lot of comic books play some other Zelda game.
Speaker 2: all we'll have by then got a Gundam model.
Speaker 1: So much like we'll save it.
Speaker 2: maybe I'll write a line of code or something.
Speaker 1: I'm waiting for Tuesday to talk about burning apocalypse con, but it was pretty fun.
Speaker 1: It was okay.
Speaker 1: It's only okay.
Speaker 2: I mean it wasn't like packs, but no one was.
Speaker 2: you know no one's saying it was.
Speaker 2: it was a completely different thing.
Speaker 1: I was in some pretty good games But the people who played in my game.
Speaker 2: I was in an excellent day game.
Speaker 1: all the game that I got bumped out of that I wanted to be as he was the best.
Speaker 2: you should have joined the horde.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I did join and I got bumped by someone who may have looked like you.
Speaker 0: It was me with my number one priority.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile in the first slot I actually had second priority But a table of people lied to me and said I had fourth and because I didn't have the schedule on me I didn't check.
Speaker 2: I actually printed the schedule beforehand.
Speaker 2: I went before going.
Speaker 2: I printed my own copy And I wrote on it my priorities for each Slot and I put checkmarks.
Speaker 2: and this is the games that look good.
Speaker 1: You know why I didn't do that?
Speaker 1: because the entire night before I was writing the game I was running and burning characters for it a free market.
Speaker 1: you require no writing Ah, but it was worth it because uh one of the players in my game.
Speaker 1: So it was the best game.
Speaker 1: They played all week.
Speaker 1: It probably was one of the better games Yeah And I was very happy that I turned a ton of people away from that game like it did.
Speaker 1: the priorities went way up way quick.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm The secret was I stole the entire game from Hyperion and the Prince of Nothing Steal from the Forgotten Masters, I started the game.
Speaker 2: I'm like he's told by.
Speaker 1: I Start the game like before.
Speaker 1: it started like there's small talk And I'm like.
Speaker 1: so if any of you ever read our Scott backers Prince of Nothing series and none of them had I was like Hey, you know who our Scott backer is?
Speaker 1: none of them did.
Speaker 1: I was like all right?
Speaker 1: And if you ever read Dan Simmons Hyperion none of them had.
Speaker 2: and I was like all right doesn't even heard of it.
Speaker 1: Uh actually I don't know.
Speaker 1: I didn't ask that.
Speaker 2: okay All right, that's it.
Speaker 1: Uh one more important thing because I was reminded of because the Prince of Nothing Kellis Nair thing, but we played a support games last night.
Speaker 1: We played Puerto Rico first time in a long time.
Speaker 1: yep Scott knows better.
Speaker 1: you should know better.
Speaker 1: yet somehow I tricked him with my simplest and dumbest trick of Acting all petulant.
Speaker 2: so that makes that we would both call Apple when you were ahead yep.
Speaker 1: So I was doing.
Speaker 1: I was doing pretty well.
Speaker 2: The only reason I went along with it is because Richard got the second ten building which convinced me.
Speaker 2: ah But I knew it wouldn't be enough to push him over the edge and the only difference between me and you Was that I didn't have the late-game doubloons to buy that one building.
Speaker 2: It was pretty much the one building between the two of us.
Speaker 2: I was actually ahead on the chips which is why I Cooperated because I said I'm ahead on the chips Scott I'm gonna stay ahead.
Speaker 1: if you thought you were you actually weren't.
Speaker 1: you forgot that I had two Unopposed captains early on.
Speaker 2: only the customs house is what put you over.
Speaker 2: if I had the customs house you would have lost.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I had the customs house.
Speaker 2: No shit No You didn't have the customs house when I started cooperating And I was pretty sure I was gonna get the customs house and I started going.
Speaker 2: Remember
Speaker 1: when we were talking about the big buildings right and I was like that's the building like I started suggesting to someone That you know an ex building and you interrupted and said that's the building rim needs buy it when in fact that was not the building I wanted or needed.
Speaker 2: It was.
Speaker 2: it was at the time it was but not no I mean at the time and I wasn't gonna tell and the other thing was I didn't want to tell them to buy the customs House because that's the one I wanted.
Speaker 1: but Scott I had more time you through the entire game.
Speaker 2: No, I had more victory chips.
Speaker 2: No, you did.
Speaker 2: I did.
Speaker 1: I had 37 points from those At the end of the game the chip.
Speaker 2: Yes, the victory point chips.
Speaker 1: I had 50 something at the end of the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they were almost the entire when you were going for that building.
Speaker 1: I had more Anyway anyway.
Speaker 1: but Hint for anyone ever plays a game with me if I suddenly start acting kind of pissy and anti-social.
Speaker 2: I do not cooperate with rim under any circumstance.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh I can't win god damn it because chase bought a building that I really wanted and I used that opportunity To just sit there and be like fuck.
Speaker 1: I lost.
Speaker 2: and for whatever reason Scott believed it I Believed it only because Richard had 210 buildings and I believed I was gonna get the customs house Once you got the customs house, I started to worry but it was already over.
Speaker 1: I was worried that Emily Was gonna be like hey rims doing fine.
Speaker 2: No, I started to worry when the governor moved twice and I hadn't acquired in a single doubloon.
Speaker 2: That's when I started to worry because I said, oh, I'm not gonna be able to buy it fuck Yeah, and then it was over and it was too late.
Speaker 2: But before those two rounds passed I was still feeling pretty good.
Speaker 1: I remembered how much I fucking love that game though It's a good game.
Speaker 2: Yes game.
Speaker 1: All right, you got some news.
Speaker 2: I do so, you know the torchlight the Diablo clone.
Speaker 2: Yeah, did you actually play that?
Speaker 1: Uh, no, but I know about it.
Speaker 2: All right Well, it's Diablo clone.
Speaker 2: I pretty much played it and then beat it and then it was done.
Speaker 1: It looks way more fun than the new Diablo.
Speaker 2: Yeah, so I looked at pecs West I saw a torchlight do and I talked to the guys and those guys.
Speaker 2: well You know It's still at its core a game where you click and click and click and click and click and eventually win.
Speaker 2: and that's it.
Speaker 1: Attack attack attack potion attack attack potion attack town portal.
Speaker 2: Yep.
Speaker 2: That's it.
Speaker 2: There's nothing to it.
Speaker 2: Mindless clicking clicking on the monsters looking at flashy colors.
Speaker 2: That's it.
Speaker 2: But Every other aspect of this game.
Speaker 2: These guys are getting right.
Speaker 2: I talked to them.
Speaker 2: They're gonna have a flat price play forever.
Speaker 2: No DLCs another bull, you know stupid bullshit.
Speaker 2: That's unfair, right?
Speaker 2: No paying to get better characters, right?
Speaker 2: Awesome co-ops that will actually work unlike say magica, right?
Speaker 2: You know, basically everything awesome.
Speaker 2: they got everything right except for the fact that it's a game where all you do is click.
Speaker 2: torchlight 2 however sadly is gonna be delayed a Delayed from this year until some point in the near future.
Speaker 1: I want to take you back to a time the distant past When we were waiting for a game called tribes to to come out and it got delayed.
Speaker 1: Yep Nothing will ever compare to that feeling.
Speaker 2: I'm gonna call it right now.
Speaker 2: This will not become the next Duke Nukem forever because what I saw at PAX was so close to done.
Speaker 1: I think that they're just wait will not become the next game that comes out and people can buy After ten years.
Speaker 2: But yeah, actually the guy this is the funny part of this right.
Speaker 2: it's like okay game was delayed.
Speaker 2: what's the big deal?
Speaker 2: He's a big deal.
Speaker 2: the guy who announced, you know from the company who announced the delay He said quote.
Speaker 2: besides you're all playing Skyrim right now.
Speaker 2: Anyway, aren't you?
Speaker 2: or battlefield 3 or uncharted 3 or Saints Row 3 or deuce Arkham City or Skyward Sword?
Speaker 2: Or Minecraft or modern warfare 3 or Dark Souls or Assassin's Creed revelations?
Speaker 2: And he's like it's a joystick.
Speaker 2: was like.
Speaker 2: you're right.
Speaker 2: No rush It'll take us this time next year to make our way through everything you just mentioned In some non gaming news, I just want to bring this up very briefly.
Speaker 1: It was kind of an open e sort of meta thing, but I can buy.
Speaker 1: Wall Street is all up in my business.
Speaker 1: They're like outside my building.
Speaker 2: every day should come and move up to where I'm working.
Speaker 2: Yes, where it's just as bad every day of every year that I ever go to work this tourists up in my business.
Speaker 1: Today was literally a constant stream of police sirens and yelling outside my building.
Speaker 2: how high up are you?
Speaker 2: 16 stories and you still hear it.
Speaker 1: Yeah From the 16th floor I can hear individual people talking on the ground floor like on the street.
Speaker 2: I'm on the seventh floor and I can only hear the following things from the street the tour bus with the microphone All right on the top, right?
Speaker 2: If a guy comes and starts busking with a sax or drumming or something like that I can hear it or a siren of some sort.
Speaker 2: I cannot hear anything else.
Speaker 1: in my old building in the Lincoln building I one time I was staying at work late for something and I heard a ruckus outside.
Speaker 1: So I opened the window and I see a cabbie chasing a guy around his cab.
Speaker 1: So I can hear the whole argument and it was really funny and I just kind of held my phone videoing the thing.
Speaker 1: in case you know It turned into YouTube and it didn't.
Speaker 1: they just ran around for a while.
Speaker 2: I was walking down the street in Astoria some months ago And there was like a cabbie was gonna fight and a yellow cab was gonna fight with a non yellow cab and the two guys Were out and like one guy was getting ready to punch the other guy and the other guy was like respect yourself What are you doing?
Speaker 1: Respect that's that's a good thing to say right.
Speaker 2: and then it was just sort of like in.
Speaker 1: Thing.
Speaker 1: is that's beautiful?
Speaker 1: that's on one hand admonishment coupled with insight.
Speaker 1: You're inciting the person but yet at the same time the thing you were inciting them about.
Speaker 1: they'll feel worse if they act.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it wasn't.
Speaker 2: I just kept walking.
Speaker 1: It wasn't Lately, I stopped whenever I see stuff except the only rare stuff because it's happening So constantly that it's like, oh look a whole bunch of riot police marching in formation.
Speaker 1: Cool.
Speaker 2: Cool Nice shields could borrow one.
Speaker 2: Oh We should buy riot police here on the internet and then show up and have two lines of real line of real riot Please in the line of fake rat police face because we keep talking about video games.
Speaker 1: So I played counter-strike one six few days ago.
Speaker 2: I keep meaning to do it, but then I end up just clicking on source and playing for real.
Speaker 1: It was fine.
Speaker 1: I was playing okay, and then I Realized as an item that I forgot about the riot shield.
Speaker 2: I thought they that was like in and out.
Speaker 1: No, it wasn't out.
Speaker 1: It's just we started playing source.
Speaker 2: I forgot.
Speaker 2: they added it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what that thing is unfair fucking hacks broken.
Speaker 1: It is awesome.
Speaker 2: How broken could it be?
Speaker 1: I was invincible God with that thing if I was gonna base, but it doesn't stop bullets.
Speaker 2: How many bullets does it stop all of them?
Speaker 2: What if someone shoots you in the back?
Speaker 1: You back up into a corner put it in new front of yourself and duck.
Speaker 1: if you have three people doing that in each bombsite The bombsite is pretty big.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Did you have the bomb behind you in a corner next to a crate?
Speaker 1: We were counter terrorists.
Speaker 2: Oh So you can you shoot from around behind the shield.
Speaker 1: Uh, you can put it to the side and then it'll protect you halfway and then you can shoot but then you can be shot.
Speaker 1: ah Interesting you'll play and you'll see it's it's fun.
Speaker 1: Okay So things of the day in the course of our game night Of course all social gatherings at the geek house unless we specifically prevent it turn into everybody show a YouTube video before we go to bed.
Speaker 1: So we were talking about adaptive Like picture stuff like adaptive scaling, you know the stuff where you like take a picture and you make it wider and it figures out more scenario or more scenery to put like in between the edges dynamically stuff like that.
Speaker 1: and The discussion went to how like a lot of techno music uses what is effectively a compressor set up wrong to make like cool effects.
Speaker 2: So the debate was like you have a tool with an intended purpose But then you somehow use the tool in a way that it was not intended.
Speaker 2: right like a saw is meant to cut wood But it can also be an instrument.
Speaker 2: right exactly, you know, it's like you're not using the saw, right?
Speaker 2: But I'm still making something cool.
Speaker 1: So we start.
Speaker 1: I started positing Why doesn't someone Do the same thing with video like set up like what if you set up a codec like really wrong to do an interesting thing?
Speaker 1: And a friend chase Gordon who was an awesome listener and friend and member of our New York City hangout crew.
Speaker 1: Now you might remember him from such classics as the old Rochester whiskey.
Speaker 2: Raymond Scott's old Rochester whiskey immediately turned that particular comics.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's a thing Datamosh young Jake did a rap did a song and when he has a music video associated with it which is my thing of the day, which is him doing exactly what I suggested and It's actually pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I dig this.
Speaker 1: Lyrics are also funny.
Speaker 1: They're funny.
Speaker 1: in the same way then, you know sit like fuck.
Speaker 1: shit stack is yep Like it's.
Speaker 1: so he's like I'm so cool.
Speaker 1: Look at my shit.
Speaker 1: I'm doing this on purpose doing this on purpose.
Speaker 2: So I found the best tumblr best tumblr magic cards with googly eyes.
Speaker 2: The guy takes magic the gathering cards.
Speaker 2: He figures out the exact best googly eyes to put on them in the exact right places.
Speaker 2: He even gets the black dots in the googly eyes in the best possible position on the magic card.
Speaker 2: Googly eyes are generally pretty useful and he just just putting you just puts googly eyes in the magic card and they become hilarious.
Speaker 2: My favorite is this one the Vodalian serpent.
Speaker 2: That's pretty great Right.
Speaker 2: There's also some clever ones.
Speaker 2: So there's like a spider and as a fuck ton of eyes or a card There's like a whole bunch of creatures.
Speaker 2: So there's a whole bunch of eyes and all of them or this one That's like a lumber knot.
Speaker 2: It's got two eyes and two weird-ass places.
Speaker 2: I'm sure there's like some Cyclops is around.
Speaker 1: I just noticed the back of the car.
Speaker 1: That's pretty good, too.
Speaker 2: Oh, yeah His background on the blog is a magic card with five googly eyes where the five colored dots normally would be.
Speaker 1: It's funny.
Speaker 1: every now and then I get this weird urge to play magic kind of like how I imagine ex-smokers Occasionally get a weird urge to smoke a cigarette.
Speaker 1: Yeah We thought I should play magic and then I remember how much I hate magic.
Speaker 2: We can just go to a gaming store and we could buy two starter decks for like almost nothing and just play whatever you get.
Speaker 1: Suck now though.
Speaker 2: I know but that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 2: We just.
Speaker 2: but the thing is the ones we get at packs for free are yeah ass Those are like babies.
Speaker 1: first magic, right?
Speaker 2: We should get the ones just two real ones from some set that's identical and just whatever you why don't we just take all of?
Speaker 1: Magic cards that we own?
Speaker 1: because I play with those because they are not equal.
Speaker 1: who gives a shit?
Speaker 2: just do it.
Speaker 2: We could do.
Speaker 2: well, you know We could do is you could try that mode where there's like one giant deck or something like that.
Speaker 2: Right?
Speaker 2: wasn't there a mode where there's a giant deck and there's five stacks of open-faced land?
Speaker 1: a better way to play?
Speaker 1: is that the star?
Speaker 1: Mode that nobody plays anymore where everyone plays a one color deck one of each color.
Speaker 1: Oh you win if you beat the two people across from you.
Speaker 2: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's a good mode.
Speaker 2: I'll be white.
Speaker 1: You could be white All right, so I don't know what happened but we just keep having guests on geek nights.
Speaker 0: Yes, so making your life cuz you got no show ideas.
Speaker 2: You know what?
Speaker 1: It is no longer difficult to have guests on the show because remember the last time we used to have guests I had that Non awesome sound card and I couldn't like multi-track.
Speaker 2: Well now you got all those little tiny sound USB external guys.
Speaker 1: Uh, no, I don't use.
Speaker 2: All right, you get the firewire interface.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know how many people we can have on geek nights with no trouble.
Speaker 1: 100 And That's if I don't use my multiplexer.
Speaker 1: then we can go up to 20.
Speaker 1: But at that point I might have some hardware problems in terms of my.
Speaker 2: we have that many inputs on the mixer.
Speaker 1: No, I'd have to multiplex.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 2: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yes So the reason I'm on the show today instead of just sitting in the corner and laughing at those guys is because those guys those guys Those little guys You're jaded to us a little bit.
Speaker 1: because when Jared was those guys It was difficult to record because Jared was laughing so hard that like he couldn't even like look at the mic Like he did go away from the microphone and start laughing like hysterically.
Speaker 0: It's funny cuz I I guess I'm kind of a nerd to it now.
Speaker 0: But it's like when I see other people react to you.
Speaker 0: then it comes back to me how hilarious it actually is, you know So, um, but yeah, I had the.
Speaker 0: we figured it's Thursday.
Speaker 0: So everything is just kind of whatever topic we want to talk about and I figured since it was rims first trip to Japan it might be kind of cool to Talk about that a little bit and how Scott asked questions like you don't want me to ask questions.
Speaker 0: No, I said you
Speaker 1: said we do want
Speaker 2: you to.
Speaker 2: also how many?
Speaker 2: how many panty vending machines?
Speaker 2: Did you see zero?
Speaker 0: the whole panty vending machine thing is a myth.
Speaker 2: how many?
Speaker 0: They have them in pornos cat girls, did you see Animated?
Speaker 0: or We went to Akiba.
Speaker 0: so like if you're in Akihabara, it's like there's a ton.
Speaker 1: There was one really cute girl in Harajuku who had like cat Fox kind of ears just on but otherwise she was dressed like fashionable Harajuku girl.
Speaker 2: how many Yakuza beat you up?
Speaker 0: 20 but we Go.
Speaker 2: did you go to the host club?
Speaker 0: we I wanted to Emily's version of the host club.
Speaker 0: We'll get to that.
Speaker 1: Yeah No, no, not the maid cafe, oh you're though That was a pretty great place my favorite guy I got to hang out with.
Speaker 0: pump.
Speaker 0: pump pump is awesome.
Speaker 0: So I I prefer them over.
Speaker 0: be she be she looking guys.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, if you guys couldn't tell you know Emily and I went to Japan for a couple goes
Speaker 2: to be The love hotel Castle theme
Speaker 0: well near where we were staying in Kyoto that there was this hotel and it was obviously a love hotel You can tell because the facade
Speaker 1: People
Speaker 0: go in and they always list, you know two prices There's the rest and then there's the stay which is overnight, you know.
Speaker 0: So rest is like a few hours and so that's when you want to have a quickie or something.
Speaker 0: you go to the love hotel and pay like 30 bucks and you Can have a couple hours in a in a fantasy themed room, but this hotel was called hotel to you I get it which was like hotel and then that happened The best hotel I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: It's like when somebody's telling a story and it's kind of like you say that before you like Big lead-up to how these people ended up.
Speaker 0: So I thought that was pretty hilarious.
Speaker 1: I guess if we kind of go chronologically the first thing I have to say is that I've determined Scientifically that jet lag is a motherfucking myth.
Speaker 2: There's no such thing Jet lag and people always complain about it, but I'd like go whole Like.
Speaker 1: you're gonna.
Speaker 1: you know jet lag you're gonna experience it.
Speaker 1: It's gonna really mess you up.
Speaker 1: You gotta be ready for this.
Speaker 1: I get to Japan and I'm just like fine.
Speaker 0: So when we were at PAX, right, it's Seattle is what three hours different for.
Speaker 0: So When we flew over it was like, you know, I get tired a little early in the evening.
Speaker 0: So it's like it hits 10 o'clock at night and I'm like guys I gotta go to bed, you know They're like, oh you big wuss baby.
Speaker 0: Come on play more games.
Speaker 0: I'm like, no seriously I'm tired, you know jet lag and they're like whatever chat like.
Speaker 0: and rim says I don't have jet lag at all.
Speaker 0: I never get jet lag.
Speaker 0: and I'm like well wait until you have a major time shift.
Speaker 0: And so I was waiting to get my revenge because here we have an international flight which is basically what 13 13 or 14 hours depending on whether it's daylight savings time.
Speaker 0: and So I was like your day will become night and you'll see the pain and then you will be sick and not want to eat anything because actually I get less sleepy and more like I'm hungry at weird times and not hungry when I'm supposed to eat like I Really sick to my stomach cuz my body is like you're not supposed to be eating.
Speaker 2: I think I'm starting to agree with rim because like when I was Israel, I didn't have any problems and when I went to Seattle I've never had any problems.
Speaker 1: I think that he is the build-up like I'd basically stayed up before But so then I slept on the plane and that was my night sleep.
Speaker 1: So I woke up in Japan at like 11 a.m.
Speaker 1: Or something had a whole day and then like 930 10 o'clock I went to bed and I was fine.
Speaker 1: I was just like on normal time.
Speaker 1: In fact, I slept better in Japan Slept in like the last decade.
Speaker 2: special beds there some shit Different kind of mattresses.
Speaker 1: Yeah futon.
Speaker 0: All right Most of the time we slept on the floor.
Speaker 0: actually because most of the the hotels we stayed at were traditional broken And so it's just like three mats.
Speaker 0: and yeah It was like we had tatami mats and then just pulled out the the futons from the closet and slept on those.
Speaker 1: They were really nice rooms.
Speaker 2: They have internet in those rooms.
Speaker 1: Interestingly a few of them did but I noticed because you know, I didn't have a data plan.
Speaker 1: I was tracking like GPS coordinates of walking around.
Speaker 1: There's basically Pretty much zero free Wi-Fi anywhere in Japan.
Speaker 1: There's a million locked Wi-Fi's and Wi-Fi's you can log into and pay money to get internet But there's no free ones.
Speaker 0: There were a few like the one in the shopping district in Kyoto like Google or Yahoo or someone isn't providing no First Man, I tell you though.
Speaker 0: I hated my cell phone I rented.
Speaker 0: I rented from a US company and it was like this crappy Nokia phone that would.
Speaker 0: the screen would stay on it would Run out of battery in a few hours And I hadn't realized how much I depend on a smartphone because there were so many times where we'd be walking around.
Speaker 0: I'd be like Google Maps.
Speaker 2: Oh, no, Google Just paid whatever it cost to get a real phone.
Speaker 0: That's I think I'm gonna do it next time.
Speaker 0: I'm like just get it from a tree Like the next iPhones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw that there were.
Speaker 0: actually a lot of the phones are starting to use the global standard.
Speaker 2: Well, it's just they have all they have, you know, both sets of radios.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it's like the old days like my pre my old cell phone way back had it could do analog and two different Digital formats.
Speaker 2: It's just a fistful of radios in there and then you could turn on only the ones you're using right now.
Speaker 1: but interestingly I did learn that a Smartphone that has good GPS and a magnetic compass but does not have any data whatsoever It's still.
Speaker 1: Do you mean what was I gonna do?
Speaker 2: not free Wi-Fi's?
Speaker 1: yeah But basically I was I could use the cache Google Maps and the GPS stuff And if I started a track like when we're going somewhere like we rented bikes in Nagoya for a day I was actually pretty good, you know, it was clown bikes Like.
Speaker 0: actually they were some of the better rental bikes because they were actual mountain bikes.
Speaker 0: the frame was okay for me But quite small.
Speaker 1: I would look like I was riding a clown.
Speaker 0: It wasn't as bad as the tourist bike rental.
Speaker 2: No, but they're meant for tiny Japanese people, right?
Speaker 0: Japanese people were riding frames that were way too.
Speaker 1: So here's the weird thing about bikes that I noticed.
Speaker 0: one two thirds of the people.
Speaker 1: Yes, so two-thirds of the people like bikes are everywhere.
Speaker 1: But there's no such thing as biking on the left or right or on the street or the sidewalk.
Speaker 1: people just bike fucking everywhere.
Speaker 1: So the sidewalks just have people careening in expertly around barely missing everybody and like wobble wobble on the sidewalk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's actually getting to be a problem.
Speaker 0: Like I was talking with Mr.
Speaker 0: Noda and he was saying that They're starting to be laws looked into because there are so many pedestrian and bicycle accidents I can tell you why nobody knows how to ride their bike.
Speaker 0: It isn't car and bike.
Speaker 0: It's a pedestrian.
Speaker 1: and bike Yeah Is the main cause of the bikes go really really slow and they wobble all over the place on the sidewalk.
Speaker 0: and also it's weird Because like in New York, it seems like the people who bike are either one delivery guys who have the really tough-looking BMX bikes You know, they're like really chunky frames and stuff or the like Hipster style like fixie whatever But it's popular in hip.
Speaker 0: it's mostly like what do they call mama Charlie's.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mama Charlie's and the mama Charlie's are like these single gear fixed, you know fixed gear bicycle.
Speaker 1: I'll put it this way Scott.
Speaker 1: Our average New York walking speed is faster than the average Cuz.
Speaker 0: think of how far we got.
Speaker 0: of course we had mountain bikes, but we were also.
Speaker 1: we were booking.
Speaker 1: I mean we.
Speaker 1: I mean any biker we came to.
Speaker 1: we just blew by it.
Speaker 0: was it was actually funny because We were riding around?
Speaker 0: No, actually actually the one time we got Called out to we were riding around campus.
Speaker 0: We were at Nagoya University and we're riding around campus and this one Group of kids was just like yo cool bikes, you know, and they were yelling Small but I was like the rentals and they're like, oh they're still cool.
Speaker 1: Almost no one had like mountain bikes.
Speaker 1: But yeah the other third like there were bikers.
Speaker 1: There was a very tiny minority of what if you had actually cool bikes?
Speaker 1: then Here's the deal.
Speaker 1: The majority of people are riding crap bikes.
Speaker 1: They don't really know how to ride them.
Speaker 1: They're going very slow and wobbly.
Speaker 1: They're on the sidewalk.
Speaker 1: a small minority are on bikes like ours Going wicked fast with the traffic in the street.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they're like two completely separate classes.
Speaker 2: I've seen initial D action on the street.
Speaker 2: I saw a lot of rice cars All right, any cars that like do not exist using the GTRs.
Speaker 2: and actually
Speaker 1: yes when we were
Speaker 0: cars Mm-hmm, like yeah boxy square cars because it's hard to park so a lot of they're
Speaker 2: all tiny could you
Speaker 0: really tall but really like Short, you know, so they're like this cube shape kind of cars instead of the more aerodynamic Aerofoil curves that we tend to.
Speaker 1: but I did see two GTRs parked in the notice neighborhood and I saw another GTR when we were in Kyoto parked out in a fancy neighborhood.
Speaker 1: Cool a lot of GTRs.
Speaker 0: I didn't notice.
Speaker 1: but well GTR I noticed it's one of those.
Speaker 1: it's one of the few cars that other than the Miata that I'm just Might have stolen it.
Speaker 1: They're kind of nondescript compared to like a Lamborghini.
Speaker 0: But So yeah riding bikes was actually one of those ideas where it was rims idea.
Speaker 0: So let's rent bikes when we get to Nagoya because we hadn't really done a lot of exercise We walked around a lot, but we hadn't like run or Yeah crazy.
Speaker 0: and so Because rim doesn't really speak much of the language a lot of the trip planning kind of falls on me.
Speaker 0: And so I was like, okay, so if we're gonna rent bikes, I have to arrange the renting of the bikes.
Speaker 0: So we stopped for an hour at a net cafe.
Speaker 0: Oh my god I thought he was gonna love the net cafe.
Speaker 1: Talk about a den of iniquity.
Speaker 0: No, it's like this huge Library of manga like there are shells and shelves of manga and free drinks and these little box cubicles and more cigarette smoke that I've been exposed to in the rest of my life.
Speaker 1: come on, I Was getting like nauseous.
Speaker 2: I couldn't have gone in like I would have gone out immediately.
Speaker 1: It's funny because people like smoking is okay in Japan for the most part like people smoke all over plays.
Speaker 0: but but you saw in Nagoya, they have anti-smoking signs in certain.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah What I was gonna get to is that it didn't.
Speaker 1: I was surprised.
Speaker 1: actually I think the smoking rates are way less than they were not that long ago because in all the upper scale places they're really like no one was smoking and like the nicer the ocons like you weren't allowed to smoke in the room and You're not allowed to smoke on the street.
Speaker 1: Really you have to smoke in like smoking areas on the street.
Speaker 2: That's good.
Speaker 0: No smoking while walking.
Speaker 1: the only place about that occasionally like if you're at a cheaper like less great restaurant There'd be like someone smoking which really sucked.
Speaker 1: but whatever the nice restaurants known was smoking.
Speaker 1: but Whenever we went into a game center everybody's smoking Especially in the pachinko area.
Speaker 1: Oh my god go over to everyone.
Speaker 1: game center.
Speaker 1: There's like 40 pachinko parlors Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: pachinko is everywhere and it's really loud and the game centers usually have pachinko in them Like they'll be like, you know one-third video game machines and one like two-thirds pachinko and slot patchy slot and stuff like that, so The crane games are off the hook.
Speaker 1: There's like food in there.
Speaker 0: It's like ice cream.
Speaker 0: it's like a refrigerated crane game where you can grab ice.
Speaker 1: This gave me a dystopian vision of the future where the homeless are given tokens and there are food crane games in the street.
Speaker 0: That's really sick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could see it.
Speaker 0: They have all sorts of stuff like, you know, there's the traditional stuffed animals But there's also like anime figures and like it's kind of like a wild world.
Speaker 0: they'll have the machines where you can like get a PSP and stuff from the crane game, but I Arcades in Japan like I knew they're awesome, but actually being in one they are awesome But they're not as good as they used to be.
Speaker 2: but they're full of smoke like it's but it's.
Speaker 1: so here's the thing.
Speaker 1: They were full of smoke But all the smokers were either in the fighting game area, which is kind of separate or in the pachinko like crap area.
Speaker 1: So where all the good games were that weren't fighting games.
Speaker 1: there's really no smoke.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I don't think it was smoking and playing DDR right now.
Speaker 1: No, we did find a DDR machine.
Speaker 1: It was like yeah, it was only one.
Speaker 1: It was like 16th mix or something crazy.
Speaker 1: It was all like that.
Speaker 1: It was all like deaf punk songs.
Speaker 0: We did gorillas.
Speaker 0: We did feel-good ink and we did.
Speaker 2: Let me see how many DDS got like.
Speaker 1: the foot system is completely different now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was like this song is 16 feet.
Speaker 1: What does that mean?
Speaker 2: Yeah, I'm gonna look up.
Speaker 0: so we were.
Speaker 0: we were like exhausted.
Speaker 0: Those are.
Speaker 1: we played tanks tanks tanks and initial D not for not five Mario, but six Initial d6 with a full-size steering wheel and Mario Kart 2 which was actually really awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was really fun.
Speaker 0: We went to game centers a couple of times like in Tokyo and then we went in Kyoto in Gion Before we went back to the hotel, but I think my favorite thing was watching you play the Gundam pod.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, the gun gun is a four.
Speaker 1: It's like you sit in a pipe.
Speaker 1: It's like the old a mech warrior belt that kind of things that were in the US that then disappeared but way more advanced and it's like a dollar to play too.
Speaker 1: and it the games like forever and it's just four on four people.
Speaker 1: and There's like there's voice chat and radio channels.
Speaker 1: So you can like chat with each other or like flip the broadcast and like chat with the enemy team.
Speaker 1: And the controls were like it looked like I was inside of a Gundam.
Speaker 1: I had all the controls of a Gundam and a million buttons and switches.
Speaker 2: and all these are.
Speaker 1: kids afford those pods Because there's tournaments in these things like every day as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: think if you get people in there constantly There's like a steady stream of people those people at school.
Speaker 1: well Scott like imagine this imagine you and me.
Speaker 1: imagine if there was an arcade that a good computers and There was just a Counter-Strike League like the bowling league and we just like go there every other week.
Speaker 1: Yeah Counter-Strike.
Speaker 0: I saw a thing where it was a soccer game, but it had like winning 11 Yeah, but it was like they had in one station for every player every player on the team.
Speaker 0: So you'd actually be in the room and play soccer Virtually with the people around you which kind of sounds funny to somebody who actually likes to play soccer in real life Because it's like why not just go play soccer.
Speaker 0: But the fact is you you have like these You know World Cup kind of matches virtually with all your friends sitting in the same room.
Speaker 2: So the newest DDR that came out in November of 2011 November 16th.
Speaker 2: So yesterday Yeah is dance dance revolution x3 verse second.
Speaker 1: Okay x2 is what we were playing.
Speaker 2: That was the set that was came out in July.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: So note on Pirate Bay.
Speaker 1: No one's even pirating that shit.
Speaker 0: so sad.
Speaker 0: DDR.
Speaker 0: DDR is really fun.
Speaker 0: It's a good way to keep fit in the winter.
Speaker 0: I've I've awakened to its its terms.
Speaker 1: So we went to like all the day when we started in Tokyo and then we went to Nagoya And then we went to Hakone and then Kyoto.
Speaker 0: No, we went Hakone before.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Yes It's.
Speaker 0: we went to Tokyo and then went to Ora Wada and took the little train over to Hakone and then we went.
Speaker 0: What one thing I must recommend and if you're gonna be in Japan for like a week or something or two weeks is Maybe and you're gonna be traveling around a lot and seeing a lot of different places Look into the rail pass because it
Speaker 1: was like a Galaxy Express style like just you show it to people.
Speaker 1: They're like, oh just step right through unlimited everything any any kind of train doesn't matter what any JR train.
Speaker 1: So all this all the Tokyo like stuff and the Shinkansen But not the Nozomi line and the buses.
Speaker 0: so you can go on highway buses once I can.
Speaker 2: even you can just take the bullet Trains all you want.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we did.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's the Nozomi the kodama and the Hikari.
Speaker 2: So what are the other.
Speaker 2: what is the difference?
Speaker 2: the Nozomi is like the Krazy Express as far as I can tell Everywhere all the way to Japan.
Speaker 0: Yes I believe it runs between.
Speaker 0: it's the Tokaido sense.
Speaker 0: So I think it runs between Tokyo and Kyoto.
Speaker 0: if I'm not mistaken, it might run further south, but there are.
Speaker 0: there are a couple different Shinkansen lines all kind of branching from Tokyo.
Speaker 1: So our trains we have no excuse.
Speaker 1: the the Shinkansen was Ridiculously fast.
Speaker 1: It's cheaper than Amtrak tickets Like.
Speaker 2: well people are using it constantly every day.
Speaker 1: It runs all the time and you know what to put it in perspective.
Speaker 1: if we had Shinkansen in America, which one to the rail gauge is narrower than our gauge, which is I think a big key to how it works well, it's because our main thing is.
Speaker 2: I've read a whole thing about how our rails because they're also had to be used for freight and Because they all right.
Speaker 2: So that's why they're watching.
Speaker 1: consent takes less right-of-way.
Speaker 1: It's faster on the outside It's quieter than Amtrak trains.
Speaker 1: Yeah, despite being fast and If we had Shinkansen here With stops with many stops it would be About the same commuting from Albany to Manhattan every day than we had commuting from Beacon to Manhattan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Albany to Manhattan you could commute.
Speaker 1: we wouldn't be that bad.
Speaker 0: We were going what like 250.
Speaker 1: yeah Fast as a plane the average speed you can get to Florida in two or three hours the average speed Including many stops along the way was like a hundred and forty eight miles an hour, which included, you know All the time it was stopped.
Speaker 2: Flying to Florida is like an hour and a half.
Speaker 2: ish, right?
Speaker 0: Might be a little much but like you figure Japan is like, California And they used to run this commercial about how you could get anywhere and I believe it might have just been the main island But anywhere in the main island of Honshu in three hours because I remember eats me son Chican and it was like anywhere on the island three hours.
Speaker 2: Did you go to the other island?
Speaker 2: No, no You didn't go to the island that had.
Speaker 2: I was among a diet with the animals on it.
Speaker 0: No, that's actually that's in Okinawa.
Speaker 0: That's like going to Hawaii.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay, but like if if I was gonna go to Okinawa, I'd plan a trip.
Speaker 1: So that's like going to TiVo and be like, oh you were in New York.
Speaker 1: Did you go see Mount Rushmore?
Speaker 0: We're like you were in New York.
Speaker 0: Did you go see Hawaiian Islands?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like it's but it's.
Speaker 2: it's the same country Right, so you entered.
Speaker 0: it's not though the okay.
Speaker 0: Well, you don't need to use your passport politically, but culturally and linguistically It's very similar to the u.s.
Speaker 0: Is relationship with Hawaiian Islands, you know, it was a distinct culture Which was then taken into the Japanese Country like I forget exactly when it was like a few hundred.
Speaker 2: But I figured like a high school can go on a day trip there.
Speaker 2: then so can a terrorist right?
Speaker 2: No, whatever.
Speaker 0: They didn't go on a day trip.
Speaker 0: I thought they did go on the school trip kind of like how I went to Hokkaido.
Speaker 2: school trip isn't just one day Trip is.
Speaker 0: usually you take it's like Might be four days to a week.
Speaker 0: usually, you know, it's it's like an actual vacation so it's.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I'd like to go to Okinawa someday.
Speaker 0: I haven't I haven't really explored that far afield but In any case now
Speaker 1: one trouble with the rail pass is that most of the subways in the cities are private like New York used to be which really sucks and half the bus is like there's Traps, I'll give you the bus stop Which takes like the normal pass but then like a Private bus that follows the same route will just show up and if you get on it You're fucked and you gotta pay
Speaker 0: there in Kyoto because we bought like it's three dollars to get all you can ride city bus pass For a day in Kyoto and actually most of the cities have that.
Speaker 0: like in Nagoya.
Speaker 0: We pay seven dollars on the private subway in Nagoya and you can just ride around all you want.
Speaker 0: But in Kyoto, we pay the three dollars for the pass and apparently they're a city bus and Kyoto bus.
Speaker 0: so if you see it's a city bus and just Kyoto bus.
Speaker 0: and It was like oh no cuz we got on the one going to Gion.
Speaker 0: and then I was like Notice the sign that was like you cannot use your pass.
Speaker 0: and then the the conductor Said that.
Speaker 0: and the funny thing is there are Japanese tourists who were confused the same way.
Speaker 0: So it wasn't just us being dumb Americans like one old lady Day pass.
Speaker 0: and he was like no day passes.
Speaker 0: This is the private bus and it was like dang it Why you know is a bit frustrated.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 2: It's yeah Subway.
Speaker 2: you would get trademarked in the US for doing that, right?
Speaker 2: It's like that's.
Speaker 2: it's like weird.
Speaker 2: We have like these laws and that's the kind of thing they're meant to stop and we're like But we get mad when the laws are too strong, but in other places, they don't have the laws.
Speaker 1: You're like, oh, yeah, we were solving a problem though Cabs in New York or in Japan at least in Tokyo.
Speaker 2: We're really funny how much money they cut.
Speaker 1: They were actually really cheap and you're not allowed to tip them like you don't tip.
Speaker 1: Well, like why would like?
Speaker 1: it's crazy.
Speaker 1: It's like it's weird if you tip them.
Speaker 0: I I know that in most Japan Businesses like restaurants you never tip which is great.
Speaker 2: I'm so like Was it was their sales tags?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it was fine.
Speaker 1: So here's the deal.
Speaker 1: sales tax is 5% on everything not on everything and prices on everything are in multiples of five or ten And as a result you pretty much almost never get like 1 yen coins or any crap like that Like they round things to reasonable amounts.
Speaker 2: Mm-hmm Any like electronic stores or anything?
Speaker 0: We went to Big camera we went to big camera.
Speaker 1: we did.
Speaker 2: They have all kinds of stuff that you can't get here Really?
Speaker 2: I mean, I thought they have like all kinds of small things that you can't buy here like laptops We can't get.
Speaker 1: the boutique laptop market is really kind of dried up.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I mean you you could see the cell phones like the fancy Japanese cell phone.
Speaker 2: But I mean are they really or anything better than like our smartphones now?
Speaker 2: I think we've caught up pretty much.
Speaker 0: I mean the smartphone thing.
Speaker 2: it's interesting because I mean except you can watch TV on their phones.
Speaker 0: Well, the traditional Japanese cell phone are still very popular.
Speaker 0: but smartphones like iPhone is super big like it's a very very coveted Cellphone, why don't everything just go get one?
Speaker 2: It's not that much.
Speaker 0: a lot of people do, you know a lot of but it's very expensive.
Speaker 2: So a lot of people everything did it cost more than it cost here?
Speaker 2: Yes.
Speaker 2: How much is an iPhone in Japan?
Speaker 1: There's the trouble to.
Speaker 1: the exchange rate was pretty much as far against us as it could have possibly been.
Speaker 0: I used to remember when it was like one penny to one yen about like one night in Kyoto because you know No one takes credit cards really.
Speaker 1: so we were kind of low on money like we had like 7,000 yen left Which is you know, that's like 70 bucks.
Speaker 1: give or take little eat less because the exchange rate.
Speaker 1: but we were in Gion The river so basically every place was too fancy and we could not afford to eat $700 with $70.
Speaker 2: two people can't eat for seven.
Speaker 1: where we were.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: It was like the Park Avenue.
Speaker 0: It was the fancy place.
Speaker 0: We're all like you go to the fancy.
Speaker 1: You couldn't go to be Walked way back to our real count and there was a little cheaper place.
Speaker 0: We didn't eat combini bento very much or anything like.
Speaker 1: I basically ate my way across Japan eating the best goddamn food That was.
Speaker 0: that was mostly thanks to our family.
Speaker 0: Oh my Notice awesome people.
Speaker 0: I love the notice.
Speaker 0: They just they're the nicest family when you see them.
Speaker 0: just the the extended family.
Speaker 0: It was actually cool cuz it was Hiro Takei.
Speaker 1: He's like my five-year-old nephew and he was playing Pokemon on his DS.
Speaker 1: I was playing Advance Wars in my DS.
Speaker 1: All of them were like like all the kids were like, oh my god He has a DS.
Speaker 1: when I had it out.
Speaker 0: so sad though because I really wanted to trade But I had the.
Speaker 0: I had platinum with me and I couldn't figure out how to do it.
Speaker 0: and he's like I can show you.
Speaker 0: And then he's like, oh my god, it's all in English.
Speaker 0: What am I gonna do?
Speaker 0: but it was really cool cuz since it was the birthday everybody came over to grandparents house and So I got to see my host sister and host brother and who are who are married and living In their own houses and I got to see all
Speaker 2: that to each other.
Speaker 0: When when I was living there Kaori nay-san was still a single and living at home, but she recently got married and she has two kids.
Speaker 0: They're both very cute.
Speaker 1: But mr.
Speaker 1: Noted that they took us out to his like his favorite sushi place.
Speaker 1: That was the best sushi I've ever had in my life.
Speaker 2: I've never had anything because where the fish are if you let the fish are you would taste good and of course Oh, it was all super good.
Speaker 2: Unless you're him.
Speaker 2: You want to eat some East River sushi?
Speaker 2: I'll cook it up for you.
Speaker 0: We had raw shrimp raw shrimp in the u.s.
Speaker 0: I would be too scared.
Speaker 2: Where would you even get a raw shrimp in the u.s.
Speaker 0: That that was maybe.
Speaker 0: maybe they're like, Louisiana You can get some yeah, but I'd to be too worried about parasites.
Speaker 2: I'm not gonna eat it A few years ago.
Speaker 1: raw shrimp is a food Entirely distinct from cooked shrimp.
Speaker 1: It is that what I ate that day Is probably between the shellfish and the shrimp the most delicious.
Speaker 2: Are you sure they weren't cheating where they perhaps injecting it secretly?
Speaker 2: So you think it was raw but really it was just butter shaped like shrimp.
Speaker 2: Did they feed the Shrimps that were like that were living in a tank or they would dump sugar in the tank for the shrimps to eat?
Speaker 0: That's silly.
Speaker 2: No, so that would work.
Speaker 1: It was weird though cuz it was like gray and I was uncooked.
Speaker 1: It was those.
Speaker 1: I cannot express to you how delicious that was.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: it was really good
Speaker 2: to make you my
Speaker 1: and of course, mr.
Speaker 1: Noda Basically kept giving me some.
Speaker 0: so yeah.
Speaker 0: as a result the first he's like, which can does your boyfriend like?
Speaker 2: Which brands?
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz it we know what all I know is he was like just rim like sake and I'm like I really like sake.
Speaker 0: and then he was like really happy And he kept filling rims glass and I mean they both drank a lot of sake and I drank some sake.
Speaker 0: but like man It was the
Speaker 1: result of this
Speaker 2: gigantic bottle is so tall.
Speaker 1: That was very so.
Speaker 1: the as a result the first four nights in Japan.
Speaker 1: I drank heavily every night.
Speaker 1: This is where the jet lag went by the fifth day Like I was slight like my legs like I felt like I should not drink for a few days like my liver runneth over But Right in not over at all Actually just my body.
Speaker 1: I felt like my body might be at a limit where if I push it any further something my bed might Happen.
Speaker 0: I I was temperate.
Speaker 1: Well, because we got a little we met your sensei tubes were in Tokyo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like for that first night and we stayed out all night drinking and you hanging out.
Speaker 0: Actually, we retired fairly early.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we drank.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we had like a few drinks, but we went to a really nice pub and then we had a head He kept ordering drinks and I was like, alright sure more of an issue for me That was.
Speaker 0: that was fun though It was.
Speaker 0: it was nice to see my Japanese teacher who had only seen over Skype And so it's like we actually met in person.
Speaker 1: It was like we met at Hachiko and then we went out and he was really cool.
Speaker 0: Hachiko Oh But yeah, we went to this really cool restaurant The.
Speaker 1: the notice treated us and oh my god Howdy, the best way I can describe this restaurant Scott Remember the first episode of giant robo when the two guys eat it like that ultra fancy restaurant where they have like their private area Like out in the lake.
Speaker 1: No, really?
Speaker 1: You don't remember at all.
Speaker 1: No So we ate at a restaurant that was just like that.
Speaker 0: it's like a Japanese garden, but it's got all these little buildings like all these little houses and You pick a house and eat it.
Speaker 0: it's like you're taking to a private room and you sit on the floor and There's like wilderness and koi outside and the.
Speaker 1: we should make a restaurant like that on a roof and the servers come to the door in the traditional way like they open the door and they're like sitting in front of the door and Then they bring the food in and it was.
Speaker 1: that was a Teva I learned.
Speaker 1: I learned what Teva meant from KO century beasts because that was what that was the birds name.
Speaker 2: And you have seen a big robot.
Speaker 1: Yes, actually is that?
Speaker 2: is that Gundam still in?
Speaker 0: we have a picture.
Speaker 1: we have a great messenger is pointing and I'm also pointing really There's also I'm also posing.
Speaker 1: was there?
Speaker 2: is there like it's a row and my tell isn't there a gigantic or somewhere?
Speaker 0: We didn't see.
Speaker 0: giant are but we did see messenger at at the Kyoto.
Speaker 0: I go to the.
Speaker 2: that place was awesome the train station as a Phoenix in it.
Speaker 0: We did actually but the Phoenix was down on the first floor and we had our luggage.
Speaker 0: So I just basically told I was like, okay rim There's an Osamu Tezuka thing way down on the first floor.
Speaker 0: we could go see it But our trains in like 15 minutes and so we were kind of like it, you know, you can see pictures of it.
Speaker 1: I saw pictures of it on where the master everything was.
Speaker 1: we went to this.
Speaker 1: It was like amusement park, but basically it was sets.
Speaker 2: Did they have all Japanese movies?
Speaker 2: Did they have the Power Rangers show with the music?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they did.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, it was so like all the stuff you'd expect
Speaker 2: you crowd her it
Speaker 0: Extra to get into the Power Rangers stuff in the haunted
Speaker 1: house.
Speaker 1: The best part was the sets like you've now if I watch old like Japanese samurai movies like these sets were all used.
Speaker 0: Yeah, only Kyoto Studios.
Speaker 1: It was like toy, but they made a lot of movies Like there's this one bridge and there's all this.
Speaker 1: like the text was like this bridge is in every goddamn movie.
Speaker 2: Yeah, we only built one bridge because it's hard to make bridge.
Speaker 1: Basically, the sign was like we changed the signs and like a little bit of the landscaping around it and it's a different bridge and we And they always set the scene by changing the name of the town on the sign on the bridge.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: But the best part of all of that was there was a building that had these sets for ninjas and all it was Was it was a part that looked like the rafters above a room and then right under that was the part that looked like the rafters Under the floor in a room.
Speaker 0: so you'd anytime they had to shoot a scene of a ninja like being above the eaves and listening in or being below the Listening and they just had that one room in the building that they'd they'd shoot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so there were.
Speaker 0: there were a bunch of things from different period dramas and did I get key?
Speaker 0: And so that was.
Speaker 0: that was really cool.
Speaker 1: There's a really cool exhibit in like the museum part of it, too.
Speaker 1: It was like famous Japanese directors and a collection of their personal effects that were kind of like relevant to there.
Speaker 1: I love that cuz actually even though I'm like a pair of binoculars and a teacup and a canteen and Beret or whatever.
Speaker 0: No, I'm like really into film.
Speaker 2: It's probably just all Japanese film directors.
Speaker 0: there were a lot of.
Speaker 2: Here's everyone's beret.
Speaker 2: Here's their backup beret.
Speaker 0: It was cool cuz it was like from the 19 Like 1920s and stuff onwards a pre-war really early stuff.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 0: it was pretty neat.
Speaker 0: But speaking of museums, how do you like the Ghibli Museum?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Ghibli Museum is like wickedly awesome People like fight to get tickets or whatever, you know, it was way crowded You know, basically it's like it looks like Ghibli movies like the whole thing like.
Speaker 1: there's there's the the Lop to Robot like on the roof kind of looking at a garden like a wildly growing garden on the roof And there's all these weird little like like hidey holes like you'd like.
Speaker 1: there's like you're walking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could.
Speaker 1: we did even though you even though you're big like you go in and there's a little spiral staircase.
Speaker 1: It's like really tiny.
Speaker 1: you like squeeze into it.
Speaker 1: It goes up like three stars, but it's meant for Japanese people.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's meant for kids.
Speaker 0: It's the.
Speaker 0: how do you fit out for kids?
Speaker 1: because we crouched in and just kind of Witched our way up and then we got to a little tunnel and it took us across and then we're like up in another part of the museum.
Speaker 0: it's it's like a museum where Actually being in the building itself is fun.
Speaker 0: Like if you were a little kid, it's a very adventureful building You know, you're like popping out of doorways and being like, oh there there it is And just going around through like you have to crouch down to get into some doorways and it's it's really neat It's very Very good design.
Speaker 2: They also show the fire marshal probably wouldn't let it exist.
Speaker 1: Oh, so I'll say this You any US fire marshal if you ever go to Japan, you will have a heart attack.
Speaker 1: Like we were on a bus right a bus to go back from the fancy restaurant and the bus had little things on the seats Like there was a aisle up the middle and sets of two seats on either side like a normal bus to take people somewhere.
Speaker 1: And there was these things like and I couldn't figure out what they are and I look at them.
Speaker 1: I realize they were pads.
Speaker 1: you could flip them up and put them across the aisle to make a fifth seat blocking the aisle All the way up the bus.
Speaker 1: Yeah And there's stuff like that everywhere in Japan like they did and I feel like.
Speaker 1: it's probably not any more Dangerous to be like that in Japan because I it's people are tiny.
Speaker 1: No because people seem more Polite and I feel like if there was an announcement like you evacuate the theater people would just walk out calmly.
Speaker 0: People are in general pretty good about that.
Speaker 0: I mean you look at the footage from after the earthquake and people.
Speaker 0: I think it's like they have a good sense of Other people of society and so they're like paying attention and not causing trouble or budging in line or anything like that.
Speaker 0: It's like okay.
Speaker 0: This is what we have to do.
Speaker 0: We'll be very orderly about it.
Speaker 1: There's a fire.
Speaker 0: everybody's gonna be George Costanza yeah, but Anyway, we got to see like one of the short films that they that they run only in the museum There was one about.
Speaker 0: it was about catching a whale.
Speaker 1: the whale was totally troll.
Speaker 2: face the whales like Like had a big eyeball and was sort of like yeah, if he'd roll it up like yeah Yeah, I know the style.
Speaker 2: I know they've done that in a lot of Ghibli movies.
Speaker 0: Do the eyeball roll.
Speaker 0: it was it was.
Speaker 1: oh so that the one of the neatest things in the museum Is that this like room of animation and they're like zoetrops and all the different like old anime?
Speaker 1: They had a 3d zoetrope with models And then a stroke so it's spinning.
Speaker 1: you're like what's this?
Speaker 1: and the strobe light comes on and it's a three-dimensional Like stop-motion animation just happening in front of you.
Speaker 0: Yeah it looks like a ton of dolls just dancing and it's got like little Totoro's jumping up and down and Jumping rope and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's so cool.
Speaker 0: But actually my favorite room was the how animation is made room whether you already know there.
Speaker 0: No, but it's like a fictional animation studio.
Speaker 1: It was to a dream.
Speaker 1: It was to animation what the matrix is to hacking.
Speaker 2: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, it was.
Speaker 0: it was very sweet and old-fashioned from a bygone era Big wooden desks and stuff like that like on the desk.
Speaker 1: It shows like an animator station.
Speaker 1: There's like paper everywhere and likes drawings and drawings and notes and notes and reference models and books strewn everywhere And then a pot full of an infinite number of cigarette butts And a lot of the signs were were more Truthful, it wasn't like.
Speaker 0: animation is perfect and wonderful job forever.
Speaker 0: One of them in English said something like this is really tedious yeah, and I I just really liked reading about it and you know, I could have spent a lot more time in there But it was pretty crowded.
Speaker 0: Tezuka Museum We didn't get time Actually, it was like also the International Manga Museum in Kyoto, which we which we also missed out on.
Speaker 2: but it was like You can't even come to New York and see all the museum City not a whole country.
Speaker 1: we went to multiple major cities and we were in Nagoya.
Speaker 1: we went to the university We out there.
Speaker 1: I wanted to see some jazz, you know where we went.
Speaker 1: blue note The blue note has a sister blue note the only other one in Nagoya because Nagoya is a huge jazz scene.
Speaker 2: Like imagine if New York Chicago and LA were in the same state.
Speaker 1: Yeah but the thing is in New York a lot of the jazz musicians that play around here are from Nagoya come from Nagoya.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I thought that was really cool and they have kind of almost like a musician exchange You know with the blue notes.
Speaker 1: and the coolest thing was there was no smoking in the blue note.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh.
Speaker 0: But I went.
Speaker 0: I actually cuz rim was like he really wanted to see a show.
Speaker 0: And so at first we were like, maybe we can go see Takarazuka.
Speaker 0: I can't see that and it was like totally sold out and it was really to try to do.
Speaker 0: But when we went to Nagoya rim was like, how about some jazz club?
Speaker 0: And and so I went.
Speaker 0: we were at oasis 21 this big park in the in the city.
Speaker 0: It's amazing all.
Speaker 0: and I went to the JTB office in the mall and I was like, I'm uh, I'm here, you know on Recommendations of the US branch of JTB.
Speaker 0: I was wondering if you could give me any information about jazz clubs in In Nagoya and the lady was super helpful.
Speaker 0: She was like, oh, yeah, the blue note is just a few blocks.
Speaker 0: that way I'm like, huh?
Speaker 0: That's funny because the blue notes the one we go to in New York and So that actually that was a really good performance and it was kind of laid-back which was nice You know, it was at least for me.
Speaker 0: The trip was kind of intense.
Speaker 0: Like I'm so used to To living in Japan where I do cool stuff, but it was like spread out and most of it was just like routine daily life.
Speaker 1: I was filled with Illimitable indomitable energy, but I think it was partly because you didn't have to do anything or talk.
Speaker 1: There's also nothing to drink Except tea.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 2: So I was didn't get like all the weird things like coffee to hit.
Speaker 2: can they heat this?
Speaker 1: I did I got all that stuff.
Speaker 1: But I basically was drinking caffeinated beverages all the time constantly while I was awake.
Speaker 0: and then you drink booze.
Speaker 1: They don't have just like water Like if you go to a restaurant, but usually they don't.
Speaker 1: they don't just water they give you tea And as far as I can tell pretty much everyone just orders a beer.
Speaker 1: Like beer is cuz.
Speaker 0: we ate a lot of the times when we were by ourselves We'd eat at like Izakaya, which is like the neighborhood pub.
Speaker 2: Yeah, you know, no, you're gonna get beer there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: it's very also like a notice like like in a place.
Speaker 1: beer with dinner is just kind of a much more Typical thing and I really really understand now why Japan seems so big on very light beers.
Speaker 1: yeah Guinness doesn't go well with Japanese food, but Like a Karen or something really goes well with like a kitsune.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're not drinking, you know, the manly beer I had to keep stay with on Scott.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you they're pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah They were pretty damn good.
Speaker 0: I haven't had one in a while But anyway, let's see what other cool stuff we did.
Speaker 0: we do I don't we don't want to go on too long or anything but So well, we went to onsen And we saw Mount Fuji from the show.
Speaker 2: how hot was it?
Speaker 2: was it like it was normal?
Speaker 0: We didn't go in.
Speaker 2: the was hotter than the bathroom.
Speaker 0: It wasn't a Rotenborough with an actual natural No, the water was hot spring, you know.
Speaker 0: So they pumped up the water from an underground aquifer and I'm assuming probably mixed it with tap water.
Speaker 0: But you could tell it was hot spring water because of all the mineral deposits.
Speaker 1: And I actually have pictures from the cable car through the mountains the volcano.
Speaker 0: We went on a ropeway over a volcano while we were there too.
Speaker 1: We went on there's like this touristy pirate boat that takes you through the lake in Hakone like our pirates.
Speaker 1: But it's silly like there's a silly statue of Nelson and there's a pirate statue on it.
Speaker 0: He's like he's pointing a pistol and everybody else points like poses like he's shooting them or something like that.
Speaker 1: But the funny thing is we're standing up in like the crow's nest area like the like the little like observation deck thing they had for people to stand on and the pirates like hanging off the ledge up There and his butt's just there.
Speaker 1: I didn't really think much of it.
Speaker 1: Every little kid who walked up there Walked up looked at the butt went straight for it and like shoved a sword into it poked at it Put their face on it.
Speaker 1: I got a really good picture of it.
Speaker 2: It's easy for people to be child brothers you show them but It's easy to become a comedian.
Speaker 1: just show someone a. but that's right.
Speaker 1: The adults weren't like stop it.
Speaker 0: they were like The kids just like they were so single-minded about it as soon as they saw the pirate.
Speaker 0: it wasn't like hey It's a pirate.
Speaker 0: and then they were like looking at the pirate.
Speaker 0: It was just like hey, it's a. but So we.
Speaker 0: so we did all the the Hakone sightseeing stuff.
Speaker 0: but yeah onsen was really really nice and apparently in the new Eva movies, there's like Scenes in Hakone or something because in the in the New type magazine there was this whole thing about like oh This part of Hakone was in this scene and stuff like that and they also were selling as souvenirs Kaji's watermelon Manju.
Speaker 0: That was pretty cute, so I thought that was funny.
Speaker 0: but there was also like a little Prince Museum like the book for the book club and So That was kind of odd.
Speaker 0: It was like going it.
Speaker 0: No, we wanted to but it we ran out of time, and it was like.
Speaker 0: I said in Hakone That's like such a random place to have a be.
Speaker 2: there's a reason.
Speaker 2: Looking up on the googles.
Speaker 1: I looked around.
Speaker 1: I couldn't really find any like Explanation, but anyway, so that was nice.
Speaker 2: We relax the museum of the little prince in Hakone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we relaxed in the bath, and it was really nice and it's in English now in Nagoya.
Speaker 1: We went to.
Speaker 1: well first in Tokyo.
Speaker 1: We went to a maid cafe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was like I was kind of why See because to see you know and we were in Akihabara And I was like maybe we should go to a maid cafe, or maybe this was Emily's idea.
Speaker 1: I was Emily was like we could go to a maid cafe.
Speaker 2: I'd look in the window.
Speaker 2: I would never even know window That's the thing.
Speaker 0: It's just like.
Speaker 0: you know usually they're on the second or third story Seems actually pretty big.
Speaker 0: yeah, that's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: But so we were like well, maybe well, maybe we'll try it out and see what it's like.
Speaker 0: and There this girl in a maid outfit accosted us in the street.
Speaker 0: It was like.
Speaker 0: would you like to go to a maid cafe, and we were like okay?
Speaker 0: let's go and see.
Speaker 0: and so he went up to the second floor and You're greeted by like this wave of sound and pink things.
Speaker 1: They were so high energy.
Speaker 0: I could not believe Really totally faking it, but faking it with the grace of a profession, but were you like?
Speaker 2: did you like okay guys?
Speaker 2: Are you for serious?
Speaker 1: really you can't you just have to go with it.
Speaker 1: There's no way but to go with it.
Speaker 0: It's just like the energy level.
Speaker 1: every time They made everyone do a moi moi beam to power it with love before people could eat it I'd be like yeah, no yeah You think you could you could.
Speaker 1: you in a maid cafe could not resist doing the crap because otherwise They bother you.
Speaker 2: no because what I would do is I'd be like really are you guys serious like come on act like you do it normally when you're outside and not at work.
Speaker 0: Actually, they were pretty cool though that like they do come over and they talk to you But it's like there's.
Speaker 0: actually there were a lot of foreigners who go there and like when we were there this German tourists were there too and Their Japanese friend was showing them that and there was also an obvious Regular.
Speaker 1: It was even look at the maze like sitting in the corner just like eating his overpriced food.
Speaker 0: But there was this one maid and she's kind of food didn't even have like omelettes and stuff.
Speaker 0: We got parfait and I got the bunny parfait and rim got the kuma The bear parfait and they put like little biscuits in it to look like ears, and they put it in nose on it.
Speaker 0: It's very cute.
Speaker 2: in the back is probably some chef.
Speaker 2: He's like the grumpiest guy.
Speaker 0: Also, they serve beer and they say cocktails and they and they dance and they they do remember the stuff that was going on.
Speaker 1: It's a maid cafe in the New York Comic Con.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, I was asking Scott you weren't there?
Speaker 1: Yeah It was that times 10 and it never stopped.
Speaker 2: and they do that every day and say everyday job and there's people in there every Day, how many of these get made cafes?
Speaker 2: are there?
Speaker 2: many?
Speaker 1: Tension among them like fighting over customers.
Speaker 1: It's fucked up and this place had a like.
Speaker 1: you could get a like.
Speaker 1: you could level up if you go there often enough.
Speaker 1: you Have to go there like a hundred times to level up.
Speaker 2: What do you get if you level up?
Speaker 1: I don't even know or made attention.
Speaker 0: I guess I don't know but it's it's not creepy or anything.
Speaker 0: It's just like a restaurant like a theme restaurant.
Speaker 0: It's just like the ninja restaurant, but it's it's a restaurant of like Super energetic kawaii like talking in a fake cute way.
Speaker 2: But I just really want to know what those maids think when like they're not at work.
Speaker 2: Are they you know?
Speaker 1: You know, so what do you think later?
Speaker 1: Not at work?
Speaker 2: I knew a girl work on the same personality At anime club, right?
Speaker 0: There was a girl who worked in a cosplay cafe Which is very similar except that instead of acting like a uber cute maid you act like the character you cosplay.
Speaker 0: So she would come and she'd be like, oh my god, there are some really stupid customers.
Speaker 0: But then she she genuinely liked her job because she was into anime and she liked cosplaying and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: So I mean It probably comes with some annoyingness, but it also comes with hey, this is kind of fun, you know.
Speaker 0: So guess what our maids name was?
Speaker 2: I don't know them time.
Speaker 2: Okay, is that a coincidence?
Speaker 0: Her name was doom and like we came in I said they'd write your name on the little thing.
Speaker 0: They say what's your name?
Speaker 0: And I'm like Emily and this is rim and they're like She was cute too and they call her over and she's like Yeah, so it's fun.
Speaker 0: But my favorite was my cafe.
Speaker 1: So in Nagoya we went to a cafe.
Speaker 0: We went to a cafe.
Speaker 0: That's my my instead of no host cafes for me things.
Speaker 1: I want a Cafe.
Speaker 1: It was basically you get food and there's a whole bunch of really cute really Like affectionate bunnies and you just hang out with the bunnies.
Speaker 1: Yeah and pet.
Speaker 2: the food area was separate But you don't want bunny hair and all the food.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you go into this little back playroom and there are like five or six bunnies out running around.
Speaker 0: they have like 20 So it's not like bunnies everywhere.
Speaker 0: Well, there's 2025 I think Regular bunnies or maybe more like what.
Speaker 0: they rotate him, but they rotate him because they can't all be out at the same time.
Speaker 0: So they give them rests and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: So they're the most like people love and rabbits like pump who's like the boss.
Speaker 1: rather as far as I can tell Run over and be like hello.
Speaker 1: pet me over here.
Speaker 0: now He'd like jump on rims lap and like flop out next to him.
Speaker 1: I'm jumping behind me and like trying to like grab my shirt and steal it.
Speaker 0: He'd pull stuff out of rims pockets and run away with it and he was.
Speaker 0: he was just very.
Speaker 0: He did little binky dances and stuff like that and he was super soft too because he was a Rex rabbit which have no Guard hairs, so he felt like velvet.
Speaker 0: It was like this little velvet rabbit who is just like so rambunctious and adorable.
Speaker 2: So it was actually probably, you know, if you're making a restaurant you're going out and you're picking the cutest rabbit.
Speaker 0: But they did.
Speaker 0: it looked like they had a few rabbits that were actually adopt this rabbit kind of rabbits and You know because one had a sign on their cage They weren't as cute as the other ones found a permanent home.
Speaker 2: you guys can have these not-so-cute ones.
Speaker 0: I know that pump but I was talking to the lady and she said yeah, he's he's a popular guy.
Speaker 0: He's one of our our most popular Staff.
Speaker 1: I was happy.
Speaker 1: Rabbits were like very happy and like enjoying it and the place like the people running a really new rabbits.
Speaker 0: The only negative thing was one one rabbit had like a bit of a nose infection But she was undergoing antibiotics and she was she was gonna be fine.
Speaker 1: So now the funny thing is we also, you know before we went to the zoo with like the family with the notice Yes, and it was that the day at the zoo and it was.
Speaker 1: it was actually a pretty good zoo.
Speaker 1: Like the monkeys were pretty good.
Speaker 1: one monkey through soup was real close to figuring out Spears.
Speaker 1: Like he was sitting there.
Speaker 1: He had a stick and he's like Working it in this hole and looking at it and working it and looking at it and he always carried it around with him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was like his tool.
Speaker 0: He had the stick and he was like Messing with crack.
Speaker 1: one little baby monkey came over and tried to grab her from and he was like, oh no no, no, no, and he like Hit the monkey.
Speaker 1: and then that monkey ran over to his mom and cried.
Speaker 1: and then it was Like watching monkeys.
Speaker 1: but so there's a petting zoo in the Japanese.
Speaker 1: Oh, that was you know what the petting zoo is a trough filled with guinea pigs that kids just like run in and grab them.
Speaker 0: So bad for those poor guinea pigs, but I mean the staff were there and they were kind of supervising But like the kids were so high energy and they did not know how to handle the guinea pigs.
Speaker 0: It was just like all piggies poor guys, you know, luckily guinea pigs.
Speaker 2: They're probably like Pee on this kid watch.
Speaker 0: they're pretty hardy, you know, luckily they're.
Speaker 0: they're a little bit more sturdy than rabbits.
Speaker 2: I think like imagine imagine if we were in.
Speaker 2: We were in a big pen and it was the Giants petting zoo and the giant kids would come and play with us like that You would.
Speaker 2: I just be like hey rim and rim would be like getting like swung around by some kid.
Speaker 2: I'd like watch this like barf on him.
Speaker 2: Anyway, I didn't run away crying cuz he a little barf on him.
Speaker 0: So is there anything that stood out in your mind?
Speaker 0: like the food is so good?
Speaker 1: Though the weird things that stood out were that nobody nobody.
Speaker 1: until we got to Kyoto I did not see a single person other than Gaijin wearing sunglasses.
Speaker 2: It's sunny.
Speaker 1: It was Stupidly Ludicrously sunny and hot.
Speaker 1: it was basically unseasonably warm summer over there.
Speaker 2: You couldn't even see yeah.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, it snowed here.
Speaker 1: It's not once yeah, but no it was like so sunny.
Speaker 1: It was painful.
Speaker 1: Nobody had sunglasses on not a single goddamn person.
Speaker 1: I can't figure out if there's a thing about sunglasses or what?
Speaker 1: Well, you're being the Yakuza if you have sunglasses, but then we got to Kyoto and people there were wearing sunglasses.
Speaker 1: Just nowhere else.
Speaker 2: people in Kyoto are the only smart people I guess.
Speaker 1: and For society where they were all Yakuza for society where no one takes credit cards.
Speaker 1: It amazes me how few ATMs there are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's basically almost no way to get money if you need money like right now.
Speaker 1: So you can pretty much assume that anyone walking around And it was like going out to dinner or something or like.
Speaker 1: if someone's gonna go buy an iPad they've got cash Tons of it in their pocket.
Speaker 2: Yeah, beat him up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my apple store.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know I didn't see one.
Speaker 0: um, I think there is there there is an apples.
Speaker 0: Yes, there was actually.
Speaker 0: we went by it and just beat up anyone.
Speaker 2: Twice the size.
Speaker 1: Actually, no, I wasn't.
Speaker 1: they don't have guns.
Speaker 2: They don't have guns.
Speaker 2: You're twice the size.
Speaker 1: Yeah, here's something interesting.
Speaker 1: people always say oh I go to Japan everyone so sure you know what?
Speaker 1: They really weren't.
Speaker 1: the only people who were short were the people who yeah Like old people like 40 and up the kids were as tall as us like the pumpkins
Speaker 0: actually, that's not quite true because I do remember being in high school and going to a girl's school and I Was one of the tallest in my grade like I was used to being average.
Speaker 0: But you know, it's not like I was crazy giant tall.
Speaker 0: It was just like I was among the taller kids.
Speaker 0: There were a few girls who were tall.
Speaker 2: He's just like what are you doing down there little people?
Speaker 1: Michael Jordan's here.
Speaker 2: He's like, what are you doing down there a little bit?
Speaker 2: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 2: So it's even worse.
Speaker 2: He'd be like, oh, I guess this is a little.
Speaker 2: put My plane go to the wrong place.
Speaker 1: So independently, you know, because I noticed that mostly on the subway I was looking how tall people were some ways my hands underwear.
Speaker 1: Subways are perfectly clean have padded seats.
Speaker 0: That's the thing.
Speaker 0: padded seats.
Speaker 0: Can you imagine padded seats?
Speaker 1: would basically Toilet paper.
Speaker 2: There are technically padded seats on Metro North.
Speaker 2: technically.
Speaker 1: no Scott These are.
Speaker 2: these are like there is an amount of padding on them.
Speaker 0: These are plush cloth seats.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm They were surprisingly thick and comfortable.
Speaker 2: No one's saying them.
Speaker 2: No, like no one even accidentally spilled coffee on them or anything.
Speaker 0: No, they they have a few little stains, but not really They're.
Speaker 0: they're not smelly or anything from what I can tell.
Speaker 1: and in Hakone We got on a little train and we got on a car that was filled with nothing but school girls.
Speaker 1: Apparently I look like Harry Potter.
Speaker 0: So that was funny.
Speaker 0: that was funny.
Speaker 0: they liked rims glasses and thought he looked like Harry Potter.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it was.
Speaker 2: it was definitely glasses and brown hair Harry Potter.
Speaker 0: And then they were also looking at the fat guy out the train when oh my god There were.
Speaker 1: no there were no.
Speaker 1: there were like.
Speaker 1: there were no fat people in Japan.
Speaker 2: You can't get fat.
Speaker 1: and then at one point We saw one guy out the window of the train and he was.
Speaker 1: he was like normal fat Like he was like.
Speaker 0: I know he was like super schlubby like obese.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I see people like that every day.
Speaker 0: He was he was wearing Hello Kitty sweatpants.
Speaker 0: It was so.
Speaker 1: He looked like one of the people who shall not be named from RIT gray sweater gray sweatpants But the sweatpants and Hello Kitty.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and he's walking and all the people on the train are like, oh my god It's like.
Speaker 0: look at that crowds over to the window.
Speaker 1: Like oh my god You know, it's like and I feel so bad if you guys win, but the fact that the fact Someone that fat in America doesn't get a second glance.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some of that back in Japan.
Speaker 1: People are like, oh my god.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's like how would you even get that fat?
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's like MC right Scott if I live there, I would have to double down at the KMC I don't know.
Speaker 1: We went to a McDonald's though.
Speaker 2: Yeah, what did they have?
Speaker 1: I had the first McDonald's non-breakfast I have had in like a deck.
Speaker 2: What did they have there?
Speaker 0: I had Korean burger.
Speaker 1: It's McDonald's food plus like they'd want.
Speaker 1: it was like the KBQ was like Korean barbecue burger.
Speaker 2: Was it good?
Speaker 1: I don't even a couple hundred yen.
Speaker 2: Yeah, but they had also.
Speaker 2: you could get a Big Mac.
Speaker 2: It was the same Big Mac you get here.
Speaker 1: They actually have a limited menu.
Speaker 0: They don't have as many items, but they did have Big Macs and they were like our Big Macs, but smaller.
Speaker 2: Yep, what was the toy in the happy meal?
Speaker 0: Actually, we had to go and ask for the other toy cuz Sota already had all the Pokemon ones and he wanted Whatever.
Speaker 0: the girl toy was.
Speaker 0: what's the girl to a sister?
Speaker 2: I don't remember pretty cure or something or kitty grade.
Speaker 0: I don't remember what kitty grade that's not for little kids.
Speaker 1: I'm just Speaking of nerd stuff in it like on TV like I don't master like.
Speaker 1: I'm not like with normal culture But it was Pokemon but in the nerd places Madoka was the biggest thing.
Speaker 1: So much Madoka.
Speaker 0: the funniest thing was going to the Meiji shrine and seeing oh, I got a picture of this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we did a wishing picture you know those wooden boards where you write your wish on and hang it on the shrine rack.
Speaker 0: and there was one that had cuba on it and it was like 100 contracts, let's go.
Speaker 1: There's also one a little kid scrawled in English.
Speaker 1: He's like I wish for happiness for my family and also for the apples.
Speaker 1: We also.
Speaker 1: we did the the fortune the fortune telling thing and whim is the luckiest I got like the ultra rare like.
Speaker 1: My fortune was like you're gonna be rich famous and everything's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: You're gonna live forever.
Speaker 1: Where's?
Speaker 0: mine said I'd die if I was short-tempered If I was sick and the sickness would continue.
Speaker 0: but it was it was.
Speaker 2: From where does it come from?
Speaker 0: it comes from the shrine.
Speaker 0: you go into this shrine or temple and then?
Speaker 0: you you go up to this little store that sells the lucky amulets and fortune-telling and you take a wooden canister and you go shukla shukla shukla and dump it out and Whatever stick you get has a little number on it.
Speaker 0: and then they pick the number from all their papers.
Speaker 0: and That's how you get your number sticks, huh?
Speaker 0: Yeah number six.
Speaker 1: I got.
Speaker 1: I got the best number stick.
Speaker 1: He got the.
Speaker 0: I can't believe it.
Speaker 0: I was just like you're gonna get cool and he didn't get cool.
Speaker 1: I never need to do it again because I know now yes And we saw it's got.
Speaker 1: you'll be happy.
Speaker 1: We saw a lot of.
Speaker 1: you know, the old shit.
Speaker 0: But actually My thing is I was kind of freaking out like I had a really really good time and it was so good to be back In Japan, it'd been like over five years.
Speaker 0: So I was really starting.
Speaker 0: I really missed my my Japanese family.
Speaker 0: So it was really cool to see basically really cool people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's I think of them.
Speaker 0: They're like my relations.
Speaker 0: I consider them part of my family and so I was good to see them, but it was also just good to be back and My whole thing was I was a little stressed out because I was like How do I convey to rim what it's like to be in a place and show him all these different facets of this country?
Speaker 0: I love so much.
Speaker 0: But actually I think for a couple of weeks we did a pretty good job.
Speaker 0: We saw a lot of traditional stuff but we also saw a lot of modern stuff and we went nerdy stuff and we went normal stuff.
Speaker 2: and you know it What's in the regular movie theater?
Speaker 0: Oh, what's going on now?
Speaker 0: There was one about like my husband is depressed.
Speaker 0: There was one about one about a police dog.
Speaker 0: It was like, you know the Canine officer saying I'm based at shakedown.
Speaker 0: I'm see that but I kind of want to see it too because if it's got like canine units in it I'm like I was in book off the other day.
Speaker 2: They have all the base.
Speaker 2: I'd shake down DVDs, but I don't think they have English on them.
Speaker 0: Ah, you could always look and see even had like the TV boxes like all the deeply DVDs have English subtitles But they had everything.
Speaker 0: that's cool.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it was pretty good and I didn't even make rim.
Speaker 0: go into too many bookstores.
Speaker 2: We have Japanese book.
Speaker 2: Is there Japanese bookstore any different?
Speaker 0: well one the books are a lot cheaper.
Speaker 2: Yeah, you go like the Muji store in the Uniqlo.
Speaker 0: there we looked at.
Speaker 0: actually we did actually go in the Muji store cuz there's one right near like Muji Stuff that we don't have here And washing machines and stuff like like washing machines and It's okay tiny it's.
Speaker 0: it's well well designed simple well engineered not a lot of bells and wind whistles, but they have like little Muji stuff like a Microwave and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that and the food is something we don't get here.
Speaker 2: What's it?
Speaker 2: What kind of food do they?
Speaker 0: well like curry mix and dried food Tried for you know can Like that.
Speaker 0: I'll take it.
Speaker 0: it's really cool.
Speaker 0: But I love the Muji store cuz it's just.
Speaker 0: it's so relaxing.
Speaker 2: It's very calming But otherwise it's like the same kind of design as the ones we have here.
Speaker 0: It's like a wooden and actually actually I was so thrilled cuz I liked Muji before they opened in the u.s Cuz that was after I graduated college that Muji started being a thing.
Speaker 0: now We have like and now we have like four actually five if you count the ones in like JFK.
Speaker 2: Well, there's the ones that are like in the part of the mobile stores.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's like cuz.
Speaker 2: the moment store is like half Muji store, but we have three big ones.
Speaker 0: We have three in the city the New York.
Speaker 2: There's the downtown one the Times Square one, and what's the other one?
Speaker 0: Chelsea.
Speaker 0: right yeah, so anyway.
Speaker 0: It was nice It was a good trip, and we saw cute bunnies, and we saw my family and we saw all sorts of cool Long vacation I've been on in a long time.
Speaker 1: That didn't involve a convention.
Speaker 2: that didn't involve me having to do anything I might like quit go on vacation and come back or I get a leave of absence.
Speaker 1: It was really surreal though to be back at work like the Monday after living in Japan right back to work And I get to the office, and I'm like back in my normal life.
Speaker 1: It was just really weird.
Speaker 1: I was like it's all.
Speaker 2: it's even weird just doing like a long convention and doing it.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 2: be sure to visit our website At front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 2: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 2: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 2: It's actually recorded at night.