Speaker 0: It's Monday March 28th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: the humble log file.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So this I understood what I'm about to talk about.
Speaker 0: like I expected it to take a while to edit 1080p 60 frames a second video and Make it into something.
Speaker 0: it took way longer than I could have possibly anticipated.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean I mean the editing part is the editing part shouldn't have taken any longer than with standard definition video.
Speaker 1: It's only the part of the rendering.
Speaker 1: right the processing.
Speaker 0: well the rendering for 20 minutes of HD video after I did all the like Camera changes and zoom in and out and everything and I had like my project done Was about two hours.
Speaker 0: so about an hour per 10 minutes of videos.
Speaker 1: that part takes a lot longer.
Speaker 1: But I mean in just actually editing the video should just you know I mean it's higher definitions.
Speaker 1: But it you know it's the same thing cut and paste same amount of time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no because before when I edited video right it was always crappy video.
Speaker 0: There's nothing I could do to it to make it look better.
Speaker 1: Oh, so because it was HD you were doing more things.
Speaker 0: Yep, like for example in this I could zoom in on you or on me when the other one of us is picking our nose on stage But I had to actually sit there and be like up rims picking his nose all right got a zoom in on Scott Still picking.
Speaker 1: all right, maybe we'll cut to a slide But with standard definitions there was no way you could zoom because the resolution would so low.
Speaker 1: yeah But if you saw that video we did for magfest yeah But if it's 1080p's then you could actually zoom in and it would still be 720p's.
Speaker 1: yeah Which is plenty of peas.
Speaker 1: it looked just fine, especially because we're not ponies We're just two guys, and then if you down sampled the full zoom to 720p The whole thing will be the same resolution even though you're zooming in on people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, give or take and you know what it worked out pretty well.
Speaker 0: I'm proud, but It saddens me even though I understand all the reasons why and I'm not complaining about it that Kanye pony video I made in like a half-hour has like 5,000 views.
Speaker 0: yeah, so it is big nights.
Speaker 1: So does my.
Speaker 1: oh my gosh.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh.
Speaker 0: I Think part of it is that there was a dearth of pony material for a long time on the internet.
Speaker 0: that was good.
Speaker 0: So anything that was even like a two out of five got tons of views.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 0: But yeah the other problem is that I didn't make a pax show with the video or anything yet because I have 100 gigabytes of video to watch and figure out what's worth keeping And you gotta submit to the pax.
Speaker 0: community DVD already did.
Speaker 0: but here's the trouble with flicker with pictures.
Speaker 0: You probably do what I do.
Speaker 0: I just take all my pictures And I look at every one of them and when in doubt I keep it.
Speaker 0: cuz who cares doesn't take up any space exactly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can't do that when every convention generates about a hundred gigabytes of video.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: because I don't have that much storage space.
Speaker 1: you could do on a terabyte drive you do ten conventions.
Speaker 1: We have two years for a hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: You can do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I keep it all and I don't do anything with it because if I want to actually do something with it I gotta bring it local before I open it right.
Speaker 1: so you always you have one.
Speaker 1: you have a terabyte drive that you use for All your current editings right yep, and when you actually get the finished video It's only a few hundred megabytes.
Speaker 0: No, no you kidding.
Speaker 0: Are you kidding?
Speaker 0: the?
Speaker 0: the triple threat that I put online got just the YouTube the 720p Rendered versions, how big do you think that was?
Speaker 1: Like for how much video?
Speaker 1: how long it's?
Speaker 0: 58 minutes of video 720p.
Speaker 1: That should only be like like you know a few hundred megabytes.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know.
Speaker 1: now wait are you talking about the raw avi's?
Speaker 0: no?
Speaker 0: I'm talking about the h.264.
Speaker 1: h.264 should be a lot smaller than that.
Speaker 1: No you did it wrong.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't because you can download full-length feature-length blu-ray rips that are not that big.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and part of it is like three hour movies if you're ready.
Speaker 0: I rendered it the way YouTube said.
Speaker 0: this is exactly how you should render it for YouTube And it was about 700 megabytes per 20 megabyte or not?
Speaker 0: 20 megabyte 20 minute shot on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but you the thing is the.
Speaker 1: you the encodings that YouTube has are gonna be you try to download the h.264 from YouTube.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be a lot smaller that you download the highest quality version actually.
Speaker 0: It's the same size.
Speaker 0: It's almost the same file I uploaded.
Speaker 1: hmm That's very straight anyway.
Speaker 0: However the cool thing is I don't need to keep those because I can just re-render anytime I want from the project.
Speaker 1: well it takes forever though.
Speaker 0: Yeah How big do you think?
Speaker 0: the point is?
Speaker 1: you have a working drive that you use for the video currently working on and then in?
Speaker 1: Storage drives.
Speaker 1: you need a terabyte every two years.
Speaker 1: not a problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's only for those conventions if I never do any other video like a certain project.
Speaker 1: We're talking about yeah Okay, so you know what they have two terabyte drives now and soon.
Speaker 1: They'll have five terabyte drives.
Speaker 1: You know what they have now.
Speaker 0: six hundred megabyte SSDs huh six hundred megabytes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a lot.
Speaker 1: I mean gigabytes.
Speaker 1: I Remember sorry sorry gigabytes.
Speaker 1: I remember
Speaker 0: when I was a kid and one of my friends was like yeah I copied the CD to my computer, and I was like you goddamn motherfucker I full installed
Speaker 1: mech warrior 2 500 megabyte on my 720 megabyte hard drive because
Speaker 0: you were in the same boat I was in when you were a kid.
Speaker 0: the Computer was yours to control because no one else in the family knew what was up.
Speaker 1: and then I delete it and then I would Install full install something else.
Speaker 1: yeah, it would be so fast Because you fold install.
Speaker 1: But I mean one time my mom everyone that was that was you people don't remember like back in the day That was that when you install the game It would actually say do you want to do the wuss install or read off the CD?
Speaker 1: Do you want to do the medium install the full install?
Speaker 0: So it always had the full installs.
Speaker 0: full install was like the ludicrous option like no way no one's ever gonna do.
Speaker 1: sometimes There'll be five different options of how much you want to install to the disk nowadays.
Speaker 1: There's none of that.
Speaker 1: It's just install and that's it you must install.
Speaker 0: I remember trying to give my mom level of install.
Speaker 0: buy me a second CD rom drive So I wouldn't have to swap CDs so often.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're playing like winkamander or Under a Killing Moon Tex Murphy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was a seven or phantasmagoria.
Speaker 0: It was like seven or eight CDs.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I've been like one DVD.
Speaker 0: but I remember a couple of times my parents would complain because the computer ran out of space and I and Basically they didn't realize this because I had deleted everything and filled it up with games On my 540 megabyte hard drive.
Speaker 1: pretty much like install a game delete a game install a game Delete a game install a game, you know, yeah, but I remembered like when I figured out oh the save files are there.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna back those up.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: So anyway, it's Monday.
Speaker 0: we haven't done a Monday show in a while.
Speaker 0: We haven't done a lot of geek nights in a while.
Speaker 1: do a lot of geek nights.
Speaker 0: now We're gonna try to not miss an episode at least until anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, hopefully we won't even miss one.
Speaker 1: Then let's get one in the hopper.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we could do that.
Speaker 0: We could do that.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: We have to make more RFE RFE.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah that other project anyway.
Speaker 0: So got a tech news got a tech news.
Speaker 1: There's been a ton of tech news, but there's only one that I really want to talk about.
Speaker 1: really Yeah, let's talk about geo hots.
Speaker 0: Ah Geo hots.
Speaker 1: Do you know the deal with geo hot?
Speaker 0: I know the deal.
Speaker 0: Okay So what do you want to talk about?
Speaker 0: the the act of doing it the act of disseminated it?
Speaker 0: Do we want to talk about the ludicrous lawsuits?
Speaker 1: Well, I want to talk about.
Speaker 1: he's fighting back against the lawsuit, right and this is the interesting part is is that it's you know There's a whole thing on grok law that has all the loi-ing right.
Speaker 1: if you are if you cuz I'm obviously gonna get it all Completely wrong.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we are not lawyers as you listeners.
Speaker 0: Tell us on a daily basis.
Speaker 1: No kidding But basically he's fighting back and it's actually really interesting.
Speaker 1: now He's fighting back of course mostly in a very loy way saying the jurisdiction is wrong, right?
Speaker 0: I had a game as a kid called jurisdiction and you had to object to questioning in court.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: That's all I got.
Speaker 1: Okay So he's basically saying like look you shouldn't be able to sue me in California or wherever it is.
Speaker 1: You should have to sue me in Jersey where I live.
Speaker 1: It's like you know that because it's like hey You know, I live in Jersey.
Speaker 1: if this crime was committed if there was a crime committed it was in Jersey.
Speaker 1: That's you should have to come after me.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't be able to have to come out to me in California just because I own a blog.
Speaker 0: it's I as a non lawyer agree with that Assuming there's many other reasons assuming that his hosting is also in Jersey.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's those things in Jersey.
Speaker 1: Well, where is it?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think that I think that's where they're getting him.
Speaker 1: That's weird like that because there's many other reasons for his trying to move the jurisdictions, right?
Speaker 1: One of them.
Speaker 1: It's like M Where was it?
Speaker 1: They couldn't prove that they had yet to offer any proof that he accepted the PS the PlayStation Network terms of service.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: They failed to offer any proof that the terms of service could be applicable to him even assuming everything they said is true.
Speaker 1: There's also a bunch of questions that he's being sued by Sony America as CEA Sony Computer Entertainment America, right?
Speaker 1: But if you look on a PlayStation 3 box Everything on the box says all rights Sony in Japan.
Speaker 1: So like SCEA Are you even allowed to sue him?
Speaker 1: Sony Japan should have to sue.
Speaker 1: Sony Japan is the owner.
Speaker 0: I didn't even think of that.
Speaker 1: Right and it's it's all this stuff That's you know, especially the stuff pertaining to terms of service.
Speaker 1: That is extremely interesting.
Speaker 1: plus it's like his is a hardware hack theoretically Right, oh there's also and all these terms of service are for the software and they can't even prove that he accepted terms of service For the software or bought any software.
Speaker 1: It was just hardware.
Speaker 1: So it's like ooh Does the GMC even apply to the hardware?
Speaker 1: it's a physical thing and it's not.
Speaker 1: he's not caught right?
Speaker 1: It's not a GMCA issue.
Speaker 0: then never mind all the weird follow-up complications.
Speaker 0: Why did it?
Speaker 0: when someone is there firmwares?
Speaker 1: Is that now software?
Speaker 0: Remember when someone tweeted it at a Sony guy and he retweeted it with an answer like a response Yeah, Sony published the code.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I can tell you the code.
Speaker 0: the code is short enough to tattoo on my arm.
Speaker 1: But yeah read this thing on grok law, right?
Speaker 1: Which has all the loi-ing bits for you lawyers and it's really really interesting and it should make nerds Kind of excited to see someone fight back Against this kind of thing at least a little bit if we can even get a tiny victory out of this like Terms of service not applicable.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, I miss extremely small case.
Speaker 0: I recall ribbon Scott circa 2005 saying something very important that is coming up yet again someday.
Speaker 0: someday terms of service and shrink-wrap are going to really be tested in court and Whichever way that bone falls we win.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because if terms of service are as draconian and restrictive and able to be applied to people as the court governments and corporations Want them to be I'm putting some crazy shrink-wrap on everything I ever do and if they're not Party time.
Speaker 0: Oh my you know, but yeah, it's good.
Speaker 1: You know, I think this is most.
Speaker 1: this is probably not gonna be anything like that.
Speaker 1: It's just a jurisdiction battle, you know, but it's still.
Speaker 1: it's still pretty neat to see someone try to fight.
Speaker 0: So are we in accord here though?
Speaker 0: I think in terms of the actual I don't think that any crime was committed at any point.
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: Now I would agree that if someone used and I definitely don't think even if there was a crime committed You know, I definitely don't think any moral wrong was done.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: if say someone else using the information He provided made a bootleg copy of a game signed it all legit and then sold it in outright piracy form All
Speaker 1: right
Speaker 0: I think that guy is liable for all the copyright stuff and I would be cool with that guy going to jail
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: but I'm not cool with one.
Speaker 0: that guy going to jail longer than a murderer That's for sure - that guy being fined more than the money in the world That's also true.
Speaker 0: or three geohot in any way being culpable.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's like if I tell you hey Scott Did you know you could put bullets and guns and then you shoot a bunch of people?
Speaker 0: Is that my fault?
Speaker 1: No, it's like.
Speaker 1: why does uh, you know if that was the case then like, you know The heckler and Koch people who would be in jail like that of the death penalty.
Speaker 0: This is why the DMCA bothers me say I buy I don't know a box of muffins and in the box of muffins There's just a little wooden box.
Speaker 0: It says do not open or I will sue you and there's nothing even in the box.
Speaker 0: how like.
Speaker 0: That's what the DMCA is.
Speaker 0: They're basically saying they can sue you They can take you to court because you open a box that you bought and own.
Speaker 0: that was given to you.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's like it says don't remove tag for mattress or whatever, but Well, I'm allowed to remove that because I'm the end user.
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying I cannot resell the mattress without that tab, but I can't resell a mattress anyway, because you bugs.
Speaker 1: We live in New York now.
Speaker 1: The point is right is you know, there's the old thing about removing tags for mattresses, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you can't buzz me for removing the tag from my own mattress.
Speaker 1: You know if I want to un DRM my own the own thing I bought an iTunes.
Speaker 0: now if I redistribute the thing I bought an iTunes publicly then yes I don't think that's morally wrong, but it is technically legally wrong.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: I'm okay with the court system going after that.
Speaker 0: I'm just I'm.
Speaker 0: I'm one of the nerds is only mad when they actually come into my personal computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, so there's an article on slashdot and one of my co-workers get this.
Speaker 0: he had never heard of slashdot.
Speaker 0: He's a super techie smart guy who just never heard of it.
Speaker 1: Well, how is he?
Speaker 1: How old is he?
Speaker 0: He's like two or three years younger than us.
Speaker 1: Okay, that makes sense.
Speaker 1: cuz slashdot faded and other things came.
Speaker 0: he's already of course.
Speaker 0: so I was so.
Speaker 0: one day I was like you should read slashdot.
Speaker 0: He's like what.
Speaker 0: why isn't it weird?
Speaker 1: How like we were NES and 16-bit kids, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, people just a few years younger than us like people who were freshmen in college when we were just slightly more than freshmen in College.
Speaker 1: they were all PlayStation.
Speaker 1: It's like that.
Speaker 1: the NES and 16-bit era was like really long.
Speaker 1: if you're just a couple years younger than us How could you be PlayStation which is the generation after?
Speaker 0: look at childhood.
Speaker 0: you me and all of our friends who were two three even?
Speaker 0: Four years older than us are clearly children of the 80s like the 80s really 90s.
Speaker 1: the thing is we knew 80s cuz we lived for eight years.
Speaker 1: We also knew 90s.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing we were children 90s more than we knew.
Speaker 0: we knew the 90s But we were children of the 80s.
Speaker 1: like our cultural heritage Is more 90s and 80s but there is still.
Speaker 1: it's a great deal of both.
Speaker 1: It's like look it's like 60 40 60 90s 48.
Speaker 0: So you're not letting me finish.
Speaker 0: a lot of our friends who were three four even five years older than us who?
Speaker 0: Remember a lot more of the 80s?
Speaker 0: their childhood culture is almost identical to ours.
Speaker 0: Yet people who are even one or two years younger than us have a completely different childhood culture.
Speaker 1: There was some sort of barrier there.
Speaker 0: There's there was a line where something happened.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure like what?
Speaker 0: Cultural event it was.
Speaker 1: it's like people born in like, you know 87 88 like the late 80s.
Speaker 1: It's like they were all.
Speaker 1: they're like completely different.
Speaker 1: They're all PlayStation.
Speaker 1: They somehow missed 8 and 16 bits.
Speaker 0: I mean people born in 1984 actually don't remember a lot of things that are just common knowledge to the 82s.
Speaker 0: Could two years be that much of a difference?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it was interesting that he's like.
Speaker 0: hey Did you see this article on reddit?
Speaker 0: and I'm like, huh an article on reddit.
Speaker 0: Did I see it?
Speaker 0: You didn't give me any clues as to what this article is about.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna say no and he's like, yeah the one about how you shouldn't work on Wall Street.
Speaker 0: and then I'm like no and I had slashed out open on my desktop because I just got into work and I was checking the news before I did my bullshit and That was the article that was just posted to slash that.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I love slash shot, but it is slow.
Speaker 0: the article basically makes the roundabout argument that You shouldn't let geeks and nerds and smart people work on Wall Street because smart people working on Wall Street is the problem.
Speaker 0: It's taking all the smart people away from every other human endeavor.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: Now this argument has been made a lot.
Speaker 0: I see people like espousing it on blogs.
Speaker 0: it gets debated a lot, but this is.
Speaker 0: this is kind of a really comprehensive article of all the reasons why this is harming our Society or technology.
Speaker 1: it is harming the society.
Speaker 1: It is harming technology.
Speaker 0: Yeah But my question to all the people who complain about this is that would you turn down a job?
Speaker 0: Where you would make more money than you currently pay in taxes to do less work than you're doing now.
Speaker 0: Yep would you actually?
Speaker 1: No, I wouldn't turn the job down I'd be like hells.
Speaker 1: yeah show me the money.
Speaker 0: that's why I work on Wall Street.
Speaker 0: That's why everyone who works on Wall Street works on Wall Street.
Speaker 0: I worked at IBM.
Speaker 0: I made less money there that I pay in taxes.
Speaker 0: now literally I worked in hospitals in the Bronx.
Speaker 0: I did IT for hospitals like straight up like, you know The one of the places where technology could probably save more lives and help more people than any other Application in the world using IT to make health care more efficient and better.
Speaker 0: I was surrounded there By some of the dumbest people I have ever had the displeasure of working with in my entire life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I quit Entirely because I could not stand to be around those people anymore.
Speaker 1: It's a. it's a you know, it's a perverse incentive and a chicken egg and a catch-22 all at the same time, right?
Speaker 1: I like the smart people and the money are on Wall Street.
Speaker 1: So smart people go there and smart people like to be around smart people and they like more money.
Speaker 1: So they keep going to Wall Street.
Speaker 1: So that bolsters Wall Street.
Speaker 1: So now smart people are even more likely to go to Wall Street.
Speaker 0: So, you know as Emily said you're welcome to not go to Wall Street.
Speaker 1: You need to.
Speaker 1: it has to be.
Speaker 1: I mean, usually you don't want to go to the government solution But really there is no other solution.
Speaker 1: The government has to rearrange the incentives to get the smart people to leave Wall Street.
Speaker 1: There's no other way to do it.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, you're just gonna go.
Speaker 0: Scott you recall as Emily said so aptly some time ago The reason you make so much money is because you work for the money factory.
Speaker 0: I mean if I work for the candy factory, I get all the candy I can eat.
Speaker 1: Yeah Why?
Speaker 1: if you ever if anyone needs a job go work at a bank why so the money is?
Speaker 0: That was always my advice to punk kids who were like I need a job You'll be a bank teller.
Speaker 0: you realize being a bank teller when you're 16 18 Cha-ching you look like 16 to 20 bucks an hour and you can steal if you're really really good.
Speaker 0: Actually not that much cash changes.
Speaker 1: hey, I'm saying you got to be really really good Scott.
Speaker 0: you realize bank tellers in the modern era really don't touch that much money because who goes to a bank?
Speaker 1: But old people you can go in the safe.
Speaker 0: There's not that much money in that say.
Speaker 0: Oh, but the safe deposit boxes Yeah, you're gonna break into one of those.
Speaker 1: it gotta be really really good.
Speaker 1: I'm not.
Speaker 1: when I say really really I mean really really really like, you know, Ninja good I think you're better off Rob unrealistic movie action hero good not working there.
Speaker 0: besides one of the pieces of advice My dad gave me before I went off to college was don't ever rob a bank because that's a federal crime Not a state crime and you don't want to go to a federal prison.
Speaker 1: good advice.
Speaker 1: other good advice Don't don't steal mail either.
Speaker 0: It's not same reason.
Speaker 0: I guess my argument my point here is that it's not just that all the money's there.
Speaker 0: I mean doing the same IT work on Wall Street as opposed to at like to some small company.
Speaker 0: You'll get paid like twice as much.
Speaker 0: But a lot of people will work even when the money is not in their favor like they'll work for a place.
Speaker 0: That's more fun rather than the money I'd work for a place.
Speaker 0: that's more money because that's just the way the world is and I really like money.
Speaker 0: But there's kind of this sublimation of smart people.
Speaker 0: if you work with other smart people All of you collectively will draw more smart people into the organization because smart people like to work with other smart people.
Speaker 1: Yep, this is why Google, you know is the way they are.
Speaker 0: But if a company already has mostly average or stupid people it it's hard for them to get smart people or they Smart people and smart people in.
Speaker 1: and if smart people show up they get pissed off and leave.
Speaker 1: Yep, so and they're not gonna put the smart people in charge of themselves.
Speaker 1: so say you've got 50 cuz they'll fire all the smart people and dumb people.
Speaker 0: if Even one or two smart people leave all the rest are gonna evaporate away.
Speaker 0: because now there's this critical mass of dumb.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and I mean beyond that a lot of these arguments are also kind of just spurious.
Speaker 0: I mean I don't know if I personally would be making the world a better place if I'd studied mathematics Like everyone's trying to tell me to do instead of IT and if I was doing IT not on Wall Street I would have quit doing IT like three years ago because I just I was sick of that bullshit.
Speaker 0: Well, there are.
Speaker 1: I do sort.
Speaker 1: that's the only thing I agree with.
Speaker 1: it's like yes if we did You know, I can't blame anyone for going to finance, you know, I would probably go to finance too Except I work with sort of open source technologies which aren't popular in finance world.
Speaker 1: if I worked with Oracle and shit I would be all that.
Speaker 1: this is why if I was an Oracle Java guy, I'd be all over that finance.
Speaker 0: Well, this is why you're like yeah using the new version of pylons to do something.
Speaker 0: I'm like, yeah soap service As Exactly.
Speaker 1: if it wasn't for that I would totally do it too, but because I can't blame anyone for doing it.
Speaker 1: But it is true I do totally agree that because the smart people are there attracting the smart people and because the money's there it is Hurting the rest of the the industries from improving right?
Speaker 1: This is why hospitals are not so good.
Speaker 1: This is why you know, I mean technology is fine But other things are not nearly as good as they could be because the smart people are all working in technology and finance.
Speaker 0: but I think it's a kind of a cycle that started.
Speaker 1: I think really what we need to do is you need to find a Way to get a perverse incentive to get the smart people to work in public service, then we could fix some shit Pretty much.
Speaker 0: let him do what they want or pay them a lot of money.
Speaker 1: Yep Either one will get a ton of smart people to apply and also having smart people already in there without bullshit bureaucracy holding back.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'll tell you what if I could be a computer teacher like in high schools Like just.
Speaker 0: I will teach computer science to high school kids anyway.
Speaker 0: I want they could pay me 40k a year and I would do it.
Speaker 0: I need to summer off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, duh, duh, but To make the rest of the money.
Speaker 1: I need to live.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I wouldn't even like question it.
Speaker 0: But the factor is zoom.
Speaker 1: it is too much bullshit.
Speaker 0: The the barrier it's the.
Speaker 0: it's weird to me that the barrier to entry for me and a senior it seems like with Otakon.
Speaker 1: right every other convention is like cooperating with us to make the convention better and Otakon's like yeah, we don't want your free help making our convention more awesome.
Speaker 1: It's like schools are the same way that my case school.
Speaker 1: Pay me and let me be a computer teacher.
Speaker 1: Only condition is that you let me teach computers the way I want and I won't I promise I won't you know hurt the children's And they'll be like, yeah.
Speaker 1: No, it's like maybe why would you say no school?
Speaker 1: You want to start a school?
Speaker 1: It costs a lot of money.
Speaker 0: rim and Scott's school.
Speaker 1: for the gifted Ever just ribbon Scott's, you know elementary technology school K through 12 K through one might be enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah Got it.
Speaker 0: Just got a show.
Speaker 0: kid like a ti-85 and be like if you can make pong happen on this without looking at the You graduate it out.
Speaker 0: You will be a wizard.
Speaker 1: We got some ribbon Scott's wizards code.
Speaker 1: Everyone gets a hat But you don't get the robe until you graduate only the hat.
Speaker 0: So things of the day kind of old, but I forgot about this and I think it's just really clever and cute.
Speaker 0: It's just a video of a girl talking about toy snakes and it's surprisingly I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's something about the way she's like snake snake snake snake snake.
Speaker 0: That's just really adorable.
Speaker 1: I like it.
Speaker 0: It's also really smart and cool raises a math question and doesn't answer it.
Speaker 0: So you'll know what kind of person you are.
Speaker 0: if you watch it and just think that was cute You're one kind of person.
Speaker 0: if you watch it and then you start trying to solve the snake problem You're another kind of person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I started to.
Speaker 1: I was like man.
Speaker 1: I wish I knew the solution to that problem, but I don't know the math.
Speaker 1: I'm not even gonna try.
Speaker 1: I'm Lazy.
Speaker 1: nerd snakes next next next next next thing.
Speaker 1: So this is old game very old game named QWOP.
Speaker 1: you may have heard of it.
Speaker 1: It's a flash game.
Speaker 1: It's semi famous.
Speaker 0: It's also known as Jesus motherfucking Christ.
Speaker 0: Fuck.
Speaker 0: this game.
Speaker 1: and basically the game if you haven't seen it right is a game where you use the four buttons on the keyboard QW o and P and the buttons control the calves and thighs on The left leg and the calves and thighs on the right leg.
Speaker 1: now This runner and you're trying to dude break his neck repeated You're trying to run as far as you can using just these four buttons and the game as hard as balls and unintuitive.
Speaker 1: now the guy.
Speaker 1: That's not my thing of the day, even though maybe we'll link to it.
Speaker 1: Anyway It's an old famous game.
Speaker 1: You should have heard of This guy who made that game made a new game called gurp gi RP and the way this game works is it's.
Speaker 1: it's actually better.
Speaker 1: I think it's better than QWOP.
Speaker 1: It's Just it still has that same frustrating keyboard aspect to it But you can make non-zero progress on your first try which makes it a little bit.
Speaker 1: You know, it's more accessible than QWOP, but not by much.
Speaker 0: I enjoy the inaccessibility of QWOP because that's where the fun comes from playing it and swearing at it.
Speaker 1: It's so weird.
Speaker 1: Like how could you make a game that was intentionally poorly designed yet that works in the game's favor?
Speaker 1: I think it's like It's like if you were making perfume and you put poop smell in there and it became the most popular for view.
Speaker 0: No, but look at what it's doing.
Speaker 0: Look at the elegant message.
Speaker 0: The game is actually a pretty good analogy of how you walk in terms of.
Speaker 0: you know Muscles are contracting in this order and our brains just do that.
Speaker 0: But when we have to think, you know calf thigh calf thigh, it's way harder to walk.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think QWOP matches real thigh and calf But I think it's a suitable analogy for the kind of you're getting too deep into a shitty little game QWOP.
Speaker 0: I think about what happens if I'm trying to raise and lower my arm.
Speaker 0: How many muscles are working in concert?
Speaker 0: and the abstract thought I'm thinking is simply make the arm go up and down in Scott's face.
Speaker 1: All right, you're thinking too hard about this.
Speaker 0: All right, we got a meta moment.
Speaker 0: very briefly we were at the penny arcade expo.
Speaker 0: We read zinc icon if you wanted to see our panels from the penny arcade expo And you were not able to either because the room was full or because you were it wasn't full.
Speaker 1: The room was almost full.
Speaker 0: It was full on this Sunday for one of them, but it wasn't full on Friday.
Speaker 1: I wasn't a hundred percent full is 99% full.
Speaker 1: You could have walked in and sat down.
Speaker 0: Well, they shut the door.
Speaker 0: So no one was gonna come in.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's true.
Speaker 0: The room was pretty much full.
Speaker 0: But basically if you couldn't get into the panel for whatever reason a lot of people, you know Don't go to PAX because they're they're dumb.
Speaker 0: Well, we did all of our panels at PAX and Through the power of video.
Speaker 0: I have put one of them on YouTube and I will try to put the other two on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Cuz I have time.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we're gonna do every panel ever cuz I want people to go to the conventions Actually have something to see if we because we repeat panels a lot So I'd like to mostly put up retired panels or panels are probably not gonna do again But panels that are brand new probably don't want to put them on YouTube.
Speaker 0: At the same time it'll be good because we have this problem at conventions where we'll do a panel and have the people who Show up or people who already know who we are and half of them have already seen that panel at another con.
Speaker 1: Then why are they coming to that panel?
Speaker 0: I don't know they but they do Hopefully.
Speaker 1: what we can do though is if we put things on YouTube, then we'll be forced to come up with new panels.
Speaker 1: But we need new panels.
Speaker 0: We have a lot of new panels.
Speaker 0: We just haven't done them anywhere yet.
Speaker 1: We need more.
Speaker 0: I mean look we had almost all new panels for PAX East.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we get.
Speaker 1: we get a lot of new conventions.
Speaker 0: all of our new all of our anime Boston panels are effectively new because we Only tested them once.
Speaker 0: a zinc icon a kinetic on kinetic on a zinc icon.
Speaker 0: Thank I can.
Speaker 1: we trotted out the old Classics and so they asked us to do we got to do the panels.
Speaker 1: They ask yeah We can't you know.
Speaker 1: just tell them these are the panels We're doing because they then they might just reject all that you know.
Speaker 1: We suggest these are the three new ones that we're only doing these three the big.
Speaker 1: we don't want any of those three.
Speaker 1: We want these old three.
Speaker 1: We don't want to do the old three.
Speaker 1: Well, we're not doing anything.
Speaker 0: But anyway all that aside the book club book as soon as Scott finishes reading it.
Speaker 1: I read one I still haven't read what Jack who's hyperspace?
Speaker 0: I'll start reading it today And we will be at anime Boston doing our usual panels.
Speaker 1: So let's do the book club book definitely a week from Thursday on that Thursday the next Thursday episode.
Speaker 0: So we've realized and we did some shows on topics related to this like remember we did that show on like NTP and all those Different things.
Speaker 0: but it's coming to my attention more and more that many many people who claim to be IT people or claim to know about technology Don't know how to administer Servers well at all.
Speaker 1: I mean system administration is sort of a dying thing, right?
Speaker 1: Which is a problem because it's like in the olden days system administration was like a legit.
Speaker 1: It was a legit deal.
Speaker 1: You needed people to administer systems, right.
Speaker 1: people who you know?
Speaker 1: Knew how to use a server because using a server was different than using a regular computer, right?
Speaker 1: It was like especially if you had mainframes and things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you needed programmers to write the software that went on the mainframes.
Speaker 0: Then you also kind of like an engineer on a train who sits there and pulls the levers and makes the software go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's not just people using to use that.
Speaker 1: There's the software that you're actually you know, there's like two different users, right?
Speaker 1: There's the person who you know takes this software say Microsoft Word right and produces documents but there's also a Separate person who has to install Microsoft Word and make sure it keeps running and keep it up to date and all those sorts of Things that you might think.
Speaker 1: well, that's the same person as the user right especially on a home computer.
Speaker 1: but in a company when you've got a mainframe it's like all right.
Speaker 1: who installs and configures exchange right?
Speaker 1: a programmer made exchange and A user opens outlook and uses exchange.
Speaker 1: But some guy has to install a copy of Windows Server install exchange configure exchange Set all the SMTP settings and all those things and that is the administrator and it's a job that was needed a great deal Especially in the windows and mainframe days.
Speaker 0: So I will argue that it is still needed.
Speaker 0: It is still needed.
Speaker 1: It is just needed less and in cases where it is still done.
Speaker 0: It is done often Saying it's needed less now.
Speaker 0: I would agree with you in that technologies made it a lot easier to run a server But at the same time that in assumes that the people who originally set up any given server Set it up with even a reasonable degree of cop.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it's what I'm saying is needed less not because it's it's not needed But it's because there are so many services out there that basically outsource this, right?
Speaker 1: So it's centralized and there are many tools that allow it to be sort of the scale of it Right.
Speaker 1: So, you know, for example, you'll have something like Amazon.
Speaker 1: So you just click a button and you get a new server.
Speaker 1: You didn't need another administrator to do this because there's like a few administrators at Amazon that can administer a lot more systems per administrator and with tools like puppy and all these other things and You know a lot of times if you have some software and you want to get it running on a server You know, you can get like a managed hosting.
Speaker 1: So there's one administrator who would?
Speaker 1: normally you would need one administrator per host.
Speaker 1: You know purse first system, but now one guy can administer so many systems at a data center Especially with cloud services you need less administrators.
Speaker 0: It doesn't mean that you don't need any only from the perspective though primarily of consumers or small companies because anywhere else there's a ton of in-house servers where there are Administrators doing physical servers and data centers.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I'm just saying overall in the world the number of administrators We need is fewer.
Speaker 0: I don't think it is.
Speaker 0: I think it's more because there's far more computers.
Speaker 0: There are more computers Yes, and also those computers many of them.
Speaker 0: The only reason we have fewer administrators is because in my experience pretty much every server I've ever run into out in the wild world like not at the place I work now and but like when I worked say at IBM and I would be tasked with hey There's this server and the guy who was maintaining it and you know just system administering it Retired see what it needs and take care of it.
Speaker 1: And well, is it running right now?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it needs nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I log into it to see you know, what's up and it's a disaster and eventually it fails And there's almost no way to get it going again.
Speaker 0: just I mean and there's a million different topics we could get into.
Speaker 0: but I really want to focus tonight just on logging because I think most people who have computers don't actually Really understand what logs are.
Speaker 0: no, not at all.
Speaker 0: Don't use them.
Speaker 1: Don't interact Me even me.
Speaker 1: I didn't really get logs until like the late 90s early 2000s You know just because I was using like DAW systems and Windows systems where logs don't really sort of exist.
Speaker 1: But I knew that logs were a thing because if you watched any sort of movies of hacking they would talk about logs and removing Yourself from the law.
Speaker 0: I saw him in the logs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like I never saw actual logs or worked with them until much later.
Speaker 1: But now I know all about logs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't think most people do I mean, I would say that nine times out of ten whenever there's a problem like a server just won't boot or there's a problem Just look at our log messages and you'll see exactly what happened.
Speaker 0: Like oh the oom killer went amok because you used up all your memory.
Speaker 0: Yep, or something like just painfully just Blunderingly obvious.
Speaker 0: but yet most of the IT people I've run into out there don't actually even know that there's a bar log Or even that what bar is.
Speaker 0: well, really?
Speaker 1: That's I mean like.
Speaker 1: I know The people.
Speaker 1: I know they know there are logs and they know to look at them.
Speaker 1: but often the logs are Misconfigured or they don't know which log to look in.
Speaker 1: or even if they find the log to look in They don't know how to read the log So they can't understand what they found.
Speaker 1: or or they'll see something that's irrelevant and think it's relevant just because it's an error message.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well people the simple thing about logs is kind of like rims pro tip number one But it's a legit pro tip not an internet ironic pro tip.
Speaker 0: If you have if you're diagnosing a problem in an unfamiliar environment and in the logs you see an error And you think it's related to your problem.
Speaker 0: Look at the previous few weeks logs and see how commonly that error occurs.
Speaker 0: Because you're gonna in var log secure.
Speaker 0: You're probably gonna see a whole bunch of bullshit even on a well running server.
Speaker 0: Yep Plenty of it but like simple things like that.
Speaker 0: I don't think people know and I think back to our IT They didn't teach us shit about logs.
Speaker 0: No, they didn't teach anyone like oh, you know Our log messages and the terminal server syslog how to use it this log NG.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I use our syslog.
Speaker 1: I use this network, you know, what's it called centralization of logging?
Speaker 0: Well, you're remotely you have log rotating Never mind.
Speaker 0: No one monitors their logs.
Speaker 1: Oh hell no we do and it's really simple.
Speaker 0: just run some sort of like Process that just reads your logs in semi real time and you know regular expression wise pull out errors and send them to someone.
Speaker 0: Yep, and yet no one even does that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think my primary blame really is gonna fall on Windows Mmm, because most people learn computers through Windows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and like I said, I've never in my life Successfully diagnosed a problem by looking at the Windows Event Manager.
Speaker 1: Okay, so that's the one thing.
Speaker 1: all systems that aren't Windows pretty much, right?
Speaker 1: They keep logs in text files and you can just look at the text files.
Speaker 1: and there are various tools you can use To parse these text files and Scan them and get information out of them and you know very easy and standard ways that always work.
Speaker 1: But in Windows all the logs are in this weird GUI.
Speaker 1: It's really hard to figure out and is non obvious.
Speaker 1: Well pretty much only Windows experts can go in there and get it.
Speaker 0: you realize there is a secret land of real logging in Windows Really?
Speaker 0: There's the kernel logs.
Speaker 1: How do you get there?
Speaker 0: So I Acquired this from a vendor a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I have it at work and it's this debug viewer that basically shows you the real-time output of the Windows kernel console.
Speaker 0: Okay, so it's basically the system dot out or the kind of like.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to think of a good analogy for Linux Like, you know when you write a crappy program or you see a crappy service that just spit shit out into the console.
Speaker 0: Yeah So ever log into a server is root and you see just all this crap flooding your screen Interrupting your commands because someone didn't set up this log only on a really old shitty system.
Speaker 0: well Windows has something like that.
Speaker 0: that's hidden.
Speaker 0: so you run a capture basically of the kernel like the debug view logs of Windows and you can see just everything that's flying by and A lot of Windows services.
Speaker 0: actually you can configure them to log different log levels to that and then capture that And then your server crashes because the program that reads is a piece of shit.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: But yeah, let's let's talk about.
Speaker 1: let's do some topics in in logging, right?
Speaker 1: So let's let's first tell us about log rotating because Pete this is something that's done often day today automatically, right?
Speaker 1: So if you install an Ubuntu system or Fedora system all the log rotation is already pre-configured.
Speaker 1: So, you know, that's good.
Speaker 0: in one way I really agree with desktop Linux and even like low-level servers intelligent defaults are better than good customizability any day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but wait, I just said that the iPhone is the best phone anyway.
Speaker 0: anyway, the problem with that is if Someone working for say a financial institution or someone working in any industry where there's regulation like telecoms there are legal requirements for certain kinds of logs and records being kept for certain numbers of years and If you just build a default Ubuntu server, you're not gonna have two years worth of your logs.
Speaker 1: No, see basically what the deal with log rotating is this you got logs So everything that happens on the computer is being written down, right?
Speaker 1: It's like a shit, you know logs go all the way back, you know to ship's logs.
Speaker 0: on boats perhaps even older than that you basically perhaps got All the records we have of the Sumerian language.
Speaker 0: are logs of grain shipments being received.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right It's like, you know, someone just writes down everything that happens well on a computer Which has such incredible power and is doing a lot of work and isn't running Windows.
Speaker 1: a lot of things happen all the time Which means the log gets really big and which means the log is going to eat up all your hard drive space.
Speaker 1: Eventually, and if you have a lot, you know if the sudden bursts of activity You could have trouble if your hard drive gets full.
Speaker 1: Which is why number one you always want to keep your logs on a separate partition from everything else.
Speaker 1: So worst-case scenario if that fills up and you're out of disk space You won't run out of disk space for your actual application.
Speaker 1: You have downtime.
Speaker 1: You only fail to log.
Speaker 0: Let's zoom out a little bit.
Speaker 0: Really, you know the Linux file system.
Speaker 0: kids out there like.
Speaker 0: there's VAR and all those different places.
Speaker 0: I keep saying VAR because VAR log is where you should log everything Yep And there's VAR temp and all the different places under VAR.
Speaker 0: VAR is the shit that changes that you don't necessarily care about.
Speaker 0: VAR is where you VAR itself should be on a separate partition because VAR is the most likely thing to fill up other than temp Yep, and you don't want that to hose your whole server.
Speaker 0: Nope Also, you know log rotation.
Speaker 0: I mean there's different ways to rotate logs circular rotation.
Speaker 0: You've got one file that just kind of gets read.
Speaker 0: the oldest records in it get overwritten as newer records come in.
Speaker 1: Well, that's a that's a ring log.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah ring log Because it writes you write in a ring.
Speaker 1: But yeah basically log.
Speaker 1: the idea of log rotation is that when the log gets too big either by you judging by how big it is or Judging by how long it's been since you last rotated you can either like zip up the logs and start a fresh blank one.
Speaker 1: You know, just maybe archive logs or delete old logs in according to some schedule.
Speaker 1: Right such that your hard drive space won't fill up.
Speaker 1: But you'll have enough backlog that you can solve problems and look things up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just rotate them such that you know We have a different file for every day - so say there's a problem and I don't have one 400 terabyte log file from the last hundred years to grep through.
Speaker 0: Instead I can look at the log for the day the problem happened.
Speaker 1: Yep
Speaker 0: Now speaking of the size of the logs, I mean, you know, it sounds like it'd be complex like alright Maybe I'll write a little script that'll say like every day if the logs more than 10 megabytes I should it turns out that in Unix and Linux Anything that anyone who administered servers back in the day would have to do more than once is already built in?
Speaker 1: Yeah this nowadays usually there's an automatic log rotator.
Speaker 1: You can look in like Etsy log rotate dot D and there'll be configuration files that automatically set up log rotator.
Speaker 0: anything you would think you would want to do with logs is already built into any Linux computer and people just don't realize it because It's handled automatically by the distribution.
Speaker 1: But if you're an administrator, you actually need to look at that.
Speaker 1: You can't just let the.
Speaker 1: you know, the even if you're using Ubuntu the defaults might work for you, which would be fine.
Speaker 1: But you better check them at least to make sure that they're working for you and complying You know with whatever regulations you have and also with whatever you want, you know, maybe you want something different.
Speaker 0: So when you're trying to you know Move on to another topic.
Speaker 0: when you're actually trying to debug a problem in the logs, like there's a problem I'm going to look into logs.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: You're really like knowing your way around Linux as in.
Speaker 0: you know tail head Grab rap less said less not so much more.
Speaker 1: a lot a lot of people right?
Speaker 1: I always see this mistake all the time.
Speaker 1: They try to open a log file in their text editor and then it crashes because it loads the entire log file into memory.
Speaker 1: They don't realize that you need to use, you know, some sort of pager like less which is the other preferred pager But you can use more if you want which will allow you to easily look at a gigantic text file without eating up all the memory on the machine and crushing you.
Speaker 0: or Grap, crap is one of the most powerful tools in your tools.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you don't know grab and regular expressions.
Speaker 1: You can't be a system administrator of Unix is regular Expressions are literally like the currency of what I was hiring system administrators.
Speaker 1: The first questions I would ask them in the interview would be regular expression related.
Speaker 1: if they didn't know I just like goodbye.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much how I interview people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I asked him.
Speaker 0: So if the question I always ask is so say you're troubleshooting a problem All right
Speaker 1: And let's see if I can get this question right and you've
Speaker 0: got to look through the log files like say it's an Apache problem Someone's like some module isn't working right or something now, of course I'm watching them to see if their eyes glaze over when I say Apache module you know, you got to watch for these things.
Speaker 0: but So a problem happened the other day and you know, the guy's username and the IP came from.
Speaker 0: How would you go about finding out what the problem was?
Speaker 0: Like what would be your steps?
Speaker 1: I know is I know his username.
Speaker 0: I know his username.
Speaker 1: I could grab the logs.
Speaker 0: All right, you already win you You're already past.
Speaker 1: I could just do.
Speaker 0: grab space username space file that is slash borrow slash log slash Apache slash access and you already know more than most people I've ever Interviewed for any position at any company I've ever worked for Sad.
Speaker 0: so then the follow-on is with Greg because you know people.
Speaker 0: usually they can use Greg kind of.
Speaker 0: hopefully I would say Yeah, they can't.
Speaker 1: they can't actually get for a regular expression, but they can grab for something.
Speaker 1: See, the thing is you got to be really good.
Speaker 1: You're like me, but you can use find and xargs and grab together.
Speaker 0: That's when you get hired and a raise, you know I never ever need to use find or xargs.
Speaker 1: really because what if you want to grab all the files?
Speaker 1: Recursively in a directory to have the same extension and you want to grep all of them.
Speaker 0: Uh, that's trivial.
Speaker 1: How do you do it?
Speaker 0: I do it from the command line.
Speaker 0: I usually do something like grep my giant regular expression and then I put you know, the file name dot star.
Speaker 1: But what if you want to do for example all HTML files recursively from the current folder grep start on HTML.
Speaker 1: That doesn't work That's not.
Speaker 1: that's not gonna do.
Speaker 0: actually I set up my shell to where that does work.
Speaker 1: What you would do is you to find dot dash Start HTML pipe, you know, sorry space grab, you know
Speaker 0: I do find something when there are too many files to do a listing When there are too many files to be arguments I'll
Speaker 1: have to show you the secrets of fine because clearly I'm in more advanced in the Unix department than you are
Speaker 0: because I've set Up my system to where that's unnecessary.
Speaker 0: Yeah I have because all my log files are name of demon Dates all in one line dot and then they roll over like 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 up to like You know nine hundred a thousand ten thousand whatever every day.
Speaker 1: What do you want to look at every Monday?
Speaker 0: Oh I never need to look at a previous day's logs for something like that.
Speaker 0: That's that's a whole different.
Speaker 0: We don't keep my.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying there's reasons to do things like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm saying I'm saying my daily work.
Speaker 0: I don't need to do that.
Speaker 1: I do that quite often usually because I'll have a big code base and I'll for example want to look for a variable but I know it's not gonna be an HTML files only Python files.
Speaker 1: So I'll grep only the py files, but recursively.
Speaker 1: I did a lot.
Speaker 1: So usually I know why I accept aliases for that.
Speaker 0: Usually I know what pile of problems in but I'm doing something more like trace a particular like execution or thread.
Speaker 1: I'll do something like I'm removing functionality from an application So I need to find every place that that functionality is used to remove it.
Speaker 0: I have more things like figure out why something happened to an order with this ID And I grew up through the logs for that ID and then I pieced together the story of that order through the logs.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm sort matters a lot actually for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got to use sort you ever use cut and paste.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, he's cut all the time because we use all your logs are delimited properly.
Speaker 0: They're delimited to it to an insane degree.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 1: Very good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's talk about writing log files.
Speaker 0: Cuz people don't think about that.
Speaker 0: you think sysadmins don't know what to do with logs.
Speaker 0: Developers don't know what to do with fucking law.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when you write a log, right you got to remember this is gonna be read by someone But that someone is gonna be using the UNIX tools to read it to read it more easily.
Speaker 0: You can't just be like yeah If my code runs into an exception just write the exception to the logs like this multi-line monster.
Speaker 0: No My log files are log channel space time and date and all other that stuff space like name of demon.
Speaker 1: You need to have a standard format and if possible a standard format for every log regardless of what it is.
Speaker 1: Yep, that way it's easy for somebody to you know easily parse that log to find what they're looking for.
Speaker 1: if every log file is a different format and if the format isn't consistent then It's like it's such a pain in the ass to find anything in it because it's like.
Speaker 1: I want to find everything with the date.
Speaker 1: Well half the things in this log file don't even have a date.
Speaker 0: or what about log levels?
Speaker 0: I want to find all the actual problems.
Speaker 1: I want to find everything.
Speaker 1: that's an error, but nothing.
Speaker 1: that's a warning.
Speaker 1: But I still want to log the warnings So they might want to see them another time, but I only want to see the errors right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah If the word error isn't there in a way that I can easily grep for it Then I'm that's gonna become impossible to do.
Speaker 0: working with shitty logs I will often just be like a case insensitive grep for the word error warning Problem fatal and I'll just see what I find.
Speaker 0: The best way to do it is actually have defined log channels Or like you can say it to Jesus because you want it to be at the front of each line.
Speaker 0: So you can do the front based grepping which is a huge performance benefit.
Speaker 1: Another thing that you can do if you're a really good system administrator Right and you have a shitty log file or even a good log file.
Speaker 1: You can whip out the heavy guns Set an awk.
Speaker 1: Oh man If you get an awk is like, you know said is like an m16 but awk is like a minigun.
Speaker 0: awk is like the whole hog.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you can use awk then you you have won.
Speaker 0: you win the game, you know I'll admit is I don't use awk often enough to like.
Speaker 1: I haven't used awk since RIT, but I know it's there.
Speaker 0: Yep, I got a look at a reference.
Speaker 1: when I use awk most of the time It's like the bomb you keep in the closet and you don't use it because you never need to actually use a bomb.
Speaker 0: you can Always get by with a hand class.
Speaker 0: at RIT That was literally the whole first half of the class was said at awk.
Speaker 1: I took that class.
Speaker 0: Yep They gave you that book.
Speaker 0: That was like a little said book and then a big awk book.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I mean I've heard stories of like guys teaching AI Programming classes using awk and it actually was better than lists and I could believe it.
Speaker 0: yeah, because awk is really good at taking a text file that has stuff in it and Processing that text into another form that is surprisingly readable.
Speaker 1: Yeah basically the way awk works is you create an awk script and an awk script is basically a list of regular expressions.
Speaker 1: and What to do if one of those regular expressions is matched?
Speaker 0: So if I find fatal warning or error in this in the first end characters of any given line do this.
Speaker 0: then take these four Columns delimited by these two different sets of delimiters and put them in this database, right?
Speaker 1: Hey basically You can process huge amounts of text in Incredibly powerful ways and incredibly short amounts of time.
Speaker 0: if you have awk and regular expression skills You can even do simple stuff like it like.
Speaker 0: It's weird that I'll often use awk instead of cut just because I have the awk syntax at my head more quickly.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But log levels are really really important and most people at best they use log for J, which is okay
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: but really like the way I would do it is have like a two or three digit number That's the beginning of every file no matter what and just define for your developers Like channel one is for fatal errors anything fatal.
Speaker 0: Channel 18 is the super debug logs log fucking everything there because you're gonna have a log mask.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna write the debug logs all the time.
Speaker 0: You only write the debug logs if there's a problem that needs serious fixing like there's some crazy logic bug.
Speaker 0: All right well the developers turn up the debug log which kills the performance and they run the program and it logs every single like memory statement and Then they go through and figure out what happened.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't want to log that every day.
Speaker 0: every day you log.
Speaker 0: I don't know the fatals the warnings the errors maybe the like messages.
Speaker 1: hmm Yeah, anyway, let's let's let's talk about some other logging topics, right?
Speaker 1: So one thing that very few people to that I actually think is sort of a good idea is do log Centralization right very important.
Speaker 1: a lot of times you got a whole bunch of servers in your data center or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: And they all have logs and something happens.
Speaker 1: But really all these.
Speaker 1: there's a bunch of physical servers, but they're really actually one system working in concert.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't need to log into the actual system that had a problem to diagnose the problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you got a log into all these different systems now to figure out where the problem was.
Speaker 1: And what if?
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: if say I've got a system that takes like information about a chip I'm building and it's on one server and it processes that and then sends it to another server.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then there's a problem there.
Speaker 0: now I get a log into both servers.
Speaker 0: look at these two separate sets of log files.
Speaker 1: Right what you can do and it's never configured by default But most modern systems you can configure logs to be sent over the network and logged in a central locations.
Speaker 1: You can have a computer.
Speaker 1: that is the log computer and every.
Speaker 1: every other computer sends its logs to to that one computer.
Speaker 1: And now you can read the logs for every system in your system in one place your dog System in your system.
Speaker 1: I logged your logs now.
Speaker 0: Let's go one step further.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's really important and no one does it.
Speaker 1: but What if the network goes down?
Speaker 0: is actually well, you've got to set up something for that.
Speaker 0: You gotta make sure your program's not gonna lock on IO.
Speaker 1: And yeah, you also got to make sure that you always have logs no matter, you know, how many systems go down.
Speaker 0: Yep, but even worse than that is alright, so I'm logging centrally, but how do I know there's a problem?
Speaker 0: fucking nobody monitors?
Speaker 0: their logs worth a goddamn Mmm, and I don't know why it is Trivial to monitor logs if you've even if your logs are shitty just have a process run everything through a stream editor or Have a grip that runs every five minutes on your log directory and just sends every warning to in an email.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean a lot of times, you know.
Speaker 1: these days for example, right front-row crew calm There's an error on front-row crew calm.
Speaker 1: then the application itself sends me the email, right?
Speaker 1: I don't need to grab the logs for that to happen But there are.
Speaker 1: there are a lot of old systems that do not do this.
Speaker 1: they do not have this functionality You know.
Speaker 0: or what?
Speaker 0: if the system dies before it can send like say it like crashes hard as some crazy exception.
Speaker 1: Well if the log was centralized and that log managed to escape the computer and to a place and that Centralized log server had a monitor you would get an email actually about that completely failed system.
Speaker 1: Now that's a lot better chance than you're gonna get from the failed system sending an email on its own.
Speaker 0: Now the other problem is that you could.
Speaker 0: it's really hard to tailor that sort of monitoring.
Speaker 0: if you're.
Speaker 0: if you send too many things from your logs via email Then you're gonna start ignoring the emails because you know, they're meaningless and you're not gonna respond to things that quickly.
Speaker 1: Very true.
Speaker 0: If you don't send enough then you get them.
Speaker 0: you get an email servers down.
Speaker 0: You're like, okay great.
Speaker 0: What caused that?
Speaker 0: So you've got to have and really my advice is to use SNMP, which is something nobody knows.
Speaker 1: Some people know it but not enough people usually right.
Speaker 1: It's the thing that you you outsourced and you're using it, but you don't realize it.
Speaker 0: But what like?
Speaker 1: you'll log into Amazon and you'll pay extra to get cloudwatch which it monitors your servers.
Speaker 1: You see all your CPU usage graphs for all your servers on Amazon, but you don't realize they're using SNMP to do that.
Speaker 0: I'm not talking about using like watches like active polls like see if this process is running or whatever.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about having an active process an agent on your servers that grips through the logs all the time in real time and Instead of using grep It's actually like a C program that is designed to know when a new log file is written and start reading there.
Speaker 0: It knows where it left off.
Speaker 0: It doesn't keep reading the same files over and over again And have it just send an SNMP trap to some monitoring system with different more log levels.
Speaker 0: So say, you know, so you've got your low-level text.
Speaker 0: They got a console open and it that if there's an alarm it pops up saying, you know bad, but I'd crashed on the wind server Wins wins.
Speaker 1: Yeah, nobody freaking says that shit up except for like, you know the top of the heap type.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know who sets it up the financial world.
Speaker 0: You wanna know why cuz all the smart people and all the money is there?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know, there's.
Speaker 1: I bet Twitter doesn't have any SNMPs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they don't know what they don't.
Speaker 1: If they even know what it is, they're.
Speaker 1: no it's awesome.
Speaker 0: When I talk to vendors for like I'm buying a product and I usually the question will come up I like so how should we monitor this?
Speaker 0: and the stony silence that follows is amazing And sometimes I'll venture forth and say is there a MIB?
Speaker 0: Can I?
Speaker 0: monitor this thing with SNMP and No one has ever given me an answer other than I'll have to get back to you on that Googling SNMP.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the vendors are not the biggest technology people, right?
Speaker 1: That's the reason that they're salesmen.
Speaker 1: You know if you talk to the developers They maybe they know what SNMP was but 99% of the time the answer is we didn't do that.
Speaker 1: Uses that in the whole world except monitor your logs.
Speaker 0: You've got to think if you're a sysadmin and you care about the server I mean you might not care like if our forum goes down for an hour Whatever we fix it, whatever.
Speaker 1: But if you if you're was line ode sends me emails when that happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're running a business or you care about your server or whatever.
Speaker 0: like my counter-struct server has been down for like a month.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 0: I'll fix it when I fix it.
Speaker 0: But like it crashed for like a week before I realized it cuz I didn't monitor it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if I cared I would have set up a system that would actively monitor this thing.
Speaker 0: I would monitor the logs.
Speaker 0: I would have it tell me if say a new version of steam came out and the client wasn't working anymore.
Speaker 0: But it's a fine line between.
Speaker 0: if you send too much stuff.
Speaker 0: No one's gonna read the.
Speaker 0: read the monitoring No one's gonna care.
Speaker 0: if you send too little then the monitoring is useless because you won't actually know what caused a problem.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you've also got to have it even more intelligent.
Speaker 1: if you've got a whole bunch of systems and you're short on administrators You got to be like, okay, if something is ultra important like business critical thing is down It should call people on the phone and have a voice that says but if it's just like, you know Okay thing that's not.
Speaker 1: business critical is down and it's the weekend have it send an email first thing on Monday.
Speaker 0: This is again.
Speaker 0: my log levels are important.
Speaker 0: I mean I kept.
Speaker 0: we kept saying things like fatal warning though message Those are in log4j.
Speaker 0: Those are like the standard log channels Yeah, and if a system is written well fatal means it couldn't recover.
Speaker 0: fatal is a fatal error.
Speaker 0: The program is fucked.
Speaker 0: Yep, so you probably want a fatal error to page someone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a warning says this may or may not be a problem depending on all these other factors.
Speaker 0: It's just a warning and you have to decide if warnings should be paid attention to.
Speaker 1: you gotta You gotta understand what the warning says.
Speaker 1: the text next to it is important.
Speaker 0: You gotta understand what logs mean and it's a lot easier when you're writing your own logs.
Speaker 0: But it'd be a good idea to understand what those things mean to say the Linux kernel Varlog messages what matters in there and what doesn't You know when you turn your computer on?
Speaker 1: a lot of people turn computers on especially Linux ones and a whole bunch of text Flies by on the screen.
Speaker 1: if you still have you know, depending on what system using?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and people don't look at that text or understand it.
Speaker 0: most people nor do they realize the D message.
Speaker 0: They can go look at that after the fact.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I mean, it's like that's text is probably important and you should read it and understand what it's saying.
Speaker 1: It's not there for no reason at all.
Speaker 1: They put that there for you know, a reason it wasn't.
Speaker 0: You know the problem with like a Windows box where an error pops up and you just ignore it and just click OK But logs are different.
Speaker 0: You're a system administrator.
Speaker 0: Your job is this if you complain about the users not reading the error messages and you don't look at varlog Messages to diagnose the problem then shut up.
Speaker 0: You're just as bad as them I think is what a lot.
Speaker 1: what happens these days right is a lot of system administrators that are out in the world are not Actually system administrators.
Speaker 1: They're just really really good users.
Speaker 1: So they get the job, you know, mostly the helpdesk job Which is I can help people fix their desktop problems because I'm a really good desktop computer user.
Speaker 1: But they're not a systems administrator But in the Windows world they can being a really good user gets you most of the way to systems administrator.
Speaker 1: You can install exchange you put the CDs in the server and you install it and 99 you send.
Speaker 0: your work is Doing exchange.
Speaker 1: you're living in the exchange world or you know setting even setting up an active directory, right?
Speaker 1: But it's when it actually comes to the administering stuff the things that a normal user would never have to do or encounter They totally fail and thus most systems especially Windows systems and Unix systems administered by non Unix Hardcore Unix people are totally fail Which is most systems.
Speaker 0: my advice if you're a young kid in college and you're learning IT or CS or whatever and you don't like Programming.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what?
Speaker 0: It's applicable to IT and CS.
Speaker 0: CS people need to know logging.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, if you're see I mean even because you're the ones writing the logs Yeah, the point is if you know programming right you still you shouldn't you need to learn enough system administrating?
Speaker 1: You know that way you can set.
Speaker 1: if you you can set up your own servers to run your own shit and you don't need To outsource it to anyone also will understand the way system administrators Well, yeah, if you're writing if you're developing an application need to have a view of the whole system.
Speaker 1: You can't just be having such as narrow view of just your code and the world around it Just not even care.
Speaker 0: at the same time if you're an IT guy You still need to know enough about coding to understand like if a developer logs of thread numbers So you can trace like what one thread was doing versus another thread or say a program crashed You see the exception and then you do a stack trace to see what was going on.
Speaker 0: If you can't read any of that and understand it to a degree you're screwed.
Speaker 0: CS And IT overlaps more than a lot of people realize.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know whatever.
Speaker 1: whatever side you pick right make sure that you you know What you need to know about logs in the very least.
Speaker 0: just take look at your Ubuntu box Which I assume you have and or virtual machine.
Speaker 0: go to var log Do an LS and look at all that stuff.
Speaker 1: There's tons of logs in there and read documentation about log rotate and syslog ng.
Speaker 0: Yep, syslog ng.
Speaker 0: don't use just syslog.
Speaker 1: Well everyone every modern system is syslog ng.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and by the if you see you're gonna see a lot of things in the world that are called ng.
Speaker 1: That means next generation.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our Website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.