Speaker 1: It's Tuesday April 19th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm ran.
Speaker 1: This is geek night tonight the seven wonders of the world.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Wow, I haven't seen Pete and Pete since I don't know middle school.
Speaker 1: I've seen it more recently perhaps on YouTube.
Speaker 0: I don't think I have actually seen Pete and Pete since I haven't seen like a whole episode, but I seen a clip.
Speaker 0: Well, there's two.
Speaker 0: remember there's the actual show and then there's those shorts they would play.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: Well, you should remember that I remember enough.
Speaker 0: I remember very clearly because it was on TV many many times.
Speaker 0: I think I was sick and I just kept seeing it.
Speaker 0: It's the one where he's Pete as opposed to Pete is mowing the side of the freeway.
Speaker 0: Yep, trying to blow up cars.
Speaker 1: classic.
Speaker 1: Yeah How about the Hoover Dam?
Speaker 1: Oh my god classic the roof stack.
Speaker 0: I think I really like the one with the lunar eclipse.
Speaker 1: No, he has a good one, too.
Speaker 1: Or the the times the daylight savings time.
Speaker 0: Oh, but he's trying to race and stay in the same time.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, so, you know, I always say right that You know, it's like I got a big trade-off, right?
Speaker 1: It's like aha all these people in the world They suffer from chronic back pain, but I will not suffer from pain.
Speaker 1: I will have a hunch instead.
Speaker 1: but be pain-free until maybe I'm old.
Speaker 0: but Scott I point out I'm also pain-free.
Speaker 0: nor do I have a hunch?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying neither what.
Speaker 0: it's possible to have no hunch And do not have back pain.
Speaker 0: the people who have back pain don't have it for their lack of hunching.
Speaker 0: They have it because they don't bend their knees.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I have suffered my first back pain.
Speaker 0: Oh back injury You know, it's funny because I did hurt my back my entire life.
Speaker 1: It is now I have.
Speaker 0: now it is hurting Scott You know what?
Speaker 0: This means we're officially old.
Speaker 0: Oh, no because my whole life I would like fall off cliffs.
Speaker 0: bicycle spoke through the leg Cushion and I never like.
Speaker 0: I just bounced back like the next day.
Speaker 0: I'd be fine Yeah, and then you know last week when I got food poisoning and I fell over backwards vomiting so hard that I threw my back out My back hurt for like two weeks really - we okay Cuz like I don't know I didn't actually do.
Speaker 1: at least remember doing anything that injured the back, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like.
Speaker 0: I know exactly what you did but nothing.
Speaker 0: hunching It's.
Speaker 1: but the thing is it's on the low back.
Speaker 1: It's not in the upper hunch area.
Speaker 1: It's like way low.
Speaker 1: It's like where my tail would be if I had a tail.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's where most back pain ends up being.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway, it's like you know where you should go Spock hassle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz my back pain actually went away completely after Spock hassle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could definitely use something like that cuz they.
Speaker 0: I mean there's some Randy in there.
Speaker 0: You gotta stay away from the Randy, but there's also just jets of water that pound your back for free.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll take that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it's like I woke up like a couple mornings ago And it was just not good.
Speaker 1: And then I went to bed last night and I woke up and it was still not good.
Speaker 1: I was like what.
Speaker 0: that's the first sign of being old.
Speaker 0: when there's pain that is there one day and it's still there.
Speaker 0: Then it's like usually.
Speaker 1: usually you're gonna go to bed and wake up and it's gonna be gone.
Speaker 0: I think the primary example of youth is that when I was a kid like when I would get hangovers like okay I got a hangover in the morning afternoon fine or really sick feeling.
Speaker 0: go to sleep You'll feel a hundred percent like new the next day.
Speaker 0: It's not true anymore.
Speaker 1: No, I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do big sleep if I still have it for anime.
Speaker 1: Boston's gonna be trouble.
Speaker 1: I gotta carry my luggage around now.
Speaker 0: You should get wheely luggage Like a sissy.
Speaker 1: you mean like everyone who travels except one see the thing is the people with wheely luggage are permanent sissies.
Speaker 1: I'm only a part-time sissy.
Speaker 1: I have been temporarily sissified.
Speaker 1: as soon as I'm getting rid of this pain I will no longer need really like.
Speaker 0: I point out that had you had wheely luggage You might not have slammed into that obstacle Shows.
Speaker 1: even less of a sissy I am.
Speaker 1: I get slammed right into an obstacle breaker of Infrastructure.
Speaker 0: I will continue to use my wheely luggage sissy.
Speaker 0: So it's Tuesday, it's tourist season.
Speaker 1: yeah That's all I'm gonna say.
Speaker 1: kill all tourists.
Speaker 0: They've actually been pretty well behaved by me not by me.
Speaker 0: Low as balls the people.
Speaker 1: I even took.
Speaker 1: I took a train to Fairfield last night to go to my parents house.
Speaker 1: I was walking down the ramp to go from the train platform to the the card.
Speaker 1: You know my dad was sitting in the car like you do.
Speaker 1: old lady in front of me slow in Fairfield tourist in front of me.
Speaker 0: She might have just been old.
Speaker 1: That's that's enough.
Speaker 1: Also the connect.
Speaker 1: I didn't actually get on one of these trains, but Connecticut is a new trains on the New Haven line.
Speaker 1: I've heard very nice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one of my co-workers used to live in Manhattan moved out there, and he's like yeah, the trains nice, but fuck this.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, I'm sad, but the trains are nice at least.
Speaker 0: So only it won't be that long till we find out who's in Jane McGonigal's take or fight the future find the future That event we talked about that thing of the day, so yeah, I applied.
Speaker 0: I think tomorrow is the last day to apply.
Speaker 0: All right, so if you want to be in that game you'd better apply now.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean anyone can play.
Speaker 0: It's just if you want to be overnight do if you want to be one of the immortal 500.
Speaker 1: Yeah anyway Is that it for opening bits?
Speaker 0: I guess you're supposed to.
Speaker 0: we're supposed to have a smooth transition.
Speaker 1: Well, you know after hundreds of smooth transitions.
Speaker 1: We can have one non smooth transition now.
Speaker 0: So that'll be the thing.
Speaker 0: non smooth transition It can be.
Speaker 1: it can be smooth in its lack of smoothness.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be smooth.
Speaker 0: intentionally Unsmooth you mean like when black dynamite glances up at that microphone.
Speaker 0: That's hanging down from the boom in shot.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: So I got sort of a news slash geek bite together.
Speaker 1: right there's this game that came out called the ace of spades.
Speaker 0: Ah the game that we couldn't get the server working.
Speaker 1: I've gotten it to work a few times I mean last.
Speaker 0: I thought I didn't get that.
Speaker 1: well I didn't get the server to work personally, but I've played it on someone else's server a few times.
Speaker 0: So how come they can get it working, but you can I?
Speaker 1: Because they were at RIT Yeah, but anyway my Counter-Strike servers still broken.
Speaker 0: so yeah, I get something running anyway.
Speaker 1: So this game basically is the kind of thing I've been asking for.
Speaker 1: It's basically that the core concept of it is very strong.
Speaker 1: this game has good fundamentals, right?
Speaker 1: Which is?
Speaker 1: it's like Minecraft you can break blocks and you can put blocks and you can put blocks of any color you want.
Speaker 1: Right and every block is just a block.
Speaker 1: There's no difference between one block and another block.
Speaker 1: everything is just the same And you also have a gun Right and the gun kills people and both sides of the map have an intelligence that you're trying to protect And you're also trying to capture the other guys.
Speaker 1: intelligence right.
Speaker 1: so Fundamentally, it's capture the flag with blocks Which is pretty damn good.
Speaker 1: the problem with the game is that it has some mechanic you know Technological shortcomings right in that the networking you know fails.
Speaker 0: Why does no one get this right?
Speaker 1: Understand the thing is they've actually gotten it right into where.
Speaker 1: once the server is working properly And you're connected to it properly it does work really well.
Speaker 0: I actually heard a lot of people complaining about the fact that there's no sort of.
Speaker 0: it appears that there's no Prediction of movement that you have to lead your shots based on lag not based on movement.
Speaker 1: Well if there is someone who is incredibly laggy, then yes, you do have to maybe figure it out.
Speaker 0: I've always been of the mind and maybe it's just because I've never in my life Had a high ping that if you have to choose between punishing the high ping bastards and the low ping bastards Fuck the high ping bastards.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: You should punish the lag guy not the not the guy with no leg, but anyway the thing is the gun in the game is actually Stupidly accurate.
Speaker 1: like there is no scatter or cone shot.
Speaker 1: you click and the bullet goes infinitely in that direction that you clicked precisely where the crosshair was and Immediately so you shit.
Speaker 1: you click to style you click on a guy and as soon as you click blood pops out of him like Right.
Speaker 1: It's like if you click on him you got him.
Speaker 1: the gun is a sniper rifle.
Speaker 1: That is has no you know There's no recoil.
Speaker 1: There's no nothing right and it has a slow rate of fire, but you can just like bam bam.
Speaker 1: And so the problem is the game has fog.
Speaker 1: So the thing is if you can see someone through the fog you can shoot him But if they're if you can't see them it becomes hard to shoot him.
Speaker 1: But eat.
Speaker 1: don't let that fool you though because sometimes you won't see someone through the fog But you'll.
Speaker 1: they'll see you when you were in the fog and you'll recede into the fog thinking you ran away from them But they just keep shooting right where they last saw you Because ammo is basically almost infinite.
Speaker 0: god if we didn't have anime Boston coming up I would have been playing some of that.
Speaker 1: No, I'd be playing portal to which I only was able to play one chapter.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but it's only gonna take us eight hours to beat portal.
Speaker 1: Well, you got to play it twice because it's a co-op game and a single-player game.
Speaker 0: I heard I heard eight hours for single-player and then another four or five for the co-op whatever.
Speaker 1: It's quality hours Yeah, anyway, but yeah ace of spades the game has some you know problems in its details You know when it's technology, and it definitely needs a lot more polishing and embellishing.
Speaker 0: well I would say that the the problems that appears to have by and large are very similar to the problems that were never solved in The old quick two mods that I like.
Speaker 1: yeah But the fundamentals of the game are very sound.
Speaker 1: and the thing is I'm already seeing emerging gameplay for example.
Speaker 1: It's just one example.
Speaker 1: then we'll move on.
Speaker 1: When you're hoping you you you start with 50 blocks and you can place blocks wherever you want.
Speaker 1: Right and you can make the blocks any color you want.
Speaker 1: so what you can do is you can right-click on any block on the screen and Then it'll change the color of the block you're holding to match the color of the block you clicked.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, and there's a mini map in the game that you press M to look at the map And it gives you a basically a perfect overhead view of the game.
Speaker 1: perfect All right, so you see pretty much every pixel of the whole map from a directly straight down overhead view.
Speaker 1: So the intelligence on the map is like a blue square or a green square.
Speaker 1: So lay down some blocks in a blue square or a green square of the same dimensions.
Speaker 1: and now the other team sees two Intelligences and if they're stupid they don't know which one is which that is.
Speaker 0: that is right up there with my bro.
Speaker 1: See another example.
Speaker 1: right go to where you to make bridges to go over the water faster.
Speaker 1: Right because swimming in the water is kind of slow and troublesome.
Speaker 1: But if you make a bridge then you're in business But you don't want the other team to see where your bridges are.
Speaker 1: So what you do is when you're making a bridge you jump in the water and you make every brick of the bridge you Use the right-click to make it the same color as the water underneath and you get Indiana Jones bridges Yeah, and no one can see them on the map.
Speaker 1: It just looks like water.
Speaker 1: But when your team actually is standing right there It's pretty easy to see the bridge from the side just like the Indiana Jones bridge is easy to see from the side.
Speaker 0: See I love it's.
Speaker 0: I realized that I like first generation emergent gameplay, but I often dislike second-generation simulacra of emergent gameplay.
Speaker 0: La I think the best example is bunny hopping was kind of a fluke in early quake games.
Speaker 1: But but you don't like skiing and tribes.
Speaker 0: Well, but that thing is skiing in tribes like bunny hopping was at least like it was done.
Speaker 0: Well, but it's very hard to do that.
Speaker 0: Most games that try to simulate some sort of errant or emergent behavior from previous games end up duplicating it perfectly rather than Duplicating the intent.
Speaker 0: and when you duplicate it perfectly you get here is a fucking new earth.
Speaker 1: Yep Anyway, so what you got?
Speaker 0: So the nation of Armenia has what is it?
Speaker 1: Are they playing games?
Speaker 1: What is it?
Speaker 0: they have decided that chess is now compulsory in all primary education schools.
Speaker 0: Chess is a class just like math and everything else.
Speaker 0: That's okay.
Speaker 0: Here's what I want to say.
Speaker 0: I think the concept is great.
Speaker 1: I think that game chess is the wrong choice.
Speaker 0: Let me finish that.
Speaker 0: games and analytical thinking and things like this.
Speaker 0: I feel like a lot of students in school learn more innately from their music classes their art classes Their chess classes.
Speaker 0: then they do from a lot of their math and science Even if they don't learn it directly.
Speaker 1: being in those classes has been shown in many studies to enhance.
Speaker 1: You know what you learn in the other classes.
Speaker 1: You're in band, you know, you're gonna learn.
Speaker 1: you're gonna be smarter and learn more in math, you know Even though you you know might not necessarily learn about music more.
Speaker 0: Yes, exactly what I was saying.
Speaker 0: So But gaming in particular I mean remember Jane McGonigal's talk from Pax and what a lot of researchers say time and time again that play is One of the primary methods that mammals learn anything.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean, it's the way that hunting instincts and predation instincts are passed on.
Speaker 1: Are you saying you want a school where people do nothing but play games all day?
Speaker 0: I'm saying that gaming needs to be more tightly integrated with education.
Speaker 0: Of course, and I've been saying that for a long time and every now and then we get a tiny Glimmer, I mean someone who gets it.
Speaker 1: It wasn't completely absent from our education.
Speaker 1: We played Oregon Trail and you know all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 0: We never played Oregon Trail officially.
Speaker 0: It was just there in the computer lab and the smart kids played it instead of doing their work.
Speaker 1: No gaming was there in my schooling from nursery school to 12th grade.
Speaker 0: There was games going on but not as much as there should be not as tightly integrated with the education.
Speaker 0: It was nothing.
Speaker 1: there could have been very active there could have been more but there was still plenty of gaming.
Speaker 1: I mean word munchers in kindergarten.
Speaker 0: I mean was your assignment to play Oregon Trail or was it just on the computer?
Speaker 1: No, I'm pretty sure it was just on the computer, but there was nothing to do on the computer but play games.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, usually they'd give you some assignment like alright type this document in this word processor.
Speaker 0: I never just sit there.
Speaker 0: So all the smart kids would just go to the shared drive get the document the teacher typed up Send it back to him and then play games for an hour.
Speaker 0: Mmm, but the thing I take issue with is that They're about 50 years too late.
Speaker 0: I don't think chess is the game that should be used because I don't think chess is a good teaching tool at all.
Speaker 0: No chess is too abstract.
Speaker 1: if there's too high of a barrier to skilled play I think the reason they're doing it is they just want to have an Armenian be like the chess champion of the world.
Speaker 1: They don't want to miss anybody.
Speaker 1: That's all about national.
Speaker 0: I Actually think it's a little deeper than that.
Speaker 0: I think that there's a recognition I mean most people associate chess with smart people that people who play chess tend to be smart.
Speaker 0: They.
Speaker 0: they know that chess is an abstraction of war that there's strategy involved.
Speaker 0: It has all the trappings of the things you would actually want to teach children on a fundamental level But it does self-reliance analytical thinking and it does have all those things.
Speaker 0: I just don't think it is nearly as good a teaching tool as say a lot of the German style board games.
Speaker 1: Of course, why don't they?
Speaker 1: what they should do is I don't understand how you're gonna have a required class But for every possible grade, so you're gonna play chess as a class every year for your whole schooling from campus.
Speaker 0: I don't know the exact details of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because it's like that's a lot of chess to be playing.
Speaker 1: Why don't you they should mix it up?
Speaker 1: There should be basically game class where you play serious games of all sorts.
Speaker 0: go chess Puerto Rico I would just call the class strategy.
Speaker 1: That's a good class or analytical thinking.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: Sure go for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah portal Do but I mean we did a panel on this.
Speaker 0: But basically I think my main argument the reason why chess and go don't work.
Speaker 0: and the same reason why a lot of video games Don't actually work.
Speaker 0: and sports and everything is that these particular types of board games the not wholly abstracted You know German or euro style games tend to be very focused and tend to reduce randomness.
Speaker 0: but more importantly because of the mechanical constraints of the game and the fact that they are a Kind of direct analogy of the real world You can hold the entire state of the game in your head to a reasonable degree that the like the actual number of different decisions you're making is Fairly constrained and you can have a board game that you teach to kids Where they play it and the smarter of them will solve it by the end of the class.
Speaker 0: And I think there's a lot more actual learning going on at least practical learning because chess will teach you to be a better chess player and Maybe it'll teach you some pattern recognition.
Speaker 0: But I don't know.
Speaker 0: playing modern art will teach you evaluation and mind reading and all sort of fighters.
Speaker 1: Street Fighter is important Starcraft why not?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Street Fighter and Starcraft?
Speaker 0: because they're not mechanical They're more mathematically complex and have a much broader Decision matrix in them and as a result I think they're less good as direct teaching tools because there's no.
Speaker 0: The answer key is not as useful to a student's progress as it is in say, Puerto Rico.
Speaker 1: It will if you want to actually produce people who are gonna be professional gamers.
Speaker 0: I think that should be a separate branch of education.
Speaker 1: Hey, they have a gym classes required.
Speaker 1: They're trying to make professional athlete.
Speaker 0: No, they're not trying to make professional.
Speaker 1: Maybe they should.
Speaker 1: You got to start young if you want even have a chance.
Speaker 0: so things of the day hobo Nichols.
Speaker 0: Nichols made by hobos.
Speaker 1: Oh, they took nickel and they minted it.
Speaker 0: Possibly do that in the early part of the 1900s.
Speaker 0: there be there's a movement of not really a movement but kind of an art form that was popularized Called the hobo nickel where people would take Nichols particularly later on via that Buffalo nickel and just carve Reliefs into them.
Speaker 0: make them so kind of.
Speaker 1: you need a pretty serious tool to carve into the nickel right with any efficiency No more than you need for any sort of metal sculpting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what would you use like a chisel?
Speaker 1: It's like would you?
Speaker 0: yeah nowadays people use dremels and things but a dremel would work.
Speaker 0: I mean hobos did this Scott.
Speaker 0: It's not that hard.
Speaker 0: Nichols are actually not that Strong either.
Speaker 1: they never actually tried to.
Speaker 0: you know, try to deface a nickel.
Speaker 0: It won't take you I could deface a nickel with a dime if I really wanted.
Speaker 0: I don't know I'm right here.
Speaker 0: So I'll work on that.
Speaker 0: Anyway hobo Nichols are Often actually made by hobos and there's a whole like hobby of collecting them and making them.
Speaker 1: and this crazy story Yeah hobos do lots of stuff like that.
Speaker 1: cuz you know your hobo you don't there are you don't have anything to do.
Speaker 1: so something That takes a long time like, you know Scratching a nickel to put draw a picture on it is gonna be perfect.
Speaker 0: There is the era of the classic hobo Nichols from 1913 to 1940. then there was the later era.
Speaker 1: So what about the other?
Speaker 1: so the hobo who made one in 1941 his doesn't count?
Speaker 0: No, this is the later era.
Speaker 0: and then 1980 onward is the modern era.
Speaker 1: what happened in 1940?
Speaker 1: Changed the hobos.
Speaker 0: Oh, let's find out.
Speaker 0: So in the original era in the 30s and on there was a guy named Bert and he had a student named Oh and Burton Bo.
Speaker 0: these hobos carved all the kind of canonical Hobo Nichols, so there were.
Speaker 1: so basically they were only two hobos who were in the game.
Speaker 0: Well, don't know they're the famous ones.
Speaker 0: There are many other people but these two were like well known.
Speaker 0: Okay, so in the 40s 50s 60s 70s onward That was a transitional period for hobo engravers because the Buffalo nickel was gradually replaced by the Jefferson nickel.
Speaker 0: the Buffalo nickel was apparently it was widely regarded as being too ugly when it was new and Too ugly when it was worn down and therefore always ugly, but it was a good medium for a hobo carving.
Speaker 0: So the Jefferson nickel wasn't as good.
Speaker 0: so people had to do very different things to the nickels They made different.
Speaker 1: Oh, so it's so it's.
Speaker 1: it's not the year that you carved it that makes the difference It's the nickel you used.
Speaker 0: Well, no, it's that the types of hobo nickels that were made transition because the kinds of nickels that existed were different and Like art styles were different.
Speaker 0: Apparently a lot of people made Chinese women and hippies.
Speaker 0: Modern hobo nickels are made mostly with dremels and a lot of people disdain them saying that only old hobo nickels count.
Speaker 1: Oh you don't rim you.
Speaker 1: I see you painted this fabulous painting and it's so incredibly fabulous But you know what?
Speaker 1: It doesn't count because you use paint from the paint store.
Speaker 1: You weren't like Van Gogh.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's the original hobo society.
Speaker 0: They will like do research on and certify because apparently there's a problem where people will make fake hobo nickels and sell them to collectors.
Speaker 0: Well for five cents Hundreds thousands of dollars.
Speaker 1: who would pay hundreds of thousand dollars for a nickel?
Speaker 0: your moron What if it's a car meets a piece of art just like a painting and that pay it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's worth that much money for a nickel, but it's not a nickel anymore.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter how fast it needs to be in this shape of a.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: if Michelangelo carved the fucking nickel It's not worth a hundred thousand.
Speaker 0: I would pay a hundred thousand dollars for a nickel carved by Michelangelo.
Speaker 1: I would pay maybe 1000. you know why?
Speaker 0: Because I could sell it for way more than a hundred thousand Museum because it belongs in a museum.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying if Michelangelo had a hoe and a buffalo nickel that is some serious crazy.
Speaker 1: So how the hell did he get it?
Speaker 0: My thing of the day is merely the existence of hobo nickels.
Speaker 0: I suggest you check these out.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I like this Viking guy.
Speaker 1: So I know that rim is a hater of the LCD Portable game game, you know the game and watch the tiger LCD.
Speaker 0: not a hater.
Speaker 0: All right, really the hater implies that the hate is probably unwarranted.
Speaker 1: those games where shit as you can see haters gonna hate.
Speaker 0: I had a gameboy and a game gear.
Speaker 0: Yeah before those existed, you know what I had before them.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I did when I had a long car trip book read a fucking book Yeah, but anyway, or I had mechanical handheld or light-up football.
Speaker 0: Now not let a football.
Speaker 1: I had a light-up baseball from like Anyway, be I am a fan of the old LCD games.
Speaker 1: game and watch tiger LCD, etc.
Speaker 1: Rim is not easy cuz they're shitty.
Speaker 0: Anyway, they were way overpriced for what they were.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they were like 10 bucks.
Speaker 1: This guy made a website called pika pic p ICA - PIC and it's hippopotums.
Speaker 1: hip.
Speaker 1: not hippopotamus is hippopotums digitized Digitalized collection of handheld electronic games and this is a. it's a flash site.
Speaker 1: It's all flash, but on this site It's basically exact perfect reproductions of a bunch not a whole ton but a whole bunch of Old LCD games.
Speaker 1: that rim doesn't like.
Speaker 1: some gaming watches Zelda game and watch a dr.
Speaker 1: Slump game.
Speaker 1: Let's see real animation animist and wide vision.
Speaker 1: Dr Slump Arale Arale song and super whatever.
Speaker 0: see now things like that are fun.
Speaker 0: I enjoy playing like kind of like old electro mechanical arcade games or a lot of vintage arcade games.
Speaker 0: They're not.
Speaker 1: so these are okay now that they're old.
Speaker 0: No, they're not actually fun But they are actually fun.
Speaker 0: if I'd been a kid I would not have enjoyed playing some of the games that are lauded as you know modern like.
Speaker 0: oh check out this class.
Speaker 0: But there's still an interesting experience in playing an old game just to see what it was like.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: You're not gonna have fun playing these shitty tiger LCD.
Speaker 1: You're gonna have plenty of fun playing these games.
Speaker 1: play some Bartman Avenger of Evil.
Speaker 1: play some terminate.
Speaker 1: They got the electronic that terminate.
Speaker 1: take a g-man.
Speaker 1: All kinds of good games going on here.
Speaker 1: The Zelda ones actually really good.
Speaker 1: but yeah if you either too young to have ever seen these games or had them or maybe you're old and you have nostalgia for them or You're really old and you were too old to have them when you were a kid.
Speaker 1: Go to this site.
Speaker 1: play a bunch of these awesome games, they're awesome.
Speaker 0: So in much more important news, I deface the fuck out of this nickel with this dime.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let me see that nickel.
Speaker 0: I mean, I didn't.
Speaker 0: I just did a little bit of scratching and look I put some surprisingly deep scratches in it none whatsoever.
Speaker 1: It looks like Jefferson to me.
Speaker 1: So you minorly scratched Jefferson's collar.
Speaker 0: Yeah in like two seconds.
Speaker 0: All I was saying is that it's not that hard to deface a nickel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay But try how long is it gonna take you to put an art in it and replace?
Speaker 0: Jefferson completely about as long as it takes to do any soft metal carving.
Speaker 1: I Think if you heat it up a little bit or used a better tool like a dremel It would take a lot less.
Speaker 0: I wasn't saying you should carve it with a dime.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying I trivially defaced it with a dime.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I'll bet in about ten minutes.
Speaker 0: I could remove Jefferson's nose.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what I could remove nose nose.
Speaker 1: I could remove instantly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, thanks.
Speaker 0: I Argue that you cannot.
Speaker 1: how can I not cuz it's already removed.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: That's how I did it so fast.
Speaker 0: So, how can you remove it?
Speaker 0: undertake the action of removing it?
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 0: No, it was removed prior.
Speaker 0: You did not remove you did nothing.
Speaker 1: How do you know I didn't do it Because Michelangelo said anyway.
Speaker 0: So metamoment very briefly we will be this weekend at anime Boston.
Speaker 0: That's why the show might have gone up a little late Today.
Speaker 1: It's cuz I was in Connecticut less tonight.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, and why we're kind of tired?
Speaker 0: We're kind of rushing the show and we may not have a Thursday episode.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: I don't think we're gonna have a Thursday episode.
Speaker 1: Anyway, lots of other Meta news.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: We got bar camp, right?
Speaker 1: I'm helping to organize bar camp NYC.
Speaker 1: if you don't know a bar camp NYC is going the internet.
Speaker 1: look up bar camp Right.
Speaker 1: It happens in a bunch of cities.
Speaker 1: It is gonna be on May 21st and 22nd in New York City The Microsoft Office and you can go to the bar camp NYC website to get all the information about it.
Speaker 1: The 20th May 20th the night before bar camp starts is actually that Jane McGonigal thing where I'm already mentioned.
Speaker 1: Yep May 7th at noon is the nerd NYC.
Speaker 1: nerd Nick a nerd picnic.
Speaker 1: go to the nerd NYC comm Website to get all the information about the nerd.
Speaker 0: I look forward to some jungle speed outside.
Speaker 1: Yep April 30th and May 1st is the comic geek speak podcast is having their convention in Redding, Pennsylvania.
Speaker 0: I probably won't go to it though because it's a really bad timing, you know I feel like this meta moment if we're gonna talk about all the other geeky things out There is better served by being a post on the website.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I can working on that.
Speaker 1: I'm working on that.
Speaker 1: It'll happen soon after we after all these geeky things end probably in June.
Speaker 0: I'm curious Do you guys care cuz?
Speaker 0: I get a feeling that the only purpose of the meta moment really is people who want to know about Our stuff or stuff that we're like, we're actually like we're doing this con.
Speaker 0: We're going in.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying people show up at these things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we but we should.
Speaker 0: but we tell them because we tell them to yeah But the things we're at how many of them show up to the things we're not?
Speaker 1: and you don't know.
Speaker 1: we'd have to go to Those things to find out wouldn't we?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but why tell them to go then?
Speaker 1: because they're cool things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but why not just have a link to it?
Speaker 0: I don't think that many people are going to things we tell them to go to Especially since they listen to the episodes often way after we made them.
Speaker 1: Anyway, and when's the next board game night?
Speaker 0: is May 13th the same night as of the nerd night that they want us to go present beyond candy land ad.
Speaker 0: so we got it.
Speaker 1: Oh, are we actually scheduled to do that?
Speaker 0: Uh, we weren't but we didn't go to two in a row and then they got emailed.
Speaker 0: me is like hey you guys want to Present so we'll see.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess if we're presenting that's more important than board games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I really want to play board games is my trouble.
Speaker 1: I can go present it with my never-ending trouble.
Speaker 1: Okay, I don't need you to be on candy land.
Speaker 0: I actually I just did a cuz.
Speaker 0: remember it's a shorter We have like 20 minutes.
Speaker 1: Oh, we only have 20 minutes, but I had to redo the whole fucking thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I already redid it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I ran it for a bunch of people at work.
Speaker 0: I ran beyond candy land like four times.
Speaker 0: Okay for various audiences.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the only meta news that's really pertinent to geek nights other than the fact that we're doing a bunch of panels at anime Boston and we'll be playing a bunch of games there.
Speaker 0: Is that the book club book is still Foundation by Asimov, you know the one of the great nerd books.
Speaker 1: Yes of all time that I sadly admittedly have not actually read and also follow me on Twitter.
Speaker 0: APR ECHE You could follow geek nights on Twitter.
Speaker 1: You can do that too, but I want more followers.
Speaker 1: Why cuz somebody else had more file.
Speaker 1: I didn't care.
Speaker 1: I don't really care about the followers, you know I don't.
Speaker 1: I'm not the kind of person to pay attention to numbers and give a shit.
Speaker 1: I'm just sort of joking.
Speaker 1: but someone else had more followers than me.
Speaker 1: That's not cool.
Speaker 0: I should unfollow you.
Speaker 0: We should all unfollow you.
Speaker 1: do it.
Speaker 1: that'd be hilarious.
Speaker 0: guys either follow Scott or unfollow him and let's see what happens.
Speaker 1: sure Do whatever you want.
Speaker 0: So seven wonders.
Speaker 0: one of the games we picked.
Speaker 0: we played like.
Speaker 0: I don't know a ton of games that we have to review.
Speaker 0: We've just been slowly like piling them up and then playing them more times to make sure.
Speaker 1: Basically seven wonders is the new hot game.
Speaker 1: I heard about it and I heard that it was the new hot game.
Speaker 1: I played it a couple times at someone's house And then I played it a few more times at like a zinc icon and then rim bought a copy and played it even more.
Speaker 0: Yep, it was sold out.
Speaker 0: I had to pre-order.
Speaker 1: obviously, you know already.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know already that if we played it so much and we kept going back to it that there is good a warning I am getting slightly tired of it and I don't think it has staying power.
Speaker 0: I agree No, well, there we go.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it's still a great game.
Speaker 0: I highly recommend you own it because straight up this is a game like Zula Rhetto where it's not the best game.
Speaker 1: if you're smart You'll have solved it pretty quickly and the winner will come down to luck.
Speaker 0: But it's a game that you can whip out and play relatively quickly that you can teach relatively quickly.
Speaker 0: It's a great game like at a con like you have a bunch of new people.
Speaker 0: We should play a game You don't really want to spend 40 minutes teaching them.
Speaker 1: Puerto Rico The game pretty much is almost exactly in the same niche as ticket to ride.
Speaker 1: It takes about the same length of time to play.
Speaker 1: It's got that same mechanic of on your turn All you do is one very small thing and you take a lot of small turns.
Speaker 1: So the game goes very quickly and in fact, this is even one better than ticket to ride because everyone takes simultaneous turns.
Speaker 1: So there's absolutely no waiting for anyone to take their turn.
Speaker 0: You just keep going and going and going and going and also prevents over any arguments of oh so-and-so always doesn't take his turn.
Speaker 0: That's a lie.
Speaker 0: You take just as long because you can see every round Exactly who's holding everyone up because everyone's taking their turn simultaneously.
Speaker 0: It's always Scott Johnson.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: So the way seven wonders works is you know You have there's a deck of cards and you split it up and you give everyone a hand and on your turn every turn Of the entire game all you do is play a card That's it and you and then you give that the remaining cards to the person to your left or right depending whatever.
Speaker 0: and some of The cards are resources and you basically tap the resources magic style every round.
Speaker 0: So you build up this kind of increasing accumulation of resources and there's a whole bunch of different kind.
Speaker 1: So early in the game you build up more resources and having more resources allows you to play other cards which allow you to play Other cards which allow you to play more cards to give you more points and then at the end of the game rose the most points Wins, right?
Speaker 1: So it's all about, you know getting a good sequence of cards that play into each other.
Speaker 1: You know every time you play a card and you never use that card it never gets you any points.
Speaker 1: You just wasted a turn because you could have used that card to get money instead Which would be worth at least one point.
Speaker 0: now It has a lot of particular mechanics that are either cribbed from other games or just analogously grown.
Speaker 0: Like you build buildings, right?
Speaker 0: And you can only build unique buildings.
Speaker 0: So if there's a granary and you build it, you can't build another granary But you can build another building similar to a great Yes Now the thing is many buildings have a notation on them that if you already have X building you can build this for free.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's basically identical to the way it works in Attica For example, I learned by, you know, if you actually look at the cards of the game, right?
Speaker 1: I learned that there's a very, the most difficult card to build in the whole game is worth like eight points.
Speaker 1: I forget what it is.
Speaker 1: It might be the Parthenon or something.
Speaker 1: It's something ridiculous.
Speaker 1: It's worth a ton of points.
Speaker 1: But if you have a theater you can build that ridiculously expensive building for free.
Speaker 1: So basically I always build the theater so that I can always try to get the expensive building for free and it's worked out In my favor two or three times already.
Speaker 1: Yep So it's like no way, once you know the cards the game starts to lose a lot of its luster because it's like just sort of obvious.
Speaker 1: the path to take?
Speaker 0: Well, I would say the path.
Speaker 0: There are, I don't know, about three, maybe four paths to victory.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's the military path.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's the green path.
Speaker 0: Well, military is a choice that modifies every path.
Speaker 0: It does true Because military alone does not win you.
Speaker 0: the game That can get you at most 10 plus six plus two points.
Speaker 1: It's mostly the green path and the blue path are the ways to go, right?
Speaker 1: And green is harder to do but has a potentially higher payout.
Speaker 1: Like if one guy goes all blue and one guy goes all green, green guy is probably gonna win because the way the math works.
Speaker 0: But here let's talk about like the reason the paths are different.
Speaker 0: You know not to get into the stupid details of the game because you should just buy it.
Speaker 0: You'll read the rules you see how it really works.
Speaker 0: But the green path is these there's sets of different types of items.
Speaker 1: Yeah, science cards.
Speaker 0: So there's three types and you get points increasingly based on the number of sets of three that you get But also two to the end points and being the number of one particular one that you have.
Speaker 1: So basically all the green cards.
Speaker 1: if you start piling them up It makes sort of like a two-dimensional grid of scoring.
Speaker 1: So all the green cards actually score twice in two different ways.
Speaker 1: What this means.
Speaker 1: And one of those ways it scores, it scores exponentially And the other way it scores, it scores linearly, but even the linear scoring is a multiple of seven.
Speaker 1: So you get basically every green card.
Speaker 1: as you get more of them The amount of points that each individual green card gives you continues to go up at a very very high rate.
Speaker 0: So if you're playing this game because the two-dimensional grid It's actually fairly complicated until you figure it out.
Speaker 0: And then it's obvious If you play this game with friends who have not played it before Get all the green cards.
Speaker 0: They will look at the green cards, their eyes will glaze over when you explain how the scoring works And they'll ignore them.
Speaker 0: You will win almost every time if you go for the green cards when people around you are not that bright or haven't played much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is sort of interesting because there isn't a lot of inter-player.
Speaker 1: You know there is a little bit, right?
Speaker 1: You can buy things from the people to your left or right And you military with the people to your left or right and things like that.
Speaker 0: But it has a heavy left-right mechanic.
Speaker 1: Yes And you know you think about your hand, you're going to play a card But any cards you leave in your hand you're giving to the person to your left or your right depending on the age.
Speaker 1: So there is significant impact you can have on your immediate neighbors in the game And in a three-player game that's really significant because you're influencing all the other players.
Speaker 1: But other than that there isn't a whole lot of inter-player mechanics.
Speaker 1: You can't destroy other people's cards, you can't steal their cards.
Speaker 1: There's really not much you can do to take points away from other people.
Speaker 0: It's a little more than say Agricola in terms of how much you can actually fuck with everybody.
Speaker 1: I'd say it's a little bit less than Puerto Rico because you can screw with people sort of the same way that you do in Puerto Rico.
Speaker 1: Like aha, I played captain so you couldn't play captain.
Speaker 1: But it's like a little bit less than that because in Puerto Rico if I craftsman out from under you.
Speaker 1: that could hurt you pretty badly.
Speaker 0: So my main problem with the game is that like I said I think I have solved it mostly And I think when I play it really just comes down to luck.
Speaker 0: And it took maybe eight plays to solve.
Speaker 0: There's not that much going on in the game.
Speaker 1: Most people though don't play a game as much as we do right.
Speaker 1: They get a game and if they play it twice it's like oh they're so happy.
Speaker 1: You know how many people play it get a game and play it eight times.
Speaker 0: But I found that games like this in a couple weeks will be played a lot.
Speaker 0: Or Zularetto gets played a lot too just because like I said at the beginning they're quick to play.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: it is quick to play so if you do bust it out you're probably going to play it two or three times.
Speaker 0: I mean this takes a half hour tops if people are slow.
Speaker 0: If people take their turn you'll whip out a whole game including scoring at the end in like 20 minutes.
Speaker 1: The scoring could actually take as long as a whole age Just because you know you have to add up so many different things and you know some of them are slightly.
Speaker 0: Now the analogy of the game is not as bad as Le Havre which basically doesn't have an actual theme.
Speaker 0: You're just kind of like yeah boats and food get food.
Speaker 1: It's a port town.
Speaker 0: yeah you make money But seven wonders you're playing a wonder.
Speaker 0: slash the civilization that built that wonder.
Speaker 1: Yeah it's like if you're playing you know the colossus well.
Speaker 1: are you playing?
Speaker 1: are you the colossus Or are you the people building the colossus?
Speaker 0: I think you're playing the city state that has wrought the colossus.
Speaker 0: But you know everyone plays a wonder.
Speaker 0: so
Speaker 1: Sardia you can either
Speaker 0: pick them or pass them out randomly And everyone has a little card and in addition to the cards in their hands that they're buying And passing back and forth you can also buy the improvements that make your wonder bigger Like as you complete your wonder.
Speaker 0: it does stuff and every wonder has a different set of powers And an a and a b side.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: so basically everyone has a wonder which is basically three unique cards That no one else has.
Speaker 1: effectively right.
Speaker 1: it's like everyone's playing with the same deck of cards But each person has three cards usually three sometimes four.
Speaker 1: I think there's one weird one weird Wonder.
Speaker 1: that is four but everyone basically has a handful of a few cards that are different from Everyone else's cards.
Speaker 1: that makes you unique which gives you a little bit more replay value.
Speaker 1: it's like Well I'll play with the mausoleum well now I'll play with the hanging garden.
Speaker 1: so it's a little Slightly different game if you have a different wonder and every wonder has two sides which gives You a little bit more replay value because there's an a side which is easy and direct And there's a b side which is a little more complicated but potentially higher payout.
Speaker 0: I would recommend when you play do the random allocation of the wonders but let players pick A or b.
Speaker 1: I would recommend you do it completely randomly.
Speaker 0: nah that gets boring because I'm already Bored with the game.
Speaker 0: I mean I wouldn't play it unless I was teaching it or playing it with new People or as like a warm-up game and a board game night.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't.
Speaker 1: just definitely it's definitely Good warm-up game I don't know.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't make the highlight game though no but is.
Speaker 1: it is an Excellent new warm-up game you know and if I was short on warm-up games I would definitely add it My game library.
Speaker 0: even if I was bored I'm accumulating a lot of warm-up games because I Lacked them.
Speaker 1: I realized that because people refuse to play the series games people just play warm-up Games and then they're done.
Speaker 0: well I particular I only owned some of the big heavy-hitter games Like el grande and t and e and I own a lot of the weird old out of print games like la cheetah.
Speaker 0: I didn't own many quick whip them out games.
Speaker 0: that's why I got zularetto and seven wonders and I'm Ordering rico.
Speaker 1: zularetto takes a little bit longer than seven wonders.
Speaker 1: I think it's more of a. It's sort of in between warm-up when I say highlight there's different.
Speaker 0: there's two kinds of Warm-up games in my mind.
Speaker 0: there's the warm-up game that's quick to play as in.
Speaker 0: you whip it out you Play with everybody and then you play the main event.
Speaker 0: and then there's the warm-up game like Zularetto where you've got a bunch of people over you're gonna play a game you're gonna play games Many games but people are still wanting to socialize.
Speaker 0: they're not in the.
Speaker 0: let's just play a Game mode.
Speaker 0: yet zularetto you can socialize over without impacting the game.
Speaker 1: I mostly think of Zularetto as more like a settlers replacement.
Speaker 1: right because like I'm looking down on settlers But zularetto I can still play a lot more easily than I can play guitar settlers in zularetto are Actually pretty equal to me.
Speaker 1: zularetto is a much better gateway.
Speaker 1: I think too.
Speaker 0: uh I don't know.
Speaker 0: it Depends on the person.
Speaker 0: someone who is predisposed toward hardcore settlers is a better like intro Game.
Speaker 0: someone who isn't zularetto is a better intro game anyway.
Speaker 1: but yeah seven wonders.
Speaker 0: my other new Trouble.
Speaker 0: I'll warn you now when you're teaching this game people who played magic as they were Kids they'll get the resources immediately.
Speaker 0: no one else will.
Speaker 0: yeah I was very surprised Has fucked up the resources.
Speaker 0: despite multiple alternative explanations analogies examples Nothing works.
Speaker 1: I can't understand why these people don't understand how the resources work.
Speaker 1: it's like You have two rocks.
Speaker 1: that means you look at the cost of something.
Speaker 1: if it costs three rock you can't.
Speaker 1: It's like money that you can only spend it once per turn and every turn everyone gives you all the Money back.
Speaker 0: it's magic resources.
Speaker 0: you tap them every round but people don't get that and they'll like They'll buy resources by trying to like play cards and just they will cock that up.
Speaker 0: you've got to make Sure.
Speaker 0: after you teach the whole game teach everybody resources again.
Speaker 0: I guarantee at least one of your Players doesn't actually understand.
Speaker 1: yeah and on top of that right even if people uh understand Resources right there's a lot of the game requires you to notice a lot of small things on the cards.
Speaker 1: For example you know the you what this card upgrades to that card for free.
Speaker 1: well it's a really Tiny icon that says that.
Speaker 1: so if you're not really looking closely at every card you might like say Not build something even though you could have for free.
Speaker 1: uh you know.
Speaker 0: because uh yep people will also Fuck up.
Speaker 0: they will not remember that they can't build the same named building twice.
Speaker 0: so they'll Build the barracks and then they'll build the barracks again and it just cocks up the game.
Speaker 0: Anyway other than that the game is great.
Speaker 0: uh i don't know if it was really worth msrp but I'm glad i own it.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm We're doing more show or is that enough?
Speaker 0: i think that's enough.
Speaker 0: this has been geek nights with rim And scott special thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music cat lee for web design and brand.
Speaker 1: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion News and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic wednesdays and indiscriminate thursdays.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.