Speaker 1: And it's the Geek Nights Book Club for July 2011.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Did you say Geek Nights twice?
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 0: You gotta work on that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a new show.
Speaker 0: So like we said- It's not a new show, it's an old show.
Speaker 1: Cut off of Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: So the new book, the next book, will be announced right now.
Speaker 0: Before we even say what the current book is?
Speaker 1: I guess.
Speaker 1: This is the book club review of Isaac Asimov's Foundation.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Chosen by Scott.
Speaker 1: Neither one of us had read it.
Speaker 1: Kind of a big glaring hole in our knowledge of science fiction.
Speaker 0: Well, it's because we read Hyperion- Hyperion.
Speaker 0: Hyperspace.
Speaker 0: Was that the last book club?
Speaker 1: I believe so.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We read Hyperspace and it was like, you know, he mentioned Foundation a whole bunch and it's an incredibly famous, important sci-fi book.
Speaker 0: and I'm like, "Well, we're nerds.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: How could we not have read that
Speaker 0: book?".
Speaker 0: So I'm like, "Well-".
Speaker 1: I believe you were like, "I've actually never read
Speaker 1: Foundation.".
Speaker 1: And I paused and I was like, "Yeah, I haven't
Speaker 1: either.".
Speaker 0: I read it partly before, but I didn't remember shit.
Speaker 0: So I was like, "That's going to be the book club
Speaker 0: book.".
Speaker 0: So it was.
Speaker 0: And what do we- we'll talk about that in a minute.
Speaker 0: What are we going to do in August of 2011?
Speaker 0: Because now book club is now monthly.
Speaker 1: For August of 2011, this is my book chosen, recommended by Emily.
Speaker 1: I have not actually read it.
Speaker 0: So it's really Emily's choice.
Speaker 1: But I will recommend it among many recommendations I've received.
Speaker 1: Some of you recommend some stupid ass crap, just so you know.
Speaker 1: But The Ear, The Eye, and The Arm by Nancy Farmer.
Speaker 1: Have you ever heard of it?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: It's a science fiction about three detectives named The Ear, The Eye, and The Arm.
Speaker 0: It's sounding more familiar.
Speaker 1: Set in Zimbabwe.
Speaker 1: Alrighty.
Speaker 1: In the future.
Speaker 1: And I don't want to say much more about it.
Speaker 0: I'm guessing.
Speaker 0: The Eye, he sees the clues.
Speaker 0: The Ear, he does the eavesdropping.
Speaker 0: And The Arm, he muscles people into confessing.
Speaker 1: Well, to quote a review of it, with its blend of high-tech futurism and authentic African tribal folklore, Nancy Farmer's Newbery Honor book is an exciting selection for recorded fiction.
Speaker 0: Isn't the Newbery Medal for kids books?
Speaker 1: It is a young adult book.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: But it's also apparently good.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying it's bad, but you know.
Speaker 1: I mean, I think what sold me on it was that how much African-styled science fiction do we get?
Speaker 1: that is well known to fans of science fiction?
Speaker 0: I've never heard of any.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So I want to try something that has a unique take on everything.
Speaker 1: Like it kind of takes everything from an angle that we might not be as science fiction readers used to.
Speaker 1: It also came very highly recommended.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: So we have read Isaac Asimov's Foundation, and you all have read it too.
Speaker 0: Only the first one.
Speaker 0: It seems like there's the trilogy, which is like foundation, second foundation, and then I don't know what the third one's called, but it's foundation something.
Speaker 0: But then there's even more foundations after that that are like, you know, but I think the three books are the like the core ones, but we only read the first one.
Speaker 1: The important thing to remember here is that you have read foundation because if you have not, you should read foundation first because we're going to talk about foundation assuming you have read it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's how book clubs work.
Speaker 1: If you want to be in the club, you got to read the book.
Speaker 0: Read a book.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should make that the theme song for this for this show.
Speaker 1: That would be some fair use possibly until we get sued.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so foundation.
Speaker 0: So I really didn't know much about foundation cause I completely forgot.
Speaker 1: I knew the gist of it.
Speaker 0: I knew it was sci-fi and it was about some galactic civilization.
Speaker 1: I knew that it was laying a foundation.
Speaker 1: No, that it was like, seriously, I knew it was about galactic civilization.
Speaker 1: I knew it was sci-fi laying some sort of foundation for a future civilization, like some sort of like making a vault, like a library of Alexandria.
Speaker 1: That is all I knew about this book.
Speaker 0: Oh, I didn't even know that.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so what it really is, is it's like, it's all, it's a collection of short stories and I think where they actually published as all these separate short stories in like a periodical and then later collected into the novels.
Speaker 1: No, I don't know actually.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Speaker 0: I didn't research it very well, but I just read the book.
Speaker 0: I didn't research it.
Speaker 0: Um, we are best.
Speaker 0: Yes, we are best.
Speaker 0: But basically what it is, this story, there was a galactic empire, a huge galaxy spanning empire.
Speaker 1: Well, when the book starts, there still is.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: There was.
Speaker 0: And this was like the great galactic empire, basically Rome.
Speaker 0: In fact, it is Rome, right?
Speaker 0: It owns almost- It's pretty obviously allegory to Rome.
Speaker 1: The things that happen and the way this thing falls apart are basically why and how Rome fell apart.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it falls apart like Rome.
Speaker 1: You know, I thought we were assuming that people have already read the book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I am.
Speaker 1: So you're explaining it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Just, you know, because- You can keep explaining the book that you all just read.
Speaker 0: If you went to a book club at, you know, a bookstore, you would still, you know, quickly cursorily go over the, you know, the plot.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you were or if they just be like, so what did you think?
Speaker 0: Oh, maybe.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But then I feel like I also want to extend the episode at the same time.
Speaker 0: And also, you know, someone's listening who didn't read.
Speaker 1: Yeah, fuck you.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the galactic civilization falls apart, but this is incredibly far in the future, right?
Speaker 0: You know, you can travel faster than light and all this stuff.
Speaker 0: So one guy is really smart and he can actually use math and psychology to predict the future of civilization.
Speaker 1: It's not that he's really smart.
Speaker 1: It's that he has this field of study that itself- He's also really smart.
Speaker 1: Anyone who understands the field of study can, you know, basically tell us a civilization.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They can't do it to a person.
Speaker 0: Statistically.
Speaker 0: You can't get the details right, but he can get the big picture right.
Speaker 1: So what do you do if, you know, you figure out that your entire world, as you know it, is going to collapse in a foreseeable span of time?
Speaker 0: He knows a dark age is coming.
Speaker 0: So what he does- But never mind, it's the rocket fuel equation.
Speaker 1: So doing something about it alters what's going to happen.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So he pretty much does everything he can.
Speaker 0: He figures out that he can't avoid the dark age, but he figures out a way to shorten the dark age.
Speaker 0: And as you read all these short stories that each take place a few decades after each other with different characters, you know, throughout this, you know, as the history unfolds, it's like it's a history, but it's not.
Speaker 0: It's the future.
Speaker 0: It's the present is unfolding before your eyes.
Speaker 0: After this guy comes up with his plan, you get to see his plan and you don't know what the plan is.
Speaker 0: You just get to see it happen and you can sort of predict what it's going to be.
Speaker 0: But, you know, there are some surprises here and there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So I will just put forth on the record, I don't think we need to bother explaining the plot.
Speaker 0: All right, fine.
Speaker 1: We'll see what the listener has to say about that.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: We're done explaining the plot.
Speaker 0: So what did you think?
Speaker 1: I was pleasantly surprised, just as I always am when I read classic sci fi I have not read before.
Speaker 1: Every time I decide to read a classic sci fi that I have not already read, I expect it to be very overwrought and very like stilted.
Speaker 1: And it is never the case that that is what I actually end up reading.
Speaker 1: It flowed very much like a real book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like it was good.
Speaker 1: It was enjoyable.
Speaker 1: I'm going to keep reading until I hear it gets really bad later.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: I heard once the beast appears.
Speaker 1: It sucks.
Speaker 1: Like it's just not worth reading beyond that point.
Speaker 0: Uh huh.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I expected it to be awesome, but I actually started reading.
Speaker 0: I didn't feel awesome until I got a few pages in that it felt awesome.
Speaker 1: What's interesting is that Asimov in this book does something very particular.
Speaker 1: Every age, because you know, it's split into ages, like the psycho historians, the encyclopedists, the mayors.
Speaker 0: Right, right.
Speaker 1: That there's always one guy or a small group of people who know what's up.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: They have a shit eating grin.
Speaker 1: You can see it in your mind's eye whole time you're reading the shittest eating his grin a human has ever had.
Speaker 0: It's like the torchbearer, right?
Speaker 0: It's like Harry Seldon lit this torch and he passed it on through the ears.
Speaker 0: And there's always one guy carrying it.
Speaker 0: And you know who that guy is immediately.
Speaker 1: And even if like it wasn't obvious from the story, it's the one guy where you don't know what he's thinking.
Speaker 0: Always a guy.
Speaker 1: Are there any girls in this?
Speaker 1: Not yet.
Speaker 1: There's that one courtesan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, great.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And she, well, they, uh, they foist off some jewelry on her and she's done.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Good job as a mom.
Speaker 1: Way to progress.
Speaker 1: women's science fiction.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm sure, you know, I guess it's all, I guess it is shortly after Rome.
Speaker 0: So women don't have rights.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But, uh, I said he has this shit eating grin character in every age and every other character.
Speaker 1: Like, you know what they're trying to accomplish.
Speaker 1: You get inside their heads.
Speaker 1: The main character always just like the other guy will say, Oh, this is why your plan will fail.
Speaker 1: Or you don't even have a well see.
Speaker 0: And the thing is like, you're always rooting for the guy who knows what's up.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: Because the guy, and you know, he's always going to win because he's always kind of a jerk because you just like, you begin to believe right after that first chapter where, or the first age where Seldon appears for the first crisis.
Speaker 0: And it was like, you were right.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: From that, you just become a believer in it, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, even though, you know, in the book, there's like the fake religion they invent to get people to believe in Seldon, which reminded me very much of last exile.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like it's almost the exact same thing almost, but it's like, now you act, the reader believe in Harry Seldon that, you know, he's almost like this godlike figure.
Speaker 0: His plan is for real,
Speaker 1: which is interesting because that's part of the reason why I think I identify so much with the like salver harden in the encyclopedist, the people who are the smart ones with the shit eating grins, because you having seen how everything played out from this objective standpoint as the reader,
Speaker 0: you
Speaker 1: believe it and you know that that guy is going to win.
Speaker 1: So when he smiles and nods, you're smiling and nodding right along with him.
Speaker 0: I do think it's in the first book, at least they didn't, your belief wasn't, uh, challenged.
Speaker 0: I wonder if in the future books, your belief will be challenged, right?
Speaker 0: Because it was like, they talk about, ah, Seldon had 95% certainty on this, but all his methods were statistical.
Speaker 0: We know that as we get further out, his, you know, the power of his plan will decrease and statistically, it's more likely that something will go wrong.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But I kind of want to see that happen.
Speaker 0: And then I want to see it go wrong and then go right again.
Speaker 1: The errors of this book kind of follow errors of human history.
Speaker 1: We control the population with just religion.
Speaker 1: Well, well first commerce first it's government and busy work.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Then it's religion.
Speaker 1: Then it's commerce.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Actually in between there's, there's, there's the nice progression, but it's, it's sort of like, they don't say it, but it's so obvious that it's like, how do we get through a dark age?
Speaker 0: We'll just force the progression of human history that already happened one step at a time as quickly as possible to get people, the whole society built back up to be, you know, modern again.
Speaker 0: But you know, it's sort of like.
Speaker 0: he's saying at first he says he wants the encyclopedia, but that's just the cover story.
Speaker 0: Then he says the goal of the plan is to bring back the empire, but it's like, when you really think about it, it's like, no, the goal of the plan isn't to bring back the empire, right?
Speaker 0: Even though it hasn't happened because we're only in the first book.
Speaker 1: The empire would fail again for the same reason, right?
Speaker 0: The empire is a monarchy.
Speaker 0: The goal is to bring back a galactic civilization that is not a monarchy or an emperor or anything, but is, you know, a democratic, you know, amazing, maybe democratic, maybe not, but you know, something awesome.
Speaker 0: That's not an emperor.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's the general idea.
Speaker 1: I did like the emperor because he wasn't that bad.
Speaker 0: Well, he was, he wasn't like Nicholas the second.
Speaker 1: He was just, I don't know.
Speaker 1: He had a fun, like the way he was described in the, the level of disparity between the nobles and the ruling classes and the rest of the people in the empire was pretty like, I also like how the empire still exists, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, that was great at the end of the, you know, it's like, you didn't really think about it, but then once, you know, at the, towards the end, you learn the empire still exists and it's like, Oh, well obviously it would, you know, it's like, it didn't
Speaker 1: get until the 1400s,
Speaker 0: didn't get destroyed completely.
Speaker 0: It was spread across so many worlds.
Speaker 0: It was like a raid, a billion, right?
Speaker 0: You couldn't take the whole thing out.
Speaker 0: It just weakened.
Speaker 0: So it lost its hold over outer territories and it was no longer a galaxy spanning ultra strong civilization.
Speaker 0: It just lost so much influence, but it still existed.
Speaker 0: You know, the capital planet was still, you know, it's like no one attacked it and conquered it.
Speaker 1: But I really like, like when the traders are trying to figure out, well, the one traders trying to figure out what's going on with the planet that somehow has nucleix and he sees the Imperial insignia on the guns, he's like, Oh shit.
Speaker 0: That's another thing is that it, there's a lot of nerd sort of fantasy fulfillment things that are happening for, you know, like what if I went to a primitive place with my advanced technologies, that would be so awesome.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: So it's like, well, what happens if, you know, one sort of planet splits off and maintains the high level of knowledge and the other places in the world descend into a dark age.
Speaker 1: I mean, I love this feeling that one trader ship could probably wipe out the majority of the space navies in the known universe.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, you like to always talk about how people in the dark ages saw shit that was leftover from the previous age.
Speaker 1: Precursor technology just gets me going.
Speaker 0: And we're like, how the fuck was this made?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Well, think of La Calama, right?
Speaker 0: There's the elder glass.
Speaker 0: Well, imagine, you know, it's one thing for their.
Speaker 0: it's like, Oh, in the past they knew how to make elder glass and no one knows how to make it anymore.
Speaker 0: Well, what if there was another place in the same time where they still knew how to make?
Speaker 0: it is just not in your place.
Speaker 0: So that's what it's like.
Speaker 0: And then suddenly one day people who know how to make elder glass show up.
Speaker 0: It's like, Oh, that's so awesome.
Speaker 1: They're like, what are you doing with our shit?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's good stuff.
Speaker 0: It just makes, it's a lot of stuff to make nerds happy.
Speaker 1: The smart jerk that everyone is mad at and opposing wins epically every time.
Speaker 0: And people always, they always seem to be able to avoid military force.
Speaker 0: usually, right?
Speaker 0: Because what's the phrase in the book?
Speaker 1: It's like violence is the last resort of a week, like weak minds or something.
Speaker 1: I forget the quote.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it's like the, you know, they're so smart that they can always avoid war and they don't avoid war with like a Gandhi strategy.
Speaker 0: They avoid war with like a clever plan strategy and you get the same sort of thing going on as you do with like sanctuary where like they find some clever way out of it to stay in the game.
Speaker 0: I think the biggest, but it's like, it's so Epic though.
Speaker 0: Cause in sanctuary, it's like two guys find a way to stay in the game and this, an entire civilization finds a way to stay in the game.
Speaker 1: But I like how the way they stay in the game is not the sort of like proper way you'd expect with some like very intricate and good guy way of doing it.
Speaker 1: And they, they just fucking like lie to people get like that.
Speaker 1: Remember they give the guy the transmuter that's going to just stop working.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They just, they do like the pirate way.
Speaker 1: It's almost the Harlock way of saving the day.
Speaker 0: The other thing about it that's pretty interesting is the whole thing about, you know, uh, Seldon is psychologist and they don't let any psychologist survive.
Speaker 0: So they purposefully make that knowledge lost.
Speaker 1: So it's like, it's like, it eliminates the rocket fuel equation where the amount of fuel you need in a rocket depends upon how much fuel you have in the rocket.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Just with psycho history.
Speaker 1: I mean, if someone knew like, what if, you know, the Prince of nothing, what if it's kept like someone like Nair who kind of knows tell us his game can cock everything up because he can affect it in ways much greater than people who don't know.
Speaker 0: So it's like they, they using a particular technology, right.
Speaker 0: To get to, to achieve a certain goal.
Speaker 0: But if someone understands that technology, if they under, they have the gnosis or whatever, they can see right through it and begin to work it the same way they worked it.
Speaker 0: Because they want their stuff to be able to their plan to work for centuries and set for thousands of years, it's going to take, I think he said a thousand years, right?
Speaker 0: That he needs there not to be anyone to do with his knowledge that could cock it up.
Speaker 0: So that way, basically he's, it's like building a robot.
Speaker 0: That's like Astro boy, but nobody knows how to make an Astro boy.
Speaker 0: Cause it's like, you know, you send an Astro boy into the past.
Speaker 0: And as long as there's no roboticists in the past, then nobody can do anything to Astro boy.
Speaker 0: So he's basically omnipotent because he's in the past.
Speaker 0: So that's basically eliminate all psychological knowledge, but at the same time in this sort of society, psychological power is unassailable for that.
Speaker 0: I have a moral question for you.
Speaker 1: If you are the mayor, let's say of terminus and a group of people start working diligently to rediscover psycho history and figure it all out.
Speaker 1: Do you stop them?
Speaker 0: Well, if they succeed, then that means that the original psycho history of Seldon either a intended that or B failed, which you can't do anything about.
Speaker 1: or maybe C by that logic, you can say that about anything.
Speaker 1: that if anything happens, either it was right or it was wrong and things would have progressed the way they progressed anyway.
Speaker 1: So why even bother?
Speaker 0: But the only, there is a way though, to tell if Seldon, if it's going the right way opens, right?
Speaker 0: When the crisis happens, that is a good way to tell.
Speaker 0: Another great way to tell is if things are generally trending away from a dark age, if something causes a trend towards a dark age, you know, to less intelligence, less intellect, then you know that it's going the wrong way and it's not working.
Speaker 0: every time, every step, every time there's a crisis, things trend up trending away from the dark age and towards Renaissance and enlightenment seem to have figured out early on.
Speaker 1: internal and external crisis were designed to coincide like that because I think that's really what he's after Harry Seldon in the end that you, if the galactic empire reforms or anything like it, then it would stagnate again.
Speaker 1: And if it was just the encyclopedist again, it would stagnate.
Speaker 1: the external crisis forces the rest of the world to be dealt with, to eventually, you know, spread the knowledge and overcome the internal crisis forces everything to constantly be changing up inside.
Speaker 1: so we can never stagnate.
Speaker 1: Like both are necessary or it wouldn't work.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They had to, they had to both evolve themselves.
Speaker 0: They can't, they, you know, they couldn't just stay in encyclopedia mode forever.
Speaker 0: That wouldn't have worked, right?
Speaker 1: That's like a bacteria that cysts and never un-cysts.
Speaker 1: It's not a bacteria anymore.
Speaker 1: And
Speaker 0: it needs to spread and it also, you know, so it's like he's basically forced it into this evolutionary pattern, you know, where the society acts in a Darwinian as a whole, you know, not within society, but as a whole, the society is like an organism that is evolving, but not using Darwinian, you know, uh, you know, like, uh, you know, to like, let's kill all the weak people.
Speaker 0: They don't do that.
Speaker 1: I really enjoyed when they first, like the vault opens the first time and they go inside, you know, the few people.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And the fact that they look around and they see way more chairs than there are them and they wonder if they already did something wrong.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I also, I think my favorite moment when I really have to consider it is when they use religion to punk wenis, wenis, the prince on, on a Korean.
Speaker 1: I love all that.
Speaker 0: Like that prince is like, I'll do whatever I want.
Speaker 0: Where they get like the glowing clothes and shit.
Speaker 1: And then he just like turns off his glowing cloak and turns off his throne and turns off all the nuclear power.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's the, it's, you know, it's the old significantly advanced technologies into, you know, into, uh, inseparable from magic and it's like, well, yeah, but here's the thing is it's not inseparable from magic because they understand the technology.
Speaker 0: The other guy doesn't say the guy thinks it's magic, but you know, it's not, I know it's sort of like, it's almost like a superhero power fantasy.
Speaker 0: It's like you have a planet of super powered nerds that are superheroes because they have advanced technology and all the moron planets are basically bad guys.
Speaker 1: My worry is that foundation is fun and good, but I don't think it's necessarily provocative as science fiction.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe it was in its day, right?
Speaker 0: This is like seventies, right?
Speaker 1: I mean more in terms of, if you look at it, the, the fundamental answer to like the question is asking is how do you like prevent dark ages going forward?
Speaker 1: Like what can you do if crisis is coming?
Speaker 0: Too bad psycho history isn't real.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe it is.
Speaker 1: I mean, sociology, we can pretty accurately predict how mobs of people will act in certain situations, but we don't, we can't do that yet, but that set, you know, some many years in the future, like 10,000 years beyond where we are now.
Speaker 0: But there's still, I think is, that's another thing I noticed about the book I want to comment on is how many, you know, it's, it's supposed to be the future, but how much of it is still so eighties and seventies, right?
Speaker 0: Cause it's like the talking about nucleix, like nuclear power is the shit and it's like, yeah, no, but look at what nucleix are portrayed as.
Speaker 1: they're not reactors the way we know them.
Speaker 1: They're more like the kind of nanotechnological manipulation in our science fiction.
Speaker 1: The point is when, you know, a lot of this stuff and I think they're called nucleix because that's, it sounds like it puts it on a parallel path.
Speaker 1: It's not like nuclear power as they knew in the eighties, seventies, sixties, fifties.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But it, you know, the point, it's still a lot of this stuff.
Speaker 1: If it sounds eighties to you, that means Asimov was a genius.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying it was published in 1951.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Well, they had nuclear power in 51.
Speaker 0: I guess I had the year, I had the year completely wrong.
Speaker 0: But the point is, is that a lot of this stuff you could tell was like a sign of, you know, the times it was written.
Speaker 0: Like some of the technologies were advanced and some of the technologies were the same as when the book was written.
Speaker 1: What was the same?
Speaker 1: The screens were all like flat screens.
Speaker 0: I didn't even see them talking about screens.
Speaker 0: There were, there were screens, but it's like, you know, they still had books.
Speaker 0: They didn't have internet.
Speaker 0: We still have books, you know, they would still use, you know, it's, it's, we have books now, but we wouldn't have books thousands of years from now.
Speaker 0: Books are starting to go away already.
Speaker 1: Maybe they kept books because, you know, the, everything was collapsing.
Speaker 0: That happens with a lot of sci-fis.
Speaker 0: Like you always think of some things to advance and some things don't.
Speaker 1: Well, like look at, we just watched Total Recall not that long ago and how everyone has gigantic walkie talkies and there's gigantic CRTs everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But except for the, in his house, there's like the great flat screen.
Speaker 1: And the fact that they're always like, it's weird how they're always using video phones.
Speaker 1: Something that to this day isn't anything that anyone wants.
Speaker 0: We have FaceTime, but no one wants it.
Speaker 1: But you know, I guess, I guess my point when I say it's not that provocative is, you know, it's a great, and it brings forth a lot of interesting ideas, but the core ideas, the way they resolve their problems are really just a superhero fixes everything every time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's true.
Speaker 1: One awesome nerd saves the day.
Speaker 0: But it's not so much about the fact that an awesome nerd saves the day.
Speaker 0: It's what does the nerd do to save the day?
Speaker 0: Cause he doesn't do anything magical.
Speaker 0: It is technology, right?
Speaker 0: And it's always like, what is he going to do?
Speaker 0: And sometimes you know what he's going to do.
Speaker 0: You know, as soon as it's about traitors that he's going to switch from religion to, you know, uh, mercantilism, right?
Speaker 0: You just know that's, what's going to happen.
Speaker 0: But in like the, the earlier ones, he didn't know a hundred percent what he was going to do, you know, when he's like going to be married, he's going out, you know, it's like, I guess it's just that.
Speaker 1: the, the problems that are present, like the fundamental question is interesting.
Speaker 1: The individual problems presented are more interesting from an illumination of our current problems than they are as a future looking like, how do we change things perspective?
Speaker 1: They're more like, if you read this from the perspective of understanding where religion and where everything we had up to this point came from, it's very provocative.
Speaker 1: If you read it future looking, not so much.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Still.
Speaker 0: It's fun.
Speaker 0: It's awesome.
Speaker 0: You can tell, I guess if it was for the fifties, a lot of the, you know, it's like, it's almost like we've heard this story so many times before, but it's like, well, maybe this was the one of the earliest instances of this story.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, Scott, you realize 1951 was when the book compiling all of them was published.
Speaker 0: Ah, so it was short stories.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, man, that's real old.
Speaker 0: Old.
Speaker 0: Um, yeah, I definitely, I'm going to read the, uh, the rest of them.
Speaker 0: At least I've got the next two to make the trilogy and I'll see if I go beyond that, you know, cause I don't know what this is.
Speaker 1: I'll read up until the beast and then I'll make my decision from there.
Speaker 0: The beast.
Speaker 1: Watch the beast is just like a woman.
Speaker 0: Oh God.
Speaker 0: We got, we definitely, the book definitely has negative points for the no women situation.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, really?
Speaker 0: The galactic empire is only a man.
Speaker 1: So we're curious, what are your thoughts?
Speaker 1: I mean, this is a book club, so this was just our short take.
Speaker 0: I think now that the book club is its own show that doesn't have news, maybe we should, you know, take some comments on the future books.
Speaker 0: So what's your, what's the book again, rim?
Speaker 0: I, the eye, the ear and the arm.
Speaker 1: This is one of those titles.
Speaker 1: That's a lot like nine somethings, nine somethings, nine somethings.
Speaker 0: You forget the, forget the order.
Speaker 1: It's the ear, the eye and the arm.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So if you read the ear, the eye and the arm, send in your comments to eat nights at front row crew.com or post them in the forum or post them in the forum.
Speaker 0: And then we will, you may perhaps read some on the next book club episode, which would be in a month.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: One month.
Speaker 0: We're going to do it towards the end of every month as its own episode.
Speaker 0: It won't be a Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday or Thursday.
Speaker 0: It'd be its own thing.
Speaker 1: But for foundation, I still want to hear your thoughts.
Speaker 1: I want to hear if you enjoyed it as much as we did.
Speaker 0: We won't talk about it on the show though.
Speaker 1: If you agree with our assessments of it and all that, if you have any interesting insights, we obviously skipped over a kind of textbook analysis of it because that's, you can read articles if you want to get like some professor talking about their thoughts.
Speaker 1: I just want to talk about our personal, like, what I got out of this.
Speaker 0: It's like I could have researched the book and talked more about that, but it's like, you can read Wikipedia too.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like, we're not the only ones who know how to read Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: I doubt many books we review in the book club will have startling insights from rim and Scott hitherto unknown to the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like I kind of, you know, most of the reason for the book club is just to get you to read, you know, and the show is just sort of like, you know, entertainment to encourage.
Speaker 0: It's like, here is an entertainment that you can enjoy more if you read the book.
Speaker 0: So that's encouraging you to read the book.
Speaker 0: You know, everything else is just icing.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: For the logos, be sure to visit our website@frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution.
Speaker 0: 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.