Speaker 0: Hey, it's Tuesday, November 15th, 2011.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and this is geek nights Tonight returning from burning apocalypse con 11 11 11.
Speaker 0: We have Jared Sorensen.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: I Promise it's corny.
Speaker 1: It's bad.
Speaker 1: It's Stan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna introduce him with my bad joke.
Speaker 0: that is all you ready.
Speaker 0: I'm ready.
Speaker 1: welcome to geek nights Podcast.
Speaker 0: it takes a long time.
Speaker 0: You're in a room with two morons So we're actually here with three morons we've got.
Speaker 0: I didn't come up with a funny title.
Speaker 0: I called Luke like the right and honorable just to see if he'd react to it and the fact that he did was funny be Wrong and dishonorable.
Speaker 0: We're here with Jared Sorenson the creator of parsley games such as action castle and Z Ward.
Speaker 0: He's not talking so we have no proof that he's actually here.
Speaker 0: we've also got teller of Penn and Teller.
Speaker 1: That was even less funny.
Speaker 1: He's like my joke.
Speaker 0: At this point I think the listeners are actually wondering whether or not we've got anyone.
Speaker 1: dude We should fake guess more often.
Speaker 1: We should have Miyazaki on Wednesday.
Speaker 1: We'll interview him.
Speaker 1: Hideo Kojima sure, oh That's so interesting and they'll just pretend like his microphone is broken the whole time and it's like.
Speaker 1: well We released our half of the interview.
Speaker 1: We sorry we lost the other part.
Speaker 1: So Jared you gonna say something.
Speaker 1: yeah, I'm just So.
Speaker 1: I guess we better start over talking about your big Activity here.
Speaker 1: on the the kick-starting right you got the the new parsley game and whatnot.
Speaker 2: I am raising a buttload of money.
Speaker 1: Oh my god a buttload buttload.
Speaker 2: That's nice and so English Arsload.
Speaker 0: so this is for Z Ward the zombie Apocalypse survival parsley game kind of.
Speaker 2: yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean I played through the first bit of it before we got kicked out of burning apocalypse con right.
Speaker 2: so you know You know what it's about.
Speaker 0: It's about zombies.
Speaker 2: It's about zombies.
Speaker 2: You are in a mental asylum And you have to rescue your sister.
Speaker 1: Oh It was a messy.
Speaker 1: I didn't even get that.
Speaker 1: I thought it was just a regular old hospital.
Speaker 0: Nope Scott You didn't read like the title screen.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't read shit at all.
Speaker 1: I was mostly worried about how I can make it as difficult as possible for the other people.
Speaker 0: You can see that picture of me.
Speaker 0: someone posted where I'm standing there And I was literally thinking inject syringe into South.
Speaker 0: and then I decided But I so wanted to.
Speaker 2: you cannot do that.
Speaker 0: I think you need I think you need to be a little more Dickish and willing to let people kill themselves in public events like that.
Speaker 1: Have you played fucking like any other parsley games?
Speaker 2: Yeah No, it's just the.
Speaker 2: the syringe doesn't kill you.
Speaker 2: the syringe kills you in in space station.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I guess in this one.
Speaker 0: It would just today spoiler.
Speaker 0: So how many parsley games are there?
Speaker 0: I haven't even played all of them.
Speaker 2: there are I'm not including the little ones.
Speaker 2: So basically the numbered blackboard.
Speaker 2: blackboard jungle death world and flaming goat flaming goat.
Speaker 1: That's a great one.
Speaker 2: Those are Those are the mini ones but the the mate the major like numbered ones.
Speaker 2: Z Ward will be number seven Are you?
Speaker 1: are you planning?
Speaker 1: just you know continue as long as it's successful?
Speaker 1: Yes So it says here, let's see you're currently at let's see five over five G's.
Speaker 1: that's a lot of money.
Speaker 2: Whoo, what's the number right now?
Speaker 2: I don't know the number.
Speaker 1: five thousand three hundred and twenty two.
Speaker 1: That's with two of 201 people.
Speaker 1: So those people are paying individually a lot of monies.
Speaker 2: That is crazy.
Speaker 1: And you have 15 days.
Speaker 2: I have a lot of things to mail out.
Speaker 2: in December.
Speaker 2: I'm gonna be like these.
Speaker 1: people are paying an average of what's five thousand divided by two hundred like fifty bucks for a piece of cardboard.
Speaker 2: No, no, no, okay Eight pieces of cardboard.
Speaker 2: Oh a t-shirt.
Speaker 2: Yeah, you get eight.
Speaker 2: you get eight games.
Speaker 2: You get a t-shirt you get a patch a cool patch.
Speaker 2: You get some buttons.
Speaker 2: kids love buttons.
Speaker 2: You get all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 1: I see nobody has paid the 1,500. nobody.
Speaker 2: You know, I thought the Danes would come through to get me to fast of all April.
Speaker 1: yeah, didn't you go to that last time or something to that last year with Luke?
Speaker 1: How was that?
Speaker 2: It was ridiculously fun.
Speaker 0: I would like to go to that in Essen.
Speaker 0: I really want to go to and I'm trying to swing some business to have an excuse to be over in Germany right around Essen time.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Yeah, you should definitely.
Speaker 1: let's go in a tangent.
Speaker 1: What's it like over there?
Speaker 2: It's crazy.
Speaker 2: I really want to go to the Finnish game con for a bunch of reasons But the Danish con fast of all it's.
Speaker 2: um It's weird.
Speaker 2: It's not typical role-playing.
Speaker 2: It's not what you think about.
Speaker 2: It's not a bunch of people sitting around a table with dice and screens and character sheets, it's a lot of Essentially like improv acting.
Speaker 2: like you get a scenario which is the scenarios are weird.
Speaker 2: Most of them are realistic Historical or kind of literary.
Speaker 2: the one I was in was like a Lars Van Trier movie we had.
Speaker 2: it was called Easter a tragedy and I played the Sun in a four-person household.
Speaker 2: my sister and I had come back from From Copenhagen to visit our family out in the country.
Speaker 2: And so we visited mom and dad and in the game We actually went to this The the con.
Speaker 2: that part of the con was held in classrooms and we actually knocked on the door of the classroom.
Speaker 2: Our mom and dad let us in and we sat down and actually ate Thanksgiving.
Speaker 2: I'm not Thanksgiving.
Speaker 2: I'm sorry Easter dinner Is Easter.
Speaker 2: a tragedy was actual food actual food.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: you didn't have to go get lunch because the food was like the game.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 2: it was.
Speaker 2: It was brown bread butter Pickled herring Historically accurate food.
Speaker 2: It was all like traditional Easter.
Speaker 2: Easter the GM that the guy who wrote The GM was okay.
Speaker 2: So here's the weird thing about Danish tradition.
Speaker 2: The GM is essentially the director.
Speaker 2: So if he doesn't like how things are going he will step in and he will whisper in your ear.
Speaker 2: be more intense Or you feel very sad about this.
Speaker 0: Well, Luke does that to me when I play in his game But but I mean the Danish guys will.
Speaker 2: actually We were in things where they made us redo scenes that they were.
Speaker 2: they didn't feel we captured the moment.
Speaker 1: They're recording these on video.
Speaker 2: No, no, it was.
Speaker 0: That almost might cheapen it in that it like without having a record you only have the rosy memory.
Speaker 0: So there's no.
Speaker 1: so this isn't like there's no rules book you can buy for this right?
Speaker 2: No, no, there's scenarios.
Speaker 2: Oh the scenario tradition.
Speaker 2: It's weird because they'll they'll.
Speaker 2: they'll have people write scenarios and the writer.
Speaker 2: the role of the writer is Huge like, you know RPGs whatever you come with the scenario who cares see it's all about the players play play play In Denmark, it's all about the writer of the scenario and the person who runs it and it's basically the writers vision in the directors.
Speaker 1: Implement implementation of that.
Speaker 2: you're essentially it's like George Lucas directing his human actors.
Speaker 2: You know where he just kind of treats them as the same as the CG actors.
Speaker 2: It's weird.
Speaker 2: we had we had one player in one of the games.
Speaker 2: I was in actually run out of the room crying and she With the game Because it got really intense.
Speaker 0: So I got a question.
Speaker 0: Do you think we could sell something like that?
Speaker 0: Not not monetary not commercialized but like get people in the US to play a game.
Speaker 2: totally no problem.
Speaker 2: So I could I could rewrite Easter a tragedy for an American audience Which it basically just involves changing maybe the holiday and definitely changing the food.
Speaker 2: Well the language I had an English version of it But pretty much straight-up run it.
Speaker 2: you are a conservative family out in the Midwest.
Speaker 2: you're home from the big city.
Speaker 1: No from the military from the military, whatever, you know, whatever.
Speaker 2: And the interesting thing about so the interesting thing about Easter which I which I didn't explain is every.
Speaker 2: The game is divided into phases and essentially the game ends when the good mood at the table is broken.
Speaker 2: So when a fight breaks out or when somebody cries or when when something bad happens.
Speaker 2: And the thing is when once you eat dinner There's a very there's a set ritual about what you eat when and what you talk about and stuff like that.
Speaker 2: and it's weird talking about Basically making small talk with people you don't know in real life who are portraying people that you don't know because you haven't Met them before in the game, but you're supposed to intimately know them because you're a family.
Speaker 2: really weird But by the second phase it was easy.
Speaker 2: so the first phase we.
Speaker 2: you go through dinner and blah blah blah blah, and then the mother says Well, you should probably be heading back.
Speaker 2: It's getting dark and that's the cue for everybody to basically say their goodbyes Shake hands hug whatever and then leave and then the GM hands out little secrets about what happened in that year And then you go back and you play the next year Easter dinner.
Speaker 2: Oh You do this over and over and over again Which meant I ate a lot of pickled herring during that game Which thankfully I like that stuff, but it was.
Speaker 2: you know It was.
Speaker 2: it was rough.
Speaker 0: that's some good stuff.
Speaker 0: we got it.
Speaker 0: we got to get that gaming Concept into us gamers.
Speaker 1: is everyone at the con playing Easter or were there just a bunch of different?
Speaker 1: No there was.
Speaker 2: I think there were four Sessions of Easter going on concurrently, and that's yeah, so there were only.
Speaker 1: there weren't that many scenarios.
Speaker 1: They were doing the same one a lot.
Speaker 2: Well.
Speaker 2: Here's the thing it's really weird is what they'll do is They'll hand off.
Speaker 2: They'll write the scenario They'll hand it off to a bunch of GM's and a bunch of GM's at the con will run the same scenario for a bunch of groups.
Speaker 2: So it's not like this one game system being run by many people, but it's different Scenarios or adventures or whatever.
Speaker 2: it's like no you're running Easter a tragedy.
Speaker 2: you're running sex drugs and rock and roll.
Speaker 2: you're running 15 men and there's a meeting where you actually get the materials and sometimes That's the first time you've seen this stuff, so you read it the GM's read it, and then they run it.
Speaker 1: That could even work with just our kind of tabletop RPGs where you know you go to a con.
Speaker 1: Someone writes up like three Burning wheel mascot scenarios for the con and just hands them out.
Speaker 1: get it yeah ten GM's over and you're like here's the scenarios.
Speaker 1: Everyone go and run them you know and then it's like players.
Speaker 0: He has all the tables there's an interesting kind of mechanism Designed to that of the whole con and that now all these players are playing.
Speaker 0: these games have a shared But disparate experience which forces them to talk to each other.
Speaker 0: Oh, how did your yeah go?
Speaker 0: well everybody died.
Speaker 2: well Easter so Easter Theoretically will last until the mood is broken.
Speaker 2: we we went I think three or four years before my sister and father got into an argument about Drinking because she did not want to tell him she was pregnant because he would have flipped out.
Speaker 2: And so he was like oh, why are you being rude?
Speaker 2: Why you know?
Speaker 2: I'm just trying to be hospitable.
Speaker 2: Why are you being you know so rude and so bratty?
Speaker 2: and they got into a screaming match in.
Speaker 2: the game ended?
Speaker 1: Oh, but he wanted her to drink.
Speaker 2: Yeah, and she was like no, but she doesn't want to say I'm pregnant I can't drink.
Speaker 2: She just has to say no.
Speaker 2: I'm not feeling like it.
Speaker 2: He's like oh your brother's gonna drive.
Speaker 1: That's good on the writer.
Speaker 1: They're coming up with that.
Speaker 1: It's really good.
Speaker 2: So what happens in the fifth year is the father drops dead at the table of a heart attack?
Speaker 2: So no matter what happens the game ends after like five years, but man that fifth year It's like a Darren Aronofsky film everybody's secrets that you get.
Speaker 2: it's just like oh my god.
Speaker 2: I want to kill myself.
Speaker 0: This is so depressing I Feel like it solves a big problem.
Speaker 0: I mean even at burning apocalypse con like the so-called hardcore like we are hardcore role players Let's go.
Speaker 2: No idea what hardcore isn't.
Speaker 0: This is.
Speaker 0: this is like a guy coming up to me like I'm a metal head.
Speaker 0: I listen to Metallica every day.
Speaker 2: There's one game very controversial game, I don't even know if I should talk about it.
Speaker 2: It's called And I'm spacing on the title something about the fat man.
Speaker 1: Is it insulting to fat people?
Speaker 1: yes, okay?
Speaker 2: Extremely, so here's how you play.
Speaker 2: everybody plays.
Speaker 2: So What happens is the fastest people got the fattest male player in the game session plays the fat man.
Speaker 0: that might prove contentious in the US.
Speaker 2: well get out the scales.
Speaker 2: You know the scales in the in the measuring tape so that so that the largest male player Plays the fat man everybody else plays the friends of the fat man.
Speaker 2: And I'm kind of air quoting friends because what the friends of the fat man do during the game is insult the fat man Constantly berate and belittle him.
Speaker 2: the fat man has a pocketful of candy and whenever he eats a piece of candy They have to stop berating and belittling him and actually complement him and act really super nice to him like they're.
Speaker 2: like the fat man Is the best friend.
Speaker 0: wow that's already a little messed up.
Speaker 2: No it gets better It's so much better.
Speaker 2: So the fat man has.
Speaker 2: the fat man character is given a safe word which if the game gets too Stressful and intense he can say that the the safe word in the game will end Except privately.
Speaker 2: the friends of the fat man are told to ignore the safe word.
Speaker 2: So the game ends when the fat man gets so upset that he actually leaves and the game is supposed to and I love this Is what's great about Denmark because everything has this deep meaning to it, and they're very serious and very earnest.
Speaker 2: They're really cool.
Speaker 2: But it's kind of comical because the the scenario guys like yes, this is and I can't really do a Danish accent.
Speaker 2: Yes this because of the game is to make you feel guilty about about being so mean to the fat man.
Speaker 2: That's what the game is about about your shame.
Speaker 2: I'm like.
Speaker 2: it just seems like abuse to me.
Speaker 1: You're teaching the people the players a lesson.
Speaker 1: what about the fat man?
Speaker 2: Yeah, he's crying in the dark.
Speaker 1: I know I feel like you could be sacrificed for the better of the group.
Speaker 0: some experiences.
Speaker 0: We've talked about a geek nights back in the day with casting people out of the crew.
Speaker 0: Did you know it's very difficult when there's a guy that nobody's actually friends with but you know he's really in a tentacle porn.
Speaker 0: you Try to make him leave you alone.
Speaker 0: Finally someone breaks it to him.
Speaker 0: You could make it the game that you give to people as the final resort.
Speaker 2: Yes Hey You want to play a game in case of bad game or break glass and inside is a cop games as tools to.
Speaker 0: actually You're working on your YouTube game.
Speaker 0: My game is a card game that you play to decide what the fuck to do.
Speaker 0: right now who gets control of the internet TV?
Speaker 0: Yes, but mine's a card game that also does meta stuff like ordering pizza.
Speaker 1: That's actually a clever idea right cuz?
Speaker 1: like people always talk about you know jokingly how like diplomacy is a friend killer or something right?
Speaker 1: Well, it's like what.
Speaker 1: if you want to get rid of some friends?
Speaker 1: You could make a game that helps you.
Speaker 1: it's like you know or maybe even stand because most most games They help you make friends even if they're not designed specifically to do so.
Speaker 1: you could probably make a game That is like the friend making game.
Speaker 1: right you know you need to make the Girlfriend getting game.
Speaker 2: well, that's breaking the ass Emily care boss.
Speaker 1: Did that did she?
Speaker 1: what's it called?
Speaker 2: I'm not breaking the ice is it?
Speaker 0: so there's actually a lot of like mini LARP's with simple rules that are designed for that.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: there's this pool one.
Speaker 0: You're all fish You're all have like goals in the pool.
Speaker 1: What's the girl's name?
Speaker 0: Emily care boss Scott, that's the game.
Speaker 0: don't break the ice.
Speaker 0: it's not the
Speaker 1: rules black and green
Speaker 2: It's about it.
Speaker 2: It's about three first dates And apparently I this one.
Speaker 2: that is it.
Speaker 2: yeah apparently people actually have gotten together after playing that game, huh All right, nobody's gone together after playing action castle though There's too many people although.
Speaker 2: I've gotten a hug.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Wait wait.
Speaker 2: No orgy castle I mean somebody suggested the the kinky the kinky parsley game.
Speaker 2: Maybe maybe in the future Playtesting that will be interesting Not it.
Speaker 2: I probably won't do it at Gen Con.
Speaker 0: maybe packs But packs you get.
Speaker 0: mag fest has a surprising proportion not to of like.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna do it 50 I'm gonna do it in Finland 70 30.
Speaker 1: Yes, yeah, I mean if they have the real food.
Speaker 1: They've got to have the real sex too, right?
Speaker 2: I mean that apparently they they have done large shot of our IT.
Speaker 0: It was exactly like.
Speaker 1: you don't want those people.
Speaker 0: I mean they were.
Speaker 0: they weren't role-playing vampires.
Speaker 0: They were vampires.
Speaker 1: That's different people are.
Speaker 1: they didn't even count as people.
Speaker 1: I mean come on whatever.
Speaker 0: But but to back up a little bit, you know the super the so-called hardcore like role players in America.
Speaker 0: Even like the best role players I know will be in character for maybe 30 seconds of their great monologue and then it always trails off into.
Speaker 0: yeah I try to convince the guy to not kill my son.
Speaker 0: It's role-playing.
Speaker 0: It's not acting Yeah, but I feel like the acting is happening.
Speaker 2: helps if you're a good actor it helps Yeah, but I like the games that trick people into acting.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like, you know burning wheels duel of wits kind of tricks people into like having a reasonable argument.
Speaker 0: It's interesting.
Speaker 1: I actually don't know how well I would do as cool as like the Danish thing sounds.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm not that good at acting.
Speaker 1: So like when it's so free like makes you stretch Yeah, but it's like, you know, that's why I like when there's dice and stuff.
Speaker 1: Not just because I like rolling dice, which I do but they do not like dice over there, right?
Speaker 1: But because it helps me suck suck less when I have some numbers to go by right?
Speaker 1: It's like I'm a computer guy.
Speaker 1: I know how to make numbers go up.
Speaker 1: So it's like I'll just do the thing I need to make those numbers go up which happens to also be good acting at the same.
Speaker 0: Yes, you did this like you go between the two like I found it's got you personally.
Speaker 0: you role-play better when you're not playing A character but you're playing an accent.
Speaker 0: if you pick an accent you play a good character.
Speaker 0: That's Yeah, that's we need to make that an RPG.
Speaker 1: all the accent RPG Ridiculous accent.
Speaker 0: So how did you come up with the idea for action cows?
Speaker 0: Like when was the?
Speaker 0: what was the moment where you're sitting there?
Speaker 0: They're like I should run this for a bunch of people.
Speaker 2: I was at a party.
Speaker 2: I've told the story.
Speaker 2: God, I just told the story in the genocides.
Speaker 2: go listen to her podcast.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 2: There's a little plug for Jen.
Speaker 2: yeah, listen to it's.
Speaker 2: I've told the story a bunch of times.
Speaker 2: basically I was at.
Speaker 2: I was at a party.
Speaker 2: We were kind of hanging out.
Speaker 2: I had this idea.
Speaker 2: I'm a big text adventure fan from my days of yore.
Speaker 2: I actually worked for info comm as a 12 year old Playtesting one of their games and I got to tour their office and meet all the peeps there and I actually have My.
Speaker 2: I was going through my box of my box of sad memories and in my box of sad memories is a t-shirt I made with Floyd the robot from Planet Fall and on the back.
Speaker 2: It says I love info comm and it would barely fit a Cabbage patch kid.
Speaker 2: It's hilarious.
Speaker 2: I'm like man.
Speaker 2: I was a tiny little kid.
Speaker 2: It's crazy.
Speaker 2: But yeah, I loved info comm.
Speaker 2: I had a poster in my Poster in my bedroom for years that said what kind of computer were using for these info comm games?
Speaker 2: Oh Apple 2e.
Speaker 2: I owned a GS.
Speaker 2: I never played.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I played wizardry all the time on my GS wizardry and Dungeon Master and some crappy games.
Speaker 1: If the thief the Apple 2 GS is probably the best computer there ever was.
Speaker 2: that was pretty sweet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's why I have one because I know you know our experience with action castle was you we didn't.
Speaker 0: you were just this weird Guy.
Speaker 0: and Luke still am a weird guy you are but Luke Crane was this other weird guy.
Speaker 0: He's very weird and you know He was that weird guy who tricked us into playing a stupid game.
Speaker 2: and I tricked you and I'm playing my stupid game Cuz we were at PAX.
Speaker 0: we did.
Speaker 0: you know that beyond Dungeons and Dragons like you guys should play.
Speaker 2: That's right.
Speaker 2: Cuz cuz we did the.
Speaker 2: we got together.
Speaker 2: We were.
Speaker 2: everybody was like kind of milling around looking for something to do after we were stupid.
Speaker 0: We were like so and if anyone wants to play this game, that's the guy who made it.
Speaker 0: follow us out We'll find a table.
Speaker 1: It was like Jared's gonna do the thing and I'm like what thing Cuz.
Speaker 0: we formed an angry mob of like 200 people who were like we want to play this We want to play burning meal.
Speaker 1: it's like already think but that was.
Speaker 1: I was oh wait, I think.
Speaker 1: yeah I think that was.
Speaker 0: that was our first temper of oh wait.
Speaker 1: So that's it's been like three four years.
Speaker 0: That was our first packs panel.
Speaker 0: That was one of the first like fan panels ever at a packs.
Speaker 0: That was it was fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's some like crappy video of that panel.
Speaker 0: we ran.
Speaker 0: I forgot how tiny those rooms used to be at packs for panels.
Speaker 1: I think they said what did they use that room for now?
Speaker 1: I think that's now like the mag mag fest stage, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, Scott came over to me.
Speaker 0: He's like, yeah that the guy with the hair is gonna do some thing to get the crowd from killing us 30 Something people just kind of lined up going what is going on?
Speaker 0: Yep, and then by the end like it became this legend of packs I got recognized in Grand Central Station leaving a Depeche Mode show.
Speaker 2: These two kids who are at the anime con kinetic on They recognized me they were at that con and they recognized me in Grand Central and as I walked by I heard Hey, that's is that the action castle guy.
Speaker 2: And then I turned around.
Speaker 2: and then they do the torch hands and they go action castle and I was just like, oh my god Isn't that great?
Speaker 0: Like cuz we're you know, we're all like D level internet celebrities like D List like C list is perhaps even F list Like the bottom of Wil Wheaton's fandom, like we're.
Speaker 0: so like we're a level under if not more.
Speaker 0: Isn't it really fun when someone recognizes you in like New York like you feel like a big man for a few minutes?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do but I'm like that.
Speaker 0: Okay, really not at all.
Speaker 2: It's just kind of.
Speaker 2: it's what it makes me think of cuz.
Speaker 2: I think I've made some.
Speaker 2: I haven't made a lot of Well known games, but you know, I've made some kind of cool ones some I'm really proud of and and it's like like John Gielgud going.
Speaker 2: I you know, I was in other movies - Besides that Star Wars crap, you know on my tombstone.
Speaker 2: It's gonna be like action castle guy Say I'm not dead yet Let's talk about.
Speaker 0: if all the games you've made that you can talk about what's your what's your favorite one?
Speaker 0: Like what's the one that you're the most proud of?
Speaker 0: not maybe the most popular successful the one that you're proud?
Speaker 2: It's definitely not the most popular.
Speaker 2: Successful.
Speaker 2: a free market.
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I really like free mark.
Speaker 0: I really like free market - The only problem I have with it is that most people only ever experience it as a one-off at a con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I feel like advancing the characters is 80% of what I love about that game.
Speaker 2: It's it's awesome.
Speaker 2: The character advancement system is awesome.
Speaker 0: What.
Speaker 0: so what do we do to get people to have that experience?
Speaker 0: because no one gets that at cons.
Speaker 0: I think that's the only reason free market isn't like.
Speaker 0: maybe you could do.
Speaker 0: maybe you could just do like instead of playing for the cam Make a cam of free market like an official place where you can log your characters.
Speaker 1: No I'm saying is we should do?
Speaker 1: is instead of playing for four hours, right?
Speaker 1: We should do.
Speaker 1: is you make the characters in one hour and then end the session every hour so that you get to Experience points on the yeah, I think if I ever do free market demos I'll split the session into two parts so people can see how the you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm thinking about doing that because the reason I want to do that is because something I learned Running free market at burning apocalypse con is that when the players actually know how it works, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz I play the game I played in.
Speaker 1: we actually knew how to how to work it, right?
Speaker 1: And we basically said it's one session burn everything, right?
Speaker 1: All right, we just set all our shit on fire and dominated And the first thing we did in the game was make level 3 tech for everybody.
Speaker 1: So we're like, all right, everyone set it on fire for the rest of the yeah.
Speaker 2: I think that that was what if that was a bullshit rule, by the way, right?
Speaker 1: We should have only had one.
Speaker 2: you should have one two at the most tied right or three level ones.
Speaker 1: but the point is is that we You know, we could have just done the challenge four times.
Speaker 1: It would have been the same thing, right?
Speaker 1: But we you know when you're not gonna go into the next session, you don't care about destroying your stuff, right?
Speaker 1: So you can easily.
Speaker 1: you can easily win if you just get rid of all your items.
Speaker 2: Okay, well the answer to that is just if I was the I haven't done this yet Cuz it'd be a real dick thing to do.
Speaker 2: but just have the the NPC super super user User characters.
Speaker 2: what the hell are they called?
Speaker 2: I don't know.
Speaker 2: Yeah, but the you know, the super user control characters have them burn out stuff Like.
Speaker 2: I have tons of tech that's not even written down.
Speaker 2: I'm just gonna burn it.
Speaker 1: That's one thing that I always have trouble with.
Speaker 1: is like when you're the super user, right?
Speaker 1: It's like how you know, what can I act?
Speaker 1: do I have gene line?
Speaker 1: I'm the super.
Speaker 2: you do have gene line.
Speaker 1: sometimes you do it.
Speaker 1: Sometimes it's a specific like if you're doing a certain kind of challenge, right you have two and two.
Speaker 2: Yeah Here's what you have access to against yourself.
Speaker 1: You're used to use the other guy's character sheet, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, it's thin slicing It's against yourself.
Speaker 1: I'll just use whatever's on your sheet.
Speaker 1: You got gene line.
Speaker 1: I have it too, but sometimes it's like What do I have?
Speaker 2: Well, there's there's.
Speaker 2: I mean you do the little card drawing thing to it to generate the NPC.
Speaker 2: So sometimes you have tech and you know, you can burn it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got it.
Speaker 1: I always keep forgetting to do that.
Speaker 1: Do the card drawing.
Speaker 2: the whole printing thing though when you were printing was a bowling ball.
Speaker 2: Yeah, because I overheard your game cheating.
Speaker 2: So the idea with printing is we kind of looked at rapid prototyping right now and just said Future.
Speaker 2: so it's not like I print a billion marbles.
Speaker 2: It's you print one perfect marble because it's.
Speaker 2: it's not made to produce mass-produced stuff.
Speaker 2: It's made to rapidly produce one thing cultivation is what you'd want if you want a million marbles.
Speaker 2: because you just set up like a little face a factory and But you couldn't print a factory you'd have to print.
Speaker 2: you could print a factory that would help you print.
Speaker 2: cultivate marbles.
Speaker 1: Okay, I got you.
Speaker 2: you print one factory.
Speaker 2: People are always like oh, why don't you just make another space station?
Speaker 2: I'm like you got.
Speaker 2: you can't print the space where the matter come from.
Speaker 1: The matter is not a problem.
Speaker 2: It's just the the space like where you're gonna store these giant girders.
Speaker 2: The problem is you'd have to do it like piece by piece by piece.
Speaker 2: It would take away.
Speaker 2: you could totally do it you could.
Speaker 2: it's like the the with the maker bot reproducing itself.
Speaker 2: It doesn't reproduce a maker about it reproduces all the parts.
Speaker 1: And what about see the problem?
Speaker 1: I've always thought of is, you know, it's like well, why don't you go out into space?
Speaker 1: I'm like if you got into space you can't get back in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you left.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So it's like, okay, we're gonna build a space station outside.
Speaker 1: Okay Well, the first guy brings a girder out and he won't get back in to print the second.
Speaker 2: You'd have drones.
Speaker 0: Well, that can be a goal.
Speaker 2: I mean, yeah, you could totally do that in the game.
Speaker 0: Like it's just it sets up the end game really well Cuz the first.
Speaker 1: every time I would just laugh because the players wouldn't think of the drones like you did and someone would go outside of the space station.
Speaker 1: I'd be like.
Speaker 0: the first thing the characters always ask like when I'm talking about the game is could I fucking blow up the space?
Speaker 2: When we were developing this game one of one of the the guys because we worked with Hidden City To develop free market originally and one of the guys who worked there was like well What's to prevent me from making like a rapist murder sociopath?
Speaker 2: And I said do you want to play him rapist murder sociopath?
Speaker 2: and he's like, no I said well That's what's stopping you your own desire.
Speaker 2: But somebody could.
Speaker 2: I'm like, yeah somebody could.
Speaker 2: so far.
Speaker 2: Nobody has.
Speaker 2: we've had some weird characters.
Speaker 2: We've had some characters who were definitely not social.
Speaker 1: Was the closest you've come to?
Speaker 1: rape is?
Speaker 1: Closest the closest that you've seen.
Speaker 2: the closest game was the group.
Speaker 2: That was essentially.
Speaker 2: They were a cult.
Speaker 2: that were cannibals.
Speaker 2: they had a religious cult that that dealt with eating people.
Speaker 1: That's close to what we had.
Speaker 2: and they got a ballerina to cut off her feet and eat them.
Speaker 2: Whoa, that was a pretty dark game.
Speaker 1: That was okay.
Speaker 1: So we did see we did.
Speaker 0: is why is it always food like the majority of persons I've ever seen our food?
Speaker 2: Well, I the thing that people need I have in the.
Speaker 1: when we played at the first burning con they did.
Speaker 1: it was similar.
Speaker 1: It was cannibalism, but it was like gourmet cannibalism.
Speaker 1: eating yourself is so cool.
Speaker 1: It's transgressive.
Speaker 2: It's one you can do it because there's no laws against it, too.
Speaker 2: It's it's you're physically capable of doing it because you can regrow parts or grow parts.
Speaker 1: We're doing a cooking show and they got this girl like cutter you know hands off into the pot so they can cook it and serve it up to everyone and then the Aggregates are repairing your hand.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like it's Sure.
Speaker 2: I mean if you lived in the society, you could have a cannibal gourmet cookery show Sure, and some people are like hey since you can't do that now and there's no way to do that in other role-playing games Let's do that, which is perfectly understandable.
Speaker 2: when I play D&D I want to kill orcs and dragons because I rarely get a chance to do that in real life Because you know, I live in the city.
Speaker 0: I feel like this gives free markets and dragons in the city They're just underground Gators and the rats but it gives free market an opportunity to.
Speaker 0: I think just not disturb but like unnerve people when they like they play and I think every player can kind of get to this moment or They kind of realize that Social strictures maybe don't make sense or that maybe there is no absolute morality And I think it can put people into an interesting state of mind.
Speaker 2: I played one game where they met The the game it it got.
Speaker 2: it was kind of comical and there was bees in an opera house and it was really light-hearted.
Speaker 2: And then it got real dark real quick and it involved This woman's grandfather contacting her from the hole which is the the hub the center of the donut.
Speaker 2: I'm the center of the space station saying I'm here pick me up.
Speaker 2: And she's like Mike again and her grandfather was.
Speaker 2: her grandfather was dead.
Speaker 2: She had a memory of her father from her grandfather from Earth and she's like, where's my grandfather doing?
Speaker 2: He's dead He what.
Speaker 2: so she goes there and he's there waiting for And she's like.
Speaker 2: and he says you're my granddaughter, right and she's like, I'm really confused.
Speaker 2: what's going on?
Speaker 2: It turns out that some hacker on the space station was just messing with people.
Speaker 2: He's a switcher and he was a hacker and he made this blank.
Speaker 2: He got genetic material was able to reproduce.
Speaker 2: her grandfather gave him some false memories and let him loose.
Speaker 2: and she's like Why did you do that?
Speaker 2: He's like, I wanted to see what he'd do and I wanted to see what you do.
Speaker 2: And she's like, well, what is he gonna do now?
Speaker 2: And he says that's not up to me.
Speaker 2: He's a person.
Speaker 2: Yeah, he has his own free will and she's looking at him like Like those two things like you built this person to play a prank on me but I'm not responsible for him because he's his own person.
Speaker 2: like There's a moment in the game Which we don't specifically talk about but if you if you kind of put the pieces together It's clear that blanks are technology.
Speaker 2: up to a certain point blanks for those people don't know are essentially.
Speaker 2: they're like replicants.
Speaker 2: They're created humans.
Speaker 2: They're they're.
Speaker 2: they're printed.
Speaker 2: They're not actually born or or grown they're they're just output on a matter printer using cells instead of you know, carbon or metal or plastic.
Speaker 2: and at a certain point They go from being tech to being a user on the space station and we never say what?
Speaker 2: You need to do to actually create a blank?
Speaker 1: I always thought it was just a printing challenge.
Speaker 1: It's a blank.
Speaker 1: It's a really.
Speaker 2: There's three parts of it.
Speaker 2: there's First you have to print the body right or cultivate the body.
Speaker 2: I guess gross gross.
Speaker 2: You need data.
Speaker 2: you need nine points of data, I think you can steal.
Speaker 1: you can donate memories, right the people, right?
Speaker 2: You have to fill it full of memories.
Speaker 2: You I have to fill it full and enough memory so I can upgrade those into skills so that it's not just the needs at Least an experience.
Speaker 2: It needs a couple experience at least and it needs interface.
Speaker 2: it needs a key to be recognized by the So that's that's a mob challenge and I was like, oh wait it needs one needs a mobbing challenge.
Speaker 2: Yeah, so we never we kind of gloss over because we just want to see what people do because we're not we're not sure.
Speaker 2: but yeah, there's that uncomfortable moment when somebody realizes one that My favorite one of my favorite reviews of the game was this game's broken because you should just play a blank because they have three Gene line, it's the only thing you can't improve.
Speaker 2: Why would you take anything else?
Speaker 2: I'm like Yeah, why would you play anything else than a blank?
Speaker 2: like eventually Wouldn't everybody on the space station be a blank?
Speaker 2: because eventually people would just I mean if they're the superior being That we created wouldn't they surpass us?
Speaker 0: Isn't that kind of welcome to the plot of the majority of anime that we like?
Speaker 1: Points you get your gene line, which you can't increase.
Speaker 1: experience which you can write Technology, which you can.
Speaker 1: and what's the other one?
Speaker 2: interface?
Speaker 2: Yeah Gene line.
Speaker 2: if you have a gene line three, you can't level up You can't you can't ever improve that.
Speaker 1: thought about it.
Speaker 2: And if your gene line - you can't ever increase the three you can you can decrease down to one but wouldn't like You know.
Speaker 1: third fourth gen, you know non Blanks have No quids came around.
Speaker 2: quids are quids which are the kids the children of the second gen the little crazy little geniuses.
Speaker 2: They're gene line - oh, they're human.
Speaker 1: They've been right, but it waited long enough like six sevens.
Speaker 2: maybe they would know because you because the ideas of blank is a perfect gene line because you've Designed it specific for.
Speaker 1: so they're not, you know, so there's not you know, really genetically engineering the the natural babies There is.
Speaker 2: that's why they have a - not a one.
Speaker 2: immigrants and first-gen have a one, right?
Speaker 2: Because they're alive.
Speaker 1: about your games like actually becoming serious.
Speaker 1: I have a really hard time.
Speaker 1: every game I play in or run always ends up silly in some way It's very silly world.
Speaker 2: It's a crazy.
Speaker 2: I mean if you lived in that world, it would be silly but it would also kind of be horrifying.
Speaker 2: It was also.
Speaker 2: it would also be kind of amazing.
Speaker 1: I can't seem to bring out the horror.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's my fault.
Speaker 2: probably I think it eventually will come when when people realize what's at stake You also haven't run a campaign.
Speaker 0: That's true a game over maybe.
Speaker 1: maybe if as you get more sessions the heart You know would be easier to get away from the silliness.
Speaker 0: Maybe when the players start to get to the point where they can do big things big things have big consequences.
Speaker 0: Yeah, big consequences lead to big Revelations.
Speaker 1: Oh, can I have another pad of character sheets?
Speaker 1: I'm I'm out.
Speaker 2: I am all out - I Wish I want extra cards.
Speaker 1: I'm like, you know, I'll trade you a deck of cards.
Speaker 2: No, I don't have any more characters.
Speaker 0: She said just a poor guy to kind of arguing with Luke.
Speaker 0: He was like, what if there's no more like?
Speaker 0: what if I lose my deck?
Speaker 0: and like you're both dead and there's no more free Market, like this is a pretty sight.
Speaker 1: and print him out.
Speaker 2: This is a pre scarcity game.
Speaker 2: Yeah about post scarcity economy.
Speaker 2: print one out or pre post scarcity.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about some of your other games since you want to you know, like, you know lacuna all this old stuff.
Speaker 0: Does anyone play lacuna?
Speaker 0: I mean we play a bunch of times.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I get lots of actual play reports and people.
Speaker 2: I still.
Speaker 2: I just sent one off in the mail yesterday to somebody in England.
Speaker 0: All right, nice Because as an aside someone gave me a copy of lacuna to get you to sign Three packs as ago and I said I've turned and said, okay How should I give it back to you?
Speaker 0: and the person already like ran away and I never found them.
Speaker 2: Remember that I signed it though, right?
Speaker 1: I've still got it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're that guy and you're listening.
Speaker 1: or if you're just someone who wants to get a free copy.
Speaker 1: lacuna If you if you are that side free sign copy.
Speaker 0: I remember enough about you to figure out if it's you or not.
Speaker 1: So I think it was a guy from a podcast maybe or something.
Speaker 2: It was either a guy or a girl.
Speaker 2: Narrows it down.
Speaker 0: At least it wasn't one of those genderless pygmies from the burning wheel game.
Speaker 1: I ran it to BAC hmm, so so let's talk about like just you know, what are you doing lately?
Speaker 1: playing any games or Listen any music's watching movies.
Speaker 1: What's cool for you right now for me?
Speaker 2: I'm spending a lot of time working on Z Ward and I have a lacuna - It's for real I've been working.
Speaker 1: return of the spider-man what's?
Speaker 2: no it's.
Speaker 2: it's actually a sort.
Speaker 2: it's a not a standalone game it's a source book and it's um, the idea is it's a collection of People places and things in blue city.
Speaker 2: So it's kind of like a little travelogue of blue city.
Speaker 2: But it's specifically because I didn't want to just do Because blue city the whole idea of it is you don't know what's in it.
Speaker 1: There's no set.
Speaker 2: So I was like, well, it's gonna be lame to do a source book.
Speaker 2: So I need to do something interesting with it.
Speaker 2: So what I did is I did 26 Originally 26 locations and they're all tramps the tram stops of the the train.
Speaker 2: so each and they're all you know the ones that are from the game like boxer and diamond and abattoir and cafe and all the stuff from the original game book and then a whole bunch of new ones and Each is like a page of information about stuff going on in that area.
Speaker 2: and The idea is there's a corresponding map tile that will go with each tram stop and during the game.
Speaker 2: What you'll do is you start with cafe station because that's most of the time that's where you.
Speaker 2: you enter the world on when you dive into blue city and Then when you want to take the tram or go to another area the the GM will just grab another tile at random Put it face face up and say that's all I get to.
Speaker 0: you know, whatever station.
Speaker 0: Well, you don't know how long that's gonna take you.
Speaker 1: It's a little bit like those Like the newer D&D dungeon crawlies like the Raven loft.
Speaker 1: you flip the tile to make the next room.
Speaker 2: Yeah, as opposed to having a map that's or definitely inspired by stuff like that I played a lot of Raven loft and you know a shard along.
Speaker 1: I played the Raven loft once I was like It's not my style.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not into those games.
Speaker 0: So I want to make a game that's like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we talked about this with Luke.
Speaker 0: So yes.
Speaker 2: Yes.
Speaker 2: I'm aware of this.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I Hear about this all the time.
Speaker 2: But yeah, so I don't want to you know kickstart that I also want to put in a lot of um There's a lot of Easter eggs about because you know You need to explain a little bit what the hell's go actually going on in blue city because I know.
Speaker 2: So I figured I might share a little bit of that.
Speaker 2: So there's little you can't.
Speaker 0: you can't figure out the mystery Just you know from the book, but it definitely gives you some interesting Like the idea of no one knowing but you because everyone I play a game with They always came up with what the mystery really is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's always very similar.
Speaker 0: But then like every twist is different.
Speaker 2: Everybody thinks they're right.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's the one thing about one of the like mystery agents like the higher-up ones, right?
Speaker 1: Like there's the list of them in the book like the break agents and it's like you sort of see him in the background Of the double static right minor agent.
Speaker 1: my eyes, you know that Sun up with him.
Speaker 2: Nobody asked nobody actually no one person asked me.
Speaker 2: So where is agent minor?
Speaker 2: And I said, what do you mean?
Speaker 2: He's like, well, they said he's a wall, but where's his body?
Speaker 1: Right, and I'm like, you're the first person asked me sort of the obvious twist which is like the mystery agents used to be the Criminals and they got cleaned.
Speaker 1: now that the mystery that is never said in the book I know it's not said in the but every day master does that.
Speaker 1: I know if you've read if you actually look read the book Slowly and carefully you had to be a moron not to at least come to that conclusion.
Speaker 1: whether it's true or not, you know You could come to that.
Speaker 0: conclude like the face Jared is making Scott while he's saying all this.
Speaker 1: But you know, but other than that, it's like there is still plenty of mystery like this.
Speaker 1: spider-man.
Speaker 1: What the fuck are they?
Speaker 1: they they're the guys who come at you late in the game when your statics too high.
Speaker 1: What else what else are they?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: They're spider-man.
Speaker 1: They're scary.
Speaker 1: They're on the cover of the book.
Speaker 1: They must be important.
Speaker 0: I just get more interested.
Speaker 0: Like what is static like?
Speaker 0: they're trying to figure out what that means.
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: Could be ghost in the Shelly.
Speaker 1: It's a number that tells you how close the spider-man again.
Speaker 2: Well static static was always in the game But it only had a stat and an actual purpose in the game.
Speaker 2: on the the second attempt and the first attempt It was just like okay be mean to the players and fuck with them and confuse them.
Speaker 2: and now it's like, okay Be nice to the players until this number starts to go up and then slowly.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that's the magic which I like.
Speaker 1: that game works.
Speaker 1: So well is.
Speaker 1: not only do you have that but it's it controls the pacing, right?
Speaker 1: so if you well the heart rate and static both control pacing, so if you Even if the GM knows nothing about good pacing the game the numbers are just right.
Speaker 1: good pacing can't not happen unless you cheat.
Speaker 0: Well, look at.
Speaker 0: look at all the like RPGs We like.
Speaker 0: like burning wheel mouse guard.
Speaker 0: These games are all designed to control Who gets control of the scene and when and like in burning wheel people push for things like they want a challenging test to advance or they want a routine test and that pushes the story toward these ebbs and flows.
Speaker 0: and Mouse guard is the system of checks like earning checks.
Speaker 0: right fucking myself, right?
Speaker 2: Now is the point in the game where things get really complicated because I want two checks instead of one.
Speaker 2: So I'm gonna you know break the tie-in.
Speaker 0: I've never seen a mouse guard game where a player uses a check against them and the entire rest of the table doesn't go.
Speaker 2: no Yeah, well you don't need those two dice.
Speaker 2: They're probably gonna roll ones anyway.
Speaker 2: So so yeah lacuna part two.
Speaker 2: I'm not sure when that's gonna come out 2012.
Speaker 2: I guess I've been busy with Z Ward.
Speaker 2: I'm gonna kickstart it and one of the things I'm gonna do with the book It's gonna be a book a PDF and I want to do tiles.
Speaker 2: I want to do cool map tiles.
Speaker 1: I want your tiles.
Speaker 2: I want to do really nice one.
Speaker 2: So, you know as it I haven't worked at the details But the the deal is you know PDF downloads that you can print out yourself at the low levels and at the high levels.
Speaker 2: if I raise enough money I'll do really sweet, you know, I'd like to do like, you know Small world style cards chipboard with the linen cover stuff.
Speaker 2: nice Yeah, small world by the way, one of my favorite games small world's good.
Speaker 1: Have you played the underground?
Speaker 2: I haven't.
Speaker 1: I want not either.
Speaker 0: Have you played the original Vinci?
Speaker 0: No, because Vinci is kind of an abstracted version.
Speaker 0: That's really fun.
Speaker 0: But the fundamental difference is that there's no restrictions on what can combine with what.
Speaker 0: it's just two things.
Speaker 0: So you can have like crazy weird powers that don't sometimes cheat.
Speaker 2: well small world you don't.
Speaker 2: there's no restrictions.
Speaker 1: there is in small world for example, there's race and ability in Vinci, oh you can have like.
Speaker 0: it's just a bag of Regeneration or like, you know medicine and barbarian.
Speaker 2: Okay, so to be like in small world if you grab orcs in spirits There's no number of turns there's a number of victory points.
Speaker 0: Okay, anyone goes over that the game ends at the end of that turn.
Speaker 0: So you see this weird like posturing.
Speaker 1: You know in small world, it's like, you know, it's gonna end.
Speaker 1: So that means I know I should decline on this turn because you know I want to decline two turns before the end of the game.
Speaker 1: So I come back into the board the sec the turn before the last time unless you have whereas in Vinci I decline when I think we're three turns away from the end and somebody else Purposefully delays to bring in an extra turn.
Speaker 1: and now I have one low scoring turn in for them.
Speaker 1: It's a high scoring turn.
Speaker 2: So Vinci is the small world as like pandemic is to.
Speaker 1: They're made by the same guy and basically Vinci.
Speaker 1: not only does it have some problems with it But it had a lot of misprints and the production quality was low.
Speaker 1: He really wanted to redo it.
Speaker 1: He put the small world theme on it, which made it sell small world.
Speaker 2: I mean it's the game itself is beautiful.
Speaker 1: She's just colored in little googly tiles.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just I like the skeletons a lot.
Speaker 2: skeleton Hi, I just it's.
Speaker 0: I like how the the fish men have like basically a fish bone.
Speaker 2: Yeah The icons are great like everything about the game is like the troll troll layers.
Speaker 1: Those are some my favorite.
Speaker 2: Yeah, the pieces are all real.
Speaker 2: I like the fact that even the mountains even though I'm like when I first started playing them Like why are there mountain pieces at?
Speaker 2: the mountains are on the board?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and at first I thought oh It's because that way everything is tokenized but forests aren't.
Speaker 0: and that pissed me off for like an hour Mmm, like I was trying to figure out why and I couldn't and it really bothered me.
Speaker 2: Well, it's because the mountains are Tokens.
Speaker 2: they count as a you know, but forests count as defense.
Speaker 2: They don't Know.
Speaker 0: oh they did in Vinci see here.
Speaker 1: Here's the problem.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem.
Speaker 0: We had no Vinci inside and out and this game is very close to it.
Speaker 0: It's like 99% but there are such tiny differences that we never know the answer at any specific question.
Speaker 2: Some of the forests have the like little magic gem for wizards.
Speaker 0: That's actually burning real gold and burning wheel revised.
Speaker 2: I'm having the same problem like oh plus one and then everyone the tables like no I I do that when we do like when we were play testing free market or when I'm play testing.
Speaker 2: You know actually if I'm doing like and parsley game from memory and it hasn't actually come out yet.
Speaker 2: Sometimes I'm like Which which game which version of the game am I running right now?
Speaker 2: All right, so that's what's going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, nice.
Speaker 1: So so wait, but you know, you see you're kick-starting, you know The Z Ward now and you're gonna kick start the lacuna - yep when it's ready like how you know.
Speaker 1: Do you think like the Kickstarter well will dry up like, you know, how often can you kick start?
Speaker 2: I don't want to.
Speaker 2: I want to do one.
Speaker 2: I decided I'm gonna do.
Speaker 1: I would be worried about if I was kick start.
Speaker 2: Yeah, like I. well Kickstarter is awesome for for me right now for my my constraints that I'm dealing with.
Speaker 2: it's really good and it's also really cool because It's I mean, I've done pre-orders on parsley games before and it was like 30 people.
Speaker 2: Yay.
Speaker 2: I got 200 people.
Speaker 2: It's weird.
Speaker 0: There's a culture around Kickstarter.
Speaker 2: there's a culture adds to the momentum exactly and it's also a nice affirmation.
Speaker 2: I'm getting lots of emails from people saying yay.
Speaker 2: I love these games.
Speaker 2: I played this game at PAX or I played this game in you know, Kinetic Con or Gen Con.
Speaker 0: I'll say this, you know, we run the panels department at Kinetic Con workshops all that stuff.
Speaker 0: You guys you and Luke other than us are the most asked about people who come to the con?
Speaker 2: Well, we can't.
Speaker 2: I mean we kill you do?
Speaker 2: I had four.
Speaker 2: I had almost 500 people in my in my room at PAX East For Action Castle, which is just stupid 15 emails ahead of the previous Kinetic Con just asking.
Speaker 0: Hey, will the Action Castle guy be there?
Speaker 0: Hey, will that text adventure?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Hey, will it be there?
Speaker 0: What room is it in?
Speaker 0: Do I have to line up early for it?
Speaker 2: Yes, you do have to.
Speaker 1: Do you wanna go to magfest?
Speaker 2: Yeah, come to magfest pay me I'll go.
Speaker 1: you can crash in our room.
Speaker 1: I'll buy a $20 bolt bus ticket.
Speaker 1: and Where is help floor in your Virginia DC area?
Speaker 2: When is it?
Speaker 1: Yeah the week after New Year's the New Year's.
Speaker 1: next I'll probably do that.
Speaker 0: It's a four-day con.
Speaker 2: I could rock it.
Speaker 0: It's music.
Speaker 1: It's 24/7.
Speaker 2: You guys have been pimping this for a while.
Speaker 2: I'm interested.
Speaker 2: I totally.
Speaker 0: it's way fun.
Speaker 0: I can't speak for getting you on panels or anything slowly for that, but there's a gaming intellectuals.
Speaker 0: We're part of the mag 9 like 9 gaming 9.
Speaker 1: maybe the mags.
Speaker 1: first of all, it's the 10th mag.
Speaker 0: Well one you and I together count as one person, right?
Speaker 1: So there's also.
Speaker 1: it's the 10th mag fest.
Speaker 1: So it would it be the mag 10 now?
Speaker 1: It was not.
Speaker 1: is it even 10 people anymore?
Speaker 0: I think it's like 11 people there's gonna be.
Speaker 0: we just got the list of it.
Speaker 0: We're on to where I don't know if I'm allowed to say anything whatever.
Speaker 0: We're on to discussion.
Speaker 1: temp.
Speaker 1: We're tentatively on to.
Speaker 1: there you go.
Speaker 0: Well, we're definitely on to.
Speaker 0: I'm still.
Speaker 0: no I would totally do it if I could get on panels and I'm saying I don't know if I can swing.
Speaker 2: Could if you could I'm just saying Let's table this and take it offline.
Speaker 0: We can introduce you to the person who runs the stuff and he will probably want you to do stuff.
Speaker 0: and I'm sure Because it's a really open con like we were running like just burning wheel and mouse guard and like danger patrol games for people Just randomly the whole con.
Speaker 0: you could just walk into an open area start doing action castle.
Speaker 0: You'd have a crowd of like a hundred within I know and no one would care.
Speaker 1: It's not like packs of the enforcers to be like, excuse me Can you move?
Speaker 2: or origins where they just don't let you do it, right?
Speaker 0: It people just be like whatever I mean, there's guys just like jamming on electric guitars like outside the hotel and no one cares.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: maybe this hotel will be more stuffy than the last one.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: also Better not fucking happen.
Speaker 1: Oh my god Is our friend coming back?
Speaker 1: John St.
Speaker 1: John.
Speaker 0: The John St.
Speaker 0: John will be there.
Speaker 1: This is a bigger hotel.
Speaker 1: So maybe he can break his hotel room party record.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: All right, I think we can wrap this up.
Speaker 0: So one last question What is the last movie that you've seen all the way through any movie?
Speaker 0: I'm just curious.
Speaker 0: Uh, that would have been Because I just jeopardy the movie because I just you know The the movie that M Night Shyamalan tried to make about Avatar that then he died that car accident.
Speaker 0: They didn't finish.
Speaker 0: it may have said I'm Netflix streaming and I may have showed Emily why it was so bad.
Speaker 1: And I thought you saw that movie.
Speaker 0: I saw it all the way through the second worst movie I've.
Speaker 1: why did you watch it a second time?
Speaker 0: I didn't watch it.
Speaker 0: I flipped.
Speaker 0: I put two three scenes.
Speaker 0: I showed her Fire.
Speaker 0: Lord Ozo is a chubby, dude.
Speaker 0: It's a bunch of white people living in the Arctic race bender, right who spends 15 minutes explaining backstory without showing you any.
Speaker 0: And what did I show?
Speaker 0: I showed her the scene where Katara runs across the entire wide screen Over the course of like three seconds to girlishly shove a guy nice.
Speaker 0: It's the worst scene at any movie I've ever seen.
Speaker 2: I saw a Halloween night.
Speaker 2: I saw a phantasm the original Which if you haven't seen it, it's very weird Scott's not up on a lot of the like those kinds of movies.
Speaker 1: I'm going through the IMDb top 250.
Speaker 1: I just watched Rebecca.
Speaker 1: So I'm almost done with page two top 250.
Speaker 0: What's in there?
Speaker 0: a lot is the original house on Haunted Hill and or Vincent Price's.
Speaker 0: is any Vincent Price movie in there?
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen him yet.
Speaker 1: Then I'm on page two.
Speaker 2: Maybe Edward Scissorhands.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's on there.
Speaker 0: really Have to guess it'd be up there.
Speaker 0: It was I like that movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Tim Burton's movies that I do like plus it was When it came out, it was kind of like scared me Edgy and slightly controversial.
Speaker 0: it was kind of like how The Simpsons used to be like our cartoon parents were afraid of right?
Speaker 2: All right.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.