Speaker 1: It's Thursday, May 5th, 2011.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights on the Cinco de Mayo.
Speaker 1: We're gonna talk about Al-Qaeda, Corona, Libya, Osama Bin Laden, all that stuff.
Speaker 0: You know, Speedy Gonzalez.
Speaker 1: That too.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So, you know, we're a big fan of the food trucks.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: every day.
Speaker 1: Well, not every day, but every day the pizza truck is out.
Speaker 0: I've never seen a pizza truck.
Speaker 1: It's in Midtown, like near Bryant Park.
Speaker 0: The thing is there's such a good pizza place near me.
Speaker 0: There's like 20 of them, but they're all touristy except one really good one.
Speaker 1: Ah, I got some really good pizza near me.
Speaker 0: And of course every everything place has pizza also.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that pizza's mediocre.
Speaker 1: It's no Sbarro's.
Speaker 0: But there's actually a quality Italian pizza place right next to the office, don't even have to cross the street.
Speaker 0: So why would I go to a pizza truck?
Speaker 1: Because all the pizza places that are good are good.
Speaker 1: They're fantastic pizza, but they are very specifically either proper Italian pizza or New York style pizza.
Speaker 1: Which are the best kinds of pizza.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: But sometimes I do enjoy the Chicago style, the Boston style.
Speaker 1: I do not.
Speaker 1: And one kind of pizza I really do like is the super thin and crispy Sandella's kind of pizza.
Speaker 0: Alright, flatbread.
Speaker 1: The pizza truck.
Speaker 0: I don't even consider that really a pizza.
Speaker 0: That's more of just a flatbread sandwich.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I'm looking and the truck appears to have that style of pizza.
Speaker 1: And it smells really fucking good.
Speaker 1: There's a gigantic line.
Speaker 1: So all the people who work near me who normally would go to the super awesome Little Italy pizza must be deciding consciously to go to this truck and stand in the longer line instead.
Speaker 0: So you went to Little Italy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I went to Little Italy.
Speaker 0: Ashley, why don't you go to friggin' Two Boots underground central?
Speaker 1: 'Cause that Two Boots is the shittiest Two Boots.
Speaker 0: The shittiest Two Boots is still pretty good.
Speaker 1: The thing is, the pizza seems like by the time they heat it up, one, they never heat it up as hot as it needs to get.
Speaker 1: And the service sucks and the line sucks and I just... Grand Central is not where you want to get lunch.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I always walk back from my lunch and see the pizza truck because I eat at like 11.
Speaker 1: Someday I just have to eat later.
Speaker 1: so I walk out and see the pizza truck and go, "Oh,
Speaker 1: right."
Speaker 1: And get a pizza.
Speaker 0: No, see, that's what I thought.
Speaker 0: There's a falafel truck that's been coming near me recently.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of falafel over there, actually.
Speaker 0: But there's one falafel truck in particular, the Taim falafel and smoothie truck, T-A-I-M.
Speaker 1: Nah, the falafel near me kinda sucks.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: That truck, every day I see it, it's only there like once or twice a week.
Speaker 0: It has a crazy long line down the street.
Speaker 0: So one day I went over there at like 2.30.
Speaker 0: 'Cause it usually parks next to Europa Cafe, so I'm like, "Well, you know what?
Speaker 0: If there's a long line, I'll go to Europa
Speaker 0: Cafe.".
Speaker 0: 2.30 PM, I look and at the line, I don't see the line, so I'm like, "Oh boy, oh boy, oh
Speaker 0: boy.".
Speaker 0: And I go to the other side of the truck.
Speaker 0: The line was entirely hidden behind the truck.
Speaker 0: It was gigantic.
Speaker 0: At 2.30 PM, there was a line for this falafel.
Speaker 0: But anyway, a couple days ago, you know what I got?
Speaker 1: What'd you get?
Speaker 0: Crepe truck.
Speaker 1: Ah, you mean crepe.
Speaker 0: Crepe, savory crepe.
Speaker 1: Ah, shit, son.
Speaker 0: They also had the sweet, but I got the savory 'cause it was lunchtime.
Speaker 1: That's kinda crepe.
Speaker 1: It's something with like feta, some spinach.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they had that kinda thing.
Speaker 0: Maybe asparagus.
Speaker 1: Asparagus, some egg.
Speaker 0: But I got like chicken with some kind of cheese, I don't know what it was, and all kinds of vegetable of some kind.
Speaker 0: It was good.
Speaker 1: Ah.
Speaker 1: But, you know, I've been riding my bike to work and the thing is, my building, which is the former Lincoln building, now one Grand Central place, those fuckers made sure the service elevator is basically impossible to use, so they are technically-.
Speaker 0: Well, what are the hours of the service elevator?
Speaker 1: Ah, it opens after I get to work and closes before I leave.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's 'cause you work weird hours.
Speaker 1: No, basically almost no one could work the hours.
Speaker 0: But independent of that- My, 'cause mine is eight to six.
Speaker 1: Even then, if you wanna use it, these union asses take forever, they don't open it on time every day, you gotta wait for the guy to come down, open the elevator, let you in, you gotta like call-.
Speaker 0: That's what I do too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it takes like ten minutes on each end of my journey.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: It only takes me like a couple minutes on each end.
Speaker 1: And even then, because the hours suck, I can't use it anyway, so I'm not riding my many thousand dollar performance hybrid to work.
Speaker 0: Your bike is not many thousand.
Speaker 1: I spent a couple thousand.
Speaker 0: That was too much for that bike.
Speaker 1: That bike is way better than your bike.
Speaker 0: That bike is not worth many thousand, there are better bikes that you can get than that for like one thousand.
Speaker 1: I mean, I got it on sale, I only paid like twenty one hundred, I think I forget.
Speaker 0: That's way too much money.
Speaker 1: Ah, nah, not really.
Speaker 1: Nah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay, mister gigantic gears in the back.
Speaker 0: Even the retail price of bikes on the official website is not that much for that bike.
Speaker 1: It's a good bike, I don't think you should ride my bike sometime and see.
Speaker 0: Well, let's go to the, what exactly model is your bike?
Speaker 1: I don't remember it, I have to go look it up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think you maybe had got the rip rip off, if you know what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Actually, I got that for about eight hundred, nine hundred dollars under MSRP, as I recall.
Speaker 0: Uh huh.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I doubt it.
Speaker 1: I had a smartphone when I was at the store.
Speaker 0: Your bike does not look like a two thousand dollar bike to me.
Speaker 1: Scott, it's completely different from your bike.
Speaker 0: Uh huh, anyway.
Speaker 1: Alright, so what do you think isn't different?
Speaker 1: I mean, the gearing is different, brakes are different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can get a bike with those gears and those brakes for like a couple hundred dollars more than my bike.
Speaker 0: No, no you're not gonna.
Speaker 0: For multi thousand dollars, you can get a bike better than Lance Armstrong's bike.
Speaker 1: Uh, probably not actually.
Speaker 0: Actually, yes, Lance Armstrong's bike is between one and two thousand dollars on Trek.com.
Speaker 1: So a street bike, which is completely different from a hybrid.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying that you, there's no way you paid that much money, you paid too much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's have a bike race and we'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: We will.
Speaker 1: So I've been riding my fifteen, sixteen, almost seventeen year old mountain bike to work every day.
Speaker 0: Because who cares what happens to it.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, I can't risk my bike getting stolen, New York City has the highest rate of bike theft of any city in America.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but what if your bike gets stolen, you just steal a different one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I haven't seen bikes as nice as mine out there and my bike is such a target.
Speaker 1: So I'm driving that shitty old Schwinn, I took all the tape off of it from the guy who stole it before.
Speaker 1: And the difference between the two bikes, now that I'm riding both of them on a regular basis, and I'm riding the mountain bike a long distance, you know, three miles or so, after having had a real bike and ridden it.
Speaker 1: Jesus Christ, it takes me almost twice as long to get to work on the mountain bike as it does on my real bike.
Speaker 1: Literally twice as long.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I feel like I'm training on this shitty ass bike.
Speaker 1: When I take my awesome bike out on the weekends, it's gonna be like just butter.
Speaker 0: Uh huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway?
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 1: You said you had some sort of crazy opening bit, you had something to say.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: No, I just wanted to talk about the Crips.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's all you had?
Speaker 1: Because right before we did the show, Scott's like, "No, wait, wait, wait, I got a really good thing to start
Speaker 1: with.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, because you were talking about food trucks, I said I had a pre-opening bit and I wanted to talk about the Crip.
Speaker 1: That was it?
Speaker 1: The Crip?
Speaker 0: Yeah, Crip truck.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 1: Nothing beats the Potend truck down on St.
Speaker 1: Marks.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There's none of that near me.
Speaker 1: I should just bike down there and get it.
Speaker 0: You could.
Speaker 1: Because my other big revelation was, I have a bike at work, I can just go biking for like an hour instead of getting lunch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I have been.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: I almost went over the Williamsburg Bridge, but I might not have made it back in time.
Speaker 1: So I just went to the base.
Speaker 0: You definitely would not have made it back in time.
Speaker 1: Well, I got to the base of the Williamsburg Bridge and then I sat and had lunch and then I biked back.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, Thursday.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Got something to talk about?
Speaker 0: Any news?
Speaker 0: I do have a news.
Speaker 1: Oh, do ya?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Doesn't have to be news.
Speaker 1: Remember, we used to call this the lounge.
Speaker 1: Talk about whatever we want.
Speaker 0: You were the only one who ever did that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because you always complained, "I never have any news on Thursday because I don't care about normal
Speaker 1: stuff.".
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I don't care about nerdery.
Speaker 0: It's geek nights.
Speaker 0: It's not normal nights.
Speaker 0: If people wanted normal nights, they could go to the rest of the internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because there's nothing nerdy about sports or politics.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So check this out, right?
Speaker 0: There's some people in Turkey who are doing a big scam, right?
Speaker 0: And this is actually sort of a genius scam.
Speaker 1: Oh, is this the street gang with the tranquilizer pills?
Speaker 0: What they did is they would go to someone's house and they would pretend to be doctors.
Speaker 0: They guess they would wear lab coats.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: Dr.
Speaker 1: Mario is not a real doctor.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: And they would go and they would tell the people they were testing a new drug and they were going door to door pretending they were doing clinical trials.
Speaker 0: Clinical trials are not done door to door, but I guess people don't know that.
Speaker 1: There's a relevant line from Archer, which you don't watch, but the line is, "You weren't suspicious at all that your chemotherapy drugs were
Speaker 1: chewable.".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So they basically would go to someone's door, pretend to be doctors doing a clinical trial, make people, I guess, sign a paper or something and then give them a pill and suggest that they should take it immediately.
Speaker 0: And people took it and it was a tranquilizer.
Speaker 0: So they went to sleep and then the people robbed their house while they were tranquilized and left.
Speaker 1: Now, I cannot disparage the Pakistani or the Turkey because there's this study.
Speaker 1: I've seen articles about similar things in the past.
Speaker 1: This type of robbery is not a new thing.
Speaker 1: The police response to it is a new thing.
Speaker 0: So what the police did is they went around to people's houses pretending to be doctors.
Speaker 0: Basically, the police did exactly what the criminals did, only instead of using actual tranquilizers and robbing the people, they gave them placebos.
Speaker 0: And after, 86 out of 100 people took it.
Speaker 1: I imagine the cops being like, "Dude, that could have been poison.
Speaker 1: What the fuck's wrong with you?
Speaker 1: I'm not a
Speaker 1: doctor.".
Speaker 0: That's exactly what the police did.
Speaker 0: It says, "Police later returned to warn residents to be more
Speaker 0: cautious.".
Speaker 1: I cannot disparage the good citizens of Turkey, though, for being stupid because this shit would probably work almost as well in America.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not picking on the country.
Speaker 0: That just happens to be the country where it happened.
Speaker 0: I'm picking on all people.
Speaker 0: All people are this stupid.
Speaker 1: I say that not stupid, not stupid, gullible.
Speaker 0: It's the same thing.
Speaker 0: Stupidity exists.
Speaker 1: It can be independent of gullibility.
Speaker 0: I think the same thing, mostly.
Speaker 0: I guess it's like a subset.
Speaker 0: Gullibility is a type of stupidity.
Speaker 1: But I say this because, remember a while ago, there was a series of vandalism incidents in hotels where someone would call a random room and be like, "There's a gas leak.
Speaker 1: You need to break your window right the fuck now or you're going to
Speaker 1: die.".
Speaker 1: And a lot of people would just throw the TV out the window.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because of the gas leak, the warning is going to be a telephone call.
Speaker 0: Well, it's weird because I don't- And you're not going to smell the gas at all.
Speaker 1: Because on one hand, there is a problem in general with fraud, especially petty fraud, where someone rips off a cashier for 50 bucks and change, where the people who are gotten often won't go to the police because they feel embarrassed and they were stupid.
Speaker 1: Simultaneously, the police often won't take these things seriously because they feel- They're not big enough.
Speaker 1: There was an evil person who did very clearly commit an act of fraud.
Speaker 1: And I am very- personally, forget morals, forget ethics, personally, I have mixed feelings because on one hand, you are stupid if you fall for some dude calling your hotel in the middle of the night and telling you to throw the TV out the window.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: And you're the one who did it.
Speaker 1: On the other hand, the guy who called you also does not deserve praise.
Speaker 0: That's true as well.
Speaker 1: But I do feel, personally, and I do not put this forth as a way the legal system should be, this is just my personal visceral opinion, the dude who throws the TV out the window should have to pay for all the damages.
Speaker 0: I disagree partially.
Speaker 1: Well simultaneously, if you catch the person who told them to do it, that person should be equally liable for the same amount.
Speaker 1: So if you catch them both, either they both have to pay 50% or they both pay 100% putatively, and the extra money goes into some sort of educational fund.
Speaker 0: That's okay.
Speaker 0: I can do that.
Speaker 1: I just, I don't know.
Speaker 0: But I mean, okay, but the person who takes tranquilizers and gets their house robbed shouldn't have to pay.
Speaker 1: No, so what's the difference between the two?
Speaker 0: Because the person got their own house- see if you vandalize a motel, you hurt the motel owner.
Speaker 0: If you let your house get robbed because you're a moron, why should you be penalized?
Speaker 0: It's like you damaged yourself.
Speaker 0: So, so, so.
Speaker 0: And it was negligent, it's not active.
Speaker 1: Scott, you were already penalized because all your shit's gone.
Speaker 0: So maybe it would be okay if your house insurance didn't pay out because you let your house be robbed.
Speaker 1: Should there be a clause in renters' insurance for gross stupidity?
Speaker 0: I think there is already sort of stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Like if you burn your own house down, you don't get arson insurance.
Speaker 0: So if you let your house get robbed, why should you get-.
Speaker 1: But Scott, burn your house down, as in I spread a bunch of gasoline and lit it, is very different from burn the house down because I turned on the oven and then I put oily rags in it to dry them out and then I fell asleep.
Speaker 0: Okay, no, I'm talking about the situation here is more akin to I was having, I decided to set off 100,000 fireworks in the backyard.
Speaker 0: Yee-haw, oops, house on fire.
Speaker 0: That you shouldn't have to get insurance, the insurance shouldn't have to pay for that because you were doing something stupid.
Speaker 1: I think you should have the option of getting insurance for that.
Speaker 0: Oh, absolutely, absolutely.
Speaker 0: But by default, homeowners insurance doesn't need to cover that shit.
Speaker 1: Yep, so here's the question.
Speaker 0: It should be like flood where you got to buy the extra.
Speaker 0: It's like you want to be stupid, you want the right to be even dumber, you got to pay more.
Speaker 1: That's why I'm saying in the case of the- I mean, you could buy insurance- It's throwing the TVs out the window, they should have to pay for the damage they caused.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: But in the case of the house being robbed because you took pills a stranger gave you, you already hurt yourself, you didn't hurt anyone else.
Speaker 1: So there's no punishment to be given, you've already punished yourself by losing all your stuff.
Speaker 1: I doubt many people who were affected by this in Turkey had renters insurance, at least like we do.
Speaker 0: Well, if they own the house, they have homeowners insurance.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, because everyone in the world has homeowners insurance available to them.
Speaker 0: They don't have homeowners insurance as like a required thing, like everyone has?
Speaker 0: Probably not.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: Most places are not- Turkey's a normal place, it's not like some backwater hole.
Speaker 1: I know, Scott, but you realize very few places in the world have the insurance requirements that the US does for anything.
Speaker 0: So in France, you don't have to have homeowners insurance to get a house?
Speaker 1: Every country's different.
Speaker 0: Anyone from Turkey, let us know if homeowners insurance is required to own a house.
Speaker 1: Plus, Scott, remember, it's not a law necessarily, but it's a requirement for the mortgage.
Speaker 0: What if you have no mortgage?
Speaker 1: Well, then maybe you don't need to have homeowners insurance.
Speaker 0: Well, what about, are you telling me the Turkish banks don't require insurance?
Speaker 1: But at the same time, what area of Turkey is this?
Speaker 1: How many people have mortgages?
Speaker 0: Uh, residents of the southeastern city of Gaziantep.
Speaker 1: Alright, how are the demographics there?
Speaker 1: Is it mostly homeowners or is it renters?
Speaker 0: I don't know, go on Google Earth and go to Gaziantep and take a look.
Speaker 0: You know what I'm saying?
Speaker 1: I am just guessing, randomly, putting forth all the biases I have and the ignorance I own about Turkey to say that I am guessing that the majority of the people who were caught by the "take these pills, I'm a stranger" scam did not have insurance that would cover losing all your shit due to taking pills from strangers.
Speaker 0: Alright, send all your Turkish racism hate to rim at FrontRecruit.com.
Speaker 1: It's not racism, it's Turkism.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay, Turkism.
Speaker 1: I'm just, I'm guessing.
Speaker 1: This is my guess.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty confident that Turkey is a completely normal place.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: I'm just guessing that...
Speaker 0: That they have insurance like all other places that are normal.
Speaker 1: I would bet that in most of the world, even the industrialized world, a lot of people do not have insurance.
Speaker 0: I'm sure they have insurance.
Speaker 1: A lot of people in New York do not have renters insurance.
Speaker 0: They have banks.
Speaker 0: Well, renters insurance isn't required by law.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's required by contract only and many leases require it and people just don't keep it.
Speaker 0: I've never seen a lease that requires it.
Speaker 1: A lot of leases do.
Speaker 0: Never seen one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually my lease requires that there be carpets on 75% of the non-kitchen, non-bathroom floors.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Or I can be evicted.
Speaker 0: I didn't know that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Mine doesn't say anything like that.
Speaker 1: A lot of leases say that.
Speaker 1: That exact clause is in most New York leases apparently.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So yeah, talking about morals and ethics, here's the situation and this really happened in Cairo.
Speaker 0: Egypt.
Speaker 1: Missouri.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: Not to be confused with Missouri.
Speaker 0: Or Cairo, New York.
Speaker 1: It also involves not the Mississippi River, but the Ohio River.
Speaker 1: So basically, you've got a situation where there's a town, town of Cairo.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Huge flooding.
Speaker 1: Levees might burst.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: There's no way to shore up the levees.
Speaker 0: No way.
Speaker 0: There's absolutely no way.
Speaker 1: Not in a reasonable span of time.
Speaker 0: Could you always just make them taller?
Speaker 1: Taller isn't the issue.
Speaker 1: It's that because the water is near the top already, the levee could just break.
Speaker 0: Any minute.
Speaker 0: Well, just make it taller.
Speaker 1: How's that going to help prevent it from breaking?
Speaker 0: Uh, make it thicker.
Speaker 1: How are you going to make it thicker in a hurry?
Speaker 0: Concrete.
Speaker 0: Pour it.
Speaker 1: Pour it into what?
Speaker 0: You put up a big wooden wall about a foot back from the existing wall.
Speaker 1: Scott, do you know how long it takes for concrete to cure?
Speaker 0: And you pour the concrete in between the old wall and the wood wall.
Speaker 1: Scott, what unit of measurement for our great dam, the biggest dam in the US, what unit of measurement do you think would be used to determine how long it took for that concrete to set?
Speaker 1: Minutes, hours, days, weeks, months, or years?
Speaker 0: Days?
Speaker 1: Years.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Years.
Speaker 0: Hoover Dam.
Speaker 1: Years.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: That shitty concrete.
Speaker 0: Get Roman concrete.
Speaker 1: This shitty levee is- Could burst.
Speaker 0: Steel wall.
Speaker 1: Destroying an entire town.
Speaker 0: Why did you live there?
Speaker 1: So, here's an option.
Speaker 0: The option was- That's like moving to the place in Pennsylvania where the coal mines are on fire.
Speaker 1: The thing is, the levee was fine, and there was a plan to be able to get around this.
Speaker 1: To save the levee.
Speaker 0: Doesn't this happen every year, though?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: The last time this happened was in 1937.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: So it's not too bad.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So, the plan to fix this, that could be enacted, was to pump a large section of the levee at a different point full of liquid explosives, blow it the fuck up, thus causing the water to destroy countless acres of farmland, and destroy tons of homes in that area, but save the much larger town of Cairo and its surroundings.
Speaker 1: And theoretically, possibly prevent further levee problems in other areas in the coming days.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So, what are the ethics?
Speaker 1: Do you think it is more ethical to leave the levees in place, risking a fairly substantial chance that the levee will burst suddenly and catastrophically somewhere along its banks, probably destroying the entire town of Cairo, or at least putting the entire town of Cairo under 15 feet of immediate floodwater, or purposefully destroying a portion of the levee, destroying 100 or more homes, and a whole ton of farmland?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Well, the first thing you got to question is, is there a third option?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: There's absolutely no third option.
Speaker 0: Well, then all the other- You can't use a bunch of helicopters to remove all the water.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: You can't pump the water into a sewer.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: None of those options were feasible.
Speaker 0: You can't get a big water pipe and bring the water to Arizona where they really need it.
Speaker 1: You realize none of those options are feasible from any engineering perspective.
Speaker 1: But anyway, no.
Speaker 0: You can't just fill up a boat with water and sail it away.
Speaker 1: How big a boat ... How much water do you think this is?
Speaker 0: A lot.
Speaker 0: All the water in a river.
Speaker 1: It's a lot of water.
Speaker 0: It's a big river.
Speaker 0: It's not like a tiny stream.
Speaker 0: It's a river river.
Speaker 1: So anyway, they did blow up part of the levee.
Speaker 1: They spent days pumping liquid explosives into a large section, and then they blew it the fuck up.
Speaker 0: Nice.
Speaker 1: Destroyed 130,000 acres of farmland.
Speaker 0: That's a lot.
Speaker 0: Whose farmland was that?
Speaker 1: Just various farmers.
Speaker 0: Various farmers.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Now, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: As far as I can tell, the area that they ended up flooding is called river bottom.
Speaker 0: And until relatively recently- It was the river bottom?
Speaker 1: It was a flood plain designed to be there so that they could breach the levee- But people moved into it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, farmers moved into it because the farmland was really rich.
Speaker 1: Because it was a flood plain.
Speaker 0: It was a river bottom full of sediment.
Speaker 1: And the real problem here is the same problem we've seen in many places.
Speaker 1: We have an abatement, an easement, a flood plain, some sort of buffer between humans and disaster.
Speaker 1: Because occasionally there are disasters.
Speaker 1: And then people decide that the risk is worth it, and they move into the flood plain.
Speaker 1: Then they complain when it floods.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So, but the same thing could be said of Cairo itself, right?
Speaker 0: It was basically two people being stupid on both sides.
Speaker 1: Ah, but Cairo was there as a town first.
Speaker 0: First.
Speaker 0: So they were the first morons.
Speaker 0: The other people were the second morons.
Speaker 1: Here's the cool thing, Scott.
Speaker 1: How big of a gap do you think they blew up in the levee?
Speaker 0: A hundred thousand acres of farmland?
Speaker 0: Were destroyed.
Speaker 0: They probably, and they used liquid explosives?
Speaker 1: Liquid explosives.
Speaker 0: They probably blew up at least 20 miles of levee.
Speaker 1: Nope, they blew up a two mile gap.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: This is miles.
Speaker 1: A tiny village called Pin Hook was completely flooded.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Did they let the people know before they flooded it?
Speaker 0: I assume they did.
Speaker 0: Did they compensate those people?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Did those people have flood insurance?
Speaker 1: Probably the insurance companies would not give them flood insurance.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean.
Speaker 1: I just thought this was an interesting story because it is many times when we have ethical arguments in the front room crew forums, people always trot out the hypotheticals.
Speaker 1: Like, say there's a trolley on a track that's going to kill three people, but you have the power to hit a switch and divert it to where it will only kill one person instead on a different track.
Speaker 1: Is it ethical to do so?
Speaker 0: It's like that would never happen.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the situation.
Speaker 1: Do we blow up the levee and destroy all these towns?
Speaker 1: Or do we not blow it up and risk the very real sudden disaster of this much larger town?
Speaker 0: I still question whether how much effort they put into finding a third way.
Speaker 1: Scott, the sheer amount of water.
Speaker 1: You realize blowing up the levee and destroying all that farmland, the rest of the levee, all the, you know, everything behind the levee, all that water, there wasn't some other levee they could blow up.
Speaker 1: That water dropped about a foot.
Speaker 1: Only a foot.
Speaker 0: There wasn't some other levee somewhere.
Speaker 1: No, that was pretty much the best, safest place.
Speaker 1: they could possibly do anything.
Speaker 0: Couldn't they just.
Speaker 1: There are two hundred and forty one miles of levees.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: How about?
Speaker 0: here's what you should do.
Speaker 0: Everyone back the fuck up.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: Like along the whole river.
Speaker 0: It's like, OK, we're going to blow this one up now.
Speaker 0: Everyone else has 10 years to get out because we're blowing everything up.
Speaker 0: And then the river is going to be as wide as it used to be.
Speaker 0: Tough shit, everybody.
Speaker 0: You're all stupid for moving here in the first place.
Speaker 0: Then you'll never have the problem again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that doesn't really address the immediate ethical concern of what do you do right now?
Speaker 0: Well, it's just who's going to be first.
Speaker 1: Because, Scott, you realize what you are.
Speaker 1: Captain Hindsight.
Speaker 1: Not that I should have thought of that before.
Speaker 0: No, that wasn't a Captain Hindsight.
Speaker 0: There was a future saying it's like, hey, listen, you know, it's got.
Speaker 1: I believe what you were saying is that Captain Hindsight has a brother, Commander Forsythe.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Kind of like Prometheus and Epimetheus.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it's not even Forsythe.
Speaker 0: It's basically, you know, it's like, OK, I see what happened.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: But now I'm saying we know what's going to happen in the future already.
Speaker 1: Scott, this is what we should do.
Speaker 1: This is one of those every hundred years disasters.
Speaker 0: So that means you should be stupid for a hundred years.
Speaker 1: No, it means that what should people be allowed to assume these sorts of risks?
Speaker 1: Should the farmers who went into this ultra fertile land fully aware that this sort of thing could happen, not be able to knowingly accept that risk for the likely ninety nine years of fertile farming, followed by one year of destruction?
Speaker 0: I guess if you want to.
Speaker 1: My only beef is that people complain and possibly that tax dollars end up subsidizing their subsequent stupid decisions.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like, you know, there's the obvious similar situation where I bought a house on an airport and I complained about the noise.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: That happened in Michigan near me when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: There was an awesome shooting range that had been there since like the 20s.
Speaker 0: But this is more like you bought a house on an old abandoned airport and then rent and then suddenly they decided to start using it again.
Speaker 1: It's like at the same time, if the airport, you know, you had to do your due diligence.
Speaker 1: If the airport wasn't condemned and was still able to become an active airport, you made your bed.
Speaker 0: No, it was condemned, but they renovated it.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So what was the zoning?
Speaker 1: I mean, was this what the zoning still have allowed the airport to someday possibly come back?
Speaker 0: Well, your mistake was that you only bought a tiny square in the middle of the airport.
Speaker 0: You didn't actually buy the whole airport.
Speaker 1: But did you know?
Speaker 1: I mean, if you don't do your research and know whether or not it could turn into an airport again, then fuck you, man.
Speaker 0: At least they told the people to leave and they didn't drown.
Speaker 1: I assume the article doesn't actually specific.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure nobody drowned.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Plus, the other thing is you can always pick up your whole house to put it on a truck and go along.
Speaker 1: That takes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But it's like how much advance notice did they have here?
Speaker 0: It takes days.
Speaker 0: I mean, come on.
Speaker 0: They had.
Speaker 0: they only had to make this decision within days.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Did they put the liquid explosive in the dam that quickly?
Speaker 1: That's pretty fast.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not like floods.
Speaker 1: give you a lot of warning like, hey, I'm going to flood next week.
Speaker 0: Didn't they know that it was rising?
Speaker 0: It doesn't.
Speaker 0: It was in a flash flood.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I didn't read the article that in depth.
Speaker 0: You gotta have more notice than that.
Speaker 1: But I guess complaining is the only thing that bothers me and hypocrisy because I mean, right now, look at what's going on with the Republicans.
Speaker 1: They complain, can complain about how the federal government shouldn't waste money and help people out and be socialist.
Speaker 1: And then they complain that the federal government isn't giving them money to deal with all the tornadoes that are happening.
Speaker 0: Huh?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so things of the day, what do you got for me?
Speaker 0: So check this out.
Speaker 0: These dudes, they took a Kinect, right, which is a Kinect is a Microsoft Kinect, you know, and which is basically webcam that can also detect depth.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And they combined it with a 3D printer.
Speaker 1: Beach of a Wookie.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: They take that and they they basically they take a picture of you and they basically create a 3D model of you and then they take that 3D model and put it inside.
Speaker 0: You know, they basically put it in the middle of a rectangular 3D model and then they print out a you a miniature you in carbonite.
Speaker 0: That's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: So you realize that this exact same advance could be used to advance teledildonics.
Speaker 0: It could indeed.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: It could also.
Speaker 0: the resolution isn't high enough yet, though.
Speaker 0: But yet I saw another example where they were just making miniature figurines of people straight up.
Speaker 1: I kind of like the carbonite thing better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not bad.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of thing you got to be pretty fucking cool to have a carbonite of you on your wall.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Another good idea, though, I was thinking for this right, is we could bring a Kinect to like a museum and go find like, you know, say Venus de Milo type sculptures or, you know, Michelangelo's David type sculptures, scan them, you know, walk around them with a Kinect a little bit and go home and print out, you know, miniature David's.
Speaker 0: because we don't we don't have big printers.
Speaker 0: But if you had a big printer, we could print out Michelangelo's David's that were accurate to, you know, a very small high resolution.
Speaker 1: Going back to I'm not going I was going to quote the Goonies because for some reason all this reminds me of is when they broke the dick off the statue in the beginning.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah, we could basically we could start, you know, basically printing out copies of famous sculptures, you know, like we have, you know, you can buy prints of famous paintings.
Speaker 1: Well, what are we going to do someday?
Speaker 0: Like, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Is there is there a place that will sell you like, you know, a copy of, you know, a Venus de Milo?
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure the answer is yes.
Speaker 0: How much does it cost?
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: Look on Amazon.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So while you look that up, I found it's kind of a blog slash web site, but I think it's worthy of attention.
Speaker 1: I'm not know the website is cool, but I'm linking to a specific entry in it.
Speaker 1: It is called The Art of Manliness, and it is telling you how to be a proper man.
Speaker 1: It does articles on things like how to use a straight razor, how to properly iron a dress shoot, a men's guide to looking like Cary Grant, you know, cool stuff like that.
Speaker 1: But they have one article here, Lessons in Manliness, about one of the baddest asses in the history of the American Old West.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: Bass Reeves was a black deputy U.S.
Speaker 1: marshal in the Indian territories already.
Speaker 1: He was invincible.
Speaker 1: He shot a lot of people, captured like three thousand felons.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't think that no one can capture three thousand felons in his whole career.
Speaker 1: Thirty two years.
Speaker 0: You're going to text.
Speaker 0: You're going to tell me.
Speaker 0: he lived in 10 Pokemon.
Speaker 1: This guy basically did.
Speaker 0: No way.
Speaker 1: This guy is just one of those.
Speaker 0: If you try to catch three thousand felons, one of them is going to kill you.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: He shot a lot of them.
Speaker 0: I'm just there's no way.
Speaker 1: Well, this is a.
Speaker 0: this is Paul Bunyan territory now that I haven't done full research.
Speaker 0: How many blue oxen did he have?
Speaker 1: But I did a little bit of research, and it seems to be at least partially legit.
Speaker 0: Apparently, because he was three felons.
Speaker 1: The area he was in was notorious for outlaws heading there to hide out.
Speaker 1: So basically, subpoenas would come in.
Speaker 0: So he had a fell in honey pot is what you're saying.
Speaker 1: So basically, he'd just go out to the area where they'd hide.
Speaker 1: The felons would fucking put up signs.
Speaker 1: There was an area I'll quote the article 80 miles west from Fort Smith was an area known as the deadline.
Speaker 1: And whenever a deputy marshal from Fort Smith or Paris, Texas, crossed the Missouri, Kansas and Texas track, he took his own life into his hands on.
Speaker 1: nearly every trail would be found posted by outlaws, a small card warning certain deputies that if they cross this line, their lives were forfeit.
Speaker 1: So Reeves would collect those cards as he went off to fuck these people up.
Speaker 1: There's a story.
Speaker 1: I do not know if this is apocryphal or not.
Speaker 1: I cannot.
Speaker 0: Are these cards available in a museum?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I cannot verify if the story is true, but supposedly at one point, a bunch of outlaws got together and tried to assassinate him.
Speaker 0: So they caught him.
Speaker 0: Good job, guys.
Speaker 1: And they get up close.
Speaker 1: One guy's got a gun trained on him.
Speaker 1: The other guy's up close with a gun at him and they get him off his horse and they ask him if he has any last words.
Speaker 1: He says that there's a letter from his mama in his pack and he would be much obliged if they would read it to him one last time before they shot him.
Speaker 1: So the guy says, all right, I see the moment he even glances toward the horse where the pack is.
Speaker 1: This dude grabs him by the neck and screams, son of a bitch, you're under arrest now.
Speaker 1: And his partner was so startled that before he could shoot him, he turned around and basically got him both.
Speaker 1: Just son of a bitch, you're under arrest.
Speaker 0: Someone's going to make a movie.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: David by Michelangelo, 12 inch statue, marble finish.
Speaker 0: It looks pretty close to the original.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Thirty five dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I don't think there's a market for printing your own just yet.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying if you want, you know, you could also do all sorts of other things like, you know, any sort of object you have in your house that you might want to duplicate in physical shape, like.
Speaker 0: maybe you've got, you know, what, what.
Speaker 1: I'm looking around the room.
Speaker 1: There is nothing where a crude simulacrum of its physical shape would in any way help me in this room.
Speaker 0: You could buy an action figure and then make illegal pirated copies of crappy unpainted ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you had to paint them.
Speaker 0: That could be a fun activity, though, if you have an action figure and then you want to paint it exactly like or if you think the paint job in the action figure sucks, just repaint it.
Speaker 0: A lot of people that is a hobby.
Speaker 0: But I'm just saying you could look at the original while you're painting the new one or you could just buy two of the action figures.
Speaker 1: I guess I could duplicate this 2007 Parsec Award.
Speaker 0: Yeah, OK.
Speaker 0: Or you could use it as paperweight.
Speaker 1: Well, I knocked LuPone off of it while I was trying to grab him.
Speaker 0: You could duplicate LuPone.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the meta moment, the book club book is still as a mobs foundation.
Speaker 1: If you're a nerd or a geek, you should have read these books.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So we're just doing the first one first, just because, you know, we should probably do all three.
Speaker 1: I'll read them all.
Speaker 1: But we're just going to talk about it.
Speaker 0: But I bought the trilogy.
Speaker 0: I think there's more than that, actually.
Speaker 1: The unofficial book club book is the entirety of the Prince of Nothing series, because there are now five Prince of Nothing books.
Speaker 1: I've read them all.
Speaker 1: Scott's rereading all of them to get up to that point.
Speaker 1: And it was, I think, the first book we did in the Geek Nights book club.
Speaker 1: And many, many listeners are suddenly reading them again.
Speaker 1: So you will be able to follow the illustrious trend of the front row crew, where one of us read the Prince of Nothing, tricked another person to reading it.
Speaker 1: They raved about it and convinced the rest of us to read it.
Speaker 0: And there's a lot of fantasy novels out there.
Speaker 0: Nerds like fantasy novels, you know, and there's Games of Thrones.
Speaker 0: I've heard of those.
Speaker 0: Locke Lamora.
Speaker 0: There's Dragonlands, Dragon this, Dragon that, Dragon everything.
Speaker 0: Don't read Dragonlands.
Speaker 0: Forgotten Realms.
Speaker 1: You really don't want to read anything with dragon in the title.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying, there's Lord of the Rings, there's all these fantasy novel series.
Speaker 0: They're big.
Speaker 0: Or Forgotten.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Prince of Nothing, it may not be the best, but it is the awesomest.
Speaker 1: It's just, there's something about it.
Speaker 0: It is the favorite of the front row crews.
Speaker 1: I mean, we're a group of geeks.
Speaker 1: We're really into fantasy stuff and sci fi stuff.
Speaker 1: And a lot of us read, you know, a lot of this stuff forever.
Speaker 1: And for some reason, the Prince of Nothing books, more so than anything other than, say, Tolkien, has just caused everyone to read the books in like repeating cycles.
Speaker 1: Every time someone gets into it again, it causes the whole conversation of, I can't even get into it.
Speaker 0: Hey, Rem, I just had an idea.
Speaker 1: What's your idea?
Speaker 0: What if the tusk is the heron spear?
Speaker 1: That is not, there is no way.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying, that could be pretty awesome, though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm pretty sure the heron spear is some sort of laser artillery.
Speaker 0: I think you're crazy.
Speaker 1: Either that or it is a spear in the same way that the Spear of Longinus is technically a spear.
Speaker 0: That is what I think.
Speaker 1: It is possible that the Prince of Nothing and Evangelion are, in fact, the same series.
Speaker 0: It's possible.
Speaker 1: Pretty much, that actually works really well.
Speaker 1: I said that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you haven't read the fourth and fifth books.
Speaker 1: It really does.
Speaker 0: Maybe fourth and fifth, but not one, two, three.
Speaker 1: Yeah, read four and five.
Speaker 0: Except for the dad complex.
Speaker 0: I guess Nair is Kaji.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God, Nair.
Speaker 1: Nair is still my favorite.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: I really like Nair.
Speaker 0: I think the most level-headed, intelligent person.
Speaker 1: Level-headed, intelligent is definitely Akamian and/or Zeswatha.
Speaker 0: No, Zinnimus.
Speaker 1: Well, actually, Scott, level-headed, intelligent, Callus.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying, the most normal person is Zinnimus.
Speaker 1: I feel bad for Zinnimus, no.
Speaker 1: And Zeswatha gets a pretty good, I don't know, I feel like he is the right kind of badass.
Speaker 1: He's very Gandalfy.
Speaker 0: I think the best person is probably like, you know, Mathanet.
Speaker 0: He knows what's up.
Speaker 1: You don't know, you know his full deal?
Speaker 0: I know enough deal.
Speaker 1: You don't know his full deal, I don't think.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah, Zeswatha is pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he knows what's up, because he doesn't shit.
Speaker 0: He doesn't need to.
Speaker 1: Actually, I have a newfound love for the oldest dragon.
Speaker 0: I don't know any dragons.
Speaker 1: The oldest dragon is both the oldest dragon and the oldest dragon.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so anyway, this weekend, Saturday is the Nerdnik, the Nerd NYC Nerdnik.
Speaker 1: We will be there nerding.
Speaker 0: It's in Central Park.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Go to nerdnyc.com.
Speaker 1: You want to hang out with us, play some Jungle Speed on a rock?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Friday the 13th, uh oh, is Nerd NYC Board Game Night.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's also Nerd Night, unrelated to Nerd NYC.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we don't know which one we'll be at.
Speaker 1: We'll be at one of the two.
Speaker 0: Friday the 20th is, oh, I'm going to be at the library all night, but the 21st and 22nd is BarCamp NYC.
Speaker 0: So go sign up for BarCamp NYC if you're going to be in New York.
Speaker 0: And that's enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's about it.
Speaker 1: So way back when the Libya situation was still kind of in its early stages before we had decided to do airstrikes and all that stuff, I kind of idly said, yeah, we should do a show on that.
Speaker 1: We'll have the debate about whether or not...
Speaker 0: You always want to do shows on like world politics and shit.
Speaker 0: And I always say, no, that's not good for geek nights, but I will entertain you one time.
Speaker 1: No, Scott, I don't think it's, why is it not good for geek nights?
Speaker 1: Is political geekery any different from world wrestling geekery?
Speaker 0: We could discover, we can discuss political geekery in the meta as to talk about political geekery, but actually being political geekery.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: I mean, we can be wrestling geekery.
Speaker 0: That is material for a show that specializes in politics.
Speaker 1: But why?
Speaker 1: Geek nights specializes in geekery.
Speaker 0: We could talk about, for example, model railroads in general, but we, you know, to be, we wouldn't be talking about like specific trains being better than other specific trains.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: It's all about the O gauge because we don't know shit about it.
Speaker 1: I used to have model trains.
Speaker 1: I was big into that when I was young.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So what's better, the Lionel or the, I don't even know any others.
Speaker 1: You realize there was a temporary line up.
Speaker 0: And that's why we don't talk about it because we're not...
Speaker 1: So get this, over, like right before Christmas, I was out with Emily.
Speaker 0: Talk about what you know.
Speaker 1: We were shopping for something, right?
Speaker 1: And you know what was in this empty space?
Speaker 1: Like there was a store that had been empty for a while, right across from Brian Park, a temporary Lionel store.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: They had like...
Speaker 0: Holiday season?
Speaker 1: A holiday season.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 1: They had every train thing in there and they actually, they had the real stuff too.
Speaker 1: Not just the kiddie stuff.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 1: No one was buying the real stuff.
Speaker 0: No kidding.
Speaker 1: It was mostly people looking at the trains they already set up and no one was buying them.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: You don't say.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there were a few model railroad nerds who went in there to go get something that couldn't be gotten anywhere else.
Speaker 0: Like limited edition caboose or some shit like that.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you don't feel equipped to talk about world events as a geekery, I guess we could get a guest on like Scott Johnson or...
Speaker 0: You think Scott Johnson's... I mean, you know, Scott Johnson's more qualified than us, but he's still, you know, why don't we got to, if you want to get someone qualified, get someone who's like, you know, actually does it for a living.
Speaker 1: I mean, a lot of geeks are not qualified.
Speaker 1: Look at how many people are gamers, but suck at games.
Speaker 0: That's why they're not on podcasts like this one.
Speaker 1: Many of them are on podcasts.
Speaker 0: I only want to talk about something I'm qualified to talk about, such as anime, mangas, comics, video games, board games, RPGs and technology.
Speaker 1: So we're not qualified to talk about anything else?
Speaker 1: Not really, no.
Speaker 0: What else are you an expert at that?
Speaker 0: you're qualified to discuss?
Speaker 1: Financial stuff.
Speaker 0: It's because it's your job.
Speaker 1: I also studied certain areas of history pretty thoroughly.
Speaker 0: You're not an expert.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: So you're saying only experts who talk about anything?
Speaker 0: Only experts make a good podcast.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't I wouldn't listen to a podcast like, you know, 12 Byzantine emperors if the dude doing it wasn't an expert on Byzantine emperors.
Speaker 1: But he is just a high school teacher.
Speaker 0: The job doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It's about the level of knowledge.
Speaker 0: I'm not in the game industry.
Speaker 1: How do you know he didn't just make it all up?
Speaker 1: Did you look at any sources?
Speaker 1: How do you know?
Speaker 1: Are you saying he made it all up?
Speaker 1: How do you know he didn't just make it all up?
Speaker 0: Because I was stupid and I trusted him.
Speaker 1: Do you even know there was a Byzantium?
Speaker 1: Yes, I did.
Speaker 1: Based on what?
Speaker 0: Because I went to the museum and saw Byzantine artifacts.
Speaker 1: Ah, but you're sure Byzantium isn't just like a town in Saudi Arabia?
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the whole point of this, that we were going to talk about Libya and have the debate, because there was a really interesting debate that I think is worthy of discussion, still not done in Libya.
Speaker 1: Whether or not assassination is a valid thing.
Speaker 0: Oh, we can we can discuss that.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much what we were going to talk about.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it's so it so happens that we didn't get to do that show because we didn't do some Thursdays.
Speaker 1: And we had a canned Thursday we put up because the conventions and then fucking killed Osama bin Laden right before we were going to do this show.
Speaker 1: So I feel like we can roll all that into one because they're all just kind of similar.
Speaker 0: Exactly the same thing.
Speaker 1: Well, at least the assassination aspect of it is.
Speaker 0: That's the part that I was saying was exactly the same.
Speaker 1: It just made me feel really old to realize that a lot of kids don't.
Speaker 1: they weren't even alive 10 years ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, the last nine years worth of kids.
Speaker 1: That's a lot of bags.
Speaker 0: A lot of kids who are, say, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, they were like three, one, two, three, four when it happened.
Speaker 0: So they don't remember shit.
Speaker 1: There was a pretty funny blog that posted.
Speaker 1: they said, like, do you really like?
Speaker 0: do you like, you know, you know about things like when Reagan was in Libya.
Speaker 0: But what were you one?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't remember it.
Speaker 1: You just the earliest political things I remember.
Speaker 1: I remember the first Gulf War.
Speaker 1: I remember perestroika and glasnost and all that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And I remember the Cold War, kind of the end of that.
Speaker 1: We did nuclear drills in my elementary school.
Speaker 0: We didn't do that.
Speaker 1: We did that.
Speaker 1: It's kind of fucked up.
Speaker 0: We only had fire drills.
Speaker 1: It was the Catholic scary school.
Speaker 1: And we would do drills where we'd hide in the basement.
Speaker 0: And yeah, we didn't do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, was was.
Speaker 1: were we legally justified in killing Osama bin Laden?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you've got to first say, is it OK to kill anybody?
Speaker 1: Is it OK to kill anyone ever?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you know, I mean, it's got death penalty, not it was not that long ago, years, some years ago.
Speaker 1: I remember you espousing to me that all forms of killing of any kind are unethical.
Speaker 0: They are.
Speaker 1: So is there no situation where you wouldn't kill where you would kill another person?
Speaker 0: I would try very, very hard not to.
Speaker 1: But if so, say there's a track.
Speaker 1: And if you pull the switch to some dudes and if you don't pull it, you're going to die.
Speaker 1: And there's no other option, no other option, pull the switch or you die.
Speaker 1: But if you pull the switch, some guy you don't know, but you can see dies.
Speaker 0: How is he?
Speaker 0: how is he going to be killed?
Speaker 0: by what method?
Speaker 1: There is a train traveling at one thousand miles an hour.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: And the switch directs it between the track you're tied to and the track he is tied to.
Speaker 0: I can't untie fast enough.
Speaker 1: The train is going a thousand miles an hour.
Speaker 1: You have literally enough time to pull the switch and nothing else.
Speaker 0: Who's who's the other guy?
Speaker 0: You don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't see him.
Speaker 1: He's blonde, about five foot, eleven.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about him.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 1: He's got blue eyes.
Speaker 0: Dude, who are you?
Speaker 1: You try to call out.
Speaker 1: You don't have enough time to call out.
Speaker 1: OK, you've got one second.
Speaker 0: How did I get tied?
Speaker 0: Don't get tied in the first place.
Speaker 1: So a doctor came and offered you some pills.
Speaker 0: I started waving at the train to get it to stop at the brakes.
Speaker 1: Robot train.
Speaker 0: Robot train.
Speaker 0: I hack into the robot train.
Speaker 1: All right, fine.
Speaker 1: There is a guy with a gun pointed at you and kick him in the nuts.
Speaker 1: He is invincible, except for his nuts.
Speaker 1: If you say the word bananas, he will die of an aneurysm somehow.
Speaker 0: He's otherwise invincible.
Speaker 1: He's otherwise invincible and he's going to kill you.
Speaker 0: He's invincible, but that doesn't mean he is omnipotent.
Speaker 0: So I hit the gun.
Speaker 0: So it's out of the way.
Speaker 1: He's omnipotent unless you say bananas and kill him with an aneurysm.
Speaker 0: He's omnipotent.
Speaker 0: So effectively, nothing I do matters.
Speaker 0: He could aneurysm himself with his own omnipotence.
Speaker 1: No, because once he dies, omnipotence ends because he's no longer potent or omni.
Speaker 0: Wait, but I can just walk around, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, you're locked in a 10 by 10 by 10 dungeon.
Speaker 0: Is anyone else around?
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 1: Uh, but there's a camera to record everything.
Speaker 0: Oh, I say, hey, camera, what's up?
Speaker 1: There's no one watching.
Speaker 1: It's just recording.
Speaker 0: Oh, I try to reason with the guy.
Speaker 0: Hey, dude, why are you going to shoot me?
Speaker 1: He can't hear you.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: He just can't sign language.
Speaker 1: Doesn't react.
Speaker 0: I give him the finger.
Speaker 1: He's grabbed your throat.
Speaker 1: He's choking you now.
Speaker 0: Oh, he's not shooting me.
Speaker 1: He's choking you.
Speaker 0: I'm slowly dying.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: You are literally one second from blacking out and dying.
Speaker 0: I try to take the gun.
Speaker 1: You fail.
Speaker 0: I failed.
Speaker 1: You're dead.
Speaker 0: Sucks.
Speaker 1: You would not have said bananas at any point.
Speaker 0: Uh, well, how would I have known to say banana?
Speaker 1: Someone told you all this ahead of time and demonstrated.
Speaker 0: Who told me ahead of time?
Speaker 1: The guy who put you in the dungeon.
Speaker 0: Who put me in the dungeon?
Speaker 0: How did I let myself get put in the dungeon?
Speaker 1: Another omnipotent guy who's not vulnerable to bananas.
Speaker 0: Why didn't he save me?
Speaker 1: Because he's evil.
Speaker 0: Evil.
Speaker 0: So there would be no point in even saying banana, because if I left, that guy could have killed me.
Speaker 0: Fine.
Speaker 1: So you're locked in a room.
Speaker 1: You were kidnapped.
Speaker 1: Some guy just like sapped you.
Speaker 1: You wake up.
Speaker 1: There's you and another guy.
Speaker 1: There's a gun.
Speaker 1: And the guy says, I'm not opening the door until one of you is dead.
Speaker 1: And the other guy says, I'm not going to die.
Speaker 0: Oh, I wouldn't shoot him.
Speaker 0: I would just wait.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: You both die of starvation.
Speaker 1: Or he picks up the gun and he points it at you.
Speaker 1: Now what?
Speaker 0: No, that's all him.
Speaker 0: I'm waiting for rescue.
Speaker 1: So you're going to let him kill you?
Speaker 0: I'm going to die of starvation if I don't.
Speaker 1: You wouldn't kill him?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: No, why not?
Speaker 0: What do you mean why?
Speaker 0: Because he might be rescued.
Speaker 0: And then I would have killed him for no reason.
Speaker 1: What if you know there's no chance of rescue?
Speaker 0: I can't know that.
Speaker 0: How can I know that?
Speaker 1: Um, all right.
Speaker 1: You're welded into a room.
Speaker 0: And the welded.
Speaker 0: Yes, I'm going to suffocate.
Speaker 1: There's air being pumped in.
Speaker 0: That means holes.
Speaker 1: Through holes that are slightly larger than air molecules.
Speaker 0: I'd make some situation like Shawshank Redemption.
Speaker 1: See, frankly, there is almost no situation where if I had to choose between me dying and someone else dying, if the other person is going to be the cause of my death, it is highly unlikely that I would not kill them if that was the only option.
Speaker 0: Right, exactly.
Speaker 0: But the point that I was trying to make with my stupidity there is that there is almost no real world situation where there is no chance.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, the practical situations are more like, say for whatever reason, you have a gun.
Speaker 0: Okay, why do I?
Speaker 1: You carry a gun.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Like say I carry a gun for self-defense.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't.
Speaker 1: All right, say I do.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: I got a gun.
Speaker 1: And someone armed with a knife who is in close deadly range tries to assault me.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I would not feel any remorse, at least at the attempt of shooting them.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, but you know what I would do is first I would threaten them with the gun, hoping that it would dissuade them.
Speaker 0: And then I would of course, even if I had to shoot- If you say shoot to wound, that's crazy and stupid.
Speaker 0: If I was forced- 'Cause that doesn't work.
Speaker 0: If I was forced to shoot them, right, I would attempt to not shoot them in the head.
Speaker 0: That doesn't work.
Speaker 1: No, you don't shoot them in the head, you shoot them in center mass.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying.
Speaker 1: And they're gonna die most likely.
Speaker 0: But for example, right?
Speaker 0: In fact, Scott, if you try- Let us go back to Bin Laden, right?
Speaker 0: I was reading, 'cause I read many accounts, as many people did, and who knows the veracity of these accounts, I don't know.
Speaker 0: But many of the accounts that I read, at least three of them, all said that when they went to get Bin Laden, there was a woman there who they intentionally shot in the leg, intentionally.
Speaker 0: And then they shot Bin Laden to kill him because he resisted.
Speaker 0: But there was a woman.
Speaker 0: they shot in the leg, on purpose, and succeeded in only wounding her, and they're Navy Seals.
Speaker 0: So it's possible, if you're a bad-ass Navy Seal, to hit someone in the leg.
Speaker 1: But Scott, they're not just Navy Seals, they're the special Navy Seals.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're the best Navy Seals.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying, it's possible.
Speaker 1: I mean, there is the conventional wisdom of shoot the hostage.
Speaker 0: I have to try.
Speaker 0: But if you- Even if my skill is nowhere near their skill.
Speaker 1: See, I would not try.
Speaker 0: I would try.
Speaker 1: I would shoot for center mass.
Speaker 1: I would try.
Speaker 1: I would basically have no qualms.
Speaker 0: I think I could hit someone in the thigh, I'm pretty good.
Speaker 1: Are you?
Speaker 1: What was the last time you fired a pistol?
Speaker 0: The year 1990-.
Speaker 1: That wasn't a 22-caliber pistol.
Speaker 0: Never.
Speaker 0: But I fired, I used a 22 in like '96.
Speaker 1: Pistol or rifle?
Speaker 0: Both.
Speaker 0: It's really hard to hit things with a pistol from far away.
Speaker 0: It's really hard to hit anything with a pistol.
Speaker 0: But if a guy is close enough in knife range, but he's not close enough to actually stab yet- Actually, you're more likely to miss at that range, according to media accounts I read.
Speaker 0: I didn't say he's at the knife range.
Speaker 0: I said, if he's farther away, he can't stab you yet, but he also isn't 15 feet away.
Speaker 1: People often greatly underestimate how deadly knives are at moderate range.
Speaker 0: Ridiculously deadly.
Speaker 1: Because pistols are inaccurate and difficult to fire at moving targets if you're not heavily trained.
Speaker 1: Basically, someone with a knife is very deadly, surprisingly far away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I could also run if he's got a knife.
Speaker 1: All right, got a gun now.
Speaker 0: Now I can't run.
Speaker 0: But now it's a wild west shootout.
Speaker 0: So it's a wild west shootout.
Speaker 1: I do not disagree that you try other options.
Speaker 1: If they are available.
Speaker 1: But in the real world, there's a lot of uncertainties.
Speaker 1: There's no perfect, you must kill them no matter what, or you will die unless you're kidnapped by a sadist.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, there's no guaranteed way to escape.
Speaker 1: And if there's more than a tiny chance that I could die, I will probably opt for deadly force if that will greatly mitigate my chance of dying.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then again, right?
Speaker 0: So let's say you're locked in this crazy room and you're going to kill the other guy, right?
Speaker 0: But they could just be lying.
Speaker 0: You don't know.
Speaker 0: that's actually going to get you out of there.
Speaker 0: You know, it's only in the real world example, this guy's threatening you with death.
Speaker 0: You know, there's so many options that you try before you try to kill him.
Speaker 0: And even then, it's like, if you try to--.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying if those options, in my personal case, would reduce my likelihood of survival, I will probably skip them.
Speaker 1: I mean, say someone breaks into a house that I was in.
Speaker 1: I would use the Batman tactic first.
Speaker 0: I try to hit, you know, I might try to club him over the head with a baseball bat from behind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, talk to him from somewhere.
Speaker 0: he can't see you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got a Batman, that's the best way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, you try a whole bunch of things.
Speaker 1: So anyway, was the killing of Bin Laden justified?
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know enough of the details to say for certain, but I can say the following things.
Speaker 0: Number one is, you know, they talk about that he resisted.
Speaker 0: Who knows how he resisted?
Speaker 0: I'm dubious of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it says like, you know, even if he was armed, he didn't get a shot off, right?
Speaker 0: And they shot this other woman in the leg.
Speaker 0: They couldn't have shot Bin Laden in the leg too?
Speaker 0: He's an old man.
Speaker 0: It's not like he would have gotten up.
Speaker 0: What was he going to do?
Speaker 0: He's an old man in the house, he can't do shit.
Speaker 1: You know, it's possible.
Speaker 1: They got, it's possible.
Speaker 1: they tried to shoot him and they accidentally shot the hostage in the leg.
Speaker 0: That is also possible.
Speaker 1: I mean, we don't know.
Speaker 0: We have no idea.
Speaker 1: The thing is, I saw a lot of people arguing that, you know, 'cause a lot of the pictures were leaked and I saw them.
Speaker 0: And I don't know.
Speaker 0: I've heard that every peak picture was fake and that no real pictures have been leaked.
Speaker 0: It could have been Laden.
Speaker 1: What was leaked was a bunch of other pictures from the compound.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw pictures, the helicopters and beds.
Speaker 1: And all the other people dead.
Speaker 1: Kitchens.
Speaker 1: I saw a lot of dead people.
Speaker 0: I didn't see any dead people.
Speaker 0: I saw a lot of stuff.
Speaker 1: The argument a lot of people are making on the internet that is ludicrous is they're saying that, look, in all these pictures, there are no weapons.
Speaker 1: None of these people were armed, clearly.
Speaker 0: They took the weapons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, there are other explanations, but I think the simplest one is, if you just conducted a raid of a dangerous place with armed people, you don't just leave the weapons lying around for whoever might wander in to find them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and plus, you know, they had this super crazy helicopter of some origin.
Speaker 1: Did you see the cool thing where they showed the picture of the helicopter and then they showed the picture when after, as they were leaving, they blew the helicopter up so no one could study it?
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, I think, but from what I've read from helicopter nerds, helicopter nerds are pretty sure that-
Speaker 1: I was reading a lot about what helicopter nerds
Speaker 0: that it is a modified Black Hawk helicopter and not some sort of secret helicopter that is stealth, but basically, it was a, they said it was like- Oh, yeah,
Speaker 1: it's probably a custom helicopter using other
Speaker 0: parts.
Speaker 0: It was basically Black Hawk helicopter plus F-117, you know, body stuff that made it stealthy-ish.
Speaker 1: Someone made a good argument that it was actually smaller than you would expect and it was kind of a specially designed, like miniature version of an old Comanche or something.
Speaker 0: Who knows, but anyway, it was a cool helicopter.
Speaker 1: I don't know, Aaron Clark, I know nothing more about helicopters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we should get Aaron Clark to ask about this helicopter, he knows.
Speaker 0: Anyway, they could have blown up all the weapons with the helicopter.
Speaker 0: That would have been very efficient.
Speaker 1: I doubt they did that.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: The weapon, someone finds an AK-47.
Speaker 1: They've now found the technology to make more AK-47s.
Speaker 0: I mean- No, but the point is you're gonna carry all those weapons back with you 'cause you don't have a helicopter to fly back in.
Speaker 1: Well, you could turn them over to the clearly competent Pakistani military.
Speaker 0: Okay, sure, good idea.
Speaker 0: They just hand them right back over, who knows?
Speaker 0: The Daily Show had a good bit where they're basically like, not only was he hiding in a house- they probably, at least we have no idea 'cause we weren't there, but they probably could have just clubbed him over the head and taken him, probably pretty easily.
Speaker 1: I would argue from a foreign policy standpoint that as a politician, obviously not knowing any of the real intelligence, I mean, this is all speculation.
Speaker 1: We don't know what the SEAL team actually was told.
Speaker 1: We don't know what Obama and all them actually know.
Speaker 1: For all we know, there's some crazy thing, like we have no idea.
Speaker 1: But knowing what I do know, I would posit that there was no way you would want to actually bring him back alive.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: Because what would you gain?
Speaker 1: The NIMBYs wouldn't let the trial happen anywhere.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're saying what would the government gain?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Nothing.
Speaker 0: The government would only hurt the government.
Speaker 1: In fact, it would probably, if anything, there would almost definitely be attacks against wherever the trial was.
Speaker 1: Wherever they put him would be attacked.
Speaker 0: Well, there already was a trial.
Speaker 0: He was already tried, so you could just put him straight in jail.
Speaker 1: All right, so we put him in what jail?
Speaker 0: The same place Bradley Manning is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then what?
Speaker 0: Bradley Manning gets off the hook, hopefully.
Speaker 0: No, but anyway.
Speaker 1: And also, it would give him a mouthpiece to speak, and we know, at least-- Ah, ah, but that is the thing.
Speaker 0: What would the government gain?
Speaker 0: Nothing, but we, we would gain a great deal from all of the interviews with him, but it might harm the government.
Speaker 0: And in fact, crazy conspiracy nuts might say, oh, and Bin Laden's gonna come out with, you know, they wanted to kill him 'cause they didn't want anyone to hear what he had to say.
Speaker 1: Yeah, except we already know that we trained those assholes a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying is that, you know, the government did not have anything to gain, but the people did.
Speaker 0: I think-- It would have been at the very least, right?
Speaker 0: Even if it wouldn't have given us any useful information or anything of that nature, it would have been entertaining to see, you know, Bin Laden on 60 Minutes.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: That would have been-- I can definitely go for that, but I think from a geopolitical stability standpoint, I think him being dead is probably more beneficial to the world overall.
Speaker 0: It's also easier.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway, what I don't understand is why did they just like, it's like they took his body, they killed him, they took his body.
Speaker 1: I read a lot of really good explanations about that, actually.
Speaker 0: And they just buried him at sea?
Speaker 1: The argument was that one, there's apparently a thing in old scary Islam, like the, you know, old caliph days, about how the bot, like if his body was anywhere, it would be a shrine, and you don't want it, you know, wherever you bury it would cause trouble.
Speaker 0: Well, someone can always go to the bottom of the sea and get it.
Speaker 1: That's not likely.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Where are they gonna find it?
Speaker 0: The bottom of the sea.
Speaker 1: It's pretty deep.
Speaker 0: There's a skeleton down there, 'cause the fish ate all the bits.
Speaker 1: You don't know where it ended up.
Speaker 1: You know, there's drift and stuff.
Speaker 0: You could still use sonar and find it.
Speaker 1: Probably not.
Speaker 0: It's down there.
Speaker 0: Plus, in the short term, it would bloat and float.
Speaker 1: Uh, you realize burial at sea, they weigh 'em down.
Speaker 1: Plus, not to sound like a conspiracy nut, I will bet you any money-- They didn't actually bury him at sea, and he's actually-- They didn't bury him at sea, but that was the excuse, and they're gonna keep the body for whatever.
Speaker 0: No, because I'm pretty sure there were photos/videos of the sea burial.
Speaker 1: I don't think it would be that hard to cover that up.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm not arguing that he's dead.
Speaker 0: I think they actually buried him at sea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it depends.
Speaker 1: In the very least, they probably kept fingers or some sort of, you know, teeth.
Speaker 0: Hair.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure there are large core samples of Osama and Laden.
Speaker 0: I'm sure that, you know, they got what they need.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Photographically, physically, relics.
Speaker 1: But I saw a lot of reasonable arguments as to why they did that.
Speaker 1: I was more surprised by, well, not surprised by, but saddened by the immediate reaction of the crazies that say it's not really him, it's a conspiracy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was really him.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm confident it was him.
Speaker 0: It was definitely him, 100%.
Speaker 1: So, was killing him justified?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, if you, you know, we don't know the details of the immediate, the immediate one, so we can't justify self-defense, 'cause we don't know.
Speaker 0: Right, so if you're gonna do it based on death penalty, then I gotta say no, 'cause no death penalty.
Speaker 0: But death penalty's no good.
Speaker 1: All right, now, you say no death penalty, and I also agree, no death penalty.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But-- But, I mean, if I was going to, if I was a cop going to arrest a guy who is, you know, a serial killer, like the guy who did the Long Island killings or something-- I believe the relevant quote is, oops.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and he resisted, then, you know, I would personally try not to kill him, but I guess, you know, your job as a police officer is to kill him.
Speaker 1: Well, my two arguments are, one, if there is no death penalty at all-- Yep.
Speaker 1: I bet you would see a lot more oopses when arresting particularly abhorrent criminals.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 1: I guess, I don't know.
Speaker 1: That's a supposition.
Speaker 1: Two, what about the geopolitical stability situation?
Speaker 1: What about, I mean, look at after World War II.
Speaker 1: The Nuremberg Trials, even if you disagree with the core fundamental ethics of the death penalty, I feel like that, those hangings were a very kind of important cathartic, like for the rest of society, the people who aren't able to just say-- Disgusting, vengeful people.
Speaker 1: Not necessarily disgusting, vengeful.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying people who-- Normal people happen to be disgusting and vengeful.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't say disgusting.
Speaker 0: Just less disgusting than Nazis.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't call it disgusting.
Speaker 1: It just, that's how humans are.
Speaker 0: Yes, humans are disgusting.
Speaker 1: It isn't even necessarily vengeance.
Speaker 1: It's just some people have this weird need for closure or this sense of justice, that if someone has murdered so many, they feel like there needs to be some sort of final society.
Speaker 0: It's called vengeance.
Speaker 0: Revenge.
Speaker 0: I think it's a little-- Someone hurt you, you hurt them back.
Speaker 1: I think it's a little more-- I think it's a little more nuanced than that, and I think you're really doing the argument of disservice.
Speaker 0: You're making it too black and white.
Speaker 0: So what is it?
Speaker 1: As I was just saying-- You've done me wrong.
Speaker 1: I do you wrong.
Speaker 1: Eye for an eye.
Speaker 1: I was saying it feels more like this sense of justice and closure.
Speaker 1: People feel that that level of, some people think it's a deterrent effect, and while there's a lot of evidence that it isn't, in the very least, I can see why someone would believe that.
Speaker 1: And two, some people might not necessarily want revenge.
Speaker 1: They might feel bad about the killing of the person who committed horrible atrocities, but at the same time, they might feel a sort of sense of closure that society casts as judgment that some people are too violent to be allowed to live or too dangerous to be allowed to live.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, your emotions are not a good enough reason to kill a person.
Speaker 0: Tough shit.
Speaker 0: But Scott-- Emotions are not a good reason to do almost anything.
Speaker 1: Scott, from a pragmatic standpoint, I feel like the Nuremberg trials did a lot of good for a lot of people to be able to move on.
Speaker 1: And while you might say that's a failing of those people, that's fine, that's how people are.
Speaker 1: You can't just ignore the fact that people are that way.
Speaker 0: I can ignore people's feelings pretty easily 'cause I'm a huge jerk.
Speaker 1: Well, humans can't ignore that and shouldn't because if you ignore that, you'll find that people will pretty much always disagree with you and side with the people who are more understanding.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the vengeful, evil people disagree with me.
Speaker 0: Huh, that's a problem, I can give a shit.
Speaker 1: Scott, you know who else disagrees with you?
Speaker 1: The people who understand human nature and are willing to sometimes make sacrifices for the pragmatic good of the majority.
Speaker 0: So there's people who are evil and vengeful and there's people who are willing to tolerate these evil and vengeful people.
Speaker 0: And there's people like me, I'm not willing to tolerate these stupid people, fuck them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 1: This is why no one ever agrees with you.
Speaker 1: 'Cause they're
Speaker 0: all shallow and disgusting vengeful human beings who can't rise above the base level of humanity and their simple human emotions and they can either A, want vengeance or B, are willing to accept that other people want vengeance and allow them that vengeance as opposed to using every inch of your will to fight against that disgusting human nature.
Speaker 1: You're not using even a quarter of your will to fight against it.
Speaker 1: Where are you protesting death penalties?
Speaker 0: You don't see me killing anybody.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you're not doing anything.
Speaker 0: That's exactly right, you're not doing anything.
Speaker 1: Fairly poor arguments that appeal almost entirely to emotion and beg too many questions.
Speaker 0: Appeal to no emotion?
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, anyway.
Speaker 0: Is in fact the opposite of emotion.
Speaker 0: So you should ignore your emotion.
Speaker 0: that is evil.
Speaker 1: See, when adults make decisions, they at least understand that.
Speaker 1: yes, even if people have failings, you have to understand and accommodate those failings while at the same time working toward a society that over time minimizes and eliminates those failings.
Speaker 1: You wanna make a society where no one needs to see a Nuremberg trial.
Speaker 0: If we have failings and we can see the failings, we know what the failings are, then that means we can not have them.
Speaker 1: No, Scott, because the people who have them usually can't see them.
Speaker 0: Tough shit for those people.
Speaker 1: So this is why you'll never be in a position of power because the reality of the world is that there are people like that, what do you wanna do, just kill 'em all?
Speaker 0: No, just ignore them.
Speaker 1: But they're the majority and they control everything, so what do you do?
Speaker 1: You already are complicit in all this.
Speaker 0: See, you're asking me if I would kill Bin Laden if I feel as justified.
Speaker 0: Those people certainly do, I do not.
Speaker 1: I feel that from a political standpoint, killing Osama Bin Laden would have been justified for the symbolic value, but at the same time, I don't think it is in any way valuable from a pragmatic or practical value in terms of stopping terror.
Speaker 0: No, absolutely not, no way.
Speaker 0: It doesn't stop any terror 'cause Bin Laden wasn't even really that good at being a terrorist.
Speaker 0: He was really shitty at being a terrorist.
Speaker 0: But anyway-- And he wasn't even doing any terror recently.
Speaker 1: So I guess I feel that on the death penalty, for situations like this, I feel like it's something that should be available and used so rarely that it's a big fucking deal when it is used.
Speaker 1: Pretty much war crimes, that's the only case of the death penalty in my mind.
Speaker 1: Meh, that's your rebuttal?
Speaker 0: I don't really, you know, like even when it comes to Nazis, right, it's like, you know, there's these people who are like Elie Wiesel, he's like still hunting down the Nazis who flew to South America, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like, okay, listen, the dude was a Nazi, he was an evil disgusting person, the worst kind of person that ever was lived.
Speaker 0: But it's like, what is there to gain by finding this person who's basically living alone, hidden away in South America, and dragging them, this like an 80 year old dude, somewhere to hang him?
Speaker 0: What is the point of that?
Speaker 1: I agree, I think it's stupid.
Speaker 0: Like, I don't get it.
Speaker 1: I don't think it serves any purpose.
Speaker 1: It's just a few people wanting revenge for something that happened a long time ago.
Speaker 0: So it's the same thing if it's immediate.
Speaker 1: No, 'cause the immediate aftermath, there's a much greater effect.
Speaker 1: And I think the hangings, the Nuremberg hangings and the Nuremberg trials were a kind of accounting and reckoning that society, even though you disagree with it, I do think that--.
Speaker 0: So it's okay to do something evil because there's a bunch of evil people who don't think it's evil.
Speaker 1: Why is it evil?
Speaker 1: What's evil?
Speaker 0: You're killing somebody.
Speaker 1: Why is that evil?
Speaker 0: So is it okay to kill people?
Speaker 1: Yes or no?
Speaker 0: Period, just, is murder okay?
Speaker 1: You know what I'm gonna say, Scott?
Speaker 1: Sometimes.
Speaker 0: Regardless of circumstance.
Speaker 0: Sometimes.
Speaker 0: You're gonna say sometimes?
Speaker 1: So yes.
Speaker 0: So why, okay, so the sometimes yes and sometimes no, right?
Speaker 0: In the sometimes no, why no?
Speaker 1: Depends on the circumstance.
Speaker 1: I have very complex opinions on killing and the death penalty.
Speaker 0: So every single circumstance is a different reason why killing is or is not okay?
Speaker 1: Yes, I don't believe in moral absolutes.
Speaker 0: All right, so if I were to stab you right now, that's not okay pretty much, right?
Speaker 1: Well, because I have many arguments as to why I don't want you to stab me.
Speaker 0: All right, fine, okay.
Speaker 1: The simplest one is that in lieu of all other things as a solipsistic being that appears to have free will and believes that it exists, I have no more deep or core purpose than to continue to exist because that's the only thing I can do truly.
Speaker 1: So if you're going to do something that I believe may stop me from existing, there is no atrocity.
Speaker 1: I will not commit to keep myself existing.
Speaker 0: All right, all right, let's make it a little easier, right?
Speaker 0: So a stranger walks into the apartment and he knocks on the door, we let him in.
Speaker 0: Let's say maybe it's a pizza delivery guy.
Speaker 0: A stranger.
Speaker 0: And I stab the pizza delivery guy to death, right?
Speaker 0: Is that wrong?
Speaker 1: - In my case, I would say yes because--.
Speaker 0: - Why is it wrong?
Speaker 1: - Because in my case, I do not see any imminent threat to you, nor any reason for the killing, nor any justifiability for the killing, and it looks like there's been material damage in a person, another being that theoretically has free will and is solipsistically self-referential and consistent has been ended.
Speaker 0: - So why is it wrong to end a theoretically solipsistic being?
Speaker 1: - It's not objectively wrong.
Speaker 1: I'm saying that I personally believe, my definition of wrong is that.
Speaker 1: That is only my definition, and even then, it's only a projection.
Speaker 1: I'd want myself to continue.
Speaker 1: I assume that person exists.
Speaker 1: Therefore, I assume that they also would want to continue.
Speaker 0: - So why do you care what the other person wants?
Speaker 1: - On a core solipsistic level, I wouldn't, but because for various reasons, some of them are probably physiological, some of them are philosophical, none of them are absolute, I feel like two solipsistic beings that may or may not be able to interact and may or may not have free will is probably better overall than one.
Speaker 1: Because there is more chance of interaction, at least as far as I can perceive.
Speaker 0: - So it's all based on interaction, right?
Speaker 1: - Well, no, that's just in this case.
Speaker 0: - So you value more interaction over less interaction.
Speaker 1: So therefore-- - Not at all scales, though.
Speaker 0: - Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So therefore-- - Scott, I think the problem is you're trying to trap me in a moral absolut--.
Speaker 0: - I'm not trying to trap you, I'm just trying to ask.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, but I'm just saying there are no moral absolutes, and if you want to argue pure philosophy, it'll all come back down to solipsism,
Speaker 0: - Of course everything comes down to solipsism, but it's basically, you have a totally subjective moral, which is all morals are, that killing is wrong, and the question is just why is that your moral?
Speaker 0: Why have you personally chosen that moral?
Speaker 1: - If you wanted the simple answer, in general, I prefer to see people smile than frown.
Speaker 1: I prefer to generally see people happy.
Speaker 0: - So is it a selfish moral?
Speaker 0: You do not want killing because a world with less killing makes you personally happier 'cause that world has more people in it.
Speaker 1: - But I believe, though I cannot prove, that it makes other people happier too, and I personally, for reasons that I may not be able to fully explain, feel happier when I see other people happy.
Speaker 0: - And that is why that you think it is okay to kill bin Laden because you see that making other people happy.
Speaker 1: - Ah, but at the same time, that alone wouldn't justify it in this case.
Speaker 1: You want, here, my pragmatic argument for killing Osama bin Laden, as opposed to the philosophical one, because that gets boring really quickly.
Speaker 1: Pragmatically, it prevents him from having a mouthpiece, which it also prevents him being a focus for terror, because we know that, by and large, terror committed, especially against the West, is not by some large, shadowy organization that has a command and control structure.
Speaker 1: It seems to be by-- - Random angry dudes.
Speaker 1: - Or small cells that coordinate in a very loose fashion.
Speaker 1: So as a result, the best way to prevent terror is to prevent a focus for that terror, kind of like how if you put an object into, like you can basically, by disturbing water that has something dissolved in it, you can sometimes cause that something to precipitate out around the focus.
Speaker 1: - That's true.
Speaker 1: - Like when you have super-heated water that's been boiled twice, and it's fine, it just sits there.
Speaker 0: - You get a bunch of calcium.
Speaker 1: - But then you poke a stick into it, or a spoon, and it explodes suddenly.
Speaker 0: - And it explodes, yep.
Speaker 1: - The focus, you gave something for the hate and the terror to precipitate around.
Speaker 1: Bin Laden being alive, there is no practical way to do anything with him but kill him, and even killing him after the fact would have been a focal point for terror.
Speaker 1: The fact that by the time the news came out, he was already dead, blunted that blow, I think, from a very pragmatic and practical perspective.
Speaker 0: - It also, right, people don't think about this, it actually decreases terror in the opposite direction, right, because it's sort of like we were on the warpath to hunt the guy down, and now that we got him, the warpath of the U.S.
Speaker 0: It's like, we're not on the warpath anymore, as much.
Speaker 1: - At least we shouldn't be on the warpath.
Speaker 1: The TSA, I really hate the fucking TSA.
Speaker 0: - Well, I mean, we're still on the warpath, many warpaths around the world, but there is one, at least the warpath has diminished a tiny bit.
Speaker 0: - The TSA tweeted.
Speaker 0: - And reverted from, we took some offense and moved it to defense.
Speaker 1: - Yep, the TSA tweeted something to the effect of, he may be dead, but we're gonna stick around like terror is still a danger.
Speaker 0: - Okay.
Speaker 1: - Yeah.
Speaker 1: - I was kinda, I feel like, okay, we got him, can we repeal the Patriot Act now?
Speaker 0: - Terror wasn't a danger before.
Speaker 1: - So get this, the Patriot Act actually expires at the end of the month and has to be renewed again.
Speaker 0: - I thought it got renewed.
Speaker 1: - I don't know if it actually got renewed, I didn't follow up after that.
Speaker 0: - I don't know, I remember there was people asking me to sign digital petitions to make it not be renewed.
Speaker 0: - It's been renewed before.
Speaker 0: - I know.
Speaker 1: - But it needs to be renewed periodically.
Speaker 0: - Hopefully it won't be renewed.
Speaker 1: - I think it will be, though.
Speaker 0: - Probably.
Speaker 0: Maybe they can renew it with an amendment.
Speaker 0: That'd be at least a little bit better, as long as it's not a bad amendment, it can make it worse.
Speaker 0: It can always happen, fuckers.
Speaker 1: - So two practical reasons, if you ignore the morals of killing someone, these were two practical, greater good reasons for killing him in the manner that we did, as opposed to trying to bring him back alive.
Speaker 1: - Yep, well I, right-- - Poorly we can disagree on that, but at least we should agree that irrespective of our personal beliefs and irrespective of-- - Well, if I was the government and I had the motivations of the government, then practically, absolutely yes.
Speaker 1: - Yep, and it just so happens that my-- - If I was the government.
Speaker 1: - My personal motivations-- - But I'm not the government.
Speaker 1: - In this case, generally aligned with what the government did.
Speaker 0: - Nah, see, but practically, right, personally, right, me not being the government, I don't want that.
Speaker 0: I wanted to have a mouthpiece.
Speaker 0: I wanna hear all sorts of crazy stuff.
Speaker 0: I wanna see all sorts of drama.
Speaker 0: I wanna see all those people who want him to be killed, all those vengeful people that I don't like, I wanna see them upset, 'cause I get some schadenfreude on those evil people who want vengeance all the time.
Speaker 0: That would be awesome-- - Why would they be upset?
Speaker 1: He probably would have been tried and then executed.
Speaker 0: - No, but see, that's why I wanted to see him not be executed, so those people would be upset.
Speaker 1: - But he probably would have been.
Speaker 0: - That's just what I know, but that's just what I personally wanted, you know, for the awesomeness of me being like, aha, you evil people didn't get what you wanted, you assholes, always looking for killing people.
Speaker 1: - I mean, I know I saw a lot of people celebrating-- - And I would've loved to see him on TV, - Like, I saw a lot of people just celebrating like crazy.
Speaker 0: - Not because I--.
Speaker 1: - Then I said it happened, but I remember I saw the news, 'cause, you know, people were over it.
Speaker 1: I look out at Fark, and Fark had it way before the real news, dude.
Speaker 1: - Well, of course, and I don't wanna-- all I thought was, huh, and I remember I was like, "Hey, Emily, Osama's dead," and she's like, "Oh,
Speaker 1: okay.".
Speaker 0: - Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: - We were like, hm, and then we went to bed.
Speaker 0: - Well, I mean, but even before he got killed, you know, we didn't even know if he was dead or alive, and we didn't really care.
Speaker 0: It was like, you know, there was all sorts of rumors.
Speaker 0: He's in a cave, he's serious there.
Speaker 1: - Here's a practical question.
Speaker 1: Suppose Al-Qaeda had been real.
Speaker 1: It really was an organization, and he really was controlling it.
Speaker 0: - So there really was basically Dr.
Speaker 0: Evil Incorporated, and he was really the big boss, and they were really, and they were confident and good at what they did.
Speaker 1: - Yes, so supposing that was, would then assassination if it were viable, and if we believe that it would disrupt the operations of this organization be justified?
Speaker 0: - Mm, that is a difficult question.
Speaker 1: - Philosophically or practically?
Speaker 0: - That is a difficult, well, first of all, if they were an organized organization, right, with structures and command and control.
Speaker 1: - We could argue that they're an army at war?
Speaker 0: - We could, no, we could just fight them in open war, right?
Speaker 0: Just straight up, you know, you roll tanks, roll.
Speaker 1: - We are.
Speaker 0: - In the advanced wars.
Speaker 1: - But God, in Pakistan, Afghanistan, we have drones just flying out, shooting people all the time.
Speaker 1: We are actively at war with these elements.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, but it's not, it's not like a one army, or, you know, a bunch of henchmen all wearing the same helmet.
Speaker 0: It's, you know, it's random dude here, random dude there.
Speaker 0: That would be like, you know, it's basically, it's like criminals all over the place.
Speaker 0: You wouldn't use drones to kill, like, all the murderers in New York City.
Speaker 1: - No, use Batman.
Speaker 0: - That's what I'm saying, right?
Speaker 0: It's a Batman situation, not a drone situation.
Speaker 0: But if it was an evil organization, and they had like a secret base, drones are the, totally appropriate.
Speaker 1: - So, I guess, 'cause I wanna dovetail this into Libya a little bit.
Speaker 1: Do you think assassination at all, forget the legality of it as we currently portray it?
Speaker 0: - Yeah, legality, all the answers of the questions of legality are just known, and there's no disagreement on them, really.
Speaker 0: So what's the point?
Speaker 1: - Is assassination ever pragmatically justified?
Speaker 0: - Pragmatically justified?
Speaker 0: It's tough, right?
Speaker 0: 'Cause I mean, if you're, the motivations of a government, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, well, if you're a world leader and you order to assassinate another world leader, suddenly your ass is grass, right?
Speaker 0: 'Cause now it's open season on world leaders.
Speaker 0: So world leaders really like there not to be any assassinations, 'cause then they don't have to worry as much, even though they worry a whole lot.
Speaker 0: Obama drove by the office this morning, and he looked pretty worried with his motorcade and blocking off the road.
Speaker 1: - Thing is, motorcade is always that way.
Speaker 0: - I know, but I'm just saying, it's like, they're still pretty worried about assassination, even when there's no assassinations, right?
Speaker 1: - Right, and we tried to assassinate Castro.
Speaker 1: how many times?
Speaker 0: - Yeah, you know, we did.
Speaker 1: I guess the only argument I have is that regardless of the realities of whether or not it's possible to assassinate people, because it's really hard to assassinate people, as we learned when we tried to get Castro.
Speaker 0: - Well, we've tried to assassinate a lot of people.
Speaker 0: It's really hard.
Speaker 0: - Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends on the person.
Speaker 0: - Especially if they're guarded at all.
Speaker 0: Saddam Hussein's doubles, I mean, come on.
Speaker 0: Couldn't even get him with briefcase bombs and shit.
Speaker 0: Doesn't work.
Speaker 1: - Yep, the Ikurai dynasty.
Speaker 0: - But anyway.
Speaker 1: - God, that was one of the best scenes in The Prince of Nothing.
Speaker 0: - That's a good scene.
Speaker 1: - When he replaced the guard.
Speaker 0: - But, you know, so from that perspective, pragmatically, assassinating is not good if you're a world leader, 'cause then suddenly you're on the line, right?
Speaker 0: But, and also, right, if you assassinate a world leader, you might create more disruption, right?
Speaker 0: 'Cause now there'll be a struggle for power, and the person that you wanna be in power might not come to power.
Speaker 0: - But!
Speaker 0: - It could actually make a bad situation worse.
Speaker 0: - But at the same time-- - There are times when it could make a bad situation better.
Speaker 1: - I think a good example of that would be North Korea.
Speaker 1: Kim Jong-il is clearly not actually in charge, because he is crazy.
Speaker 1: - No, no.
Speaker 1: - Killing him would disrupt everything.
Speaker 0: - Maybe, you'd have to kill a bunch of other guys too, but not too many guys.
Speaker 1: - You're better off letting him die of old age and letting them disrupt themselves than having an external disruption.
Speaker 0: - But you could speed it up.
Speaker 0: It's like you could save them sooner, you know?
Speaker 1: Why wouldn't you?
Speaker 0: If all the assassinating him now does is make the good stuff, or hopefully good stuff, happen sooner, then why wouldn't, you know?
Speaker 1: - 'Cause it might not.
Speaker 0: - That's true.
Speaker 0: - But in the case of Libya-- - I'm assuming you know it would make it better.
Speaker 1: - That's more of a case where, I mean, basically, we have one man who is kind of a demigod.
Speaker 1: He has personal, charismatic power over the elements of the military that are loyal to him.
Speaker 1: And the elite, at least, are loyal to him as well, because he keeps them in the goods.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, I do not believe that if he suddenly died, that the rest of the power structure around him could continue much longer.
Speaker 0: - Well, what you want is you want a situation where all those elite guys and military leaders, right?
Speaker 1: - Turn on him.
Speaker 0: - Well, no.
Speaker 0: Well, they could turn on him, yeah.
Speaker 0: But it's like, if he's assassinated, there's a few ways it can go, but one of the ways it can go is they get really mad, and then you made it worse.
Speaker 0: - But considering that his army is a lot of mercenaries-- - Another way it could go is that they flee, and that's a good way for it to go, is if they're like, "Oh, shit," and they get out.
Speaker 1: - The best way, from a stability standpoint, even though it's not the best in the short term for the regular people, is if the elite, realizing that it's all gonna fall apart, he dies, let's say, and they publicly side with the rebels and say, "Yes, we will form a new government.
Speaker 1: "It's over, hooray," and they don't actually change anything.
Speaker 0: - All right, well, let's go back historically, or let's think of some people that were famous, right, and would assassinating them have been-- - Hitler, Hitler.
Speaker 0: - You think so.
Speaker 1: - Would Hitler, is assassinating Hitler early enough?
Speaker 0: - It depends when you assassinate him.
Speaker 0: If you assassinate him very early, no bad ever, well, a lot less bad ever happens.
Speaker 0: Nazis never take power or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: And that's a great move.
Speaker 0: - Maybe not.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's possible someone else in his organization would've kept up the good fight.
Speaker 0: - Possible, possible, but it would've been different.
Speaker 1: - In fact, someone less crazy might've actually managed the war more competently toward the end.
Speaker 0: - But if you kill him in art school, right, but there's no way you could've had that foresight to do that, but I'm just saying, time machine, right?
Speaker 0: That would've been a great move, but if you assassinate him in the middle of the war, that actually may have been a bad move.
Speaker 1: - Well, especially because he was largely incompetent toward the end of the war.
Speaker 0: - That's what I'm saying, is if you killed him before the end of the war, would they have pressed to the east?
Speaker 0: Maybe not, and then they might've been more successful, so maybe a bad move at that point, practically speaking.
Speaker 1: - Yep, it depends on when, though.
Speaker 1: Maybe in 1941.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, maybe, it depends.
Speaker 0: It's all timing, a lot of timing issues, right?
Speaker 0: And then, okay, so what about, you know, there's another one where it's like definitely good move.
Speaker 0: Pol Pot, any time.
Speaker 1: - At the same time, Pol Pot, what was going on, I feel like the whole movement would've continued.
Speaker 1: Him dying would not have affected the movement.
Speaker 0: - I think it would've.
Speaker 1: - What about Chairman Mao?
Speaker 0: - Chairman Mao wasn't really as bad as those other guys.
Speaker 1: - Exactly, I want a much more morally ambiguous situation.
Speaker 1: - So.
Speaker 1: - I mean, Stalin.
Speaker 0: - And I mean, it's not like Chiang Kai-Shek was an angel, either.
Speaker 1: - No, but I'm pretty sure if Stalin had been assassinated once he really--.
Speaker 0: - Oh, Stalin, you can kill Stalin any time you want.
Speaker 1: - I'm pretty sure there is nobody in the power structure who would've taken over, who would've been as crazy as he was.
Speaker 0: - No, you could kill Stalin any time you want.
Speaker 0: When he's zero, sure, go for it.
Speaker 1: - Saddam Hussein would've been a clusterfuck had he died.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, you know, I don't know about him, either.
Speaker 0: But I mean, there's also-- - What kind
Speaker 1: of fucked up world is this, where, and Emily and I were talking about this the other day,
Speaker 0: because
Speaker 1: of the way we did everything, we live in a world where I look at people like Bill O'Reilly and say, wow, you're one of the more reasonable people on that side.
Speaker 1: And I look at someone like Saddam Hussein and say, you know what, you're a real bad dude, but I kinda feel sorry for the way you ended.
Speaker 1: The fact that I felt sympathy for Saddam Hussein really makes me uncomfortable with the way our foreign policy has worked out the last several years.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, you know, that's what happens.
Speaker 1: - Like, you know, you were a bad guy, but there were worse.
Speaker 0: - There were, yeah, that's the thing with bin Laden is everyone's acting, that's the one thing that upsets me the most, is everyone acts like bin Laden.
Speaker 0: was this big, big dangerous bad guy, right?
Speaker 0: Well, first of all, right, the first thing is that he was a bad guy, real bad, right?
Speaker 1: But-- - He was dangerous, too.
Speaker 1: He had the money.
Speaker 0: - He was dangerous, and that he provided resources to many dangerous people, helped them out, gave them training and such and such.
Speaker 0: Clearly bad, clearly dangerous, clearly a threat, no question, right?
Speaker 0: He was also responsible for many bad things, definitely, such as embassy bombings in Africa, et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 0: Bombing in the U.S.S.
Speaker 0: called, directly responsible.
Speaker 1: - To get rid of him and his little organization, and yet, Rwanda.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, there are many places where much worse things are happening.
Speaker 1: - Right now, they're still happening.
Speaker 1: - Syria?
Speaker 1: - Yep.
Speaker 1: Of course, there's little we can do about Syria.
Speaker 1: - Bahrain?
Speaker 1: - We can't really invade.
Speaker 1: Actually, you know, to get into Libya, this is, I mean-- - Libya?
Speaker 1: - Gaddafi, whether or not we want to assassinate him, the reality is we probably couldn't easily do it.
Speaker 0: - Well, first of all, he's probably in a more secure place than bin Laden.
Speaker 1: - Well, especially now that we killed his son, which sadly, I read that the one that died was the most liberal and most progressive of his entire family who was in the country.
Speaker 0: - Then why did they kill him?
Speaker 0: Wouldn't they have known that that was the good one and not gone after him?
Speaker 1: - I think they just bombed a building that they knew someone was in.
Speaker 1: They didn't know who it was, I don't know.
Speaker 0: - Oh, so they can just indiscriminately bomb those buildings.
Speaker 1: - Well, the thing is though, Libya and Syria, 'cause he brought up Syria, are very different situations.
Speaker 1: Libya, because it was a rebellion, there are cities that are straight up, this is a rebel city, there are clearly demarcated forces.
Speaker 1: - Well, Libya's very large geographically.
Speaker 1: - But as a result, it's very easy, if we want to intervene, to intervene by literally attacking military assets with relatively little chance of collateral damage.
Speaker 1: Syria is a lot more plainclothes policemen in cities attacking people.
Speaker 0: - It's also much smaller geographically.
Speaker 1: - Yep.
Speaker 1: But it's not like, oh, we can bomb all those people to slow down the hostilities, because those people are mixed in with the people we're trying to protect.
Speaker 0: - Well, I think a lot of that is just a side effect to the fact that the US, we really don't want to see any US people being killed, right?
Speaker 0: So we won't send in a giant army of a million soldiers and tanks.
Speaker 0: - Well, Libya, too-- - It's always bombs and missiles and boats.
Speaker 1: - Is definitely more of a NATO initiative, and really, France and a lot of other countries.
Speaker 0: - NATO, which is what, percent US forces?
Speaker 1: - Yeah, but at the same time, they were pushing for it much more than we were.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, that's 'cause they're close.
Speaker 1: - Also because-- - And Libya doesn't affect us as much as other things.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, also because there's a long-- - I mean, it affects us certainly, clearly.
Speaker 1: - I realized recently that many of our listeners probably actually have no idea what the Pan Am Lockerbie bombing was all about or even know what that is.
Speaker 0: - I just discussed it earlier and how we were basically zero when that happened, right?
Speaker 1: I knew about it, and-- - Yeah, but we don't remember it.
Speaker 1: - A lot of, yeah, but I knew about it.
Speaker 1: - Of course.
Speaker 1: - I've known about it for most of my life, because Lockerbie bombing.
Speaker 1: - Yeah.
Speaker 1: - And yet, I have talked to many, many people in the past few weeks who have never heard of that.
Speaker 1: - Really, 'cause people I talk to-- - I was like, you know, when terrorism really appeared, as far as Westerners in the US cared.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, you know, before then, you could just walk into any airport right up to the gate.
Speaker 0: There was no security or anything.
Speaker 1: It was just like a bus station.
Speaker 1: - My grandfather, when he was flying back from Australia, had a machete with him, and the stewardess asked him if he could put it under his seat, because she was worried it would fall out of the overhead bin.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, right?
Speaker 0: After the Lockerbie bombing, that's when they added, you know, the metal detectors.
Speaker 0: - Well, that was one incident.
Speaker 0: - Well, there's also the Iran hijacking.
Speaker 1: - Yeah.
Speaker 0: - That was pretty much those two.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: - Kinda got off on a tangent there, but-- - But yeah, most people I talk to, they know there was a thing, the Lockerbie bombing, but they couldn't tell you any details, and most they could tell you it had something to do with Libya.
Speaker 1: - I think the Libya thing, I feel like we're going about it as NATO, at least, the best that we can.
Speaker 1: I don't think there's anything better we can do, short of just trying to stop the hostilities with the air strikes, and wait for everything to normalize.
Speaker 0: - I think people are, you know, it's like, you know, Iraq War was basically like an invasion, right?
Speaker 1: - Iraq War was completely unjustified.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, but it's like, well, in this case, like, there's a rebel force, right?
Speaker 0: And it's obviously good, right, and at least better than the other, you know, the loyalists, right?
Speaker 0: We always like rebels better than loyalists, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, come on.
Speaker 1: - Except us.
Speaker 0: (laughing) - And I mean, no, we're rebels, come on.
Speaker 0: Right, so really, if they decided to just send in, you know, a whole bunch of regular armies to go support the rebel army, I wouldn't really have a problem with that so much.
Speaker 1: - It's got civil war.
Speaker 0: - It's called civil war.
Speaker 1: - No, that's what I was alluding to, our civil war.
Speaker 1: We were not the rebels there.
Speaker 1: I wasn't talking about the Revolutionary War.
Speaker 0: - Oh, I thought you were talking about us personally today.
Speaker 0: - No, I'm talking about us, civil war.
Speaker 1: We were the evil empire, marching down with troops and keeping them in.
Speaker 0: - No, we weren't, it was the War of Northern Aggression.
Speaker 1: - So we were the bad guys, marching down.
Speaker 0: - No, it was, we were aggressive, but good.
Speaker 1: - But we weren't rebels.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, we were.
Speaker 1: - We were rebelling against the people.
Speaker 1: - Who rebelled against us.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, they won, they took over.
Speaker 1: - But I guess that's why I'm for what's going on in Libya.
Speaker 0: - But yeah, actually, Revolutionary War, right?
Speaker 0: Perfect example, right?
Speaker 0: You got some rebels, us against loyalists, British, and the French army just comes in and joins our army, kinda.
Speaker 0: - Well.
Speaker 0: - Sorta, but it's a similar situation I would not have a problem with.
Speaker 0: If like, you know, US Army goes in, joins Libyan rebels.
Speaker 1: - I think it's just a pragmatic thing to do at the time, especially because otherwise it would have failed.
Speaker 0: - Also French people, they'll take any excuse they can to fight against French people.
Speaker 1: - The amount of force and intervention it would take to intervene, to do something in Syria, one, would anger the entire region and destabilize everything.
Speaker 1: It'd be ground forces, it'd be crazy.
Speaker 1: It takes relative, compared to that, it takes relatively little to intervene in the Libya situation because we can do it primarily with our massive, massive force projection capabilities.
Speaker 0: - Yep, which cost a zillion dollars.
Speaker 1: - But at the same time, do they cost a zillion dollars or do they cost a zillion dollars regardless of whether or not we use them?
Speaker 0: - That is a good, the question is, right, we already know that like a lot of these missiles and things cost like a million dollars each, right?
Speaker 0: But the question is, if we use them, are we buying new ones or are we just using it up?
Speaker 0: It's like, if I have a box full of ammo, well, if it just sits there, it's not like I'm saving money by not shooting it.
Speaker 1: - I imagine it depends on, you know--.
Speaker 1: - But if I shoot all the ammo and I don't refill it, then okay, but if I-- - I imagine it depends mostly on like what the next weapons program is, like maybe there's a new cruise missile in the works.
Speaker 0: - I think that's.
Speaker 0: another problem is that we are, we are already spending money on all sorts of weapons programs and things.
Speaker 0: - But at the same time, we spend relatively-- - But we could not be doing that.
Speaker 0: But we are, so it's like--.
Speaker 1: - I'm actually not that angry at all about our level of military spending.
Speaker 0: - I am.
Speaker 1: - Because Social Security costs way more than that.
Speaker 0: - It does.
Speaker 1: - Medicare, Medicaid.
Speaker 0: - Well, no, not Medicare, but Medicare is a huge, is like number three.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, I'm saying of all the costs, we could be more streamlined in our military spending, but I feel from a pragmatic standpoint, the fact that the United States has not just overwhelming military power-- - Triply overwhelming.
Speaker 0: - But
Speaker 1: at least in terms of raw force projection capabilities, unlimited power, not in terms of anything other than projecting force, not in terms of occupation, maintenance, anything like that, but in terms of
Speaker 0: being able to-- - We could blow up any spot on the earth we want at any time.
Speaker 1: - Even without nuclear weapons.
Speaker 0: - That's right.
Speaker 1: - I feel like that in and of itself is a force of stability in the world.
Speaker 0: - Oh, but the thing is, right, I would cut the spending, right, not on, I would still maintain-- - I'm curious what you're gonna say here.
Speaker 1: - What do you mean you're curious?
Speaker 0: - I'm curious.
Speaker 0: - Right, the budget is gigantic, right?
Speaker 0: - Yeah.
Speaker 0: - We could, the force projection capabilities alone is not like 99% of that budget, right?
Speaker 0: Who knows what percent it is, but it's not 99%.
Speaker 0: - Right, so, and you don't wanna cut a lot of the research stuff, right, obviously, because--.
Speaker 1: - In fact, we need to raise spending.
Speaker 1: - Exactly.
Speaker 1: - And we need to put most of that money into taking care of our goddamn veterans when they come back from wars.
Speaker 0: - That's true, but the thing is, I would shuffle a lot of the monies around, right, 'cause it's like you have, you keep, you up the veterans' spending, right, you keep the research spending stable, you keep the force projection capabilities, but then you take it down in all the other
Speaker 1: areas.
Speaker 1: - Like what?
Speaker 0: - What do you mean, all the other areas?
Speaker 1: - What other, name an area.
Speaker 0: - Like just, you know, having X number of soldiers, period, decrease, you know, shrink everything.
Speaker 0: You don't need so much armies.
Speaker 1: - Actually, we kinda do, because all those force projection things require a lot of supply lines and maintenance and just work.
Speaker 1: Most of the people in the military are doing a lot of that stuff, not the shooting.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, but you don't need, you know, you can still maintain the force projection and get rid of a lot of the extra militariness.
Speaker 0: That's not the only-- - I just, I'm actually kind of dubious of that.
Speaker 0: - You think so?
Speaker 0: - If anything, I think-- - There's also a lot of places that the military is in the world that it doesn't necessarily need to be.
Speaker 0: - What do you mean, like where?
Speaker 0: - Like where?
Speaker 1: Where are they that they don't need to be?
Speaker 0: - All kinds of countries.
Speaker 0: - Same one.
Speaker 0: - We have military bases like all over the world.
Speaker 0: - Where?
Speaker 1: Which one are we gonna get rid of?
Speaker 0: - All the ones that aren't like right in the middle of doing something?
Speaker 1: - Like what?
Speaker 1: Name one.
Speaker 0: - We got bases in South Korea, we got bases in Japan.
Speaker 1: - The bases in South Korea are probably useful.
Speaker 0: - Why?
Speaker 1: - To be ready to deal with North Korea, which will happen probably in our lifetime.
Speaker 0: - Well, you know, do we really need to actually be there right now?
Speaker 0: We can get over there.
Speaker 0: - No, not really.
Speaker 1: Without bases there, it would actually be a while to have significant, constant force maintenance there.
Speaker 0: - We have aircraft carriers, they float around.
Speaker 1: - They take a while to get somewhere, and that's one kind of force projection.
Speaker 1: Having a base there provides a much different kind of force.
Speaker 0: - Like what?
Speaker 1: - Large numbers of troops on the ground to occupy in rapidity.
Speaker 0: - But I don't think there's large numbers of people there at all the time.
Speaker 1: - There's more people there than you'd think.
Speaker 1: Also, the logistics field to assist the South Korean military in what would eventually be a war of occupation with North Korea if it comes to that.
Speaker 1: Or, you know, dealing with the artillery strikes, rapid response, it takes a while for an aircraft carrier to get anywhere.
Speaker 0: - But it's already hanging out there.
Speaker 0: We have a lot of them.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, and where do you work?
Speaker 0: - More than anybody.
Speaker 0: - Where are they?
Speaker 0: - In fact, more than everyone else combined.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, do you know where they are right now?
Speaker 0: - If I did, I would be working in Washington, wouldn't I?
Speaker 0: They don't know where they are.
Speaker 1: It's pretty trivial to know where all our aircraft carriers are.
Speaker 1: They're not difficult to find.
Speaker 1: They're big.
Speaker 0: - Aren't they secret?
Speaker 1: - No, they're huge.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, but how are you gonna find them?
Speaker 0: It's not like I have a satellite, but I can just find them.
Speaker 1: - You can find them.
Speaker 0: - Really?
Speaker 0: Okay, so where are they then?
Speaker 1: - I can go look it up.
Speaker 1: - All right.
Speaker 1: - There's websites to track.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, this one's here right now doing this.
Speaker 1: These are over here.
Speaker 1: Military nerds, eat that shit up.
Speaker 0: - I don't know.
Speaker 0: I find it hard to believe that the locations of all the aircraft carriers are just known.
Speaker 1: - No, not the exact GPS coordinates.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna know exactly where it is.
Speaker 1: You'll know what region it's in, what sea it's in, where it is.
Speaker 0: - People are watching these things all the time and it's just on the internet?
Speaker 1: - And they often issue press releases of where they're going and what they're doing.
Speaker 0: - Really?
Speaker 0: - Yeah.
Speaker 1: In fact, it's on the news all the time.
Speaker 1: Aircraft carrier going here for this.
Speaker 0: - Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: - The submarines are kind of secret.
Speaker 0: - Well, that's a different story.
Speaker 0: Obviously, you can't see the submarines.
Speaker 1: - I guess, Scott, I'm just saying-- - That's Captain Obvious.
Speaker 1: - My only point here is that you made a broad statement about what you think the military should be doing with its money and yet don't actually know much about what the military's doing with its money.
Speaker 0: - I said at the beginning we were not qualified for this kind of podcast.
Speaker 1: - But you've made a strong opinion despite saying that you're not qualified to make the opinion.
Speaker 0: - I'm on a podcast, it's my job.
Speaker 0: - Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: - It's probably entertainment for the listener.
Speaker 0: If I just go ho-hum, that's not very entertaining, is it?
Speaker 1: - Anyway, it's been an hour and a half.
Speaker 1: I think we're done.
Speaker 0: - All right.
Speaker 1: - This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: - Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: - Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: - Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.