Speaker 0:
Speaker 1: It's Monday June 6th 2011.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight warm today.
Speaker 1: So we talked about cooling your computers.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: And of course my goddamn bike got stolen.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean, I can't say those and bike steel in his city around.
Speaker 1: Oh my god It's the most bike steel in his city.
Speaker 1: Even the cops are like, yeah, there's like this professional ring of like me.
Speaker 0: now Understand that right?
Speaker 0: I mean if you're a professional thief Bicycles think about how easy it is.
Speaker 1: I mean you've seen those performance guys who basically go in very openly and sometimes right.
Speaker 0: But you see there isn't that much money in by other.
Speaker 0: is how much money could I steal a relatively new?
Speaker 1: Nice, like not a fancy like super racing bike like a nice bike that costs like five hundred thousand dollars You can easily sell five hundred thousand five hundred to a thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: You can easily sell that for a few hundred bucks and it basically cost you nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there are many other things you could steal that is much better off than what.
Speaker 1: that's that Most things like that are higher risk and are more difficult defense.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not ready card numbers Yeah, and you know what people steal those all the time.
Speaker 1: I'm just probably competition in the credit card thievery market.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying they're also kind much more lucrative.
Speaker 1: And if you don't if you're not already, you know in the good with Russian hackers, you know, you're some street punk.
Speaker 1: What are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: dealing drugs is likely to get you arrested.
Speaker 1: There's no way anyone will ever arrest you stealing a bike jewelry.
Speaker 1: Who are you gonna steal jewelry from?
Speaker 1: and more importantly who the fuck?
Speaker 1: Are you gonna sell jewelry to?
Speaker 1: jewelry has almost no resale value.
Speaker 0: sell it to all those guys.
Speaker 0: You know you ever walk down like the jewelry street and they're always like we buy gold.
Speaker 0: You know who's?
Speaker 0: you think who the hell would walk down that street to sell gold jewelry thief.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: The jewelry thieves are much better off than the bike.
Speaker 1: There's not that much jewelry to steal.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not like people leave their jewelry tied up to posts on the street.
Speaker 0: You'd be surprised What I really.
Speaker 1: yeah, what amazes me though is that you know, I Was careful with my bike like I knew that the city is just a fucking like den of thieves.
Speaker 1: I knew this.
Speaker 1: So I never rode my nice bike Unless it was gonna like I would never leave it out of my sight for any like length of time Like if I knew I'd be in a store for more than like 15 minutes.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't use my nice bike.
Speaker 1: I was in the Home Depot less than 10 minutes.
Speaker 0: That's too long Yeah, and they stole it.
Speaker 1: in that time There were cops who visible like 50 feet away who didn't notice anything.
Speaker 1: huge crowds broad daylight.
Speaker 0: Well, of course, they couldn't notice because it was in the middle of a huge crowd.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if it was quiet and there were cops 50 feet away They would have seen it because they've been the only person to look at.
Speaker 1: Yep, but what was very funny is that Emily's bike was chained to my bike.
Speaker 1: They didn't steal hers.
Speaker 0: No, this is a piece of crap.
Speaker 0: I Did I did.
Speaker 0: how'd you get home subway?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah subway.
Speaker 1: Well since we went to the Home Depot and they chose they wanted like 25 bucks to deliver the one thing we wanted to buy.
Speaker 1: So we were like fuck it.
Speaker 1: We'll just go get it later.
Speaker 1: And then my bike was stolen.
Speaker 1: So since I didn't have my bike Emily just biked home and I went back into the Home Depot and bought the thing and carried it home on the subway.
Speaker 1: The cashier was even like, ah, you really needed this pegboard didn't you?
Speaker 1: and I was like now my bike got stolen And she's like.
Speaker 1: I see you might as well.
Speaker 1: I'm like, yeah, I might as well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually mad props to Home Depot.
Speaker 0: I saw a video recently Oh, yeah of it was like some crazy right-wing nut job and he was like.
Speaker 0: I called up the Home Depot cuz they were donating to gay.
Speaker 1: No usually when something like this happens the story is always and the company quietly backed down and made some noncommittal statement and he was Like and he's like.
Speaker 0: they said they support diversity and we got you know.
Speaker 0: So I got.
Speaker 0: we got boycott Home Depot cuz they're going to hell.
Speaker 0: It was something along those lines and I was like, yeah Home Depot.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah Home Depot basically said, you know what?
Speaker 1: We're totally okay with gay people and we don't really need your business that much.
Speaker 1: So go nuts.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think Home Depot is gonna be alright because it's actually Hardware is one of the few things that you know is.
Speaker 0: you know online isn't always gonna be able to beat it out.
Speaker 0: I mean, I buy hardware is online from you know, like You know screwdriver, you know a level small amounts of wood I'm not gonna buy online because wood is very non-uniform.
Speaker 1: if I'm buying like three pieces of wood for a small project I want to see the pieces of wood and buy them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's not just wood.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, there's all kinds of stuff that out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's all kinds of stuff that like especially if you're doing a hardware project, right?
Speaker 0: Like you're remodeling your house or you're building something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you might be like, oh shit I need X and you need X like now Really specific and it's like you can't be waiting three days and you always have the instinct.
Speaker 1: You're like, I wonder if I could use these other three tools to make something that would almost do that thing.
Speaker 0: Oh, this is a situation Like you need to replace a screw because you stripped it and now you go and you're like you go online and you're like, okay I don't need it right away.
Speaker 0: Let's see I need a. this inches screw and the thing of screws shows up and they're slightly off.
Speaker 0: You're like fuck.
Speaker 1: you're like, ah, you're trying to get the pic one time.
Speaker 1: I remember one time I was looking at pictures of screws on Amazon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, good job and trying to figure out if the threading was the same as the scrubs like holding up to the monitor.
Speaker 0: It's like no you just got to go to the hardware store and put the screw.
Speaker 0: hold the screw up next to the example screw And look at I hate going to hardware stores though.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 1: because every time I'm in a hardware store the geek comes out and wants just random stuff I think like Oh electronics.
Speaker 1: I wonder if I could ooh HDMI cables ooh HDMI ports to put in my wall.
Speaker 1: Maybe I should replace all my cat six with cat seven And then I end up in like the nail gun area just thinking like yeah It'd be really fun to have this for like 15 minutes.
Speaker 1: Sure would Was that xkcd where the guy buys a house?
Speaker 1: He's like, oh I can do whatever I want.
Speaker 1: if I want to drill a hole through this wall I can just do it.
Speaker 1: and then he drilled his house down.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I also ran a race right before my bike got stolen.
Speaker 1: the first time in almost a decade Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I ran in a win.
Speaker 1: No, of course not.
Speaker 1: Are you kidding?
Speaker 1: It's New York the most poodle grace you could have like five-year-old kid charity run for autistic Alzheimer's and Some marathon runner will show up and win it.
Speaker 0: So a place did you come in?
Speaker 1: I came in 80th out of like 1,300 people Which is not too bad and in my age class gender and age 20 to 29 year old.
Speaker 1: So I'm at the top of that age class.
Speaker 1: I came in like 20th.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, and I came in like 60th.
Speaker 0: They can really track all this data.
Speaker 0: This is pretty interesting.
Speaker 1: get this.
Speaker 1: So here's how they do it.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, you wear a number.
Speaker 0: they write your information So they put your time and your number and then the computer figures are actually really nice.
Speaker 1: You wear the number.
Speaker 1: number is basically just for photo verification after the fact.
Speaker 1: But really they give you this big RFID thing that you put on your shoe And it tracks when you cross the start line and cross the finish line And wait a minute.
Speaker 0: So why don't I wave it at the start line get on a motorcycle and wave it at the finish line?
Speaker 1: They'd notice.
Speaker 0: I could.
Speaker 0: just I could get off the motorcycle like a mile before the end.
Speaker 1: It's only a 5k run.
Speaker 1: It was like three and a something miles, right?
Speaker 0: So that go to the two miles on the bike.
Speaker 1: It was in Central Park.
Speaker 1: There's you wouldn't know it worked.
Speaker 0: Oh, it was just completely in Central Park.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I probably could done that.
Speaker 0: I probably wouldn't have been an 80th place.
Speaker 0: I would have been more like 100 plays proud of myself.
Speaker 1: But I also realized I'm old because the proud part came that I started the front like I started with the people who were trying To win which I'd never done in a race before because usually people are stupid and they all disappear.
Speaker 1: Well, remember that Chase corporate challenge we did that was the last race I ran and remember how we all stood at like the six-minute mile mark is we're like, yeah six seven minutes We can do this.
Speaker 1: and then everyone near us was actually in the 15-minute miles And they just were stupid and stood in the wrong place and it took like 10 minutes for us to even get going.
Speaker 1: But I started in the very front and I ran with the lead pack all the way past the first mile.
Speaker 1: and then The fact that I didn't eat breakfast.
Speaker 1: I was late to the race so I biked over there really hard parked and ran right away and I chugged a Red Bull right before Caught up with me and that right the Red Bull was supposed to help you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Red Bull helped me.
Speaker 0: There's only three.
Speaker 0: It was only three K's.
Speaker 0: the Red Bull should have helped you the whole way.
Speaker 1: the Red Bull helped me in the first mile The stomach not so happy in the second mile.
Speaker 0: You should have brought two more Red Bulls.
Speaker 1: I should have just vomited and then kept running.
Speaker 0: but now you could have pooped and kept running too.
Speaker 1: that pooping wouldn't really had done It.
Speaker 1: it wasn't at the poop stage.
Speaker 1: But so almost a decade ago I ran a three and a half mile race and I end by time ended up being like 22 minutes almost exactly This time.
Speaker 1: a decade later ran the same race after having trained and run rigorously for a decade.
Speaker 1: Yeah 22 minutes.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, you know the winners time was probably like 12 minutes 17 Really for three.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Hmm three back-to-back five six minute miles is actually pretty tough to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: but usually it's like the.
Speaker 0: you know, the people who are like the best in the world.
Speaker 0: They're on four minute miles, right?
Speaker 1: So if they're you know, yeah a minute mile one mile run three of those.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are people who run multiple four minute miles.
Speaker 1: Yeah Those people don't show up to every race anyway, but I realize I peaked Probably somewhere in between there and I'm basically by working so hard.
Speaker 1: I am maintaining the fitness level I had when I was 20 Mmm, which is both optimistic and pessimistic.
Speaker 1: but optimism reigns because at the three mile mark when there's like a half mile to go The oldest dude you can imagine just flew right fucking by me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that guy was like 70.
Speaker 0: I've seen I think I've seen that guy had an old man run like.
Speaker 1: he was kind of shuffling But he was shuffling faster than I was running.
Speaker 0: I might I it either might be the same guy I see or a similar guy because when I bike sometimes in the morning down Second Avenue or whatever Avenue it is to go south.
Speaker 0: There's sometimes an old guy running north who's way old but he's fucking running and I'm like damn.
Speaker 0: look at that guy.
Speaker 1: I've seen him like three or four times when I bike to work There's always one super homeless guy with a giant Shopping cart full of homeless guy stuff and he must have a commute because he's always coming up the Queensboro Bridge at the exact same Time every morning.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I guess he commutes to Queens to do whatever hobos do.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of people I see daily Just like you.
Speaker 0: just see them doing the same path on the street like the.
Speaker 0: this is one guy who comes over the Queensboro Bridge in the mornings and Basically, he's I don't know He's some sort of worker in a building of some sort cuz he's wearing like almost everyone.
Speaker 0: He's wearing that some sort of you know building, you know, you know, no works for the building like, you know Superintendent uniform kind of thing.
Speaker 0: I heard you gots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Basically, this guy has the hunches hunched like his.
Speaker 0: he doesn't have a hunch like his back, you know has a big blob on it.
Speaker 0: He has a hunch like he's like literally bent over and he's like flimsy like a Twizzler.
Speaker 0: It's like if you're holding a Twizzler and you let it droop over.
Speaker 0: that's what this guy looks like.
Speaker 1: Well now you got something to work toward.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't think you can possibly end up that bad.
Speaker 1: So it's Monday and You know, there's a lot of tech news, but we probably have to talk about jobs.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's Apple day today, which Seems to always occur a lot on Mondays.
Speaker 0: Guess it's just you know, I guess coincidence that we do our tech show on Monday and Apple does Mondays also.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well clearly Apple is emulating us.
Speaker 0: But anyway So we report on them in a timely manner if you just want all the information you can go to engage it and read it All.
Speaker 0: but I just want to hit some high notes and provide some insights that I don't think other people have right.
Speaker 0: Oh first major Insight OS X lion.
Speaker 0: right regardless of any features.
Speaker 1: It's adding the pricing is the story.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: No, no You're wrong.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's 30 bucks, but that's not a big deal because actually if you remember snow leopard was also similarly lowly priced.
Speaker 1: Well, this is 30 bucks for every Apple PC you own.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: That's slightly better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but are you ready for the real the real?
Speaker 1: What do you think is the real story here?
Speaker 0: You can only buy OS X lion in the OS X App Store.
Speaker 1: I Didn't even notice that.
Speaker 0: and why is that a big deal?
Speaker 0: Well, you think oh, it's not a big.
Speaker 1: well There's that lawsuit where Apple's trying to claim that the App Store is a is a mark of theirs.
Speaker 1: because Apple App Store You're missing it.
Speaker 0: You're saying that's one thing.
Speaker 0: now What is the biggest problem with OS X line only being available in the Mac OS X App Store?
Speaker 1: Oh It's harder to I don't know pirate.
Speaker 0: It's impossible to get it say in VirtualBox or make a hackintosh or anything because there's no DVD.
Speaker 0: There's no USB stick.
Speaker 0: There's no nothing.
Speaker 0: You know, the only way you can get it is if you already have a Mac that already has the Mac App Store.
Speaker 0: There's no other way to get it.
Speaker 0: We won't be able to install it in anything other than a Mac that already comes with it.
Speaker 1: So I have a hackintosh running snow leopard.
Speaker 0: Is it gonna upgrade?
Speaker 1: That's what I'm curious about.
Speaker 0: I'm very curious.
Speaker 1: That's the only way.
Speaker 0: that's the only way.
Speaker 1: That's the second only way.
Speaker 1: the real only way is some hackers gonna come up with a way.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling that maybe they're gonna come up with some snow leopard upgrade the lion trick But what?
Speaker 0: one or two more versions down the road, you know, they're not going back, right?
Speaker 0: I think it's gonna be total SOL.
Speaker 1: Well, I think there are many reasons Apple is doing this.
Speaker 1: I do agree now that your yours is probably the primary reason but It worries me.
Speaker 1: It's not just that.
Speaker 1: in general people are really.
Speaker 1: it's like the PC world is going through the same thing.
Speaker 1: It went through, you know, 10 20 30 years ago.
Speaker 1: the same cycles happen where suddenly they're becoming very Like this app thing is happening where people aren't down there like people are downloading apps for their androids their iPhones The same way that people used to go to CNET and download shareware.
Speaker 0: Yeah as opposed to installing only now They're paying.
Speaker 0: only now they're paying money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because you know everything in the Mac world always cost money and those things that cost money in the Mac world are free everywhere Else, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you owe a Mac.
Speaker 0: Oh you want to develop for the Mac, right?
Speaker 0: Well, you know you can sort of buy this Mac developer thing for $100 and you could buy Xcode for 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: Oh show you want to develop something for Windows here.
Speaker 0: Here's Microsoft Visual Studio Express for free.
Speaker 1: You got an emulator, but you want to use your fancy controller with it.
Speaker 1: Well, there's an app that'll do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh, you know, it's everything on Apple's platforms cost money.
Speaker 0: That's free everywhere else.
Speaker 0: All right, let's let's continue down this road, right?
Speaker 0: iOS 5 greatly improved integrated Twitter notification thing.
Speaker 1: which notifications Android is like?
Speaker 1: I really like Android.
Speaker 1: I have no complaints about my phone, but notifications Android are just so like 10 years ago.
Speaker 0: Are they really because they really can't be worse than they are in the iPhone now with iPhone is similarly bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so but this looks like this looks like a winner here.
Speaker 1: You know, you know what the real winner is in that front web OS.
Speaker 1: web OS to this day has the best Notification system I have ever seen.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I agree and it beats even the new iOS notification center.
Speaker 0: They're also bringing out this integrated Twitter like integrated into the iOS Twitter Which is great competing with the palm free there also, right up cuz palm free.
Speaker 1: What.
Speaker 1: the only other good thing it had going was that messaging other than Twitter was completely integrated.
Speaker 0: Yeah speaking of messaging iMessage which is like what the fuck it's like a messenger that you can only use to message with other people on iOS It's competing with definitely BBM, right as opposed to say, you know, what anything else but it's like.
Speaker 0: Why don't they just put fucking I chat on iOS?
Speaker 0: boom done?
Speaker 0: And what's so weird right is why would they put I Message right, which is an I you a messaging system where you could only message between Apple devices on the iOS.
Speaker 0: but meanwhile IChat is now has support where you can add more modules to it's allowing I chat to chat with anything that has a module.
Speaker 0: It's like they opened up the I chat and they closed down with this weird ass.
Speaker 0: I message bullshit on The iOS.
Speaker 0: I don't understand what they're doing there.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I actually don't have anything on that one.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, let's see.
Speaker 0: What else we got?
Speaker 0: Oh, so another thing is most of the features that they announced right almost all of them Right have two things in common right or fall into one or both of two categories, right?
Speaker 0: Number first category is something typical from Apple.
Speaker 0: They act like it's new and it's a hundred years old.
Speaker 0: Yeah Think all you're not that?
Speaker 0: not that I'm talking about things like we added full screen support.
Speaker 0: Whoa, that was like a big deal like full screen and it's like welcome to DOS Welcome to the Apple - everything was full screen, but they're acting like it's a big deal, right?
Speaker 0: They're acting.
Speaker 0: they come at they come up with a new feature They treat it as if they have invented something when really what they've done is they had you in Locked up this whole time and they've removed one pair of handcuffs.
Speaker 0: But they pretend like they've created something new and really all they've done is release a lot You know a lock on you which in a way, I mean, can you fault them for it?
Speaker 1: It works really really well.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying it doesn't work.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying it's like you got to see through that shit.
Speaker 0: You got to come before that, you know.
Speaker 0: It's like they didn't.
Speaker 0: you know what they're adding an OS X lion the ability to resize a window by grabbing it on any edge Instead of just the bottom, right?
Speaker 1: Well, wait, wait, wait Scott.
Speaker 1: They're way ahead of a default unconfigured FVWM.
Speaker 0: now It's like it's just like when they added spaces and they acted like it was a big deal.
Speaker 0: It's like I've only been using a virtual desktop since 1985 on my Amiga.
Speaker 1: Hey to be fair Windows doesn't have fucking virtual desk windows fucking retarded.
Speaker 0: But actually that Windows 8 looks sorta has virtual desktops sorta sorta I mean effectively doesn't really need him with that interface and props to Microsoft because he looked at the new Xbox Interface that they showed at e3 today.
Speaker 0: They're giving all their stuff that window that Windows Phone 7 interface Which is not.
Speaker 0: I actually like it as it's not so bad and whether you like it or not I like being uniform across everything with the same interface.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 1: That's Simultaneously, I'm sure that for a long time if you do need some other interface for whatever reason the good old Windows thing will be there because corporate people lose their shit.
Speaker 1: and The
Speaker 0: other category of things that they added were features that somebody else was adding and they're basically eating someone else's lunch Right, which is I think we talked about this recently on geek nights where it's like if you go
Speaker 1: with the Twitter apps If
Speaker 0: you build something on someone else's platform and then they end up basically making you useless, right?
Speaker 0: You can't complain Right?
Speaker 0: and that's Apple did a whole bunch of that.
Speaker 0: Like there was that iPhone app that used one of the volume buttons to snap the picture and Apple said no.
Speaker 0: and now what?
Speaker 0: Are they adding the default camera program?
Speaker 0: You can press the button to take a picture.
Speaker 0: It's like There's so many.
Speaker 0: there was like a whole list of.
Speaker 0: Someone made a funny list of all the different like third-party apps that are now useless because those features have been integrated into iOS.
Speaker 1: Really interesting to me.
Speaker 1: Look at the culture of computing now that there was a time when I mean the most apps the majority of apps in any app Store, you know Android web OS iOS whatever are Trivial apps.
Speaker 1: They're the kind of thing any competent developer could write in like an afternoon at most Yep, and they basically do almost nothing and in the old days stuff like that was at most at worst Shareware where they're like wins it.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: or they were four windows that latches unzip in itself Yeah,
Speaker 1: or they were you know various forms of freeware We're like, that's
Speaker 0: actually a great example because now wind zip is not needed anymore because Windows has its own unzip But you still need like, you know seven zip because some people some morons ever our files.
Speaker 1: But now we have this culture where people will write these tiny meaningless apps that do this tiny tiny thing.
Speaker 1: But because the platforms are kind of closed and it's not super obvious how to install stuff.
Speaker 1: You know side-loaded if you even can in certain situations And these people all want to charge like a dollar for it and then they get indignant When someone else implements the thing that they want a dollar for for free because it took them ten minutes to implement it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time these are all things that should have been in there already, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a separate problem.
Speaker 0: There was a great article which is totally true that said hey Look, if you want to write an app for a platform, right?
Speaker 0: Don't write something that adds a feature.
Speaker 0: The platform is missing.
Speaker 0: you need to write anything if you want to try to make money doing apps.
Speaker 0: You need to write something that is vertical right?
Speaker 0: For example, Apple is never going to ever ever ever ever.
Speaker 0: Create it, you know build in to iOS.
Speaker 0: right like a calculator for physicists.
Speaker 0: Right like a special physicist thing, right?
Speaker 0: So if you write something that is for physicists and is not for the general populace Then it's never going to be part of iOS.
Speaker 0: your app will always have a home there, right?
Speaker 0: But if you do something that's like, you know, here's adds a missing feature to iOS.
Speaker 0: Well, that feature might no longer be missing anymore.
Speaker 0: Anyway, and lastly I guess we don't think about the iCloud, right?
Speaker 0: So they came so close with this right.
Speaker 0: what I've always wanted right for 10 years 20 years 100 years is why do I have to plug my iPod into fucking computers?
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: my Android syncs everything over the wireless.
Speaker 0: It sure does and it's great.
Speaker 0: It sure does.
Speaker 0: but So the the iOS there with the iCloud They've done a whole bunch of really good stuff.
Speaker 0: in some ways beats the Android and some ways doesn't right.
Speaker 0: in some ways It's great.
Speaker 0: You're gonna be able to update.
Speaker 0: if they want to update the OS It's just updates just like Android.
Speaker 0: you want to update apps.
Speaker 0: They just update all good over the air.
Speaker 0: No problem Just works.
Speaker 0: if you want to sync right you can sync with iTunes using the Wi-Fi.
Speaker 0: So it finds your computer with iTunes running and syncs to it.
Speaker 0: That's pretty good.
Speaker 1: granted I don't want to have to even do that.
Speaker 1: I still want to just run it on my iPhone.
Speaker 0: So you can do that too, right?
Speaker 0: So if you buy a song right then that song, you know It knows in the database on the cloud that you bought that song and any iTunes up to ten devices that you have will just have that song.
Speaker 1: The Amazon store they it's just mp3 and any device I have can download it infinity time, right?
Speaker 0: But this is this difference between can download infinity times and is already downloaded, right?
Speaker 0: You see what they did there.
Speaker 0: It's like if I buy a song on my phone and I listen to it and then I go and I pick up my iPad And I hope I push the iPod icon and the song is in the library already.
Speaker 0: That's a step up.
Speaker 1: Oh, you mean like my phone can do with droid.
Speaker 0: Can you really do that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you buy a song in the Amazon store, yeah, and then you go sit at your computer That song will already be on your computer on the hard drive.
Speaker 1: So to make it go on the hard drive I believe I have to do something you have to.
Speaker 0: it saves a click.
Speaker 0: basically It's one click more.
Speaker 1: but the one nice thing is it is almost never that I am not connected to the internet That's true.
Speaker 1: So as a result I leave it all in the cloud and just download it as I want it.
Speaker 1: and if I'm gonna go on a trick a trip Where I think I'm gonna go out of cell service like on my phone I can just be like download all these albums to my phone right now and then delete them when I'm done.
Speaker 0: Yep But anyway, so I didn't say anything about the podcast.
Speaker 0: what how that was gonna work.
Speaker 0: We'll see if it works or not.
Speaker 0: That's a big deal for me at least I don't know about for other people, but anything you buy on iTunes will do that.
Speaker 0: Also, if you take say a photo or a document It'll be saved in the cloud and then all your other Apple devices will have it download, you know.
Speaker 1: So unintended consequence and something my droid doesn't do.
Speaker 1: yeah There have been a lot like an ever increasing number of stories about police officers Doing bad things and then destroying people's cameras or freaking out when they get filmed or whatever.
Speaker 1: Autosyncing pictures and videos to the cloud is gonna make it a lot harder for cops to get away with stuff like that.
Speaker 0: It's a good thinking.
Speaker 0: I wasn't even thinking along those lines.
Speaker 0: That's a great idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I want that for Android.
Speaker 1: I want the option of just sending video I take as soon as is possible to some cloud server.
Speaker 0: Well, that's what it does.
Speaker 0: So along all those lines they vastly improved this situation in the way I wanted to.
Speaker 0: but There's one problem, which is this whole deal with the the music Matt iTunes match.
Speaker 0: Have you have you read about this?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well say here's how it works.
Speaker 1: Everyone's got something like this now.
Speaker 0: Well, no, here's the way it works Right with Google or Amazon cloud, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say I have a CD I ripped or music I pirated from the Pirate Bay and I want to you know Sink it in the cloud.
Speaker 0: Well with Google or Amazon I can just upload it to the cloud.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it's that's it.
Speaker 0: Even if it's pirated.
Speaker 0: They don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: Yep, theoretically Google claims to have the right to remove pirated material.
Speaker 1: sure if it's pirated Amazon just says whatever as far as I don't care.
Speaker 0: So the what Apple's doing is there this is they got one angle on it, which is technological.
Speaker 0: That's a pretty good angle.
Speaker 0: But the other angle which is anti piracy.
Speaker 0: It's a bad angle, right?
Speaker 0: So the good angle is this you don't have to actually upload the music which could admittedly take a long time if you're not like rim with the fires right at my house, it would take forever.
Speaker 0: and Instead what they'll do is you pay $25 a year, which is pricing that I like.
Speaker 0: That's my Scott's kind of pricing.
Speaker 0: I'll pay that shit.
Speaker 1: double digits per year is pretty much what I want to pay for everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah and Then they will scan your music collection and it will see.
Speaker 0: you know using whatever logic it wants if any of your music Matches music that's in iTunes.
Speaker 0: and if the music's in iTunes Then it will put that iTunes music.
Speaker 0: make that available to you via the iCloud.
Speaker 0: so so if I have buy a CD in the store and I rip it and I have iTunes scan it for $25 a year then all that music from not the not the music from the CD But the music from iTunes would basically be added to my account sort of.
Speaker 1: so I take my whole CD collection Run it through and then sell my CD collection for like five bucks to someone who does the same thing, right?
Speaker 0: now here's what I'm waiting for.
Speaker 0: when is somebody gonna figure out how to fool this matching system?
Speaker 0: and there'll be a thing you can Get from Pirate Bay that gives you every song on iTunes.
Speaker 0: That'll be awesome for 25 bucks a year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then we'll see what Apple does.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: But how awesome would that be though, right?
Speaker 0: That's what they should do.
Speaker 0: is they should just be like look 25 bucks a year.
Speaker 0: You get everything.
Speaker 0: That's what they should do because who would not pay the $25 a year.
Speaker 0: They could make it $100 a year.
Speaker 1: I would pay that.
Speaker 0: who would not pay $500 a year?
Speaker 0: I would pay $500 for all the music in iTunes a hundred percent of it anytime you want on any device.
Speaker 1: Hell, you know what?
Speaker 1: I would even pay that if you had if there was a separate higher tier you had to pay for that to get me like.
Speaker 1: basically Music that's new isn't in the lower tier for even six months.
Speaker 1: Who cares?
Speaker 0: The thing is I realize the vast majority of the music I have is not in iTunes.
Speaker 0: It's like really they're gonna have.
Speaker 0: you know, it's for anybody soundtrack created even available yet Yeah, but it's like Creative Commons music Foreign music old weird music.
Speaker 1: Yep, you know not a lot of gemendo music which is all free.
Speaker 0: None of that is in there.
Speaker 0: But the thing is it's still worth it.
Speaker 0: If just if you have just 25 songs a year So the second year you would need 50 songs.
Speaker 0: But if you have that many songs that are not in iTunes then it's worth it to pay for it and I'm sure everyone here has at least a few hundred songs that it would.
Speaker 0: that would match if They met.
Speaker 0: if you have that many that match it's worth it to pay the $25 a year for many years.
Speaker 0: So I'll probably end up paying it even though I'm waiting for them to use this data from scanning people's music collections This they could use it in good ways in bad ways bad ways detecting piracy.
Speaker 0: Yep good ways.
Speaker 0: What's actually pop figuring out what's popular?
Speaker 0: Hey, look at this we've noticed like the superhero be in like hundreds of All these people with superhero be in the u.s.
Speaker 0: My team, uh, who's that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, what the fuck is it Lloyd?
Speaker 0: Oh, maybe we should add that to the iTunes, you know.
Speaker 0: And maybe they could do good thing.
Speaker 0: and then what would happen?
Speaker 0: as soon as they added it to iTunes?
Speaker 0: Then it would start.
Speaker 0: everyone who had it would hit a match Alright, so that'd be pretty good.
Speaker 0: But yeah, they they were 90% of the way there but they're not a hundred percent of the way.
Speaker 0: They're a hundred percent of the way there would be.
Speaker 0: let me upload my obscure music into the cloud and don't worry You know ignore my pirating ways.
Speaker 1: Oh Amazon, maybe Google now, you know.
Speaker 0: But the thing is, you know, the iOS isn't gonna work so well with the Amazon and the Google.
Speaker 1: Yeah Look your latitude barely even works.
Speaker 0: Not a latitude works.
Speaker 0: I know it doesn't.
Speaker 1: you're not on ever.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: I'm not here to a while ago.
Speaker 1: What I'm on we talking about doesn't even sure where you are right now.
Speaker 1: What I gotta go check that's that's what you get for using an Apple product anyway.
Speaker 1: So I'm sure everyone's aware of lull sec and that I love lull sec.
Speaker 0: Oh kukaku Did you not?
Speaker 1: because they're nothing there no one.
Speaker 1: and yet people think there's someone but yet they're doing things.
Speaker 0: No, she's no one doing things and it's like the cult of the dead cow.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's great but one tiny thing that came out of all sec that I do want to point out is that They're basically attacking everybody.
Speaker 1: and hey, they went after Nintendo.
Speaker 1: Nintendo said on Sunday over the weekend that They'd been hacked but that no company or customer information was compromised at all.
Speaker 0: What were they gonna compromise?
Speaker 1: Well, and this is why I say props to you Nintendo.
Speaker 1: You have avoided being attacked by lull sec in any substantial way by not actually having any online services.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what are they supposed to attack?
Speaker 1: I mean, they don't even keep your credit card.
Speaker 1: You got to type the fucking number and every time you buy anything.
Speaker 0: The one thing though is you know these hacks against Sony and whatever are all trying to get personal data.
Speaker 0: And this is the one thing that still bothers me Even though it's a step up from what we had before right where people just try to hack you to make botnets.
Speaker 1: Well, though before before I would hack my friends and then open their CD tray while we were playing quake, right?
Speaker 1: No, but the point is and then sniping them.
Speaker 0: people have just been hacking for profit, right?
Speaker 0: Now they're hacking to embarrass companies and get personal information, right?
Speaker 0: Where are the people who are hacking Maliciously, I want to see.
Speaker 0: so, you know, you know don't?
Speaker 0: when you hack Sony, right?
Speaker 0: You shouldn't be getting their personal information and shaming them.
Speaker 0: That's that's pretty good.
Speaker 0: That's pretty good.
Speaker 0: It's all about I gotta.
Speaker 0: I got a better idea.
Speaker 0: Why don't you make all the games free for everybody?
Speaker 0: That would be awesome, right?
Speaker 0: do that And I'll be fucking impressed.
Speaker 0: and you know next time you hack some people's computers Don't?
Speaker 0: just you know, put some key lager on there and try to get their passwords to their Facebooks, right?
Speaker 0: How about you erase the fucking hard drive like a badass because nobody wants to do that shit anymore.
Speaker 1: Remember, there's no Hierarchical organization.
Speaker 1: all second things like it are just the.
Speaker 1: you know The simmer last similar lacquer coming out of the internet the aid of the internet the collective Movement of individual actors altogether goes to the shell.
Speaker 1: blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: most people Despite all appearances are not total dicks.
Speaker 0: I got his what you know, there was that recent Mac thing Mac defender.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right where they should have done They should have made the Mac defender, right?
Speaker 0: If you got it then it would try to you know Mac defend or offend all the Macs nearby for a certain amount of time and then Destroy the Mac that it's on and then that would cause Apple so much trouble.
Speaker 0: It would be so glorious.
Speaker 0: I just want to see someone do something really malicious and really damaging not because I wish ill upon people Right, but because it's possible.
Speaker 0: Scott it hasn't occurred.
Speaker 0: counter-argument and I want to see what happens.
Speaker 1: counter-argument.
Speaker 1: Is that not the same thing?
Speaker 1: Aside from the we actually want to see it that we say about terrorism.
Speaker 1: smart engineers could cause terrorism Trivially if they wanted to but this doesn't easy to do right, but no one does it.
Speaker 1: But why?
Speaker 1: the same reason nobody deletes some poor old guy's computer for no reason because the people who are capable of doing so Not evil yeah.
Speaker 1: Well sec and things like it look at the way that these I keep wanting to call them organizations because we don't have good words for these things.
Speaker 1: When things like this when simulacra like this Aggregors like this go out and do stuff.
Speaker 1: They're a collective will.
Speaker 1: the collective will seems to be primarily concerned with funny pictures of cats.
Speaker 1: Yep making people angry without hurting them substantially, yep, and Being socially activist for the things that geeks and nerds care about.
Speaker 1: yep So those things together mean shame a company like Sony because Sony is a long history of being dicks about things like DRM.
Speaker 0: Still I would really like to see you know The I sort of science fiction story of geeks conquer the world basically hold the world for ransom.
Speaker 0: We're in charge now all evil politicians.
Speaker 1: You have five hours.
Speaker 1: Let's get the fuck out in high school nerds rule.
Speaker 1: now I don't even know if I have it.
Speaker 1: It's probably on one of those dead hard drives.
Speaker 1: I wrote a short story that I didn't finish those about that.
Speaker 1: It was about that.
Speaker 1: it was for a class like the beginning of it And then I tried to finish it, and then I just I don't know what happened to it.
Speaker 1: But the premise was it needs a movie.
Speaker 1: the premise was that the internet one day declares sovereignty You know like imagine 4chan declaring sovereignty yep, and demanding a seat at the UN and of course everyone ignores it And then like a month later declares war in the world.
Speaker 1: it gives an ultimatum and when that is ignored obviously A shopping cart full of gallon jugs of milk gets simultaneously thrown into every intersection of every major city in the world.
Speaker 0: I know you love that one That's your favorite.
Speaker 1: and then the internet announces that it did that and that it wants to and then you know it goes from there.
Speaker 1: Yep, yeah, anyway anyway, but anyway.
Speaker 1: That was a while things of the day.
Speaker 1: So there's a movie that Scott loves that I had not seen.
Speaker 1: Emily not seen until recently.
Speaker 1: Robert Redford Paul Newman some of the data about a con, man It's like everything rim likes in a movie.
Speaker 1: I can't believe I hadn't seen this movie.
Speaker 0: I kept telling you watch if he took so long Do what I say immediately.
Speaker 1: the sting is a fantastic movie, and if you like heist movies.
Speaker 1: It's way up there I'll say it's a con.
Speaker 0: It's not a heist.
Speaker 1: yeah Well the thing is is a con not simply a form of heist?
Speaker 0: no It's not.
Speaker 1: has all the elements of a heist movie.
Speaker 1: the big gang that gets together do the really complex Payoff, but they're not robbing something.
Speaker 0: They are tricking a person.
Speaker 0: right It's it's a heist.
Speaker 0: is physic is about is about the physicality of breaking in to some hardened structure.
Speaker 0: It's about.
Speaker 0: it's about buildings and architecture, and you know explosives and drills like you know.
Speaker 0: I can die hard right.
Speaker 0: but You know a con is all about trickery and manipulation and acting and putting on Disguises and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: It's you know the the.
Speaker 0: the execution of it is a completely different skill set completely.
Speaker 1: You know anyway the movies great, and I'm you know if you've watched any number of movies You'll figure out what the fullness of the whole thing is and it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: if you've read the lives of Locke Lamora I'm Pretty sure Scott Lynch saw this movie and cribbed from it.
Speaker 1: It's too close.
Speaker 0: You don't say And three.
Speaker 1: it'll give you a ton of inside jokes.
Speaker 1: For we almost watched this other movie called alphaville that many people have seen and commented on how they should watch it in Netflix.
Speaker 1: Don't watch it the ball.
Speaker 0: I couldn't finish it.
Speaker 0: so who knows what has the plot.
Speaker 0: I'll probably finish it at some point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I want to know what the deal is but the plot is as such.
Speaker 1: There's a really hard-boiled detective guy report.
Speaker 1: He works for newspaper Yeah in a noir futurist setting and every five minutes someone comes out of a closet with a gun comes out of the closet.
Speaker 1: So anyway my thing of the day other than the fact that it was weird to see Robert Redford looking young and kind of Brad Pitt ish I'm used to seeing him very old is a is a time waster.
Speaker 1: on Wikipedia This will take about an hour of your life away.
Speaker 1: It is the Wikipedia page that lists confidence tricks.
Speaker 1: so if you've ever heard the term pigeon drop or the Spanish prisoner or The wire or the pig in the poke or the badger game You'll learn all about them, and there's a lot of links to follow.
Speaker 0: you could learn everything on the internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you've read American gods you probably know some of these.
Speaker 0: all right, so rim you ready for this right?
Speaker 0: Have you ever heard of Capricars operation?
Speaker 0: nope all right?
Speaker 0: You ready?
Speaker 0: Take any four digit number, but the four digits can't all be the same.
Speaker 1: so I picked one one one one fine One one two.
Speaker 0: you can't all right.
Speaker 0: one one one two is fine.
Speaker 0: You just can't do one one one one all right.
Speaker 0: Okay, now rearrange the digits right to make the biggest number You can make and also the smallest number.
Speaker 0: so for your number one one one two.
Speaker 0: the biggest number you can make Two one one one and the smallest is one one two.
Speaker 0: Subtract the smaller one from the bigger one all right What's the?
Speaker 0: what's your result there?
Speaker 0: 999 not oh zero nine nine nine.
Speaker 0: yeah, right, okay?
Speaker 0: Take Zero nine nine nine.
Speaker 0: yeah, right and repeat Capricars operation again.
Speaker 0: So take the biggest thing you can possibly make and subtract from it the smallest thing you could possibly make.
Speaker 0: so nine nine nine zero minus zero.
Speaker 0: nine nine nine.
Speaker 1: Wait nine nine one.
Speaker 0: eight nine nine one.
Speaker 0: okay?
Speaker 0: Do it a few more times.
Speaker 1: if I recurse this it's gonna get me back where I was.
Speaker 0: no not at all.
Speaker 0: I Guarantee recurse it up a few times.
Speaker 0: keep doing it.
Speaker 0: Just real quick all right I'll just give you a minute there.
Speaker 0: Eventually what's gonna happen is you arrive at a number and once you arrive at that number?
Speaker 0: You will arrive at that number every time because that number if you perform Capricars operation on it results in itself yet again.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh so far.
Speaker 1: I haven't hit that yet.
Speaker 1: I've gone through about four iterations in my.
Speaker 0: it might take a few more.
Speaker 0: It's it it will happen.
Speaker 1: so is it always the same number?
Speaker 1: is that the deal?
Speaker 0: it is absolutely always the same number.
Speaker 0: I've written that number on this piece of paper.
Speaker 0: How much would you like to bet that I am correct or not?
Speaker 1: well you see?
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure that since you probably just looked this up that you know the number already And I trust mathematicians to be accurate.
Speaker 1: so the smart part of my brain says to bet Negative ten dollars.
Speaker 1: Do you accept my bet?
Speaker 0: no?
Speaker 0: It must be if I will bet a positive amount of money that I am correct any negative amount of money that That you and I have.
Speaker 0: you arrived at the number yet?
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: it's kind of tedious actually to do this since I got a microphone in front of me but anyway the number is Six thousand one hundred and seventy four.
Speaker 0: uh-huh how fucked up is that?
Speaker 0: so this website?
Speaker 0: Explains to you.
Speaker 0: Why this is true.
Speaker 1: does it have pictures?
Speaker 0: it has many pictures and charts and proofs and tables and graphs and It's actually Pretty incredible And it's sort of freaking me out, but why is it six one seven four?
Speaker 1: Why is it pie?
Speaker 1: Why is it e?
Speaker 0: I know right, but it's something about six one E to the pie.
Speaker 1: I oh Shit, oh shit.
Speaker 0: I think that this is the bride the fifth most fucked up thing in math after Either the pie.
Speaker 0: I is always gonna be the winner.
Speaker 0: This is mysterious number six one seven four by you Taka Nishiyama a very smart, man.
Speaker 1: So you know what I'll bet if you're ever trying to break into a nerd's locker.
Speaker 0: six one seven four Whoa New pin number everybody.
Speaker 0: I believe you mean pin dun dun dun for the ATM machine.
Speaker 0: yeah Automatic ATM machine all right, it's it's.
Speaker 0: it's metamoment all right.
Speaker 1: So you know you many people saw.
Speaker 1: I uploaded it without much fanfare last night.
Speaker 1: for a long time I've been hinting that we may have made a spin-off show that was in Production and you took and you took way too long.
Speaker 0: you said you were gonna have it out weeks ago Yep,
Speaker 1: and I ran into a lot of trouble partly because all the very high-quality sources that I downloaded in torrents have really washed out color in them and the YouTube versions and the TV versions have the correct colors and FFD show.
Speaker 1: I can use that to convert them to the correct colors, but that was very anyway.
Speaker 0: The point is is that you don't know how to do things quickly.
Speaker 1: I was also busy doing other things like the fact that you know I'm scheduling every panel for kinetic on and such.
Speaker 1: Also, we brought it out kind of right as the the pony Love was starting to not not fade But falter and slumber and wait for the following season.
Speaker 1: the updates were drying up the PMVs were slowing down and suddenly Oh shit, it's radio free equestria coming to you live from the everfree forest.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Scott and I started a legit my little pony video show.
Speaker 0: we'll see how it goes.
Speaker 1: we have one pilot up Uploaded last night with very little fanfare.
Speaker 1: It got a surprising number of video views almost immediately.
Speaker 1: a lot of positive commentary Mmm, so we'll see where this goes.
Speaker 1: every other week probably to start the show will go up and then as soon as I have the production process down it'll go to every week and If the pilots are all successful and you people like this we will see about making it a much more legit show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 0: you know plus it depends how long pony I mean if the show ever ends It's like how we supposed to.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean of course many of those Firefly podcasts are going to this fucking day.
Speaker 0: I know right.
Speaker 0: I don't understand How.
Speaker 0: like what do you say?
Speaker 1: and also Sweden had a bowel movement this Harry Potter podcast and shit - yeah But there's still Harry Potter stuff.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 0: no there's no more books are there though.
Speaker 1: No no more book and more movies.
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: I don't know or care about Harry Potter Spoiler sites cuz I hate the Harry Potter writing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we don't.
Speaker 1: Yeah, radio-free equestria.
Speaker 0: Oh other other metas kinetic ons coming up.
Speaker 0: Yep You but how's the e-commerce?
Speaker 0: go in there and it's going fine everything.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna ship actually tomorrow.
Speaker 1: All right every pending order which?
Speaker 1: and the international order?
Speaker 1: people should tomorrow get invoices Which will start a whole process that hopefully ends up in them getting t-shirts.
Speaker 1: All right The book club book is still Isaac Asimov's Foundation.
Speaker 1: yep, no official book club book is still the all of the our Scott backer prints of nothing books.
Speaker 0: Recess nerd NYC racist is Saturday the 18th of June game hack days in New York and June 25th and 26.
Speaker 0: Yep, I just search for game hack.
Speaker 1: We might not be at the recess.
Speaker 1: We might be doing our own thing.
Speaker 0: That doesn't mean you shouldn't go to recess.
Speaker 0: However, if you go to recess and I don't know maybe if we don't start dragging out this meta moment I'm trying to just go through it real quick like You keep adding all these add stuff to keep adding all these details.
Speaker 0: the show is already long.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: it is okay.
Speaker 0: I think that's all the meta there is.
Speaker 1: is it all the meta there is?
Speaker 1: Good friend of ours talked about on the show a while ago going in a massive Many mile bike ride with the team easy riders to support the funding to hopefully try to get rid of Lou Gehrig's disease.
Speaker 1: Okay, good luck with that good friend of ours who also happens to be planning to walk around the world Mmm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So if you want to support this at all I would highly recommend you donate a small amount of money to his cause or a large amount if you have it All right.
Speaker 0: Do you have a URL for that shit?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I'll post the URL All right Which means you have to go to the site if you want to get the URL which is Also the site that has our awesome forum, which you should join.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're not gonna ask you for money for us.
Speaker 0: Well, that's for money for other people instead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe we'll kickstart if we want to do another show because of one last announcement.
Speaker 1: We you know radio free equestria is finally going.
Speaker 1: once the crank machine is going we have another show that's in the works.
Speaker 0: third show We're doing a lot.
Speaker 1: We're trying to ramp up the game.
Speaker 1: geek nights will always be here, but We reserve the right to possibly make money off of other non geek nights things.
Speaker 0: They'll still be creative comes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much Anyway anyway, so it's warm real warm lately.
Speaker 1: So we thought we'd talk about computer cooling because we've never actually talked about that.
Speaker 0: specifically We talk about overclocking which I think we covered a lot of cooling some up our overclocking episode.
Speaker 1: It's no longer a good idea.
Speaker 1: What the fuck you doing you fanboy?
Speaker 0: Yeah Just you know.
Speaker 0: to sum that up in a couple more sentences your hobbyist and go nuts, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if your goal is to just have fun overclocking.
Speaker 0: well go nuts, right?
Speaker 0: But if you want to overclock for performance, that's just a bad idea.
Speaker 0: nowadays There's no reason to.
Speaker 0: you could just get a better CPU.
Speaker 0: also if you have a normal computer There's really no reason to ever use anything but the heatsink that comes with the CPU.
Speaker 0: right there.
Speaker 0: in my Intel every Intel chip I've ever bought comes with the heatsink.
Speaker 0: that heatsink is perfectly fine.
Speaker 0: It's quiet.
Speaker 0: It works.
Speaker 0: if you're having trouble with it It's probably cuz you have a stupid case and that leads us into the current show.
Speaker 1: So let's talk about cases.
Speaker 1: pretty much there is no longer any goddamn reason to get a full tower.
Speaker 1: No that the last full tower I bought was the previous computer I owned.
Speaker 1: it was a gigantic tower because I set up.
Speaker 1: I put a ton of hard drives in it.
Speaker 1: I even got to the point where if I wanted to add more hard drives I was gonna put in a second power supply just for the hard drive and raid them all together.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: by the time I got that going computer technology moved along so fast.
Speaker 1: It didn't even matter anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but nowadays right it's like you can move all your hard drives.
Speaker 0: You only need one hard drive in the computer probably solid-state I would.
Speaker 1: you can put I would argue you want to you know one solid-state drive.
Speaker 1: that usually won't be that big and you put Your OS on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you need a second hard drive.
Speaker 1: Just get the biggest fucking cheap drive ever for local storage.
Speaker 1: Like I'm editing video.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna edit video.
Speaker 1: That's all stored on an Ethernet net.
Speaker 0: No if you're editing video put it on the fucking solid-state where it's the fastest.
Speaker 0: Well, you got to get big ones.
Speaker 1: you got to see you're gonna spend a 64 gig one wouldn't be big enough.
Speaker 0: If you're not you gotta get the 128 first of all wouldn't be big enough.
Speaker 0: two of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna spend that much.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: Yeah, these games are actually not big enough to justify their rear real big.
Speaker 1: For the kinds of video editing you're better.
Speaker 0: That's your editing a video.
Speaker 0: You just get the whole video in RAM while you're editing you only write it to disk when you're saving it.
Speaker 1: Ah The most RAM I've ever had in a workstation is Bob 24 gigs.
Speaker 0: That's enough Depends.
Speaker 0: The point is is that you don't need really that many drives in your computer.
Speaker 0: You definitely don't need optical drive anymore.
Speaker 0: You definitely don't need more than one video card.
Speaker 1: If you're a performance nut have one solid-state drive.
Speaker 1: Just the OS.
Speaker 1: two Cheap hard drives just for like local scratch face working storage.
Speaker 1: Like I downloaded a bunch of shit.
Speaker 1: I'm working on it, you know torrent whatever.
Speaker 1: just make a raid zero or raid one doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: And if the drives crash who cares you?
Speaker 1: just replace them cheap And then buy a super cheap NAS.
Speaker 1: I got a netgear NAS.
Speaker 1: I can see it from here.
Speaker 1: It's got two two terabyte hard drives in it and they're just rated together perfectly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I lose the drive just pop another one.
Speaker 1: every populates gigabit Ethernet shared everywhere.
Speaker 1: It has some problems just because it's consumer grade shit.
Speaker 0: But you gotta get a higher quality.
Speaker 1: those problems are all related to the administration of the thing not to the performance of the thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway, you know the point is you don't really need a big computer anymore.
Speaker 0: But a lot of people have taken this to the extreme and they try to get small computers, right?
Speaker 1: Well, don't get a micro ATX unless you're making a HD PC.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like a lot of you know, I can understand the desire to get something like, you know, that's Mac mini sized, right?
Speaker 0: Because small and quiet is just so awesome.
Speaker 1: If you don't need performance go for that.
Speaker 0: just buy the mag, right?
Speaker 0: But you got to keep in mind if you.
Speaker 0: well you can buy the Mac mini itself sure But if you want to build something really small make sure you keep it really weak.
Speaker 0: a lot of people I've noticed because they can And because they sell these parts have been putting full power computers inside a very tiny case.
Speaker 1: now you can do that But you need to really ramp up the cooling which is gonna make the thing fucking loud Which defeats the purpose of having a computer in your living room.
Speaker 1: and why else would you want a tiny computer?
Speaker 0: Yeah, just get you know a mid tower or just you know, they have these sort of half-ish mid towers.
Speaker 0: Those are those are good enough mid towers pretty much what you want.
Speaker 1: I would argue.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's definitely good, you know while it might be a little bigger than say one of those like half-towery things but you can still get away with it was.
Speaker 0: it's so much easier even though it's mostly empty air and The cooling is just gonna work and it's gonna be so quiet and you can still put it underneath your desk where it won't get In the way, so who cares now, I wouldn't?
Speaker 0: it's cheap.
Speaker 1: I used to also get a full tower because I had a bunch of shit in the front of my computer like, you know My DVD drive my CD burner my no one has any that shit drive.
Speaker 0: It's not just all gone.
Speaker 1: It was in front of my computer a $10 DVD burner.
Speaker 1: It burns every possible format.
Speaker 0: It's super fast and you never use it.
Speaker 1: I burned an ISO a Month ago to rebuild a server to put counter-strike.
Speaker 0: I use USB sticks for that.
Speaker 1: Ah, this this is a computer you gave me.
Speaker 1: the USB is broken.
Speaker 0: No shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's a reason I got rid of that computer and you know what.
Speaker 1: that computer didn't have an optical drive.
Speaker 1: I had to pull mine out and plug it into that one snap.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so, uh, very simply though, you know get a mid-tower get a reasonable, you know Get like an Intel chip or even if you get an AMD chip just use the default cooler Don't?
Speaker 0: a lot of people buy like these fancy coolers the thing coolers that look fancy.
Speaker 0: They're usually a bad idea, right?
Speaker 0: They're just bigger and stupider and they cost extra money and they probably use more electricity and they make more noise Whether or not they actually cool the thing down.
Speaker 0: and also, you know, a lot of people try to excessively cool, right?
Speaker 0: It's like as long as your CPU is always within the recommended operating temperature It doesn't need to be any colder.
Speaker 0: being colder isn't really gonna help you, right?
Speaker 0: It's like oh my compete my CPU is running at 70 and now it's running at 50.
Speaker 0: It's like well with 70 within the limits.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, well then what the fuck's the problem?
Speaker 1: and also I mean, alright It's not gonna go faster now not gonna cool it loads.
Speaker 0: I told you not to overclock.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna cool it lower than the ambient temperature with a heatsink.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: So fans get big fans.
Speaker 1: big slow fans are better than small fast fans.
Speaker 1: any goddamn day.
Speaker 0: Yep, because a big fan have one like Gigantic fan or two gigantic fans one of the front one of the back.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, I got a standard antique case.
Speaker 1: It's got two pretty big fans in the front intake one Gigantic fan in the top and then it's got the power supply fan.
Speaker 1: That's it What works great.
Speaker 0: the reason gigantic fans are so much better than small fans Right is because it's all about how many cubic centimeters of air it pushes per unit time.
Speaker 1: But also small fans.
Speaker 0: they can push the same amount of air, but that means they have to spin faster Which means they're louder.
Speaker 1: Yes, and they were out.
Speaker 0: loudness is come almost entirely determined by how what the rpms are.
Speaker 0: So a big fan at low rpm pushes the same amount of air at a small fan at higher rpm.
Speaker 0: Which is why a bigger fan is better because it can provide the same amount of cooling with less noise and less Spinach, right?
Speaker 0: So big fans always win if you can.
Speaker 1: so you have a case and a CPU and a motherboard.
Speaker 1: really not CPU But a motherboard that supports it.
Speaker 1: use dynamic fans and then you know set the hardware switches as low as they can go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my fans speed up if my computer is actually overheating.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's pretty easy to set that up.
Speaker 1: Just actually read the documentation.
Speaker 1: Don't bother with the additional side blowhole whale fan unless your case is overheating like for example, if you have a Gigantic set of video cards or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you shouldn't really have those because they're waste of money.
Speaker 0: But then again, if I want a lottery and I was building a computer I might be tempted to get like for and video or for example.
Speaker 0: So get there's.
Speaker 0: I got so much money working with video.
Speaker 1: Right if I am rendering a video from for like radio free equestria took about an hour to render that right?
Speaker 1: My computer heated up substantially and hot air was blowing uncomfortably out of the area where my computer is.
Speaker 1: hmm and The you know could have caused a problem if I was rendering like a hundred things in a row over a weekend while I was Out of town.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I'm thinking about getting the side fan But only get the side fan if you need it because it's gonna add loudness Lot of loudness and loudness is the thing I care about more than almost anything.
Speaker 1: Yep They'll arrange your cables.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of people they don't know how to arrange your cables properly and it can sometimes be tricky depending on what parts you Get how long their cables are what your case is like.
Speaker 1: it's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: It'll take you forever And if you're not good at it.
Speaker 1: You're probably gonna have to tear it all out and do it again after you're done.
Speaker 1: And this is another
Speaker 0: reason for the mid tower because while the mid tower you don't need all that space for the actual computer because Your computer is gonna like be like a tiny speck inside that big box That gives you a lot of places to hide and squish and stow all these Cables that aren't being used and you're just getting in the way for much more efficient cooling Right.
Speaker 0: So that's why you get the mid tower Even if your computer could fit in something like half or a quarter of the size.
Speaker 1: Luckily, it's becoming mood because no one needs, you know, serial ATA cables anymore.
Speaker 1: Well parallel ATA cables Yeah, and serial ATA cables are tiny.
Speaker 1: Yeah used to be that you needed ribbon cables or if you were fancy you'd break a ribbon cable up and then band it together.
Speaker 0: It's mostly all about the the power supply cables.
Speaker 1: I know we really need a better solution.
Speaker 0: Well, they do have.
Speaker 0: there are some power supplies that where you could actually fuck that You know what?
Speaker 1: I want.
Speaker 1: you know what I want.
Speaker 1: I want there to be a standard like ATX for cases where cases include buses.
Speaker 1: Yeah You put you slide the power supply in.
Speaker 1: there are bus bars and wires.
Speaker 1: in the case you slide the hard drive hard drive can Closure in.
Speaker 1: it has ports for the power for the hard drives just built in.
Speaker 1: why the fuck don't we have that?
Speaker 0: It's 2011 cuz it would.
Speaker 0: you know, cuz it's a little bit.
Speaker 0: It's a less flexible.
Speaker 0: You know, I do it that way All right.
Speaker 1: Wait, how is it less flexible though?
Speaker 0: So let's say you have a slot for a hard drive, right?
Speaker 0: Well, it's an SAT hard drive.
Speaker 0: So it's got the SAT a plugs.
Speaker 0: But what if I want to put it on if I have a regular old hard drive?
Speaker 0: My motherboard supports it.
Speaker 1: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you see here's this is where they're probably leave.
Speaker 1: You leave a legacy port in the bottom or something, right?
Speaker 0: So that was a useless slot in my computer.
Speaker 0: I want to add another SAT a but there isn't one.
Speaker 1: it was not that long ago.
Speaker 1: My computer had an ISA slot.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying it's like now.
Speaker 0: I've got one more SAT a drive.
Speaker 1: But my case has a built-in non SAT a slot and also if you make the standard to start then people start supporting it and eventually you get to the point where everything does it.
Speaker 1: Then you just drop the ISA slot.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying is that you know, it's significantly lower.
Speaker 1: Distribution inside of consumer PCs that are built by nerds has not gotten better in 20 years?
Speaker 0: No, not really.
Speaker 0: and there were the power supplies to let you remove the cables You weren't using but those for some reason never caught on that.
Speaker 1: now The only reason I'm not super mad about it is that in the old days?
Speaker 1: I'd open my computer up surprisingly often for various reasons.
Speaker 1: Yep I haven't reopened my computer down there since I built it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm times have changed and they're better.
Speaker 1: So there's no market for what I just said.
Speaker 1: But if I were like Dell or gateway like his game if I was Dell I would do that on my own for my own piece.
Speaker 0: Well, they basically sort of do right is you know?
Speaker 1: They do a lot of good stuff.
Speaker 1: if you they have not gotten to the point of integrating bus bars with the case.
Speaker 0: No, I don't think it's just not economical now, but it would.
Speaker 1: it might be in the long run I could make a case for it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the other thing right is that it's all about you want to have more intake.
Speaker 0: You know people always think about exhaust fans like this hot air.
Speaker 0: I got to push it out of the computer.
Speaker 0: Well, no You also need to bring in the cold air.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 1: bringing in air is better for two very obvious reasons.
Speaker 1: one if you put filters On your intakes, there's no dust in your computer.
Speaker 0: now if you usually yeah positive pressure is more important than filters, right?
Speaker 1: So well, I'm not up because if you have positive pressure and filters, you're all set.
Speaker 1: No dust gets in.
Speaker 1: if you have positive pressure and no filters your computer is still gonna fill with dust.
Speaker 1: But if you have negative pressure The dust is going to be sucked in through your optical drive that you hardly ever use.
Speaker 1: and the one time you put a DVD In it, it's not gonna work.
Speaker 1: It's covered in dust.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's odd.
Speaker 0: the reason, you know dust in your computer probably won't actually ruin your computer.
Speaker 0: But what it will do is it'll make the you know, it'll get in the fans It'll get on the heat sinks and make them heat let you know cool less efficiently.
Speaker 1: But if you have negative pressure and no filters and you don't have any optical drives or anything It is arguable that there is no effective difference.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so positive pressure What that means is that the air pressure inside your case right is greater than the air pressure of the room.
Speaker 0: So greater than what atmosphere?
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: you do this usually by having intake fans that are Bringing in a lot more air than the exhaust fans are exhausting out, right?
Speaker 0: You still need exhaust fans To in the areas where the air is the hottest like right near the CPU to blow out the hottest of airs in the computer.
Speaker 0: But the intake fans are bringing in cool air probably from the front of your computer just the air in your room.
Speaker 0: So they're bringing in room temperature air, which is gonna be cooler than what's in the computer.
Speaker 0: So they bring in more room temperature air then the hot air that you're blowing out.
Speaker 0: That's gonna keep the temperature low And also the fact that the inside the case the pressure is higher than it is outside the case Dust can't get in because there's basically air.
Speaker 0: come all the seams in your computer cuz it's not airtight Right all the seams all around the optical drive all around the edges of the case air is gonna become getting pushed out Sort of like when you stand next to a doorway and the room on the other side has different pressure and like a wind coming Out of this cracked open doorway.
Speaker 0: your case will be like that and dust won't get inside Which is totally awesome.
Speaker 0: And if you don't have that you get it wrong.
Speaker 1: dust will get in through the main fans in taking air if you don't have Filters on them.
Speaker 0: Yes, obviously, but the point is if you set it up, right?
Speaker 0: There won't be any dust in your computer, you know hot air will be getting pushed out.
Speaker 0: cool They're will be getting pushed in to be totally awesome.
Speaker 0: If you have negative pressure you fucked up.
Speaker 1: if you don't have the discipline to clean your filters Don't bother with filters just once a month.
Speaker 1: open your computer and air, you know, just air dust it all out.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Uh That's mostly it.
Speaker 1: I mean don't put your computer in a cupboard Yeah, don't smoke In your house ever ever ruin your computer.
Speaker 0: Yep Now there's also bother with any weird fancy cooling.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah water cooling right.
Speaker 0: so water cooling if you do make it work It is kind of cool because it makes no noise.
Speaker 1: Yeah, dude, well and he keeps everything say it makes no noise, but most people I've seen it makes no noise except for the pump.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well you can get.
Speaker 0: you can get some of these, you know quiet pumps.
Speaker 0: and you know I've seen water cooling systems where you may be here.
Speaker 0: It sounds like a fish tank.
Speaker 0: It's a quiet bubbling.
Speaker 0: It's actually soothing Yeah, or I've heard completely quiet ones as well get around.
Speaker 0: you can try like heat pipe things Lots of stuff that you can do and it actually works.
Speaker 1: They're really only do these things if you're a hobbyist.
Speaker 1: exactly Are you gonna make very very specific need if you're making case mods or like say you're made you're making a computer.
Speaker 1: That's gonna be inside of a recording studio for whatever reason and it has to be as quiet as possible.
Speaker 1: So you set up an air a water cooling rig where the pipes come from outside the room cool it and go back outside the room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even recording studios don't do that shit.
Speaker 0: They just get really quiet.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends on what you're doing.
Speaker 0: I've never heard of a recording studio doing that.
Speaker 1: Well, usually you're not gonna have a computer in there anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know the thing is is that if you know there are reasons to do water cooling, you know Especially if just you want to do it for fun.
Speaker 1: You go for it liquid nitrogen, but immersion and all that It's fun and silly but don't it's not for any practical purpose.
Speaker 0: It's completely pointless and unnecessary because there is no consumer computer that you can't cool with just normal old fans and heat sinks.
Speaker 0: in a good case Right the old water cooling is only necessary if you're doing something really fancy or you just want to do it for the sake of it.
Speaker 0: Now that covers, you know computers that people have.
Speaker 0: that, you know, they bought and of course most people have.
Speaker 0: you buy laptops.
Speaker 0: You don't have to think about this at all.
Speaker 1: No laptops You have to go one thing one dust your goddamn laptop and don't cover the fan with anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't put it on your rug or your.
Speaker 1: get your Afghan and try to use it.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: Yes, you know a well-designed laptop is gonna cool itself.
Speaker 0: Don't buy a piece of shit laptop that has problems because there's nothing you can do to fix it.
Speaker 0: Just don't if you buy a crappy laptop and they designed it poorly you can't fix it because.
Speaker 1: so one last thing.
Speaker 1: It's more so wasn't for quietness.
Speaker 1: Don't buy a cheap PSU.
Speaker 1: They're way louder than the better ones.
Speaker 1: Just do your research and find what people say and find the quietest PSU you can find.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're you know, the PSU is a fan.
Speaker 1: It counts as an X an output fan.
Speaker 1: So if you're designing a case you want positive pressure, don't forget that the PSU is drawing power out of your case.
Speaker 0: Most of the PSUs though have adjustable fan speeds on them nowadays.
Speaker 0: At least all the ones I've bought recently have little knobs to control the plate the power supply fan speed and the motherboard actually has Ways of controlling this the PSU fan speed as well.
Speaker 1: So let's talk a little bit as you were alluding to to enterprise cooling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I see people need to know this shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean everyone always, you know thinks about cooling their computer in their house, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what nerds do.
Speaker 1: Server usually needs to be about 20% cooler, right?
Speaker 0: But when you've got a you know, it's not just you know a server having a server.
Speaker 0: It's mostly the same as consumer cooling right, but it's all about when you're doing enterprise stuff or at a business.
Speaker 0: You've got racks.
Speaker 0: You've got a lot of servers in the same exact room with not a lot of space between them and it's usually a small room Which means that even though each computer might be designed well for cooling individually The room itself is like a secondary case and that room All the exhaust.
Speaker 0: the hot exhaust comes out of the computers into that room and into the intakes again and basically The whole room heats up.
Speaker 0: and now you've got a problem because how can you cool something with intake fans that are bringing in air?
Speaker 0: That is basically almost as hot as the air that's being exhausted and you're fucked now.
Speaker 1: I was very lucky in my career that I started at IBM and I actually very rapidly came to manage a Relatively small raised floor, you know traditional data center.
Speaker 1: So I learned all this stuff a long time ago and the vast majority of data centers you ever run into at least for the foreseeable Future will be exactly as I described.
Speaker 1: So if you're an IT guy or you're just a guy who wants to know about this stuff I'm going to in maybe five or six minutes tell you everything you need to know about cooling data centers.
Speaker 0: there are conditioners.
Speaker 1: we can't talk about the Fancy like Facebook's data centers or Google's data.
Speaker 0: Actually Facebook's data centers are completely open source and you can totally see videos of them and diagrams of them online.
Speaker 0: And if that's your interest go for it, there are very cool upcoming emerging technologies about data center.
Speaker 0: Yeah basically there are certain plate data centers in the world that are so big and the people running them are so technologically apt that They actually, you know if they can save like one bit of energy It's this because they're so gigantic that saves them a ton of money.
Speaker 0: So they push the envelope of Efficiency of cooling and power usage in their data centers as far as they can possibly go.
Speaker 0: But the vast majority of data centers aren't like that, you know.
Speaker 0: They aren't run by Google or Facebook or someone who's so big.
Speaker 1: So here to make it to make a good analogy for people who might be more code inclined The super future far-out data centers.
Speaker 1: That's the equivalent of writing like a pyramids web app like bleeding-edge brand-new barely documented shit.
Speaker 1: Most data centers all generally follow the same sort of, you know Tried-and-true best practices of cooling even because the people who run like the level of Django like alright kind of fancy But used in a lot of place.
Speaker 0: Well, you get Google does stuff like those, you know data center in a Shipping containers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which you know what is actually not super out there.
Speaker 0: It's still pretty fancy.
Speaker 1: It's fancier than normal stuff, but both the vast majority of data centers are alright.
Speaker 1: You've got Apache running serving up static pages.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So you're gonna have a raised floor if you don't have a raised floor.
Speaker 1: I failed already.
Speaker 0: I really there's a raised floor is basically like the reverse of a drop ceiling, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know a drop ceiling is when you have all these ceiling tiles And if you push a ceiling tile out of the way you go Oh, look, the ceilings actually much higher than the ceiling that I see.
Speaker 0: there's a ceiling in front of the ceiling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you basically got floor tiles and under that is between one and four feet of space.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's like there's a floor and you can actually open the floor and then this room under the floor before there's the All the you know other stuff about raised floors.
Speaker 1: cuz frankly I think we could do a show on raised floor data center man At least I could.
Speaker 0: But as boring as hell we're gonna do a show about floors that are above floor.
Speaker 1: actually, I got a lot to say because it said These are useful IT skills that people don't fucking know in the real world.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah Cuz almost no one has a raise.
Speaker 1: just talk about cooling.
Speaker 1: you'll have huge units usually that pump cold air under the floor.
Speaker 1: So the floor is kind of fairly highly pressurized cold air just being pumped in high pressure.
Speaker 1: Yep, and you'll have rows of servers.
Speaker 1: you spread everything and you break it up into hot aisles and cold aisles.
Speaker 1: So you've got a rack a line of racks a hundred racks all in a row.
Speaker 0: It's a cold.
Speaker 1: Well, no, no, no it separates.
Speaker 1: it's basically the wall between two aisles.
Speaker 1: The servers are all side by side top to bottom in racks The servers and the two aisles that are next to each other the fronts of the servers face each other.
Speaker 1: so all the fronts of the servers on the left rack are Facing in and all the servers on the right rack are facing in.
Speaker 1: So if you stand in the middle of this aisle any direction you look you're gonna see the fronts of servers or more aisle.
Speaker 0: Hmm That's a cold aisle because all the intake fans are on the fronts of the server.
Speaker 0: So they're all into.
Speaker 0: all the servers are in taking the cold air from the cold aisle.
Speaker 1: So in front of every rack is a floor tile that has holes in it.
Speaker 1: Mmm cold air comes up and the servers suck it in.
Speaker 0: so every other now Why now they think you think why would the cold air go up?
Speaker 0: because cold air sinks and hot air rises?
Speaker 0: Well, it's because the hot the cold air is pressurized.
Speaker 0: So it's actually being squeezed out of those holes in the floor and being shot up in front of the servers.
Speaker 1: So the air goes through the servers which are all, you know rack units.
Speaker 1: So they're long thin servers and the air comes out the back.
Speaker 1: The next rows are hot aisles the next aisles and all the backs of servers are facing these.
Speaker 1: So all the hot air that has already cooled these servers down and has now the server heat in it comes into those aisles and Goes up because it goes up and away.
Speaker 0: Yep You have vents or some sort of you know drop ceiling with basically the reverse of the cold floor is up there.
Speaker 0: Maybe you send that air out of the building.
Speaker 0: Maybe you send it back to an air conditioner.
Speaker 0: It's usually easier to send it out of the building and the air conditioner because it would air conditioner to cool The hot air would be more energy than just cool new outside air Which is already colder than the hot.
Speaker 0: it, you know, the heated up air from the CPU.
Speaker 1: So when you're building a rack just fill it Just fill it with servers and more importantly any spot in your rack that doesn't have a server Put a faceplate to block kind of like how on your PC You put a faceplate to block those five and a half inch bays that you never use.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz if you don't put a faceplate to block then some of the cold air from the cold aisle will just shoot straight through the Hot aisle getting completely unused.
Speaker 1: if you have racks put sides on your racks.
Speaker 1: Don't put doors on the front that don't let the air in.
Speaker 0: Yeah I've seen those racks with doors and it's like what the fuck.
Speaker 1: every rack has doors.
Speaker 1: but the thing is you have doors where either they have vents in the side where the air gets in or The fronts of the rack are actually over a hole.
Speaker 1: So there's a door and the cold air is coming up through the inside between the door and the fronts of the server.
Speaker 0: Sometimes though you do want a door because what you'll have is you have a rack unit that doesn't actually have servers.
Speaker 0: that has like.
Speaker 0: You know when those little terminal bits or something like, you know.
Speaker 1: So I could go into all those details, but but you don't leave that for the raised floor.
Speaker 1: data center management show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's.
Speaker 1: but the key is don't put holes in the hot Put faceplates in your racks.
Speaker 1: fill your racks if possible.
Speaker 1: Don't block the intakes with anything.
Speaker 1: Yep That's really all there is to it.
Speaker 1: If the air conditioning unit fails call somebody.
Speaker 1: don't just let it stay failed.
Speaker 1: Don't turn it off because it's loud.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wish that wasn't the advice.
Speaker 0: I felt I needed to give yeah, but big big data centers They do things pretty differently.
Speaker 0: like instead of most of what they the advancements You'll see is like instead of using regular old air conditioners and backup regular old air conditioners They'll have some sort of other cooling system You know that pumps the cold air into the cold isle.
Speaker 0: or they'll have more directed flow like something like, you know They'll use like misters and fans or rulers Yeah, or heat pumps or all sorts of different ways of making the air cold.
Speaker 0: That's more energy efficient.
Speaker 1: or directed flow Like you have ducks coming up out of the floor that basically direct feed the cold air to the individual servers in your rack.
Speaker 0: Yep,
Speaker 1: cool things like that a
Speaker 0: lot of people have tried sometimes You know and it's like the aisles won't actually have any air and what they'll do is all the racks will actually be sort of Sealed from all the sides but not the top and the bottom and they'll pump cold air directly into the bottom of the racks Which are sealed right?
Speaker 0: So the cold air doesn't go into the aisle It only goes into the area where the servers are right.
Speaker 0: and then the cold air is underneath the servers.
Speaker 0: the servers heat it up and it rises out and they'll put the fans on The bottom and the top of the servers instead of in the front.
Speaker 0: in the back All kinds of people try all sorts of weird things.
Speaker 1: So last important thing there too cold is just as bad as too hot.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah Obviously people don't.
Speaker 1: a lot of people keep their data centers way colder than they should because if it's too cold One glitch in the humidity and you've got condensation.
Speaker 1: That's the fucking end.
Speaker 0: Humidity is something, you know, you don't really to think about when you're just you know A normal person with consumer hardware, but humidity in a data center.
Speaker 0: It's like Station.
Speaker 1: if it's too hot overheating if it's too dry static problems.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like, you know, you're cooling you just your computer.
Speaker 0: Condensation is probably not gonna become an issue right?
Speaker 0: But if you're cooling a whole room with air conditioners it's very possible that it could.
Speaker 0: basically the whole room is a refrigerator and It can condensate very easily.
Speaker 0: Any big trouble?
Speaker 0: Computers and water are not fun.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and my comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.