Speaker 0: It's Thursday, February 9th, 2011.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we talk about the Casa Play.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So lately in Midtown, there's been a ton of kind of like new lunch places that open.
Speaker 0: that are chains, but they're like a new chain.
Speaker 1: So it's like they're trying to be the next Chipotle?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're trying to be the next Chipotle.
Speaker 0: It's very clear that they are and I've decided I like going to these places because they all kind of opened around the same time.
Speaker 1: I wish I had some of those places nearby.
Speaker 0: They're all not that great, but the thing is they all are like.
Speaker 0: they have managers and like all the staff are like crazily well like trained and they're super.
Speaker 0: shall I warm sirs crack pipe.
Speaker 1: Oh, it is excellente.
Speaker 0: Like I went into this one today.
Speaker 0: So my goal is to eat at all these places.
Speaker 0: One of them is a coffee shop and actually they had pretty good coffee that cost the same as Starbucks.
Speaker 0: And it's on the way to Starbucks so I can shave like 30 seconds off in my day.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I went to this place.
Speaker 0: it was called like for food with a number in it or two food.
Speaker 0: I don't even remember but it was way weird.
Speaker 0: So I walk in and I can't.
Speaker 0: I look at the menu and I don't quite get it.
Speaker 0: It shows like these donuts, but it's a burger joint.
Speaker 0: But the menu is like what donut do you want and what do you want in the donut?
Speaker 0: And what do you want with the donut?
Speaker 0: All right, and then this guy in a suit walks over.
Speaker 1: But I thought that you know, that's that's good.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot of donuts going on in the city.
Speaker 0: They're not donuts.
Speaker 0: They're beef.
Speaker 0: So, but so here's the thing.
Speaker 0: this guy walks over very well-dressed.
Speaker 0: he's like, "Sir, have you been to our fine establishment
Speaker 0: before?".
Speaker 0: And I'm like, "Nah, I've never been
Speaker 0: here.".
Speaker 0: He's like, "I shall explain to you the many mysteries of our
Speaker 0: restaurant.".
Speaker 1: Why it looks like a donut, but is it?
Speaker 0: And he proceeds to walk me through the menu.
Speaker 0: He's like, "Basically, you build your own lunch.
Speaker 0: But the deal is our donut, our burgers are shaped like donuts and the burgers aren't just beef.
Speaker 0: They can also be chicken or hummus or whatever.
Speaker 0: It was like ten kinds and basically you go down the line and you pick an item from every column and it when it comes out at the end is a lunch.
Speaker 0: And like if you get a burger, it's like this donut shaped burger.
Speaker 1: So something goes in the middle?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you.
Speaker 0: so I got one.
Speaker 0: and the thing is if you can't if you're uncreative and you can't like figure it out.
Speaker 0: you can get their pre-made ones, but they all have names.
Speaker 0: One of them was "They's a-rapin' everybody" and it's it's a picture of that guy.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: It's called "They's a-rapin' everybody"?
Speaker 0: It doesn't spell out a rape, but it is a. Okay in a restaurant, yeah the place and get this.
Speaker 0: all the seats had iPads.
Speaker 0: You can just like go on the internet with the iPad while you're eating.
Speaker 1: Hide your kids, hide your wife, don't go to that restaurant.
Speaker 1: And it was like 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: Like it was pretty good.
Speaker 0: The food was okay.
Speaker 0: But the deal was.
Speaker 0: I got this like beef burger donut on a brioche and inside of it was a cheese stick like melted into the middle.
Speaker 0: There's some jalapenos in it and and I got some fried potatoes and I I don't know.
Speaker 0: It was pretty good though.
Speaker 0: They clearly microwave everything behind the scenes.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 1: Oh, you don't get to see?
Speaker 0: Nah, you don't get to see.
Speaker 0: But I don't know.
Speaker 0: it was kind of weird and I'm not sure if I like the place but the fact that they had a picture of "They's a-rapin' everybody" and named one of their burgers after.
Speaker 0: that was.
Speaker 0: It was most memorable.
Speaker 1: I would just go to the place that's been there for a while.
Speaker 1: That's meat on steak in a box with a miso soup and a rice.
Speaker 0: Thing is if I want stuff like that, I'll go one step further.
Speaker 0: I go to the Omsipie right by me and you can.
Speaker 0: they have like the fanciest rice balls and you buy like four rice balls and that's your dinner.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: They're way big.
Speaker 0: They're way good.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: Or wait till you know if it's warm and I'll go over to Le Pen Côtillon again.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I'm not walking over there now.
Speaker 0: It is a bit cold.
Speaker 1: There's one.
Speaker 1: it's oh my god It's so warm and like freaking.
Speaker 1: last yesterday when I morning was so warm I was like, oh Or when we did the show and I was like you came over and you're like it is fucking cold out there.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, what are you talking about?
Speaker 1: And I was like the friggin.
Speaker 1: I was like the groundhog said early spring.
Speaker 1: So I'm like maybe right because they don't the grant.
Speaker 1: these is they?
Speaker 1: the groundhog doesn't see anything.
Speaker 0: They park the day on Groundhog Day.
Speaker 0: The first post was a photoshop of the groundhog dead covered in ice and everyone crying.
Speaker 1: Yeah Pretty much.
Speaker 1: the weathermen know if it's gonna be an early spring or not and then they tell the groundhog people whether it's yet It is or not.
Speaker 0: I read somewhere that they're pretty much like not statistically significantly over random.
Speaker 0: So I don't.
Speaker 1: I thought I thought that they were just more recently.
Speaker 1: They've been listening to whatever the weatherman.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they actually do that or not.
Speaker 0: Well, who knows?
Speaker 1: who knows when they started doing it.
Speaker 1: We should look like one year at a time.
Speaker 0: So if I were them, you know what I would do.
Speaker 0: I would actually just do the groundhog thing.
Speaker 0: Whatever to.
Speaker 0: however the groundhog reacts is how I would do it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But how can you tell?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: you set up a webcam and you put him in his hole and you just wait.
Speaker 1: and How do you know if the groundhog sees a shadow or not?
Speaker 1: You it's not like the groundhog says to you.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, I see it.
Speaker 1: There it is.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 0: you gotta come up with some sort of metric like once he comes out cuz the thing is he sees a shadow when?
Speaker 0: He runs away.
Speaker 0: So the first time he pokes his head out Does he get all the way out of the hole and walk off or does he go right the fuck back in that hole?
Speaker 0: That's what you do.
Speaker 1: Maybe make some sort of robotic groundhog thing is I imagine it would be pretty rare that he goes right back in that hole.
Speaker 1: and Also, what's to guarantee?
Speaker 1: He's gonna come out of the hole.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you might be frozen to death in there, right?
Speaker 1: Where does the groundhog even live don't they?
Speaker 1: isn't it like it in a zoo or something?
Speaker 0: but you were like.
Speaker 1: and then they just and then just carry it out to like the Town square.
Speaker 0: it's like a pet.
Speaker 0: I don't know but you were like, it's cold I'm like bullshit.
Speaker 0: and then I open the window after you left and Literally well one.
Speaker 0: I try.
Speaker 0: I heard this noise.
Speaker 0: I couldn't figure out what it was.
Speaker 0: then go to the window and I don't see Anything.
Speaker 0: I try to open the window and I can't like it won't open.
Speaker 0: It's frozen shut.
Speaker 0: No, it's not frozen shot.
Speaker 0: So I go to the balcony and I open that and the wind almost knocks me over.
Speaker 0: The wind was so strong I was crazy in my windows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it was so cold
Speaker 1: I was so I was like almost feeling like maybe biking will come soon, but then no punishment for even thinking that
Speaker 0: Just because
Speaker 1: I thought about bicycles it just punished me and was like, oh I hear Scott's thinking about bicycles - 50 degrees Friggin Tetris God and weather God hitting it up playing ping-pong.
Speaker 0: I mean, I like skiing.
Speaker 0: Skiing is one of my favorite ice peace ice peace Tetris God sketch.
Speaker 0: just for some reason not.
Speaker 0: that's like one of my favorites of all time from them.
Speaker 1: It's a good one.
Speaker 0: But yeah, also, you know tomorrow well tonight I'm going to the symphony.
Speaker 0: that's what we're actually recording the show a night early.
Speaker 0: I'll let the bag out of the can But I got a phone call from the Philharmonic today interesting and they were like it was a recording but it was like.
Speaker 0: Dear sir We would like to inform you in case you were unaware that there will be no late seating for the Shostakovich and Beethoven Show on Thursday, so if you show up after the appointed time, you will not be allowed in with no refund.
Speaker 0: No, it says you will not be granted entry nor will you receive a refund?
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: We humbly suggest that you arrive a full half hour before the event Thank you and have a wonderful performance.
Speaker 1: It's just they got an automatic auto dialer and you bought tickets here in the system.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm I'm digging this because I've been to symphonies in a lot of places But I feel like Lincoln Center is the one place where a hundred percent of the old etiquette about Concerts that people don't seem to goddamn know anymore.
Speaker 0: It's still in effect.
Speaker 0: I feel like I have an intermission.
Speaker 0: They have you know, I feel like nobody's gonna clap at the wrong time.
Speaker 0: No, not pretty much not and I feel like everyone else there is gonna be wearing a suit just like me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably better be.
Speaker 1: I've been there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's how they do.
Speaker 0: I was very disappointed when I paid hundreds of dollars a seat to go see a play not that long ago And it was you know, it was a really good play with big-name people in it and half The audience was basically wearing jeans the t-shirt.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, there's no dress code on Broadway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but in this kind of show, I feel like I should have people should have dressed up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was disappointed.
Speaker 0: I'm disappointed son.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway It's really cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 0: So it's Thursday.
Speaker 0: You can talk about whatever you want.
Speaker 0: Got something.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know what yesterday you want to hear the greatest thing that happened?
Speaker 1: Cuz you know yesterday considering that today is Thursday, right?
Speaker 1: Did you not go to work the greatest thing to happen on Thursday?
Speaker 1: I got a promotion.
Speaker 1: I got a promotion from sheriff to federal marshal.
Speaker 1: We're talking to Scott Earp.
Speaker 0: This isn't good because if you talk to us at any point prior to Tuesday of this week.
Speaker 0: I was the outlaw god.
Speaker 0: Nobody could fucking beat me Scott Lee.
Speaker 0: Nobody could beat me.
Speaker 0: I was just like hands down invincible.
Speaker 1: It's not too looking so good for me at the moment really and I just gonna lie and say you won like you do a T&E.
Speaker 1: just you beat the everliving shit out of it, right two days in a row again, you know what rims new title is.
Speaker 0: What's my title?
Speaker 1: Swiss to Coster Swiss?
Speaker 1: So many holes through you Swiss.
Speaker 0: Okay I realized when I said it you automatically said cheese.
Speaker 1: I wanted to say cheese.
Speaker 0: Did you?
Speaker 0: Yes Are you sure that it wasn't some sort of neurolinguistic?
Speaker 1: Well, no cuz I wanted people to get the joke.
Speaker 1: They'd be like Swiss rim.
Speaker 1: What does that have to do with winning an outlaw?
Speaker 0: since when do we expect people to get the joke?
Speaker 1: It's because if he's Swiss cheese, I shot him full of holes.
Speaker 0: So is that your news?
Speaker 0: you want to talk about our outlaw exploits?
Speaker 0: I could talk about some news also because I mean we could play some combat or some maze craze or some spider-man.
Speaker 1: So anyway Sexism and anti-womanism in the video game world, especially the public online Multiplayer gaming world is not news.
Speaker 0: Don't forget racism a lot of racism.
Speaker 1: Yeah racism, of course, right but sexism also right.
Speaker 1: just as much not news.
Speaker 1: It's been around it's gonna be around.
Speaker 1: It ain't going nowhere.
Speaker 1: All right, however You know and plenty of feminist gaming blogging people have written about it in the past many times most recently Dick Wolf scenario Etc.
Speaker 1: Etc.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I mean we all know it's a problem and it I don't.
Speaker 0: we don't have any good ways to deal with It in the short term.
Speaker 1: However, so this I found a new thing.
Speaker 1: It's pretty new that is taken.
Speaker 1: I think what is the best approach to this ever right?
Speaker 1: and is a blog called fat ugly or slutty calm?
Speaker 0: and On this blog don't Google for that by the way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, go directly to fat ugly or slutty calm.
Speaker 1: They post not dot org screen captures and videos and audio captures but mostly just screenshots of Sexism in multiplayer online video games.
Speaker 1: So most of them are like pictures of Xbox Live messages and it's like, you know stuff.
Speaker 1: for example Hey if I bet you can I see you with a thong?
Speaker 0: Here's one Really?
Speaker 1: I'm going to travel back in time dot dot find a dinosaur egg dot dot.
Speaker 1: bring it back to the future Sit on it till it hatches raise it love it and then watch it mangle your lifeless and helpless carcass while I touch myself Inappropriately.
Speaker 0: that wasn't really sexist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know, basically that was actually pretty good.
Speaker 0: These are things that you know, that was that was above the line.
Speaker 0: I don't know what to call.
Speaker 1: These are things that girls have received as messages while playing games online Messages like that and they don't like them and they post them in this blog and some of them are just you know examples.
Speaker 1: but This one so is I think the most quality right?
Speaker 0: Oh, wait, wait.
Speaker 0: So your news is hey.
Speaker 0: So there's this blog of the horrible sexist things.
Speaker 0: people say pause and here's the best.
Speaker 1: goddamn All right, cuz most of them are just like ah, oh, that's terrible.
Speaker 1: What is up with that disgusting person?
Speaker 1: But this one it's like, okay, even the comments on the blog are like, okay This guy gets points for being at least funny, right?
Speaker 1: Basically this guy is his avatar is the picture of the godfather and his username is pick a boss and he says Keep camping woman.
Speaker 1: I hope there's a kitchen in that tent.
Speaker 1: And one of the comments is even like man I want a tent with a kitchen in it.
Speaker 1: that's some high-tech shit And I was like hell.
Speaker 1: I want to get a tent with a kitchen in it.
Speaker 1: That is some high-tech shit.
Speaker 0: It does sad me though I mean I've been playing a lot of counter-strike lately and I I can literally tell you exactly how many women I have played Counter-strike with in the last I don't know six months.
Speaker 1: The answer is one Literally one and you know It's not the only reason but a big part of the reason is because of the things like you see on this here blog.
Speaker 0: What I what I really don't get and I want a term for it because there's like this sliding line of intelligence But there's sort of a black hole like a line below which I do not consider something that someone said online
Speaker 1: To be
Speaker 0: in any way actually a comment like.
Speaker 0: it's not any more communication of any kind But some other thing kind of like how when I take a dump, I don't consider that communication.
Speaker 0: I consider it taking a dump.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's.
Speaker 1: it's weird that like, you know, I mean verbal dump.
Speaker 0: people post like I'm are you cocker?
Speaker 1: Right, it's like if I'm playing a game and someone's like fuck you Jew faggot rotten hell Negroes Fuck shit Strong.
Speaker 0: a bunch of words together and not your nouns and verbs like I don't.
Speaker 1: I don't even read it or process it Right, but it you know, these things apparently are upsetting many female gamers.
Speaker 0: Someone is like fuck you racist slur something at least they formed what is almost a coherent sentence.
Speaker 0: I feel like most of these and looking through that blog.
Speaker 0: It sounds like it's the case there too.
Speaker 0: They're below that.
Speaker 0: They don't even make sense in and of themselves like the words together in no order or combination.
Speaker 0: Actually conveys any message.
Speaker 0: Yeah, some of them but a lot of them are just like, you know I mean my evidence of this is look at the comments on YouTube like who who's posting that?
Speaker 0: Who's saying these things?
Speaker 0: Like I want to see the kid who is sitting there.
Speaker 0: He's 12, dude But I can't believe all 12 year olds are that way.
Speaker 0: How many is it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, I have some much more.
Speaker 1: So wait, there's one more.
Speaker 1: This is an example of a bad one Right.
Speaker 1: So king of lols whose avatar is mice Hughes is is clearly not okay says, how are you playing banette Bayonetta?
Speaker 1: There's no console in the kitchen.
Speaker 1: And then he says I can tell if a game is good just by looking at the cover.
Speaker 1: and it's unrealistic because how did the angels?
Speaker 1: Get in Bayonetta's kitchen in the first place?
Speaker 1: Okay, yeah, see that's the kind of you know bad ones that are most of this site.
Speaker 0: at least it was still a complete sentence.
Speaker 0: I'll give it that.
Speaker 0: yeah kind of.
Speaker 0: So this will outrage you on a much more profound.
Speaker 0: love a new list.
Speaker 1: Love the outrage.
Speaker 0: I love the outrage.
Speaker 1: You should make an outrage podcast.
Speaker 1: It's like outrage.
Speaker 0: You know, what grinds my gears.
Speaker 0: So this is a story from North America.
Speaker 0: It's from North Carolina, in fact North Raleigh And a citizen of the United States has been accused and there it looks like there will be a court case about that.
Speaker 0: There's an investigation a very suspect.
Speaker 0: He's been accused of practicing engineering without a license.
Speaker 1: Do you need a license to engineer?
Speaker 0: So Thus the problem.
Speaker 0: basically what happened here?
Speaker 1: I mean in a license to doctor?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you need a license to be an auctioneer however and your license to drive a car?
Speaker 0: I believe a lot of those.
Speaker 0: they're all different situations, but consider the case of a doctor, right?
Speaker 0: I cannot Pretend to be a doctor unless I'm actually a doctor.
Speaker 0: I cannot go operate on someone unless I am a doctor, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but what if I state an opinion that is related in some way to medicine just out in the open Like on my blog or something that's called freedom of speech.
Speaker 1: You just can't say that you're a doctor.
Speaker 1: You can't present it as medical advice just like you can't say this is legal advice.
Speaker 0: So you're expecting where the stories are gonna go.
Speaker 0: So here here's I'm gonna head you off.
Speaker 0: The deal was a city.
Speaker 0: North Raleigh was like we don't think we need to put a traffic light somewhere.
Speaker 0: like they decided they didn't Need signals at these two intersections and they hired an engineering firm which said you know gave their opinion that they weren't needed and The people in town basically said this is kind of bullshit.
Speaker 0: We don't agree with you.
Speaker 0: one of the guys in town who felt strongly about it who is not an engineer or anything Put together in a short simple eight-page document where he just stated his opinion.
Speaker 0: He showed map here quote eight-page document with maps diagrams and traffic projection Objections and he offered this to the city saying look I think we should have one regardless what that engineering firm says.
Speaker 0: Here's my opinion.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm And the city said we disagree with you.
Speaker 0: and to quote the article Lacey who is the chief traffic engineer for the state Department of Transportation Called the state licensing agency the new North Carolina Board of Examiners for engineers and surveyors to investigate him.
Speaker 0: because quote He filed the complaint because the report appeared to be engineering level work By someone who is not licensed as a professional engineer.
Speaker 1: At
Speaker 0: no point that this person claimed to be an engineer Claimed to be claimed to any of these things work as an engineer except money for all he did was state his opinion publicly and mail it to the city and the city's accusing him of Practicing engineering without a license not because he practiced engineering but because the opinion he gave quote appeared to be Well done.
Speaker 1: Well, you know if the court doesn't throw this out.
Speaker 1: It's This sounds to me like who knows what the law for engineering license is looking out of that This is someone who claimed to be a lawyer actually said I'll paraphrase here claiming to be a lawyer.
Speaker 1: That's dangerous that
Speaker 0: if you strictly read the law that the and those statutes and all the things that they're referring to which I couldn't Actually find online it basically forbids Anyone from observing any professional performing any service needed for the planning or completion of virtually any civic project for any?
Speaker 0: Evaluatory purposes whatsoever, even if it is only for a personal opinion.
Speaker 0: It also particularly cites if you use math or if you compare the work to drawings or plans.
Speaker 1: Well, that's clearly unconstitutional.
Speaker 1: First Amendment situation.
Speaker 0: Here's where this really bad.
Speaker 1: It's like cut and dry.
Speaker 0: I feel like this is a problem.
Speaker 1: You know I think it's pretty obvious that both that law and this person using that law are both Were created and do exist for the purposes of covering up corruption.
Speaker 1: the town didn't want to spend money on traffic lights So instead they spent a little bit less money to get some engineers to put a rubber stamp on that.
Speaker 1: You don't need traffic lights.
Speaker 1: so people call so that they would could save money.
Speaker 0: and it was just called this guy out on his bullshit and I have a quote from him when he was basically presented with the fact that this is a quote from the State Department of Transportation.
Speaker 0: Who's the bullshitter when you start applying the principles for trip generation and a route assignment Applying judgments from engineering documents and national standards and making recommendations.
Speaker 0: That's technical work that a licensed engineer would do.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah That's his rationale.
Speaker 0: that because the guy was competent and intelligent and had basic reasoning skills That he does no longer have the right to freedom of speech I think this guy should run is an elected position to be head of the.
Speaker 0: I have no ID.
Speaker 1: Run for that position or further because you should vote for someone who will appoint him to that.
Speaker 0: because we have a problem in the US where we have free speech, but we restrict commercial speech and I agree with both of those.
Speaker 0: 100% Yeah, but we have a situation where there are a lot of this political speech.
Speaker 0: It's the first speech that there are things that are free speech that are regulated nonetheless.
Speaker 0: for example it is very tricky as to whether like to what degree me saying my opinion on a law becomes giving legal advice and The Actual laws about that as I was trying to.
Speaker 1: it's only advice if you specifically say you should do this And you just say I believe this and the.
Speaker 1: this is the same.
Speaker 0: So here's the problem, but by that logic almost every senior IT engineer in the in America is breaking that on a regular basis.
Speaker 0: because one of the primary things that these people will do and none of them are lawyers is Give internal advice as to open source licensing Mm-hmm, and a lot of things are technically illegal under those sorts of regulations.
Speaker 0: and at least in this case I can say that I am an engineer.
Speaker 0: I've worked as an engineer for many many years.
Speaker 1: My title is currently needed a license to be an engineer in New York.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: But then again, maybe I could be wrong.
Speaker 0: Maybe you need one to be a civil engineer.
Speaker 1: Maybe I don't know I mean to be a civil engineer.
Speaker 1: that actually would do something like actually survey a bridge.
Speaker 1: Sure, that's okay.
Speaker 1: If you need a license to do that Yeah, but at the same time at the same time some guy just doing the actual surveying work for the bridge.
Speaker 0: She was just yes, but Scott what if I am NOT an engineer or surveyor, but it's my hobby.
Speaker 0: So I go out to the bridge I get the permission to do it You know pry pods and whatever and I survey the bridge on my own for fun and I put it on my blog That's fine.
Speaker 1: As long as we're not making the bridge or making adjustments to the bridge based on you.
Speaker 0: All right, so what?
Speaker 0: Problem According to some of these laws It looks like you could get in trouble if someone else unbeknownst to you use the information you publicly made available To then make a decision.
Speaker 1: Well that laws bullshit.
Speaker 1: They should get in trouble for using your information because that's would be copyright infringer.
Speaker 1: Would it not?
Speaker 0: Ah, perhaps but may but it using someone's information is not copyright infringement It's only if you redistribute it in its original form or in a replacement form.
Speaker 1: If you if I do a big report and that report is you know made available under a not, you know Depending on what license I make that available under.
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess.
Speaker 1: no Mmm, I don't know.
Speaker 1: That's that's tough.
Speaker 1: Like if I if I architect a bridge and then you just I put my plans online You know, but it no.
Speaker 1: if you make the bridge that I made plans for and I put the plans online You're it would clearly be copyright infringement If you took my all rights reserved blueprints and copied them and gave them to everybody.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's a minor.
Speaker 1: if you make the bridge It's like if I make some sheet music and I put it online.
Speaker 1: right you you pass the sheet music around.
Speaker 1: That's copyright infringement.
Speaker 1: But what if you play the song?
Speaker 1: do I have any claim to that if you make a YouTube of you playing the song?
Speaker 1: That does not include the sheet music.
Speaker 0: There's a whole body of law that I'm not familiar enough.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what.
Speaker 1: so that would be the same thing.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: I Cannot legally give my opinion.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying this would be.
Speaker 1: that would be the same.
Speaker 1: It's the same situation legally as far as I see If I make blueprints and you build the bridge.
Speaker 0: That's not me saying so you can't publicly perform for example a cover of something unless you have the ASCAP licenses.
Speaker 0: Mmm, but there's a little update here.
Speaker 0: Andrew Ritter the executive director of the engineering licensing board in the state Said that it'll take three or four months to investigate this.
Speaker 0: but some follow-up here.
Speaker 0: It looks like The they admitted that they receive things like this all the time that the Department of Transportation Constantly receives this sort of thing from citizens who are pissed off about one or other decision they made.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm This is the first time they've ever taken action against someone because the level the quality of the work was too high And that it appeared to be an unlicensed engineer as opposed to simply a concerned citizen.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: It's almost like they want to criminalize Smart yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but They should bust the people who Sort of agrees with this quote.
Speaker 0: He said there's a potential for violation of the Department of Transportation and the public were misled by quote.
Speaker 0: Engineering quality work unquote even if the authors did not actually claim to be engineers.
Speaker 0: All right, I'm done with my outrage.
Speaker 0: that's just yeah.
Speaker 0: I point this out because things like this happen pretty regularly And this is just one specific example.
Speaker 0: I happen to pick up from FARC and it does not get a lot of press and I don't know if I'll bother following up On it four months from now when I've forgotten and I have some new outrage.
Speaker 0: But you should be outraged and whenever if anything like this ever happens to you fight the goddamn fight to the end.
Speaker 1: Anti-intellectualism number one enemy.
Speaker 1: So with things over the day Man, so this thing of the day was all over the internet.
Speaker 1: So whatever I'm gonna show it to you.
Speaker 1: Anyway Some dude he told the story of Star Wars for you know, only he told it in icons.
Speaker 0: So it's all icons like nothing.
Speaker 1: but yeah, so it's there.
Speaker 1: It's well, it's it's a retold in icono scope.
Speaker 1: So it's 32 lines long and each line is he's just little graphics with little pictures of droids and floppy disks and Luke's and lightsabers.
Speaker 0: Oh, you realize you realize that four thousand years from now Archaeologists are trying to piece pierce back to what happened during our century based on those hieroglyphics.
Speaker 1: Quite possible, but they would not be they might not last because they're in JPEG for So they may not survive and they also, you know may not have the JPEG cipher.
Speaker 1: They'll need the JPEG Rosetta Stone first.
Speaker 0: so There's a reason that we can't have nice things in America and partly it's that Because anyone who's smart gets in trouble for being a fake engineer.
Speaker 0: also because if anything is in a public space It eventually gets peed on and written on.
Speaker 0: that's true without exception.
Speaker 0: if it's in a public place long enough Don't forget pooped on the number and it is a function.
Speaker 0: not just that it's it's how long something has been there And it's also a function of the number of human beings who encounter it on a daily basis on average Yep, and the higher those are you're guaranteed to have poop urine and graffiti.
Speaker 0: Yes, no matter what this is why we can't have capsule hotels because they would become hobo hotels, yep followed by poop hotels Yep.
Speaker 1: Well the other the other thing is that right?
Speaker 1: So in other countries, why don't they have hobo hotels?
Speaker 1: because if a hobo shows up they say get the fuck out of here hobo and they Are.
Speaker 0: or some countries have social safety nets that make sure the people who have mental problems that lead them living on the streets get the help they need.
Speaker 1: Not that many though.
Speaker 1: a lot of plague in.
Speaker 1: you know in Japan There's plenty of homeless people.
Speaker 1: but if a homeless bum tries to go to a capsule hotel They'll just run them out of there and hit him with sticks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right in the US you can't do that.
Speaker 0: The other thing is that in general, I mean even if it's not hobos It's just stuff that's in public gets pissed on and written on people got a pee.
Speaker 1: Well, I think a real solution to be the peeing is Public bathrooms.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then they get full of hobo.
Speaker 0: So the New York City subway is one of the best subways in the world.
Speaker 0: the only factor it lacks is Cleanliness.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean it's so old.
Speaker 1: it used to be clean.
Speaker 0: It is relatively clean.
Speaker 0: It's just that it's not that pretty on the inside.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile Sweden, this is some awesome shit.
Speaker 0: Here are just a bunch of pictures of subway stations in Sweden.
Speaker 0: I don't know what strikes me more the fire red sky painting on the rock the Classical statues carved into the bedrock from which the subway was wrought.
Speaker 0: Maybe the giant Tolkien s column that was built just in the middle for fun.
Speaker 1: Well, Sweden's totally metal, right?
Speaker 0: So yeah, there's the statue that looks like it's Odin or Thor or something.
Speaker 0: There's a Pac Man ghost.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, yeah, you know goes to vote.
Speaker 0: Also, it's clean enough to where I would know.
Speaker 1: you think you think you're Clyde.
Speaker 0: I would not feel that uncomfortable rolling around naked in here.
Speaker 1: Is it Clyde?
Speaker 1: You want to roll around naked with Clyde?
Speaker 1: is that what it is?
Speaker 0: But before we move on the meta moment always important the book club book is still Michio Kaku's hyperspace.
Speaker 0: God has to finish reading it.
Speaker 0: Have you finished reading it?
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: Will you finish reading it?
Speaker 1: I figure we just did a book club.
Speaker 1: I give it some time.
Speaker 1: I didn't want to rush it.
Speaker 0: What are we gonna put the book club site up?
Speaker 0: When I'm not lazy I did all that data entry.
Speaker 1: My problem is I got too many things I'm working on and I haven't.
Speaker 1: they're all 90% done.
Speaker 0: I've gotten to the point where I have simple projects that it'll take me an hour to finish.
Speaker 0: I don't have a whole hour to do it.
Speaker 1: There's an old saying in the computer world the first 90% of the work takes 90% of the time and the last 10% of the work takes the other 90% of the time.
Speaker 1: So I've done the first 90% of the work for like a hundred things.
Speaker 0: in the last 90% of the work for like one thing Yep, but independent that we've got we're gonna be a pecs Boston bitch packs.
Speaker 0: We're doing five panels in three panel slots.
Speaker 0: Yep We're gonna be at you know zenk icon the weekend after that doing a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be a nerd NYC in a few days doing the board game night and think coffee.
Speaker 0: Yeah as always if you want to meet us and you live in the New York City area come to the nerd NYC board game nights once A month and think coffee in Manhattan.
Speaker 0: We're there.
Speaker 0: We'll totally hang out with you and play a board game unless you smell.
Speaker 1: There's a podcast known as Atomic Trivia.
Speaker 0: Ward 9,000 Scott's is going to be a contender.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be on it.
Speaker 1: I guess tomorrow I don't know when they air it but I'm recording it.
Speaker 0: tomorrow I will warn you because I did quiz Bowl a lot in high school and I will tell you this.
Speaker 1: He told me there's no ringing in.
Speaker 0: so The it doesn't matter no matter how smart you are.
Speaker 0: any quiz show no matter how simple it is will make you look stupid.
Speaker 1: No kidding because you don't say especially since I don't know pretty much any famous people or any trivia Yeah, but the thing is even like simple stuff like you'll like.
Speaker 0: maybe you know the whole history of the Roman And I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna cheat and use the internet either now.
Speaker 1: No, but you play to win the game But he said there's no winning.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there is.
Speaker 1: he said he's just for lols.
Speaker 1: There's no winning.
Speaker 1: So there's winning.
Speaker 1: Well, if there's a prize I'll cheat but until then I'm not gonna cheat.
Speaker 0: I Think that'll be fun.
Speaker 0: I'm only not going because I have a Prearranged thing that I'm going to also, you know, make sure you check us out on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, our forums been rocking.
Speaker 1: go to front row crew calm.
Speaker 1: go to forum that from Good like other internet for.
Speaker 1: go to twitter.com slash geek nights.
Speaker 1: go to Everything that is us on the Internet.
Speaker 1: I know all over the place listeners who listen forever.
Speaker 0: We've been saying this a lot lately, but it's been working.
Speaker 0: You've noticed all the people coming into the forum.
Speaker 0: It's not because of our show at magfest.
Speaker 0: It is definitely because of these talkings.
Speaker 0: yes, a lot of lurkers are coming out of the woodwork and Yeah, other than that.
Speaker 0: We've got a bunch of big stuff in the works.
Speaker 0: You saw that shit video.
Speaker 0: We did not that long ago.
Speaker 1: We got more to come More shit videos coming and then hopefully with enough shit video practice.
Speaker 1: They'll be quality video.
Speaker 0: Well, I do have a real 1080p 60 frames a second awesome HD camera sitting in front of me right now that I'm still learning How to use.
Speaker 1: yeah You spend a lot of money and then it's like you get to buy fancy golf clubs and you still hit it way out Into the woods.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see we'll get there and I bought a thousand dollar golf club instead of $100 golf club And it's in the water, but you gave me shit about buying skis.
Speaker 0: You're like, how much do you ski?
Speaker 0: I calculated that they've already saved me a few hundred dollars.
Speaker 1: Ski rental is a ripoff.
Speaker 0: Not really a rental.
Speaker 0: I mean 30 bucks for a day of skiing including the sizing and the liability and everything.
Speaker 1: and how much is a ski?
Speaker 1: 200 bucks, right?
Speaker 1: So if you ski like seven times, yeah, you're good.
Speaker 0: However, if you don't take care of your skis, they will suck long before you have skied seven times.
Speaker 1: really they wear out that fast.
Speaker 0: No, it's more that they'll like rust and you probably won't know how to wax.
Speaker 1: They're made of metal.
Speaker 0: There's edges that are metal.
Speaker 1: I thought they were made out of either wood or some sort of composite Situation.
Speaker 0: they're made out of some composite with a wood or metal core.
Speaker 0: But the bottom surface is something called p-tex.
Speaker 0: p-tex which is it soaks up wet.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna get into it.
Speaker 0: suffice to say Kind of kind of yeah Basically, I've learned I started.
Speaker 0: I'm at the point where I wax my own skis and I do like all my own stuff and I can Tell the difference now.
Speaker 1: Wait, so you put the wax on the bottom of the ski?
Speaker 0: Yeah on top of the p-tex and then it melts into the p-tex And I got a melted in.
Speaker 0: I use a hairdryer and an iron and all this - anyway, that's crazy.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah geek nights.
Speaker 0: Our forum is not full of shit.
Speaker 1: already did that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we didn't.
Speaker 0: it's not every tower.
Speaker 0: We kick people out who can't enjoy.
Speaker 1: I'm saying the meta moments over.
Speaker 0: It's not it's over.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right.
Speaker 0: So we're doing the show on.
Speaker 1: we are doing the show on something we unbelievably have never done the show on before Which is one of the main most popular rising geekeries has been rising for many years.
Speaker 1: It's still very high up there.
Speaker 1: It has not been seeing any decrease if anything.
Speaker 1: It's still seeing an increase.
Speaker 0: It's something that you know.
Speaker 0: You'd think oh this should be an anime show because you always see this at the anime cons.
Speaker 0: You see it just as much of the gaming cons.
Speaker 0: You see it at football games.
Speaker 0: You see it just in the street.
Speaker 0: You see it at parties.
Speaker 0: This is actually.
Speaker 0: it's everywhere in geek culture and in non geek culture.
Speaker 0: Yep Of course, we're talking about the Casa play.
Speaker 0: the Casa play a K costume wearing.
Speaker 0: Yes, you play.
Speaker 1: Well, there's all the costume making and the costume wearing.
Speaker 1: are they the same right?
Speaker 1: Play only referred to the costume.
Speaker 1: not even it's just that cosplay is actually would isn't that a subset of costume wearing?
Speaker 1: Not only are you wearing it, but you're also acting in the character or actually performing a play as that character?
Speaker 0: Yep, of course, then there's if you want to get to the anime stuff they get all the way down to well.
Speaker 0: is it the masquerade or the costume contest or the?
Speaker 1: Well, the costume contest judges craft the cross to making skills, right?
Speaker 1: But the costume, you know masquerade counts your cosplaying skill.
Speaker 0: Well, it counts Never mind I I am so sick of those events that it's almost painful to talk about.
Speaker 0: there's this guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know I don't know how much you have this problem.
Speaker 0: But I mean when I put on my first suit the zipper always Lose some weight.
Speaker 1: I Get the thing with cosplay right.
Speaker 1: is that you know, it's a legitimate geekery just as every other geekery is legitimate geekery Right.
Speaker 1: We want people to participate in as many geekeries as is possible.
Speaker 1: We have no, you know, and I geek nights.
Speaker 1: We love all geekeries, even if we personally don't like them like.
Speaker 1: I personally don't like Star Trek.
Speaker 1: But if someone likes Star Trek, I want them to be a Star Trek geek, you know, embrace the geek domes.
Speaker 0: I think whatever you are maybe are Unreadable.
Speaker 0: I also think Harry Potter is Awful, it is painful for me to attempt to read Harry Potter Magic by Neil Gaiman.
Speaker 0: instead that writing is like knives into my eyes.
Speaker 1: I weep but you know whether we like or don't like cosplay, right?
Speaker 1: there are many people who like or don't like cosplay or cosplayers or typical cosplayers or stereotypes of cosplaying.
Speaker 1: But that doesn't mean that it's no good.
Speaker 1: or it should go away or we should get rid of it.
Speaker 1: No We should have as many geekeries as we can possibly get and we should get as many geeks as we can possibly get no matter what their geekeries may be.
Speaker 0: what's funny is that as a kid like the only cons I went to were basically small gaming cons like Michicon and Renaissance fairs and land parties, I guess and as a result, I never really saw a costume culture.
Speaker 0: I mean Renaissance fair.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone's in a costume.
Speaker 0: I don't think I ever saw anyone in a costume at a gaming con as a kid except for always without Exception that one fat guy in chainmail.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm The thing with cosplay right is when I was young costumes are pretty much for Halloween or for you know I guess like Broadway shows and things like that right there were.
Speaker 1: costumes weren't for anything else, you know I guess maybe also amusement parks that be the costumed characters, right?
Speaker 1: but you know early on the first anime cons I went to like Ohio con and for Otacon 02, right The cosplay was interesting to me then because it was like most.
Speaker 1: for me At least the enjoyment was holy crap.
Speaker 1: That guy is in a costume.
Speaker 1: That is not a cut that you can't see that costume anywhere.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know that guy's dressed up as something obscure that there is no costume you can buy in a box.
Speaker 1: He's like.
Speaker 1: he's not dressed up.
Speaker 1: as you know, a Ninja Turtle like I was for Halloween stuff is vampire hunter D. Right, and oh my god, he actually it's a high-quality costume actually looks like vampire hunter D. That's so awesome.
Speaker 1: Or there was also the awesomeness of oh my god That cosplay is so clever and hilarious.
Speaker 1: if I put a picture of that on the internet people will lol.
Speaker 0: I Jewish wolf would.
Speaker 0: I was about to say Jewish wolf would pretty much wins that.
Speaker 0: all other things with him aside The one time he did that cosplay was also been on this show.
Speaker 0: He was on this show.
Speaker 0: Yeah We interviewed him about and some bullshit.
Speaker 0: Otacon drama in fact Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: So anyway see that for me that was the enjoyment of seeing cosplays was ones that were clever Ones that were like high quality like wow, look at that.
Speaker 1: That's pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: Look in you know, or just you know, this the sheer novelty factor of wow, that's a costume.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna see that anywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah It wasn't until RIT that I was like, oh man cuz I always liked wearing costumes like when I was in high school.
Speaker 0: I dress up as something go to Halloween party and then I rarely had cause to ever put on a costume.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm not so big a fan of wearing a costume mostly because a lot of costumes are uncomfortable, right?
Speaker 1: Especially if there's some sort of like, you know strange Accessories involved or for like face paint, you know, it was always gonna get you all greasy and blend.
Speaker 1: You got to wash it off, you know and that sort of stuff depending on the costume, you know Some costumes are just regular clothes and those costumes I don't have that problem with because they're just regular clothes.
Speaker 0: But going to these cons mostly was that it was all girls dressed up and they were really cute a lot of cat girls and Sort of things.
Speaker 0: I was digging it already when you're very young.
Speaker 0: Yeah I was like 19.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but now that's kind of scary because you're like 28 and there's then they're like 14.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, uh, it was better when I was 19 and they were also 19.
Speaker 1: It was those days are over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I used to go to the masquerades too because back then I watched a few simulcast Yeah, but I mean I went to like anime central.
Speaker 0: I went to them and they were enjoyable to a degree.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the thing with the masquerade right which is separate at least You know at an anime con is that these people are putting on skits most of the time, right?
Speaker 1: If you're walking across the stage It's pretty much the same as the hallway stuff except the fact that some people bring out the big guns just for that.
Speaker 0: So I realized something the skits are not worse than they were then but the masquerades are And I think how is that?
Speaker 1: so I've realized this because I mean the skits were always usually really bad Always be one or two that had something good about.
Speaker 1: yes.
Speaker 0: So here's what's different.
Speaker 0: every masquerade I ever went to back when I went to masquerades The whole thing was actually really short.
Speaker 0: It was like a half-hour 45 minutes time.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: the Otakon ones are always at least an hour.
Speaker 0: I never went to the fucking Otakon ones.
Speaker 1: I saw the simulcast while I was waiting for some horrible movie to start I knew better.
Speaker 0: I didn't go to the Otakon ones.
Speaker 0: I went to the ones all these other anime cons that were smaller and they were like a half hour And every skit was like two or three minutes and they were all stupid.
Speaker 0: They all had time limits on them Yeah, and just because there were less of them The novelty was enough to where you could enjoy it, but I can't sit through two hours of the same gay joke Mmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I think you know the same.
Speaker 0: Oh shit We talk really badly and we're not actually acting and then we do the caramel dance and I think part of the.
Speaker 1: you know The part of the problem that they're so bad is that they have at simultaneously.
Speaker 1: They have too many limitations and also not enough limitations, right?
Speaker 1: They limit them in ways that restrict them from beat.
Speaker 1: They keep them from being quality and creative like you can't futz with the lighting, right?
Speaker 1: So I couldn't do a skit that involved like a spotlight that follows someone and then turn all the lights on and then do a blue Color, you know, yeah, so it's basically everything's lit all at once.
Speaker 1: So you can't even do like, you know Keep the something in the dark while you rearrange a set piece or anything like that, right?
Speaker 1: See it that really restricts the quality of your production if you can't even control the lights or anything like that.
Speaker 1: And because there are so many problems of people not being able to like use microphones Properly or project their voice properly they a lot of cosplays I know do stuff where it's like you have to provide an audio file of your audio and You don't get to talk on a microphone.
Speaker 1: There aren't any.
Speaker 1: so you just had to do your skit in sync with this audio.
Speaker 1: if that involves lip syncing or whatever I think it's easy to fix.
Speaker 0: and if I ran if I was ahead of cosplay at a big con like Otacon I would have this shit down so fast because I learned a lot.
Speaker 0: running You know the first spring cosplay at our IT anime back in the day doing our costume contest and everything and I realized if I Were Otacon or some big anime con what I would do is All year if you've got to send in a video an audition and I would pick they don't
Speaker 1: have those though But they do them at the con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would do this ahead of time.
Speaker 0: You have to send a video like a four months Deadline ahead of the con.
Speaker 0: we will pick the best 10 or 15 or so and then work with them directly To have.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't even I wouldn't even set a number, right?
Speaker 1: I would say we're only gonna pick the ones that are good enough and if it's zero, it's zero now.
Speaker 0: that doesn't work.
Speaker 0: That's actually kind of a bad way to handle it.
Speaker 0: Why is it?
Speaker 1: we're all gonna be terrible anyway.
Speaker 0: now if you set it up like that the first couple years They'd be pretty slim pickings.
Speaker 0: But then while you'd lose the Shitty.
Speaker 0: Oh wait, there's no bad drawback.
Speaker 0: It's perfect.
Speaker 0: It just requires more work on the part of the staff.
Speaker 1: Which yeah anyway, no, but the thing is right.
Speaker 1: here's why I don't have confidence in this plan.
Speaker 1: Right is because look at cosplay chess.
Speaker 1: cosplay chess is that thing?
Speaker 1: Basically, these people will actually meet and prepare all year for this cosplay chess.
Speaker 1: They write it and prepare.
Speaker 1: It's still terrible.
Speaker 1: play chess is like four hours long Even if it was only ten minutes long.
Speaker 1: these people practice and prepare for us so long and it's doesn't it?
Speaker 0: It's not good in the end or how about this?
Speaker 0: you do the same masquerade as always But then at the end of it you show the three best skits from the separate.
Speaker 0: Send us a submission if you want to be the real people that get real microphone skits Mmm, so you have like the real ones like like real tear and shit tear and you separate the two.
Speaker 1: I guess you could do something like that, but it's not gonna help that much right?
Speaker 0: No, well the root problem and I don't want to dwell on this much more is that people eat that up.
Speaker 0: You know, you know, we had a lot of feedback from Connecticut last year and very true You know.
Speaker 0: people said the panels were the best they'd ever seen at Connecticut and they notified us of all the problems We already knew existed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but like everything was great, but half of the positives we got were specific awesome panels that we agreed were awesome and the whole other half were Cosplay chess is the best thing ever.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, and I've seen cosplay chess.
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: People just like that shit.
Speaker 0: I don't get it.
Speaker 1: I don't get it either but they like it.
Speaker 1: So let him have it.
Speaker 0: I say let him have it too, but I didn't.
Speaker 0: I was forcing me to watch it But remember, I mean we used to have to judge Costume contests.
Speaker 0: I've done it.
Speaker 1: I've done it a couple times at RIT anime.
Speaker 0: We had to do it Yeah, and at sitcom we were actually the celebrity judges.
Speaker 0: That was awkward because they do their skit and then we as the judges and there were like three or four other people on the Panel would have to like ask them questions on stage and some of them were okay And some of them were really sad and it was really hard to come up with questions.
Speaker 1: for the thing is I don't know why we were doing that because I've never seen anyone ask questions of a skit at a Another cosplay besides that one.
Speaker 0: well Because we're no to con they go up to do their skit they get off because they didn't have that many and it was a small Con and we were supposed to all be funny.
Speaker 1: No, okay, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean for the six people in the audience it definitely was Yeah, we did cosplay like for real only once ever at.
Speaker 1: Well, we've also there was you know, the RIT anime Club had an annual costume.
Speaker 0: Oh my god I was famous for my half acid not even half ass.
Speaker 0: It was like an eighth of an ass was what I put into that cuz I had no money I had no time.
Speaker 1: the the oh my god is cosplay.
Speaker 0: I think that was the best one.
Speaker 1: No, no that when I took our curtains I wrapped around And then you had a piece of felt that you turn that you rotated 90 degrees.
Speaker 1: So it was now a diamond right?
Speaker 0: So there's a triangle in the front a triangle in the bag and I glued it And I put that over my shoulders and then I glued up like a diamond of felt to my forehead and I wore white pants.
Speaker 0: Yep, I didn't even get to shave that day.
Speaker 0: It looked awful.
Speaker 1: Yeah even I did the.
Speaker 1: I did the initial D car which is a car made out of poster board that I attached two LEDs to the front and Put some straps so I could wear it over my shoulders and it might still be in the anime club library somewhere Maybe they?
Speaker 0: we that was lost.
Speaker 0: I heard was it?
Speaker 1: they lost god.
Speaker 1: They lost my car.
Speaker 0: I heard the car is gone.
Speaker 1: work so hard to make that car.
Speaker 0: a lot of the things we'd left behind are gone.
Speaker 0: my car I did the one.
Speaker 0: what's his name?
Speaker 0: the guy the sniper guy from?
Speaker 0: 8.
Speaker 0: I Dressed up as him because I had the trench coat add the hat but one I lost the hat so I couldn't wear it.
Speaker 0: So my costume was half-assed.
Speaker 0: to that point I basically took my trench coat taped some fake fur around the neck and then to make his shirt I took.
Speaker 0: I bought a square of felt and I made the front half of a shirt because I couldn't afford enough felt to also Make the back half and I duct-taped it to my chest.
Speaker 1: one time the anime club people decided to do star ocean And I knew nothing about star being Greg dressed up as the dragons that stand on either side of the guy.
Speaker 0: Yep, so I wore a red suit.
Speaker 0: He wore a blue suit and we taped signs written in marker to our chest.
Speaker 1: that said dragon Yeah, and I was supposed to be some character.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what the character was and we basically went to the you know the goodwill and they're like bought a white shirt and a vest and then I wore rims trench coat and yeah, I guess people said That that was the character.
Speaker 1: I'm like, okay.
Speaker 1: I don't even know this character's name or anything.
Speaker 1: Whatever they decided on star ocean theme.
Speaker 0: Ah, but at that one Otacon we got a whole bunch of the front row crew like ten or so people To dress up as the axe gang.
Speaker 1: It was actually is pretty good.
Speaker 1: I realized we did a good job.
Speaker 0: Exactly why people cosplay icons?
Speaker 0: because basically what it means is everybody's paying attention to you Even though you might not deserve it.
Speaker 1: Our costume was not that great No, but but there was some cleverness to it and that we actually had a gang.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the axe gang was sort of an obscure thing.
Speaker 1: So the people who are new to cons or whatever were like, oh my god There's people dressed up as a thing that you'll never see.
Speaker 1: people dressed up.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, the axe gang and we were doing the dance and we had little axes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we had.
Speaker 1: we bought little axes from like the dollar store.
Speaker 0: Those are actually hard to find Really little plastic axes.
Speaker 1: We bought the fireman's kit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was that one fireman set and we bought all the ones that they had at the KB toys by RIT And we got someone else who would live further away You know, we could get a whole bunch of those at the KB toys in Atlantic City.
Speaker 0: But that was good times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it on the one hand right it was kind of annoying because it was really hot in the summer and the costume Was very warm.
Speaker 1: right because it was actual dress clothes and not shorts and a t-shirt.
Speaker 1: And also, you know, it's like if you want attention Congratulations, you've got attention and people are taking pictures of you if that's what you wanted.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 1: You win, but Basically, you can't walk anywhere because people keep stopping you and asking you to take the picture and you're blocking the hallway and it's terrible.
Speaker 1: All right It's kind of you actually want to do something at the con.
Speaker 1: You can't do it while wearing a costume even if the classroom was normal clothes which it was in that case.
Speaker 0: Scott made this rule and I agree with it a hundred percent and we needed to spread.
Speaker 0: if Anyone at a convention ever blocks a hallway to take a picture or is causing a physical space Disruption because they have a space clear to take a picture.
Speaker 0: Just walk right through they have no right or excuse to block the hall Like that.
Speaker 0: just walk right through their picture.
Speaker 0: Just don't even care.
Speaker 0: I feel like everybody needs to start doing that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if they're in an aisle or whatever.
Speaker 1: if they're you know, do not allow someone to use walking space for picture.
Speaker 1: In Japan they say there's no picture-taking allowed inside.
Speaker 1: they don't even let cosplayers into the conventions.
Speaker 1: They force them to stay outside.
Speaker 1: They don't let them in because it blocks the hallways and it's way too crowded.
Speaker 0: now Don't be a dick.
Speaker 0: that's why you like walk over into the corner like photobomb everybody.
Speaker 1: No, no, but go go to any blog that has pictures of Japanese cosplayers.
Speaker 1: They will always be outside or in some sort of designated cosplaying area.
Speaker 0: They also put any costume I've ever seen in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well they put a lot more work into it and they have more skills and that's one thing I can say is that anime Cons aside like if you go to a pecs or any non anime culture con They're like the average individual.
Speaker 0: cosplay is higher quality and there's far fewer of them as a result.
Speaker 0: They garner way more attention.
Speaker 1: You know, I haven't really paid attention because cuz I'm so jaded.
Speaker 0: I don't like oh, there's a big fruit fucker Whatever.
Speaker 0: I mean like.
Speaker 1: I don't even like 40 people like oh my god Yeah, it's like at this point going to so many conventions cosplay just sort of like.
Speaker 1: I don't even see it.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: you have to point it out to me like look at that Like I just is.
Speaker 1: it might as well be a person in regular clothes Like I don't even recognize it or it doesn't process in the brain whatsoever.
Speaker 1: It has to be something way clever or way it has to stand out from the crowd Right in some way that I'll actually notice like guys on stilts.
Speaker 0: Don't even faze me at this point, right?
Speaker 1: It's got it.
Speaker 1: Not only does it have to stand out somehow so that it catches my eye But it also has to be recognizable.
Speaker 1: There's so many times lately.
Speaker 1: My problem is I go to a con someone's cosplaying is something and I see them and I say guy and my brain says cosplay guy and that's maybe at most right.
Speaker 1: But that guy was actually cosplaying as something that I really like and I'm totally into.
Speaker 1: and later someone would be like Scott Did you see the cosplay of such-and-such from whatever?
Speaker 1: and I'd be like no They'd be like.
Speaker 1: there it is and I'm like, oh I saw that I didn't realize that's what it was because it was a cosplay didn't even enter my brain, you know.
Speaker 0: Well, there's also.
Speaker 0: I've had the.
Speaker 0: it's funny that back in the day.
Speaker 0: I used to always like at conventions I dressed a lot dressed actually less nerdy geeky than I do now and I'd usually wear like a collared shirt maybe a tie like.
Speaker 0: I was always kind of dressed up at Conventions and people would always stop me to take pictures.
Speaker 0: They thought I was cosplaying as like kaji or something or they didn't even know.
Speaker 0: like one time a guy stopped me.
Speaker 1: that does happen a lot.
Speaker 1: when I was at Kinetic on and we had those little headsets with the things right to walk around Somebody was like are you out?
Speaker 1: Uh, and I'm like what?
Speaker 1: I was like, I thought that they were asking if I was staff and I was like, yeah I'm staff and they're like, can I take your picture?
Speaker 1: I'm like, all right, but they were actually asking if I was a scout from Team Fortress 2 because he has the headset thing.
Speaker 1: They thought that I was a scout.
Speaker 0: what I used to say is every time someone asked me I'd be like I'm dressed up as a katani from initial day.
Speaker 1: Yeah Whereas jeans and a polo shirt.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a key just a t-shirt jeans and a t-shirt.
Speaker 1: I'm it's a key.
Speaker 0: third People would at one point.
Speaker 0: I remember this very vividly.
Speaker 0: I don't know what kind it was, but someone stopped me and they took my picture and I was like, what do you what?
Speaker 0: do you think I'm cosplaying as?
Speaker 0: and He looked at me and he really didn't have an answer and he's kind of wandered away And it was just such a weird experience.
Speaker 1: Maybe he just you know had the hots for you.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of those cosplay photo.
Speaker 0: Oh my god There's all of them Otakon.
Speaker 0: every year There's that one fat guy who has a super awesome DSLR and he is just taking pictures of cleavage and being super creepy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's plenty of guys like that.
Speaker 1: No shortage You know, I want to address that one issue right?
Speaker 1: is it?
Speaker 1: in the cosplay community?
Speaker 1: There's loads of drama.
Speaker 0: How do you people have so much drama?
Speaker 0: Jesus fucking
Speaker 1: Christ, but a lot of the drama is you know the way we you know the way we as you know gamers hate on for example Farmville people or the way that you know comic fans will hate on people who read the kind of comics that they don't read.
Speaker 1: whatever the you know, The regular superhero guys will hate the manga people and vice versa and indie people hate everybody.
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: the cosplay people seem to have that same hate for the people who wear a Naruto headband and draw some whiskers on their face and Think that they're you know cosplay but they also hate each other like oh that costumes too good.
Speaker 0: It was clearly mass-manufactured and I did.
Speaker 1: they hate anyone who buys a costume.
Speaker 1: also, right and it's like, you know Okay, I don't really see somebody wearing the Naruto headband the same as a Farmville player.
Speaker 1: I see them more as a street fighter player who mashes the buttons Doesn't get any hits.
Speaker 1: right they're playing the same game, right?
Speaker 1: They're playing the highest skill game.
Speaker 1: They just have really low skill.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I'm not gonna hate him cuz they're trying.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm not gonna give him any recognition cuz I suck in.
Speaker 0: Scott don't know where they are.
Speaker 0: hate the game.
Speaker 1: No, I'm not hating the game either or the player.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying man you Play if you boil it down.
Speaker 0: It's wearing costumes in public.
Speaker 0: It's just one tiny piece of social currency.
Speaker 0: the Naruto headband is like throwing pennies of people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: I got a penny got pennies.
Speaker 0: I don't want a penny.
Speaker 1: Yep You know, and if that's you know, that's what you're gonna do.
Speaker 1: be my guess.
Speaker 1: It doesn't hurt me You know, yep, your Naruto headband isn't costing me any money But probably magfest had almost like.
Speaker 0: it's weird.
Speaker 0: It had very little cosplay That's true, but the few cut the one cosplay that stood out.
Speaker 0: you can tell when things stand out.
Speaker 1: There's some team fortress 2 cosplay.
Speaker 1: No, there was one zombie type a lot of zombies cosplays.
Speaker 0: It was I love like there's these.
Speaker 0: it was there was nobody.
Speaker 0: It was a Tom Servo puppet that itself was dressed up as Lena inverse.
Speaker 1: Yes, that was crazy seeing that kind of that specific combination.
Speaker 0: cuz that at mag fest.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's where yeah at mag fest.
Speaker 1: We didn't see any Colossus cosplays.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is the convention of Colossus?
Speaker 1: what the fuck?
Speaker 1: No, but yeah That is one.
Speaker 1: that's back to what I was saying at the beginning about the clever cosplays.
Speaker 1: I love clever cosplays and one subset of clever cosplay that I really like is the combo cosplay.
Speaker 1: you cosplay as something.
Speaker 1: Cosplaying as something.
Speaker 0: there's the guys as the tentacle.
Speaker 0: Yeah Just cosplaying as link.
Speaker 0: they dress up as the tentacles who are also cosplaying.
Speaker 0: or at RIT our friend combat He made this state.
Speaker 0: They were all freshmen in the anime club and they stole this traffic safety barrel.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and they kept bringing it to the club like it was their friend.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, they dressed up as a barrel.
Speaker 0: Well, what they do is they bring it in they'd wear shirts with it.
Speaker 0: They like set it in a seat like it was just at the club and then at the spring cosplay.
Speaker 0: They dressed it up as Naruto and it was safety barrel Naruto and inside of it They had a guy wearing an orange shirt who I think was combat himself.
Speaker 1: Maybe I forget who was actually in it.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it was calm.
Speaker 1: It's one of those people in the trouble.
Speaker 0: I saw a picture of that group Not that long ago.
Speaker 0: I was looking through old pictures I'd taken.
Speaker 0: They look like like 12 year old little kids.
Speaker 0: They were like I Can't even get by how young they look.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they were.
Speaker 0: then I look at pictures of us and we don't look that much younger.
Speaker 1: But anyway, yeah, is there anything else to say about cosplays?
Speaker 1: I have no cosplay making skills.
Speaker 0: No, I'm famous for my lack of cosplaying making skills.
Speaker 1: I guess you know cosplay does have a lot of crossover right because it crosses over into the animes and the comics and the game steampunk and the sign and the sci-fi.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and people cosplay as like historical figures of SCA stuff Renaissance fairs.
Speaker 1: You can do Civil War reenactments very like, you know, all kinds of.
Speaker 0: forget the furries.
Speaker 1: It's this one geekery that you know much like.
Speaker 1: we always say you should learn technology No matter what your geekery is because technology touches every part of your life.
Speaker 1: Well cosplay doesn't touch every part of your life.
Speaker 1: You don't need to learn it, but it does touch every geekery, right?
Speaker 0: Well, I think what it is is that any no matter what your hobby is even if it is possible to make a costume related To it.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean people dress at sports people cosplay right when they go to cheer for their teams or the mascots are basically cosplay.
Speaker 1: You know You know, I can't even think of a single geekery.
Speaker 0: theater theater geeks love making costumes.
Speaker 1: Peter is cosplay.
Speaker 1: That's the same.
Speaker 1: I can't think of a single geekery.
Speaker 1: The cosplay does not cross over with drinking.
Speaker 1: yeah, you can cosplay as Lady Godiva or Many other things.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot-com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.