Speaker 1: Hey, it's Wednesday, February 16th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight the 90s OAV my hope sky tie.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So get this.
Speaker 1: I was poking around on the internet and there was an article on FARC about blockbuster of all things.
Speaker 0: I thought blockbuster was out of business.
Speaker 1: There are still apparently blockbuster stores in a few places that aren't gone yet.
Speaker 0: What is the towns like only old people?
Speaker 0: Apparently are they towns where they don't.
Speaker 0: not only they they only have dial-up internet.
Speaker 0: So no one get Netflix and Everyone's old.
Speaker 0: so they don't know how to use.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing and they don't have one of those red boxes at the grocery store.
Speaker 1: Blockbuster was completely irrelevant.
Speaker 1: that the brick-and-mortar Blockbuster.
Speaker 1: well, I'm not provide anything that I couldn't just get online from Netflix.
Speaker 0: I thought the red but the red box at the grocery store put it out.
Speaker 1: Actually, the red boxes are doing really shittily now, too.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but I mean they they were.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like it was the combination of the red box and then Yeah, I agree.
Speaker 1: until it put it out this FARC article I was convinced like you that there is no purpose left in the world for a brick-and-mortar Blockbuster.
Speaker 0: wait, let me guess which all of the extra stock from every other blockbuster that went out of business all went to this One blockbuster which is now a paradise of cheap DVDs and video games for a penny.
Speaker 1: Not quite.
Speaker 1: This was sad to me a little bit because as a kid I mean blockbuster is the only place that in Suncoast I could either go to Suncoast and buy my anime for like a $40 VHS with two episodes at a time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or I could go to Blockbuster and watch like dune megalopolis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we had FYE Sam Goody in blockbuster.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but no apparently, you know, you can just download movies over the internet.
Speaker 1: But you know, you can't download right cash.
Speaker 1: someone fucking robbed one of the last blockbusters Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I guess there's still a purpose for the brick-and-mortar blockbuster.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: You can't rob Netflix or Amazon.
Speaker 0: That's actually.
Speaker 0: that's actually like.
Speaker 0: I'll bet you could rob an Amazon warehouse.
Speaker 0: It would be very difficult.
Speaker 0: the thing I don't think it would.
Speaker 0: that actually, you know, you think about it, right and you're like, okay How does Amazon make so much more, you know, how can they charge so much less than Best Buy, right?
Speaker 0: It's like well, they don't have the cost of the store and the sales people and all that.
Speaker 0: But they do have other costs like servers and these sorts of things, right?
Speaker 0: but a significant cost to Best Buy's and other retail stores is basically Insurance and also like basically, you know stop-loss, which is shoplifting.
Speaker 0: it cost them a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Amazon has zero shoplifting compared to pretty much any percentage.
Speaker 0: actually They save a ton of money on that.
Speaker 1: How do you know?
Speaker 1: because most loss is actually employees and not customers.
Speaker 1: and there are people who work in the Amazon warehouses.
Speaker 1: You don't you can't tell me I don't.
Speaker 1: there aren't people just taking boxes of shit out of there.
Speaker 0: I don't think people are walking out of the Amazon warehouse with a bike with tons of shit.
Speaker 1: I would I'd be interested actually.
Speaker 1: I'm a shareholder.
Speaker 1: I should email and be like, what are your loss statistics?
Speaker 1: I really want to know.
Speaker 0: you can get the annual report.
Speaker 0: if it's public.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's probably in.
Speaker 0: it might not be in.
Speaker 0: there might be find out.
Speaker 1: I've only.
Speaker 0: I'll be very interested to see about.
Speaker 0: you know The theft if there is any from Amazon and any other internet there's gotta be.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's some retailers that are also brick-and-mortar stores, right?
Speaker 0: Like Midtown Comics will sell you comics online, but you can also go to the store and I'm sure people steal from Midtown Comics You know, at least sometimes.
Speaker 0: no, I don't know I don't like shoplifting.
Speaker 0: that's real stealing it's not okay.
Speaker 0: So this would normally be like a Tuesday news because it's gaming related.
Speaker 1: You got nothing to say about anime Do you know?
Speaker 0: but it's Pokemon?
Speaker 0: So it is.
Speaker 0: I think the anime crowd the Wednesday listeners care more than the Tuesday listener.
Speaker 0: They may.
Speaker 0: So basically, you know the Pokemon card game.
Speaker 1: I know of it.
Speaker 0: I've played it on occasion All right, so they're gonna make a thing at the Pokemon website website pickups.
Speaker 0: That's an official game, right?
Speaker 0: It's gonna be a flash game where you can play the Pokemon card game in flash, right and there's three Pre-made decks that you can use.
Speaker 0: Yeah, three pre-constructed decks and twelve virtual trainers.
Speaker 0: You can play against across three leagues.
Speaker 0: so basically you can go learn how to play the game without spending any money and play it a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: and What I find, you know, I mean that's not the greatest thing in the world.
Speaker 0: It's not like you can use any card in the world and make any deck and play against any of your friends.
Speaker 1: But I can't say I did enjoy playing a little bit the magic on the Xbox.
Speaker 0: I was gonna say the magic on the Xbox.
Speaker 0: right they try to charge you money for that shit, right?
Speaker 0: But this is free flash in the browser and is basically to the same extent as the magic at the gathering on the X.
Speaker 1: Why is Nintendo so smart about some things and so dumb about very similar thing?
Speaker 0: Well, I think they're all.
Speaker 0: you know, this is like they're smarter than Wizards of the Coast in this particular department But they're not maximum smart.
Speaker 0: if they were maximum smart They would say one dollar a month.
Speaker 0: you get a program or five bucks a month.
Speaker 0: Even you get a program.
Speaker 0: you can play the Pokemon card game online against anyone with any card.
Speaker 1: No a much better Forever would be five dollars a month to maintain it.
Speaker 1: and then you know, you get access to all the basic cards.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, you get everyone gets one set, but you have to pay 20 bucks to add a new set of cards.
Speaker 0: But once you add the new set you can have any card in that set as you could probably get away With forcing them to buy boosters.
Speaker 0: You people do have done that online.
Speaker 0: the way you do it our games that do it.
Speaker 1: I know the way you do a Pokemon is you sell Physical boosters.
Speaker 1: that are the only way you so if you buy a physical booster It has a serial number that gives you a one-shot that gives you an in-game booster and or you can buy an online only booster.
Speaker 1: That's like three dollars cheaper Maybe.
Speaker 1: but that's what I would do.
Speaker 0: I mean that's if you want to those kids for everything They're were that would let you milk some kids who were way into it.
Speaker 0: really hard, right?
Speaker 1: But usually milking kids put you in a federal prison.
Speaker 0: But I'm just saying right is if you look at say the way the comic book people do it Right is they'll be like, okay.
Speaker 0: We got a new event, you know, it's the crazy war.
Speaker 0: So they'll have crazy war issues 1 through 12 and have crazy war side story and spider-man crazy war and Batman crazy war issues.
Speaker 0: Right, and they just went.
Speaker 0: so many issues a crazy war.
Speaker 0: the super collecting nerds have to buy them all right.
Speaker 0: But I think if you know, no one is willing everyone dips in the toe, right?
Speaker 0: No one jumps in the pool.
Speaker 0: I think if you made it, you know full-on like Netflix you get infinity cards for.
Speaker 0: you know These set prices instead of making people do the collecting thing that enough Extra people would be willing to buy in when the collecting I don't know.
Speaker 0: So it's not there that you would actually make more money.
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: I think they should go one step further.
Speaker 0: you get my money if you did it that way.
Speaker 1: No, if they just want to make money why aren't you even thinking about a good game?
Speaker 1: just make a Pokemon skin Farmville Pokeville, that's it.
Speaker 1: That'll make more money than any effort.
Speaker 1: any bullshit.
Speaker 0: Just throw it out there.
Speaker 0: But this is pretty.
Speaker 1: it's Farmville, but it's a little Pokemon icon.
Speaker 1: You make a little Poke Center and then you you know You put the Pokemon art in the fields and you don't even have to skin it.
Speaker 1: Don't even make the rules different.
Speaker 0: Why don't they do that?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But they could do that and they could also do this and those two things would not conflict with each other and they would Make even more money.
Speaker 1: or they could just make the Pokemon MMO.
Speaker 0: They could do all three of those things the card game the Farmville and the MMO and none of them would conflict with each other And they would all make maximum money.
Speaker 1: So further all the outside things are ways to get items that are Of course, they were all.
Speaker 0: all three of those things would cross over.
Speaker 0: So in the Pokemon MMO you would find cards you could use to play the card game And if you win the card game against someone you get points you can use to upgrade your Farmville.
Speaker 0: and in your Farmville You would grow items and those items would be used in the MMO.
Speaker 0: I Just pictured a kid growing and since you can only play each game on a little bit each day So you can.
Speaker 0: now you've got enough games.
Speaker 0: You can occupy your entire living time with spare time with Pokemon games.
Speaker 0: so anyway, and then you can cross it over with the actual GBA game.
Speaker 1: and Okay, it's interesting to me and kind of sad that you know We see pretty much every anime movie that comes out in theaters in New York.
Speaker 1: because every good one Yeah, everyone that isn't one piece number 100 But even then it's there aren't that many anime movies let alone anime movies that actually are in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Well, there are a whole bunch but they're all like I said one piece number 35,000.
Speaker 1: yeah, there aren't even that many of those 10. yeah, that's not that man.
Speaker 0: That's a line.
Speaker 0: They come out with one every year.
Speaker 0: They come with a Pokemon movie every year they come at right.
Speaker 0: So this is quite a few of them.
Speaker 1: I considered watching Pokemon forever the other day.
Speaker 0: So I guess that was number four.
Speaker 0: I Guess we saw.
Speaker 0: anyone we saw was number three the best way to see anime.
Speaker 1: It said that it's during this.
Speaker 1: but the New York International Children's Film Festival, which is an awesome event in and of itself.
Speaker 1: It's just this great kind of film festival in New York, and there's no reason not to go.
Speaker 1: but they always show pretty much every current big anime movie and The crowd at the anime movies at these things is half kids and half people like me and Scott.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the same posse.
Speaker 0: It's actually a pretty good crowd though.
Speaker 1: I remember we saw summer wars that way.
Speaker 0: summer wars is on DVD blu-ray.
Speaker 1: I think today we got that great Q&A at the end when all the questions were why is King Cosmo so awesome?
Speaker 1: is King Cosmo Your favorite character when I grow up?
Speaker 1: who's your favorite?
Speaker 0: I was like, who's your favorite character grandma?
Speaker 0: Was I supposed to say So?
Speaker 1: this year the International Children's Film Festival has two anime movies in addition to everything else.
Speaker 1: We got tell welcome to the space show.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and time of Eve.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So if anyone lives welcome to the space show was shown at the Otakon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I go to if anyone's in the New York area.
Speaker 1: I highly recommend this month.
Speaker 1: well I guess next month in March check out the International Children's Film Festival.
Speaker 1: and If you like the anime movies, I'd recommend seeing at least one non anime movie summer wars is on DVD and blu-ray starting yesterday.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day, what do you got?
Speaker 0: Oh, so the new hotness that everybody is all hotness about is obviously MLP FIM.
Speaker 1: I Enjoy my little pony.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know, we'll probably do a whole show on it.
Speaker 0: So I'll refrain from saying anything, you know too deep about it to ruin that future show.
Speaker 0: But here is a totally awesome super great my little pony AMV.
Speaker 1: it is way well done.
Speaker 1: I mean it's to the level of the good old anime music videos that we would show at conventions or at our IT anime The ones you used to see in like the tournament round.
Speaker 0: I would like to go to our T anime.
Speaker 0: Just show the same thing.
Speaker 1: Oh my god over.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't doubt for a second that they have already shown it at our IT And there's no way they didn't.
Speaker 0: I hope so.
Speaker 1: It's not really an AMV.
Speaker 1: It's not anime Animated music video.
Speaker 0: Yeah animation music video is spider-man manga.
Speaker 0: Japanese person would say No, it is way good or is it, you know the spider-man manga the one that.
Speaker 1: So in the spirit of AMV things of the day because Scott's still my thing of the day That was my head.
Speaker 1: I have another AMV.
Speaker 1: I want to go back to the classics because this one's way good, but it's new.
Speaker 1: and I realized again that a Good half if not more of the good anime music videos I've ever seen or done by Kevin Caldwell.
Speaker 1: So I linked to one of my favorite AMVs.
Speaker 1: it is to koto cha and it is pretty great.
Speaker 0: You know people like koto cha like people don't bring it up at all anymore.
Speaker 1: But this used to be a super popular is a super huge big day deal.
Speaker 0: It's got OAVs.
Speaker 0: It's got movies.
Speaker 0: It's got TV.
Speaker 0: It's got manga.
Speaker 0: right if you ask a Japanese person with ultra relaxes, there's some good odds They'll know how to do the frickin dance.
Speaker 1: If you ask any anime fan in America who went to conventions in the 90s, they'll know koto cha, right?
Speaker 0: So this is like a huge deal that like completely disappeared from the mind share of it.
Speaker 0: Nobody talks about fans in the US, right?
Speaker 0: So maybe we'll have to watch it and do a show on it.
Speaker 0: We got it.
Speaker 0: We got to bring it back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean this kind of like I don't know golden boy Battle athlete.
Speaker 0: those are not quite the same as koto cha.
Speaker 0: They don't have OAVs and TVs now they don't.
Speaker 0: and dances that everybody knows.
Speaker 1: Mangas and you know, I guess part of it's you know, the main bit.
Speaker 1: we're talking about mahoutse kaitai.
Speaker 1: But I I suddenly remembered all the anime that I loved from a long time ago that I haven't seen in a long time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, that's a lot of it.
Speaker 1: But I guess we should do the meta moment because a lot of conventions are coming up in a hurry.
Speaker 1: I remember back in the day convention season.
Speaker 1: It's weird, but convention season for me used to be May through like early September.
Speaker 0: Well, most of the conventions are always in the summer because that's summer is to traditional convention season because that's when people are not in school.
Speaker 0: So you can get and you know You can get the most people to show up on a summer weekend and you won't have weather ruining you and such and such.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: but I'm San
Speaker 0: Diego comic-con Otakon, you know, these things are all in July August You know,
Speaker 1: I think anime central was in May but it was like May June July August September was all my cons and then there was katsu khan like hanging off by itself in February
Speaker 0: Yep,
Speaker 1: but now it's like February starts our convention season and that just goes constantly through the
Speaker 0: forever.
Speaker 0: Well, I think what happened right is that you had more conventions Can you know?
Speaker 0: and the thing is we go to a wider geographic area of conventions?
Speaker 1: We also stopped going to a lot of conventions though.
Speaker 1: We got like we hit a peak I think earlier and I don't think we go to more cons now than we used to.
Speaker 1: I think we just go to more quality Cons, right?
Speaker 0: But anyway, the thing is is that conventions as more of them appeared moved and shuffled to get out of the way and basically the bigger ones got the times they Wanted and all the other ones that have moved to the side, right?
Speaker 0: so you've got like anime Boston in April and you got PAX East in March and you've got New York comic-con in October and you Got PAX West in September and you got Otakon in August July and you got kinetic on also in all.
Speaker 1: now The reason I bring that up.
Speaker 1: It's kind of you know, this is the meta moment.
Speaker 1: Usually we just do announcements, but this is kind of a very gignite scheduling thing.
Speaker 1: A lot of people inquire asking us to come to conventions many of them like generic on.
Speaker 1: a lot of cons recently have been asking us to come and Don't feel bad that we don't come.
Speaker 1: we basically are already at critical mass of very large conventions.
Speaker 1: Yeah Let alone small ones.
Speaker 0: and part of the reason we don't come is now that we're in New York City.
Speaker 0: We used to go to more mostly because we had cars and we had more free time.
Speaker 1: now That's not in any way the reason I don't go to little cons.
Speaker 0: That's the reason.
Speaker 0: one of the reasons I'm going is because you know, we're in the city.
Speaker 0: We don't have cars.
Speaker 0: So, you know getting there it is is an extra cost and I can just go down and get that zipcar if I want it.
Speaker 1: That's not.
Speaker 1: that's not the reason I don't go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they still.
Speaker 0: it's one of the reasons I'm not going.
Speaker 0: It's it's.
Speaker 0: it's an increased cost of transportation.
Speaker 0: And is it really worth a vacation day and a whole weekend, you know for a car, you know It's got you got to make it worth my while.
Speaker 0: You know Scott Some conventions make it worth my while because their conventions are so awesome that it's worthwhile Like packs.
Speaker 0: and some conventions make it worthwhile because they're so awesome like anime Boston, but anime Boston also Gives us money, which I would still go if they did not give us money.
Speaker 0: But they do because they just do.
Speaker 1: but I guess the whole moral of this is just that we've been rebuffing a lot of requests Lately, so if anyone's listening you're wondering why.
Speaker 1: you know, maybe you told your convention Hey get geek nice and geek night side.
Speaker 0: This meta moment is turning into the meta month.
Speaker 0: So let's let's just get to it.
Speaker 1: the convention is the original Intent of the meta moment to get out all the kind of meta.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's also supposed to only be a moment.
Speaker 0: We don't want to fill the show with too much meta.
Speaker 0: So the conventions we are going to in very near times are PAX East.
Speaker 0: we're doing three panels Week after PAX East Zenkai con we're doing a bunch of pan one anime panel Then the rest is all gaming kind of old recycled packs panels.
Speaker 0: and then in April anime, Boston.
Speaker 1: We are confirmed as always preferred panelists will be an anime Boston bringing the a-game and those are the near-term conventions.
Speaker 0: You should go to all our way.
Speaker 1: You want to hurry this up.
Speaker 1: You're all.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: You're delaying it.
Speaker 0: right now We have all signs of websites and Twitter accounts and all sorts of internet presence for front row crew.
Speaker 0: calm You should go and check out all our stuffs and our Twitter's and everything to participate with us.
Speaker 1: You see I feel like this would be more focused if every show you just did one like don't forget the forum.
Speaker 1: and then some Other show be like don't forget.
Speaker 1: We got a Twitter that tweets out the things of the day.
Speaker 0: We could do that.
Speaker 1: I don't think we need the whole.
Speaker 1: we've got an internet thing.
Speaker 1: All right, if you're worried about speeding it up.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's the best way to speed it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and so you're slowing it down right now again.
Speaker 0: The book club book is Michio Kaku's hyperspace.
Speaker 0: How far in that I'd still didn't read anything beyond chapter one.
Speaker 0: I Got time.
Speaker 1: you got time.
Speaker 1: We should.
Speaker 1: we could do the show though It's an important book.
Speaker 0: We'll do it real soon.
Speaker 1: So way back when we were at our IT We would you know pick up just a random anime or if we couldn't pick anything we'd ask the wise and old veterans of the Anime club.
Speaker 1: Hey, what should we watch?
Speaker 0: They pretty much just watched everything eventually.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean there were literally like four or five hundred VHS tapes of just fan subs and pro releases and everything and we got up To a thousand while we were running the club later with Scott Johnson.
Speaker 1: Even when we were freshmen there was more anime than we could ever possibly watch.
Speaker 0: our consumption rate However was extremely high.
Speaker 0: We watched a ton of and well the entire for enemies that if they came out today We would not even give a second Look.
Speaker 1: the entire front row crew as it was back then would go to the anime club and we were all members.
Speaker 1: So after we'd all go to the library and each one of us would check out three tapes And then we would.
Speaker 0: we had a lot of people.
Speaker 0: So if you had five people you had 15 VHS tapes of anime.
Speaker 0: many of those tapes had like four episodes on.
Speaker 1: That's all of Ava.
Speaker 0: That's a lot of tapes.
Speaker 1: In fact, I remember that one time on my birthday I happened to win the raffle and it was my birthday.
Speaker 1: So they gave me a gift and the gift was check out as many tapes as you want.
Speaker 1: Yep, I checked out all of Ava in fact that day.
Speaker 1: But of all the many shows we watched at RIT one that I kind of Forgot about until relatively recently was Maho Skytie Magic Users Club the OAV.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not talking about the TV show or the manga or any of the other stuff related to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's kind of crazy that this show that people really don't know about or you don't even know exists.
Speaker 1: Mostly I've never seen a cosplay of this Ever.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I have.
Speaker 0: I don't remember it.
Speaker 1: I might have maybe It's possible but anyway It's just a random show that we watched one of many many shows and when I remembered that it existed a few months ago I remembered that I enjoyed it, but I didn't remember the plot at all.
Speaker 0: I remembered.
Speaker 0: I remember aliens Yeah, and there was a magic.
Speaker 0: there were kids at a high school and they had a club where they were doing magic Yeah, and that next door to them was the manga club that was fighting with them by pushing the wall back.
Speaker 1: I remembered that very clearly.
Speaker 0: I knew that the aliens had a big bell and I remembered what the main character looked like with like her hair looks like a Mop, and I remember that the main dude is told nerd.
Speaker 0: and that's all I remembered.
Speaker 1: The only other two things I remember that are very important Is that one at some point in the end sigh the main girl has to draw a magic circle and she kind of fucks it Up, I don't remember that.
Speaker 0: remember I watched it and I saw that but I don't remember that stood out in my mind.
Speaker 1: I couldn't tell you why and that the opener is one of my favorite openers to an anime.
Speaker 0: I was a real good opener with the That little bit.
Speaker 1: you'll all know.
Speaker 1: watch the opener.
Speaker 1: I'll link to just pa.
Speaker 1: pa and it's.
Speaker 1: I don't know that just the openers is so like 90s anime fun.
Speaker 0: and Well, the whole show is 90s anime fun, right?
Speaker 0: I mean especially with like casting magic spells like it.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's a lot of the slayers kind of humor that goes on.
Speaker 0: I guess I did not including like, you know tall big-breasted women who go It's in the whole thing.
Speaker 1: Well, I didn't remember much else about the show.
Speaker 1: I didn't know how the plot was resolved written really what the plot was.
Speaker 1: No I really Didn't know if the show would hold up because I have nostalgia for a lot of anime and you know I rewatched Ava not that long ago and Oh Ava's brilliant and everyone says otherwise is stupid.
Speaker 1: I rewatched Trigun not that long ago great show but not as great as I remembered.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know it's a mixed bag watch an old anime that used to like and My own sky tie actually way exceeded my expectations of holding up.
Speaker 0: Well and the one hand right it sort of you know Exceeded it and also did not exceed the expectations.
Speaker 0: right because I was expecting like all right It'll be a cute magic girl show whatever, you know, it'll be.
Speaker 0: it'll be average, right?
Speaker 0: But it was slightly above average, but it was way more perverted than I ever remember.
Speaker 1: See, I don't.
Speaker 1: I would argue that it's not really that perverted.
Speaker 0: It's pretty perverted.
Speaker 0: Even in the extreme climax of the final episode where they're resolving the core plot They're fantasizing with the panty shots and the boobs and such at the even at the very height of every, you know I mean at least some shows that have fan service.
Speaker 0: when you get down to resolving the core plot They can put the fan service behind them.
Speaker 0: the thing is and the fans focus on the climax.
Speaker 1: Here's a big difference between an old anime like this and modern fanservice.
Speaker 0: That is true Is that the fan service is a lot less gratuitous.
Speaker 0: No, not even what I'm gonna say kiss exists.
Speaker 1: All I'm saying is that the fanservice in this show was basically serving the joke that Takeo You know the president of the Magic Club would get distracted and kind of whenever there's a dangerous situation.
Speaker 1: He just kind of have this weird fantasy.
Speaker 1: It always played that one weird song.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess if you're unable to think in the meta Then you could do you.
Speaker 0: you could say that that is an excuse for all the pervertedness.
Speaker 0: But then is not the you know, Moe excuse also valid?
Speaker 1: Because I also note that the way they did those scenes is that every time every time there was fan service They wouldn't really animate it.
Speaker 1: They'd come to like a series of kind of blurry shots of life and it was always the same stupid fantasy.
Speaker 1: He's always like oh They're all gonna suddenly rip their clothes off and adore me.
Speaker 0: Well, that was the clever trick They use.
Speaker 0: right is basically okay in.
Speaker 0: the characters won't actually get all sexual and naked But what we'll do is we'll have this one guy The pervert will imagine them doing that so we can draw them in their underwear without the characters quote Really being in their underwear.
Speaker 0: Ah, but thus they won't be like.
Speaker 1: version of Takeo is very.
Speaker 1: I don't know it fits his character.
Speaker 1: all that.
Speaker 0: I guess the characters are all really yes We made a perverted character so we could make the anime perverted but he's not that perverted.
Speaker 1: He's actually just a loophole.
Speaker 1: He's just a nice normal guy.
Speaker 0: He's a nice.
Speaker 0: He's a relatively nice not as creepy pervert.
Speaker 1: Still I'm curious why you're fixating on this so much because there actually wasn't that much fan service.
Speaker 0: Is it really it just?
Speaker 0: it really stood out to me when I while I did not remember the show being you know Like that and when I watch it again, it just really stood out like every single episode.
Speaker 0: There were like at least four or five, you know, everybody's in their underwear Joe.
Speaker 1: actually no there was about one Explosion.
Speaker 0: now there was quite a few for it.
Speaker 0: I don't know what you watch count because there were definitely multiple.
Speaker 1: I'm really surprised that that stood out to you so much because what stood out to me was just how funny it was.
Speaker 0: It was pretty funny, but it wasn't extremely fun.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know other than the pervertedness the rest of the show it was like.
Speaker 0: alright It was like ko beast maybe better than ko beast quality.
Speaker 0: It was like hey, you know this plot with the aliens is actually pretty interesting and you know The even though each episode is sort of like an episodic kind of.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: Situation is they're actually stringing it together and the characters are actually good characters and you know the there are plenty of funniness of.
Speaker 1: I'm just still hung up on your weird kind of Fixation on the relatively minimal fan service II jokes in the show.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you've been watching like a whole bunch of crazy moe shows that you know I just that perversion was minimal.
Speaker 1: level of fan service is barely what I would even use the word perversion for okay.
Speaker 0: So maybe on some animes otaku scale On a normal person scale is pretty high.
Speaker 1: Have you watched any popular show like Dexter lately?
Speaker 1: There's similar level.
Speaker 0: I even know what that is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz you don't watch anything.
Speaker 1: You have no perspective.
Speaker 0: Maybe show maybe TVs just getting real perverted and I've been watching too many old animes.
Speaker 1: But Scott if it's getting really perverted old stuff isn't any more perverted than news.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've been watching like 70s stuff though.
Speaker 1: So a lot of 70s stuff is also kind of perverted.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the galaxy Express is not preferred.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't use the word perverted if I had to say anything off the show.
Speaker 1: I'd call it a heartwarming Comedy.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's it's you know, the perversion is not.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying that the perversion is the majority of the show.
Speaker 0: I'm saying is that saying that it's barely know worthy and you're really fixed is definitely noteworthy.
Speaker 0: It is a. it is not a majority but it is at least like 10%.
Speaker 1: First episode of blue seed was way more perverted than mahout sky tie.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying.
Speaker 0: I'm saying is that on an anime scale right?
Speaker 0: It's probably less perverted than a lot of animes But it is still quite perverted.
Speaker 0: a significant portion of this show is TNA and underwear And ladies and you know it is.
Speaker 0: if you cut that out you would have 10% less.
Speaker 1: you have to go to the listeners on this.
Speaker 1: you guys watch the show cuz one, you know If you want to skip the whole review the show I think is definitely worth watching.
Speaker 0: It's a short OAV.
Speaker 0: You can watch it in like a night and it's really entertaining and really funny.
Speaker 1: I'm just I'm asking you this listeners when you watch it think to yourself how Perverted you think this show is and compare my feelings to Scott's.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: We'll compare it to apocalypse zero.
Speaker 0: Sure It's completely clean.
Speaker 0: It's safe for children.
Speaker 0: No Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that I don't think they're gonna find it terribly perverted.
Speaker 0: I am saying a significant portion.
Speaker 0: I think you have a 10%.
Speaker 1: I think you're you're obsessed.
Speaker 0: Okay, I'm obsessed.
Speaker 1: So anyway, the plot of mahout sky tie is actually pretty straightforward.
Speaker 1: There's aliens that come down and they're better than everything we've got.
Speaker 1: They just wipe out all the armies of the world and they have this giant bell and they broadcast that We're here to take over the earth and invade it.
Speaker 1: Yeah And then they just kind of stick around and everyone just kind of gets used to them and they're just there Watching everybody like going and they're weird.
Speaker 0: They're not eat.
Speaker 0: They're like weird robot aliens.
Speaker 0: They're not like green aliens they're all robots and mechanical type shit.
Speaker 1: and Independent of this a guy happens to know magic and he started a magic users club in his school like any other club and it's actually one of the Least popular clubs and no one really cares about it.
Speaker 1: But they actually just do real magic and I kind of like how the way the show does the magic is they?
Speaker 1: they have these Kind of fetishes that they use, you know The little duck.
Speaker 0: if the aesthetic styling of the magic is pretty cool because I get they draw symbols.
Speaker 0: They had the quacking duck on a stick.
Speaker 0: They ride on a broom Which is but they're not which is very self consistent.
Speaker 1: and just like the duck is never explained.
Speaker 1: None of that stuff is explained.
Speaker 0: It is explained.
Speaker 0: It's Explained in episode four.
Speaker 1: I think yes, it's explained that.
Speaker 1: yes.
Speaker 1: I got the duck from this box.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he was a basically he.
Speaker 1: Where'd the box come from?
Speaker 1: Why is it a duck?
Speaker 0: There's no it's an ancient artifact.
Speaker 0: and he found his box in a cliffside cave near the beach.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that box contained all the magics.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it was an ancient relic of magic from an agent Anything beyond that.
Speaker 1: like they didn't go into any depth at all.
Speaker 1: It's just this is the way it works.
Speaker 1: a picture of this thing will make magic happen.
Speaker 0: There was a magic book that was in the box that told him what to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, they didn't go into anything beyond that.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean the explanations in the book.
Speaker 0: You just haven't read it.
Speaker 1: And they decide he decides Takeo that he's going to fight the bell But actually he only decided this because he wants to impress the girls who I don't even know I don't even really understand the whole like the motivation to fight the bell.
Speaker 0: I mean cuz it's like in the beginning of the first episode they're going out to investigate it right on their brooms And whatever.
Speaker 1: cuz the bell keeps messing with them.
Speaker 1: That's why they wanted.
Speaker 0: does the bell key?
Speaker 0: messing with them?
Speaker 1: It just sort of rolls around town checking shit out until it sees magic and then it freaks the fuck out and tries to kill People.
Speaker 0: right but that was only after they went and started using the magic near it wasn't messing with they.
Speaker 0: I think they messed with The bell first before the bell messed with them.
Speaker 1: Oh, but I point out not to really spoil But once you know what the bell was actually after they were pretty justified in fighting the bell.
Speaker 0: But I mean the bell was sort of.
Speaker 0: I mean, here's the thing right?
Speaker 0: That's the trick.
Speaker 0: That's what the bell is So smart.
Speaker 0: wait, you know, they attacked the bell right away.
Speaker 0: Did you do but remember Independence Day, right?
Speaker 0: It's like are these aliens peaceful or are they bad?
Speaker 0: and then so it's like well, we don't know yet So we can't attack yet.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: They're bad, right?
Speaker 0: It was like you don't know.
Speaker 1: until they do so, of course, I point out they did not attack it They simply flew up to it.
Speaker 0: Well, no the the opener the very beginning part of every episode which is actually really cool because they keep it completely silent because you Can't hear anything in space You know.
Speaker 0: and then as soon as you can hear it once the the opener gets down into the house I got that really not holding up CG from Gonzo Yeah, but they clearly the humans clearly went to war against the bell and laughs.
Speaker 1: but they point out before That in the overture it says the bell arrived and announced to the world that it was invading.
Speaker 0: okay, okay I guess that counts.
Speaker 0: but in you know, it wasn't invading like.
Speaker 1: and at the end the bell was like yeah, we were here to invade Yeah, but it didn't.
Speaker 0: it wasn't invading in a militaristic way I think it was.
Speaker 0: I think it just was didn't have all the info yet It was yeah, it had years and years and years of reconnaissance.
Speaker 1: Yes, and it wasn't done.
Speaker 0: It wasn't done with his reconnaissance What was really cool.
Speaker 0: this is one of the and if they're doing reconnaissance in plain sight like here I am.
Speaker 1: No, any live planes big black balls rolling on the show is basically that this magic users Club antagonizes the bell and It's a cast of five just actually I'd say really strong really well done characters that complement each other.
Speaker 1: Well, and what is a very heartwarming?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean even the weakest character the the sort of the girl who's I guess semi famous.
Speaker 1: Any of their names?
Speaker 1: can you name anyone from the show?
Speaker 0: I forget them all.
Speaker 1: so not Sion Anika the two main characters.
Speaker 0: That's their names.
Speaker 1: Takeo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 1: Abras above.
Speaker 0: Are you looking at a list?
Speaker 1: Well, I remember them because of the.
Speaker 1: every time they did the eye catches or not the eye catches but the Caffeine, um, you know, they're like what's coming up in the next episode.
Speaker 1: They just scream each other's names over and over again.
Speaker 1: I Never watched the coming up in the next episode.
Speaker 0: Oh, you should have watched those.
Speaker 1: They were actually.
Speaker 1: that was a big part of my anime culture back in the day is watching that for every episode of every show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I never.
Speaker 1: I never watched the next episode bits except for initial D Don't miss it, but likes the main character Sion Anika that have this good thing going on with each other.
Speaker 1: They're kind of I don't know sighs one of those cute ditzy girls, but it's not.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there you can see sort of like some moe precursors present But they're so small and it's definitely not full-on moe.
Speaker 0: So it's like hey, whatever.
Speaker 1: Well while she has the moe precursors at the same time, she kicks some ass and takes some name.
Speaker 0: Well clearly, you know, it's not it.
Speaker 0: So I'm saying is there?
Speaker 0: the precursors are pretty much just like she falls down a lot.
Speaker 1: I love her as a character sighs.
Speaker 1: You're so cute.
Speaker 1: I enjoyed the way she interacted that one scene because she kept bumping into everyone and just being kind of klutzy.
Speaker 1: and the one time Akane is walking up and she turns around and she's like And they don't collide and she's like I did it.
Speaker 0: I Think the best character though is the is Oberetsubo, no, well, he's alright, but the Jeff the sidekick girl who Danica Yeah, the spunky girl who's like you should quit this fucking club.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz she's like the most, you know level-headed not weird one, you know.
Speaker 1: I would say that Akane the fashion girl is equally level-headed.
Speaker 1: She just doesn't care.
Speaker 0: Yeah, kinda but it's like she just has really strong magic for some reason.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it just has kind of a spin to it.
Speaker 0: And every time she gets mad you just spins.
Speaker 0: I don't know why This happens now.
Speaker 1: I don't it's hard to say if my perception was colored though because I actually Because we just did a show on dubs and sub.
Speaker 1: I watched the center Niklaus dub.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: Most dubs are bad.
Speaker 1: This dub is not great, but it is not terrible.
Speaker 1: I actually do not Disrecommend the dub.
Speaker 0: I watch this up.
Speaker 1: Nanaka is of course Lisa Ortez, you know, it's all like good.
Speaker 1: Well relatively good American voice actors and surprisingly the Japanese cast is pretty high-powered.
Speaker 1: They got a while junco to do Akane.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm famous singer and Takehito Koyasu Shit plays Oberetsubo, of course Of course good.
Speaker 1: I do like the one scene where you know, cuz part of the plot is that Oberetsubo is totally gay for the main character.
Speaker 0: Yep Like I'm the one it's.
Speaker 0: it's weird because it's all stereotypical tropes.
Speaker 0: Well, no because he's sort of acting in such a strong Come on way that you almost think he's just sarcastically fooling around kind of a put-on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but he's not actually gay for the main character, but no he actually is gay for the main character.
Speaker 0: I love
Speaker 1: that scene where they're staying over in the beach house and he's just laying there obviously Dreaming about something cuz it's
Speaker 0: like if I was like if I go to rim and I'm like, hey, baby, you know People be like, okay, he's just joking around right, you know, they might you know say mad, but you know, it's joking around.
Speaker 0: But the thing is he's like hey, baby, but he's not joking.
Speaker 0: He really wants him.
Speaker 1: There's that one scene where they're sleeping in the same room together He's just kind of freaking out weird and fantasizing and then and the main characters like I mustn't fall asleep I mustn't fall asleep.
Speaker 0: I wasn't Classic sort of.
Speaker 1: I guess it's the.
Speaker 1: this show if we have to review it has a lot of like if you watch it Stereotypical 90s anime like straight up all the tropes and yet it executes them Elegantly and humorously and it has really good animation.
Speaker 1: Oh, the animation is nothing not.
Speaker 0: and good, you know, except for the CGs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the animation is great.
Speaker 1: And I realized watching a lot of old anime recently not 70s anime which doesn't have this so much except for the mech stuff.
Speaker 1: but 90s OAVs in particular tend to one be way better than their equivalent TV shows.
Speaker 1: you know El Hazzard, Tenchi and two.
Speaker 0: they have
Speaker 1: that kind of old-world cell animation where there's tons of weird little comedic details all over the place like little facial expressions background characters make reacting to things and Everything's kind of moving and there's always stuff going on everywhere like
Speaker 0: a new type magazine in the trash can in the apartment.
Speaker 1: or you know Things on the posters are on the school like someone like in the foreground, you know, they're hitting on each other Whatever in the background.
Speaker 1: the two girls are like sharing this look Mm-hmm and like kind of whispering to each other.
Speaker 1: all these little Tiny details little shivers that the main character does every time he's hit on that are all you wouldn't even notice them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I don't know a lot of new crappy anime doesn't have anything like that.
Speaker 0: No They don't.
Speaker 1: they don't bother with like background details this weird specific kind of detail that you really see in these 90s OAVs.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of stuff you also see like manga backgrounds to that, you know.
Speaker 0: They just they don't.
Speaker 0: you know, not so many people are doing that anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the show also kind of elegantly like, you know with the duck like.
Speaker 1: they explained it like you said to a degree But they didn't really explain it explain it enough.
Speaker 1: but there's tons of other things like that that are just the world is presented to you and Yet beyond like it's presented to you as though this is just the way it is and they don't bother with the fanboy level of Explanation.
Speaker 1: they just give you enough to make the show work.
Speaker 1: A lot of modern shows either have the fanboy explanation like gunslinger girl type shows.
Speaker 1: You know where they go.
Speaker 1: like this is the specific bullshit of this specific bullshit moe.
Speaker 0: Well, they explain every single freaking.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, well, I think the one thing that the show really that makes the show really strong right is the alien part.
Speaker 0: Right is because if you look at all the old animes Especially the ones that we like or that were really really well liked it from the olden days, right?
Speaker 0: the one thing a great majority have that have in common is the Central sort of sci-fi mystery, right?
Speaker 0: Even if it wasn't some shows were sci-fi shows right such as say vote Tom's or Ava.
Speaker 1: Hey, let's go a step further.
Speaker 1: even look at fantasy shows like slayers.
Speaker 1: slayers is goofy comedy But it has the.
Speaker 0: here is the serious backdrop plot that if you just wrote down what that plot was I'm saying is that you know Somebody's old shows if they were sci-fi shows had a mystery at their core some sort of thing That is like to be discovered at the ending.
Speaker 0: It's like who what the hell is this mysterious thing that carries us through the show that's always in the background Right, even cowboy bebop has that right and pretty almost every you know, cool show You know macross everything has a sci-fi mystery even shows that are not sci-fi shows.
Speaker 0: Fancy la la right or you know stuff like that has a sci-fi mystery.
Speaker 0: not always Sci-fi no, but a lot of the times it is a sci-fi mystery at the core.
Speaker 1: I would pull back.
Speaker 1: There's two things, you know, what got me into anime other than the fact that it was crazy Ultraviolet cartoons I'd never seen before.
Speaker 1: cuz you know I was eight and I watched vampire hunter D but it was that there were.
Speaker 1: it was different and a lot of the old 90s anime was just really sci-fi or really fantasy really kind Of out there and had these plots and some of that is lacking from a lot of new stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think a lot of new shows right.
Speaker 0: they made mahoutsukai tie today.
Speaker 0: It would have been the magic club strike which is without the aliens Yeah, and then it's like well that totally ruins the whole thing.
Speaker 1: or they would have done like darker than black.
Speaker 1: We're all right.
Speaker 1: Here's a plot but one.
Speaker 1: the whole show focuses on this plot and to the plot is so.
Speaker 1: Either they hide it all from you and it's not kind of elegantly done or you just don't give a shit about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's all about.
Speaker 0: you have these characters so you can have this character drama.
Speaker 0: But you also have a you know and a sort of epic plot somewhere that you know for them to go do something.
Speaker 0: I think you get both at once.
Speaker 0: if you do just one without the other it doesn't work So well.
Speaker 1: in contrast things there's the scenes where like sighs being really cute practicing riding on a broom And then she makes a little butt saddle for it cuz her butt really hurt And that's hilarious.
Speaker 1: and yet simultaneously you have like the scene where Akane is reading the bells mind That was some deep sci-fi awesome action right there.
Speaker 1: Like if you took just that scene You could you would not be able to differentiate the show from a dead serious sci-fi drama masterpiece.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just from that scene extrapolated out.
Speaker 1: and if you did the comedy It's the exact same thing for comedy and the show elegantly blended the two together in a way that many Shows not just anime are not able to do well.
Speaker 0: Well, he's not able to do well recently, right?
Speaker 1: There's also a sort of idiosyncratic elegance like Jeffy or Jeff Coon.
Speaker 0: Jeff is the best.
Speaker 1: I love how.
Speaker 1: you know, there's kind of a Gandalf the gray element going on there Yeah, and there's also just the.
Speaker 1: that's just her cute little thing.
Speaker 1: Like it's just hanging like a cell phone charm on her broom.
Speaker 0: yeah, no, but there's the.
Speaker 0: What's it called?
Speaker 0: Right, if you look at more modern shows Right a lot of the shows today would are just the character parts and the only show, you know If I try to really think really hard about a recent show that actually has you know Character parts and the sci-fi mystery right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, look at like something like Haruhi has a sci-fi mystery.
Speaker 1: Hurry, actually, I think is the best example of a more recent show.
Speaker 1: that gives me the same Feelings that a show like mahout sky tie does.
Speaker 0: yeah, but you know other shows.
Speaker 0: I'd even put them in You know, yeah, they were definitely in the same genre.
Speaker 0: So, you know what is cool as a sci-fi mystery.
Speaker 1: straight out if you liked Haruhi you will love mahout sky tie and vice versa.
Speaker 0: Yeah straight
Speaker 1: up without any Reservation I say that,
Speaker 0: you know, but try to try to think like some other recent animes that have come out right and Some of them are just you know, I mean not too many of them at all really or sci-fi Or have any kind of
Speaker 1: action
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Okay, so Right, so that doesn't really have you know, the the mystery of anything that's that's pretty much just.
Speaker 1: the first season had the mystery Of you know, what's up with the head?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that was the what's up with the head was actually one of the characters dramas.
Speaker 0: it wasn't really this sort of background You know thing that nobody knew what was up.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess the way we can sum this all up is that mahout sky tie.
Speaker 1: at least for me.
Speaker 1: It reminded me of how much I fucking loved anime in the 90s.
Speaker 1: But it's it didn't tell me that 90s anime was better.
Speaker 1: specifically It just taught me that the anime I liked from the 90s still holds up today by and large.
Speaker 1: Well this one Yeah, well I try gun was probably the least holding up relative to what I expected of anything I've watched in recent memory that I had seen back in the day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you had to go.
Speaker 0: do a lot more re-watching.
Speaker 0: bring me.
Speaker 1: Let's remember a lot of shows that I have seen.
Speaker 1: I Expected not to hold up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Also, I don't you know, I don't remember if I watched or did not watch them.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's a Kai Tai TV.
Speaker 1: I've never seen the TV or have only seen the OAV?
Speaker 0: Like I don't even remember.
Speaker 0: so now I kind of want to go and check out the TV to see like did I see the TV?
Speaker 0: did I not see the TV?
Speaker 0: how much of the TV did I see?
Speaker 0: if I saw any is it good?
Speaker 0: Is it bad?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: how similar is the OAV?
Speaker 0: who knows mystery?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean it picks up pretty much right where the OAV leaves off really so the aliens have been vanquished.
Speaker 1: Ah, there's just the fucking tree.
Speaker 1: Oh really and now they got to deal with the tree, but it's just a tree.
Speaker 0: What's the problem?
Speaker 1: It's blocking out the Sun and the road.
Speaker 1: the pedals are busting everything up in Tokyo Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they could be alright, baby but yeah That gets an interesting.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah But anyway, I mean I don't want to really like.
Speaker 1: I could talk a lot about all my favorite scenes and why I think they're Great, like.
Speaker 0: no, we don't need to do that.
Speaker 1: It's like what he's like when he one more when he's doing the the magic show for the manga club on the beach.
Speaker 0: That's a good one.
Speaker 1: And it's the magic shows.
Speaker 1: great and then he whips out the truth teller.
Speaker 1: But then look at the the mark of an elegant show.
Speaker 1: they do the wow Thing with the truth teller and of course they bring it back.
Speaker 1: but they bring it back in such a subtle and Heartwarming and kind of sad way and it's that the show very bled blends Very well the drama and the comedy and the sci-fi all together.
Speaker 1: and just a great show.
Speaker 1: Yeah a solid B anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah You should watch this show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much any anime fan should watch this.
Speaker 0: It's only six episodes.
Speaker 0: You can watch this show.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna kill you and if you enjoy it at all one You know.
Speaker 1: watch like Haruhi if you like this.
Speaker 1: if you liked Haruhi watch this.
Speaker 1: also check out other similar OAVs, like I don't know El Hazzard the original Tenchi OAV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was hard.
Speaker 0: that had the you know, the sci-fi mystery at the core.
Speaker 0: So did the original Tenchi OAV the original original Yeah, not any of the others.
Speaker 1: No, no the Tenchi every Tenchi other than the original Ryo Oki OAV.
Speaker 1: Not so great.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand Okay for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.