Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, October 26th, 2011.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights tonight because I am actually in Japan.
Speaker 0: We are continuing with our coverage of the new 52, week 2.
Speaker 1: Boogaloo.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So as promised, week 2 of the 52.
Speaker 0: We'll just go right down the list.
Speaker 1: I can't wait for this to be over.
Speaker 1: Alright, so...
Speaker 0: I feel like week 1 was... better?
Speaker 0: Like, I enjoyed reading week 1.
Speaker 1: According to my... I don't remember, 'cause it's... or I read these a while ago.
Speaker 1: But looking at my little spreadsheet here, week 2 was the worst week by far.
Speaker 0: Week 2 was definitely the worst week.
Speaker 1: Alright, so let's just go into it.
Speaker 1: The first one was Batman and Robin.
Speaker 0: So here's what pisses me off.
Speaker 1: Yet another Batman book.
Speaker 0: Right away.
Speaker 0: Obviously they know Batman is their strongest franchise because Batman is in, like, all these comics.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like 30-40% of the books.
Speaker 0: Every Batman is different.
Speaker 0: Like, way different in how he's presented.
Speaker 0: And it's kind of annoying.
Speaker 1: It's not the same Batman in all the different books.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing with the Superman.
Speaker 1: The action comic.
Speaker 1: Superman was clearly not the Superman in the other books.
Speaker 1: It's like, these are different people here, but you're supposed to try to tell me it's the same person?
Speaker 1: I can't believe it.
Speaker 0: The Superman was a little... like, there was too much of him being kind of sardonic and Robin being a punk-ass bitch kid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, you don't know if you're getting Mad Batman or Sad Batman or- I was getting, like, Stern Dad Batman.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, which one is gonna show up this time?
Speaker 1: You know, I mean, fanfiction does a better job of getting characters right than this.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like, if I go read, you know, a fanfiction of, say, Spider-Man, it's gonna be Spider-Man.
Speaker 0: Spider-Man having sex with a tiger version of Spider-Man.
Speaker 1: Even though he's doing weird things, his personality will be recognizable as Spider-Man.
Speaker 1: 'Cause, you know, when people do fanfiction, it's 'cause they like the character, and they make the character like the character.
Speaker 1: Here, it's like, who is Batman, really?
Speaker 1: What is Batman's personality?
Speaker 0: But a miserable pile of sad.
Speaker 1: It depends which of the 13 or 14 different books you read, 'cause there's a different Bruce Wayne in each one.
Speaker 0: At least we know that the worst Batman was from last week on Justice League International.
Speaker 0: That was like Guy in Batman's clothes.
Speaker 1: That was Super Friends Batman.
Speaker 0: Maybe that's it.
Speaker 0: There are like 10 guys who are Batman, and they're all actually different.
Speaker 1: Well, that actually, I think, from what I understand, is there was a Batman Incorporated something, where there were like franchised Batmans.
Speaker 0: Well, isn't that like Nightwing?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think that there were actually Batmans who were not Bruce Wayne.
Speaker 1: Is it Batman?
Speaker 1: But the thing is, all of these Batmans are Bruce Wayne.
Speaker 1: Batman Incorporated was like, okay, you're Batman.
Speaker 1: You're another Batman.
Speaker 1: You're Batman Paris or something, but you're not Bruce Wayne.
Speaker 1: These are all supposed to be Bruce Wayne and Batman.
Speaker 0: I guess with this one, the plot started out.
Speaker 0: okay, but I really... I don't need to deal with... Batman dealing with his parents' deaths no longer interests me.
Speaker 1: Well, that's something I liked in some of the other books.
Speaker 1: It skipped over the origin bullshit.
Speaker 0: And it kind of kept like, you know, this is the last time I'm going to celebrate the death.
Speaker 0: I'm going to celebrate the life instead.
Speaker 0: And that was all neat and good, but it's tired because Batman's a tired old character.
Speaker 0: I don't care anymore that he's sad that his parents were killed by whoever killed them, depending on what continuity you're looking at.
Speaker 1: Okay, so here's the notes that I wrote, right?
Speaker 1: So first, a lot of the art looked like they were underwater when they weren't underwater.
Speaker 1: There was like a haze over it or something.
Speaker 1: I don't know what's up with that.
Speaker 0: It wasn't that bad though.
Speaker 0: I kind of like the art.
Speaker 1: No, it's not too bad.
Speaker 1: It was just average.
Speaker 1: Okay, this is what I understand.
Speaker 1: You have all these different Robins, right?
Speaker 0: I guess they're all dead from the past?
Speaker 1: There's like four or five of them, and I think the dead ones are back to life or whatever.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: But here's the question, right?
Speaker 1: That Justice League number one... I keep going back to that Justice League number one because it was the first book that came out, right?
Speaker 1: That Justice League number one was supposed to be how many years ago?
Speaker 1: Five years ago.
Speaker 0: So in the span of five years...
Speaker 1: In the span of five years, there are all those Robins?
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Not only that... Really?
Speaker 0: This is supposed to be a number one.
Speaker 1: You started from scratch and you've already fucked it up.
Speaker 0: And I'm fine if you've started in media res.
Speaker 0: I like that, in fact.
Speaker 0: But I feel like too many of these number ones are trying to shoehorn in backstory that nerds already know anyway to have an excuse to use it in number twos and number threes.
Speaker 1: And not help itself by shoehorning in Adam West with the bat poles.
Speaker 1: I'm surprised they didn't use the clock to open it and not the Shakespeare bust.
Speaker 0: That was actually part of my problem with this one.
Speaker 0: It was a little too campy in its plot.
Speaker 1: It's weird.
Speaker 1: It tried to take the campiness and put a dark shade in front of it.
Speaker 0: That's exactly what I was going to say.
Speaker 0: There's a veneer of dark, badass Batman, but underneath it's Adam West.
Speaker 0: I think the biggest example of that was that the radiation was going to leak out and Batman just totally busts open the pool that happens to be above it.
Speaker 1: That might as well have been shark repellent.
Speaker 0: When he had the net to catch all the kids who fell through the hole, that did it.
Speaker 0: But then they're dark when Robin effectively totally was like, "I'm going to fucking kill those guys.
Speaker 0: Shut up, Batman.
Speaker 0: You're not the boss of me.
Speaker 0: I can kill people if I want
Speaker 0: to.".
Speaker 1: The other thing I didn't like was there's something going on in Moscow.
Speaker 1: Obviously they're going to tie it in later, but it's like you're reading two separate things going on that aren't related at all within the entire comic.
Speaker 1: A comic book is a single work, so you can have that disjoint.
Speaker 1: show me one place, show me the other place over a trade.
Speaker 1: But this is a single comic.
Speaker 1: It has to make sense within itself.
Speaker 1: All that Moscow stuff just felt thrown in and out of nowhere because it never tied together within the entire issue.
Speaker 0: Well it did, in that the Moscow guy probably wanted the radioactive doomedads that Batman stopped from being stolen.
Speaker 1: The only way you can assume that is because they happen to be in the same book on adjacent pages.
Speaker 0: Which is why I assume.
Speaker 0: Also because the guy lowered the two dead guys from before into that vat of acid.
Speaker 0: Which was kind of a weird scene in the way it was drawn.
Speaker 0: They're kind of hanging in space.
Speaker 0: It felt like they were going with almost two different styles in Moscow and I guess Gotham.
Speaker 0: Didn't feel like Gotham.
Speaker 1: So anyway, I gave this a meh.
Speaker 1: What did you give this?
Speaker 0: I almost want to say it's bad.
Speaker 0: It's not even worth my time.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 0: I'm going to say bad.
Speaker 1: Oh, bad.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: Because I wouldn't read number two even if we had it.
Speaker 0: I just don't care.
Speaker 1: I also don't care.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: Batwoman.
Speaker 1: Not Batgirl.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: I don't remember this really.
Speaker 1: It's been a while and I don't have the book on hand to bring it back to memory.
Speaker 0: Batwoman is really pale.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about Batwoman.
Speaker 0: But I was talking to Daryl Surratt about this and he told me that Batwoman, this one, was written before the 52 thing happened.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: Which is why it kind of just picks up.
Speaker 0: It's funny because it kind of works as number one.
Speaker 0: Because it's completely in media res with zero backstory.
Speaker 0: It's just, hey, Batwoman.
Speaker 0: Here's Batwoman.
Speaker 1: I wrote down, let's see, the plot can't stay focused.
Speaker 1: And I wrote down that the art was actually awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it started out really strong.
Speaker 0: Batwoman is investigating the ghost.
Speaker 0: that's drowning people.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And there's like a teenage gang or something and she goes after her, right?
Speaker 0: That was like an afterthought.
Speaker 0: It was almost like an Adam West flashback to her and her equivalent of Robin.
Speaker 1: There's like a weird serial killing kind of thing going around and she's chasing it and she ends up at some house.
Speaker 0: But independently she's got her Robin who has a superhero name, I guess.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about the Batwoman.
Speaker 1: I don't think that that person is a Robin.
Speaker 1: I think it's actually a superhero girlfriend from another group or something.
Speaker 0: But now she's training to be Batwoman's Robin.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: But she had a uniform from before and Batwoman seems to do the same dialogue.
Speaker 0: It might as well be Batman.
Speaker 0: When she's in Batwoman mode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is bad.
Speaker 1: I don't want it.
Speaker 0: The art was good to a degree.
Speaker 0: I liked the...
Speaker 1: Yeah, the art was great.
Speaker 0: I really liked that two page spread of all the people talking around the center image of the kind of drowned woman Rusalka, almost like a stained glass thing.
Speaker 0: But otherwise the plot really was not...
Speaker 1: Make an art book, dude.
Speaker 0: If the plot had just straight up been Batwoman investigates the ghost that murders children.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they could have concentrated on it and only on like one murder as opposed to the whole string.
Speaker 1: Oh, it could have been the whole string.
Speaker 0: That would have been fine.
Speaker 0: If it didn't also have the I'm training a Robin and all that other... If it had just been that story, like one episode of BTAS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean, it was meh.
Speaker 0: It wasn't bad.
Speaker 0: I would read it, but I wouldn't buy it.
Speaker 0: Definitely a meh.
Speaker 0: I just... It wasn't grabbing me.
Speaker 1: So far we got meh bad and bad meh.
Speaker 0: And I wonder why she's so pale.
Speaker 1: Alright, so Deathstroke.
Speaker 1: I actually remember this.
Speaker 0: I like this one kinda.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Because it reminded me of Cable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it sure did.
Speaker 1: Basically you have this, you know, some government, another acronym organization.
Speaker 1: He wants to hire, or government thing, wants to hire a guy to do something.
Speaker 0: Ah, but Deathstroke's too old.
Speaker 0: It's almost like a Dark Knight Returns situation.
Speaker 1: He's too old for this shit, but he's the ultimate badass assassin guy.
Speaker 1: He gets the job done like Golgo 13.
Speaker 0: Alright, obviously spoilers.
Speaker 0: Fuck you guys.
Speaker 1: I actually wrote Golgo 13.
Speaker 0: He basically is Golgo 13.
Speaker 0: I kind of actually did not see coming him murdering his entire team at the end of the first issue.
Speaker 1: I saw that coming.
Speaker 0: I didn't know anything about this character.
Speaker 1: He was basically... I didn't know anything about him either.
Speaker 1: But I know he's like an incredible badass.
Speaker 1: You know, the loner, awesome assassin Golgo 13 guy.
Speaker 1: And suddenly he gets tricked into working with these kids.
Speaker 1: Usually in those cases, it's like, you know, the guy will be like, "Oh yeah, I'm not working with these kids.
Speaker 1: Get them the fuck out of
Speaker 1: here.".
Speaker 1: But he actually went along with it.
Speaker 1: And as soon as he went along with it, I'm like, "Oh, they're all gonna
Speaker 1: die.".
Speaker 0: Well, I thought they were gonna die.
Speaker 1: He wouldn't go along with it if he wasn't gonna teach them a lesson about how he works alone.
Speaker 0: I thought they were going to die in the course of the mission or something.
Speaker 1: If Golgo 13 got an assistant, they would be dead.
Speaker 0: I did not expect them to be murdered by him just outright at the end of the issue.
Speaker 1: Especially since because they weren't superheroes, you knew that they were done.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, I was like, you know, when he killed them, I was like, "Oh, the slightly clever idea of instead of them dying on the mission, he killed them.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Cool.
Speaker 1: Whatever.".
Speaker 0: He's a little too stereotypical badass though.
Speaker 0: I feel like if I want to read this kind of story, I'll read Golgo 13.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like...
Speaker 0: If I want to read about an emotionless, unstoppable killing machine, that's what I'm gonna read.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: He was such... Even though he was a badass, he was such a vanilla badass.
Speaker 1: He didn't have any... At least Deadpool has humor or attempts at humor.
Speaker 1: You know, failed attempts.
Speaker 1: At least there is an attempt.
Speaker 1: They don't even try.
Speaker 1: It's just like, he's just a badass.
Speaker 1: There's no... Even Golgo 13 has a style with his quiet and his dot, dot, dot.
Speaker 1: And he's always raping some girl or whatever.
Speaker 1: But this guy had nothing other than, "I kill people and I awesome at
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 0: "And I work alone.
Speaker 0: I'm not too old for this
Speaker 0: shit.".
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Also, did you notice on the one page, they threw in a J. Jonas Jameson?
Speaker 1: It's like,
Speaker 1: "What?".
Speaker 1: This is Marvel Comics, dude.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, the actual action that was going on when he boards that plane, it reminded me of Air Force One in that it was kind of...
Speaker 1: Yeah, boarding the plane in flight is an old, "We need the extreme action scene.
Speaker 1: Let's do
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 0: But the action was otherwise just kind of lame, and they threw in the weird alien plot and then immediately forgot about the word alien plot.
Speaker 0: Granted, it's one issue.
Speaker 0: I'm sure that's gonna come back.
Speaker 1: Obviously.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I had no intention of reading this.
Speaker 0: Why didn't they just fucking shoot the plane down?
Speaker 0: They did not need to send him onto the plane.
Speaker 1: 'Cause it wouldn't have made it such a badass action scene.
Speaker 1: He wouldn't have been a badass if he just shot a rocket at a plane.
Speaker 0: It's just, it's meh.
Speaker 1: I put meh.
Speaker 0: I put meh on it.
Speaker 0: Because I wouldn't mind knowing what he does next.
Speaker 1: If someone told me.
Speaker 1: I just don't care at all.
Speaker 0: See, I can't say bad on something like this, because I got other things to say bad about.
Speaker 1: Right, well, if he had some character to him, I would have put maybe even good.
Speaker 1: You know, it was that, that just made the huge difference there.
Speaker 1: It was just that there was no character at all.
Speaker 1: In fact, those kids that died had actual character to them.
Speaker 0: They were a stereotypical 24 assistant, basically.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but actually I would have rather read a book about them, would have been meh.
Speaker 0: You just read a book about them.
Speaker 1: But a book about Deathstroke would have been bad.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's bad.
Speaker 1: Alright, so, Demon Knights.
Speaker 0: So, this is just straight up fantasy, but it's written like superhero comic.
Speaker 1: Right, that's, it was so weird, 'cause like, when it started getting all fantasy, I was like, oh, actually, I'm kind of- This is, like, I was kind of digging it, like, alright.
Speaker 1: Like, even though it's a little bit of that R.A.
Speaker 1: Salvatore kind of fantasy.
Speaker 0: But, like, the bad guys had their thing.
Speaker 0: where they're, you get the sense that they're conflicted villains, like, they're doing evil for a greater good.
Speaker 0: At least, they believe it to be a greater good.
Speaker 1: Actually, it felt almost like a slayers plot without the comedy.
Speaker 0: I was also reminded slightly of, take the plot of Bone, not the character.
Speaker 1: Like a light surface level fantasy.
Speaker 1: that's not, it's not, you know, a Lord of the Rings or a Prince of Nothing.
Speaker 1: It's just an adventury party going to stabby stabby, you know?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, like, the child's death was regrettable, and all this, the villains were conflicted.
Speaker 0: Also, the cover art was hideous.
Speaker 1: I looked at the cover, and I was like, blech.
Speaker 1: But then, when I looked in the book, I was like, oh, this is pretty great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I liked seeing Merlin, and I liked how the demon is like, uh, yeah, the guy who I'm possessing is kind of a fuckwit, but whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and he talks, they're in the inn, and the inn explodes, of course, and the girl is like, you know, she acts like she's friends with the guy who's possessed by the demon, sort of a birdie the mighty, almost.
Speaker 1: But then when the demon comes out, she's like, yeah, let's just not let that jerk know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like it rough.
Speaker 0: They start making out, and then they fight, and then at the end, it's like, but it got a little derpy.
Speaker 0: at the end, when the villains are like, we'll do what we always do when there's a problem.
Speaker 0: We throw dragons at it, and then, oh, shit, a dragon appears and attacks the inn.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that, you know, that derpiness combined with the fact that the plot was a little bit all over the place.
Speaker 1: It didn't have enough focus.
Speaker 1: I think that's what put it to meh.
Speaker 1: If they would've just made it, like, you know, kept with that fantasy aspect more strongly, it could've been good, but it's meh.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would like it, but they got too much superhero on my fantasy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it's--.
Speaker 0: Also, the action scenes, where they're actually fighting in the inn, were pretty incomprehensible.
Speaker 0: Like, I couldn't tell what was going on, and I lost track of who was who, and it kept, like, focusing on all these other people that I worry that maybe people who know these characters would recognize them, but I had no idea.
Speaker 1: I'd known about the demon, 'cause he was in Wednesday comics, but the Wednesday comics is nothing like this at all.
Speaker 1: It might as well have been a separate character.
Speaker 0: So, it came down to meh.
Speaker 1: It's like demon Etrigan, yeah, meh.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Could've been good.
Speaker 1: Had potential.
Speaker 1: Unfulfilled potential.
Speaker 0: So, let's talk about the other Jeff Lemire.
Speaker 1: So, Jeff Lemire, who has so far done no wrong.
Speaker 0: Agent of acronym.
Speaker 1: Agent of acronym group.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the first, if you notice, like, the first two pages actually look like a Jeff Lemire book.
Speaker 1: They do.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure he drew those first two pages, especially that second page looks a lot like the sweet tooth, you know, with that dead dog there and everything, and the monsters coming out of the woods, right?
Speaker 1: So, I was reading these first three pages, and I'm like, "Yeah, Jeff Lemire, all
Speaker 1: right.".
Speaker 1: After those first three pages, it's like, "Is it still Jeff
Speaker 1: Lemire?"
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 0: It's like-- Yeah, I kind of wish it would've kept up with what it was doing.
Speaker 0: It turned into a weird-- It reminds me of manga.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Like, random-- I was not reminded of that at all.
Speaker 0: Partly because the mad scientist put himself in the body of a schoolgirl, and-- Okay, yeah, that visual aspect, sure.
Speaker 0: And just kind of the way the mad scientist talked.
Speaker 0: It reminded me of Washu from Tenchi Muyo.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: A lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this reminded me more of, like, crappy Hellboy wannabe, right?
Speaker 1: I think Jeff Lemire was definitely phoning it in on this.
Speaker 1: Or at least I feel like he was.
Speaker 1: It's just like, "Okay, "acronym org science organization "gets a group of powerful guys together "to go fight acronym bad guy
Speaker 1: organization.".
Speaker 0: Now, it could've been fun if it had been a little more over the top.
Speaker 0: Exactly, that's true.
Speaker 0: It didn't go over the top enough.
Speaker 1: Right, it's like you had this mummy who was kind of silly and mysterious and some of these other characters, right?
Speaker 0: And Franklin sounds like, "Where's my wife?
Speaker 0: "Oh, whatever, I'm too old for this
Speaker 0: shit.".
Speaker 1: But see, that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: It's like Hellboy goes to the extremes.
Speaker 1: He either gets the really funny BPRD kind of Hellboy wisecracking or the incredibly dark Cthulhu Hellboy, right?
Speaker 1: This was just sort of in between with both at the same time.
Speaker 1: Hellboy shows you one and then the other, you know, back and forth.
Speaker 1: This had them both at the same time all the time in the middle.
Speaker 0: It never felt dark or serious.
Speaker 0: It just felt like it was trying to be funny.
Speaker 0: I mean, the whole explanation of we made our base in this tiny microscopic bullshit explanation.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, this is the one with the base and the floating ball, right?
Speaker 1: Are you seriously telling me no one just come and smash that fucking thing?
Speaker 0: You don't need to explain your bullshit to me.
Speaker 0: and if you're gonna explain it, explain it in context.
Speaker 0: Don't just, you know, tell me it and it's stupid.
Speaker 1: And it didn't matter at all.
Speaker 0: Maybe if it didn't matter.
Speaker 0: Like, if they'd explained that and then like four pages later Frankenstein ate it or something, that would've been awesome.
Speaker 0: But they didn't do that.
Speaker 1: Just a bunch of proper nouns and nonsense.
Speaker 0: I don't want to say bad because I kind of like the art, but I don't want to read more of it because I just don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: I put bad.
Speaker 1: Jeff Lemire, you know, no one's perfect.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm gonna agree with you and put bad because I'm not gonna read more.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: So, alright.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: I feel like we should do Green Lantern number one and Red Lanterns together.
Speaker 1: Okay, we can skip around.
Speaker 1: So, Green Lantern.
Speaker 0: You told me that these were 52 number ones.
Speaker 0: That this, I can start reading this and I don't need to know about your universe.
Speaker 0: So, who the fuck is Sinestro?
Speaker 1: I think it's Sinestro.
Speaker 0: This made no goddamn sense.
Speaker 0: I might as well have picked up Green Lantern issue 1008.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: This is, you know, go listen to our episode we did about Green Lantern Rebirth because this Green Lantern is still the same shit even though it's how many issues later.
Speaker 1: Same crap.
Speaker 0: Like, everything is explained in the stupid derpy comic book superhero way.
Speaker 0: All these characters, I don't know who they are.
Speaker 0: Pointless exposition.
Speaker 0: Ludicrous space sector gobbledygook bullshit.
Speaker 0: What the hell?
Speaker 1: This doesn't even seem to... And the thing is, at least it partially makes sense even though I know so little about Green Lantern.
Speaker 1: Oh, it does.
Speaker 0: Obviously, this is a bad guy.
Speaker 0: Who is forced to be a good guy, doesn't want to be but he's probably actually really good at heart for whatever reason and he's gonna be the reluctant good guy in the end.
Speaker 1: But here's the thing, right?
Speaker 1: There's two aspects to the continuity, right?
Speaker 1: That, you know, you only get this comic because you read what came before.
Speaker 1: One is the understanding, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know what's going on because I don't know the history of Green Lantern.
Speaker 1: This doesn't have that problem that much.
Speaker 1: It has a little bit, but not that much.
Speaker 1: The problem it really has is I don't care because I haven't read the hit, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, unless you're already invested and you care about these characters and already know about them, unless you already care, this comic has no meaning for you.
Speaker 1: It's like, what's the emotional impact of this guy saying this thing if I don't already care about Green Lanterns?
Speaker 0: And I don't care.
Speaker 1: It only has an emotional impact if you already know and care.
Speaker 1: So even if you understand it, the fact that you don't care makes the whole comic just completely vacant of anything.
Speaker 0: I read it and I felt nothing at the end.
Speaker 0: Green Lantern is bad, but it bothers me too.
Speaker 0: I don't like continuity between, you know, comics, the whole "I gotta read all these comics to make sense of it,".
Speaker 0: but the Green Lantern stuff going on in all the other DC comics seems to have no goddamn relation to this Green Lantern stuff.
Speaker 1: Well, that's no different from the Batman or the Superman stuff.
Speaker 0: But it's like almost negative continuity.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see, this is, you know, I was surprised at some of the other Geoff Johns books.
Speaker 1: I've always hated everything he's ever done, you know.
Speaker 1: We're actually kind of okay, but this one is typical Geoff Johns, don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: But as bad as Green Lantern was, Red Lantern takes the page.
Speaker 1: Was somehow worse.
Speaker 1: Like, I wish I had double bad.
Speaker 0: First off, I gotta bring this up again.
Speaker 0: There's a page when the woman, the Red Lantern woman with the gigantic boobs and the skeleton wings What page number is it?
Speaker 0: There's no page numbers.
Speaker 0: It is page, let's see, if I count every page other than the cover, including the ads, but not including the cover piece of paper, one, two, three, four, five, six.
Speaker 0: On page seven, she's picking poop out of her butt.
Speaker 1: She sure is.
Speaker 0: She just pulled her finger out of her butt and there's poop on it.
Speaker 1: There is.
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: There's no other way to interpret that.
Speaker 1: That's one of those accidental arts, right?
Speaker 1: Because he just drew someone in a typical comic pose.
Speaker 0: But why did they draw the poop?
Speaker 1: He drew the typical comic pose of someone with their hand in a claw behind them to be menacing, like, ahh, right?
Speaker 1: And it just so happened that the hand is supposed to be in front of the butt.
Speaker 1: Not on the butt.
Speaker 1: But the finger happens to align with the edge of the butt.
Speaker 1: And they also did that thing where there's sort of sparks coming off the finger.
Speaker 1: But they're black poop sparks.
Speaker 1: It's because the finger's near the butt and the sparks.
Speaker 1: it looks like she just picked some dingleberries out.
Speaker 0: There are not black poop sparks on her other hand or on any of her other fingers.
Speaker 0: It is just the finger that just picked the butt.
Speaker 0: And I don't know what's going on.
Speaker 0: There's, I guess there's a bunch of red lanterns and they're all insane except for one of them?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just like there's a pack of wild dogs.
Speaker 0: And they're almost, like, they say weird stuff like they're trying to think, but they can't.
Speaker 0: They're full of rage and they're fighting with each other all the time.
Speaker 1: I think the red lanterns are supposed to be, if my understanding is correct, the rage, right?
Speaker 1: Each lantern is supposed to mean something.
Speaker 0: But the main red lantern doesn't have this problem.
Speaker 1: So it's like red lantern is rage and I think orange is greedy or something.
Speaker 0: But the main red lantern is totally, like, with it.
Speaker 0: And he's just kind of, like, musing over things.
Speaker 0: But then, like, a fever pod explodes nearby and covers him in blood and the pain is unbearable.
Speaker 0: And I just, fever pod?
Speaker 0: Like, what?
Speaker 1: Is this the one where the rings started running away from people?
Speaker 1: Or is that a different one?
Speaker 0: That's the other one.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: This is just weird bullshit.
Speaker 1: Let me see it again.
Speaker 1: I haven't looked.
Speaker 0: And then it cuts to this weird flashback where the red lantern guy's like, "My whole sector got wiped
Speaker 0: out."
Speaker 0: And it shows his family getting killed in front of his eyes.
Speaker 0: That is one of the most derpy, poorly executed examples of that I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow.
Speaker 1: There's, like, nothing really happens in this at all, does it?
Speaker 1: No, other than the poop.
Speaker 1: Like, I'm flipping through it and, like, there's nothing that happens.
Speaker 1: It's basically just a bunch of red lanterns going, "RAH!
Speaker 1: We're red lanterns!
Speaker 1: RAAH!".
Speaker 0: Yep, and the guy's saying, "It sucks.
Speaker 0: Everything's
Speaker 0: pain.".
Speaker 1: And what the fuck?
Speaker 1: This cat, the double-page spread of the cat lantern?
Speaker 1: It's like, that cat lantern is there just for, like, fanboy appeal.
Speaker 1: Poop got a single page.
Speaker 0: Like, "Oh my god, there's a cat lantern!
Speaker 0: Lulz!
Speaker 1: They should have made the cat long.
Speaker 1: It would have been
Speaker 1: funnier.".
Speaker 0: I just... Naito manga makes more sense than this red lantern.
Speaker 0: I just read.
Speaker 0: However, this red lantern still is a paragon of linear storytelling compared to Legion Lost.
Speaker 1: You want to go to Legion?
Speaker 1: Alright, Legion Lost.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess we didn't actually review that yet, did we?
Speaker 1: No, do you want to?
Speaker 1: Let's go to it.
Speaker 0: Give me my list back.
Speaker 0: Legion Lost.
Speaker 0: I wrote notes for these.
Speaker 1: Legion Lost is the worst.
Speaker 0: So I gotta say, I wrote a note for another one.
Speaker 0: I threw away the notes I wrote from week one, since we're already passed on week two.
Speaker 0: But for one of the other entries, I wrote, "What the
Speaker 0: fuck?".
Speaker 0: Oh, Olmec, I wrote, and I quote, "What the fuck did I just
Speaker 0: read?".
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I wrote that again and underlined it for Legion Lost.
Speaker 1: Okay, so Legion Lost, here's my youngest.
Speaker 1: read my notes.
Speaker 1: Ready?
Speaker 1: Samoflange.
Speaker 1: Flashpoint Breakwall, proper nouns.
Speaker 0: The girl with the antennas who transforms all the time is kind of cute.
Speaker 1: "What is after release?
Speaker 1: Bad art.
Speaker 1: At least the others that weren't really number one were
Speaker 1: comprehensible.".
Speaker 1: I actually asked people at Comic-Con, I went to a guy that I know knows more DC Comics stuff than anyone.
Speaker 1: And I asked him, "Legion
Speaker 1: Lost."
Speaker 1: And he's like, "Yeah, there are even people who know all about the Legion that couldn't understand what the fuck was going
Speaker 1: on.".
Speaker 0: Daryl Surratt said it best.
Speaker 0: It is a number one, and we were talking on chat today, in that it's as incomprehensible as any other number one in Legion Lost.
Speaker 1: Yeah, from what I understand, the Legion of Superheroes is basically, in some years in the future, way in the future, from the ranks of the DC Universe, there's a whole legion of superheroes, like this big super team, right?
Speaker 1: And they have flight rings, so even if they can't fly, they all get rings so they can fly.
Speaker 0: Because otherwise, I don't know.
Speaker 1: And they all get sent, and there's a ton of them.
Speaker 1: Tons of them.
Speaker 1: And they're all in this one team.
Speaker 1: Like, imagine if Justice League was all the heroes.
Speaker 1: And they all split up into teams and go on missions in different places.
Speaker 1: And, you know, even if you read all the Legion comics in the beginning, even big fans of this sort of, it's almost like a sub-universe.
Speaker 1: Like a demi-universe.
Speaker 0: Because they time travel to multiple dimensions all over the place.
Speaker 1: They time travel all over the fuck, and there's a ten billion characters, so people don't understand it.
Speaker 1: So this Legion Lost, in particular, is about one group of legionnaires who are in a time bubble, who they travel in time and get trapped in a place, and something happens there.
Speaker 1: That's all I can figure out.
Speaker 0: I don't know if anything actually happened.
Speaker 0: I can't...
Speaker 1: Aren't they trapped there because the time bubble is smashed?
Speaker 1: The time bubble!
Speaker 0: Something's wrong!
Speaker 0: Don't let it crash!
Speaker 0: And then it crashes, and some guy yells, "The Time Institute warned the Legion of Superheroes not to ride the time stream,
Speaker 0: Timberwolf!".
Speaker 1: Yeah, first of all, this has- "My bad!
Speaker 0: Baphmadad will control your scuba-doo and kill the
Speaker 0: fuckmadad!".
Speaker 1: That's why I wrote down
Speaker 1: "Baphmadad.".
Speaker 0: It's just, everyone says things that can only be described as, "I will hit you, you little guy, with the samoflange, because samoflanges do
Speaker 0: Baphmadad.".
Speaker 1: Right, so, the thing is, this book has something that exemplifies one thing that is a problem across all superhero comics, or many of them, but this has it the most.
Speaker 0: It's bad?
Speaker 1: Yes, but it has the character.
Speaker 1: that's not a character at all, right?
Speaker 1: Remember how I talked about how Deathstroke was sort of vanilla?
Speaker 1: But at least he was a badass.
Speaker 1: In this, what you have is you basically have people standing there in costumes with powers, right, and names.
Speaker 1: They're a superhero name, a superhero costume, and that's it.
Speaker 1: They don't have any personality or anything.
Speaker 1: You can just shuffle all the characters around between the speech bubbles, and it wouldn't make a difference.
Speaker 0: It is much like Final Fantasy VI, where depending on who's in your party, different people say the same line.
Speaker 0: Someone needs to say, "I'm sure glad my acting gig at the Time Institute turned into this.
Speaker 0: Locate the Daphnorian DNA.
Speaker 0: The ring sensor array isn't
Speaker 0: working.".
Speaker 1: Right, it's like none of the characters, there are no personalities.
Speaker 1: All they are, these characters don't even exist.
Speaker 1: They're just visual designs with powers.
Speaker 1: That's all they are, and there's just tons of them.
Speaker 1: There's tons and tons of characters, but none of them are actually characters.
Speaker 1: Compare this to any good thing ever.
Speaker 1: Look at, say, Lord of the Rings.
Speaker 1: Right, it's like they actually have a character to them.
Speaker 1: There's no character to these characters.
Speaker 1: They're just a picture with a name and a list of powers, and you could shuffle them all up.
Speaker 1: You could replace them all with pictures of Superman.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't make any goddamn difference.
Speaker 1: So, fuck this book.
Speaker 0: I don't know what I can say beyond that.
Speaker 1: By far, I think it might be the worst of the whole thing.
Speaker 0: I could not tell you how many characters are in this.
Speaker 1: I couldn't tell you any.
Speaker 1: I can't even remember a single character from it at all.
Speaker 0: I remember the shape-shifting girl.
Speaker 0: For whatever reason, I remember her, and...
Speaker 1: Maybe everyone was just her.
Speaker 1: That's why they're all the same.
Speaker 0: And there was a girl with wings.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I'd have to look at it to remember anything.
Speaker 0: The rest of them, I didn't.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's a bug-looking guy.
Speaker 0: I forgot about him.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: He says a bunch of random stuff.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: And the art was bad on top of that.
Speaker 0: It was just really generic-y, comic-book-y, boring art.
Speaker 1: At least some of the other bad books had the good art, like the Batwoman.
Speaker 1: This one, just bad.
Speaker 1: 100% bad.
Speaker 1: Fire all these people.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry, guys.
Speaker 0: I want to know if there's anyone in the world who likes this comic, and if so, I really want to know what they like about it.
Speaker 1: I did see some people who liked it a lot.
Speaker 1: They must be the biggest Legion fanboys in the goddamn universe or something.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Or maybe that's what they like, is they like non-char--?
Speaker 1: I read the incredibly famous Christ in Infinite Earths, right?
Speaker 1: So I bought it and read it, just because it's so famous and important in comic history and everything, right?
Speaker 1: And it has every DC comic superhero from the late '80s in it, or whatever, as all of them.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, on most of them aren't actually characters.
Speaker 1: They're like this, where they appear on the page, and maybe they say something, but there's no character to them.
Speaker 1: It's like, "I'm going to do a story about the Rocketeer,".
Speaker 1: and I drew a picture of the Rocketeer.
Speaker 1: And that's it.
Speaker 1: He's on the page.
Speaker 1: Look at him.
Speaker 1: It's the Rocketeer.
Speaker 1: It's like, "Oh, it's just a picture of the
Speaker 1: Rocketeer.".
Speaker 1: He's not acting like the Rocketeer X. It's like, I could make a Back to the Future comic, and I could draw the Professor and Marty there, but if they don't act like the Professor and Marty, just like, "Hey, hey, let's go travel in time.
Speaker 1: Okay, we've traveled in time.
Speaker 1: There is danger
Speaker 1: here.".
Speaker 1: It's like, if they're not acting like, "Oh my God, Marty, what are we going to--" then it's not actually them.
Speaker 0: That was actually a pretty good Professor voice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was good.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I'm giving this one a good.
Speaker 0: Just to fuck up your rating system.
Speaker 1: You actually want me to put good for Legion Lost next to your name?
Speaker 1: Nah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: I couldn't consciously.
Speaker 1: All right, Grifter, which I don't really remember, but-- It was really boring.
Speaker 0: The art was okay, but it was so boring, I don't care.
Speaker 1: All right, so here's my notes.
Speaker 1: "Find you with a creepy mask on.
Speaker 1: Easy.".
Speaker 1: I think this guy was-- all right, he was trying to hide, but someone was trying to hide himself.
Speaker 0: All right, so he's a grifter, and he does this really generic, like, grift that wouldn't work on anyone.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I don't even remember there being a grift, which shows just how bad this was.
Speaker 0: And then he gets kidnapped by aliens.
Speaker 0: They try to put an alien in his body.
Speaker 0: He wakes up during it and runs away.
Speaker 0: Now they can sense him, and he hears their voices.
Speaker 0: They live style.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was-- I wrote, "They live," with an exclamation point.
Speaker 0: So he's sitting there, and a random person will turn to him and be like, "Find you.
Speaker 0: Find
Speaker 0: you.".
Speaker 0: And he's like, "Shut the fuck up.
Speaker 0: Get away from me, you
Speaker 0: bastards.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember that part.
Speaker 1: I also wrote down that the art was great.
Speaker 1: I'd have to see it again to remember that, but-- It was cool.
Speaker 0: It was kind of gangly, the characters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like-- the fact that I remember nothing from this book at all.
Speaker 1: Like, at least Legion Lost was so bad that I remembered how bad it was.
Speaker 1: Grifter was just so nothing that I'm having a hard time remembering anything about it.
Speaker 1: I couldn't even remember what the character looked like until I looked it up on Google Image Search.
Speaker 1: And Rym left the book at work, so I can't look at it now.
Speaker 0: It just didn't give me a compelling reason to care about his narrative.
Speaker 0: I don't care what the aliens want.
Speaker 0: It wasn't really-- none of that was presented.
Speaker 0: Now, I think what they were going for is a, "You don't know what they
Speaker 0: want.".
Speaker 0: That's why it's so horrifying, but-- Yup.
Speaker 0: Also, he jumped out of the plane before it took off, and that action scene just didn't really make any sense.
Speaker 0: The side character dialogue was dumb, and I'm going to say bad just because it was really boring.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Terrific.
Speaker 0: Might as well be Static Shock.
Speaker 0: It was the same "I'm smart, look at my science" bullshit.
Speaker 1: But he's the third smartest guy in the universe or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: As he keeps telling me.
Speaker 0: And I don't care.
Speaker 0: He's got these three balls, and he throws them around.
Speaker 0: He tricks the guy that's chasing him to go to a metal thing, just like in Static Shock.
Speaker 1: And it's like he's got these magic balls.
Speaker 1: All his powers reside in these magic balls.
Speaker 1: Magic balls are him.
Speaker 1: Magic balls.
Speaker 1: The third smartest guy in the world has magic balls.
Speaker 0: Wouldn't you if you were the third smartest guy in the world?
Speaker 1: I would have a lot more magic balls.
Speaker 0: More than three?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So he tricks the bad guy into going by the big metal thing, and then-- And the guy's like, "What?
Speaker 0: You magnetized
Speaker 0: me?".
Speaker 0: And the guy's like, "Yeah, I did.
Speaker 0: I guess you know
Speaker 0: science.".
Speaker 0: Like, no.
Speaker 0: None of you know science.
Speaker 1: No, not even the third smartest.
Speaker 1: If that's the third smartest guy in the universe, that explains a fucking lot.
Speaker 0: But it was the same "I science you, you little guy" with my Baphidad crap that I hate.
Speaker 1: Also, what's the origin story?
Speaker 1: I thought we were getting away from the origin stories in all these other books.
Speaker 1: But here we go, talking about the origin of Mr.
Speaker 1: Terrific.
Speaker 1: It's like, what the fuck?
Speaker 0: But it was a boring origin.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who gives a shit?
Speaker 0: And he's a boring character.
Speaker 1: I think the idea of making a book about a really smart--just a guy who's really smart could work out.
Speaker 0: They did, Scott.
Speaker 0: He became the mayor of New York.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: But I'm talking about also in Fantastic Four, right?
Speaker 1: Fantastic Four often is good.
Speaker 1: Not always, but often is good.
Speaker 1: Because Mr.
Speaker 1: Fantastic is really smart, and they do stories about how smart Mr.
Speaker 1: Fantastic is.
Speaker 1: And how his smartness and his diligence at working so hard pulls him away from his family and all that kind of, you know.
Speaker 0: Yup, yup.
Speaker 1: And he solves problems with actual clever things as opposed to just making a Baphidad, although he often makes a Baphidad.
Speaker 1: But yeah, this Mr.
Speaker 1: Terrific is nowhere--even the worst Fantastic Four story is ten times better than Mr.
Speaker 0: Terrific.
Speaker 0: It was all Baphidad, and I was really annoyed by the dialogue of the bystanders, even more so than in Grifter.
Speaker 0: Because there's a scene where he's up there, and the crowd's like, "Who's that?
Speaker 0: Nice
Speaker 0: ass!".
Speaker 0: Like, they're checking out his ass, and just the things they're saying don't make sense.
Speaker 0: No one would say things like what they were saying.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: No one would say anything like any of these characters in any of these books would say.
Speaker 0: Nah, Batman would say what Batman said in Batman #1.
Speaker 0: Well, actually, Detective Comics #1.
Speaker 0: Batman would say what Batman said in that comic.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so Mr.
Speaker 1: Terrific, what are you giving--I say bad.
Speaker 1: It's a meh.
Speaker 1: Are you giving meh?
Speaker 0: 'Cause it was not--it wasn't actively as bad as a lot of this other stuff.
Speaker 1: I think also I read all these week twos in a row, and I think my mood might have affected my string of bads here, but yeah, bad bad bad.
Speaker 0: I read 'em in two strings.
Speaker 1: I can't change my mind without re-reading it, but I'm gonna say bad.
Speaker 0: So, Resurrection Man seems like a really cool concept that they're running into the ground.
Speaker 1: You actually think the concept is cool if a guy who doesn't die and keeps coming back?
Speaker 0: I think it could be cool.
Speaker 0: as--take the Highlander concept, which people really dig, and-- I don't dig it that much.
Speaker 0: But you actually kill the guy, and he just wakes up, you know, Shadowrun the SNES game style a couple of days later.
Speaker 0: But no, every time he wakes up, he has some super power, and again, the plot was kind of boring and incomprehensible.
Speaker 1: Okay, so first of all, the art in this was horrendously awful.
Speaker 1: I showed you the rib boob.
Speaker 0: I guess I didn't notice that, 'cause I was trying to figure out what was going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like, some of the art in this is just hideous and inconsistent and doesn't stay on model, really, and I can't tell who's who a lot, and it's just like, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Yet again, there's another comic with an airplane involved.
Speaker 1: How many of those are there?
Speaker 1: All of them, I guess?
Speaker 1: The art style also seems to change from page to page a lot.
Speaker 1: I don't know, it's just all over the place.
Speaker 0: I also like the story of maybe, you know, Final Destination style.
Speaker 0: You know, they're trying to kill him dead, 'cause he's supposed to be dead.
Speaker 0: But it's like they took that story, and they put superhero crap into it.
Speaker 1: The thing is, what's disappointing about this is this is written by Abnett and Lanning.
Speaker 1: Now, Abnett and Lanning actually wrote a whole bunch of Marvel comics, all the more recent cosmic outer space Marvel comics that I actually like a lot.
Speaker 1: They went downhill over time.
Speaker 1: They started off good, and they went down to meh.
Speaker 1: But I actually liked them.
Speaker 1: But this Abnett and Lanning book is not good.
Speaker 1: So, there you go.
Speaker 1: Just 'cause, you know, no one's perfect.
Speaker 1: Jeff Lemire wrote a bad book.
Speaker 1: Abnett and Lanning wrote a bad book.
Speaker 0: It just, I don't know, it feels like one of those pulp comics from a long time ago, and they're trying to recapture that, I think.
Speaker 1: I like pulp comics from a long time ago.
Speaker 0: But it's just, it's a little too...
Speaker 1: Like a nice Flash Gordon?
Speaker 0: I just feel like the storytelling in this general sense, it's kind of hard to explain, but it feels like a lot, like Demon Knights had the same problem.
Speaker 0: Like, it feels like this kind of, the DC crap just edges its way back in, even if the story would have otherwise been good.
Speaker 0: Like, they do this certain kind of portrayal of the story that just reminds me, "Oh yeah, I'm reading a superhero comic book that's actually kind of
Speaker 0: generic.".
Speaker 1: Well, I think what these people, I get the feeling that a lot of these books like this, right?
Speaker 1: The books that aren't necessarily superhero books directly, but are still DC Universe, they're looking at Sandman, and they're looking at Alan Moore's Swamp Thing, and how those books were able to be sort of, you know, dark and sort of mystic and magical.
Speaker 0: You're right!
Speaker 0: I hereby dub this a wannabe of that kind of comic.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: All these books like that are looking at those two examples that had a little bit of superhero world, they're in the DC Universe, but they managed to keep most of it out, but a little bit in, and it totally worked.
Speaker 1: And they're looking at those books and trying to be that and totally failing because Abnett and Lanning, as much as I liked some of their previous works, are not Neil Gaiman, and they're not Alan Moore, nor can they be.
Speaker 1: They should stick to being Abnett and Lanning, which is, you know, if they had stuck to being Abnett and Lanning and done, say, "You know what?
Speaker 1: Actually, I like their outer space stuff in Marvel so much, maybe you should have had the Geoff Johns do the Resurrection Man, and had the Abnett and Lanning do the Green Lantern, maybe it could have been the first goddamn good Green
Speaker 1: Lantern.".
Speaker 0: I would have rather seen Jeff Lemire do the Resurrection Man, because they need to focus on the guy being sad and alone because he keeps on dying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that could have worked out.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So, for Resurrection Man, what do you have?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go with Med, just because in Week 2, some of the stuff was so bad that I'd feel really awkward putting Resurrection Man in the same category as Legion Lost.
Speaker 1: I know, just because that's why you need a 5-star system is the best, because in a 5-star system, you'd give it a 2, and you'd give the Legion Lost the 1.
Speaker 0: I'll say Med, because I would read one more of this to see if it goes anywhere or gets interesting, but I would not read any more of Legion Lost if you paid me to.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Suicide Squad.
Speaker 1: Suicide Squad.
Speaker 0: I didn't know that was Harley Quinn until they said her name.
Speaker 1: Same thing, exactly.
Speaker 1: I did not know at all, because the character design was changed, and she wasn't acting like Harley Quinn at all.
Speaker 0: Not at all.
Speaker 0: I liked her hammer, and some of the flashback-y stuff was more like her, but the her in the present of this comic was just boobs with a hammer.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And the story is kind of… cliche?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We've got a Suicide Squad of criminals that we've put explosion collars on, only in this case we injected them so we wouldn't have to draw an explosion collar, and we send them to do suicide missions that they'll always survive.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: It's hardcore.
Speaker 1: So first of all, right, King Shark is fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, King Shark.
Speaker 1: Just because he's a fucking shark.
Speaker 1: King Shark is….
Speaker 0: I also like the dynamic.
Speaker 0: The characters, to be fair, are actually characters in this.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: They have personalities.
Speaker 0: King Shark is basically….
Speaker 1: I wish they would have gone more all out with that.
Speaker 1: It would have been better.
Speaker 0: King Shark is like Dr.
Speaker 0: McNinja crossed with Radiscoll.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Actually, I kind of liked where this was going up until the reveal that they were all Battle Royaleed or whatever.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: It was like, "Oh, this is getting good.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's what it is.
Speaker 1: Ah, dang
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: You know?
Speaker 1: It's like they were going in a good direction, but then it wasn't actually.
Speaker 1: The reality was better than the lie.
Speaker 0: I'd rather them have a more complex hook to be there.
Speaker 0: They're not forced to be there.
Speaker 0: There's no just, "Oh, the explosion collar.
Speaker 0: You gotta do
Speaker 0: this.".
Speaker 0: But more….
Speaker 1: I would have rather had just be like, "Let's fucking make mischief,
Speaker 1: bitches.".
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: And have them sort of be all out, sort of kooky, making mischief, fucking shit up.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: I would read that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right?
Speaker 0: Harley Quinn goes around just being Harley Quinn.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: With fucking King Shark and these other dudes.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: If you just let them loose instead of reining them in to be yet another forced together acronym team to go fight against the other organization.
Speaker 1: If you would have just let them loose, but kept them together because they were all going….
Speaker 1: Maybe they were all getting revenge on the same person or something.
Speaker 1: You know, maybe….
Speaker 1: You know what you could have done?
Speaker 1: One page, you're all trapped.
Speaker 1: You're all going to work for me.
Speaker 1: Next page, we totally just smashed your stupid system on fucking King Shark.
Speaker 1: And then them getting their revenge on… Oh, fuck yeah.
Speaker 1: Let them loose.
Speaker 1: So, there was potential there, which actually I put meh.
Speaker 0: I also put meh because I liked the characters enough to where I wouldn't….
Speaker 1: You had another….
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I think you encapsulated my thoughts, too, that I don't feel like the characters are going to be given enough room to thrive to where I'll care.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Also, fucking King Shark.
Speaker 0: King Shark is the best.
Speaker 0: When he just fucking bites that guy's arm like….
Speaker 1: They should have just made fucking King Shark the book.
Speaker 1: Ten to twenty-two pages of biting.
Speaker 1: That would have been great.
Speaker 1: Best book.
Speaker 0: King Shark and Radiscoll, an epic adventure.
Speaker 1: Okay, so Superboy, the last book of this week.
Speaker 1: So, a lot of people… Is this Astro Boy or what?
Speaker 0: It's Astro Boy.
Speaker 0: Now, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: This is Astro Boy the same way the Lion King is.
Speaker 0: Many people hinted to me saying, "Oh, yeah, Rick's obviously going to like…".
Speaker 1: I mean, just look at this fucking page.
Speaker 1: It's Astro Boy without the hair.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 0: But I did like the….
Speaker 1: The art's actually really good.
Speaker 1: I like it.
Speaker 0: I did like the fact that the whole Smallville thing kind of gets explained that it was a virtual reality to figure this guy out.
Speaker 1: Well, because, yeah, this is going on, right?
Speaker 1: It's like this isn't a story of Superman's youth.
Speaker 1: This is a story of someone who is not Superman.
Speaker 1: He's like a robot android something Astro Boy.
Speaker 1: But, they want him to be like Superman, so they need to give him similar memories or experiences to Superman, so he gets the virtual reality, you know, Smallville in sort of the Matrix style, which is sort of like, "Oh, that's pretty
Speaker 1: cool.".
Speaker 1: But actually, I would have rather read that, you know, that Smallville comic than read the Astro Boy comic because I already read Astro Boy.
Speaker 1: Now,
Speaker 0: there's
Speaker 1: kind of an aside,
Speaker 0: but I've noticed and I didn't point it out in all of them because I didn't, you know, I stopped noting it after I saw it so often, but
Speaker 1: a lot
Speaker 0: of these comics are making very quick oblique references to fan culture or current events in ways that reek of trying to be pop-cultury edgy.
Speaker 0: Like in this one, the white haired girl is like, "I totally wasn't a Mary
Speaker 0: Sue.".
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, "Yeah, really?
Speaker 0: That didn't… That line kind of came out of
Speaker 0: nowhere.".
Speaker 1: I do want to give some props to this book.
Speaker 1: This book was a very high meh, almost good because… Almost good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The props I want to give it are, number one, there was no fighting in it and there was only one explosion.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Almost every other book has like an obligatory action scene.
Speaker 1: There was like five pages of superhero battling.
Speaker 1: No battling in here.
Speaker 1: None whatsoever, right?
Speaker 1: There's one explosion and that's it.
Speaker 1: Also, I wrote boots.
Speaker 1: Is someone wearing cool boots or something?
Speaker 0: There were some really good….
Speaker 0: Multiple people had really good footwear in the art.
Speaker 0: I also had a note about that.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I like that footwear.
Speaker 1: Also, proper nouns ahoy.
Speaker 1: Yet another acronym organization working on evil science or good science.
Speaker 0: But I did like how I….
Speaker 0: The expected story of, you know, they're going to kill him.
Speaker 0: She sets him free.
Speaker 0: It was building up to that in the beginning and then immediately that was not it.
Speaker 0: He, you know, when they try to kill him, she doesn't stop them.
Speaker 0: She's like, "Oh, well.
Speaker 0: This is
Speaker 0: sad."
Speaker 0: And then when he blows up, all those people die.
Speaker 0: She doesn't let him free.
Speaker 0: She puts him back in the fucking lab.
Speaker 1: I actually kind of wish they would like….
Speaker 1: It would be really cool if they took this book, right?
Speaker 1: And you could even leave the Astro Boy story.
Speaker 1: But what you do is you make that girl the focus.
Speaker 1: Like everything is from her perspective.
Speaker 1: And like the Super Boy is like just sort of barely in it in the background.
Speaker 0: He's the force of nature.
Speaker 1: He's sort of like not even there, but it's all about this girl.
Speaker 1: Like you show her going home at night and the Super Boy is just sort of there-ish.
Speaker 1: You know, that would have been fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: Because then you could do a whole thing where his thoughts are really just her projecting.
Speaker 1: And because the girl's actually pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But like her projecting on him and her having, you know, expecting all these reactions to situations or expecting all these sorts of things, but really it's just her projection.
Speaker 0: She can't understand him.
Speaker 0: He's totally alien to her.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and he's….
Speaker 0: But no, they didn't go in that direction.
Speaker 0: And, you know, to go from you saying props, my biggest con with this, and it's funny because everyone told me that they thought I'd really like this one.
Speaker 0: And they're probably going to be surprised that I give it a met.
Speaker 0: It wreaks a little too much of effort.
Speaker 0: Like it's trying too hard to be poignant and serious.
Speaker 0: And it's not doing it terribly elegantly.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 1: I like the arts.
Speaker 0: I like the arts too.
Speaker 0: It was a little too, you know, the monologues of Super Boy were a little too forced.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: What am I?
Speaker 1: Who am I?
Speaker 0: Oh, this is a simulation.
Speaker 0: What do you see?
Speaker 1: What do you see?
Speaker 0: But in this case, he's like, what do I see?
Speaker 0: I see this and this and this and this and this.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to have to give it a met just for that because it could have been so much better, but they didn't go….
Speaker 1: I also gave it a met, but it was almost good.
Speaker 0: It's funny to me how I've given one of these comics a met because it wasn't crazy enough.
Speaker 0: And yet the ones that I hate the most are the craziest ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's a certain kind of crazy, like there's over the top crazy, like if….
Speaker 1: I think what it is, is it's just about, it's not about that you like crazy or you like uncrazy.
Speaker 1: It's like given this sort of raw material, what direction do you take it?
Speaker 1: And it seems like they take the raw materials in the opposite direction of whatever direction they naturally want to go in to make a balance.
Speaker 1: Whereas what they should do is they should just take it to the extreme.
Speaker 1: If something wants to go crazy, let it be crazy.
Speaker 0: And then you get Legion Lost.
Speaker 0: It wants to be what it is and it is what it is.
Speaker 1: At least it's for somebody.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have to give it that.
Speaker 1: In 52 comics, not all of them are going to be for everyone.
Speaker 0: I mean if you really like incomprehensible bullshit, Legion Lost is probably one of the better comics you could read.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean there are 52 of them.
Speaker 1: There's no way they could possibly all be good nor would I expect them to be because that would mean they would all be catering to me, which is not a good idea.
Speaker 1: You want to have some of them cater to different groups.
Speaker 1: So, you know, but I don't know.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: You still should let them go in the direction they naturally want to go.
Speaker 0: I think that's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: That's it for week two.
Speaker 1: Next time on week three we got Batman, Catwoman, more Green Lanterns.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, that Green Lantern shit.
Speaker 1: More Legions of Superheroes and Wonder Woman with the cool cover.
Speaker 0: I feel like week one is my favorite week.
Speaker 0: Week four is my second favorite week because I kind of liked Aquaman.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll see.
Speaker 1: We'll get there.
Speaker 0: But seriously, Blue Beetle, that's the only one I didn't read yet from week three.
Speaker 0: The fuck's the Blue Beetle's deal because I see him.
Speaker 0: He comes up a lot.
Speaker 1: It's a guy who's got sort of this mechanical... It's like an outer space...
Speaker 0: So Iron Man.
Speaker 1: No, it's a magical scarab that came from outer space and you turn into Iron Man that way instead of being Iron Man because you're rich.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Imagine if an alien artifact came in the window and you took it and it turned into cat armor.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Cat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.