Speaker 1: It's Wednesday June 22nd.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm sky and this is geek night tonight in the year 2011 We talk about anime that we have not seen.
Speaker 1: opposite wise Let's do this Awkwardly constructed episode title.
Speaker 1: I think you could have come with a better title than I could have but I didn't come up with one And it already started saying the thing.
Speaker 0: so yeah Just go back and redo it later, and then this part will make no sense Which is I don't know if I want to do that or not.
Speaker 1: I think it's a good meta joke either way anyway.
Speaker 1: So you know it's really upsetting a lot of things the fact that you know the Patriot Act got extended The wars in the world poverty obesity yeah sure anyway.
Speaker 0: So this New York Asian film festival is gonna be coming to New York again.
Speaker 0: Oh, and I think there's one thing that we really wanted as it does every year And they're gonna show something.
Speaker 0: that is you know last year There was some cool stuff that I wanted to see like there was was a crazy kaiju thing.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that was playing it like midnight or something.
Speaker 0: It was like it was like kappa death kappa or something like that Something like.
Speaker 1: I don't wanted to see that but it was like the kind of thing we would usually go to see it like the 11 o'clock showing at Otacon.
Speaker 0: It was like a midnight showing and I think Scott Johnson people were over for some reason, but anyway Well, we didn't go see it, but I so this year.
Speaker 0: They're showing Basically there's a new anime version of Tezuka's Buddha, or is it live-action.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: I want to see that so bad.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it's animated either way.
Speaker 0: They're showing it Thursday night and Sunday night Matt lining up right with kinetic on which also lines right up with that my little pony convention.
Speaker 0: We could go see it Thursday night, and then leave for kinetic on mutley.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we could but we have responsibilities at the con.
Speaker 0: But it's at 630 so it's actually.
Speaker 0: it's not late Thursday night, so we could go watch it.
Speaker 1: 637 All right, so we get on the road at like 9. we get to the kind of like 11 all right all right.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with that?
Speaker 1: a lot of people check in on Thursday stuff to do?
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah, that's the trouble of having responsibilities.
Speaker 0: That's all right.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: It'll definitely be something We can see at some point in the future by hook or crook.
Speaker 0: But if you are you know I guess this normally would be met a moment.
Speaker 0: But whatever, New York Asian film festival 2011 check it out.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of good stuff to see.
Speaker 0: yeah Kung-fu's etc.
Speaker 1: so I heard up Spider-Man's dead.
Speaker 0: Hey, Spider-Man's not real.
Speaker 0: so how can he be dead?
Speaker 1: well in the comic universe?
Speaker 1: Well, I thought parker who was Spider-Man Was killed by some but that's only ultimate Spider-Man not regular spider-Man.
Speaker 1: I didn't realize until I read this article that there was a difference because the guy writing the article was like.
Speaker 1: I thought they were all in the same stupid universe.
Speaker 1: then this guy's like oh But in this universe if you die you're really dead and in the other universes you can come back.
Speaker 1: So this is the real deal.
Speaker 0: Spider-Man dead What I don't know.
Speaker 0: who's right?
Speaker 0: basically it for people who don't know right?
Speaker 0: Marvel comics Recognized that there was a problem that people who had not been reading Spider-Man or x-men or whatever for a hundred years had a hard Time getting into these Spider-Man x-men and superhero comics.
Speaker 0: You know that have been going on since the 60s and the 70s.
Speaker 0: so they made some years ago Actually a very long time ago already.
Speaker 0: you know Many many years ago.
Speaker 0: They made ultimate Spider-Man ultimate x-men ultimate avengers I'll you know actually was called ultimates as opposed to ultimate avengers.
Speaker 0: They made a whole bunch of ultimate ultimate fantastic four right.
Speaker 0: and this is these comics.
Speaker 0: these ultimate comics were in their own universe.
Speaker 0: So it's like they made a new universe that nothing to do at all with the old universe and all those comics had the word ultimate on the top.
Speaker 0: so you could just read those and not worry about anything else.
Speaker 0: and if you start at the beginning you'd be all good.
Speaker 0: and You know if you can still easily go and acquire all the trades of all those comics and read them from the beginning And it won't be too expensive or take you that long and you won't miss anything, and there's only a couple crossovers
Speaker 1: And they only cross over issues in spider-man.
Speaker 0: yeah, they only cross over with themselves right.
Speaker 0: so it's not really that big a deal.
Speaker 0: It's all contained in like this little bubble.
Speaker 0: So it you know, but the problem was is that they kept that going for so long.
Speaker 0: It was actually kind of popular that It eventually itself became too long and too big and and too difficult for people to get into.
Speaker 1: so now I've decided that the big it's not comics It's everything nerds like worlds where they can Gandalf girth.
Speaker 1: And they like there to be continuity in things like if they read a Star Wars comic And it lines up good enough with the Star Wars movies.
Speaker 1: They love that shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I'm no exception.
Speaker 1: I like things like that.
Speaker 1: Comics like this just take it too far.
Speaker 1: you got to leave a lot more gaps and not I don't know I feel like too much.
Speaker 1: continuity Hurts all but the hardest of the hardcore nerd.
Speaker 0: See the problem isn't necessarily the world building or You know such like that.
Speaker 0: the problem is the linearity and the serial ness of it.
Speaker 0: right for example I could create a world pick a fantasy world forgotten around.
Speaker 0: Perfect example.
Speaker 0: right I can tell you a story in forgotten realms about drizzet.
Speaker 0: He was very popular.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we pretty much know everything did.
Speaker 1: I can tell you know who drizzed was?
Speaker 0: he was some guy with two swords, right?
Speaker 1: I What race was he?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna guess drow all right.
Speaker 1: Oh, you got that really oh shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, was he a good guy or a bad guy?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna guess bad guy.
Speaker 0: It's complicated actually okay sure anyway I only know is that he's.
Speaker 1: you have no idea who artemis and troy is though not a clue.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can also tell you with another story about el minster.
Speaker 0: All I know about him is he's like the most powerful wizard there was.
Speaker 1: ah you know what I learned from elements like Merlin equivalent.
Speaker 1: You know what I learned from el minster when he was a girl.
Speaker 1: I learned a lot about what that author thought girls felt like when they had sex, okay, and From that same author.
Speaker 1: I learned a lot about what turns elves on.
Speaker 0: right now These are both in the same universe.
Speaker 0: if you're a nerd you're gonna love these things right?
Speaker 0: if you're that kind of nerd But you don't have to read the drizz story to also read the el minster story.
Speaker 0: They don't go in order necessarily true, right?
Speaker 0: They're not like.
Speaker 0: it's not like part one drizz part to a minster, but I think it's not a serial tale.
Speaker 1: It's a bunch of separate tales all in the same world part of that Very large world and they didn't write that many stories inside of it.
Speaker 1: They then and the word the stories they did write were broad and spread out across all these different places though Some of them were very linear.
Speaker 0: There was like one series of like eight books But all went together and another set of books that also kind of anyway But the Forgotten Realms is more like a jigsaw puzzle and you can get each piece and sort of make out what's going on.
Speaker 1: You know that I think jigsaw puzzles are better for the nerds in the long run.
Speaker 1: Of course the line of spider-man
Speaker 0: Yes, you know what Marvel has is they basically have one long reel of film and they give it to you in pieces And you it only goes in one order and if you're missing a piece of the film, you can't play the movie.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean sure there are plenty of times where they don't do that, you know.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like they have a jigsaw puzzle and film together sort of right like I read.
Speaker 0: You know a bunch of Marvel cosmic stuff like all the you know annihilations, but every time I'm making the jigsaw puzzle There's all these missing Wolverine pieces.
Speaker 0: Every piece has Wolverine on it.
Speaker 0: Wolverines on every single piece.
Speaker 0: It's either a claw or the horn on his hat thingy.
Speaker 0: You know something he's on every piece.
Speaker 1: team a will be Psylocke and Wolverine team be Cyclops and Wolverine team Just Wolverine, yeah, but so yeah, so they're.
Speaker 0: they're killing ultimate spider-man, which I think they're sort of killing off ultimate Everything.
Speaker 0: from what I can tell I think they're trying to end the ultimate stuff.
Speaker 0: I could be wrong.
Speaker 0: Well from what I read that's the door.
Speaker 1: All right, there's already going to be another ultimate spider-man.
Speaker 1: It's just not gonna be Peter Parker cuz he's dead.
Speaker 0: Okay, I Thought that there I guess they're not ending ultimate everything.
Speaker 1: as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: I mean this is I have not read a Marvel comic since The end of the executioner's song and x-men.
Speaker 0: didn't you read Many for the show like x-men forever.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I've read all those like individual bits here and there But I have not like continued to read anything.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know the continuity.
Speaker 0: I you know, I bought you know, I stopped sort of when they you know, they that cosmic stuff I just talked about sort of ended.
Speaker 1: ish I started with the end of excuse your song going back and read that whole like arc.
Speaker 1: and then I read I kept reading from There for a little and I just kind of give up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh No, well, so yeah the killer.
Speaker 0: I wonder if they will actually bring him back or not.
Speaker 0: I will bet you because it's ultimate that they won't for quite a long time, but they will eventually.
Speaker 0: but it's like Captain America Who got brought back?
Speaker 1: Oh in the very least I will bet you this I'll bet you $100 that within three years Peter Parker will reappear in something that isn't a flashback But it has to be in ultimate spider-man.
Speaker 1: Yeah ultimate spider-man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they'll probably go back in time and like talk to him about something.
Speaker 0: They do that.
Speaker 0: That's another thing, right?
Speaker 0: It's like a lot of characters die and even though they're still dead They find some way to manage to put them in a story even when they're dead.
Speaker 1: Just go back in time and kidnap right before they die and bring him into the future.
Speaker 1: Who knows anyway Didn't I do that to chrono?
Speaker 0: anyway, so We all know about a lot of virtual idols like Hatsune Miku and such right?
Speaker 0: That's that's sort of old news.
Speaker 1: It's not Ruben.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's old news to us by now, even though it's news to the rest of the world, but check this out All right, so, you know What are their names?
Speaker 0: girls generation, right?
Speaker 0: GGG, right?
Speaker 0: We talked about them on the show before.
Speaker 0: song never got stuck in my head.
Speaker 0: You didn't listen to it enough.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you should very pointedly.
Speaker 0: It's a good song.
Speaker 0: It's okay kind of anyway, it's a good song for sticking in heads.
Speaker 0: So, you know over in Japan Korea, I don't know about China.
Speaker 0: They have you know, these these girl idol groups.
Speaker 0: It's like a big team like morning moves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like we can't just have Britney Spears.
Speaker 0: We got to have 20 Britney Spears in a in a group and Like something different.
Speaker 0: So no matter who you are.
Speaker 0: One of them will be your favorite one.
Speaker 1: That's the surly one That's the bubbly one.
Speaker 1: That's the strange one.
Speaker 0: And instead of sexy one instead of having you know one person do a bunch of commercials.
Speaker 0: we can have them all doing all the commercials all the time because it's so.
Speaker 0: so AKB 48 is one of those groups very popular especially among the nerds and they recently released a commercial for For a sort of candy called ice no me sweet.
Speaker 0: and In this commercial was a new member of the group named.
Speaker 0: I me a Gucci.
Speaker 0: what they did not tell you until just now is that this I am.
Speaker 0: II Gucci is Not a real person.
Speaker 0: It looked like a real person in the commercial and sounded like a real person not like Hatsune Miku Which is obviously a digital person.
Speaker 1: Yeah well I read a number.
Speaker 1: I was poking around about this because I didn't.
Speaker 1: I wasn't aware until Scott pointed it out and It seems like a lot of nerds had suspicions.
Speaker 1: They're like, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I can't find any info on this girl.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they sort of put some fake info out there about her on you know, their website like, you know.
Speaker 0: oh she you know did a photo shoot and Right.
Speaker 0: They made like a fake biography to try to convince you.
Speaker 0: This is a real person.
Speaker 0: I get hiccups.
Speaker 1: Good job.
Speaker 0: And so, you know people were like But they it looked like a real person and it was in it and then they finally came out with it like nope It's not a real person.
Speaker 0: They took different visual aspects of many different members of the group.
Speaker 0: So they took like one girl's eyes and one girl's hair and one girl's you know Lips and one girl and they digitally pasted them all together to make a new person that did not really exist.
Speaker 0: I predict they had one of their sort of you know research students Which is like one of the you know B team like girl who works for them and is training to become a real member.
Speaker 0: But isn't they had her do the voice?
Speaker 1: That would be a good plot for an anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and so they made this fake person for this commercial Which is pretty cool two predictions from rim.
Speaker 1: one, you know what our future is now.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna be the Terminator 2 apocalypse.
Speaker 1: It's Macross Plus, of course.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and two Currently, what do they do?
Speaker 1: They used to you know, we have the one idol like a Megumi or an I you me.
Speaker 1: But then you have the idol team, you know one idol for every kind of person.
Speaker 1: The real future now is going to be the virtual person where it detects who's watching and makes the perfect idol for that one person.
Speaker 1: Oh shit, so everyone sees their perfect idealized idol.
Speaker 0: That is some forward fucking thinking right there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, you get points for that one because that's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: That is so gonna happen like it knows what your tastes are and of all the idols it combines all of your favorite aspects of Each one.
Speaker 0: so you're watching TV.
Speaker 0: I see something different from what you see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I'm gonna be seeing some Rainbow Dash.
Speaker 0: Okay But yeah, that's that's pretty fucked up right there.
Speaker 1: So I have one more little news because Emily pointed this out to me and she would have totally gone forward if it was more convenient.
Speaker 1: Makoto shinkai studio is recruiting a very specific type of intern Or the fall unpaid and all that you got to get to the studio yourself.
Speaker 0: I wonder what?
Speaker 0: the laws of an unpaid orange pad probably much more lax than they are here.
Speaker 0: The thing is they're not followed here at all.
Speaker 1: I imagine in Japan you're given some sort of medal for if you hire the most people and pay them the least.
Speaker 1: So specifically they're looking for young interns to do Makoto shinkai Background art.
Speaker 0: so but they would to do anything like his backgrounds.
Speaker 0: You would need to hire God of interns.
Speaker 1: I guess they're looking.
Speaker 0: or the quality is gonna go way down Or they're gonna whip them until they do.
Speaker 1: maybe they're trying to make more people.
Speaker 1: They're just gonna put them in front of sad videos of puppies and just wait until they start crying and then make them draw.
Speaker 0: listen, if you really like clouds, this is a job for you.
Speaker 1: or possibly Cherry blossoms.
Speaker 0: Yeah clouds though.
Speaker 1: Mostly cloud blossoms.
Speaker 0: It's be hard trains.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be real hard power lines for trains.
Speaker 1: Sure with clouds in the background always class.
Speaker 1: So things of the day, what do you got for me?
Speaker 0: So, I'm pretty sure I used this before but I Extensively searched and may have failed at finding when I used this before.
Speaker 0: so I'm using it.
Speaker 0: Fuck you I don't know if you've heard of this.
Speaker 0: It's called.
Speaker 0: you definitely heard of it.
Speaker 0: Mama Shiva.
Speaker 0: It is dogs That are also beans Basically, what is foreign you use that.
Speaker 0: I also would have That.
Speaker 1: maybe we had a party and you used it for our crew But you did not ever put it on the show.
Speaker 0: I don't know but the I was.
Speaker 0: I found out about it from our crew at a party.
Speaker 0: So anyway Mama Shiva is these bean dogs and basically there's this YouTube TV episodes which are like incredibly short.
Speaker 0: There's books This cut there's all kinds of you know, this you can buy.
Speaker 0: you can buy plushies.
Speaker 0: It's a whole Empire sort of the same way.
Speaker 0: moyashi Mon was an empire of you know stuff.
Speaker 0: and basically the shtick is this Somebody's sitting around and maybe they're doing something and a mama shiba appears.
Speaker 0: It's a bean that looks like a dog and there's all different.
Speaker 0: There's one for every kind of bean and then It says some sort of weird fact that may or may not be true.
Speaker 0: That is just like what the fuck.
Speaker 0: and Then it goes mama Shiva and that's it.
Speaker 1: That is definitely a formula for success is a formula for success.
Speaker 0: the official mama shiba website says What exactly is mama shiba?
Speaker 0: they're not quite a bean nor a dog but rather a hybrid of both.
Speaker 0: They love to appear out of nowhere and offer random bits of trivia whether you asked for it or not.
Speaker 0: That is pretty much sums it up entirely.
Speaker 0: It's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: I like it.
Speaker 0: if I've used it before I don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: There's nothing no other good things of the day to use that aren't just college humor.
Speaker 0: So this is what you get Repeat for a long time like.
Speaker 1: I would just pick like some random funny video the kind of thing that when it's like 1130 and one of our parties is winding down.
Speaker 1: There's like three people left.
Speaker 1: We always end up in front of the TV watching random internet shit, usually going through the things of the day.
Speaker 1: But recently we've been using a lot of more newsy kind of things the day like.
Speaker 1: oh check out this interesting fact.
Speaker 1: as opposed to Here's a two-minute video you can watch.
Speaker 1: I'm going back to just videos for a while.
Speaker 1: Just things that you can watch.
Speaker 1: show to your mom.
Speaker 1: She'll go.
Speaker 1: What the fuck's wrong with you?
Speaker 1: It's dragon-eyed, bitch.
Speaker 0: Okay, I like dragon eyes my favorite.
Speaker 1: yeah This is.
Speaker 0: this is a particular style of internet humor that I like to call power thirst.
Speaker 1: No, it's the same joke.
Speaker 1: Just dragonite instead of Gatorade.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean dragon eyes ten times more powerful than well.
Speaker 1: It's the the og.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment Which we're trying to do more quickly lately because you guys don't care about a lot of this stuff unless you live near us Kinetic count is coming up.
Speaker 1: We'll be there not doing a lot of panels because we're running the panels.
Speaker 1: department Book Club book is still Isaac Asimov's foundation.
Speaker 1: Secret book club book is our Scott backers prince of nothing series.
Speaker 1: A lot of you been bugging us to interview him.
Speaker 1: We never really pursued that.
Speaker 1: If you really want us to interview him keep bugging us and I don't know bug him - I gotta finish the books again Yeah, and then we can.
Speaker 1: do you realize if we interview him?
Speaker 1: We're not gonna.
Speaker 1: we're gonna have to make sure we do something that every other jackass hasn't already done.
Speaker 1: He's already been interviewed by people.
Speaker 0: We're gonna ask him all the questions that no one else has asked.
Speaker 1: now We're gonna do a profile and geek that too.
Speaker 0: But yeah, but also how big is the tusk?
Speaker 0: What animal is it from?
Speaker 1: We'll just go down the list of every character in alphabetical order.
Speaker 1: We were like, so how big is his junk?
Speaker 1: Until he hangs up on us Of course, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I feel like he might answer and that might be dangerous.
Speaker 0: He seems to be into that.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway Any more meta moments.
Speaker 1: pecs dev is coming up.
Speaker 1: We may or may not be there.
Speaker 1: We cannot officially say anything yet.
Speaker 0: kinetic on definitely mag stock.
Speaker 1: Maybe mag stock Maggie.
Speaker 1: maybe mag fest.
Speaker 1: long way out.
Speaker 1: more gaming than anime But convention culture.
Speaker 1: we went to mag fest last year.
Speaker 1: It was fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: I guess was this year.
Speaker 1: Technically it was fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: We're gonna go back and it's moving to a real venue.
Speaker 1: It's in the Gaylord where a katsu khan was.
Speaker 1: maybe still is.
Speaker 0: Go to front crew.
Speaker 0: calm because go to twitter.com.
Speaker 0: slash geek nights because go to forum front crew to come.
Speaker 1: Yeah, check out geek nights rim my youtube channel, which has radio free equestria one of our shows.
Speaker 1: We've launched another shows coming in the works.
Speaker 0: We have a shop.
Speaker 0: are all the t-shirts sold.
Speaker 1: Don't buy t-shirts.
Speaker 1: I gotta shut down the shop.
Speaker 0: I saw somebody was inquiring about a status.
Speaker 0: Did you actually mail them out?
Speaker 1: Yep, I pinged him back.
Speaker 1: I gave one guy a free t-shirt.
Speaker 1: I gave everyone else 50% discounts and we're out of goddamn shirts.
Speaker 0: Okay, so we're gonna order some more merch right before kinetic on right.
Speaker 0: maybe.
Speaker 0: yeah get on that shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe we need another design.
Speaker 0: All right, we can reorder the original one also though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we could I got a contact the people and see if they still have the templates and everything.
Speaker 0: if you design an awesome geek night shirt And we think it's worth making we'll sell it and make all the money and give you maybe a portion of the money.
Speaker 0: that is Tiny, who knows?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can also just make your own goddamn geek night shirt.
Speaker 0: cuz the Creative Commons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much everything we do is Creative Commons.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: So so but that's all you.
Speaker 1: So a while ago some time ago.
Speaker 1: I was watching way more anime than Scott and now that was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: now We're a few years ago.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: We're pretty much in the exact opposite situation.
Speaker 0: Well, actually not anymore because I sort of I watched a fuck ton of anime in the past few months and in the past one Month or so.
Speaker 0: I stopped watching.
Speaker 1: I think what happened to you is you were.
Speaker 1: you're like a spaceship that got caught in a gravity.
Speaker 1: Well of things like Hajime no Ippo where it pulls you in.
Speaker 1: you gotta watch the whole thing and then you catapult out of it.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean I would if I could get a hold of it.
Speaker 0: I would watch Queen millennia But I can't seem to find all the episodes with subtitles so I can't get pulled into it.
Speaker 1: Yep, and I've been working on a lot of stuff where I've also been working on a lot of stuff.
Speaker 1: I'm doing stuff and I want to watch anime or something.
Speaker 1: But I want something I can watch kind of not with the full attention like not looking directly at the screen.
Speaker 0: Also a pony sort of ruined everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah ponies kind of got in the way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we're gonna both talk about anime that we know the other person hasn't seen.
Speaker 0: also comics also some comics You know.
Speaker 0: it's pretty much like hey This is gonna be like a flurry of geek bites of things that I watched and rim didn't watch and vice versa.
Speaker 1: sir I'll start because we don't review a lot of recent anime lately, and I want to rectify that.
Speaker 1: so I've been watching three anime Simultaneously.
Speaker 1: oh shit because as you all know madhouse and Marvel teamed up to make Four anime based on Marvel properties.
Speaker 0: really I didn't.
Speaker 0: wow really I guess I did sort of know.
Speaker 0: It's like I knew it, but I sort of also forgot about it And it sort of felt like something that was in the future.
Speaker 1: There's there's a madhouse Wolverine X-men separate from Wolverine Iron Man, and I think blade is the one that is now yet Or I haven't seen.
Speaker 1: I don't really care about because I don't really care about blade.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay, so I've watched a few episodes of all of them and the animation is Fantastic.
Speaker 1: well,
Speaker 0: I imagine they put a ton of monies into it
Speaker 1: And it looks great like rent aro did the pilot for I think the x-men one and a lot of big people you know it's Like all the different teams at madhouse are on this and it's looking pretty great, so the Iron Man one I think has the most potential,
Speaker 0: but I hate Iron Man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what Iron Man is a gigantic douche.
Speaker 0: I know that's why I hate Iron Man, and it's great.
Speaker 1: No, no because in Japan he gets interviewed like in one of them I think the first episode and they're like so uh he's like how can I be more popular with the Japanese people?
Speaker 1: they don't seem To like me that much and the reporters like well, you could stop being such a douche.
Speaker 1: basically She's like you could be more humble, and he's like yeah, that's really outside of my abilities.
Speaker 1: you ask too much.
Speaker 1: I Feel like to not spoil anything.
Speaker 1: It's about a dude with a power suit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I feel like Japan could not cock that up.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's pretty much their specialty and the plot seems to be kind of giant robo e Iron Man or Ava.
Speaker 1: Iron Man made a production model of the Iron Man suit and they got a bunch of pilots from Japan and other places to Be Iron Man so he can retire from being Iron Man and just be a guy again.
Speaker 1: Yeah And the suit goes crazy and kills all the pilots and he has to get in the prototype Iron Man suit and save the day Me and play gods.
Speaker 1: It's pretty great.
Speaker 0: It's it's caveman.
Speaker 0: science fiction.
Speaker 1: x-men is pretty much just Imagine the the x-men cartoon we knew and loved only done by madhouse.
Speaker 1: Okay, it's great.
Speaker 1: All the characters look.
Speaker 1: they're very like.
Speaker 1: I don't know the 90s like the cut the style of x-men that we like and the Animation is great kind of thick line, but I like it.
Speaker 1: the fighting is super awesome.
Speaker 1: It's a good show.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes, that's something else.
Speaker 0: You know, I don't see too often is actual fighting.
Speaker 0: That's fun to watch.
Speaker 1: It's fun to watch fighting in the same way that a lot of old like a birdie the mighty had similar Like even in Hajime no Ippo.
Speaker 0: the fighting, you know is fun not because intense and very rarely is the animation of the fighting something That's other than like repeat of a special move.
Speaker 0: This to the North Star fighting is fun to watch only because only because the dude fucking explodes all over the place.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not animated in a cowboy bebop.
Speaker 1: No, it is not the first fight.
Speaker 0: a cowboy bebop I think is like, you know, that's one of my favorite fights in anything ever as the first lesson.
Speaker 0: Dead wife kick in iron monk I know but I'm talking about animated fight choreography cowboy bebop episode one fight outside The cantina is pretty much number one.
Speaker 1: I think it's specifically the kick and the table like.
Speaker 1: that part right there got me Yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, uh, the Wolverine one is the only one that sucks.
Speaker 0: Oh, it actually sucks.
Speaker 0: So it's not like.
Speaker 0: oh shit is Wolverine.
Speaker 1: So in the regular x-men, it's oh shit is Wolverine.
Speaker 1: Wolverine is always hunched with his arms out and the blades he's like.
Speaker 1: And if they didn't tell you that the Wolverine anime is Wolverine and if the fan sub didn't keep using bub, even though I don't hear anyone actually saying bub You would not know it's Wolverine.
Speaker 1: It is unless you knew all the plot of Wolverine and you recognize the plot Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It's basically the shonen looking guy who happens to be invincible and have claws is in Japan fucking shit up.
Speaker 0: It's just really well, that's that's interesting cuz it's like Iron Man never really went to Japan as far as I know.
Speaker 0: So yeah, all the places are men don't go to Japan that often but Wolverine is all about Japan.
Speaker 1: He's a huge Japan part of the Wolverine in Japan plot, except he's all kind of be shown in Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: He's not nearly gruff enough.
Speaker 0: Alrighty, and the thing is when he was in Japan, that was the most gruff ist.
Speaker 0: I know that he was comics wise.
Speaker 0: So that's it.
Speaker 1: So I was.
Speaker 1: I basically I watched one episode of that and gave up on it But the regular x-men one.
Speaker 1: it's like they took all his gruff out of Wolverine and put it all into the x-men anime Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Let's see what.
Speaker 0: I watched a ton of animes, but most of them were oh And also they're like one show that you went all the fuck way through and a lot of them are Like.
Speaker 0: I see I saw so many lazy Matsumoto's like space battleship Yamato all of Captain Harlock all of Galaxy Express all Galaxy Railways all Space Symphony may tell right many of these are shows that I've seen several episodes of but just didn't finish.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean Galaxy Express.
Speaker 1: I got like 40 in and then I just haven't.
Speaker 1: I got to watch more.
Speaker 0: Alright, so I think the one I want to talk about those I wanna talk about Galaxy Railways, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz that's that's newer and it's uh, you can just get like all the DVDs in a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: I think it might even be on Netflix or something, right?
Speaker 0: So the deal with Galaxy Railways is basically when you're watching Galaxy Express, right?
Speaker 0: Sometimes it'll be like the Galaxy Railways will have to enforce the law of the trains.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the rules of the trains basically change episode to episode to serve the plot.
Speaker 0: But they're always jerks like the like.
Speaker 0: you can't get out of train without a ticket except We'll make a special exception for main characters.
Speaker 1: you mess with our train will kill you all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you fuck with the train, we'll just blow your brains out and all these sorts of things.
Speaker 0: So Galaxy Railways is like two separate TV series, right?
Speaker 0: It's a season one and a season two and basically It follows the story of this kid whose dad works for the Galaxy Railways and his dad get.
Speaker 0: his dad is like the best pilot Ever the best, you know train captain.
Speaker 1: I was gonna say pilot.
Speaker 0: Yeah train captain engineer, whatever it is right, and basically his dad is He.
Speaker 0: his dad rides the train.
Speaker 0: that is like the defense train, right?
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: it's not a passenger train It's the train that goes out when another trains in trouble to save it from whatever horrible secret of space Is attacking it this week?
Speaker 0: So his dad dies and this kid grows up and then tries to get the same job as his dad, right?
Speaker 0: So he goes to work for the train and of course it makes us.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, and his mom is all upset.
Speaker 0: and the story follows this, you know, both seasons follow this kid who grows up obviously, you know working in the Galaxy Railways on the defense train and It's sort of like, you know the quality of it.
Speaker 0: You know some of the episodes are episodic Galaxy Express style, right?
Speaker 0: It's like this episode They have to go and there's some weird thing happening on this planet and they go and they rescue a train and this episodic stuff.
Speaker 0: But there's also a plot that sort of also, you know goes on not only development of the characters But also like ooh, there's a secret of the Galaxy Railways.
Speaker 0: What is it?
Speaker 0: Someone's up to no good.
Speaker 0: Will you uncover this?
Speaker 0: no goodness?
Speaker 0: You know and it has to do with like oh the Galaxy Railways themselves the technology that makes them work is tearing a hole in space and Disrupting this other universe and that other universe.
Speaker 0: who wants to attack the Galaxy Railways and someone's covering it up?
Speaker 0: And there's something along those lines.
Speaker 1: How Matsumoto-ey is it?
Speaker 0: It's kind of Matsumoto-ey, right?
Speaker 0: It's like half right?
Speaker 0: It's like half Matsumoto half modern, you know I Enjoyed it.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't say it's like the greatest show ever of all time, but it's definitely like, you know, it's like a b-plus show.
Speaker 0: You know the second season like, you know sort of goes, you know in a like the first season has sort of an end But the second season builds up to a more real ish and that like puts a nail in everything.
Speaker 0: But the second season has like different characters.
Speaker 0: they bring in, you know, and all that kind of stuff that you know Usually happens in the second season.
Speaker 0: Yeah So it's like if you're really attached to this stuff in the first season you feel a little bit detached in the second season because these characters you care less about.
Speaker 0: there's also an OAV that goes between the two seasons.
Speaker 0: that Basically is a crossover between Galaxy Express and Galaxy Railways where Maytel and Tetsuro You know, they meet up with the Galaxy Railways guys and some weird dimension planet for that, you know against the bad guy It's an OAV.
Speaker 0: That's what they do.
Speaker 1: That is what they do, you know.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if you know, it's like if you're already a Galaxy train fan, then Galaxy Railways will probably work out for you.
Speaker 0: If you're not you might be a little bit lost, but you should be able to understand it.
Speaker 0: but I think the reason that you'll be lost is because a lot of the enjoyment I got show from the show honestly is because I was like I already knew what the Galaxy Railways was.
Speaker 0: and in the other shows the Galaxy Railways like they never show you anyone's face.
Speaker 1: It's like this mysterious and incredibly powerful overseer of the train would be kind of like if you what if they made an Ava spin-off that was about like all the Background character.
Speaker 0: Yeah, an Ava spin-off that was about Sele.
Speaker 0: It was just like Sele guys hanging out like what's up and you could totally see them and they were yeah, right?
Speaker 0: That's her.
Speaker 0: so it's like you know.
Speaker 0: so the fact that I had this mystique of the Galaxy Railways and the show builds on that is what sort of gives it a Lot of its feeling and if you don't have that care for the Galaxy Railways as an organization Some of that feeling may be lost but the show Still hold up.
Speaker 0: I feel like You don't need to have any pre knowledge to understand what's going on of the Galaxy Express.
Speaker 1: 3 9 that I've seen.
Speaker 1: the Galaxy Railways is basically the in the Chinese kung-fu movie.
Speaker 1: The guy in the white suit is not doing anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, he does something a couple every now and then he comes in and does something.
Speaker 1: then he goes away and you want to Know where he went.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is guy in white suit kicking ass every episode.
Speaker 0: Of course, of course, you know, there's another level of guys in white suits, you know to keep the show interesting.
Speaker 1: So it wasn't that long ago actually that I watched, you know, remember birdie the mighty the old anime That was actually pretty fun.
Speaker 0: I never watched.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so birdie the mighty was remade.
Speaker 1: I think I did a geek bite on this a while ago.
Speaker 1: birdie the mighty decode.
Speaker 1: and then they made a sequel to that which I haven't watched yet and it has the all the same things that I like about the x-men anime birdie the mighty actually had because it's like Superhero sci-fi well choreographed fights good music good animation fun to watch.
Speaker 1: I don't really want to say much more about it other than that.
Speaker 1: if you're an anime fan Not you know, like an actual like I enjoy anime.
Speaker 1: Birdie the mighty decode is one of those kinds of anime that reminds you how much you like even the dumb sci-fi anime.
Speaker 1: You know, I've been.
Speaker 1: there's something to the dumb sci-fi anime I've been trying to.
Speaker 0: you know, because I've been an anime drought I've been looking for one to go next.
Speaker 1: you really should watch birdie the mighty decode.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll do birdie the mighty then birdie decode and then birdie decode do.
Speaker 0: I'll do the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Ah, I've been.
Speaker 0: I've been good at that lately.
Speaker 1: The thing is the original birdie the mighty is a pretty good show.
Speaker 1: I didn't finish it, but I'd seen a whole bunch of it because Gerald recommended it.
Speaker 0: I've seen zero but I haven't heard anyone say anything bad.
Speaker 1: Anime had always told me to watch it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've only heard good things about all birdie the mighties But I've never seen any.
Speaker 0: so maybe I'll maybe I'll get on that.
Speaker 1: It's just one of those.
Speaker 1: It's it's got the kind of over-the-top Anime kind of plot kind of stereotypical.
Speaker 1: you can kind of see where it's going.
Speaker 1: But at the same time the plot is interesting.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a giant robo II plot, but bring it scale it back like a hundredfold And her power suit has high heels.
Speaker 0: Maybe now I don't want it.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: You're making it not appealing now.
Speaker 1: See you'll think that but then you watch it.
Speaker 1: You're like wow, really high heels.
Speaker 1: Hey, okay It's definitely like it's kind of playing with the tropes of old anime but doing it in a fun way Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: All right, another show.
Speaker 0: I watched completely all of that.
Speaker 0: I know I think there's some OAVs and movies I haven't seen but I watched the entire Votoms TV series all three parts.
Speaker 1: I've seen 11 episodes of photons, right?
Speaker 0: So basically the deal with photons is this right.
Speaker 0: you got this guy Who is on.
Speaker 0: he's in some military where they use, you know powered armors that are sort of like battle mechs But smaller kind of gun to me, but you know the shit gun lower non Gundam.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the slow lumbering type, right?
Speaker 0: and he's on some secret mission and During the secret mission he encounters some weird secret of space like this Magical girl of some kind and he doesn't know what the fuck's going on.
Speaker 0: And then he you know sort of escapes this secret mission and he loses memory.
Speaker 0: and he like all you know He basically he doesn't have any memory before that mission and he's sort of like what the fuck.
Speaker 0: So the show's you know, and it's the story of what.
Speaker 0: what's up with this guy.
Speaker 0: He has no memory really but he's an awesome pilot of mech suits.
Speaker 0: So part one is like he's trapped in this city, you know where there's all this bad guys going on.
Speaker 0: in part two He's on another planet in a jungle scenario and in part three He's on a completely different planet.
Speaker 0: Well, he's first he's in space then he's on a different planet.
Speaker 0: So part one You know obviously starts off with that secret mission and then it's sort of you know Builds and it's a big sort of gets in this groove of being a pretty typical mech show like be quality You know, it's alright, you know, we got a mech show going on here some interesting stuff
Speaker 1: I mean, it's the kind of thing like while people in our crew put it on while we were in Wildwood on the shore And just like, you know put six episodes on in a row while we're dicking around playing games.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like a Gundam but a little bit less, you know good, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, also a little less gun to me and a little more military.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's a little more like this from what I saw It's a little closer to some of the stuff that goes on like Venus Wars in terms of the way people fight.
Speaker 0: Definitely the style of it is definitely more that you know early 90s, you know tank police kind of aesthetic Tank police again.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so part two in the jungle actually starts off.
Speaker 0: We were kind of like But then it sort of builds towards something and you're like, oh, okay They're bringing it back into the plot because the beginning of that second arc with the jungle I was sort of being like what should I stop watching because I'm not too interested now
Speaker 1: It seems like it's definitely a show worth watching and I will finish it someday.
Speaker 0: But then the third part, right?
Speaker 0: This is you know, it's like, you know people talk about shows like Gao Gai Ga and how they start off crap and then get Good later.
Speaker 0: So right and I'm always like it's not worth sitting through crap for to get to the good part, right?
Speaker 0: But photons is like you sit through the slightly above average part to get to the above average part.
Speaker 0: It doesn't get amazing.
Speaker 0: It gets pretty great.
Speaker 0: Good great good, right?
Speaker 0: So it's basically BB BBB and you get to part three and it's like a - right a - that's some pretty heady praise.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good, you know, but it's not like the best.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah the So that third part basically is where it busts out, you know The anime sci-fi stuff we're like, there's the terrible secret of space What it is love old sci-fi stuff where the terrible secret is revealed and then there's like ten more episodes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's exactly.
Speaker 0: that's the thing right because in a lot of shows There'll be a terrible secret of space that might be revealed at the very very end.
Speaker 0: eska flown a yep Right the very very end.
Speaker 0: they reveal it and we're done or they'll sort of half reveal it and they won't Completely answer everything and then they're done vote Tom's.
Speaker 0: they answer 99 or a hundred percent of the terrible secret of space Well before the final final final episode.
Speaker 0: So they actually you know It's like you learn a lot of terrible secrets of space and they build on it over quite a few episodes Towards the end of that third arc and there's sort of also sub secrets of space.
Speaker 0: So it's like square bosses upon square bosses and each one is a good one.
Speaker 0: So that third arc is is pretty good.
Speaker 0: I liked it and you're pumping me up.
Speaker 1: I think I'll have to move this up in the queue.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you haven't watched the vote Tom's and you like sci-fi Animes go for it.
Speaker 0: and then you know, it is a mecha show.
Speaker 0: There are robot fights, but actually there's like a lot less robot fighting than say, you know a Gundam or whatever It's and when there is it seems like I said more like a venus wars fight.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the thing is in the early lucky a little there are some things that are you know presented as like tournaments But not really.
Speaker 0: it's pretty much like, you know, hey you you know, we're it's part of the plot like hey We're gonna use you You know to fight for money in in the games because you have these mad robot skills and then he sort of tries to escape From them is not like it's not like they ever
Speaker 1: actually why would you try to escape for one must fall 2097?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not like a tournament ever actually happens or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Right, all the robot fighting is actually battles that make that have a reason in the context of the plot.
Speaker 0: It's never like one battle per episode because you have to like that and because and the robots actually are sort of all you know More I mean there are sort of superpowers, right?
Speaker 0: And sci-fi things that make them, you know, some people just awesome Coordinators new types.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much exactly that.
Speaker 0: but Even though eat despite that the robots are pretty slow and lumbering and the weapon attacks are pretty real, you know more.
Speaker 0: I Guess not realistic but more like battle tech and less like less firing the lone greens.
Speaker 0: Yeah less of that.
Speaker 1: So speaking of B plus a minus anime and terrible secrets of space I watched all of scrap princess instead of going to a class at our IT and I then failed.
Speaker 0: I never watched the scrap print Watch four episodes at an anime club meeting.
Speaker 1: that princess is a solid B plus.
Speaker 0: I think it's largely forgotten by people.
Speaker 1: I know scrap princess the plot of scrap princess.
Speaker 1: on the surface It is a fantasy world, you know, there's wizards and it's not remember.
Speaker 0: There's not too many fantasy anime out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I should add this to that animation C panel on hey fantasy anime.
Speaker 1: There aren't that many Yeah, but it's a fantasy world on the surface, but really it's sci-fi.
Speaker 1: It's one of those worlds where everyone is magic and wizards and swords and whatnot.
Speaker 1: But yet the terrible secret of space.
Speaker 1: it's kind of obvious from a meta level that the magic is actually very advanced science but people have forgotten and There's space plot that people don't see coming Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to avoid spoiling but also spoiling just enough to get people to consider watching the show that yes.
Speaker 1: This is a space Sci-fi terrible secret show that pretends to be fantasy.
Speaker 0: So it's like it was a sci-fi world.
Speaker 0: But then some sort of apocalypse happened that turned it into a fantasy.
Speaker 1: It picks up in kind of in media res.
Speaker 1: the story is that the scrapped princess is a girl Who for various reasons is destined as far as the establishment of this world says the protectors of the world the rulers?
Speaker 1: Everyone.
Speaker 1: she will destroy the world.
Speaker 0: So when she turns a certain age Why don't you just kill her before then?
Speaker 1: The world is like, alright, we figured this out.
Speaker 1: We're going to murder her.
Speaker 0: Well, how do they know this?
Speaker 0: Where's the legend come from?
Speaker 1: So this is that's part of the plot.
Speaker 1: You don't know right away where this comes from.
Speaker 1: It's just everybody knows it.
Speaker 1: That's like the legend of forever.
Speaker 0: So how do they know?
Speaker 0: it's her?
Speaker 1: Uh, well, that's the plot.
Speaker 1: they know.
Speaker 1: okay, and some people Smuggle her away and try to protect her because they think this is all bullshit.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh they did.
Speaker 0: They really just care about her They don't.
Speaker 0: I thought that they were just people who you know wanted the world.
Speaker 1: one of them.
Speaker 1: So one of them cares about her but basically says if it turns out that this is true I love you, but I will kill you.
Speaker 0: See I thought it.
Speaker 1: see but that's like the other person just cares about her and thinks this is bullshit.
Speaker 1: It's it's complicated.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's kind of weird though.
Speaker 0: It's like they they saving her because they care about her as if it's like the real reason to save her because you want the World to end not because well, maybe there are people who want that too.
Speaker 1: It's a kind of.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of characters in this show and it kind of it starts out slightly Episodic like a lot of shows like that do and then it actually the sci-fi plot builds and builds and builds.
Speaker 1: the characters are great.
Speaker 1: There's a couple of really big turnabouts.
Speaker 1: It's BB plus BB plus all the way through.
Speaker 1: it would have been an a-minus show Except you know how I said.
Speaker 1: I like a show where the terrible secret is revealed and then you've got like ten more episodes.
Speaker 1: So the last episode, right?
Speaker 1: The I catch happens halfway through the episode, you know, Jack and shit.
Speaker 1: Okay, the second half of the last episode Reveals the entire terrible secret from space resolves it all and has the epilogue Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they ran out of money I don't know what but this show could have been a-minus if they had done that like even an episode earlier.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so does it like.
Speaker 0: does the pacing get really fast at the end?
Speaker 1: Like oh the pacing is the same rate all the way through and then after the I cash.
Speaker 1: And yeah, like it's it's crazy.
Speaker 1: I can't.
Speaker 1: I can't think of any show short of What's that show that ended early.
Speaker 1: They ran out of money as they said fuck it A lot of them.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll look it up later and put it in the show notes.
Speaker 1: cuz I can't.
Speaker 1: the title just escapes me.
Speaker 0: Okay, there's a lot of shows that did that.
Speaker 1: Yeah But anyway that that's my only complaint with the show and that brings it down to the B plus instead of the a-minus.
Speaker 1: But it's definitely worth watching if you're looking for a pretty good anime to watch.
Speaker 1: pretty good.
Speaker 0: Not great All right Let's see here.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I watch what you are 100% of the galaxy.
Speaker 1: frow line, Yuna.
Speaker 0: I only watched a part of that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I should finish it though.
Speaker 0: It's not that long.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's not.
Speaker 1: I've got it right there.
Speaker 0: I watched all the Pat LeBourde the OAV TV series second TV series second OAV movie movie movie.
Speaker 0: I've watched all of.
Speaker 1: I've only seen movie see.
Speaker 0: But here's something that happened, right?
Speaker 0: So I knew Pat LeBourde was a cool thing at RIT.
Speaker 0: I tried to watch a bunch of it.
Speaker 0: I watched two movies on VHS and I watched.
Speaker 0: the VHS is from the anime club.
Speaker 0: But the VHS from the anime club were sort of screwy.
Speaker 0: See people don't know this but the laser discs of Pat LeBourde.
Speaker 0: if you bought them The first episode on the laser disc would be an episode from OAV.
Speaker 0: I think one or two I don't remember.
Speaker 0: but then the rest of the laser disc would be TV episodes.
Speaker 0: So it was sort of like OAV and TV episodes were mixed on the laser discs and the VHS is restraint from the laser discs.
Speaker 0: So they were also mixed up also and I sort of didn't know I didn't have that kind of information in the year 2000.
Speaker 0: Kind of watching you're like man Encyclopedia was not so fully flesh.
Speaker 1: the animation jumps all over the place.
Speaker 0: Well, it was like why the opener changed and the plot wasn't.
Speaker 1: you know, I was I you know But I wasn't paying close Like I remember watching this fan sub of like project a co and it had just all this random shit.
Speaker 1: after project a co ended Just like 45 minutes of like music videos and stuff Yep, but anyway.
Speaker 0: So I went back You know recently and I rewatched all the Pat LeBourde and I understood which parts are which and I'm the right order and everything.
Speaker 0: So here's here's how it breaks down.
Speaker 0: Everybody in the entire universe should watch Pat LeBourde OAV number one.
Speaker 0: that is made by Mamoru Oshii.
Speaker 0: It is the first Pat LeBourde there is.
Speaker 0: it is a hundred percent awesome and it's only a few episodes.
Speaker 0: It's made of tons of win, right and that introduces you to everything.
Speaker 0: Everyone in the entire goddamn universe should watch Pat LeBourde movies one and two also made by Mamoru Oshii Also made of tons of win all over the place, right movies are good.
Speaker 0: That's some of the best anime movies ever.
Speaker 0: and the thing is you can watch the movies without having seen that first OAV.
Speaker 0: But I recommend watching the OAV first anyway Because you'll get more familiar with the characters.
Speaker 0: and really characters are what drives Pat LeBourde right more.
Speaker 0: So, you know it has robots, but it's basically the robots in the show.
Speaker 0: They're just basically police cars, you know, it's like kind of like Gasaraki.
Speaker 1: the robots are just tanks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they just happen to be drawn as robots, right?
Speaker 0: The show would work.
Speaker 0: It's basically a police show.
Speaker 0: It might as well be Odoro Daisousasen only they happen to have police robots.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, I could watch that movie again.
Speaker 0: In fact, it's incredibly like Odoro Daisousasen.
Speaker 0: I put it in the exact same genre.
Speaker 1: We've done a show on Odoro Daisousasen, right?
Speaker 0: I think we did a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I feel like we should watch it again and do it a show on it.
Speaker 1: I know I'll get it.
Speaker 0: I'll get both of them.
Speaker 0: Rainbow Bridge also.
Speaker 0: Rainbow Bridge wasn't as good though But it was still the part of the beginning that opening scene with the boat with the paintball.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually the whole thing was great except for the very end, which is kind of just a yeah.
Speaker 0: But I mean, you know Rainbow Bridge wasn't as good as part as the original but it was still.
Speaker 1: I mean For all you listeners who probably don't know what we're talking about Odoro Daisousasen is a TV series and some movies in Japan about cops Like if you like like you're under arrest like a character driven cop drama mostly humorous also kind of serious.
Speaker 1: But the first movie we watched at RIT and we liked it so much that when I was president of the RIT anime club one of the few one of the big like privileges you get is that on the last day of your tenure the Final like meeting of the year of the season of everything you show whatever the fuck you want And I showed the live-action.
Speaker 1: Odoro Daisousasen Bayside Shakedown, baby, and I gave all these hints.
Speaker 1: I was like, yeah, the opening theme is also in Dance Dance Revolution, which is true.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: None of you have seen it Which is true.
Speaker 1: It's about cops, which is true.
Speaker 1: The show got a standing ovation from the crowd at the end.
Speaker 1: It is one of the best goddamn movies.
Speaker 0: Huh this according well not not best in like citizen.
Speaker 0: according to Wikipedia Bayside Shakedown 3 came out in summer 2010 But I'm checking that right now.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with us?
Speaker 1: You know, what's wrong with us?
Speaker 1: We don't have a video bar to tell us when stuff like that comes out.
Speaker 0: I'm doing some searching right now.
Speaker 0: But anyway Bayside Shakedown 3.
Speaker 0: Yeah Got hot as a 5.7 and IMDb is it?
Speaker 0: It might be awful.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the trouble is Bayside Shakedown is the kind of movie that is besto if you're the kind of person who likes Movies like Attack the Gas Station.
Speaker 0: So back to Pat LeVoir.
Speaker 1: Back to Pat LeVoir.
Speaker 0: Which is the same genre, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know you got movie 1 movie 2 OAV 1 awesome.
Speaker 0: Then you got TV series 1.
Speaker 0: TV series 1 is not actually directed by Mamoru Oshii, but a lot of it.
Speaker 0: I think he's written some of it directly or indirectly and you can sort of tell Some of the episodes that he had a major influence on and the ones that he didn't, right?
Speaker 0: Like there's an episode that has no robots in it and is all about waiting for the Chinese food order to show up.
Speaker 1: There was a Seinfeld about that too.
Speaker 0: And that episode is so clearly Mamoru Oshii's doing, right?
Speaker 0: There's like no robots in it whatsoever and he's like one of the best freaking episodes.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it actually has a contiguous plot that you know goes.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know tells a story but some of the episodes are more episodic than others And it's a little bit more light-hearted and less serious sci-fi anime than the movies in the first OAV.
Speaker 1: Well kind of like look at the differences between like Ghost in the Shell the anime versus the manga versus the movies Exactly.
Speaker 0: So this is more like the standalone complex to the Ghost in the Shell movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right But it's still.
Speaker 0: I really like it a whole lot.
Speaker 0: You know, you might not like it as much as the first OAV in the movies But it's still good and it gives you more of those characters and they're in character and it totally works.
Speaker 0: So it's like you're all- Palobor is all about being attached to the characters And if you're attached to them, you're gonna want to watch TV series.
Speaker 0: The second OAV comes after the first TV series before the second TV series, right?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure if I remember correctly and it sort of ties, you know, it's sort of basically Continuation of TV series into.
Speaker 0: you know The second yeah, it's like the in-between part.
Speaker 0: It's just like a plot connector Right, so I got a fairly egregious one.
Speaker 1: You do need to see it.
Speaker 1: And then the second time you see gone Yeah, you got more Palobor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the second TV series is sort of like, all right, you know we're just gonna keep going.
Speaker 0: and The quality- Just like you?
Speaker 0: Yeah You know the quality goes down.
Speaker 0: You know a little bit but you know, it's still good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's one of those like A to A minis I'm trying to remember like maybe there isn't a second TV series.
Speaker 1: Oh Careful now.
Speaker 0: This is the problem.
Speaker 0: According to Anime News Network, there isn't.
Speaker 0: I'm just remembering things fucked up like Anyway, all right old man Scott.
Speaker 0: Yeah old man me.
Speaker 0: But anyway, you should watch all the Palobors.
Speaker 1: So a show that you Scott should watch so we can do a show on it because I think it's actually a great goddamn show Is the melancholy of Haruhi Suzumiya.
Speaker 0: I'll have to watch that at some point.
Speaker 1: It's really good and it's not about what you think it's about.
Speaker 1: What do you think it's about?
Speaker 1: because you've you've obviously heard about it.
Speaker 1: people have said things about based.
Speaker 0: I've absorbed a lot of information.
Speaker 0: I've watched a few episodes, right?
Speaker 0: So from what I can tell the few episodes I watched was like, okay, they're in school.
Speaker 0: There's a girl named Haruhi.
Speaker 0: She's totally weird.
Speaker 0: She drags in these other weird people.
Speaker 0: Clearly each of the people has something weird about them, right?
Speaker 0: That is some something sci-fi ish, right?
Speaker 0: And from what I can tell it's you know It looks to be high school silliness with a weird girl at first glance.
Speaker 0: But really based on all the things people say and all the things that I've just sort of absorbed pulls Scott is Scott.
Speaker 1: it pulls a big o2.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's some sort of end of the world.
Speaker 0: Haruhi is Aliens and who knows well?
Speaker 1: here I will summarize it yet simultaneously not actually spoil anything.
Speaker 1: I think most of our listeners have probably already seen Haruhi and there's more Haruhi that was made later, but whatever.
Speaker 1: Basically it's about a girl who's obsessed with finding Anything crazy like magic or aliens or ESP or you know any just finding something like that like our friend Scott Johnson.
Speaker 1: If you find one then odds are some other ones out there too.
Speaker 1: Like if you find one vampire shit is on.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: So she's obsessed with this and she never finds anything.
Speaker 1: cuz you know cuz whatever.
Speaker 1: It just so happens that everyone around her is one of those things Except for this one guy who's friends with her and he sees all this crazy stuff and she doesn't see it.
Speaker 1: Like she can't find it, but he's always like running afoul of it.
Speaker 1: There's a lot more to it than that, but that's kind of the the first layer gist of this.
Speaker 0: That's why she's melancholy because she can't find any of these awesome things bored with existence.
Speaker 1: She's bored with life.
Speaker 1: She's bored with everything.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, and it's just.
Speaker 1: it's a good show really.
Speaker 1: It's solidly done.
Speaker 1: The animation is great The story is great that the the moral of it is pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's it's I call it an anime Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: All right, so I figured out why I was fucked up in the head with Pat LaVoir.
Speaker 0: because you're old No, because OAV - basically might as well be TV - right.
Speaker 0: so I was remembering them sort of like two separate things Really?
Speaker 0: They're the same.
Speaker 0: so you watch right so it's the TV right and then the OAV - comes after it.
Speaker 0: the OAV one Comes first.
Speaker 0: So it's OAV one then TV then TV - then movie movie movie if you want to go chronologically Right, but the movie standalone the third movie actually Doesn't really have the characters in it has like these other characters who aside characters gonna be see destiny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it has like, you know, it's basically focuses on these two detectives.
Speaker 0: It's still an okay anime sci-fi movie, but it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not like super awesome Pat LaVoir, but it's in the Pat LaVoir universe All right.
Speaker 1: All right, you know the even more egregious than Hari the fact you haven't actually seen Irresponsible Captain Tyler.
Speaker 0: I watched a ton of it though.
Speaker 0: Yes, but 11 episodes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you didn't even get to.
Speaker 1: it's one of those shows.
Speaker 1: It's like big O where you know What's part of the movie.
Speaker 1: the first half is great.
Speaker 1: And then the second half is like oh, oh, oh, I see.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh I'm sure I'll watch it at some point, but it's I don't have a DVD box.
Speaker 1: it I've got it.
Speaker 1: if I didn't lend it to anyone I'll lend it to you, but I think I lent it to someone.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, then I can't be borrowing again.
Speaker 1: I will find it.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's on my like triple-a top list Like I put it at the top with cowboy bebop and Ava.
Speaker 0: No you do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know what else does.
Speaker 1: Oh, I think you might.
Speaker 1: then once you see it all it has It's definitely possible.
Speaker 1: It has a scene at the end where somebody salutes somebody and it is off the hook Rainbow Dash.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I'm gonna talk about a manga that I read now.
Speaker 0: it's called seven billion needles.
Speaker 0: It was put out by vertical in the US and it's actually only four little volumes.
Speaker 0: so you can totally get the whole thing real easy like all right, and Basically the story in seven billion needles is this is girl who's mad bored with everything.
Speaker 0: All right, she's in school She doesn't have friends.
Speaker 0: She doesn't talk to anyone.
Speaker 0: She sits there with the headphones on all day.
Speaker 0: she's like I fuck this shit, right and then she's on the beach for some reason and something comes crashing out of space terrible secret and Actually possesses her.
Speaker 0: but it doesn't possess her like you're possessed by the demon.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like aha now, I'm living in your body alongside you right some sort of space spirit.
Speaker 0: I'm sort of symbiote right something and it talks to her in her brain, right and It also has incredible powers.
Speaker 0: But this thing has morals so it won't just control her without her permission or use her body without her permission.
Speaker 1: Right, how birdie the mighty is a lot of that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, cuz it pretty much is about the guy who transforms into right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because she punches him to death by accident in any way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway, so So this thing possesses her and basically tells her look there's some horrible evil thing is basically the opposite of me.
Speaker 0: It's an horrible evil thing that possesses and doesn't have morals and wants to like eat your whole world and I chase it here from Outer space.
Speaker 0: so we have to find it and you know do what I say.
Speaker 0: and over the course of four volumes It actually, you know, you think of four volumes.
Speaker 0: this the story is gonna be find it Get beat by it then come back beat at the end.
Speaker 0: But actually Pretty early it's like they encounter it and some crazy shit happens and a big change happens and it swings another direction Really quickly, huh?
Speaker 0: And it's like whoa, that's really surprising and I didn't actually read the fourth volume yet I'm gonna reread from one two, three, four and one go just so I can get the whole picture.
Speaker 0: So I could imagine another big swing near the end being very likely.
Speaker 0: so, you know If if you like, you know sci-fi animes or mangas at least, you know And you like things that are short and cheap, but also a highbrow Right without a lot of dragging out of fights or anything like that You should definitely pick up all four volumes of seven billion needles at your earliest opportunity.
Speaker 1: Alright, we should probably wind this down.
Speaker 1: I guess I just got one more.
Speaker 1: I don't you have any more.
Speaker 0: I could do a quick one.
Speaker 1: if I'll do a quick one, too I'll skip on all these things that I got listed here, but this is kind of an old one.
Speaker 1: But have you actually read any of the earthsakes are a manga?
Speaker 0: No, I didn't know there was a manga.
Speaker 0: I thought it was incredibly long anime and that was it.
Speaker 1: It's also incredibly long manga.
Speaker 0: I did not know that because it's done by miss.
Speaker 1: Let's write incredibly long manga that don't go anywhere.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess that's true.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, so the earthsakes are a manga is up your alley to a degree that is startling you realize.
Speaker 0: I'm sure I know it is But it's like I got to get.
Speaker 0: all of earthsakes are is very difficult.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean everyone I know Read the old volumes that were put out in America.
Speaker 1: that were bound very poorly and fell apart immediately like so fast.
Speaker 1: It's ridiculous, but it's like you like Hakaba, Kitaro, I do.
Speaker 1: it's a lot like that.
Speaker 1: It's very like inside baseball.
Speaker 0: I would have gotten I would get the entire TV series and all the movies from anime ego.
Speaker 0: But they sort of stopped some of this printing some of them and the DDS are always so expensive.
Speaker 0: The thing is they would have just made a slim case with the whole thing Guaranteed in one shot with one empty spot.
Speaker 1: Remember there was that box set of all the movies except two, but that's all the movies.
Speaker 0: I want the whole TV series in a slim case of some kind right and all those movies except for number two You know in a box for like a hundred bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do it.
Speaker 1: So I guess my thing here is all the roomie go Takahashi stuff because I don't think you've.
Speaker 1: actually I mean Did you how much Ranma have you actually seen or read?
Speaker 0: Maybe five to ten episodes.
Speaker 1: I've seen like at least half of Ranma.
Speaker 1: How about mezani koku?
Speaker 0: One or two episodes and maybe half a manga volume.
Speaker 1: I read the whole manga cow style.
Speaker 0: I know you did.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I love that that stuff is great.
Speaker 1: And I think ursa dessert is my favorite of it.
Speaker 1: But you know what Ranma is some funny shit And I feel like people don't give it enough credit for being so.
Speaker 1: I feel like new fans never go to watch Ranma, but I feel like new fans would love Ranma if they just watched it.
Speaker 1: I don't think they realize it's a goonie.
Speaker 1: calm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's almost like it was a gateway drug of you know, some some bygone era and That it was sort of all used up.
Speaker 0: and now people are you know using Naruto or whatever?
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz in the old days like I would take friends in high school and they'd never even heard of anime I'd be like watch this I'd show them like one episode of Ranma and they're like wait so this is a show about a guy who turns into a girl and that guy
Speaker 0: and I really get wet and
Speaker 1: And they love it and they turn into anime fans.
Speaker 0: Yeah Maybe we should try out some Ranma on.
Speaker 0: some people see if it still works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it might it might it might rabbit.
Speaker 1: You got it.
Speaker 1: You got one one more one more one more.
Speaker 1: I got one two, three four five nine more.
Speaker 0: All right, fine.
Speaker 0: I do have a lot more.
Speaker 0: most of them are.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about Rosa Versailles, which I watched all of I've seen up to all the Madame du Barry stuff Not that far.
Speaker 0: That's so early on.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Madame du Barry When a Herp de derp de derp.
Speaker 0: So Rosa Versailles totally awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah How many Louie's.
Speaker 0: were there too many?
Speaker 0: yeah The point is it's totally awesome.
Speaker 0: The end is totally the French Revolution.
Speaker 0: if you didn't know that.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people might die.
Speaker 0: I should watch it again.
Speaker 0: It was so good.
Speaker 1: as soon as I finish fist of the North Star, which I'm doing slowly cuz I've been busy I think.
Speaker 1: Rosa Versailles my next big long one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just basically I just couldn't hold back.
Speaker 0: We were watching it together one episode at a time But then I just said I'll fuck it and watch the whole thing.
Speaker 1: You know It'd be really easy to do because every time like we'd watch an episode or two at your place and then we'd have to go Home and I on the one on the like bus home.
Speaker 1: I'd be like fuck what happens?
Speaker 0: I know everything that happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what they die.
Speaker 0: You know what.
Speaker 0: guess what happens to the best deal.
Speaker 1: I believe People break into it.
Speaker 0: Oh Do you know what happens to Versailles?
Speaker 1: The palace cuz it's still there today, I know nothing.
Speaker 0: it's it's Jagged.
Speaker 0: but what happens to the roses, you know, what happens to robes Pierre?
Speaker 1: You get shot in the jaw and then guillotined.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: He might have shot himself in the jaw.
Speaker 0: Do I happens to Marie Antoinette?
Speaker 1: I guess the chop.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Everything everything happens in real life happens in the show except the show.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna tell you at which point in history the show ends because some of those things Happen after the end of the show.
Speaker 1: Oh shit, son.
Speaker 0: And some of those things happen before the end of the show so you don't get to see the whole thing.
Speaker 1: It's a great show.
Speaker 1: It is the awesomest as opposed to say brother dear brother, which I haven't watched Brother dear brother.
Speaker 1: Come on I'm gonna spoil brother dear now.
Speaker 1: I'll save that for another time.
Speaker 0: everyone dies Now.
Speaker 1: I used to have a hobby where I would people would be like oh I heard that.
Speaker 1: you know Utena was kind of like.
Speaker 1: a lot of the style and theme were borrowed from brother dear brother and I would say alright look I'm Gonna spoil brother dear brother for you and you're never gonna watch the show now.
Speaker 1: and I've been thanked in every case.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So how come you're not doing it right now?
Speaker 1: Cuz it's gone on for an hour.
Speaker 1: All right, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.