Speaker 0: It's Monday October 10th, 2011.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm sky and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: I Was gonna feel I was sitting there thinking like you have no idea what you're gonna say for the title of the show.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had no idea what I was gonna call this episode and you know normally I can just say something.
Speaker 0: it's like tonight.
Speaker 0: we're talking about ducks, but There was no one word to say what we're talking about back.
Speaker 0: Should we do a show on ducks?
Speaker 1: I don't know anything about ducks except that they're tasty.
Speaker 0: Well, you never had a pet duck.
Speaker 1: No, really?
Speaker 1: You didn't either.
Speaker 0: Uh, yes.
Speaker 0: Actually I did an actual duck an actual duck for a while.
Speaker 1: How was it?
Speaker 1: You're how did you take care of it?
Speaker 0: It was a rescue duck and we raised him and then when he was old enough We have a pond for it to live in.
Speaker 0: we had a kiddie pool.
Speaker 1: You left the duck in the kiddie pool.
Speaker 1: It didn't fly away.
Speaker 0: No, he walked around the garage and he packed it.
Speaker 1: I didn't need a big duck to follow around a little duck train.
Speaker 1: You have wooden ducks and a string to teach it to flutter walker.
Speaker 0: Now I'm just thinking about the next key CD where they make the circle of ducks.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I digress.
Speaker 0: so we were in Manhattan over the weekend.
Speaker 1: It's not that far having a party.
Speaker 1: I'm in Manhattan almost every weekend.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we're having a party in Central Park kind of a picnic because it was not a party.
Speaker 0: It was a party picnic.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: Well, you wouldn't call that a party bunch of friends hanging out drinking wine Playing the hive with random kids.
Speaker 1: It's not a party.
Speaker 0: What's a party?
Speaker 1: It has to have partying.
Speaker 0: So standing around listening to that one really lame song or a cake or cake a cake would would work.
Speaker 0: Well, you had strawberries.
Speaker 1: It's not a.
Speaker 0: and we had some cake pastries from a Korean deli.
Speaker 1: Those aren't working our Korean Baker.
Speaker 0: They were not cakes anyway, but we're there hanging out and I'm climbing rocks and we're doing all this stuff and then Words start appearing in the sky.
Speaker 0: first we appeared.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh you I as we that Yes, and then a bunch of other stuff.
Speaker 1: and it's amazing because in New York pretty much Well, I think before that we only noticed when the we appeared.
Speaker 1: but when we looked up at the we there was an ST Over to the side.
Speaker 1: So it was like st.
Speaker 0: We street.
Speaker 1: we stewie st.
Speaker 1: Louis Maybe Ellen the answer coming in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it was weird because in New York people don't react to things Usually like a gun could go off and most people just keep walking because they got somewhere to be Fire trucks going by.
Speaker 0: there's some jackass jaywalking in front of it.
Speaker 0: Yep But yet in Central Park, there were thousands of people just looking up at the sky.
Speaker 0: because what's that?
Speaker 0: What's it say?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Well, they weren't.
Speaker 1: you know, we're hanging out in the park.
Speaker 1: It's not like you're doing anything or in a rush to go anywhere.
Speaker 1: You're just laying down in the grass.
Speaker 1: You look up in the sky writing.
Speaker 1: it's like oh I wonder what that's gonna say.
Speaker 0: So, uh, we kept trying to watch it for a while and a bunch of words appeared.
Speaker 0: It didn't really make any sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think at the end it like said st.
Speaker 1: We lease or our lease.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Today I went on Google and I was like art Google News.
Speaker 0: Tell me what I was up with sky writing over.
Speaker 1: How come they allow sky writing over Manhattan when that isn't that fake like coming after that?
Speaker 1: Maybe they got a permit.
Speaker 0: Maybe I figured out what happens an easy permit again.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I want to draw eight equals equals equals D?
Speaker 0: Sure, so I go to Google News right and I type sky writing.
Speaker 0: Manhattan.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: The first headline is what jittery New Yorkers fear.
Speaker 0: sky writing terrorists, right?
Speaker 0: Next one sky writing in New York causes confusion.
Speaker 0: every article about the sky writing makes a mention of 9/11.
Speaker 1: I'm sure that the sky writer was, you know going to drop bombs from his tiny sky writing play.
Speaker 0: Well, apparently he wrote many messages.
Speaker 0: One of them was lost our lease.
Speaker 0: One of them was now open one of them was last chance and supposedly people who saw the last chance one Got scared.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, but it bothers me that every single article about who is now open Who lost their lease and it's the last.
Speaker 1: I'll get to that.
Speaker 0: but the fact that every article about this thing Brought up 9/11 as though they're in any way related.
Speaker 0: But at the same time I didn't see any citations of actual people bringing it up.
Speaker 0: It was news people saying.
Speaker 0: some people Reminded of 9/11.
Speaker 0: some people were afraid that it was a warning some people.
Speaker 1: I don't think there were any actual people who thought.
Speaker 0: I think it was just.
Speaker 0: you know Some people is code in the news for I made some shit up or my personal opinion is Up up.
Speaker 0: No, god damn it.
Speaker 0: Here's a person.
Speaker 0: Oh, I was genuinely gonna be.
Speaker 1: yeah There's always gonna be said Morgan 29 an Upper West Side actress.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I was really concerned.
Speaker 0: There was some sort of terrorist attack.
Speaker 0: It's so creepy.
Speaker 1: Sure, whatever.
Speaker 0: So anyway, you know what this was.
Speaker 0: what art project?
Speaker 0: Nice they were writing lines from billboards that were in some way evocative of or Related to the economic problems.
Speaker 0: We're facing right now.
Speaker 0: Nice lost our lease Mm-hmm, and then the last message was now open saying you know what will eventually open back up.
Speaker 0: Everything will be okay in the long run.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: So it was just a kind of lame art projects and there.
Speaker 1: but you're allowed to do I guess dude, how much does it cost?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: We should write something actual like what?
Speaker 1: Well, first of all, we got a point out.
Speaker 0: one thing Yeah, we could not read lost our lease due to how quickly the letters dissipate.
Speaker 1: But that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: He's got away for the exact right weather You know and you got to have a very succinct message.
Speaker 0: like eight equals equals D.
Speaker 1: Exactly I think our message should be front row crew comm.
Speaker 0: maybe a Good message about just hash ponies.
Speaker 1: How about.
Speaker 1: they draw a rainbow - an outline of rainbow - or just they draw a cloud with lightning coming out of it.
Speaker 1: I would actually like to say they can do the colored smoke the Jets do it.
Speaker 0: The thing is this sort of art like is a neat art project But I don't know that I don't feel like it's really that original are like.
Speaker 0: The idea is cool.
Speaker 0: taking these slogans that are related to the economic crisis in some way gathered in some artsy way But why sky?
Speaker 0: write them like that was kind of just.
Speaker 0: that was like the equivalent of going to the gallery Cuz if you put your art and jelly surrounded by broken glass.
Speaker 1: if you put your art in a gallery 10 hipsters will come see if you put it in the sky.
Speaker 0: About how they didn't understand it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's better than not seeing it at all.
Speaker 0: I doubt that the majority of people will ever know it was an art project because you didn't even think To look it up.
Speaker 1: I did think to look it up But then I just didn't before I forgot and stop caring and you know what now now that I know I still don't care.
Speaker 0: see now.
Speaker 0: It would be a better art project if I drew.
Speaker 0: say the word fuck.
Speaker 1: Fuck.
Speaker 1: yeah, because then for speech And it would really it would definitely get more attention in the right kind of way I can imagine because the F you see would be up there and everyone in the street.
Speaker 0: We think in the same thing.
Speaker 0: They're not actually writing fuck, but I hope they write fuck.
Speaker 0: I should hire actually fuck.
Speaker 0: people would lose their shit.
Speaker 1: I should hire a sky writer to go to Philly and sky write like Philly.
Speaker 1: sucker Eagle suck.
Speaker 0: You're like Eagles.
Speaker 0: They're like whoa.
Speaker 0: you're like.
Speaker 0: They're like wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Oh suck Big X big ass exclamation point at the end or maybe even write Eagle suck dick.
Speaker 1: Get the extra word in there.
Speaker 1: How much does it cost per letter?
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: So in the news you all know that Netflix decided to launch Possibly the most stupidly named company the world has ever seen regardless of the dumb name, right?
Speaker 1: I don't believe that dumb names are harmful in the long run.
Speaker 1: look at the Wii.
Speaker 0: okay, the Wii wasn't that dumb of a name because whatever because it got people talking.
Speaker 0: Nobody I mean remember when they announced the name of the console.
Speaker 0: nobody would shut up about that for like a month.
Speaker 1: And now people don't even think about it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, because the we made so much money that they except they're coming out with a blue we now and Sonic is on the box.
Speaker 1: All I gotta say is if you're we got a blue.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we would not even be talking about the we.
Speaker 0: now my Wii is red, but at least that's mine's Flesh colored sure slightly red if I overuse it.
Speaker 0: mine's very anyway But seriously quickster Who?
Speaker 0: no human could think that was a good idea.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of name that you use.
Speaker 1: if they would up in 1991 if they were going to whatever if they would have just gone through with it people would have forgotten about the name thing and like You know a few months the big problem was they by.
Speaker 1: if they had gone through with it They would have split Netflix into two and people just want less thing.
Speaker 0: I was got the same way.
Speaker 1: you want less boxes under your TV.
Speaker 1: You want less bills less accounts with less different less companies?
Speaker 0: He's got.
Speaker 0: my point is that naming it quickster means that even the people who want the DVD would Probably not remember the name quickster because they would.
Speaker 0: they would think oh, that's some old pirating thing.
Speaker 1: No, there would be links to it from netflix.com.
Speaker 1: Like hey still want DVDs?
Speaker 1: click here.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the thing is a lot of people got confused.
Speaker 1: They thought there were two things that Netflix did.
Speaker 1: they did a price hike and then a little while after that They did.
Speaker 1: they were they were gonna do the split.
Speaker 1: so people thought that the price hike and the split were the same thing.
Speaker 1: That's not true.
Speaker 1: the price hike Was announced before the split was announced and the price hike isn't going anywhere.
Speaker 1: and the split was actually gonna keep the same price.
Speaker 1: It's just gonna give you two separate bills from two separate companies.
Speaker 1: That would have added up to be the same price as what you're gonna pay now anyway.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess my point is that the fact that they named it quickster.
Speaker 1: I just I think that you're obsessed with his name and I'm pretty sure it's the worst name.
Speaker 1: names don't matter.
Speaker 1: People have changed names of things.
Speaker 1: Phoenix changed to fire.
Speaker 1: bird would change the Firefox names.
Speaker 1: Everyone goes crazy when names are stupid or change.
Speaker 1: It'll never met anything.
Speaker 1: but you're one example of a stupid name or name change that caused the company any problem whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Zima No one drank Zima.
Speaker 1: No one drank Zima not because of the name It wasn't and it wasn't a name change or anything.
Speaker 1: It was a new name.
Speaker 0: This wasn't a name change.
Speaker 0: This was a new company called Napster whatever.
Speaker 1: people just didn't like quickster because they didn't want to have two separate fucking accounts.
Speaker 1: They wanted to keep this the one to keep it simple.
Speaker 0: and most people don't even want the DVDs.
Speaker 0: They just want streaming.
Speaker 0: but the majority of things you want to watch are not in the streaming because that's why I keep one DVD.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is and as soon as I finish IMDb top 250, I'm probably gonna cancel the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Well, I remember let's go back because something similar happened a long time ago when Netflix dropped the multiple cues per account.
Speaker 1: Did they bring that back or not?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure they brought it back, but I'm pretty sure they didn't.
Speaker 0: I'll bet you ten bucks that they did.
Speaker 1: Let me go look I'm gonna sign into my Netflix now because so here's the deal.
Speaker 0: back then they said, you know what one day You can't have multiple cues in your account anymore, which really we talked about this on geek nights.
Speaker 0: It really messed a lot of people like me up because I have a cue for like TV shows that are serial We're like, I don't want two DVDs of this show at the same time.
Speaker 0: I want to send back the DVD.
Speaker 0: I just finished and get the next DVD of a show.
Speaker 0: Independent of that I want all my movies in another queue.
Speaker 0: that way if I watch a movie and I send it back I get another movie.
Speaker 0: I don't get the next DVD of the show that I don't need.
Speaker 0: Yeah and they got rid of that and I said far if you have
Speaker 1: five people in your house and you're crazy and you pay for Five discs you want to have one account with one bill and you want to get five separate discs and five separate cues
Speaker 0: Yep, or you've got kids.
Speaker 0: you give them one DVD and their own cue so you don't have to deal with it.
Speaker 1: Okay, I'm logged into my Netflix and I had it says your cue and I can't find any way to get another cue.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure they announced that they were bringing it back.
Speaker 0: I Don't see anyway, I will try to look it up but regardless.
Speaker 0: so what happened was They they did this and I said fuck you.
Speaker 0: and I went down to one DVD.
Speaker 0: I'm like if I can't have multiple cues I only need one DVD.
Speaker 0: and then I realized that even if I could have cues back Which I don't know if I ever did get it back.
Speaker 0: and here's why there's confusion on that point.
Speaker 0: I only needed one DVD.
Speaker 0: I didn't watch enough Netflix for it to matter.
Speaker 1: Okay, so they didn't add multiple cues, but I can add profiles same thing which mean but it's like a whole separate account.
Speaker 0: But Scott it was always that way and those separate accounts can't watch instantly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was always that way.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Only there was no instantly back then anyway, maybe there was but it sucked.
Speaker 0: but Yeah, the DVD The whole DVD rental online model needs to go away.
Speaker 0: It's pointless to have the ability to rent DVDs in this fashion to the modern era.
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: No, it's.
Speaker 0: the only reason it's not pointless is because not everything is available for stream.
Speaker 1: Well, that's yeah.
Speaker 1: Everything was on the fucking stream.
Speaker 0: pointless in the high-level sense because there's no reason.
Speaker 0: Anything that is available on DVD can't be available for streaming.
Speaker 0: and you can't tell me That's because it takes too much space because space is infinite.
Speaker 0: and you can't tell me it's cuz it'll take too much bandwidth.
Speaker 1: It's just because the content is.
Speaker 1: they're trying to do it legally.
Speaker 1: someone should just start an illegal Netflix Just the way crunchyroll was illegal Originally.
Speaker 1: just put every fucking movie on there and just be like, yeah What what what?
Speaker 0: where are you gonna host this?
Speaker 1: some other country what country?
Speaker 0: Somalia?
Speaker 1: Fucking I don't know pirate Bay.
Speaker 0: All right, you're gonna get enough bandwidth for millions of people.
Speaker 1: It's in Sweden's.
Speaker 1: actually there's plenty of.
Speaker 0: but the problem is that the people who own the copyrights to things basically refuse to play ball with the modern media world.
Speaker 1: and I don't still don't know why a big smart tech company doesn't just buy all the fucking movies.
Speaker 1: Straight up movies might be a little it's like but look at it's like Netflix.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like.
Speaker 1: Netflix is like buying the rights to movies to put them streaming, you know, it's making deals.
Speaker 1: It's like don't make a deal just buy their entire fucking collection.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: It's like if I it's Remember how I asked the wedding photographer at Scott's wedding about.
Speaker 1: you know He basically lied to me because if you go to his website to look at the photos They all these watermarks on and he has a JavaScript to prevent you from context clicking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and he told me differently.
Speaker 1: He said yeah, you can do whatever you want with him as long as you're not like selling merchants, you know.
Speaker 1: But he was lying.
Speaker 0: Oh, of course wedding photographers always lie.
Speaker 0: I could have told his coach Oh that I didn't believe that guy for a second.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was very skeptical.
Speaker 1: But anyway, but I asked him and at least he answered me instead of just copping out.
Speaker 1: but yeah, but The point is it's like if I'm gonna pay a photographer to photograph an event at some point, right?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna just buy.
Speaker 1: you know, I'm not gonna be like.
Speaker 1: I will buy the prints from you.
Speaker 1: It's like no you're gonna give me the copyright to all the photos in writing, you know.
Speaker 1: So it's like Netflix.
Speaker 1: don't pay people to let you stream movies.
Speaker 1: buy the copyrights to all the goddamn movies.
Speaker 0: either They're not for sale The company just won't sell it to you or they ask too much money you if it's a public company It's for sale.
Speaker 1: No, that's what public means for sale.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you have enough money to just buy it out.
Speaker 1: Netflix was $300 a share before they fucked up even then.
Speaker 0: that doesn't mean they have that much cash.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't think you know how stock works.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying Google maybe could do.
Speaker 1: you don't have to buy all the movies.
Speaker 1: you just buy some movies and you start with some and you Can you make enough money off of the fact that people don't pay you extra?
Speaker 0: In fact, they have all their subscribers.
Speaker 0: Anyway, all they have to do their business model from a game theory perspective is to not lose subscribers and to gain more subscribers.
Speaker 0: Independent of what content they offer they have no incentive to add content unless it will add Thing.
Speaker 1: that's the number one reason that subscribers leave is because the contents.
Speaker 0: do they leave?
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone leaves.
Speaker 0: People have left.
Speaker 1: I don't think enough people have left to be even left because they watch all the good movies and stuff and then they don't have The newer seasons of the TV show.
Speaker 1: so they start pirating again.
Speaker 1: Day, they came out.
Speaker 0: people it's got it Scott.
Speaker 0: Do you have any numbers to back that up?
Speaker 1: No, that's what everyone's people say.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what people say the opposite that everyone just keeps their account.
Speaker 1: Netflix's subscriber numbers did go down.
Speaker 1: I read a thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the thing is they go.
Speaker 0: they went down during the profile business back in the day, too.
Speaker 0: They any company's subscriptions go down anytime anything changes.
Speaker 1: Mmm Anyway, we've got a lot too.
Speaker 1: Well too long about this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they basically capitulated and said alright, we'll have DVDs.
Speaker 0: I think you should be legally justified if you own a DVD of some media.
Speaker 0: I'm free to lend it to someone, right?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I should be free in my opinion to Transfer that to a digital form or have a fucking drive with the DVD in it.
Speaker 0: And if anyone wants to borrow it I can lend it to them.
Speaker 0: But I can only lend it to one person at a time or end people based on the number of DVDs.
Speaker 0: Mmm I believe that Netflix should be able to.
Speaker 0: if they own, you know, a hundred DVDs of some movie independent of what the guy who made the movie or the guy who owns the copyright of the movie wants they should be able to Let up to a hundred people stream that movie at the same time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 0: Well probably lawsuits and bullshit.
Speaker 1: Well, no, there was a similar thing where Cablevision wanted to.
Speaker 1: instead of giving people DVRs They wanted to have one DVR that were recorded all the shows at the Cablevision headquarters and then to stream the show to you when you wanted to watch On-demand.
Speaker 0: I think that should be fine.
Speaker 1: And I think they won when they tried to get that one over.
Speaker 0: I don't know because you brought that one up.
Speaker 1: The onus is on you anyway onus, but I don't think they did it.
Speaker 1: It's onus Charles.
Speaker 1: Something weird happened, but they should have.
Speaker 1: they should have just done it No matter what the court said.
Speaker 1: people have no balls.
Speaker 1: So anyway, anyway, I guess we should say something about Steve Jobs Even though it said the internet has said too much.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean a person died.
Speaker 1: It is sad.
Speaker 1: He changed the world in many ways.
Speaker 0: He was also bad in many ways, but he was like good in more ways than he was bad like all people's.
Speaker 1: Are there any people's who are all bad or all good?
Speaker 0: Maybe Hitler?
Speaker 1: he made paintings which were apparently they weren't that good.
Speaker 1: They weren't good, but they didn't hurt anybody.
Speaker 0: How do you know?
Speaker 0: maybe they were so bad that they drove him crazy.
Speaker 1: They couldn't have been as bad as like fanfiction paintings.
Speaker 1: You see They weren't for repainting saucy ones, maybe right.
Speaker 1: there weren't saucy furry paintings, maybe they were Yeah, and I guess when he was a baby he wasn't bad right did?
Speaker 1: maybe he cried a lot and everyone hated him.
Speaker 0: Maybe he might have been horrible.
Speaker 0: We don't know.
Speaker 1: a lot of babies are horrible and there's nobody who's all good not even like Gandhi.
Speaker 1: Well, especially not Gandhi, but you know Steve Jobs.
Speaker 1: It was even Steve Jobs If he would have not had fake medicine.
Speaker 0: Thing is Apple will probably be fine probably in fact.
Speaker 0: if anything I have a feeling that the culture he instilled will live on.
Speaker 0: but The company might open up a little bit.
Speaker 1: I hope it opens up.
Speaker 1: the only major change I've seen so far since and it happened before he died But after he left the company was they started doing a charity thing to where like Apple employees can have their paychecks.
Speaker 1: go to charity.
Speaker 1: You know Porsche whatever.
Speaker 0: every big company does that Apple didn't do it.
Speaker 0: That that's kind of sad Steve Jobs was it?
Speaker 1: people are you know, people don't know cuz.
Speaker 1: you know Bill Gates and Warren Buffett are very open with the charity like give all the fucking money away bitches.
Speaker 1: Steve Jobs was either of like the Jewish mentality where you give but you don't tell anyone that you gave cuz.
Speaker 1: that would be.
Speaker 1: You know cuz.
Speaker 1: it's like.
Speaker 1: it's not charity.
Speaker 1: if you're letting everyone know cuz then you're like I'm so charitable and great.
Speaker 1: look at my Scott.
Speaker 0: if good is done for a bad reason good is still done.
Speaker 1: Yes, of course, but I'm just saying is it you know?
Speaker 1: Is it it's?
Speaker 1: if your motives are not pure if you're gloating about the goodness that you do.
Speaker 0: I'd argue that no one's motives are pure because dopamine of course not.
Speaker 1: but the point is is that there are these people aren't sure if either he did he was very giving but kept it anonymous or Was he just really not fucking giving?
Speaker 0: well There is no problem with having the company that does this sort of thing.
Speaker 0: People feel pressured to donate some amount of their paycheck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well the company matches though.
Speaker 1: So why you know, you could just have it donate to something That's gonna go to you.
Speaker 1: For example a good strategy a CLU.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, but I mean give to a charity that is a scholarship that might be won by one of your kids.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I'll give to.
Speaker 0: yeah the human fund human fund Best fund All right.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So the Steve Jobs, we just said it because I guess obligatory Nothing, I'm going to say now will not have already met.
Speaker 1: the whole internet already said whatever.
Speaker 1: Okay, so Google It was recently they were.
Speaker 1: there was some rumblings that they were come up with a new language not go which they already came out With but another one stop called dart And now they actually came out with it.
Speaker 1: You can go to dart Lang org to read about it.
Speaker 1: Basically, they're trying to replace JavaScript which is.
Speaker 1: But of course they you know, they can get it put into Chrome which is rapidly gaining share which is helpful.
Speaker 1: but how are you gonna get anyone to write their website in Dart unless Safari and Firefox and IE all support it and that's gonna take at least you know I use.
Speaker 1: probably if they're gonna add it aren't gonna add it into like I 11 or 12 right and Firefox probably won't add it.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like so.
Speaker 1: good luck with that, but it can compile down to JavaScript sort of like coffee script.
Speaker 1: So who knows?
Speaker 1: But it's actually.
Speaker 1: it's a pretty interesting language.
Speaker 1: Like it sort of looks like Java, but it can be strictly typed or not typed.
Speaker 1: It's sort of.
Speaker 1: it's sort of weird But I don't actually know much about it as long as it's better than JavaScript.
Speaker 1: I'll be happy.
Speaker 1: right now It's just sort of in development But it's object oriented as opposed to the functional JavaScript which is good for a lot of people who mostly understand object-oriented programming.
Speaker 1: it's got a little bit that jQuery ness where you use, you know, the CSS selectors to grab objects from the from the DOM and It's got interfaces.
Speaker 1: So just like in Java where you implement interfaces.
Speaker 1: That's how this works.
Speaker 1: You just implement interfaces all over the fuck.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So We'll see how this goes.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna try it out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm interested but actually I write very little code.
Speaker 1: these just cuz I hate JavaScript.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and who doesn't?
Speaker 0: People who only know JavaScript, but they probably hate it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you probably you know, you should.
Speaker 0: So very briefly Amazon there's this whole problem with sales tax and every state has its own rules.
Speaker 0: It's really hard to follow all of them and whether or not you have to pay sales tax and the fact that all of you Out there probably owe and do not pay fully your use taxes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like in New York if I buy a car like when I moved to New York from Michigan.
Speaker 0: I had a car I had to prove to New York State that I paid sales tax on it And then I had to pay a use tax because I bought it out of state and brought it into New York.
Speaker 0: but all that aside Tennessee is working with Amazon and There's an idea coming out of this that I think is really interesting that I think won't happen Even though I think it really needs to happen.
Speaker 0: I don't think we state should have any right to tax internet sales And I think there should be a separate federal internet sales tax.
Speaker 1: Well, of course, I mean this is something I haven't understood for the longest time.
Speaker 1: is you know states trying to regulate the internet in Any way whatsoever.
Speaker 0: It's got because states regulate commerce internally.
Speaker 0: So if I for me, for example, I have to form it in a state and it's true that states laws So what they say is you form this company in New York.
Speaker 0: You got to follow all New York's rules, which includes collecting sales tax for New York, right?
Speaker 1: But the point is is that you know, the company is a New York company.
Speaker 1: I am physically in New York, but the business we are conducting is on the internet.
Speaker 0: There is a. well now you could argue Where's the server?
Speaker 1: It does so fine.
Speaker 1: is the server in the same fucking state?
Speaker 0: It's in New York.
Speaker 1: Is there any traffic routed to any other state whatsoever or any other country as any part of that transaction?
Speaker 0: Scott if I buy?
Speaker 0: Something in New York drive out of New York turn around drive back in.
Speaker 0: that does not change the status.
Speaker 1: It should.
Speaker 1: why?
Speaker 1: because the internet is not.
Speaker 1: it is like big.
Speaker 1: the internet is bigger than the United States.
Speaker 1: It should actually count as like international commerce, even if I buy something from Amazon and they're a US company and I'm in the US regardless, I There's this whole deal Amazon's making with Tennessee, but it's not that interesting.
Speaker 0: But I really honestly think that no state should be allowed to collect any sales tax on any online transaction.
Speaker 0: We should have a federal tax and at best all the taxes that go to the Fed for that You know 5% 6% whatever should be allocated back to the states based on I don't know The Fed could just calculate it based on whatever state gave the most in gets the most out or something.
Speaker 1: So I mean think about this.
Speaker 1: right even though there are radio towers within states Right that might be broadcasting from a state to the same state.
Speaker 1: the FCC regulates that shit because the airwaves is federal territory.
Speaker 1: So are the phone lines.
Speaker 1: so should be the internet.
Speaker 0: well most of the laws from what I can gather I'm not a lawyer related to sales tax on the internet are the laws that were used to regulate mail-order catalogs and Catalog.
Speaker 1: that is pretty similar.
Speaker 0: It is actually but The scale of commerce is on such a difference, but the thing is even mail-order catalogs, right?
Speaker 1: You're using the mail, which is a federal thing.
Speaker 1: Therefore my.
Speaker 1: even I'm sort of doing interstate commerce because my mail is entering the post office, which is federal territory.
Speaker 1: So the mail goes into federal territory, which is not a state in itself, but is no state.
Speaker 1: So it goes to no state and then comes back to same state that it left from but it still left the state and came Back in.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure that doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: I know obviously it doesn't matter But you know what?
Speaker 1: I would change that if I could.
Speaker 0: I'm just you know, as much as I would love You know my smarter state that I live in now to be able to do its own thing.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of sick of states all having their own slightly crooked rules about pointless crap.
Speaker 1: Well, this is the only reason Amazon is complaining.
Speaker 1: is they don't actually care about collecting the tag?
Speaker 1: No They just care about it so ridiculously complicated for them to actually get all the tax rules right in their system that they would have to have like an army of people and Lawyers constantly updating all these incredibly tiny rules and when you click check out this Ridiculous database would look at would probably be slow as molasses when you click check out to look up and calculate The exact right sales tax that you have to pay right.
Speaker 1: so they're not over or under charging anyone that you know.
Speaker 1: And they got to go by your address and where you are and it would.
Speaker 1: it wouldn't be exact 100% precise because they don't even the data for that right?
Speaker 1: It's like you put in your address, so they try to find you on the map But if the map slightly off you might be in a different tax zone.
Speaker 0: now You can argue.
Speaker 0: you can argue Scott that Amazon is big enough.
Speaker 0: They should have to you know.
Speaker 0: Come to possible.
Speaker 0: no, it's not impossible.
Speaker 0: It's really expensive companies.
Speaker 1: it's impossible.
Speaker 0: there are databases for stuff like this kind of like what we're gonna talk about a little bit and People can deal with this on a large scale.
Speaker 0: It just cost money.
Speaker 0: You could say it's a cost of doing business.
Speaker 0: Just like how if I have a brick factory I have to pay the cost of diff.
Speaker 0: You know following all the environmental regulation is you can get it really.
Speaker 1: you can get it very close to right.
Speaker 1: It's impossible to get it 100% right especially on those things like five-day tax holiday in.
Speaker 0: But Scott that is a Problem of the fact that our legal system and particularly our tax laws are just 100 200 300 year old cluster Fox.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but all that aside you could argue that Amazon should have to bear that cost of operating That cost for Amazon would not be that bad.
Speaker 0: the cost for like Joey Jojo selling his Etsy stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah Impossible.
Speaker 0: yeah it would.
Speaker 0: regulations like that because they're so Byzantine destroy small businesses.
Speaker 1: But even if they could do it, right, where would you even get the data if some databases, right?
Speaker 1: But eat let's say some.
Speaker 1: tiny County has a three-day tax holiday basis.
Speaker 1: Even so you're telling me that tiny County with ten farmers in it is gonna update that Database for those ten days.
Speaker 1: They have a tax holiday.
Speaker 0: Most of the civilize states do as far as I can tell even for the even A lot of this information, but they're all very expensive.
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: So this is a pretty great video.
Speaker 0: Scott showed it to me.
Speaker 0: it's a couple minutes long like four or five and It's a scientist pointing out that Dopamine levels go up to reward you when you do stuff, but okay that they go up more in Anticipation of Getting rewarded for doing stuff than they do the door.
Speaker 1: actually getting reward It doesn't mean actually comes out before you get the reward while you're while you're anticipating the reward.
Speaker 0: So it's I push the button I get a reward.
Speaker 0: I push the button.
Speaker 0: I get a little bit of dopamine I get a reward I push the button I get a little more dopamine I get the reward and then it gets the point to where I get.
Speaker 1: like the reward is from Anticipating the reward you get the dopamine is squirted into your brain before you push the button Pretty much not after you push the button and then you definitely don't get anything when you get the reward.
Speaker 1: right as I can and on top of that right is Let's say there's a button that you push and only half the time you push the button the reward comes out.
Speaker 1: You're not guaranteed to get the reward.
Speaker 0: So what do you think is gonna happen?
Speaker 0: Are we gonna have more or less dopamine?
Speaker 1: you get a zillion times more dopamine like double and you still get it before you push The button but you get more when there's only a chance of the reward happening.
Speaker 1: So it's like scratch-off.
Speaker 1: lottery tickets give you way more than say lottery tickets are guaranteed to win or candy bars Which you're guaranteed to eat.
Speaker 1: So I'm just gonna make a farm ville which is you know, or half the time you click and nothing.
Speaker 1: yeah a game Just like that.
Speaker 1: only sometimes Your farm doesn't get better.
Speaker 1: You have to come back every hour You can click again and sometimes when you click your farm gets better and sometimes when you click the front doesn't get better.
Speaker 1: It just you know, it won't be a farm.
Speaker 0: It'll be something else, you know Could be like that the money tree.
Speaker 1: you remember that tree that I clicked on that tree so many times in high school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I went in high school.
Speaker 1: I went during the school day.
Speaker 0: I wasn't wasting my time at home, but I went and clicked around for a while and I was like, wait a minute There's no money in here.
Speaker 0: No, stop doing it.
Speaker 0: What I did have?
Speaker 0: I did have a computer 486 that ran this bar on the bottom that showed ads and paid you like a penny an hour And I had a thing that moved the mouse back and forth.
Speaker 0: I never got paid though.
Speaker 1: So Okay This isn't the greatest but the internet hasn't been that great lately.
Speaker 1: In fact your thing of the day I gave to you.
Speaker 1: so I took this one for myself because you didn't want it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my policy is only things of the day that I can show to someone on an HT PC.
Speaker 1: I can show this to someone on HT PC.
Speaker 1: It's a YouTube video called pac-man the musical.
Speaker 1: It's just a cute little claymation pac-man with a little song and that's it.
Speaker 0: It's okay.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cute.
Speaker 1: It's okay It's not the greatest but you know internet slow lately.
Speaker 0: that was the best thing you've seen in the last 24 hours.
Speaker 1: My theory is that all the internet the best people who make the best internet stuff are all occupying Wall Street All the crazy people.
Speaker 0: So very briefly in the meta moment the book club book was the ear of the eye of the arm by Nancy farmer.
Speaker 1: Did we put that up yet?
Speaker 0: Not yet, but it's done.
Speaker 0: the episode will go up whenever I put it up.
Speaker 0: and the next book club book the current book club book is You forgot didn't you know?
Speaker 0: it's your book.
Speaker 0: you get to say it.
Speaker 1: What is it then?
Speaker 0: a little prince?
Speaker 0: and and What's the other book?
Speaker 0: that you're like you the white guy?
Speaker 1: so I was right.
Speaker 1: you forgot it.
Speaker 0: I forgot the name of the book.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's called the wind sand and stars.
Speaker 1: By on top.
Speaker 1: they saw as you pretty and I'm waiting for a French person to tell me I'm saying his name.
Speaker 0: We will be at the New York comic-con but not doing panels just hanging out.
Speaker 0: If you want to see what panels we would have done come to some other anime con like anime Boston.
Speaker 0: Mag fest is shaping up.
Speaker 0: We're part of the mag 9 though I think there's more than 9 people now gaming intellectuals and burning apocalypse con 11 11 11.
Speaker 1: Yeah a month from now We will be there.
Speaker 0: All right doing stuff.
Speaker 1: Yep,
Speaker 0: so there are a surprising number of databases or just large collections of factual information that are very very important to the way computers technology the world work and Yet not only do like non-technologists not care about it But most technologists don't care about it or even think about it or know it's a problem.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz these are things, you know It's sort of like I was reading today about the problem of the the shrinking kilogram, right?
Speaker 1: I would like it's losing.
Speaker 1: it lost like a fraction of weight and how they're trying desperately to get rid of the kilogram and Instead base it on something else and like.
Speaker 1: well kind of like how we made a second be defined by you know Like one guy instead of trying to define a kilogram based on the weight of What's it called like the case something mass of right captain massive?
Speaker 1: What's it called the something K?
Speaker 1: But anyway instead of you basing it on that particular object that's stored in a vault in Paris, right?
Speaker 0: Which I point out we can't actually be basing it on that.
Speaker 0: if we recognize that it is fact it has in fact change.
Speaker 1: actually, no we are because there is a Go.
Speaker 1: read about that how it works But they have these other ones next to it and all this stuff.
Speaker 1: but One guy is trying to base it on Avogadro's number.
Speaker 1: He's paid that.
Speaker 1: basically what they're trying to do.
Speaker 1: Do you remember Avogadro's number?
Speaker 0: nine point?
Speaker 1: Oh two times ten to the twenty six close enough, right?
Speaker 1: What they're trying?
Speaker 1: but they need it to be a cert.
Speaker 1: They need to basically calculate Avogadro's number to more decimal places than it currently is.
Speaker 1: They need eight decimal places of a hundred percent certainty basically to get it to be.
Speaker 1: have it be good enough?
Speaker 0: six point.
Speaker 1: So what they're trying to do is they're trying to fashion a sphere of silicon, right?
Speaker 1: That's that's exactly that.
Speaker 1: they know exactly how many atoms are in there and then base it on that Because then they'll know aha the mass of nine point oh two times, you know this many, right?
Speaker 0: Six point oh two to another guy's ten to the twenty-third, right?
Speaker 0: Keep saying nine.
Speaker 1: I don't know why I say that it is six point.
Speaker 1: Oh two days.
Speaker 1: Oh, I had the six and whatever.
Speaker 1: There's another guy who's training.
Speaker 0: wait wait wait you had the six and what?
Speaker 1: Well, I had the six in the wrong place.
Speaker 1: Okay, I had a nine that came out of nowhere because you said I had the six.
Speaker 0: and well never mind I'm like, what do you mean?
Speaker 0: you had the six?
Speaker 0: Where'd it go?
Speaker 1: Well, I said nine point oh two times ten to the twenty six Even though my brain was thinking maybe it's third.
Speaker 1: Well, then I was like, no, it's six point oh two times ended, right?
Speaker 1: I had this.
Speaker 1: I put the six where the three should be.
Speaker 0: Because my brain, you know, if you go back in time rim in Like chemistry class when I was at the community college in high school is looking at rim today being what the fuck is wrong with You.
Speaker 1: come on, dude right, so one other guy is trying to do it where he's?
Speaker 1: he basically put a kilogram mass on a giant scale in his hat in a building and he's gonna pull down the other end of the scale Right with an electromagnet and then he's gonna figure out exactly.
Speaker 1: So precisely how many you know volts or watts or whatever of electricity you have to put into that electromagnet To get the thing to be perfectly balanced and then he can be like aha.
Speaker 1: So a kilogram is the mass that you can pull with exactly this many volts of electricity to met, right?
Speaker 1: So those two guys are trying to figure out, you know a better way of measuring the kilogram.
Speaker 0: But anyway now that one's not so relevant to computer technology Is that information right?
Speaker 1: that fundamental base of How much is a kilogram right underlies all this science?
Speaker 1: But if you're like a biologist, you know kilograms are important to biologists.
Speaker 1: But they're not thinking about the weights and measures all the time In fact, they're probably not thinking about it even on an annual basis unless an article about it shows up, right?
Speaker 1: They're just.
Speaker 1: they got the scales in their lab and the scales, you know, they calibrate them and it's a kilogram.
Speaker 1: good You know, they're not basing their scales on the real kilogram, right?
Speaker 1: But somewhere along the line deep down the person who made the scale and the person they have a thing that they use to calibrate and that thing was based On something which is eventually was based on the real deal and in the world of computers.
Speaker 1: There are a whole bunch of servers out there that are way down at the bottom Just like the real kilogram is way down at the bottom and all of the other computers are based on that sort of like the root 13 DNS servers, you know, you're hardly ever talking to them.
Speaker 1: your computer basically never talks to those servers.
Speaker 0: Well window old Windows computers constantly talk to them, right?
Speaker 1: It's extremely rare.
Speaker 1: It is possible You know, it happens once in a while, but it's extremely rare that your computer ever contacts those computers.
Speaker 0: Let's zoom back a little bit because you know, you all know how DNS works on some level But you probably don't actually know how like bind works or the difference between a recursive query and all the different ways DNS functions.
Speaker 0: And the you know, the the pointer records the in at an ARPA and all that stuff, but think about it on a high level.
Speaker 0: Alright, you want to look something up you say?
Speaker 0: Oh, well, I go to the comm server.
Speaker 0: How do I know where comm is?
Speaker 0: How do I know what server manages calm?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm?
Speaker 0: How do I know what server manages net?
Speaker 1: because there's a text file on your computer that says what yep.
Speaker 0: So where's that text file come from?
Speaker 1: Someone wrote it.
Speaker 0: Yep, and by hand yeah, and when you in like when you bootstrap a Linux computer from default and you like like from scratch and you set up like Their base based stuff in your system What are the things you do?
Speaker 0: is you get your like seed file for your DNS and it uses that.
Speaker 0: well.
Speaker 1: If you install bind it comes with the text file.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that seed file comes from somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yes, so the guy it's in the bind source code repository.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah but yet so Basically, there's these bunch of servers providing all kinds of services way down at the bottom of all technology.
Speaker 1: Right that you hardly ever talked to or notice but there's often drama around them.
Speaker 0: Yep, great There was a point where I think two or three of the root DNS servers got hacked and went down and they were some of them Were in weird countries Where shit can happen?
Speaker 0: There's only 13 of them.
Speaker 0: There can't be more.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Also, what you'll often have is the typical cloud situation, right?
Speaker 1: It's like the cloud is great because if something's in the cloud, it's on the internet You can access it from anywhere but also is a single point of failure.
Speaker 1: So it's like they'll be the server that provides some service that everyone needs and then it goes down.
Speaker 0: It went down or never mind.
Speaker 0: look at the fact that you know people think oh the Internet's just a big web.
Speaker 0: It's actually not that web like at all.
Speaker 1: And I mean it could be more web-like.
Speaker 1: It you know architecturally could and should be.
Speaker 1: it is not you know, the technological stopping us from doing it.
Speaker 1: It's mostly stuff that is you know, I guess Organizational that is stopping us from doing it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there are you know, you think you have an ISP but there's ISPs for ISPs and there is drama the likes of which You will never fathom between those ISPs.
Speaker 0: Oh god on a regular basis Sometimes you try to go to like part of the like a websites down.
Speaker 0: You're like, oh the internet like.
Speaker 0: there's some problem That is sometimes been caused by pissing matches between two chunks of the internet who say we're not gonna route to you anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, think about it.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: So you get let's say you live somewhere and there's like four ISPs, right?
Speaker 1: Well, you know, there might be only one undersea cable between country A and country B. So no matter who your ISP is if the person who runs the servers on the ends of the international underwater cable as a pissing match.
Speaker 1: Suddenly the whole internet in that country looks like it's down and you're.
Speaker 1: they look like your country is down.
Speaker 1: So you'll try to go to www.co that other country and nothing will come up to any of the sites.
Speaker 1: You're like what's going on here and they'll sit.
Speaker 1: think the same thing about you.
Speaker 1: But really it's just a pissing match between two dicks.
Speaker 0: So this has happened yet again.
Speaker 0: There's a new story that has come to light something very.
Speaker 1: that's why we thought of doing this episode.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I know who the smart techies are the ones who are on not I don't want our level But the ones who think about stuff the way we do because all of them emailed me and said oh my god rim this will piss you off and I'm like one step ahead of you.
Speaker 0: home song.
Speaker 1: Well, I was the one I said it to you first.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm I actually know I invest in it is the Administrator in my office sent it to me long before you did.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I had not read slash shot yet that day, huh?
Speaker 1: So you want to talk about it?
Speaker 0: All right, let's talk about it.
Speaker 0: So time zones right.
Speaker 0: time zones just work and computers I mean, I make a Linux computer and it just has this list of time zones like New York USA.
Speaker 1: yeah, you look at your cell phone and it if you travel somewhere when you get off the plane the time zone just magically Changes.
Speaker 1: it knows where it is.
Speaker 1: It knows the difference between wherever you are and whatever time.
Speaker 1: it is UTC and it changes the.
Speaker 0: oh Okay, just in my Windows computer if I want to pick UTC I have to choose between Monrovia Rick I'm not gonna say that word Dublin Edinburgh Lisbon London CUT or Casablanca or GMT Or GMT even listed.
Speaker 1: no just UTC, oh really you can't pick Greenwich, okay, whatever it doesn't say Greenwich.
Speaker 1: Yeah, GMT and UTC are not a hundred percent exactly the same thing, but they're the same time.
Speaker 0: Oh, I can bet Caracas or Santiago
Speaker 1: effectively
Speaker 0: anyway, and not just that like you might think All right, maybe I could do it manually like all right I put in minus five because that's you know I'm there except
Speaker 1: if you pick minus five when the time changes because of daylight savings you gotta switch it to minus four.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and what are you gonna switch it back to minus five?
Speaker 0: And what if you're in Indiana?
Speaker 0: What if you go to Indiana?
Speaker 1: and it's not just a matter of you know, what date?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like, you know people are used to just waking up at like 8 a.m.
Speaker 1: And changing their time back.
Speaker 1: You know, it doesn't matter if you do it right away.
Speaker 1: and for displaying dates to human beings It doesn't matter right away.
Speaker 1: But for computers computer needs to have the time change at the exact Millisecond that the time changes.
Speaker 1: if the daylight savings time changes at midnight on October something I don't even know what date is supposed to be They need to happen that second the clock has to go blip and go back an hour immediately.
Speaker 0: now this information.
Speaker 0: I mean who has this information?
Speaker 0: It's Countries can kind of do what they want.
Speaker 0: So in the US it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: We don't change around our time zones very often and in most of you need to know what day the daylight savings time flips.
Speaker 0: Yeah, every year change forever.
Speaker 0: until recently We were stupid and move suffer.
Speaker 1: But also there's some funky ass states that are like split in the middle and there's some other states that like do different things And it's weird.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I think I just want to say in terms of time zones You know talking about time zones specifically sort of off-topic But the point is I think what we should all do is the entire world should just use 24-hour UTC clocks.
Speaker 1: there should be no time zones and wherever you live you just get used to it.
Speaker 1: if you're waking up at 13 and going to bed at 24 and meanwhile on another time zone people get up at 7 and go to bed it some you Then just get used to whatever your number happens to be where you live and that should be it.
Speaker 0: I'm entirely ambivalent because while I see the merits of your proposal I also see the useful normalization of being able to say 7 p.m.
Speaker 0: And that means Evening to everyone in their context.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but how useful it would to be to be like we're going to have this.
Speaker 1: You know, we're going to record this podcast at 13 and just everyone knows 13.
Speaker 0: I definitely see the use in it.
Speaker 0: For example, anytime someone said, you know, some of our listeners live on that other coast I don't know why but they occasionally will say hey, we're gonna play a game of counter-strike at four o'clock PST.
Speaker 0: And my answer is to ignore all things that are at any time other than Eastern, right?
Speaker 1: It would be so much easier if we just said hey We're gonna do it at 14 and everyone just did and no one even had to think about time zones ever.
Speaker 0: No, well think about the weird problems you can have like say alright, my computer just jumps forward and falls back.
Speaker 0: What if I'm writing log files?
Speaker 0: All right jumping forwards fine.
Speaker 0: I jump forward.
Speaker 0: There's just an hour gap in my logs once a year Falling back.
Speaker 0: something happened at you know 1 45 a.m Something happened at 1 45 a.m Which one is which?
Speaker 1: Yeah, did this actually happen at the same time as another thing or an hour later?
Speaker 0: So what do you?
Speaker 1: of course the log file usually writes in order?
Speaker 1: So what you're gonna see is you're gonna see 11 59 then 11.
Speaker 0: But what if it's a log file?
Speaker 0: that's machine read that's based on timestamps.
Speaker 1: This is why you always have your log files writing in UTC.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but even that.
Speaker 0: so what if for example, you know, we don't want to talk about the tech stuff Let's talk about the real story about the for the story.
Speaker 0: So, uh This database, you know, you have to maintain this.
Speaker 1: What's what is it?
Speaker 1: I'll send something.
Speaker 0: I forget I got something vague.
Speaker 0: I barely knew about it.
Speaker 0: to be honest This shows that even we don't pay attention that much until there's a problem.
Speaker 1: But it is.
Speaker 1: it's the all since easy database so countries can change their stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean what if some countries like oh I'm changing X someone's got to collect all that information and put it somewhere and You can't trust private companies to just do that because they'll probably try to charge money for the database.
Speaker 0: Try to license it out.
Speaker 0: some sort of bullshit shenanigans On the web and the mailing list.
Speaker 0: for this whole thing.
Speaker 0: a post was made four days eight hours and 23 minutes ago.
Speaker 0: Quote a civil suit was filed on September 30th in federal court in Boston.
Speaker 0: I'm the defendant.
Speaker 0: the case involves the timezone database.
Speaker 0: the FTP server at LC dot NCI dot nih dot gov Has been shut down.
Speaker 0: the mailing list will be shut down after this message.
Speaker 0: electronic mail can be sent to me at Arthur David Olson at gmail.com.
Speaker 0: I like how this super GNU Linux sounding guy uses Gmail.
Speaker 0: that says a lot actually.
Speaker 0: I hope there will be better news shortly Otto.
Speaker 0: and That innocuous letter made thousands of nerds around the world start screaming fuck Yeah, I mean I was just actually today.
Speaker 1: I had to write a program that used the timezone data And I used the Python TZ data module and it worked even though this database is down.
Speaker 0: But if some change happens you won't be up to date.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: I'll be fucked Yeah, which actually is fine for most of the industrialized world in the short term very short term.
Speaker 0: now The story as far as I can tell is that this private company is suing them, right?
Speaker 1: So here's the story as it is on Wikipedia, which is as trustworthy as Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: is you tell it the Wikipedia way?
Speaker 0: And I have this other article.
Speaker 0: Okay, we'll see if there's any.
Speaker 1: there's a lost route a lawsuit between astrolabe Incorporated verse Olson et al.
Speaker 1: it was filed concerning copyright of the database, right?
Speaker 1: So the database is maintenance and dissemination operations are shut down The you.
Speaker 1: the case revolves around the use by the database maintainers of the atlases the American Atlas by Thomas G Shanks and the International Atlas by Thomas G. Shanks and Rick Pottinger.
Speaker 1: It's specifically complaints of unauthorized Reproduction of the atlases data in the timezone mailing list archive and some auxiliary link collections maintained with it with the database But doesn't actually point at the database itself.
Speaker 1: The complaint relates only to the compilation of historical timezone data and does not cover timezone data world timezone tables.
Speaker 1: The Atlas is one of the favored sources for the database And so the database includes much factual data that has been copied from it.
Speaker 0: now There are many ways to look at this.
Speaker 0: on one hand.
Speaker 0: It takes effort to gather facts.
Speaker 0: It's so.
Speaker 0: maybe we have a vested interest in protecting the intellectual property rights of people who gather facts So that they will continue to gather facts.
Speaker 1: the fact fact gathering is incredibly useful Even though say an almanac would only collect, you know publicly available information and publish it in a compact format.
Speaker 1: It takes work to produce that.
Speaker 0: so that work you want your reward and it is a useful service.
Speaker 1: So we want people.
Speaker 1: you know, I don't necessarily needs to be intellectual property But there needs to be.
Speaker 0: it is intellectual property just doesn't necessarily need to be the current copyright regimen We have.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying there needs to be some way to you know.
Speaker 1: We want to encourage and come and perhaps compensate those people by a means.
Speaker 1: It may not be an intellectual property means but some means probably a good idea, but simultaneously We want people to collect facts in useful ways.
Speaker 0: We have a vested interest as a society to make factual information readily available with zero Licensing concerns of any kind, right?
Speaker 1: I should not have to pay anyone any amount of money to know what the time zone is Anywhere ever in the history of the world or the future let alone that needs to be publicly available and free information for all people
Speaker 0: Now let alone what the time zone was Twenty-four point six seven years ago,
Speaker 1: which also needs to be publicly available and for free for everyone forever.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of thing that should be in a history book.
Speaker 0: Exactly now that the new Law gets down to the weird stuff of like.
Speaker 0: say, you know If I read if I have a history book that talks about Peter the Great doing something and I copy that text verbatim Committing copyright violations.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But if I just take the facts from that book and republish them on my own I'm not actually sure what the specific line is where someone can go after.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as long as you got a bibliography going on Right.
Speaker 1: I mean you that's all you did in school, right?
Speaker 1: Is that you would?
Speaker 1: they would say read books and don't plagiarize but you still have to get the facts from the books and you?
Speaker 1: Would cite them and then that was considered.
Speaker 1: Okay, I think there was.
Speaker 0: I turned in the same essay to five different professors at RIT And in my bibliography I cited myself Giving it for another class, but I obfuscated it and no one noticed.
Speaker 0: but had they called me on it I did not actually violate any of the policies of the school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, but that is they really was kind of a great essay, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I don't even remember.
Speaker 1: I was saying cuz you're funny story.
Speaker 0: In fact one class I didn't do the real essay and I was gonna get like a C. so I was like look can I write a paper just for you on some other topic like say This thing I already wrote an essay on that.
Speaker 0: I've turned into four other professors.
Speaker 1: That's good stuff.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So anyway, so Basically at what point do we?
Speaker 0: eminent domain?
Speaker 0: Factual information that has been collected even if someone put effort into collecting it but more importantly This company that's suing these people.
Speaker 0: I Can't really be on their side.
Speaker 0: No because who is going to buy this data?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's sort of like, you know, even you know, there's certain things I don't even think you know.
Speaker 1: Most people would say all the US government should eminent domain and or something like that.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: no the world should eminent domain it.
Speaker 1: this needs to be for everyone.
Speaker 1: It's not just one country Right.
Speaker 1: This data is important for the entire world.
Speaker 1: Nobody should be without this data They just have like some international law come down and be like BAM.
Speaker 0: There's no such thing as international law.
Speaker 0: It's only there if countries are willing to enforce it but there should be some.
Speaker 1: this is why we need some sort of Internet.
Speaker 1: should Be its own country, right?
Speaker 1: It's just like BAM.
Speaker 1: This data is now public for everyone.
Speaker 1: Here's some money guys who collected it.
Speaker 1: now it belongs to everybody the end and then you know The higher one guy to maintain it.
Speaker 0: The thing is effectively if the if that were to happen in the US that effectively means that that happened for the world But it'd be better if it was really for the world.
Speaker 0: Ah, but if it was truly international We're still in dodgy territory as to you know, international organizations still have to have people in places.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why we need to fix that flakiness.
Speaker 0: moon moon, maybe Antarctica space station Maybe we need a Washington DC equivalent of the internet.
Speaker 1: We need actually, you know satellite wouldn't be a bad idea.
Speaker 1: We could just take all the important data's and put them in a satellite.
Speaker 1: then, you know Like a homemade satellite that'll have great throughput and incredibly low latency, but it doesn't need to be hit that often.
Speaker 1: We just need to keep it somewhere.
Speaker 1: It's like great.
Speaker 1: You won your lawsuit against who you can't sue face.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you hit space lawsuit.
Speaker 1: No, you know what you win.
Speaker 0: I hereby award you 10 million space dollars.
Speaker 1: Congratulations.
Speaker 0: Here's a penny, but I need change.
Speaker 0: Now it is worth noting that Microsoft Windows and probably presumably at least many of the cell phone providers that they might be using their own files because Microsoft According to this guy.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at his website has their own time zone data files that they get from some other source.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I can't use those Microsoft ones and say my own personal app Can I?
Speaker 1: I don't know I could probably if I'm writing a Windows app There's probably API calls to access that data But they probably you know I can't just take that out of Windows and start using it my Linux app or my iPhone app.
Speaker 1: I need something more general and free like the Python T Python TZ data module, which I use today.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah But anyway, it's not.
Speaker 1: you know, we this came up because of the timezone issue with this particular server going down But there's actually a whole bunch of things just like this that are Either more clear or less clear in terms of should the information be public and all that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: For example Maps right.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of companies that make maps and cartography is hard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we need to reward these people.
Speaker 1: but or at least, you know, there needs to be incentive for people to do cartography.
Speaker 1: but at the same time Knowing where shit is and knowing the shape of the earth and knowing, you know That should not be secrets that people should have to pay for.
Speaker 1: if you need to know where something is It doesn't matter where it.
Speaker 0: but I did see stories of people lobbying to shut down Google Maps in its early days on the grounds that having free maps that were that accessible.
Speaker 0: and I think the same thing happened with What was that side?
Speaker 1: I used to use before man quest map quest Yahoo Maps Microsoft also, I think no use.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think there's a Bing Maps also.
Speaker 0: until recently actually kind of an aside Map quest used to have better driving directions, but now Google caught up.
Speaker 1: So well because Google does everything based on data So it just took long enough for their computers to learn whereas map quest was you know better to start out with because they hired People to drive around that too, but they also didn't.
Speaker 1: it didn't learn at the same rate as Google Maps.
Speaker 1: So Google Maps started out crappier but caught up.
Speaker 0: The only time Google Maps kind of fails is when you're trying to drive through Manhattan anywhere around Manhattan.
Speaker 0: It like pulls you into Manhattan.
Speaker 0: It's like don't go over the RFK go through a tunnel and drive through Manhattan.
Speaker 1: It'll be fine.
Speaker 0: But so what do we do there?
Speaker 0: I mean Should we just eminent domain all the maps people made?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean there we have government workers making maps.
Speaker 1: There is actually an open map site.
Speaker 1: I forget what it's called.
Speaker 1: I think it's open street map and they get a bunch of maps from this.
Speaker 1: I think it's like a tiger database, which is a database of open maps, but it's not a hundred percent, right?
Speaker 1: But it's a lot of maps, but it's not all the math.
Speaker 0: So what about that?
Speaker 1: would be like if there was a free government dish timezone database that only had most of the time zones in It but not all of them.
Speaker 0: What about Google Maps where it's freezing beer?
Speaker 1: pretty much, but it's not freezing speech.
Speaker 0: I mean People embed Google Maps all the time.
Speaker 0: You can make your own maps and directions and everything.
Speaker 0: It's effectively free.
Speaker 0: Sorry, those all intents and purposes not all the intent.
Speaker 1: There are certain, you know, if you want obviously for most things normal people are gonna do.
Speaker 1: it covers it.
Speaker 1: But there is some weird things that you a map person might want to do that.
Speaker 1: You just can't do on Google Man.
Speaker 0: Can you name one?
Speaker 1: I'm not a map expert, but I'm sure you know, there's something that someone might want to do.
Speaker 1: It doesn't do.
Speaker 0: I was trying to find the terms of service and I actually couldn't find them quickly.
Speaker 0: So I'm just gonna yeah regardless.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't have a good answer.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the best way to handle this is.
Speaker 1: How about even something like phone books?
Speaker 0: or Well phone books just need to disappear.
Speaker 1: Well that too, but I mean still a directory of phone numbers and names, right?
Speaker 0: I think about it.
Speaker 0: Most people don't want there to be a directory of their phone number and name.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter It's.
Speaker 1: it's actually had this idea this morning, right?
Speaker 0: What if the majority of people who know me couldn't look me up in the phone book because the name that would show up would Not match any name they know I was thinking.
Speaker 1: what if we made a crowdsource database?
Speaker 1: and the way the crowdsource database works is you type in Information about other people that you know, for example, you look across the street out your window at your neighbor's house.
Speaker 0: You know the address of your neighbors you go to that address and you're like one occupant blonde hair blue eyes Where's?
Speaker 1: maybe you wetters, maybe you even know their name, you know what cars they have you know a license plates that are on their cars and you just start typing this stuff in and just everyone starts doing it.
Speaker 1: and Eventually, we have a database of everything that no one opted into and there's nothing anyone could do about it.
Speaker 0: I had an idea.
Speaker 0: I wanted to do that just for the WTF moments.
Speaker 0: I wanted to make like what the fuck calm where you Post locations and timestamps for something happened and try to get other people to give you data about what was going on in that Area at that time right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's always like, you know, there's this A shitstorm because look at how many countries in the world and how many people are so mad that Google has the audacity To take free pictures of every street and put them online.
Speaker 0: So, what would they do?
Speaker 0: they gotta blur out the license plates - I don't think they should.
Speaker 1: I don't think they should either.
Speaker 0: I don't think they should have to any of them.
Speaker 0: and you yeah, whatever you want to make that website You want to add that to the shit-talk list.
Speaker 0: we get sued so fast.
Speaker 0: It's sued the fastest someone else make that website.
Speaker 0: I will put in so much data.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I might even invest in you, but I will not make it whatever.
Speaker 1: But yeah, all these these databases of important information.
Speaker 1: We got a we got to do something about this.
Speaker 0: I don't know what Government subsidy.
Speaker 1: I don't know it either but you know what, you know for something like time zones Like you can make a personal backup of that shit.
Speaker 1: but there are a lot bigger databases out there that you can't make a personal backup of and They could be problems if something happens to them.
Speaker 1: because like one country's a dick or something.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.