Speaker 0: Hey, it's Thursday, June 14th, 2012.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm sky and this is geek nights tonight hats Cuz.
Speaker 0: we couldn't think of anything better.
Speaker 1: That's every episode.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I got a funny story that I think relates to a funny story.
Speaker 0: you had my uh My GoPro fucking fell off my bike while I was riding.
Speaker 1: Yours is still in one piece.
Speaker 0: well because I caught it in my hand and then it fell.
Speaker 0: so I picked it up right away And it was fine.
Speaker 0: But the mount literally like I was riding and the mount just like Went whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa and before my brain could react the thing just fell like out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just cleaved in two.
Speaker 1: Yeah mine alright, so broke in the exact same way.
Speaker 1: Yeah around the same time yours broke, and I just I didn't even realize it was falling.
Speaker 1: It was just like click click clickety clickety, and I was like whoa and I picked it up.
Speaker 1: But then I got a new.
Speaker 1: I emailed them And I was like hey that shit broke and they sent me a free replacement.
Speaker 1: So I put the free replacement on.
Speaker 1: that shit broke and I didn't even realize it.
Speaker 1: I had to backtrack.
Speaker 1: luckily I found the GoPro lying in the middle of the road about five blocks back on my route Going against traffic you know to search for it.
Speaker 1: But the camera was completely destroyed like smash smash like Hulk.
Speaker 1: well like it was in the shield right the black Clip on top of the shield that keeps the shield sealed.
Speaker 0: We thought you knew what I was laughing at.
Speaker 1: yeah that black clip was just shattered in pieces that I picked up off the ground.
Speaker 1: Right yeah, the shield itself was mostly in one piece.
Speaker 1: Just has some you know scarring on the back of it the the you know these.
Speaker 1: You know the back part that you.
Speaker 0: but my camera gets smashed.
Speaker 1: the camera is in one piece.
Speaker 1: the LCD part is Smashed the but there's no LCD.
Speaker 1: Yeah on the front a little tiny one.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay that thing it smashed the buttons.
Speaker 1: You can't press them right And like it doesn't from far away It looks like it's in one piece, but you get close to it, and you realize it's like bork right and basically It's non-functional.
Speaker 0: So GoPro.
Speaker 0: I want to point out the same mount that you sell broke three times in New York like biking around town biking.
Speaker 0: this wasn't even a hardcore mount.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this was not jumping off a cliff skiing or skydiving Wasn't even like jumping over curbs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is regular old just biking around the city.
Speaker 1: this mount breaks.
Speaker 1: This is why I realized third-party companies are selling metal mounts Which I ordered.
Speaker 1: so I'm like.
Speaker 1: I email GoPro, and I'm like hey this time the mount broke again.
Speaker 1: Which is bullshit I?
Speaker 1: Want it, but my camera broke because your mount was faulty.
Speaker 1: and they're like well We'll give you half off a new camera, and I'm like you should take him to small claims court or something just for fun.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's like I can't because it's like the warranty.
Speaker 1: I'm like.
Speaker 1: I'm like I don't want to be that Indignant lady that I because I can't complain about the indignant lady and be the indignant lady true But at the same time there is a big difference in dignity.
Speaker 0: indignant ladies that particular brand of person Will annoy everybody else around them and be in their way.
Speaker 0: you can't get away from that lady.
Speaker 0: It's not indignant lady if you're doing it on your own quietly.
Speaker 1: I'm still bothering this customer service person.
Speaker 1: It's not their fault, right?
Speaker 1: They're not the person who made the shitty mount or decided the warranty policy.
Speaker 0: if GoPro We just had a little thing that said like warning don't actually use this on a bike.
Speaker 0: It'll break.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this bike mount that we have pictures of using on a bike.
Speaker 0: yes next to your purportedly indestructible camera Yeah, but anyway.
Speaker 1: So I guess I bought the surf edition for half off to replace the one I had because at least that way I'll get some new accessories.
Speaker 1: I didn't have before and they also offered me a free mounting accessory, so I guess I'm getting the wrist strap We could use that for that was the only Accessory that would be of any use that you didn't already own right, but here's what you got to do.
Speaker 1: if you have a GoPro You know they only really show examples of this in these surfing examples.
Speaker 1: But if you mount it to something and you're moving or at all you should also Tether it to that something with a rope.
Speaker 0: or I do that when I ski because the thing is biking all right.
Speaker 0: I can go back and get it though apparently in your case that didn't really work now, but If I'm skiing you're down a hill and it's now this camera is up the hill.
Speaker 0: it is Basically impossible to go back up the turn.
Speaker 1: this you have to turn 90 degrees sideways and go right left right like a ladder.
Speaker 0: I can do a sort of fishbone thing where you're walking forward.
Speaker 0: There's a couple of ways to do it But it's a pain in the ass sucks and it hurts.
Speaker 0: and if I go all the way down and ski back up like at A real mountain all right.
Speaker 0: It's been an hour.
Speaker 0: Let's see if it's still there And if I can even find it and you got to stop before you get to it If you stop below it that I would cry.
Speaker 0: I think I would just cry.
Speaker 0: she's a grown man.
Speaker 1: You could ask the ski patrol to help you get it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually luckily one thing you could do is if you ever drop anything skiing not that you'll ever go skiing.
Speaker 0: I get the impression Yeah, you can just basically if anyone's coming down the hill be like hey And they'll usually grab whatever you drop and give it to you.
Speaker 1: That's not bad.
Speaker 0: just the GoPro is kind of tiny.
Speaker 0: usually It's like a ski pole and it's gonna be buried in the snow yeah, or a ski or something that they're picking up for me.
Speaker 0: So yeah GoPro, I guess we could leverage our negative publicity machine Whatever that you know.
Speaker 1: and the thing is it became a little more frustrating because the way they worded their customer service email was pretty Much like hey order a new one then tell us the order number, then we'll take half off right, so I'm like okay I did that and then I. and then they're like yeah, there was a miscommunication.
Speaker 1: You actually have to sort of you know.
Speaker 1: Send us a picture you receive and then we'll take you send you a coupon code a picture of my receipt you mean the email I guess and I'm like what the fuck you told me to do this.
Speaker 1: And then they're like no and they sent.
Speaker 1: I sent them the quote from the email that they originally say to that.
Speaker 1: They sent the quote of the full email and actually the just the way their email was worded is.
Speaker 1: there was a sentence later in The email that was like about the coupon code.
Speaker 0: Oh, so you got owned there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the poorly written, but it was poorly written, but it's not your thing on the forum.
Speaker 0: read all the words.
Speaker 1: It was yeah, or you're a dumbass you I guarantee.
Speaker 1: if you would have gotten the same email You would have done the same stupid thing.
Speaker 0: you know we hadn't talked about this.
Speaker 0: You could have showed me the email and be like what do you do?
Speaker 0: and we could have seen.
Speaker 0: but now we can't.
Speaker 0: cuz now I know it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: It's still.
Speaker 1: the point is is that their mount broke.
Speaker 1: They should have replaced the camera, which is a lot of money.
Speaker 0: They shouldn't sell a mount that clearly doesn't is faulty and they know it's faulty.
Speaker 1: if you go to reviews everyone says yeah this mount breaks.
Speaker 0: I've done class action.
Speaker 1: the Amazon the Amazon reviews for the metal mounts from the third-party company are like man.
Speaker 1: this thing's overpriced But it works.
Speaker 1: I'll probably just get it because I want to start like 60 bucks for like a metal ring with a stick coming out of it.
Speaker 1: It's a bunch of bull.
Speaker 0: Well if that's bullshit make your own.
Speaker 1: I Don't know how to.
Speaker 0: So I don't really have news per se.
Speaker 0: it's Thursday.
Speaker 0: You know the lounge your mom But we did go see Prometheus, so I guess I want to geek bite it a little bit.
Speaker 0: all right You know what.
Speaker 0: it was a pretty good movie.
Speaker 1: Dude gets his guts ripped open his liver gets pecked and it they just keep this.
Speaker 0: this is a movie.
Speaker 0: This is the first time in my life There is an early scene with an automated surgery table and by God was that not Chekhov's surgery table.
Speaker 0: everyone knew that I saw the thing.
Speaker 0: I was like somebody's gonna have an alien Extracted from their abdomen with that thing within the bounds of this movie and sure enough Yeah, I don't even consider that a spoiler.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: There's an automated surgery.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much the best scene in the whole movie.
Speaker 1: That was the yeah the using of the checkup surgery.
Speaker 0: the second best scene not to spoil anything is when one person asks another person to question and then that person is like oh, and then he answers it.
Speaker 0: I Don't remember what seemed the whoa the question that we didn't understand And the way it was answered.
Speaker 0: yeah, that was it was a good scene But the movie was pretty good.
Speaker 0: the special effects were great.
Speaker 0: I like how they use 3d in this movie because I've seen most 3d movies that I have seen.
Speaker 0: Either have like the shit coming at you Or shrunk the audience or they're really just like it's shoehorned in and done poorly.
Speaker 0: But Prometheus was actually filmed with 3d cameras, and it showed like it was like night and day compared to other 3d movies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it was all right, but that's the thing.
Speaker 1: it's like they didn't have anything coming at you right and at the same time You know they.
Speaker 1: you know they didn't.
Speaker 1: you know really go whoa 3d whoa, so it's like a lot of times You just don't even notice.
Speaker 0: That's the best way to use 3d.
Speaker 1: Have the 3d why then?
Speaker 0: it's it's atmospheric like notice how now I could like focus on the foreground in the background And you got this really big sense of space.
Speaker 0: There's a contrast between the wide open areas on the planet and the confined areas inside the depth of the tunnels.
Speaker 0: But it really shown every time there was a user interface to a thing like that was breathtaking.
Speaker 1: I think what you really got to do to make 3d really have stuff come out at the screen?
Speaker 0: No Because that's what you seem to be going for.
Speaker 1: no see the problem with all 3d.
Speaker 1: whether you got IMAX 3d Omnimax any kind of 3d movie right that we have now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, is that even though there's some sort of depth perception you can tell that that's farther away That's sort of closer right.
Speaker 1: It's still a two-dimensional image.
Speaker 1: You can't like lean your head to the left and look behind a thing a little bit Right.
Speaker 1: if they could make it do that somehow don't ask me how I don't even know is possible.
Speaker 0: I don't really want that.
Speaker 1: but see that's what.
Speaker 1: but that's the thing.
Speaker 1: is it's like it's.
Speaker 1: you know It's not really 3d because it's still you're just.
Speaker 1: it's really just this square and some pieces a rectangle and some pieces of the rectangle Are closer, but there's nothing behind them.
Speaker 1: They're not round.
Speaker 1: There's nothing behind them.
Speaker 1: It's not really
Speaker 0: 3d, but at the same time you could argue that for most movies There's a camera angle and by giving people leeway to poke around in there Then now all those elements that previously in a screenplay don't have to be worried about have to be worried about Makes it harder for director to actually have like a unified vision.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean the thing is right is how much can you really move your head in a movie, right?
Speaker 1: It doesn't need to be.
Speaker 0: you know, you want You want the televisions from that fucked up show that I've talked about.
Speaker 0: I seem to the only person in the world who remembers this and watched it from my generation.
Speaker 0: but our wild palms The plot of wild palms of the hologram other than being about Scientology is that they make a device that replaces TV that sits in the living room and the action just takes place in 3d in Your living room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't need to be the hologram in the middle of the room.
Speaker 1: I just want it to be to really enhance that 3d effect is You know, there's like a ball on the screen if I lean my head a little bit to the left.
Speaker 1: It should be like, you know, like my angle should change.
Speaker 1: That can be done.
Speaker 0: it can't be done right now for multiple people at the same time I know without everyone having active glasses as opposed to passive.
Speaker 0: I know and by active I mean more active than anything.
Speaker 1: But anyway, but I'm saying that I'm saying that's what would really make.
Speaker 1: Like if 3d significantly, you know doing the subtle 3d The way it's done is probably the right way to use it without making your movie into an amusement park ride.
Speaker 1: But what I'm saying is it's not really that much.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like you can see it in 2d and be just fine because the 3d doesn't add that much.
Speaker 1: But if it added that that little I got is I then it would be a significant.
Speaker 0: I would disagree in that there are a few scenes in Prometheus that if they weren't in 3d would not have been nearly as breathtaking Especially when they turn on the HUD on the alien thing.
Speaker 0: Hey, and well you you you once argued that aesthetics are meaningless.
Speaker 0: So anyway But I like this.
Speaker 0: movies like this that use 3d in this way are the kinds of movies that'll make 3d actually be just a Technology that's used or not used properly as opposed to a gimmick?
Speaker 0: because for the last what 40 plus years It's been a gimmick every time 3d has been.
Speaker 1: it was a gimmick for so many years right because our 3d Technology was sort of crappy.
Speaker 1: right red and blue 3d doesn't really work that well.
Speaker 1: now the 3d actually kind of sort of works.
Speaker 1: ish.
Speaker 1: That's the reason you know, and you can do it with these cheap plastic glasses, you know It's.
Speaker 1: it's not that obtrusive like it used to be.
Speaker 0: but in terms of you know Prometheus pretty good movie.
Speaker 0: I liked it better than I liked Avengers, but not by that much, but and it raised good questions, but I There's a big discussion going on in our forums.
Speaker 0: I've seen a lot of similar discussions around the internet.
Speaker 0: I'm not arguing.
Speaker 0: It's the greatest movie in the world.
Speaker 0: It is by no means alien and aliens are both much better movie.
Speaker 0: But for me the is.
Speaker 0: there are things that you can legitimately complain about both from a semi-objective critical and from a taste like.
Speaker 0: I liked or didn't like this standpoint, but the majority of the criticisms I've seen online are Basically bullshit like they're the criticisms of someone who didn't actually watch the movie or at least someone who didn't pay attention.
Speaker 0: They'll complain about things that they'll say like I didn't understand X or why didn't make sense when actually it made Perfect.
Speaker 1: people say the same things about anything.
Speaker 1: That's sort of weird and ambiguous right.
Speaker 1: instead of being just a literal Straightforward what you see is what you think they complain about her.
Speaker 0: literal and straightforward.
Speaker 0: They're like, why did the guy, you know giggle and mess around with the alien?
Speaker 1: Well, he was high Something that wasn't explicitly stated right?
Speaker 0: No, but I'm saying things that were pretty much explicitly stated.
Speaker 1: We're also points of confusion, but I mean that you know, but I'm saying it's not.
Speaker 1: There's a difference between explicitly stated as in oh, yeah There was a shot of the guy getting high versus you know The constant reminder for dumb people that is in a lot of media in the United States Like you show the guy hitting little guy and it says I hit you you little guy.
Speaker 1: So there's no way you can miss it right as opposed to we watch a lot of animes, right?
Speaker 1: You know, you watch your tenor and it's like yeah They showed it to you for like a second and if you weren't paying attention because you have no attention span You would have missed it.
Speaker 1: and you know If you weren't actually, you know focusing on the action and looking at all the things on the screen You would have missed that.
Speaker 1: so, you know because they didn't hammer it into people and they don't have attention spans They don't have focus.
Speaker 1: They miss things that aren't repeated or Really focused on and highlighted with you know, big spotlights on them, right?
Speaker 1: So any movie that doesn't have all those things or book or anything like that a lot of people just miss those things.
Speaker 1: And then they say it made no sense.
Speaker 1: Well, it made sense to me just like evangelical antenna make perfect sense to me.
Speaker 1: I know exactly what's going on.
Speaker 1: All right, there's no ambiguity like ooh, I can explain any scene.
Speaker 1: I will tell you what's going on, right but a lot of people are like it makes no sense.
Speaker 1: Well, there are things out there that make no sense.
Speaker 1: These aren't them.
Speaker 0: well, I guess that's my point.
Speaker 0: the things that people say made no sense were actually the things that were the most obvious.
Speaker 0: and Peep I would have a lot more respect for these criticisms if they actually touched on the things that seem more legitimately Confusing or poorly done anything that's not perfect can be criticized which is everything.
Speaker 0: So In general nerds I see peep nerds in general seem to mess up two things.
Speaker 0: when they try to critique something that they like Or that they hate one They they confuse not liking a character with the character being well represented.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean pretty much it's the same thing we've been discussing for 10 billion years.
Speaker 0: They don't like Katniss in the book Hunger Games But really what they're saying is I don't like teenage girls and I don't want to read about what a teenage girl's doing Which is fine.
Speaker 0: That means you don't like Hunger Games because you don't like that kind of story that kind of character.
Speaker 0: But it doesn't mean that is not an accurate representation of that character.
Speaker 1: Well presented I'm just saying this is the same thing We've discussed a billion years a billion times that people will never figure out and that will.
Speaker 1: that is what separates People who can validly critique something and people who can't is people who can separate their personal feelings From their evaluation of a thing no matter what that thing is or what category it is.
Speaker 1: You just go on the internet and you find people arguing about anything a video game a book a movie Right and people will 99 times out of a jillion.
Speaker 0: Well, ninety nine point up in the ante on these numbers here.
Speaker 1: Yeah the overwhelming majority of the time All you know almost a hundred percent of the time somebody if they like the thing they will argue the thing is good And if they don't like the thing they will argue that it is not good.
Speaker 0: Well as funny as I remember when I said well cannot separate their personal and I said in the forum that Avengers was okay People acted like.
Speaker 0: I told them that their puppy is a bad puppy and I'm gonna kill it and then I actually killed.
Speaker 1: They have personal feelings for Avengers and therefore they you know got good feelings in their body when they watched the movie there You know, they had good emotions.
Speaker 1: They found out.
Speaker 0: Scott I gotta get a point of the way.
Speaker 0: the way you present, you know, we're we have the same argument.
Speaker 0: You present it in a somewhat more caustic fashion.
Speaker 1: What's caustic about this?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: you you you free.
Speaker 1: people watch people watch a thing or read a thing or whatever and they feel good.
Speaker 1: It gives them good feelings.
Speaker 1: It scratches their itch.
Speaker 1: They like it.
Speaker 1: They enjoy it.
Speaker 1: Therefore they say that makes the thing good.
Speaker 1: That is not the case, right?
Speaker 1: Get good feelings watching.
Speaker 0: You're making an unspoken argument that you are there for the urban edge.
Speaker 0: that is no.
Speaker 1: I'm making an argument.
Speaker 1: The unspoken argument is that I have the ability to separate my From evaluating things and many people if they have that ability do not exhibit I'm smarter than everyone and you're all stupid.
Speaker 1: a Lot of people most people are stupid.
Speaker 1: Everybody knows that.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying There is an ability that I have.
Speaker 1: other people have not demonstrated to me that they also have this ability.
Speaker 0: I'm just making a tangential point that this is why we can both say the same Argument in the same thread and people will disagree with you and agree with me even though we said the exact same thing.
Speaker 1: So, how would you word that differently?
Speaker 1: That is not but you but also say the same.
Speaker 0: I would word it mostly the way I was wording it before.
Speaker 0: talk a lot more about the ideas of valid invalid criticism of what?
Speaker 0: They mean and what people get out of a movie without directly Impinging upon the perceived intelligence of the people.
Speaker 1: but why what is that?
Speaker 1: I didn't say anything of anyone's intelligence.
Speaker 1: I just said there's an ability that I have.
Speaker 1: Are you saying that like you're the one implying that if someone does indeed lack that ability that they are unintelligent.
Speaker 0: I just don't coach.
Speaker 1: you're making a logical leap there.
Speaker 1: No, you are also Scott.
Speaker 0: however, I'm pointing out that if you are arguing with other people or Discussing something in a Buzz Aldrin fashion for the benefit of other people You have to take into account the way they will likely interpret your words.
Speaker 1: If they cannot interpret words properly Maybe that that is why they are upset because they have discovered the truth that they are less intelligent.
Speaker 0: But at the same time that is if they were intelligent as they claim.
Speaker 1: Right because you shouldn't be insulted by someone calling you dumb if you're not.
Speaker 1: if you are dumb because then it's true You can't be insulted by the truth You should only be insulted if you're actually not dumb.
Speaker 1: right and someone called you dumb then there's a reason to be insulted.
Speaker 1: So if you aren't dumb you should be able to interpret those words properly Wouldn't you say so?
Speaker 1: and if you interpreted those words properly, you wouldn't be insulted by them.
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: have no comment because I have a vested interest in maintaining my ability to convince people of the exact same things you want to without Hitting that shield or that barrier that you inevitably you're like a Klingon ship coming into an argument and
Speaker 1: captain
Speaker 0: What the fuck is that shields all the way up, right?
Speaker 0: They see me.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh crazy.
Speaker 1: So I never actually said the people lack the ability You don't have to.
Speaker 1: I say that the people have not Demonstrated their possession of this ability, right?
Speaker 1: and if they get upset by that and make the logical leap to sit to that they don't have the ability and that therefore they Are dumb.
Speaker 1: if they make that logical leap they are then not aren't they?
Speaker 1: Admitting they don't have the ability.
Speaker 1: perhaps however Simply by are they not wrecking?
Speaker 1: and and the thing is they also Never make a movement.
Speaker 1: They also never argue that I do not have the ability.
Speaker 1: No one ever tries to do that.
Speaker 1: They they never try to do that nor do they try to prove that they do have the ability or they don't even discuss that At all.
Speaker 1: luckily, they just humbly admit It's like they silently admit that I'm right and then just say you're insulting me.
Speaker 0: You have to come in.
Speaker 0: No, you have to come in with the self-deprecation first.
Speaker 0: You do something like like what you.
Speaker 1: I have an ability who don't have.
Speaker 0: no you need to come in Earlier with the I like initial D. Initial D is a terrible show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I come out with that all the time But I have the ability.
Speaker 0: is that remember you have to frame the debate in terms of your own self-deprecation In order to make other people lower their shields and then you can worm the point in.
Speaker 0: but anyway, I say to your good sir What is your news today Thursday in the lounge?
Speaker 1: So finally Finally yeah, we got some big movement here, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz you know pretty much one of the number one things troubling especially nerd communities if not the whole internet community these days other than arguments on the internet exactly is the Accessibility of video programming particularly television programming.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute You're just what is you're doing?
Speaker 0: because I had my backup news of why everyone's pirating Game of Thrones.
Speaker 1: Mine is related but not that news.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, go on go.
Speaker 1: So, you know and it is the whole HBO thing with the Game of Thrones, right?
Speaker 1: Let's tie the news together.
Speaker 1: Okay, cuz we did.
Speaker 1: we just talked about something else.
Speaker 1: So fine, and you know, there's the Hulu and Netflix are gimped because the cable companies got a lock-in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you can watch stuff on your Xbox or your PC But only if you have pay for cable and login with your cable login Like you can watch ESPN on your Xbox if you pay for ESPN on your cable Which is like well, but then what the fuck do I need it on my Xbox?
Speaker 0: What's interesting is that he's letting me use my Xbox as a cable box But as we know, you know for that case, I would be perfectly willing to pay for just ESPN without cable, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like oh, yeah, you can pay for just baseball but on your phone Which I did one or two years in a row when I got first got the iPhone 3g, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't get Mets games.
Speaker 1: who's gonna use the GPS?
Speaker 1: you found out that you're in New York So we're gonna block all New York games.
Speaker 1: It's like well then why the fuck did I pay 10 bucks for this app?
Speaker 1: if I can only watch frickin Seattle Mariners and Milwaukee Brewers?
Speaker 1: I only care about the fucking meds.
Speaker 1: But you're using the GPS to figure out that I'm in New York and if I don't let you activate the GPS You won't let me watch anything.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, if I don't pay and I just do a pirate stream.
Speaker 0: I can see everything just fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so anyway, there's you know, there's this whole thing that you know, we everyone knows this topic, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah So the Department of Justice finally is doing something my favorite department I know other than I'll call tobacco and firearms justice.
Speaker 1: She's got a blindfold over eyes.
Speaker 1: She's really good at magical drop.
Speaker 1: No She knows how much things weigh.
Speaker 1: it always gets it even anyway, so What they're doing is they're going after, you know Comcast Time Warner, etc.
Speaker 1: But you know everybody saying hey We're gonna try to see if you're doing any antitrust business trying to gimp competition from Hulu Netflix, etc.
Speaker 1: On purpose to you know, keep with your cable monopoly, right.
Speaker 1: survey says Yes, right.
Speaker 1: So cable is a monopoly right and it's sort of you know, it's one of the right and it's a local monopoly Monopoly in a local right?
Speaker 1: It's a monopoly.
Speaker 1: and the rule the law in the u.s Is not that you are not allowed to have a monopoly.
Speaker 1: YKK has a monopoly on zippers.
Speaker 1: They are allowed to have a monopoly on zippers right.
Speaker 1: Microsoft Windows is allowed to have a monopoly on operating systems, right?
Speaker 1: What is illegal is to use your monopoly power in one area to thwart competition.
Speaker 1: Right, because if you have a monopoly on zippers like YKK does right if I tried to compete in the zipper department.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna take them on.
Speaker 0: They're not allowed to use the advantages they have of being the existing Monopoly like saying if you ever buy another zipper from another company, we're gonna not let you buy any YKK zippers again, right?
Speaker 1: So if there's a you know, Uniqlo wants to buy zippers from me, right YKK could be like well We're not gonna sell you any of our zippers if you buy theirs.
Speaker 1: and you know They only want to buy some of ours and some of theirs and I'll do that.
Speaker 1: Like when Intel was like Dell you got to buy Intel.
Speaker 1: shit, you know, I'll do that.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, that was right around the arrow when I really hated Intel.
Speaker 1: or you know and Microsoft is like Windows You can't be like.
Speaker 1: well We're gonna make sure.
Speaker 1: we're gonna use our Windows monopoly to get Internet Explorer everywhere and I'll do that.
Speaker 1: So basically what they're saying is hey these people with the cable monopoly are using their cable monopoly.
Speaker 1: prevent competition Netflix Hulu etc.
Speaker 1: No So the Department of Justice is investigating but most specifically they're investigating the bandwidth limiting, right?
Speaker 1: It's like oh well If you have like an AT&T mobile phone the be using ABC's video app doesn't contribute to the bandwidth cap.
Speaker 1: But using Netflix does giving your existing monopoly on you know an advantage of.
Speaker 1: you know Alright, and this is what Comcast when they merge with NBC Specifically agreed not to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah guys, so because
Speaker 1: reality so that's why they're honing in on this one specific Usage, you know because that's one that they have on paper somewhere that they can really nail them on if they discover that it has In fact been done and you really much guarantee it has.
Speaker 1: so let's see how big the balls of the Department of Justice are And maybe the FCC can bring back the a la carte cable and etc.
Speaker 1: etc.
Speaker 0: thing is.
Speaker 0: a la carte cable is 15 years too late.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying but we could maybe get right what they should have.
Speaker 1: I don't even know why.
Speaker 1: see I don't know why the cool cable companies don't do this, right?
Speaker 1: We know why the stuffy ones don't do it right way.
Speaker 0: name a cool cable company, right?
Speaker 1: So we know why.
Speaker 1: name one a cool cable channel cable company.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: No, I'm coming channels.
Speaker 0: Okay, maybe a cool cable channel that isn't HBO or Showtime isn't Comedy Central is pretty cool, right?
Speaker 1: Even though it's owned by Viacom which is not cool.
Speaker 0: Yep, but cable sent Comedy Central itself is cool But I actually though my trouble with Comedy Central is that most of the programming for the last I don't know ten years I've not cared about.
Speaker 0: no really only things I like on Comedy Central are South Park in the Daily Show and the Daily Show web app has Possibly the second most annoying advertising scheme in the world.
Speaker 1: That's also broken but I'm saying is like look be comedy central.
Speaker 1: It's already cool enough to let you watch South Park Daily Show just on their web.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling that Daily Show and South Park are only there like that because those two particular shit No, not just those.
Speaker 0: Yeah those shows the people who make them have a lot of Independent power and cash.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: Trey Parker and Matt Stone can basically go to comedy central.
Speaker 0: They look we will fuck you if you fuck with them, right?
Speaker 1: But anyway, I don't know why for example comedy central or some other cable channel that actually has viewers as opposed to the ones that Don't have viewers like time, right?
Speaker 1: says go to Comedy central comm.
Speaker 1: there's a video player right there and you can watch street live streaming Comedy Central 24/7.
Speaker 1: It's the exact same thing that's on our channel on TV.
Speaker 1: You don't need cable anymore.
Speaker 1: Just come to our website.
Speaker 1: Fuck all the cable companies.
Speaker 1: and if every channel did that right independently one is better for the advertisers.
Speaker 1: The problem is is this exact monopolistic antitrust practice?
Speaker 1: is you know You have the companies that own the cable right?
Speaker 1: cable vision also owns cable channels like MSG.
Speaker 1: They don't want to just let you watch Ranger games on the computer because then you won't also You know pay them in a day, you know, they get the advertising from that which they already get on MSG.
Speaker 1: but in addition They're getting money from you every month to pay for the cable vision.
Speaker 1: if they they basically just Doing what we want them to do which is go to MSG comm watch Ranger games It's basically just throwing away all the money that they get from people subscribing.
Speaker 0: Well, this is a problem that Sony has had for a long time that when you've got multiple You know, you're a big enough company.
Speaker 0: to where do you have multiple arms?
Speaker 0: any company in the modern world who was into both?
Speaker 0: distribution of content and creation of content that isn't just completely independent and Has these weird sort of conflict of interest within themselves where if one wing of the company as well It'll basically destroy the other wing of the company, right?
Speaker 0: If I were the heads of these companies, I would be rapidly trying to spin off all the legacy stuff.
Speaker 0: I would spin off the networks on their own and get the content creation Separate and I would stay on the content creation boat, right?
Speaker 1: Well, see that's the one thing I don't understand Is that there's no one in any of these companies realize this?
Speaker 1: This is the thing I don't get.
Speaker 1: is that you know, there's only like six media companies really, right?
Speaker 1: But you would think that if one company of the six went for it and said we're gonna sacrifice our old shitty Distribution business just let it Peter out right and we're just gonna put all our content online the modern way.
Speaker 1: that that one Right, even though would have a temporary setback in revenues right of people bailing and just.
Speaker 1: well, you know watching online Whatever right would gain favor from the people's of course, they would gain advertising money of the wazoo, right?
Speaker 0: I actually said wazoo.
Speaker 0: That's how much money.
Speaker 1: I think they would gain money from people Just paying them for their shows directly, which is what people want to do.
Speaker 1: You know the good shows at least right and three.
Speaker 1: all of the other companies now would be at a competitive Disadvantage and that one awesome company would be getting newer better content.
Speaker 0: So Scott, I think it comes That these are large companies right in any large company.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of momentum Yeah, and there are people who carve out tiny little empires.
Speaker 0: So the guy in the company who has a lot of power, but is his boat is completely tied To the old legacy.
Speaker 1: shit It's a god if it has to come from the guys at the top who have the most power And the least vision in these cases.
Speaker 0: Yep But anyway, I mean look I work for a small company and basically the heads of the company every day are like What can we do this crazy?
Speaker 0: What should we do?
Speaker 0: Let's fuck everything over and start.
Speaker 0: Let's just go crazy.
Speaker 0: They want they don't push it faster than I would push.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, the big, you know big companies, you know, I used to work at IBM.
Speaker 1: Basically there is so much momentum but right but it makes you think these six seven media companies are competing with each other Theoretically, but they're also.
Speaker 0: they're collaborating right.
Speaker 1: only way This could still be clearly collusion which is also illegal because if there wasn't collusion Some of them would pick orange right and Cut out and be like, all right, we're gonna bail, you know, I don't think Viacom owns.
Speaker 1: Time Warner owns cable NBC Comcast has regular kid.
Speaker 1: I don't think Viacom.
Speaker 1: I think Viacom just has content.
Speaker 1: Do they own a cable operator?
Speaker 1: I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: RCN.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't think so, right?
Speaker 0: So that's a separate show on this.
Speaker 1: Research that.
Speaker 1: but what you know?
Speaker 1: one of them that only does content, you know.
Speaker 1: could we know Fox News Corp has you know?
Speaker 1: Cable and whatever right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, look at this.
Speaker 0: if I if if you didn't think about the corporate relationships HBO is probably the best position as a Thing that's owned by it's all my time Warner.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but here's the thing.
Speaker 0: HBO.
Speaker 0: if it were its own thing still It would be able to basically be the one that does that and they were probably the guy who runs HBO.
Speaker 1: He's on video.
Speaker 1: people have asked him this stuff and he's just.
Speaker 1: he's the oldest thinking fuddy-duddy.
Speaker 0: Well HBO is owned by Time Warner and Time Warner would get fucked if HBO destroyed the old model.
Speaker 0: But I think HBO as a network could single-handedly destroy the old model.
Speaker 0: possibly.
Speaker 0: I think they're the.
Speaker 0: I think they're actually the only ones who have.
Speaker 1: that's the one that people are pushing for the most because they Have the show.
Speaker 0: well that was the article I was thinking about.
Speaker 0: talking about that I decided not to bother with because we had plenty of news that Game of Thrones is possibly the most pirated television show in history.
Speaker 0: That's old news Yeah, but we talked about that before we only talked about it tangentially.
Speaker 0: there's an article that really goes into like who's pirating it and why.
Speaker 1: and People in countries who can't get it mostly people who don't want to pay for HBO.
Speaker 1: And you know, there's no legal way to get it without paying for cable, but that's so much money.
Speaker 1: It's not worth it.
Speaker 0: Well, you can buy DVDs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't get the DVDs as soon as it comes out the day of the show comes out.
Speaker 0: and the thing is, you know Six or seven years ago, we'd be a convention saying that live is dead because other than sports live was.
Speaker 1: and yeah I mean, I'm the person who doesn't care I could like if I want to watch Game of Thrones.
Speaker 1: I haven't watched it at all yet.
Speaker 1: I downloaded the first season.
Speaker 1: I'll watch it some time Eventually, I'll check it out.
Speaker 1: cuz how can I not?
Speaker 1: it's so hyped.
Speaker 1: How can I not at least check it out, right, but I'm in no rush, but these people it's like they're obsessed.
Speaker 1: They got to see it as soon as it comes.
Speaker 0: Well, because it's remember when we were reading the Prince of Nothing in the crew.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all the people who weren't reading it basically were shunned from at least half of our conversations.
Speaker 1: I just whatever I read before I read it.
Speaker 0: I remember everyone else who had read it in the first wave We'd be talking about and he stepped into the circle inscribed by his sword.
Speaker 1: But meanwhile when I eventually got around to reading it, there was plenty of discussing.
Speaker 0: That was only because there was a second simultaneous wave.
Speaker 0: There is a certain social currency.
Speaker 0: but you know in the old days remember there were no.
Speaker 0: there more than many shows like Dick Van Dyke would be on TV and literally Everyone saw it.
Speaker 0: and the next day in the office in school Everyone had seen the same thing and had that to talk about.
Speaker 0: now It's fractured but it's starting to come back and look at nerds.
Speaker 0: ponies happens the next day every nerd who watch ponies talks about ponies.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: But you know while I can see that right person I'm not saying it's that important to you or me.
Speaker 0: I'm saying that there is.
Speaker 0: there is serious social currency in seeing something Early in the cycles that you can then discuss it and be part of the internet mashup free-for-all.
Speaker 1: Let me insult people again indirectly About what if you're doing the spoilers thing and It's that you look at someone like me, right?
Speaker 1: Um, well, I'm totally hipster in nerdy, right?
Speaker 1: I'm reading things.
Speaker 1: No one else is reading and watching things.
Speaker 1: No one else is watching right and then when I come over I know you didn't watch every episode of running man.
Speaker 1: I talked about it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, right?
Speaker 1: I'm just like whatever.
Speaker 1: I don't need to talk about the thing that you've also seen.
Speaker 1: I'll just talk about the thing that I seen.
Speaker 1: Right, but if you if you seen something I haven't seen I don't mind.
Speaker 1: if you talk about the thing I've seen it's actually more interesting Scott.
Speaker 1: That's not even close to the argument I'm making but I'm saying it's more interesting if you talk about the thing I haven't seen.
Speaker 1: so I don't need that.
Speaker 1: Everyone has seen the same thing.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 0: you say no Scott you say that but it's not if they're talking about the jargon of The thing that then it doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 0: Mmm, possibly if it's a thing with jargon - all I'm saying is that for the majority of people and ours included There is social currency to being in with whatever the thing is.
Speaker 0: So if it's good and you want to consume it you get more out of it.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like buying the laptop on day one as opposed to day hundred if the price doesn't drop.
Speaker 0: if you buy it On day one you got a better deal than on day hundred because otherwise you got a hundred less days and paid the same amount Of money.
Speaker 0: you pay the same amount of time to get the media But if you get it when other people are in the getting there's more immediate like payback on that in the turf in the form Of social currency.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's all I'm saying.
Speaker 1: That's a bigger calculation though Cuz you also got to wonder what other media could you have been consuming at that time, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, if you say what what Scott?
Speaker 0: that's a bigger calculation About the entropy of the universe caused by my brain consuming the thing and the electrons moving around.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, I could consume that right away and I get this bonus.
Speaker 1: But that means I'm not doing this other thing and today is today.
Speaker 1: who knows what's going on today?
Speaker 1: That might mean not biking because it's good weather in the summer.
Speaker 1: I'll wait till the winter to watch it, which is coming.
Speaker 1: Look at how this works.
Speaker 1: I see I can get the joke.
Speaker 1: I haven't even watched one minute of the show.
Speaker 0: Why is a winner a big deal?
Speaker 1: I'm curious because there's a guy who says Winter is coming and that means it's gonna be cold and it's medieval time.
Speaker 1: So it sucks when it's cold and that means it's gonna.
Speaker 1: everyone's got to stay inside and be trapped with and have sex.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much it except Winter last like 20 years.
Speaker 0: Oh And it's a medieval war.
Speaker 1: I thought it was only medieval world.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize it was fantasy of a world where because of the way the planets work There's like five years of summer and then some number of years of winter.
Speaker 1: Oh, see I thought see I was not aware that that it was.
Speaker 1: winter is coming is tickle a word?
Speaker 1: I thought it was a only got this dragon.
Speaker 0: It's Prince of Nothing, but other wizards.
Speaker 0: Yes, but they're far away But they are there.
Speaker 1: I see I thought it was just sort of slightly fantasy like sort of like King Arthur, right?
Speaker 1: It's a little got.
Speaker 0: it is and that everything the game show focuses on is the slightly fantasy.
Speaker 0: But there's big fantasy like right on the edges like epic level D&D fantasy.
Speaker 0: It's out there.
Speaker 1: It's out there, but it's not where.
Speaker 1: you know when it's coming Scott when winter comes in season four Wizards are gonna fly in on dragons casting spells.
Speaker 0: I have no faith that the show is gonna go anywhere.
Speaker 0: I know where the books have gone magic ring and the books aren't going anywhere either.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's gonna be wheel of time.
Speaker 1: Let's move on.
Speaker 0: So anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: So we were watching this video of a bunch of models falling over and it was funny.
Speaker 0: It was funny, but it was also kind of sad.
Speaker 0: So to get the taste out of our miles, we watch a video a bunch of guys Opening beer bottles in a manly fashion and it was actually a surprisingly enjoyable video.
Speaker 1: They do a lot of repeats, but it's good But there were no actual repeats.
Speaker 0: everyone was crook slightly.
Speaker 0: So but it was like they were like three machetes.
Speaker 1: What are you talking about?
Speaker 0: They were differently shaped machetes.
Speaker 0: They weren't the same machete.
Speaker 1: I think I saw the same.
Speaker 0: now you do them plus there was like monkey wrench other kinda wrench.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So here's a little fun like how some of them don't work.
Speaker 1: here's a similar short and funny video.
Speaker 1: This guy is in Russia, right and he pulls up next to some Russian police And he notices that the policeman in the car is not wearing a seatbelt and it's talking on his cell phone.
Speaker 1: So he's like hey Hey and he yells at the police officers to roll down the window and he tells him hey put your seatbelt on and Turn the phone off right regulation number, whatever whatever.
Speaker 1: And it's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: look on the cops face because he can't.
Speaker 1: It says in Russia police obeys you.
Speaker 0: the policeman is just like I can't even yell at this guy.
Speaker 1: It's like we get away with this in New York.
Speaker 0: like hey, I would be actually kind of afraid to do that.
Speaker 1: I know right I really even that even if there was like a really nice cop if I saw him doing something like, you know It's like if he was had no seatbelt and he looked really nice and friendly was smiling.
Speaker 1: I might maybe I could get away with like hey, man Dude, I had a seat belt.
Speaker 0: thing is?
Speaker 0: I take to heart the advice we got from that thing.
Speaker 1: The thing is that smile could turn into a frown and like one flash of a second the rule number one of getting by in Life is if you can avoid it don't engage yourself with police officers or really low life people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we did a whole show crazy crazy bum when that crazy guy tried to punch me while I was riding my bike in Beacon.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, you know it's more simple.
Speaker 0: never get involved with the police or Anyone who has nothing to lose or the perception of nothing to lose.
Speaker 0: That's right All right, met a moment met a moment.
Speaker 0: The book club book is 1 q 8.
Speaker 1: for you teen 84 or you want to say it's uh, we're I'm about done with it.
Speaker 0: I gotta read like the last hundred pages.
Speaker 1: maybe yeah, maybe.
Speaker 1: so it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's a good book.
Speaker 1: You should read it.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't be the book club book if it was not good.
Speaker 1: There wouldn't be hundreds of people reading on a subway every god damn day if it wasn't any good, right?
Speaker 0: The thing is I'm a little.
Speaker 0: I like it.
Speaker 1: I mean it's long enough to wear that if it was just a fad.
Speaker 1: People would like read the beginning and it you know and stop but people are like finishing it on the subway Which means they're you know, they're still reading it.
Speaker 0: Well, how do you know?
Speaker 0: you're watching people like finish it on.
Speaker 1: I see what page they're on.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The thing is it's a book where I start reading like, okay Where's this going?
Speaker 0: Oh crazy murder.
Speaker 0: Okay, maybe it's about that.
Speaker 0: little people Little people ears.
Speaker 0: What do they mean by little people?
Speaker 0: What's up with the ear?
Speaker 1: Oh little people little people two moons Little people.
Speaker 0: that's right thing is?
Speaker 0: it's one of those things where I kind of expected like oh little people will be Little people and then sure enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah, somehow it's like what really.
Speaker 0: yeah Our other new madam news Connecticut coming up real soon Mostly online.
Speaker 0: I got a tweak it a little bit.
Speaker 0: Panelists or two bailed on me.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be filling in some extra panels.
Speaker 0: Connecticut is gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: If you want to work at Connecticut and do like volunteer II whatnots you can talk to me or the Connecticut volunteer department.
Speaker 0: I will say this though if you want to help out and you talk to us first and then them and you're cool We will make your job easy because I think you know We don't really need people to work incredibly long.
Speaker 1: Basically, all we need is like two people on maybe two or three people at all times on shift Right and even at late night.
Speaker 1: Maybe even less people.
Speaker 1: probably like one or two people at night when there's less traffic just so that there is someone in the hallways and somebody checks on every panel to make sure it starts.
Speaker 1: and if a panel has a problem they have somebody to ask for technical help.
Speaker 1: and Yeah, I'm going to go into the panel room and say hey you have five minutes left Get out all that manage a line.
Speaker 1: if a panel is really popular It is your chance to.
Speaker 0: actually you'll probably if you volunteer and help us out at Connecticut You will probably hang out with us more than you can at any other convention we ever go to and you'll put something on your resume.
Speaker 0: Guys, look at my college kids.
Speaker 0: I actually put Otacon and Connecticut on my actual for real Yes, and all you got to do is to word it right.
Speaker 1: you got to be like Connecticut panels operations specialists.
Speaker 0: Well, well Depends you got we pick your title.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying you can you know, you make up something.
Speaker 1: That's well.
Speaker 1: What are?
Speaker 0: we were the directors of panels and workshops?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway other men it is July 13th 14th and 15th in Hartford, Connecticut And if you want to go to Connecticut I would not fly across the country to go to Connecticut.
Speaker 1: It's not worth a fly across the country.
Speaker 0: if I lived within.
Speaker 1: it's a relatively small to medium ish kind 7,000 ish unique.
Speaker 0: so about turnstile ish 17,000 give or take.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's an everything con.
Speaker 1: The board game library is better than any board game library at any convention I have ever been.
Speaker 0: that includes both mag fast.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there are some that are better maybe like SN or that, you know gathering of friends or something, but Personally have ever been.
Speaker 0: did I not just say packs?
Speaker 0: I'm not kidding.
Speaker 0: It has much better board gaming than packs.
Speaker 1: It does have better board gaming than packs.
Speaker 0: Both taxes.
Speaker 1: Yes all taxes.
Speaker 0: It does not however have an arcade like mag fast.
Speaker 0: No, but there are panels on Everything we've.
Speaker 0: it isn't everything con.
Speaker 1: It's not one of those cons.
Speaker 1: It's like we're an anime con and then people get pissed because they have a panel about some video game.
Speaker 1: We got a lot of anime.
Speaker 1: kinetic on is an everything geeky con.
Speaker 1: It makes that's what it calls itself everything and the kit but the kitchen sink.
Speaker 1: if you have a geekery whether it's furriness or Music or cosplay or animes or mangas or comics or sword fighting?
Speaker 0: technology is belly dancing juggling.
Speaker 1: we have running Airsoft parkour juggling events right no matter what your nerdery is Sci-fi it is at kinetic on.
Speaker 0: so also John St.
Speaker 0: John's coming back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you are in I'd say if you're in New England, maybe Maine is too far or New York Connecticut yeah, then it's worth going.
Speaker 1: if you're farther away than that If you have to if you can't drive there in a day in a few hours, then it's not worth it.
Speaker 1: But otherwise it is and you should go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not gonna like.
Speaker 1: it's gonna sell out.
Speaker 0: Pax prime packs dev.
Speaker 0: those are coming up.
Speaker 0: We'll be talking about what we'll probably do in there.
Speaker 0: Not going to Otakon obviously but if you want if you guys go tell us how it goes.
Speaker 0: and if you want us to go tell them that you Want us to be there.
Speaker 1: and lastly our website has been recently updated and house and more updates are coming down the line Which reminds me we're gonna add the video section.
Speaker 1: maybe today after that we finish a show.
Speaker 1: You should go to our website and this cool.
Speaker 1: It's now better.
Speaker 1: But if you don't like our website and I can see why you might not like websites are kind of old-fashioned.
Speaker 1: the website Automatically pushes everything to Facebook Google+ Twitter and we're gonna even remember unlike everyone else We actually don't try to make money off of this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we just want to push our content everywhere.
Speaker 1: It can be pushed.
Speaker 1: I'm even thinking of making a geek night's reddit that everything will get posted there as a link and Also making a geek night's tumblr and just pushing everything everywhere so that no matter where
Speaker 0: you look at everybody and everybody's
Speaker 1: room So no matter where you like to be
Speaker 0: fish tank
Speaker 1: on the internet
Speaker 0: deep and other people
Speaker 1: geek nights is available there.
Speaker 1: iTunes we're available everywhere and Except to know - that's right.
Speaker 1: So you if you like us and you're listening to the show You should go to your favorite place on the internet and follow like grab subscribe Whatever it is you do to us Pinterest, I guess I still don't even know what Pinterest we can't.
Speaker 1: Pinterest is basically delicious that looks different and Organizes differently.
Speaker 1: So just use delicious like I do delicious.
Speaker 0: It's been really slow lately.
Speaker 1: really.
Speaker 0: I mean, alright, so 45 minutes later.
Speaker 0: It's time to talk about hats.
Speaker 1: That's good because I intentionally did that because we don't have that much to say about hats.
Speaker 0: I feel like I could do a long show on hats.
Speaker 1: Well, okay, so let's start with this, right?
Speaker 1: I have no hair anymore.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: I have some hair but and I point out during the five borough bike tour You got one - you got eight sunburns on your head in the places where there are holes in your bicycle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've corrected that now.
Speaker 1: I Need a hat, but I can't find a hat.
Speaker 1: That's a good style and every style of hat I see Either a isn't for me personally as my body doesn't matter My clothes don't match it like.
Speaker 1: I would totally do like 20s 30s awesome hat.
Speaker 1: But that would mean I need to wear 20s 30s suit maybe with the vest every day and you know what it's warm.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, you got linen.
Speaker 0: Linen is the key.
Speaker 1: It doesn't go with that kind of hat.
Speaker 0: does a linen Jack?
Speaker 1: No, the linen goes with like the straw hat, you know the Panama hat with the red white and blue.
Speaker 0: There's a long tradition of Italian businessmen wearing these sort of like linen suits while they're going around.
Speaker 1: The kind of hat you throw up in the air to parade.
Speaker 1: That's not a good hat for me to wear either.
Speaker 1: You know, you could wear what stovepipe.
Speaker 1: not wearing a stovepipe.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna look.
Speaker 0: just do it.
Speaker 0: No, just own it double down.
Speaker 0: No, what's funny is when I was young like before I had long hair like I was just a punk kid.
Speaker 0: like a really young I hated wasting time in the morning on things like Brushing my hair like.
Speaker 0: I remember that was the thing like.
Speaker 0: I didn't want to bother with stuff like that.
Speaker 1: I definitely still don't want to bother with stuff like that.
Speaker 0: So I pretty much always wanted to wear a baseball cap.
Speaker 0: just because that meant I didn't have to do anything I wore it.
Speaker 1: see we weren't allowed to wear a baseball cap in in school or we but we could wear the hallways.
Speaker 1: So wait, so I didn't bring one to school and didn't wear one because I'd usually just lose it.
Speaker 1: But when I get to high school the rule changed in high school.
Speaker 1: in high school, you could wear it just not in class Right.
Speaker 1: So in class, I just take it off and put it on the table.
Speaker 1: and I started like freshman year of high school Up through freshman year of college.
Speaker 1: I just wore Mets hat every day.
Speaker 1: None, they just always had the Mets hat on everywhere.
Speaker 1: I went.
Speaker 0: I pretty much wore baseball caps every time.
Speaker 0: I was like going around Outside unless until when I was in 10th grade I got what I affectionately called the stupid hat.
Speaker 0: It was this sort of like bucket hat like a sort of Panama style, but really crappy and smaller.
Speaker 0: I Pretty much wore that up until I lost it at RIT all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wore that Mets hat up till freshman year at RIT and then sophomore year.
Speaker 1: I sort of just stopped.
Speaker 1: I don't remember why.
Speaker 0: of course RIT, you know I'll dig up a picture to link to for this episode.
Speaker 0: But it's funny because right around my senior high school when I got to RIT, you know I had a bunch of like I wore a brown duster everywhere because it was winter.
Speaker 0: in Rochester We're gonna one degree in freezing and a duster is not only a coat but it's also basically a portable bed and portable pillow and A portable backpack because I could fit everything I needed in the pockets.
Speaker 0: So I would use.
Speaker 0: I wear like pajamas under it and wear it to class and curl up in the library and use this blanket Or a bed or whatever.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing that always happens.
Speaker 1: right is if you're a freshman in high school You're a sport in middle school style for a while And when you're a freshman in college your sport in high school style for a while and then you grew out of it.
Speaker 0: But the thing is in college.
Speaker 0: I didn't do that in High school.
Speaker 1: It was only really and then when you get out of college to the real world your sport college style for a while and then you Get turned into adult.
Speaker 0: Yeah But I would.
Speaker 0: I got to you know.
Speaker 0: at RIT I had the duster and I wore it a lot cuz it was cold and unlike the rest of my life I didn't have a car to just drive everywhere.
Speaker 0: So I started wearing the duster all the time.
Speaker 0: and What goes better with the duster than a Leather cowboy ish hat.
Speaker 0: Yep So I was actually you know for a couple of years at RIT The majority of the people who saw me the majority of the time I had a duster and a cowboy hat on.
Speaker 0: I looked And I had a huge mustache.
Speaker 0: I look very different from how I do now in terms of style Mmm, I wore that cowboy hat like every goddamn day like every picture of me at RIT.
Speaker 1: That's how you can always find a rim.
Speaker 1: It was easy to find.
Speaker 0: The thing is no one brown stick walking around Yep, but no one could call me Tex cuz we knew a guy called Tex.
Speaker 1: Yeah that he's the only Texas I could say.
Speaker 0: if anyone had called me Tex I think he would have killed me just to make sure.
Speaker 0: maybe so one day I'm sitting in the RIT cafeteria, but I mean you didn't have a 10-gallon cowboy hat.
Speaker 1: It was more of like an Australian Outback kind of like I'm on the bush Wrangling horses.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but darker brown.
Speaker 0: and then you know, like crocodile Dundee looked a lot like what's-his-name's hat in Final Fantasy 8?
Speaker 1: No, wasn't it Star Ocean?
Speaker 0: No Final Fantasy 8.
Speaker 0: Whatever The sniper guy.
Speaker 0: I didn't actually play Final Fantasy 8.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sort of like a Grit hat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Grit doesn't wear a hat in Advance Wars 2.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, actually you were very Grit style.
Speaker 0: I was.
Speaker 0: I was always kind of unshaven.
Speaker 0: So I had that kind of Grit.
Speaker 1: You didn't have the pointy G-gen beard though.
Speaker 0: No, I had the epic mustache.
Speaker 1: You know Grit and G-gen same actor.
Speaker 0: I Got to say playing Advance Wars 2 again, Grit is hex.
Speaker 1: I should go watch the Lupines.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen.
Speaker 0: I haven't caught up on them either.
Speaker 0: all right, so I wore this hat like all the time like that was just I was known as wearing that
Speaker 1: hat and
Speaker 0: One day we're eating lunch or dinner or something in Gracie's the cafeteria and out of nowhere Someone from behind like like on this balcony like above where we were eating Grabs the hat off my head runs away and
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: look I'm dumbfounded like I can't
Speaker 1: believe this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you think it's just like a practical joke like lol's got your hat, dude Like I can't believe this happened and I assume it's someone I know.
Speaker 0: and then our friend Greg looks at me.
Speaker 0: It's like I think that guy just fucking stole your hat.
Speaker 0: So you had to chase and I look up and the guy just keeps running like he's almost out of the cafeteria.
Speaker 0: I'm like fuck.
Speaker 0: so I get up and run and then like Greg follows me and like part of the crew to start following.
Speaker 0: He's like this chain of people and I get outside and I and I the guy would have gotten away, but he stopped.
Speaker 0: He's just walking and right behind him.
Speaker 0: I grab his shoulder and spin around like give me my hat back and he was deaf Mmm, and he looks at me like I'm stupid.
Speaker 0: He's like what and I pointed the hat.
Speaker 0: I'm like my hat and he doesn't want to give it back to me.
Speaker 0: and I'm I'm debating threatening him when other people start to show up and suddenly got this posse behind me.
Speaker 0: I'm like, give me the fucking hat back and I grab it from him and he kind of stands there.
Speaker 0: But then he backs down and I walk back into the cafeteria like a hero and I resume eating.
Speaker 1: No, even what I assume was it was not like a clapping or it was just like walking back in.
Speaker 0: But I was a hero to me because I got your hero to you.
Speaker 0: only I still got that head.
Speaker 0: But the problem is later the head shrunk.
Speaker 0: It doesn't fit my head anymore.
Speaker 1: I think your head grew Inflated.
Speaker 1: sense of self-worth.
Speaker 0: I just couldn't believe.
Speaker 0: someone stole my hat.
Speaker 1: Yeah off my head.
Speaker 1: What would they want with it?
Speaker 1: Were they dared to do it?
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't even someone I knew was a random deaf kid.
Speaker 0: I never saw him again on campus.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what else we gotta say about hats?
Speaker 1: I like you know, you watch old movies you see everyone wearing a hat and you think yeah I wish you can go back to the days and everyone wear a hat and was styling but at the same time I can't even get there myself.
Speaker 1: So he's got anyone else for not getting there.
Speaker 0: No There's Derby style canes like when people have a walking cane and has like the thing you hold on to like the Johnny Walker label.
Speaker 0: And there's alcohol and there's like a little hook on the front of it.
Speaker 1: Yep, you know, that's what I had on.
Speaker 0: You hang it over your arm and then you hang the hat on the hook.
Speaker 0: that way your arm is free.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: I see more and more people like whenever them around the theater district or whenever I go to a show or something.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of people sporting that kind of look again in New York.
Speaker 1: Yeah at a formal event you could totally do it, but it's like to wear that every day is a expensive be warm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well expensive.
Speaker 0: I'm already having the problem if I wear like a jacket like every day like I dress up nice and as a result now I own like 14 jackets and I get dry cleaning done constantly and it's actually really expensive.
Speaker 0: and I've worn out two jackets.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not just expensive to buy them right?
Speaker 1: That's like a one-time cost a few thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most people you own a jet.
Speaker 0: you don't like two jackets.
Speaker 1: You've got a dry clean haul that shit constantly instead of regular laundry.
Speaker 0: Well, that's something I've learned.
Speaker 1: cause just as much to wear the suit for one day as it costs for like a whole basket Of regular teeth.
Speaker 0: when I was younger I never paid much attention to the formal attire other people wore but now because I wear jackets all the time I kind of think about it a lot more.
Speaker 0: and what's funny is like when I go to an event Like a convention like not a nerd convention, but a more business II convention You can pretty much tell someone's profession and income level based solely on literally the cut of their jacket.
Speaker 0: Yeah And I gotta say when you see the guy wearing what is clearly the same jacket he order was prom complete with the hole for The button near at a professional convention.
Speaker 0: That guy is still in college or fresh out of college.
Speaker 0: He's like the low-level tech guy.
Speaker 0: Maybe he's a coder.
Speaker 0: It was forced to go there by his boss.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that has never steered me wrong.
Speaker 0: Lately I really haven't been wearing hats anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's like I want to wear a hat But I just can't find.
Speaker 0: what I don't get though Is that I see a lot of people in the city who are businessmen, but they're like a schlubby normal middle-aged But they're like 45 and they have like a normal job So they have to like.
Speaker 0: they have to dress up as opposed to dressing up because they want to But they have to dress up in this boring like white dress shirt with a particular.
Speaker 1: Why don't they go more style?
Speaker 1: and if you have I had to dress up, but I didn't quit the job Which I probably.
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: why is it always be like the crappy white dress shirt, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I wouldn't take the job in the first place.
Speaker 1: But if I had to have that job where they force you to dress up and that's the job I had to me a white Dress shirt literally exists.
Speaker 1: only you're paying the dry cleaning cost the same no matter how fancy the clothes are, right?
Speaker 1: It's the jackets 250.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter if it's a thousand dollar jacket or a $1.00.
Speaker 1: Goodwill jacket, right?
Speaker 1: Dry cleaning is the same.
Speaker 1: I would get.
Speaker 1: it doesn't need to be expensive.
Speaker 1: I just be styling right as opposed to you know Shlubby.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but those people almost a third of them on the subway are always wearing a Really?
Speaker 0: Non-matching random baseball cap.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I Don't know why But it bothers me even more than wearing the baseball cap.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: is the people who get the baseball cap put the plastic in the back as opposed to the fitted hat, right?
Speaker 1: It's like oh, are you kidding?
Speaker 0: every baseball cap I ever owned had the plastic in the back.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's awful.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's the words.
Speaker 1: and it was even worse than that is when the entire back half of the hat is sort of that mesh That's only for talkers.
Speaker 1: truckers and fishermen are the only people.
Speaker 0: God, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: You're the one now who's complaining about other people's fashion.
Speaker 0: Oh Look at the hat she's wearing.
Speaker 1: we're la de da can't wear that hat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, where you're gonna complain about people wearing socks and sandals on the beach?
Speaker 1: next you can do that from the beach.
Speaker 1: I don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: care about hats.
Speaker 0: Care about hats.
Speaker 1: hats are important.
Speaker 1: You want your hat back because hats protect the head which is the important part of the.
Speaker 0: but no helmets protect the head.
Speaker 1: Helmets are hats.
Speaker 1: once I've a helmets.
Speaker 0: No, I think helmets is a separate show.
Speaker 0: Okay, because I have a bunch of helmets You gotta squeeze out another episode.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to get a formal hat but with long hair like I have to tie it back in a very particular way to wear a nice hat and because I have a atypically large head in terms of like measurements Off-the-shelf hats don't fit me.
Speaker 0: Like I have to.
Speaker 0: really I've just been a lot of money.
Speaker 1: that is annoying right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know It's hats are one of those things with the more expensive when it's clearly superior.
Speaker 0: Same thing with canes because I was thinking about getting a nice cane to only take when I go to like the theater like nice Jacket, you know pants cane.
Speaker 0: Thank you.
Speaker 1: You should bring your little mustache the wooden.
Speaker 0: Oh my god the mustachical that I love that thing.
Speaker 0: The problem is I looked at canes.
Speaker 0: The cheap canes look like shit the nice-looking canes.
Speaker 0: if they were I expected like alright if I'm crazy And I spent like 200 bucks.
Speaker 0: I'll get the best-looking cane.
Speaker 0: now Talk to thousand dollars right for a good-looking game.
Speaker 1: Here's what you do rim, right?
Speaker 0: So the best-looking cane and guys if you want to make me a cane I'll be your friend forever.
Speaker 1: Right, the best-looking cane in my opinion is the plain black smooth, you know thing that tapers to a point at the bottom.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a little metal tip and then the metal handle at the top, you know That's sort of like the sideways handle that you can hang the hat on right?
Speaker 0: So what do you want?
Speaker 1: That's all you got to do.
Speaker 1: It's so simple.
Speaker 1: It's not doesn't have need to it doesn't need to be one of those ones.
Speaker 1: There's all sorts of engravings on the metal.
Speaker 0: I don't want that.
Speaker 0: I want very simple.
Speaker 0: I want black with silver tips and I Or and he's gonna be the right shape right or I want to really like sort of art deco style in one.
Speaker 0: I saw one online.
Speaker 0: It was a one-off custom cane someone made for a project.
Speaker 0: It was beautiful, right?
Speaker 1: But anyway, they wanted like nine thousand dollars for we could make that cane Right really cheap.
Speaker 1: Just get a piece of wood, you know, put it in the spinny thingy make it the right shape.
Speaker 0: No, that's not how you make anyway, but it doesn't.
Speaker 1: it just has to look right.
Speaker 1: you you lacquer it black You put them get the metal things and attach it to both.
Speaker 0: now There's more to it than that.
Speaker 0: if you just do that one that's not gonna be a super even coat.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna look nicely black.
Speaker 0: You gotta get a wood and stain it.
Speaker 0: You don't mean it.
Speaker 1: No, if it's if it's spinning and you spray it black.
Speaker 0: Well, you don't spray it.
Speaker 0: you stain it or look like shit.
Speaker 0: It's also gonna be matte not shiny.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: You don't use spray paint for that.
Speaker 0: That would look awful.
Speaker 1: You don't use spray paint, but you would spray the paint.
Speaker 0: No, not with an air spray You don't use paint for something like that.
Speaker 0: You've clearly never worked with a wood before.
Speaker 1: anyway You can make it really easily and it would not cost you even close to ten.
Speaker 1: You know ten dollars let alone thousand now.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't it wouldn't have that certain level of polish.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like how you see the guy wearing the suit now At least I do and you can tell like how expensive the suit is and or how nice it is Just by the cut.
Speaker 0: like you see a cheap suit and you're like, wow, the lapels are really on.
Speaker 1: I bet if I had the materials and enough extra materials to practice a few times I can and I could make Canes that look great.
Speaker 0: I don't think you can make them cheaper than similarly.
Speaker 0: No, the ones that are of that level of quality you're talking about are like 40 bucks But they kind of look like shit and they break.
Speaker 0: What kind of wood do you propose to use?
Speaker 0: Cheap wood.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if it breaks, it's not a problem.
Speaker 1: Just don't break it.
Speaker 1: It's just gonna look good, right?
Speaker 1: It's like the four dollar umbrella.
Speaker 1: It's just gotta it works.
Speaker 1: It gets you home.
Speaker 1: The cane will get you to the theater and home.
Speaker 1: It's all good.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to get a top hat.
Speaker 0: Alright, so get one to wear with tails at things.
Speaker 1: what thing?
Speaker 1: you're gonna wear that to the Opera.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you'd stand out.
Speaker 1: be weird.
Speaker 0: I saw.
Speaker 0: The last time I went to a show I saw many one.
Speaker 0: I saw one person with a top one, dude.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's the weird dude.
Speaker 1: Everyone points out and goes giggly.
Speaker 0: Do you think I'm not a weird dude?
Speaker 0: You think I'm not gonna be eccentric silver-haired old crazy guy?
Speaker 1: then why don't you go full out with like purple jacket and sparkles?
Speaker 0: That's a different kind of rainbow tie and yellow orange pan rainbow - tie.
Speaker 0: yeah sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know Rod Roddy style.
Speaker 1: Or who's the hockey guy?
Speaker 1: Don Cherry just like Don Cherry I think we're done here.
Speaker 0: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and my comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.