Speaker 0: It's Monday September 10th, 2012.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: My cell phones too big and I guess the tech news roundup.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: You know the part where we say Yeah, I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott this geek night.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know we could just only record.
Speaker 0: you mean like way back when we recorded that one.
Speaker 0: really good Let's do this that we've been using to this day, right?
Speaker 1: We should only record the tonight blah blah blah part.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's a little more of a pain in the ass and people might notice though I think most of our listeners to this day do not realize that that clip of us saying let's do this is Literally from 2005.
Speaker 0: Nope 2006.
Speaker 1: There's no way.
Speaker 1: they could not realize that it's exactly the same.
Speaker 0: They might have figured it out the few times when I did a show by myself and yet magically you were still here to say that There's no way that we could say something.
Speaker 1: so precisely.
Speaker 1: you'd have to be a moron To listen to more than one or two shows, ah, but you more than two or three memory My memory as bad as it may be at times Would not fuck something like that up.
Speaker 0: All right name any character from the man who was Thursday other than Thursday Monday Tuesday Wednesday Sunday and Friday.
Speaker 0: Gregory, okay, you got it.
Speaker 0: I kind of like Gregory.
Speaker 1: I finished it by the way.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm like two chapters to go.
Speaker 0: I thought you finished it.
Speaker 0: No, I've got close to the end.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I did not just yeah say something.
Speaker 1: I was about to say I Like Gregory you had given me the impression that you had finished it long ago.
Speaker 0: No, I'm.
Speaker 0: basically If I sit down for 45 minutes, I'm done with it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I blasted through it when I was at Django kind of such that I could read other things.
Speaker 0: It reminds me this is our book club book, by the way, we probably have a lot of new listeners.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it reminds me of the kind of book that in middle school would have been assigned to me to read and then write.
Speaker 0: I like a one-page paper.
Speaker 1: You're reading the free edition.
Speaker 0: No, I bought the really nice like Kindle one.
Speaker 1: Oh you bought the Kindle one.
Speaker 1: Okay, did it have footnotes on all sorts of things that were?
Speaker 1: no no See mine whenever they were weird sort of References.
Speaker 1: yeah references to things that are no longer relevant to modern times But you would have gotten them if you were alive in the 1900 like what different hats and things?
Speaker 1: Well, no, like he would make you know, he'd be like, oh, you know, he made a For example, there's one part where he says oh there's something of Aesop, right?
Speaker 1: And then there's a whole thing in the back about how like actually the pig of Aesop was.
Speaker 1: You know, it was probably referring to this other fable by this other guy.
Speaker 1: Aesop never wrote any fables like that.
Speaker 1: But there's a fable by this other guy.
Speaker 1: That's exactly like what he's referring to.
Speaker 0: but he missed the point cuz the point was that he was referring to Gibberish on purpose in that scene sort of right?
Speaker 1: No, but if you read the footnote then you know what that fable with the pig that by the other guy is about.
Speaker 1: That is super relevant.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of a Hamlet.
Speaker 0: he's crazy.
Speaker 1: but situation exactly where it's like, you know, it's.
Speaker 1: it's for example You know if it was Shakespeare It would be like bite my thumb at the.
Speaker 1: you know with the number two next to it you go in the back and they'd be Like number two and be like, yeah a long time ago people would bite their thumbs off and throw them.
Speaker 1: He'll be like, you know that used to be an insult that basically meant fuck you.
Speaker 0: good, sir I feel like everyone today knows that that isn't in.
Speaker 1: so of course, but I'm saying as an exam There are things in you know, man who was Thursday where you would not know.
Speaker 1: Even a smart well-read educated person would not know unless there were a hundred years old.
Speaker 0: regardless.
Speaker 0: We are back from PAX.
Speaker 0: But so we said there'd be a bunch of downtime and there's gonna be beyond this because next week I'm flying overseas for one or two weeks and all sorts of other crazy.
Speaker 1: So there's no shows next.
Speaker 1: for basically now It's only give me one week of shows in September which is this out the call for guest episodes.
Speaker 1: Did anyone answer the call?
Speaker 0: I have one guest episode done one guest episode And we have someone else who looks pretty cool who promised another guest episode.
Speaker 0: So I'll probably have those up to a guest episode And if I'm in India for the week after that I might just record some things and send them out or I don't know I'll figure something out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll save that for the meta for the baby.
Speaker 1: September's gonna be light on shows but October the month of geek nights show.
Speaker 0: that's when I'm going to Turkey in Germany All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah Also burning Khan, is that October?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think so.
Speaker 1: Oh, I thought it was December.
Speaker 1: I gotta prepare.
Speaker 0: I don't know when it.
Speaker 1: actually I only half prepared.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about it in the minute I'm gonna finish preparing my game for recess.
Speaker 0: But uh, so many of you are probably here brand new after packs.
Speaker 0: You probably saw us do our awesome lectures.
Speaker 1: There's no way that you're listening to this show right now because there's no way you remembered us.
Speaker 1: A whole week after packs.
Speaker 1: we had Remember we existed.
Speaker 1: you probably started by listening to the last show We put up and I don't even know what that only if you like that episode Which I don't think was probably the best episode in the world.
Speaker 1: Would you be listening to this one?
Speaker 0: It's been a while, but I'm full.
Speaker 0: I am back in court and full of fresh ideas.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: I But yeah, we're back.
Speaker 0: we're bad we're gonna be not back soon and then we'll be back again.
Speaker 0: But we wanted to talk about something very important because it's been pissing Scott off for a long time Not for a lot just for months or so.
Speaker 0: really it's been pissing me off for longer.
Speaker 0: In fact, I've complained.
Speaker 1: It's only been a problem for months.
Speaker 0: It's been a problem for me since I got my current phone the Samsung Nexus s.
Speaker 1: When did you get that phone?
Speaker 0: like a year and a half ago?
Speaker 0: Okay, and I the problem isn't that this phone is too big.
Speaker 0: The problem is that I can't get a phone this small when this phone eventually dies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's really annoying that you know, you go to the phone store and all the smartphones now are Gigantic and it's like wasn't sort of the point of a mobile phone?
Speaker 1: that it's mobile and small and just adding features to it Without making it bigger is like whoa, that's crazy.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 1: You added all this stuff in that tiny phone.
Speaker 1: Holy shit I've never fucking small.
Speaker 1: that palm pre was right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: I have my.
Speaker 0: I pulled my palm pre out the other day right and I have it on my desk at work.
Speaker 0: I charged it up and I reset it and I'm gonna like see if I can figure out something cool to do with it.
Speaker 0: Cuz it's internet, you know, it's a computer.
Speaker 0: I Forgot how much I love that form factor.
Speaker 0: The only problem with the pre other than the lack of support by anyone was the fact that the screen While the right size was too low.
Speaker 0: res if I had a palm pre Identical except that it had the screen resolution of this Nexus s. I would pay like a thousand dollars for that.
Speaker 1: But anyway nowadays it seems like what everyone's doing at least phone manufacturers is going.
Speaker 1: Uh Shit guys, we can't really fit all this stuff.
Speaker 1: We want like a giant ass battery inside the small phone and It's kind of hard to get high resolution.
Speaker 0: The battery is a red herring because they make the big-ass phone with a big-ass screen that eats the battery just as fast.
Speaker 1: now Right, but it's also that you know, it's like hey we make this screen bigger it'll look more impressive and we can get the higher resolution.
Speaker 1: and you know, it's sort of like Best Buy faking the Got a cough little coughing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not really coughing that much when I'm not talking which I wasn't doing a lot of.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't see you with Luke Burrage all week More coughing.
Speaker 0: I'm not editing any of that shit out wheezing Oh Anyway Okay.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's sort of like in Best Buy where they fake the TVs, you know And people buy some 50-inch TV for their three inch living room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I would do a website when I bought my TV.
Speaker 0: My TV is pretty ridiculously big.
Speaker 0: It is the maximum size that actually works for the room any bigger and you could not read subtitles or See the entire screen at once.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I'm pretty sure according to the calculator that the TV is too big for you.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: So here's the deal.
Speaker 0: There are two separate there.
Speaker 0: There are three calculations.
Speaker 0: One of them is for vision impaired people.
Speaker 0: One of them was for like television watching and one of them was for quote Cinematic watching and they kind of the websites I used all broke them down among those three or at least two of those and The what they said was basically if you primarily watch movies You want you want to go one class bigger because it'll be about the same size as a movie screen if you're in a real theater.
Speaker 0: But they warned that if you're watching non HD stuff or if you're watching like TV shows They'd actually kind of sucks on that size TV because then it's a little too big.
Speaker 0: It'd be like watching I don't know home improvement or the Simpsons in a theater Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But yeah, anyway, but beside the point I Think throughout all of human history.
Speaker 0: There's been this idea that bigger is better.
Speaker 0: I mean from penises to TVs to cars.
Speaker 1: I think it's actually a unique Only for certain cultures.
Speaker 0: bigger is okay.
Speaker 0: So fine in the history of Americans.
Speaker 1: Well, I think there are other country.
Speaker 1: I don't want to say America I mean it is America, but I think there are also other places in the world and other cultures besides just America Where bigger is also better probably.
Speaker 1: but there are also places where smaller is better like Japan.
Speaker 1: They like small things.
Speaker 1: They're compact and they fit in their small places.
Speaker 0: I like small things - I also like small things But I just.
Speaker 0: this is why it bothers me.
Speaker 0: My phone right now is literally the ideal form factor.
Speaker 0: I can hold it in one hand.
Speaker 0: I can touch every part of the screen with my thumb.
Speaker 0: That's right In fact my thumb.
Speaker 0: I have a really big hand.
Speaker 0: I could do the same thing with slightly bigger phones But I'm kind of an odd case.
Speaker 0: I have abnormally long fingers as I learned recently by measuring them and looking at a website.
Speaker 1: You're not as long as rock Manon off.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I wish I had fingers as long as rock Manon off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not doing so well there.
Speaker 0: I think you're dying.
Speaker 1: It's only because I keep talking.
Speaker 1: I wasn't did I?
Speaker 1: I didn't cough it off before we started doing the show.
Speaker 0: No, you didn't that is true.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you didn't lie.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Why would I lie?
Speaker 0: because I would I ever lie?
Speaker 0: You lie often captain mclay pants.
Speaker 0: that in fact was a lie liar.
Speaker 1: Anyway You know, what's really bad about this?
Speaker 1: coughing?
Speaker 1: Yeah losing whatever I was thinking about I'm just like what was I saying?
Speaker 0: So the phone also is really thin.
Speaker 0: it fits in my pocket.
Speaker 0: It's tiny it battery lasts a long goddamn time unless I play like Oregon Trail all day, Oregon Trey Oh my god, Oregon Trail.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about that in the next Tuesday show.
Speaker 1: So I try to look.
Speaker 1: you try to find a synonym to the cell phone situation and the first thing that comes to mind.
Speaker 1: Well CVS and SUVs, right.
Speaker 1: But the thing with TVs and SUVs is they still sell fucking small cars and small TVs if you want them.
Speaker 1: But with smartphones, it seems like no one is selling a small smartphone anymore.
Speaker 1: You go to the store and there just isn't one and it's like, okay There might be one thing that is technically a smartphone that is smaller But it's crap.
Speaker 1: like the smartphones that aren't the best smartphone may as well not exist.
Speaker 0: I know I mean the thing is.
Speaker 0: the only exception to that is that to this day?
Speaker 0: I still assert that the Samsung Nexus S is the best non iPhone phone hardware in the world.
Speaker 1: but it's like you go to the cell phone store for any of the carriers or whatever and you see a whole bunch of Phones and a lot of them are smartphones.
Speaker 1: But really only two or three of them actually count and the rest of them might as well be like, you know brick crap phone.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And now when I go to the store every one of those phones is like an inch bigger than my current phone with this Gigantic screen.
Speaker 1: It's like what the fuck?
Speaker 1: I want a phone not a fucking tablet.
Speaker 0: No, the worst thing is we're by we.
Speaker 0: I basically mean the sort of power Technorati kind of users.
Speaker 0: We're the kind of excluded minority now because normal people I talk to who just like have a smartphone or don't really think about it.
Speaker 0: Not only do they want bigger phones they complained that like the HTC hero was too small.
Speaker 0: These are the people who buy a tablet But yet at the same time want a bigger smartphone.
Speaker 0: I don't get it Cannot understand where this is coming from.
Speaker 1: it just maybe they you know, we know we tend to be the kind of people.
Speaker 0: I have to stop using that phrase.
Speaker 0: I don't understand.
Speaker 0: I don't understand why Republicans want stupid things like.
Speaker 0: no I do understand why I just think it's stupid, right?
Speaker 1: Well, I think what it is is we're the kind of people who you know, somebody who is against us could say Well, you guys are just so, you know anti Conformist that you're intentionally, you know indoctrinating yourselves against Indoctrinated -
Speaker 0: so
Speaker 1: if everybody else in the country is going bigger is better We're gonna go.
Speaker 1: no no smaller is better.
Speaker 1: Just because I've always said smaller is better I've always wanted right because you always wanted to go against the grain.
Speaker 1: You've never not wanted to go against the grain.
Speaker 0: No, it's because a small phone means I have less shit to carry in my pockets.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: That's all I want.
Speaker 0: The reason I want my phone to be small is because all my phone is my entire life.
Speaker 0: It is just a link to the rest of the world.
Speaker 0: That is always on me.
Speaker 0: No matter what.
Speaker 1: Yep I think a lot of the people who want the big phones I've heard what a lot of what they've been saying is like people keep talking about like watching video.
Speaker 0: That's what I was about to say.
Speaker 0: everyone I've talked to.
Speaker 0: it's the same thing.
Speaker 0: They say that the primary thing they use their phone for is watching movies.
Speaker 1: I did hold on.
Speaker 1: I did when I was riding the train.
Speaker 1: watch full anime series is on my iPhone 3g.
Speaker 1: I Did that many times and you know what?
Speaker 1: Okay bigger would have bigger have been better Maybe but you know what?
Speaker 1: that iPhone 3g with his non retina screen and watching like all of Evangelion all of Escaflowne on the Metro North train When you know when you start watching something it fills your whole field of vision Even though it doesn't fill your field of vision.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it occupies your your you know, your optical processing units of your brain.
Speaker 1: So you don't see anything else.
Speaker 1: It was just fine.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: I have good vision.
Speaker 1: Maybe people now Independent.
Speaker 0: if someone makes the well you I could read the subtitles with no issue whatsoever even if vision is an issue.
Speaker 0: You know what I did because I didn't want to watch videos in my phone.
Speaker 0: I had a tiny phone that I didn't watch videos on and I had my laptop on the train and I watch stuff on that because I watch them in the laptop - but I also currently I watch youtubes on my iPhone 4 occasionally and it's just fine.
Speaker 1: I Having it bigger might be better but it's not something I. it wouldn't outweigh the Pain of having a gigantic phone that I can't have to use two hands to hold and is big and clumsy.
Speaker 0: I mean my phone.
Speaker 0: I got a shoulder mount So when I run I can have it like on me because I never.
Speaker 0: I mean I carry my phone in the shower Like when I go into the bathroom, I just put it like in the cupboard and just sits there waiting for me to come back.
Speaker 1: I thought you mean you're brought into the shower.
Speaker 0: Well, I occasionally I've read slashed out while I was soaking my lower half.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I you know, the rumor is and we'll find out I guess in a few days the iPhone 5 I don't 5 is bigger than the iPhone 4.
Speaker 0: I'm not getting it.
Speaker 1: Well, it's the rumor is it is bigger.
Speaker 0: I think the rumors BS.
Speaker 0: I'll say that hold on I lost rumor you didn't.
Speaker 1: the specific part of the rumor is not that it's big like, you know The freaking Android Samsung Galaxy gigantos eyes.
Speaker 1: if you wanted that big just buy a tab.
Speaker 1: The rumor is is that it is the same width so that you can still get your thumb all the way across.
Speaker 1: But and it is only slightly taller so that 16 by 9 videos will play with no You know bars on the side.
Speaker 1: that is fine that you know, that is acceptable.
Speaker 1: I would rather not.
Speaker 1: But if that is my choice Obviously, I'm just gonna buy that.
Speaker 0: but all of you listeners out there I want to know why do you want a gigantic phone if you could buy a tablet?
Speaker 1: Well, a lot of the people say oh, it's not too big and it's it's like they're like, oh it fits in my pocket Just fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everyone my hand is really big.
Speaker 1: I can reach all the way across it.
Speaker 1: What's the problem?
Speaker 1: And it's it's like, you know the same people have an SUV and they say all these things.
Speaker 0: I think it's just a matter of their use.
Speaker 0: cases are very different.
Speaker 0: These are the people who I think travel and then they you like they don't have a good laptop Or they don't carry it with them.
Speaker 0: probably cuz I have a gigantic laptop - yeah They could.
Speaker 1: they have gigantic.
Speaker 0: everything probably is gigantic.
Speaker 0: laptops are way cheaper at least Like a small laptop.
Speaker 0: that's powerful is way more expensive than a big laptop.
Speaker 0: That's equally powerful That's true.
Speaker 0: But when it comes to the phones, like I've watched.
Speaker 0: I won't.
Speaker 0: the reason.
Speaker 0: smaller things are more expensive They're better, but people I know who I see with these gigantic stupid phones.
Speaker 0: They carry them around everywhere and when they like visit someone they use it as their computer And it occupies a good deal of their mental sort of concentration.
Speaker 1: I mean, I do use my phone like a computer quite often But it doesn't.
Speaker 1: it's just fine that it's the size it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't need it to be my point.
Speaker 0: my point is that these are the people who Maybe show up at a social event or like go somewhere for a weekend and spend a good deal of their time Not just like while I'm waiting for you to take your turn in mini golf But like while we're sitting around on the beach just constantly using their phone.
Speaker 1: even bring my fucking phone to the beach.
Speaker 1: What do we get?
Speaker 1: sand and shit?
Speaker 0: I do in a plastic bag because I want to have my phone.
Speaker 1: if someone takes it out of my time I'm gonna take it.
Speaker 1: I don't take my phone.
Speaker 0: No one steals shit in Wildwood.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't know I don't bring my phone to any beach.
Speaker 0: When I went to Rockaway Beach I carried my fucking bike onto the beach And then I locked it up like the chain like through the wheels on The beach on my towel and then as I swam I look back at it every two seconds I don't bring.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah Yeah, but the thing that bothers me is you read articles talking cuz you know our it's phone season.
Speaker 1: Right, all the new phones are busted out holidays shopping and iPhone included and all the articles that talk about this.
Speaker 1: when they bring up Size they sort of take for granted that bigger is better.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: I read like three articles and all of them were like, you know, they did the pro and con thing and they're like pro You know You know, it's faster con too small iPhone 5. if the rumors true It's gonna be too small and it's like they'll go like Samsung Galaxy X, you know 100, you know pro.
Speaker 1: It's so awesomely big guys And it's like you're just taking them granted that bigger is better.
Speaker 0: on the other side of this notice how there's there's this move toward.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of rumors of different people having Tablets that are one size smaller than the current sizes.
Speaker 0: So there'll be a tablet that is halfway between the current tablet.
Speaker 1: Yeah Kindle size tablet Kindle size tablet instead of iPad size tablet.
Speaker 1: This is.
Speaker 0: this is where I'm really confused.
Speaker 0: I do not think there is a place in the market for every one of these sizes.
Speaker 1: No, what it is is that they they're really, you know If you buy all these devices, you're gonna find that you really don't use them all.
Speaker 0: In a lot with a trend I've seen more and more people also will have a tablet With 3 or 4g and they use it effectively as a cell phone.
Speaker 1: That's crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I've seen people doing that's like anyone holding up an iPad to take a picture.
Speaker 1: Just I actually didn't see anyone at PAX doing that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not.
Speaker 1: if I did, you know, I'm kind of glad I didn't granted.
Speaker 0: at PAX one year I saw a guy holding up his MacBook Pro and taking video To drop it.
Speaker 1: but anyway, yeah It's that.
Speaker 1: I think what it is is a large component of this is not people need a device of every possible different size.
Speaker 1: It's that company's just looking for something to sell and they're telling people what to want and that works.
Speaker 1: Of course, it works.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's worked for a long time.
Speaker 0: I think there's going to be a coming bust at least in the tablet market much like The sort of aces EPC style crappy.
Speaker 1: I think it'll take.
Speaker 1: you know, it'd be sort of like, you know Netbooks lasted a couple years.
Speaker 1: So give it two to three years and what you're gonna see I think is that people realize You know people bought netbooks and then realize that they were worthless and didn't use them.
Speaker 1: So you're gonna see two three years.
Speaker 1: people are gonna realize which Combination of devices and sizes they actually use and they're gonna upgrade those devices.
Speaker 1: some guy who bought every size He's gonna have the you know, the phone the tablet the computer the laptop.
Speaker 1: He's gonna realize oh I'm not really using You know this tablet so much.
Speaker 1: I'm not really using my laptop anymore But I am using this tablet and maybe you know He'll figure out that all he needs is small phone big tablet and desktop and he won't re-buy Laptop or some other guy will realize he only needs big phone, you know and laptop.
Speaker 1: and you know people Will not re-buy the thing that they don't use and the things that they do use.
Speaker 1: they'll upgrade The things you'll see they'll stop selling the things that people.
Speaker 0: I will say is that I don't think that'll happen in any conscious way.
Speaker 0: No one's going.
Speaker 0: no one who is guilty of that is going to realize what they've.
Speaker 1: no No, the basically, you know the guy who's got say iPhone and you know Kindle tablet and doesn't use his big iPad anymore, right?
Speaker 1: Because he has a laptop.
Speaker 1: that big iPad is sitting in a drawer or forgotten or maybe he gave it away to someone.
Speaker 1: and then The devices that you have and use you think about and when a new one of those comes you think of upgrading it.
Speaker 0: now one Good thing.
Speaker 0: don't get me wrong the idea that we're converging on this world where it's they're all just computers to some degree and you just use whatever physical device is the most convenient.
Speaker 0: form factor is the future
Speaker 1: of course,
Speaker 0: but It seems like which
Speaker 1: combination of four factors
Speaker 0: like everyone's rushing to very large form factors without a lot of thought and I think they forget the convenience of having a phone that Effectively takes up zero space and has a battery that lasts a long time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because the phone in the end is the minimal core communication device Even though I don't use it for the phone part ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: I know this might seem late to the party But enough people I know had not seen this before that I feel like it's worth mentioning.
Speaker 0: So there's a song called somebody that I used to know that I'd never.
Speaker 0: I actually had not heard the song Until long after I saw this parody of the song.
Speaker 0: But this parody of it is that Star Wars that I used to know and it is both very well done from a sort of production value level but also very well done from a satire parody and poignant Angle.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's great.
Speaker 0: It's about why the new Star Wars is possibly bad and George Lucas is a bad person.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I think people have probably already seen this but it's so cuz.
Speaker 1: it's from 2010.
Speaker 1: This may have even been a thing of the day in the past.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: you didn't even try to find out.
Speaker 1: I yeah, I did a bad job.
Speaker 0: Let me just Look it up right now.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: I gotta kill time while you're looking up.
Speaker 0: All right, I'm doing another thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Well you wait, so two things.
Speaker 0: I'll do this as a secondary thing of the day at PAX.
Speaker 0: This is a Monday show.
Speaker 0: Many of you may know or you may not know that NASA showed up and did an hour-long lecture in the main events hall.
Speaker 0: It was
Speaker 1: really
Speaker 0: well done and at the end of it they did a TED style sort of inspirational speech about what space means in the future and games and what it's all gonna be and it was Amazing and I can say without any reservation that a good number of people in the audience were visibly and audibly choked up during it.
Speaker 1: Okay, so even though this is from 2010 and it was reposted all over the internet recently It's still something that was never a thing of the day even though it definitely feels like it was.
Speaker 1: so here we go.
Speaker 1: You probably saw this if you're an internet person, but what happened is there was this guy a long time ago in like 1909 so around the time the time of our book club book right and he was in Russia Hanging out with Nicholas the second and he had a camera because cameras existed then even though they were the poofy kind with them You know, and what he did is he was very smart.
Speaker 1: He took a green filter and he took a black and white picture with the green filter and then he took a black and white picture with the red filter and then he took a black and white picture with the Blue filter and then he or whatever the three color, right green red blue, right?
Speaker 1: And then he put the three pictures together and he made color photos.
Speaker 1: This isn't someone taking a black and white photo and Photoshop coloring it.
Speaker 1: This is actually fucking color photos from Russia in 1909 through 1912.
Speaker 1: It's kind of freaky because you don't think that the world looked the way but it totally did.
Speaker 1: You know, it did right and It sort of looks like you're looking at National Geographic photos of a foreign place That has old technologies But it's at.
Speaker 1: well it is a foreign place with old technologies, but it's the past.
Speaker 1: It's not like this anymore.
Speaker 0: There's always something very startling about seeing a color picture of something that traditionally is viewed as being in black and white like World War One.
Speaker 1: right, but the quality of the photos is just unbelievably high like that resolution because the method was so, you know Awesome, I mean they had good, you know resolution then with you know photos because using horrible chemicals and whatnot They just had no color without this clever trick.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, you should look at these awesome photos from over a hundred years ago that are in full hundred percent color that were not photoshopped.
Speaker 0: So in the meta moment where we talk about all the kind of meta stuff Yep, we did three panels at PAX the one at PAX dev.
Speaker 0: We obviously cannot talk about.
Speaker 0: The other one is gonna be on YouTube as soon as I edit it together.
Speaker 0: and the board game workshop.
Speaker 0: if you read the rules That is the workshop.
Speaker 1: Okay, so let's never talk about PAX in the meta moment again until PAX East.
Speaker 0: Oh PAX East is coming up.
Speaker 1: Let us instead say magfest coming up.
Speaker 1: magfest is after New Year's So you've got a. you got a few months here of not so much.
Speaker 1: I think New York Comic Con is somewhere in there.
Speaker 0: I'm probably not even going to be honest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I might go for one day at most.
Speaker 0: I'm not.
Speaker 0: I don't even think I'm gonna go for one day.
Speaker 0: I was looking at what is going to be there and I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm not interested in the New York Comic Con anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, really, but anyway the end of October 26 27 28 is our next convention burning con 2012 the triad.
Speaker 1: um for it.
Speaker 1: if you are anywhere close to New York City and You enjoy the tabletop role-playing games This is the thing that you must do now.
Speaker 0: Remember, this is a curated event meaning that you can only run and play games that are from the authors of board game Or of tabletop games who are running the event now.
Speaker 1: Here's the way this event is gonna work a little different from previous burning cons.
Speaker 1: Here it goes.
Speaker 1: Here's how it works a weekend registration $50.
Speaker 1: a one-day $30.
Speaker 1: But and the way it works is the same way as other burning cons.
Speaker 1: you show up you get to play in all the game.
Speaker 1: You know one session they have.
Speaker 1: they have a priority system where if you're a tabletop role player You should be able to figure out the priority system and how it works.
Speaker 1: and you play some role-playing games run by other people And then you have to run one game yourself, you know as sort of that's the key to play.
Speaker 0: you gotta run.
Speaker 0: There is no exception to that.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: Now you can.
Speaker 1: they're adding a thing this year, right?
Speaker 1: It is the $10 beginner track.
Speaker 1: now that doesn't mean it's only $10.
Speaker 1: It means you add $10 to your badge price and you can go to the beginner track, which is for beginners.
Speaker 1: And the way this works is on the first day of the con You sit there and pretty much Luke Crane teaches you fucking burning wheel.
Speaker 1: You know, so you learn.
Speaker 1: that's like getting you know, Gary Gygax teaching you D&D on day one and then on day two You run a game because you have to run again.
Speaker 1: But he teaches you how to run the game in day one even if you've never played or maybe in fact I'm pretty sure if you've never role-played.
Speaker 0: Tabletop or large made a big point about how if you if you sign up for that and it is obvious you are not a beginner He will kick you the fuck out of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right because you're trying to get away without running, you know a proper game for everyone else.
Speaker 1: You're trying to scam the system.
Speaker 1: So, you know anyone who's a beginner?
Speaker 1: you've never role-played before.
Speaker 1: you wonder what's up.
Speaker 1: It's only two days of your life.
Speaker 1: You know, just you should totally do it.
Speaker 0: Now guys also seriously, don't just run a game.
Speaker 0: Just go for it.
Speaker 0: It's not that hard to run a game.
Speaker 0: People are super friendly at things like this.
Speaker 0: I know a lot of people who aren't going because they're afraid to run a game.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I am running into the mountain.
Speaker 1: my the same game you ran last time.
Speaker 0: Yes much improved However, and converted to burning real gold.
Speaker 1: I'm running a new game that I just came up with Scenario, I immediately kill myself.
Speaker 1: Oh you want to play in my game?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not if you give me a dick My character is a dick.
Speaker 0: Not me.
Speaker 1: Well, none of the characters are well actually Right in that, you know, usually when I play a burning wheel I make a character this dick, right?
Speaker 1: So when I made a scenario, I made one good character in three dicks And it's pretty much the three dicks dick in each other and the good in the one not dick being like anyway, I Don't know whatever other meta shit can wait.
Speaker 1: book club book is the man who is Thursday.
Speaker 1: It's on fucking project Gutenberg.
Speaker 1: It's free.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do the episode real soon.
Speaker 0: man Who was Thursday.
Speaker 1: most likely the next Thursday episode?
Speaker 1: Who knows when that's gonna be?
Speaker 0: We'll do it Whatever.
Speaker 0: The book is short.
Speaker 0: Just read it.
Speaker 0: It's also pretty cool.
Speaker 0: And if nothing else I'll say this even if you hate it There are some gems of quotes in here that you would behoove you to memorize and spit out it.
Speaker 1: Yeah I know I just I couldn't fucking memorize them, but I could when I came across them.
Speaker 0: I was like The Kind of quotes you got to put effort into memorizing.
Speaker 0: they're not the ones you'll just remember.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah, let's do something.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So since we've missed a ton of stuff, I think it's time and since we sort of ranted in the first half.
Speaker 0: How do y'all time for a tech news?
Speaker 1: Random you haven't done one since March so we can totally do this.
Speaker 1: It's okay.
Speaker 0: So I want to start right off because today GoDaddy went down.
Speaker 1: I think that's actually Really good thing that this happened because You know everyone.
Speaker 0: so what's funny is I heard it went down like I was at work, right?
Speaker 0: And we're actually migrating to Google mail, but we still have some GoDaddy stuff like running as we shut it all down.
Speaker 0: So the people still on GoDaddy you're like my email is not working.
Speaker 0: So I look on Twitter and it's like duh GoDaddy's down.
Speaker 0: duh GoDaddy's being DDoS and Twitter knew way before anyone else knew.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course I pretty much.
Speaker 1: if something is happening right now I always search Twitter before I search Google News or anything else.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so GoDaddy This is cool because they suck.
Speaker 0: Yeah terrible company.
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: think it's one of those ones where a lot of people are on them And the reason people are customers of them is because they got into it somehow in the past like you didn't know who to register your domain with you went with GoDaddy because that's sort of like the One, you know or something and it's cheap, you know.
Speaker 1: Or people like got GoDaddy email before Google really existed or Gmail was good or you know.
Speaker 1: So they have a ton of customers.
Speaker 1: and they get customers because like people who aren't super internet He don't know where else to register domains like GoDaddy is domain registry sort of synonymous for a lot of people.
Speaker 1: But I think most of the people who are sort of entrenched in there as opposed to the new clueless customers Want to leave.
Speaker 1: but they sort of works.
Speaker 1: it does work and even though they don't like GoDaddy They're just like.
Speaker 1: well, you know, they just go with the flow.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna put in effort.
Speaker 1: They're so lazy They don't want to.
Speaker 1: just you know, do work to get off of it.
Speaker 1: Even they don't like it.
Speaker 1: So this is like aha now they're down.
Speaker 1: Now what are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: and I think a lot of more people are gonna are gonna bail.
Speaker 0: Well, I saw something like they lost a ridiculous number of subscribers, you know, not that long ago Right, they backed SOPA and that was a small, you know impetus to leave.
Speaker 1: now your fucking website doesn't work.
Speaker 1: Cuz their DNS server is down and your DNS is hosted there.
Speaker 0: No A lot of people seem to point directly at their DNS.
Speaker 1: Well, that's what it does.
Speaker 1: by default if you register a domain with them You don't think people know to change DNS servers, but keep GoDaddy is the registrar.
Speaker 0: You know how many people my support team was dealing with saying they're calling and they're like, I can't get to your website.
Speaker 0: We're like, can you get to any website?
Speaker 1: They're like, no Yeah Yeah, but anyway, I think it's good.
Speaker 1: a lot of people leave GoDaddy.
Speaker 1: The thing is the news articles are of course not accurate.
Speaker 1: what apparently happened.
Speaker 1: This was done by one anonymous guy.
Speaker 1: But a lot of articles are saying anonymous brings down GoDaddy But it's like.
Speaker 1: no was actually one anonymous guy at least claims that he did it.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: So who knows well anonymous?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I guess it was me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, it is one specific guy who is like anonymous Underscore something on Twitter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but he may or may not be.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think he's proved that he did it.
Speaker 1: He just has taken claim that he did also.
Speaker 0: what is anonymous?
Speaker 0: I mean, there's the I'm Spartacus situation exactly.
Speaker 1: But anyway, that's yeah.
Speaker 0: I've just between tasteless advertising shady business practices and the whole SOPA thing.
Speaker 0: I have no truck with GoDaddy.
Speaker 1: Why would anyone still be a customer of GoDaddy if you knew how to change?
Speaker 0: I Think that is the only reason GoDaddy has customers.
Speaker 0: Yeah So you got something.
Speaker 0: tech news roundup your turn.
Speaker 1: oh But I mean, I thought we sort of when I didn't open up my all right Let's talk about my internet didn't work because your routers all Google fiber Getting rolled out in Kansas City and they set up.
Speaker 1: we talked about that a while ago.
Speaker 0: So they had all these neighborhoods.
Speaker 0: There were two hundred and two neighborhoods that were offered the service and I don't know exactly what the process is.
Speaker 0: But apparently now that the deadlines have come in 90% of them said hells.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 1: Hells.
Speaker 1: Yeah people are you know, no one's that dumb.
Speaker 0: Now what's interesting is that a lot of the people in neighboring neighborhoods that are kind of outside of this seem to be of the opinion that AT&T and other providers in those areas are doing everything they can to keep the Google fiber out forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well because they the thing is right their choice is do you keep the Google fiber out or try to compete with it?
Speaker 1: And like they can't compete with it because then they're fucked I mean
Speaker 0: look FiOS will have a hard time competing with it and FiOS is Actually kind of horribly kicked out of areas even in New York City by Comcast and other companies that don't want to compete with
Speaker 1: it.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the.
Speaker 1: here's the real problem, right?
Speaker 1: So you you know use this sort of.
Speaker 1: you have this sort of Collusion that's going on to jack up the prices with these local monopolies and the whole thing.
Speaker 1: So your prices are way high So you're making a lot of money and you can't really go to more other places because some other guy has a local monopolies.
Speaker 1: You can't expand that much.
Speaker 1: So you're a cop.
Speaker 1: You're a public company though.
Speaker 1: You have to grow.
Speaker 1: You're not allowed to shrink.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: Fuck that local monopolies should be like Obviously, they have a cap on profits and everything else has been refunded to customers, right?
Speaker 1: But you know, they it's basically you have to keep growing because that's what public companies have.
Speaker 1: So if you suddenly have to compete in a price war, this is why they collude.
Speaker 1: If you even even if they're not actually, you know Literally getting together in secret meetings and colluding they collude by accident because they all need to grow.
Speaker 1: So if one guy goes low to take all the customers, you know Everyone else goes low and the customers will not.
Speaker 1: you know, everyone knows everyone will drop down in the price war.
Speaker 1: You know, the margins will shrink and everyone will shrink.
Speaker 1: There's no way to win.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: the battle of the price There's also the situation of it will guarantee to make your company Shrink and not grow.
Speaker 1: but in some neighborhoods, even if you're profitable and doing well You will be losing.
Speaker 0: but in some neighborhoods like co-ops and condo boards and things and in like certain apartment buildings One company will actually get an exclusive contract with that building.
Speaker 0: Yep to prevent anyone else from going in straight up.
Speaker 1: Yep But it's now Google comes in and it's like usually the only people who you know.
Speaker 1: an outsider who sees a collusion situation.
Speaker 1: He doesn't you know to get any business for him is growing as opposed to shrinking.
Speaker 1: So that's the person they're worried about.
Speaker 1: if you come in from the outside with a low price You're just busy gonna fuck all of them.
Speaker 1: and you know, we talked about how like.
Speaker 1: well this slow adoption here, right?
Speaker 1: Who's gonna really?
Speaker 1: you know, people are lazy to go off.
Speaker 1: go daddy people are lazy to.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: Get you know, we're gonna find out what size tablet or phone they need.
Speaker 1: But when people really hate something and people really hate.
Speaker 0: everyone hates their local telco.
Speaker 0: They're local.
Speaker 1: everyone hates them so bad Right that even normal people hate their Comcast and the cable visions and the.
Speaker 0: you know people People really treating nothing about.
Speaker 0: how is the local internet time orders?
Speaker 1: everyone hates Time Warner's right and people hate their mobile phone carriers so much.
Speaker 1: if One person came into the market with a viable product at a real price.
Speaker 1: That wasn't bullshit.
Speaker 1: Everyone would switch to them like that like boom.
Speaker 1: so this is what exactly what's happening.
Speaker 1: Google's coming in because it's Google.
Speaker 1: they can't keep them out because Google's so big and Everyone even normal people's like, oh you kidding me.
Speaker 1: I can get away from Comcast Time Warner AT&T.
Speaker 0: Fuck Yeah, it's not just that it's that it's so cheap and it's so fast.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I mean it's ridiculous.
Speaker 0: But yeah The the fact that there I see some you know Some of the older media people who are surprised that so many people are you know going on board with Google.
Speaker 1: duh Yeah, if Google made a mobile phone carrier guess what happened.
Speaker 0: So speaking of Google, uh They've recently put forth this idea.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's live but some people claim to have been running into them where instead of having a paywall They have a survey wall.
Speaker 0: So it's you can't do this thing until you get you like on a thing in Google News and it pops up a little survey Google News, I've never seen that.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's where people Sometimes does that with like.
Speaker 1: the ads will have a survey in them, but you don't have to take it You just wait or skip it or whatever, you know, yep.
Speaker 0: So apparently Google demoed this new thing 18 months ago to Publishers saying this is something we'd like to offer.
Speaker 1: I'm sure yeah I mean, I'm sure Google would love to.
Speaker 1: basically what that means is on your website.
Speaker 1: Google is never gonna put it on their website.
Speaker 1: It's on your website.
Speaker 1: You're stupid and you decide that it's not.
Speaker 0: so when I say Google News right now Remember what Google does is that if they can't get to your site because you have a paywall You're just not listed.
Speaker 0: like those articles don't show up in Google News.
Speaker 0: So I think what they're gonna.
Speaker 0: maybe they'll make a deal where if you use the survey wall You can still be listed on Google News.
Speaker 0: That's the speculation the big thing.
Speaker 1: I do notice though that on Google News a lot of times I'll click on something on my phone on Google News and there won't necessarily be a wall of any kind But they'll get one of those pages.
Speaker 1: that's like install the app or continue to the news.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, fuck that who listen.
Speaker 0: local news team.
Speaker 0: I'm never going to install your app.
Speaker 1: No kidding.
Speaker 1: And the worst is when someone links to a news from Facebook and it's like click on it and it's like you must Use our app to read this article and it's like no the articles on your website.
Speaker 1: But because there's a link on Facebook and you have some things set up It's forcing me to install a Facebook app to reach your article.
Speaker 1: Guess what?
Speaker 1: I'm just not gonna read your article.
Speaker 0: now the trouble with these one.
Speaker 0: I find the price is kind of ridiculous.
Speaker 0: it says in the article that people companies have said straight up that you're willing to pay a rate of a hundred and fifty dollars per 1,500 responses.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: so one I Don't like.
Speaker 0: I. if anything like that ever appears I just close it and if I can't get to the content without clicking through it I pretty much click randomly until it disappears.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine.
Speaker 0: I'm not the only one.
Speaker 0: No I'm dubious of this but it's no.
Speaker 0: it's a ripoff to the people Paying for it in the same way that most internet ads are ripoffs to the people paying for them.
Speaker 1: Here's something I sort of realized lately.
Speaker 1: right you look around the world and you can sort of organize companies into a few categories.
Speaker 0: Well, you get it the ones you can.
Speaker 1: You can organize anything into any number of categories.
Speaker 1: That's a pointless thing to say.
Speaker 1: But I see some companies that do a real business of some kind and make a money for a reason.
Speaker 1: for example a laundromat Makes money.
Speaker 1: they provide a service.
Speaker 1: they clean your goddamn laundry.
Speaker 1: They make money.
Speaker 1: you buy soap you put coins in the machines They're selling you a thing directly.
Speaker 1: There are other companies that they don't really make any thing.
Speaker 1: take for example the Olympics, right?
Speaker 1: What is the Olympics make?
Speaker 1: Nothing.
Speaker 1: they sell tickets, I guess you can argue that they manufacture entertainment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean, you know, the entertainment isn't really something, you know, it's it's sort of ephemeral.
Speaker 1: Most of their money right comes from ads.
Speaker 1: right sponsorships and advertisements is where the bulk of their money comes from.
Speaker 1: They don't make enough money from the tickets and the direct sales to pay for the whole thing.
Speaker 1: It's way too expensive.
Speaker 1: So because of that what ends up happening to a company like the Olympics or a newspaper, right?
Speaker 1: Is that you're still owned by yourself?
Speaker 1: you make all the decisions for yourself But you have these advertisers who give you most of your money and the advertisers.
Speaker 1: They don't give a fuck about your business.
Speaker 1: They only give a fuck about their business, but they're not dumb.
Speaker 1: They know.
Speaker 1: maybe you know, they're not so dumb that they think that their ads are actually working seat.
Speaker 0: now Here's the problem.
Speaker 0: Every study I ever read about this says that certain kinds of ads work so well that their industries depend upon them entirely.
Speaker 0: Those industries are the cars the upper-end alcohol industry and the car industry.
Speaker 0: I read something.
Speaker 0: it was talking about how the majority of people today who buy cars Buy the first car that they test drive With doing no research and they're primarily influenced by advertisements.
Speaker 0: They saw a force-head car.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But anyway the And notice how if you watch like The Daily Show, it's nothing but alcohol and car ads, of course.
Speaker 1: But the point is alcohol and car companies actually make something.
Speaker 1: Daily Show doesn't really make something right?
Speaker 1: So what ends up happening?
Speaker 1: entertainment it does but it doesn't make a thing.
Speaker 1: They don't make money directly.
Speaker 1: They made all their money from the ads and the ad companies.
Speaker 1: They might know their ads may or may not work But they recognize the fact that that company would not exist if not for their ads.
Speaker 1: So they boss that company around right.
Speaker 1: for example visa at the Olympics was like hey Olympics.
Speaker 1: in the Olympic area No one's allowed to accept any credit card, but visa right and they know that that's not good for the Olympic people.
Speaker 1: It makes them look bad, but they don't give a fuck.
Speaker 1: They're like, yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: That's we can come up with any ridiculous demand We want.
Speaker 1: you have to say yes, because if we pull our gigantic sponsorship, you're fucked.
Speaker 0: So yeah, we like Kickstarter or so disruptive.
Speaker 0: Look at the penny arcade Kickstarter, right?
Speaker 0: It was basically you know what?
Speaker 0: We're not gonna have ads anymore if you guys give us the money right now.
Speaker 1: in effect a company that depends on advertising Even if you're not even if you have a business other than advertising if advertising is a large enough part of your revenue Remember you have to keep growing.
Speaker 1: you can't shrink You know, you have to do what advertisers tell you to do.
Speaker 1: They sort of they're sort of like they own your company in a way and they can give you orders and you have to choose to either Hurt your business badly or obey but they had.
Speaker 1: they take on none of the risk.
Speaker 1: So they'll just order you to do ridiculous things like dance for me monkey dance Or you'll be out of business cuz I give you 25% of your revenue is my advertising dollar.
Speaker 0: I think I still think and I've read this for a while I think we're getting actually kind of close to the point will start to happen.
Speaker 0: I think there's gonna be a crash in the online advertising.
Speaker 1: I think a big crap, but I think but it's an example.
Speaker 1: So the newspaper your newspaper, right?
Speaker 1: Newspapers are a little different than other businesses and they sort of have this ethical thing where you can't necessarily write articles Really been true exactly.
Speaker 1: but other companies that are not newspapers don't even have that Not really been true.
Speaker 1: ethics.
Speaker 0: They got nothing and the arcade did.
Speaker 1: that penny arcade had its own ethics.
Speaker 0: Yeah, their own ethic of you know, we'll nominally only advertise things that we directly and little not nominally.
Speaker 1: they will only at right.
Speaker 0: Well, that's what they say.
Speaker 0: I say nominally because I can't read their brains.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: But other companies that aren't penny arcade with it with a stated ethos or newspapers with a supposed to have an ethos They just can do whatever the Olympics.
Speaker 1: they can just do another fuck.
Speaker 1: advertisers tell them and there's nothing wrong or unethical about that Whatsoever.
Speaker 1: they can just totally do whatever that right.
Speaker 1: So these newspapers some advertisers says yeah, you know what I'm fuckin You know would be really nice for me as an advertiser.
Speaker 1: I don't care if anyone sees your content or hates your newspaper.
Speaker 1: That doesn't matter to me.
Speaker 1: So, why don't we just turn your site into a survey that gives me information I really need to make my products sell better.
Speaker 1: So Scott says you brought this up and the newspapers choice is lose a large chunk of revenue.
Speaker 0: to you a question How do we pay for content that does require money to make?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I Opposed it because we don't have an answer.
Speaker 0: No one has an answer.
Speaker 0: whoever answers that effectively Wins.
Speaker 1: but the point is if you own the company like say a magazine, right?
Speaker 0: I'm a bad example because and so I've gotten closer and closer to the upper ends of business and Like I know what pitches work like and you know, like equity like all that stuff I've seen the trend in a lot of mid to smaller sized companies not becoming public and Remaining privately owned so they can do whatever the fuck they want And then thus like say I ran a game studio if I made enough money To pay everyone who worked for me good money.
Speaker 0: I would not try to grow.
Speaker 1: Okay, but let's say you have a company that already exists, right and I would not see.
Speaker 0: that's the thing I wouldn't know.
Speaker 1: and you know, you had you already.
Speaker 1: you own this company, right?
Speaker 1: It's a private It's a privately owned company you own.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and 25% of your monies comes from an advertise.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wouldn't I would not assume that revenue stream in the first place.
Speaker 0: And if I were.
Speaker 1: but I say no, but it's already there.
Speaker 1: and if the advertiser is a good advertiser they only want completely tasteful ads and it's totally legit.
Speaker 1: and you like them and you have a good relationship with them right and you're friends with them and You know, they're they're not bad.
Speaker 1: and 25% of your money comes from ads they buy.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's fine.
Speaker 1: one day They come to you and they say look We would really like it if you put this horrible pocky all go to business before I'll deal with that bullshit.
Speaker 1: and then they say Okay, and they take away 25% of revenues.
Speaker 0: So I've.
Speaker 0: I've lost more revenue than that on things before and you get it back.
Speaker 0: What if it's 50%?
Speaker 1: Well one.
Speaker 1: if it was 50% That's what.
Speaker 0: if any one source of my company's revenue was more than like 20% Already, I would have sort of weekly or monthly meetings of how do we distribute our income such to not be beholden to anyone, right?
Speaker 1: And what if your options are?
Speaker 0: Well, if my options are then my business model was fucked anyway, yeah Now what it now?
Speaker 0: here's the and that's when you try something radical.
Speaker 1: All right, try this ready?
Speaker 1: Here's getting radical.
Speaker 1: You ready?
Speaker 1: You're set your.
Speaker 1: you don't own the company.
Speaker 1: You're set your lower on the totem pole.
Speaker 1: You're gonna be second or third down the line, right?
Speaker 0: Okay This is you're gonna like my answer.
Speaker 1: Half of the revenues come from an advertiser.
Speaker 1: the advertiser makes these ridiculous demands like, you know Oh makes only except visa.
Speaker 1: All right, is this kind of paying me my salary?
Speaker 1: and wait, the boss is totally okay with that.
Speaker 1: He's just like just fucking do it.
Speaker 1: Let's only accept visa guys.
Speaker 0: Are they paying me my salary?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 0: Don't give one shit.
Speaker 1: Don't give any shit.
Speaker 1: Look at all the fucks he gives.
Speaker 0: I only give a fuck if either I have a vested interest in the company or I'm passionate about what the company does exactly.
Speaker 1: So we have this situation where most of these companies don't have rim as the number one They might have rim is number two or lower.
Speaker 0: But no matter because all or two quits that look at face the majority of these number one all the number twos quit.
Speaker 1: the majority of these number ones.
Speaker 1: just say yes to these advertisers and they're living off advertising money and They're just like whee who gives it.
Speaker 1: we're making money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, awesome.
Speaker 1: And they just basically what they're operating is not the company.
Speaker 1: They think they're operating.
Speaker 1: They're not operating newspaper.
Speaker 1: they're operating basically a. You know just a place for.
Speaker 1: you know ad inventory for this advertiser and Really the advertiser owns them not doesn't really own them on paper.
Speaker 0: But so it's got much like in the 1920s.
Speaker 0: the factory owner owns the worker, right?
Speaker 1: He the the advertiser de facto owns your company and that they can give you any order.
Speaker 1: They want to benefit their business and your choices are obey or be fucked.
Speaker 1: obey and the advertiser who's you know?
Speaker 1: Is taking no risk.
Speaker 1: the advertiser could start his own magazine if you wanted to like GameStop owns their own magazine, right?
Speaker 1: But then it's a risk because you're paying for this thing.
Speaker 1: Whereas, you know, there's no risk.
Speaker 1: It's like oh my god some ad inventory disappeared.
Speaker 1: There's other inventory.
Speaker 1: We'll just move that money elsewhere.
Speaker 1: Well, it's no we don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: So someone else lost their job.
Speaker 1: No one at our company got hurt at all by that newspaper going out of business.
Speaker 1: So they'll tell right so they'll tell all the newspapers Yeah, you know be great.
Speaker 1: if your newspaper was really just a thing to collect data for us That would be great.
Speaker 1: So two things.
Speaker 1: It's very simple.
Speaker 0: I have a sense of business ethics and would never ask Anyone who worked for me to do anything that I was morally opposed to know.
Speaker 1: you're asking some company that you deep some other company.
Speaker 0: You don't give a shit Oh and I don't play.
Speaker 0: not you realize how many times when Anyone in any industry asked me advice about things involving like two customers that have competing interests or anything like that My answer is always a fistful of dollars.
Speaker 0: And basically if someone gets the reference I usually know they're good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's that's an aside two rocks Throw rocks at both the customers.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway to move on so Kindle Amazon announced that the new Kindle fire was gonna have ads.
Speaker 0: you couldn't get rid of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah up until now you've been able to buy Kindles with or without ads and the idea was well This is the fire the tablet, right?
Speaker 1: But well you the regular Kindle.
Speaker 1: at least you could buy it without ads or you could buy it with ads and it would be.
Speaker 1: But then you could pay money to make the ads go away.
Speaker 0: now I bought my Kindle without ads because I also my mind without it.
Speaker 0: seriously.
Speaker 1: I Also don't.
Speaker 1: I've never bought a Kindle book 95 called.
Speaker 0: they want their free PC back.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's actually you know, there is a place for it right in that, you know.
Speaker 1: on the one hand You've got device, you know Someone wrote a thing on the internet a week or so ago a few days and it was like hey look I think was a guy writing on Google+ and he's like look Google they sell you this thing for cheap Because they want you to look at their ads.
Speaker 1: Amazon sells you this thing for cheap because they want you to buy Amazon products through it.
Speaker 1: It's a bait-and-switch.
Speaker 1: Apple is selling you the thing and what do they want to do?
Speaker 1: They want to sell you the thing Right.
Speaker 1: That's why the Apple thing is not a bait-and-switch.
Speaker 1: instead The Apple thing is a ridiculously high margin and cost us a million extra dollars.
Speaker 0: I just I have an ideological problem with this just in the sense that Every in all of history the moment you have hardware that has arbitrary software restrictions like this.
Speaker 0: What did everyone smart do who got one of those free ad PCs?
Speaker 0: No, they installed Linux on it or something.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: Oh, what about the people who got the piece that at the bar in the bottom?
Speaker 0: That would show you ads and you pay you like a penny a day to have those ads there and you'd have like a thousand Of those toolbars with a macro that moved your mouse around randomly.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the I did that for a while.
Speaker 0: I made like 10 bucks over the course of a year.
Speaker 1: great You could've just done virtual machines.
Speaker 0: No, I had an old 486 that we weren't using.
Speaker 0: so I installed this Virtual machines back then not like now.
Speaker 0: Yeah I just got this ad bar running as many times as I could and I had the windows macro thing that I copied from my Windows 3 1 1 and literally my mouse just went.
Speaker 0: I left it running for like weeks and weeks and weeks and weeks and weeks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I think there is this place probably only made a few dollars.
Speaker 1: He's sort of subsidized by bait-and-switch devices, you know Sell you a music player because I'm gonna for cheap cuz I'm gonna make money on the blades.
Speaker 0: I'm fine with that.
Speaker 1: I'm also fine with it.
Speaker 1: I don't like it as long as I will still buy your razor that needs blades as long as It operates without blades.
Speaker 1: I bought a Kindle.
Speaker 1: I paid for no ads, right?
Speaker 1: It was only slightly more expensive.
Speaker 1: and you know what?
Speaker 1: I've never bought a single Kindle book that has DRM.
Speaker 1: that was not free not ever not once You know.
Speaker 1: and it's like.
Speaker 1: it doesn't like magically turn off or anything.
Speaker 1: It doesn't not work.
Speaker 1: It's it's a device and it works as a device and I got it for cheap because someone else is subsidizing it by buying Kindle.
Speaker 0: That's at least an indirect Subsidization.
Speaker 1: it's not my problem and you know it.
Speaker 1: everyone can do it and then basically Amazon will be forced to either a realize Oh this Kindle is not working out for us and they'll stop making it or B. They'll go to the Apple.
Speaker 0: Here's why I was a little more Mad about this one in particular because one you couldn't turn it off.
Speaker 0: You couldn't turn it off.
Speaker 1: So basically don't buy that device.
Speaker 1: It wasn't.
Speaker 0: it wasn't a bait and switch It was just switch, but it was just here there ads on your thing Not just on the sleep screen, which isn't visible all the time But also at the lower right hand corner of your little desktop or whatever all the time.
Speaker 0: Oh, I thought it was just in the sleep Yeah, and they announced, you know, no opt-out and all that there was an internet shitstorm and within one day They retracted it and decided that you know what?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can opt-out for $15.
Speaker 0: What bothers me is what Bezos said about it?
Speaker 1: He said most people leave the ads.
Speaker 0: No I don't care about that because I know that Conrad said something that I do agree with.
Speaker 0: he pointed out that what Amazon is going after with this with these devices They're subsidized is the the recently emerged demographic that literally Does not care at all about privacy or advertising and will trade Anything anything they have.
Speaker 0: that is not physical property or money for content.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean look at you know, how many people at PAX are like desperate for swag.
Speaker 1: Oh my god free shit Exactly.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's free t-shirts.
Speaker 1: Oh my god some ugly ass t-shirt that I'd be embarrassed to wear except while sleeping and you're like fighting to get it.
Speaker 0: That is a Perfectly valid demographic to go after though.
Speaker 0: You could argue there are ethical considerations.
Speaker 1: Those are the only people advertising works on and so that's the only people you can get smart people gonna do it.
Speaker 0: Because this reminded me a little bit of Larry Ellison and his bullshit.
Speaker 0: for many years ago Jeff Bezos said and I quote we want to make money when people use our devices Not when they buy our devices.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I The I can't say, you know slippery slippers.
Speaker 0: all these arguments that are not really that solid about why that's bad.
Speaker 0: as a professional in the technology industry a large company whose goal is to Monetize hardware beyond selling the hardware through a means that isn't just selling you more software on top of it is As close to evil as I think you can get without being even
Speaker 1: well sort of right
Speaker 0: from the perspective.
Speaker 0: You know evil is a relative term of my own ideology as a technologist.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing that people have based, right?
Speaker 1: So it's if you look at video games, right?
Speaker 1: It's we started out with arcades and people loved arcades because you know that the arcade games are way better than home games.
Speaker 1: Also the social element and social element and you would go in and if you own the arcade People would just keep paying you money.
Speaker 1: So you bought this thing, but that thing paid out.
Speaker 1: You know, it just kept filling up with money all the time like woo It's a money machine, right and that's what you like to own and when your business is money machine.
Speaker 0: But then one guy was like wait a minute the crane game makes ten times the money compared to what I.
Speaker 1: well What happened is there's a console at home.
Speaker 1: people could get as good as arcade at home.
Speaker 0: I don't think that killed the arcade.
Speaker 1: No, but I mean, you know, the point is is that That that did not make anyone a money machine.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: we need no money machine?
Speaker 1: Yes, but it was.
Speaker 1: they kept.
Speaker 1: they need to kept working hard for you to make more stuff.
Speaker 1: They wouldn't just make money off of.
Speaker 0: that's what you're getting at.
Speaker 1: This is why this mother play Mario as much as you wanted from home.
Speaker 1: But now they've sort of got the best thing they've ever wanted.
Speaker 1: these businesses in the current time period well Basically installed an arcade machine in your house and all the quarters get teleported to their house and you actually paid to put the Machine there.
Speaker 1: it's like you pay them to install a. would you pay to have someone and put a laundry machine in your basement that you had to put quarters into and the Them if the laundry machine was half price again, that's fine.
Speaker 0: Here's where it bothers me the.
Speaker 0: we want to make money when people use it not just when they buy it.
Speaker 0: It's very close to where you want to make money when someone resells our book game movie Whatever not just when they buy it the first time.
Speaker 0: the erosion of first sale rights Well, that's you know.
Speaker 0: It'll know they're part and parcel because this statement and what they're doing It's the fact that I could buy a washing machine for a half price, but then the quarters go.
Speaker 0: that's fine.
Speaker 1: The problem lies if you sell that washing machine to me the quarters still go to that.
Speaker 0: first problem lies if I Cannot modify the machine to keep the quarters once I own hardware I think I have a unilateral right to whatever the fuck I want with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, obviously barring things like if I beat someone over the head with the Kindle until they die.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean, it wouldn't be illegal to hack your Kindle to remove.
Speaker 0: Yes, so it once we so what?
Speaker 0: TPA the Likes the.
Speaker 0: there has always been this huge push by large Industry to get it to the point where it they'd actually largely would like it to be a crime for you to circumvent Hardware restrictions and hardware you own for personal yet
Speaker 1: to keep the quarters that are in your laundry machine.
Speaker 0: So if I buy the Kindle with ads on it and I hack it to where the ads aren't there anymore Could that be a crime now?
Speaker 0: and more importantly would Amazon ever lobby to make that a crime?
Speaker 0: because There is that there is a perverse incentive to criminalize the use of your own hardware If the company has a vested interest in making money from the software running on the hardware.
Speaker 0: That is what I'm worried about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I think the real thing is that you know Even if they don't want to make it a crime, it's what I said before.
Speaker 1: is the situation where okay Look people are reselling things, right?
Speaker 1: But if we make money from people using the thing Then it doesn't matter if they we don't get any money on the resale in forms of a new sale Because the quarters still go to us.
Speaker 1: So if you we sell you a washing machine for half price we get all the quarters teleported.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if
Speaker 1: I buy the why you sell the washing machine to me, right now Normally, they would be pissed like because they didn't get another washing machine sale, you know They could have sold two washing machines a new one to you and a new one to me and they wanted you to throw that One out.
Speaker 1: but because you sold it to me they lost a sale.
Speaker 1: But now they've got two houses teleporting quarters to them.
Speaker 1: so but that's that's how they still make money.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 0: If I can just open up the machine and have the quarters bender back out on a string
Speaker 1: As soon as they criminalize the bender
Speaker 0: string
Speaker 1: well
Speaker 0: in my it's like if I bought a payphone And then it was a crime for me to take the quarters out of my own payphone,
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: But here's the other situation.
Speaker 1: right right now at least, you know hardware.
Speaker 1: when people sell you hardware You do own the hardware, but for example the laundry machines in my building take quarters.
Speaker 1: Do you think those quarters go to my landlord?
Speaker 1: I don't think they do.
Speaker 1: I think they go to some service company.
Speaker 1: He's got like a contract with that's fine.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: But it's like these.
Speaker 1: hardware that's in his building but some other guy owns and operates it.
Speaker 1: and soon what you're gonna see is You know if we sort of win the battle of owner decides it's gonna be the.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be like, okay We don't even own your fucking Kindle it's oh it's owned and operated by us is just in your house.
Speaker 0: Yes Now that is.
Speaker 0: that is where again where the perverse incentive comes in.
Speaker 0: if I can just cut that tether and get it and hack It to make it work.
Speaker 0: That should be okay.
Speaker 0: And if that's not okay, that's not okay.
Speaker 1: Well this Cory doctor actually had a pretty Recent speech about this talk he gave and what he talked about was how we keep fighting for basically the rights of the owner.
Speaker 1: Right, it's sort of obvious to us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whoever owns hardware Decides how it works right.
Speaker 1: and he talks about how like.
Speaker 1: well the company owns the computer at work.
Speaker 1: So they decide what goes on the computer at work.
Speaker 1: We'll lock that shit down, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and he talks about.
Speaker 0: so what about when someone else owns the hardware, right?
Speaker 1: He talked he basically talked about like well What if we got what we wanted?
Speaker 1: then what so if we got what we wanted?
Speaker 1: He's basically says we need rights of the user.
Speaker 1: Even if the user doesn't own the hardware know what we need.
Speaker 1: Well, that's nobody's buddy something much simpler than he says he doesn't know how you know.
Speaker 1: The solution to that would be he just shows all the problems that would happen.
Speaker 0: I think it's actually pretty simple.
Speaker 1: We got we wanted need.
Speaker 0: there are two examples.
Speaker 0: one.
Speaker 0: We have the nominal right of first sale.
Speaker 0: I think that needs to be expanded but you don't owe it.
Speaker 0: I can't resell Expanded such that if someone sells me a physical thing in certain circumstances Whatever regardless of any license they have if it is not a lease if it is a purchase There's got to be a way where I can find those.
Speaker 1: I start leasing technology.
Speaker 1: They won't.
Speaker 1: your cell phone company will just start leasing the phones out.
Speaker 1: There's loopholes all over the place.
Speaker 1: So you always do to me when I come with an idea?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so now you're leasing your cell phone.
Speaker 1: You can't buy it.
Speaker 1: They don't offer to sales of cell phones.
Speaker 0: So you could expand that further by having you could.
Speaker 0: you could try to argue that those lease contracts because there's no other option Are there for one-sided which are already not?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: How you gonna write this law?
Speaker 0: But Scott the problem is with any reform is you can't make any laws in the u.s.
Speaker 0: So it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, we talked about that for a while.
Speaker 1: Do we want to talk about anything else?
Speaker 0: Do one more really quick two quickies.
Speaker 0: so ie 10, of course, you know, there's that whole thing about the do not track bit, which I Feel like that sort of bit was a non-starter.
Speaker 1: well it's because nobody who is doing tracking wants to not track and basically this this method requires them to.
Speaker 0: Well the method if there were the thing is Theoretically not following it if it was well known and well communicated could constitute a breach of other rules.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they would need a law to force companies to do this.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I want to talk about the hissy fit that happened when Microsoft did what I think is the good thing and said You know what?
Speaker 0: We're gonna enable the do not track bit by default and the writing Microsoft do this.
Speaker 1: people are thinking why would Microsoft do a good Thing?
Speaker 1: it's obvious Microsoft is the one the browser owner.
Speaker 1: that isn't an advertising company, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so they want, you know, they don't want Google to make money by tracking.
Speaker 1: They want that stuff off by default, you know to be better for them.
Speaker 1: It's it's helping them.
Speaker 1: That's why they do not doing it because they're you know, not you can argue it was.
Speaker 0: it was a pseudo false flag operation.
Speaker 0: You can argue that they didn't want it to happen.
Speaker 0: So they did this knowing that everybody else would throw a hissy fit and the format would maybe the standard with us being validated Defecto.
Speaker 1: that's true.
Speaker 1: The other thing is you say why doesn't Mozilla do this, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz they Mozilla doesn't.
Speaker 0: so the argument why no one did it is that if it is opt-out of Tracking as opposed to opt-in the behavior is very different.
Speaker 0: if it is opt-out of tracking Then the majority of people won't bother to opt-out and no one goes to the options Yes, and check box, but if you set it to opt-in then nobody's gonna say yes track me, right?
Speaker 0: So that everyone evil and everyone who's just greedy Needs it to be no opt-out.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying is that the reason Microsoft did it is because they don't make money from advertising so this can make them look Good, you know to disable it by default.
Speaker 1: now Why doesn't Mozilla who is open source and awesome got their argument Mozilla's argument?
Speaker 0: And everyone's argument was that if it's opt-out No, Mozilla doesn't care about.
Speaker 1: you know, Mozilla doesn't want people to be tracked.
Speaker 1: I know the reason that they left it as opt-out of tracking instead of opt-in to tracking like Microsoft did is because number one open the open-source Mozilla type.
Speaker 1: people are obsessive about standards and adhering to them.
Speaker 0: I don't do it and I was gonna say a lot of Mozilla's moneys come from Google but also the standard.
Speaker 0: everyone argued that if any major browser made it to where it was on by default that everyone would ignore it and They might have justification in doing so and it would make it thus useless.
Speaker 0: It would be about as effective as what.
Speaker 0: the comparison everyone makes is that it would just be the opposite of the evil bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, you know about the evil bit.
Speaker 0: That's like if you go read that RFC.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like it's really.
Speaker 1: the whole idea was kind of dumb.
Speaker 1: I mean the idea is basically Alright everyone, we're gonna leave our bikes in the street unlocked But nobody's allowed to not steal bit that we gonna put it any.
Speaker 1: anyone who puts a little sticker on their bike.
Speaker 1: This is do not steal.
Speaker 1: You're not allowed to steal those ones.
Speaker 0: You know, what'd be interesting if we did that?
Speaker 0: it's like by If you stole a bike that had that sticker.
Speaker 0: Felony life sentence.
Speaker 0: right bike doesn't have a sticker.
Speaker 0: $10 fine Of course.
Speaker 1: Microsoft the company that makes their money selling new bikes and not stolen bikes is like or stealing bikes is like yeah Free do not steal stickers on all our bikes.
Speaker 1: You don't have to buy the do not steal sticker.
Speaker 0: So anyway there this issue or even apply it yourself.
Speaker 0: I want to talk about how the guy Who I think wrote the standard for do not track is Super pissed and through a hissy fit that Microsoft said it to be enabled by default.
Speaker 1: and I Looked he probably loves tracking and was just trying to sort of be nice.
Speaker 1: but still they you know.
Speaker 1: So he was probably thinking hey, you know tracking is totally awesome.
Speaker 1: I make mad money on this but you know There's obviously some people who really want to turn it off.
Speaker 1: I can look like a really good guy if I let them opt out and the people who are blocking ever all the ads anyway.
Speaker 0: So he put it.
Speaker 0: he submitted a patch to Apache.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at the actual text of the patch right here and the first thing in it is a comment that says Deal with user user agents that deliberately violate open standards, right?
Speaker 0: And then he's like.
Speaker 1: that makes it sound like maybe he's one of those standards nuts Which is you must follow the standard no matter what it is.
Speaker 0: And then it's like if it's ie 10 bad do not track unset do not track Yeah, so basically track everyone with ie 10 whether they want.
Speaker 0: the comments on this patch are That's.
Speaker 0: There's a funny image in the comments.
Speaker 0: you just go look at the comments and look at the image there.
Speaker 0: it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: whatever It's a dumb idea.
Speaker 1: They should just Frickin, you know have an ad block for the tracking.
Speaker 1: that you know, that's the best method.
Speaker 0: is that's what I was gonna say.
Speaker 0: It's you know get standards.
Speaker 0: The real answer is The internet is in for well the web not the internet.
Speaker 0: the web is.
Speaker 0: you seek out information It's given to you in an abstract format and you format it and display it.
Speaker 0: However, you like So I just don't display things I don't want to see it I don't give out information I don't want to.
Speaker 1: yeah, I send some bits to a web web server.
Speaker 1: It sends me back some bits and then I can do whatever I want with those bits.
Speaker 0: It just so happens that no no But Ted Turner says you're stealing.
Speaker 1: if you do that web browsers will will are Programmed to do certain things with those bits by default.
Speaker 1: So we just have to modify the web browsers to do the things with the bits they get.
Speaker 1: Be what we want them to do with them.
Speaker 1: The user wants to do with them and not what the person who sends you the bits wants you to do with them.
Speaker 1: You know if I it's like the New York Times is like sending you newspaper and forcing you You know to read it one page at a time because they it's like no no No, I you send me the pile of paper and I decide I'm only gonna read the sports section.
Speaker 1: You can't make me do anything else.
Speaker 0: So I feel like we're blowing a big load here because we you know There's not a lot of geek nights around this season.
Speaker 0: I got one more that I just found really fascinating.
Speaker 0: I was tweeting about it.
Speaker 0: This is bad.
Speaker 0: away from technology into science.
Speaker 0: So there's a study in psychological science.
Speaker 0: It was a reason like a university study and it's pretty solid in terms of the methodology as far as I can tell Based on reading other people's commentary of it.
Speaker 0: basically, they were looking for correlations between Certain sorts of conspiracy theories and other kinds of ideologies to see like if there are clusters of crazy It's like, you know, I'm sure that like they could find Bigfoot people probably also believe in chupacabras, right?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: What was the South Park?
Speaker 0: They're like if you believe in Bigfoot You're either evil or stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah But basically they found a really strong and interesting correlation that I think is worth noting.
Speaker 0: So people who what's the exact word?
Speaker 0: people who believe in a quote free market?
Speaker 0: ideology, okay are very much more likely statistically to deny the relationship between HIV and AIDS to deny that there is Climate change and that humans may be causing it and to deny that smoking is correlated with lung cancer.
Speaker 0: Okay But specifically that's the thing free market ideology.
Speaker 1: Are these people who said that?
Speaker 1: did they check to see what the people's ideologies were and then?
Speaker 1: Categorize them as free market.
Speaker 0: No, they asked direct question.
Speaker 1: Do you believe in a free market ideology?
Speaker 0: direct questions?
Speaker 0: They asked about things like what you know Is it was?
Speaker 0: is the story on Princess Diana's death plausible or was she assessed?
Speaker 1: Specifically the free market?
Speaker 1: one right because you could ask someone like no they Do.
Speaker 1: you is do you believe in you know free market idea that that's actually different than checking to see No What the person's actual ideology course is?
Speaker 0: look at all the studies that show that the majority of Americans are Super for every piece of Obamacare, but against Obamacare.
Speaker 0: the title exactly?
Speaker 0: Yeah, no This is.
Speaker 0: people who say they believe in a free market ideology also say they believe in all this crazy bullshit Mm-hmm, and I found that fascinating that the statistical correlation with those things was less than for example People who don't believe in the moon landing or other craziness believing in similar crazy things.
Speaker 1: So conspiracy people This is not really a revelation that crazy someone who's crazy is likely to be crazy.
Speaker 0: No But here's the thing.
Speaker 0: and then people who are crazy in certain ways are pigeonholed in just those ways like the guy Who is.
Speaker 0: you know, Princess Diana was assassinated is not also lizard people or HIV AIDS.
Speaker 1: But the guys also know that guy is probably mostly focusing on political Conspiracies like JFK who shot him and all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's not focusing on Bigfoot.
Speaker 0: He doesn't believe in Bigfoot.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: he believes in government conspiracy.
Speaker 0: from these abstracts one of the strongest correlations between Anti-science was with people who are free market ideologists and not anything else.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm The primary driver of believing in a scientific theory is Little more than consensus among scientists.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which that's?
Speaker 0: yeah, that's the best I can do.
Speaker 0: That's me.
Speaker 1: What do you want me to do?
Speaker 1: research all the things myself?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I can't even read one paper and understand what it's saying.
Speaker 0: Read this full paper, but I can read these abstracts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, I can.
Speaker 1: you know, I can whatever.
Speaker 0: I just found it really interesting.
Speaker 0: So yeah, geek nights.
Speaker 0: We're back off and on off.
Speaker 0: mostly This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and my comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.