Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, February 15th, 2012.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym, and this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we bring you the stunning conclusion of our reviews of every single one of the DC new 52.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So All-Star Western 1, basically Batman.
Speaker 1: Uh, well, let me give you a little information here, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know, you get this Jonah Hex situation going on, right?
Speaker 1: And I was reading the Jonah Hex.
Speaker 1: Did we do an episode on it at some point?
Speaker 1: I don't know if we did or not.
Speaker 1: But basically, this is written by, it's got Jonah Hex in it, at least half of it, right?
Speaker 1: And it's written by the same guys, the same team that did that Jonah Hex.
Speaker 1: that's been going on for a while.
Speaker 1: So here you go, it's basically the continuation of Jonah Hex, which has always been sort of episodic and such, so that's kind of nice.
Speaker 0: I actually surprisingly enjoyed seeing, like, you know, cowboy time era Gotham.
Speaker 0: Like, I like that whole aspect of, like, you know, seeing the old families and all this stuff kind of together.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, the actual plot, as was revealed, was a little too forced and cliche.
Speaker 0: Moved a little too quickly, I think.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing I wrote, here's my three notes that I wrote, right?
Speaker 1: First of all, I agreed with you entirely, you know, Jonah Hex that I read in those Jonah Hex books was a different character.
Speaker 1: Even though this Jonah Hex, it's the same person on paper.
Speaker 0: He is way too not an asshole.
Speaker 1: I wrote, Jonah Hex is basically just old-timey Batman here.
Speaker 0: Yup, that's what I was saying, this was Batman.
Speaker 1: Number two, I think the doctor did it.
Speaker 1: And number three, this is a mystery, not a Western.
Speaker 1: Even though it takes place in Western times and is drawn like a Western, and everything looks Western, this is a mystery story.
Speaker 1: You know, the same way the Star Trek is not sci-fi as a soap opera.
Speaker 0: Mystery story, so two counts of Batman.
Speaker 1: Right, exactly.
Speaker 0: And it's in Gotham.
Speaker 1: And that's the thing though, the Batman comics weren't actually mysteries.
Speaker 1: Detective Comics wasn't a detective story.
Speaker 1: But All-Star Western isn't a Western, it's the mystery the Detective Comics should have been.
Speaker 1: So does this mean that I have to read All-Star Horror to get the Western story?
Speaker 0: No, that would be a comedy.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it wasn't a bad mystery, I guess.
Speaker 1: I also, you know.
Speaker 0: I kind of liked it, it was a high meh.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It just, that wasn't Jonah Hex.
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't.
Speaker 0: Jonah Hex would not have suffered most of those people to live.
Speaker 1: You know, this is the thing, I've mentioned it a hundred times, hopefully this will be the last time I mention it.
Speaker 1: But it's like, you have a character, a character has a personality, there's something about that character, right?
Speaker 1: And I mean, you know, it's like, what's Mario like?
Speaker 1: You know, if I say, if I mention Mario, you know what Mario is like.
Speaker 0: He's a fat plumber named Lou Albano.
Speaker 1: Right, I could make a story, draw Mario in it, call him Mario, but he could act like, you know, a princess instead of being the plumber.
Speaker 1: And he could be like, you know, "Oh, save
Speaker 1: me.".
Speaker 1: "It's a pretty, pretty
Speaker 1: princess.".
Speaker 1: He wouldn't even have the accent, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like, well, you drew Mario and you called him Mario, but that's not Mario.
Speaker 1: And that's what goes on in these DC Comics, is they draw a character.
Speaker 1: Well, Batman is the worst example.
Speaker 1: It looks like the character, they name it.
Speaker 1: that character, doesn't act like that character, acts like someone else in every different book.
Speaker 0: The Batman in Justice League isn't, he's nothing like any other Batman anywhere.
Speaker 1: Justice League International.
Speaker 1: Batman is the Super Friends Batman, right?
Speaker 0: That Batman was the same, I don't even want to, we already talked about how bad that was.
Speaker 0: Alright, so let's move on.
Speaker 0: I liked Aquaman, I was surprised.
Speaker 1: Aquaman, I was going into this and I was saying, "Well, it's Aquaman.
Speaker 1: Everyone makes fun of
Speaker 1: Aquaman.".
Speaker 1: It's written by Geoff Johns, the guy we hate, who wrote the Green Lantern Rebirth, who, you know, does all the most fanboyish stuff.
Speaker 1: But you read this and you're like, okay, how is, you know, everyone, people have tried to do Aquaman for years and everyone has failed.
Speaker 1: What is this guy going to do to do Aquaman?
Speaker 1: He's starting fresh.
Speaker 0: Well, let's see, the plot involves the ocean.
Speaker 1: It does, that's good.
Speaker 1: That's a good start.
Speaker 1: Keeping Aquaman in the ocean, not in the Justice League satellite dish, whatever.
Speaker 0: And he's got a personality.
Speaker 1: He does, and I don't know what Aquaman's personality is.
Speaker 1: I'm willing to bet that this is not the personality Aquaman has had in the past.
Speaker 1: But I like this one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've seen pictures of like old Aquaman, like bearded Aquaman and all sorts of, right?
Speaker 1: Pretty sure this is not anything like those ones, but maybe that's good because those other Aquamans sucked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well like, Scott, while the Jonah Hex in All Star Western was not a real Jonah Hex, that's the one I'd rather hang out with in a bar if I had to choose.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: This Aquaman is kind of an awesome dude.
Speaker 0: Because he's kind of a dick.
Speaker 1: He's sort of Rainbow Dash-ish.
Speaker 0: Isn't that what we also liked about Superman in Action Comics 1?
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: It's sort of the same kind of guy.
Speaker 0: A little bit of Rainbow Dash, a little bit of Astro Boy, all mixed into one.
Speaker 1: And then he was pretty awesome when he just gives the waitress the two undersea golden coins.
Speaker 0: She's like, "What the fuck am I supposed to do with
Speaker 0: this?".
Speaker 0: He's like, "Send your kids to
Speaker 0: college?".
Speaker 1: Yeah, and she's just like, "Holy shit, fucking Aquaman's got-".
Speaker 0: I love how they go right in and have the nerd be like, "How's it feel to be everyone's least favorite
Speaker 0: superhero?".
Speaker 0: And how Aquaman just punks the kid.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I like this one.
Speaker 0: I want to read the trade when it comes out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I actually realized that, but it is good.
Speaker 1: It's like the exact opposite.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I bet the fanboys probably hated this Aquaman.
Speaker 0: They had to have.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: I think it's just something about jerk characters that I just personally like.
Speaker 0: It has to be a certain kind of jerk, though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that certain kind of jerk.
Speaker 1: I like it no matter what.
Speaker 1: Who knows if this is actually good, but it's Scott Rubin's alley.
Speaker 0: Speaking of Batman, there's another Batman here.
Speaker 1: How many Batmans are there going to be?
Speaker 0: I forget which one this is.
Speaker 1: This is Batman colon The Dark Knight.
Speaker 0: Was this the one with the Joker cutting his face off?
Speaker 1: No, that was Detective Comics, right?
Speaker 0: Oh my god, I don't even remember then.
Speaker 0: Which one was this?
Speaker 0: What happens?
Speaker 1: I barely remember.
Speaker 1: Let me look at my notes about it.
Speaker 0: My note just says, "It's
Speaker 0: Batman.".
Speaker 0: I didn't write anything else.
Speaker 1: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: This is the one with one face.
Speaker 0: Oh, all right.
Speaker 0: I remember.
Speaker 0: This one had way too much supervillain bullshit.
Speaker 0: And it felt way more like superhero.
Speaker 0: supervillain and way less.
Speaker 0: Batman is just a person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my notes were not even one clever thing.
Speaker 1: I don't know what that was meaning.
Speaker 1: All over the place.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the plot didn't make any sense.
Speaker 1: Here's the other thing.
Speaker 1: I wrote that it wasn't related to the other Batman books at all, which is good and bad, right?
Speaker 1: It's good on the one hand that, well, you can read it on its own, but it's sort of bad in that, you know, it's like they set the expectation that there's some mixing with the other books, and then when one of the books doesn't mix, it's like, well, now this one doesn't even fit.
Speaker 1: More importantly, why are you-- Like the one where Batman showed up in Africa.
Speaker 1: It doesn't fit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because if you're throwing, if you've got three straight up Batman comics, and they're all different, and they don't line up, and they're all kind of uninspired, the fact that I couldn't remember which one was which actually is very telling in my opinion.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was able to remember that Aquaman was an awesome jerk.
Speaker 0: And I like detective comics the most of the Batman.
Speaker 1: This one was sort of structured, though, as sort of the same way as like the start of a Batman movie, where you have the Bruce Wayne part where he's getting all business-y.
Speaker 0: But I hate the Batman movies.
Speaker 1: And then you'll have that, you know, Batman fights all the villains part after that, right?
Speaker 1: And that was sort of the way it went.
Speaker 0: I hate Batman fighting a villain, like, straight up.
Speaker 0: I like all the other stuff about Batman.
Speaker 0: The villain part is just the vehicle for my Batman enjoyment.
Speaker 0: If you actually think I care about the villain part, then you don't understand why I like Batman.
Speaker 1: Well, if you like those Batman video games, you probably love this, because he just walks around punching and kicking all the bad guys in Arkham.
Speaker 1: So yeah.
Speaker 1: So Black Hawks-- I put that as bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I put it as bad, too.
Speaker 0: Well, I didn't put it as bad, but since I don't remember it, it had to have been bad.
Speaker 0: So, Black Hawks, I have one note.
Speaker 0: Why is the logo of their secret organization on the side of their--.
Speaker 1: Are you reading my fucking notes?
Speaker 0: Because the fact that it was there didn't bother me.
Speaker 0: The fact that a guy took a picture of it was funny.
Speaker 0: The fact that that is the plot is crazy bullshit.
Speaker 1: You don't see the fucking Navy Seals walking around with the word Navy Seals on the side of a truck driving around the city.
Speaker 0: And if the Black Hawks are this crazy, ultra-elite organization, seriously, that's your plot?
Speaker 1: They have a logo that everyone knows that they slap all over their bodies and all over everything they own, and it's bright yellow and everyone can see it.
Speaker 1: That pissed me off enough to hate it already, but the whole-- Also, this is yet another-- I should count how many of these books were secret government or corporate organization with an acronym sort of-ish name, goes and fights some generic terrorist group of some kind.
Speaker 0: But also, way too much-- It was very clumsily.
Speaker 0: The whole thing about she was bitten and the nanocytes were in her was so clumsily set up that I actually didn't expect it because it seemed too obvious and cliche.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I think that there's some-- I get the feeling that someone's done some sort of focus group study that's like, "Well, if we add a sidekick, then the sales go
Speaker 1: up.".
Speaker 1: Is that information they use?
Speaker 1: And someone figured out, "Well, books about paramilitary organizations fighting bad guys in such and such a format get great ratings, so let's make seven comics about that and ten TV
Speaker 1: shows.".
Speaker 0: Well, Scott, what is Ghost in the Shell's stand-alone complex, but a paramilitary organization fighting bad guys with awesome technology and equipment secretly funded by the government with acronyms?
Speaker 1: That's correct, but they add an extra layer on top of that, which is it's actually procedural police-detectiving, sort of.
Speaker 0: Except it isn't because they replace all the procedural police stuff with proper-known gobbledygook bullshit.
Speaker 1: It's also actually real sci-fi.
Speaker 1: At least Ghost in the Shell is actually real sci-fi.
Speaker 1: Reels, like, you know, for serious.
Speaker 1: But this, at least, is not.
Speaker 1: This is just government organization fighting some guys.
Speaker 0: Had it not been so clumsily done and had the picture of their logo not been the plot, then I would have said, "Meh, but I have to say bad because I really didn't like
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, the thing-- whatever.
Speaker 1: I actually like some of the equipment they had because you see all these people get special equipment.
Speaker 1: This guy's got really cool sunglasses.
Speaker 1: I kind of want those.
Speaker 0: They're not as good as the Deus Ex sunglasses.
Speaker 0: Those are the best sunglasses ever.
Speaker 1: Black Hawks, I put bad.
Speaker 1: So The Flash-- He's the fastest dude.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm surprised that I needed to know more about The Flash than I did.
Speaker 0: Either that or it just was a poorly told story.
Speaker 1: First of all, The Flash is one of the main dudes, right?
Speaker 1: And I was actually surprised.
Speaker 1: The Flash was not in any of the other 51 books.
Speaker 1: He was only in this one, so good job on that.
Speaker 1: Two, I actually kind of like these arts.
Speaker 0: I also like the art.
Speaker 1: The sort of faded-out, grayish look with almost-- I don't know if that's sort of water-color-y-ish.
Speaker 1: I don't know much about arts, but I sort of liked--.
Speaker 1: It was pleasant to look at because the contrast wasn't so high, but it was still colorful, and I don't know if it was accidental, but I hope it wasn't because it was pretty cool.
Speaker 1: But here's the thing that really bothered me, which I've mentioned sort of already, which is how come the bad guys even have time to say anything, right?
Speaker 1: It's The Flash.
Speaker 1: The bad guys wouldn't even be able to say one word, and then The Flash just-- even if he was going to stop and take care of them, they would just be knocked out instantly.
Speaker 1: You just punch them in the face really fast, and they don't talk, ever.
Speaker 1: So how come the scenes where The Flash is talking with a guy and sort of fighting with him?
Speaker 1: Those scenes cannot happen.
Speaker 1: He's The Flash.
Speaker 1: He's so fast, you would not see him.
Speaker 1: The bad guy would not even be able to see him to start a fight with him.
Speaker 1: It would just be over before the bad guy even knew The Flash was there.
Speaker 0: Also, every time The Flash needs to appear, he runs away at his slow-ass speed and then turns to The Flash and comes back.
Speaker 0: No one notices.
Speaker 0: That's even worse than Superman.
Speaker 1: That's even worse than Superman in the phone booth, whatever.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's The Flash.
Speaker 1: I also wrote Jin Ro armor.
Speaker 1: Was there Jin Ro armor in here for some reason?
Speaker 1: I'm trying to find it.
Speaker 1: Maybe that was it.
Speaker 1: I wrote it under the wrong--.
Speaker 1: Did I write it under the wrong comic?
Speaker 0: I wrote Jin Ro-- Yeah, the soldiers that he was fighting in the beginning.
Speaker 0: He killed the guy by throwing him into the wall or into the building, and then the guy ended up being a clone of his old friend, and there's a million of them, and I didn't care anymore.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, right in the beginning, all these dudes are wearing sort of Jin Ro-ish armor.
Speaker 1: I really like this page, though, the title page.
Speaker 1: It's like, man, The Arts is really good on that shit.
Speaker 0: Honestly, the only thing I didn't like about it was that the story seemed really kind of boring.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I was doing a story about The Flash, I would make it all about The Flash having all these mental problems, because he just goes so fast and he sees so many things, and his brain isn't any better, right?
Speaker 0: Maybe it is faster.
Speaker 0: We don't know.
Speaker 1: So it's just like he's traveling all around the world, and he gets disoriented and sort of fucked up, and he could even be leading five lives simultaneously, but he could run back and forth between the different lives so quickly that it's instantaneous, that if you were having a conversation with one of them, you wouldn't even notice that he was leaving, because he'd be there for one fifth of every nanosecond.
Speaker 1: I would do shit like that and make it some crazy story.
Speaker 0: Well, The Flash runs into the problem of his powers such that you have to be really clever or really narrow path to make any challenge that would fit, that he wouldn't just solve immediately.
Speaker 1: Alright, so Firestorm, well, the fury of Firestorm, the nuclear man.
Speaker 0: I didn't get that it was only two guys, not three, and that it was the two combined into one until I read Wikipedia, because I couldn't figure out what was going on.
Speaker 1: I only knew it because I had heard about Firestorm in the past from other people.
Speaker 1: I knew that it was two guys.
Speaker 0: It didn't make sense.
Speaker 0: I read Wikipedia, now it makes sense.
Speaker 0: This was just awful.
Speaker 1: It was awful.
Speaker 0: It was like everything I hate about comics condensed.
Speaker 0: With forced high school drama, and then obviously the two- All the fake sciency talk as usual.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what else is there to say?
Speaker 0: And how did that girl survive, get the blow up?
Speaker 0: I didn't care.
Speaker 0: It was terrible.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like it could be the key to all human knowledge, really.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's what Firestorm is dealing with, the key to all human knowledge.
Speaker 1: What's Superman dealing with, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, really?
Speaker 1: There's something that's dealing with the key to all human knowledge.
Speaker 1: Is that important, and Firestorm is the guy who's dealing with that?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Not the Justice League, not the Green Lanterns, not someone more important.
Speaker 0: So- Yeah.
Speaker 1: I put bad.
Speaker 0: So Green Lantern- New Guardians.
Speaker 1: So these are like young Green Lanterns, I guess, right?
Speaker 1: Something like that?
Speaker 1: They're new Green Lanterns, they're not the other ones?
Speaker 0: I thought this was the one where all the rings disappear.
Speaker 0: That was the previous one, wasn't it?
Speaker 0: Green Lantern Corps.
Speaker 0: See, I mix them all up again because I didn't like any of them.
Speaker 1: No, this is the one where all the rings fly away.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's the one I thought we were talking about with Green Lantern Corps.
Speaker 1: No, this is the one where the rings fly away.
Speaker 0: Oh, Green Lantern Corps, I remember which one that was.
Speaker 0: I didn't like it either, but for different reasons.
Speaker 0: This is the one that didn't make sense because all the colors, how would you know?
Speaker 0: What can I say?
Speaker 0: It was terrible.
Speaker 0: Unless you really like Green Lantern and you know all about it.
Speaker 1: All right, so I wrote cute elder guy because of this panel.
Speaker 1: The guy's got the eyeball.
Speaker 0: He's got a good look.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's got this look.
Speaker 1: I also wrote Mary Sue because this character is a comic artist in the comic book.
Speaker 0: So also, how come the pink lanterns, I guess, are all girls?
Speaker 0: Like, why?
Speaker 1: Hot ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why?
Speaker 1: In space.
Speaker 1: And then, here's the other thing.
Speaker 1: This one, more so than any of the other books I've read, right?
Speaker 1: We've read all 52 of them.
Speaker 1: More so than any of them, this felt like pretty much a direct continuation of a previous book.
Speaker 1: It's like some of the other ones, they sort of started...
Speaker 0: Oh, because Red Lanterns had some of the characters in it, too.
Speaker 1: Right, but it's like some of the other ones, they tried to start fresh and they brought a few things in that were obviously you had to know.
Speaker 1: This felt like they weren't even trying to start fresh.
Speaker 1: It was just direct continuation of something that already happened without starting any newness whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like season two.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and whatever.
Speaker 0: Every Green Lantern was bad, in my opinion.
Speaker 1: And then it's sort of like this rings all flying away thing.
Speaker 1: was just this excuse to get these bunch of different lanterns all in the same place for no reason.
Speaker 0: And I gotta admit, in all media, I no longer...
Speaker 1: That's worse than the D&D using an "in" to get the characters together.
Speaker 0: I no longer ever want to see a plot that ends with a big misunderstanding that a bunch of people just have to stop and talk about because I hate watching that.
Speaker 0: I hate seeing it.
Speaker 0: I hate anticipating it.
Speaker 0: One of the best things you can do to get me interested in media is to set that up and then not do it.
Speaker 0: Like, uh, not to bring up ponies, that episode with Rarity and Canterlot.
Speaker 1: I'll use a non-pony example.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Is Kentro meets, uh, what's-his-face, the blind guy.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: And he thinks he's a bad guy, and so Kentro has a misunderstanding and he's sort of fighting him, but then Kentro realizes the guy isn't fighting to kill.
Speaker 1: And he's like, "Oh, you're actually a good
Speaker 1: guy.".
Speaker 0: They didn't make it this long, drawn-out...
Speaker 1: They didn't make it this long, drawn-out thing of, "I must fight you.
Speaker 0: Oh, you were good guys the whole
Speaker 0: time.".
Speaker 0: You know what it is?
Speaker 0: If I, as the viewer, figure it out, and the characters don't figure it out for the majority of a scene or show, then I really get pissed off.
Speaker 1: If it's obvious.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so yeah, bad.
Speaker 1: So... I, Vampire.
Speaker 0: I, Vampire.
Speaker 0: I'm assuming that these characters have all this history that I don't know about.
Speaker 1: Something like that.
Speaker 0: As far as I can tell, the plot is weepy.
Speaker 0: vampire wants to kill all humans.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, the art, I gotta give the art credit for being different from other art, but...
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it reminded me so much of every White Wolf story ever.
Speaker 1: I did not like this art, though, even though, like, I give them credit for being different from the other superhero comics, but I is not a fan.
Speaker 1: Pretty much everything was two colors.
Speaker 1: Gray and different gray and black, and that's it.
Speaker 0: And, I don't know, the plot was just like some White Wolf.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that's the plot of whoever these characters are.
Speaker 0: I don't know their names.
Speaker 0: I haven't even read this.
Speaker 1: Also, dude, vampires, you know, this is in the DC Universe, right?
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 0: I guess.
Speaker 1: There's no way any vampire, even Dracula, is gonna do anything in a universe...
Speaker 0: With Superman, the Green Lanterns...
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: If there's actually vampires and they're actually trying to bite everyone, like I said...
Speaker 0: What about Frankenstein, Agent of Shade, though?
Speaker 1: Superman would just punch them all in the head, and that would be it.
Speaker 1: And, you know, you toss vampires into the vacuum of space...
Speaker 0: Well, speaking of which, 'cause you know what?
Speaker 0: I think we can just say bad and move on, because Justice League Dark had the same problem.
Speaker 0: But they got around it by saying that magic is more...
Speaker 1: Well, first, did you put I, vampires... Bad.
Speaker 1: Bad?
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So, I didn't think it was 100% bad.
Speaker 1: I gave it points for doing different arts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I just didn't like the story.
Speaker 1: So, Justice League Dark, right?
Speaker 1: So, what you got here is they've actually taken a bunch of characters from Vertigo Comics, right?
Speaker 1: So, you got, you know, like Madame Xanadu's in here, right?
Speaker 0: I don't know who any of those characters are.
Speaker 1: John Constantine, I think, is in here.
Speaker 0: Other than him, because there was a movie.
Speaker 1: Right, I think.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's in there.
Speaker 1: He's in there, right?
Speaker 1: So, it's like, oh, they sort of brought in these magical characters all together to make sort of a magic wizardy, you know, dark wizard Justice League.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but... One...
Speaker 1: The art is kind of colorful and nice.
Speaker 0: The fact that they had to do this whole thing of showing you, look, Superman can't deal with this.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They almost died.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's the typical thing where it's like, oh, there's something that only magicians can handle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or the Green Lantern Corps, I guess, to come down and fix this.
Speaker 1: That's for sure.
Speaker 0: But two, what bothered me is that they had, like, all these paranormal events all happening at the same time.
Speaker 0: One, they all, I guess, are caused by this witch in the envelope.
Speaker 0: And two, they really had too many of those things.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: They listed, they went through so many, like, a cow gave birth to a meat slicing machine.
Speaker 0: One of the farmers who saw it shot himself.
Speaker 0: There's, like, ten of those.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also, why did the real superhero show up?
Speaker 1: It's like, ugh, really?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, you gotta bring the regular Justice League into Justice League.
Speaker 0: They're torn apart by those teeth, and they cut away, and then all you get is one- That was actually very Madoka-esque witch kind of scene.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 1: But, you know, it didn't make the story any better.
Speaker 0: But then you get this one line or later where someone's like, yeah, Superman and them almost didn't survive.
Speaker 0: And that's it.
Speaker 0: That's all you get.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Also, I was disappointed yet again.
Speaker 1: Every time I see Superman, I'm looking for- Action Comics Superman.
Speaker 1: The Action Comics Jumping Superman, and you're getting the Flying Superman.
Speaker 1: I'm like, ah.
Speaker 0: But this- even calling it Justice League Dark.
Speaker 0: I mean, really?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You're calling it that?
Speaker 0: It's like, I'm doing Green Arrow and Green Arrow Dark.
Speaker 1: It's like- It's gonna be the same, but all, like- Why couldn't you just call it, like, you know, magic something something.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Come up with a new name for it.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It just, it was, it seemed so forced and simultaneously kind of bad.
Speaker 1: What are you, a Mayor bad?
Speaker 1: I'm giving it bad.
Speaker 1: I give it low med.
Speaker 0: I don't know who any of those characters are, for one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess because I knew some of them.
Speaker 1: That's sort of, you know, and the art was so good.
Speaker 0: The supernatural aspect was so forced.
Speaker 0: It was super forced.
Speaker 0: Am I supposed to know who that witch is?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, alright.
Speaker 0: It doesn't tell you who it is.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: So thanks, comic book.
Speaker 0: Thanks for giving me nothing.
Speaker 1: Alright, so.
Speaker 1: Savage Hawkman.
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: I've seen- Why is this a comic?
Speaker 1: Well, like, I don't know what the deal is with Hawkman.
Speaker 0: Like, I see Hawkman all over the place.
Speaker 0: Is Savage Hawkman different from Hawkman?
Speaker 1: No, he's just, it's the Hawkman.
Speaker 0: This already started with him, you know, like, throwing away the Hawkman suit that I guess was his.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like, I don't get Hawkman.
Speaker 1: He's a dude who has a weird suit with wings and a mace.
Speaker 0: No, it's made out of the, it's made out of the oomph metal.
Speaker 1: But isn't he, like, an alien or something, Hawkman?
Speaker 0: No, the metal is alien.
Speaker 0: The oomph metal.
Speaker 1: So Hawkman's a regular dude.
Speaker 0: He's a regular dude, as far as I can guess.
Speaker 1: I thought he was this thing, I thought he was from some other planet, like.
Speaker 0: So Scott, I am basing all of my cosmology of the Savage Hawkman on this one comic I read.
Speaker 0: And in this comic, there is a man, normal dude, who was the Hawkman because he had a suit made out of the oomph metal, and when he burned the oomph metal suit, it exploded and turned him again into the Hawkman.
Speaker 1: So the art, at least in the beginning part, was way awesome, especially the dude being set on fire.
Speaker 1: Oh, the art was great.
Speaker 1: Oh man, that was, it was just, like, a lot of these books, it's like, wow, they actually brought out some pretty good artists.
Speaker 1: I wonder if the fanboys like these arts as much as I like them.
Speaker 1: Here's another question.
Speaker 1: So there's this archaeologist going on here, right, and they're trying to dig up some alien shit.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Why are there archaeologists in a world with Superman who can x-ray vision the whole world and can just fly out into outer space and find out anything you have to know about alien history?
Speaker 0: Why, yeah.
Speaker 1: Archaeology is completely unnecessary in a world with superheroes who can go into space and fly faster than the speed of light.
Speaker 0: In a world where there is also a long history of epic space battles, I mean, we know from the one of the Green Lanterns, no, not from Green Lantern, from Blue Beetle, that when the Mayans were around, that one Green Lantern guy was out there doing the Green Lantern bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the point is, archaeology is obsolete in a world of superheroes.
Speaker 0: No, you have archaeological experts who tell the superheroes what to do.
Speaker 1: You just know, you just have superheroes who have already done all the archaeology in about two days, and then the other guys would just be studying all the stuff that was 100% dug up and discovered.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that aside, I don't have any motivation to care about the Hawkman, and because, clearly, the comic book decided that it didn't need to tell me anything that was going on, I had no idea what was going on.
Speaker 1: This also reminded me of Independence Day, where they got that cocoon there, and it's sort of like the peace, no peace kind of situation.
Speaker 0: Is this class bulletproof?
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is- See that college humor, where the guy's like, "Yes, it is," and then they shoot anyway, and then they get hit with a ricochet.
Speaker 0: He's like, "What the fuck?
Speaker 0: I said it was
Speaker 0: bulletproof!".
Speaker 1: Bulletproof glass doesn't ricochet, though.
Speaker 1: The bullets just get stuck in it, right?
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, and then, also, this is one of those cases of, "I hit you, little
Speaker 1: guy.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was a lot of that going on.
Speaker 1: Always minus points, but you get mad because your arts are awesome.
Speaker 1: What are you going to give it?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I got to give it a meh minus.
Speaker 1: Meh minus?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Because, like you said, the art is really good, but the story, one- I don't know anything about the Hawkman, so it makes no sense.
Speaker 0: I wonder if it would be slightly better if I knew, but I pretended, like, what if I knew what all these things were?
Speaker 0: The story still wasn't that compelling.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: All right, so, regular old Superman.
Speaker 0: Wasn't action comic Superman, would not buy from again.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much what he got.
Speaker 1: It wasn't the Superman I want.
Speaker 1: So, first of all, it's like, the Daily Planet is bigger than the New York Times.
Speaker 1: Does the internet exist in this world, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, "Are you kidding
Speaker 1: me?".
Speaker 1: It's like, "How is the Daily Planet-".
Speaker 0: And how come they- I guess they feel like the only way to keep Superman fresh is to make the Daily Planet start to turn into a rag?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like, obviously, they were trying to make this social commentary, but you failed because you were too overt and not subtle at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know, why didn't, you know, Superman just save the old globe instead of just letting it fall?
Speaker 1: Like, he could have just taken it and put it in a museum.
Speaker 1: He's Superman.
Speaker 0: Who's going to stop him?
Speaker 0: And put it in space in an orbit and left it there until someone asked for him to give it to them to do something with it.
Speaker 0: And then he could have gone out and got it and brought it back.
Speaker 1: If there's a thing you care about and you're Superman, no one can fuck it up for you.
Speaker 0: The Superman just had no personality.
Speaker 0: Action Comics Superman has personality.
Speaker 0: Where is that guy?
Speaker 1: Oh, the thing that bothered me the most of the whole book- The most.
Speaker 1: The most, I don't know if you remember this, right, is if you go to, uh, what page was this fucking thing on, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, God, I'm going to find it.
Speaker 0: I'm wondering if I'm thinking the same thing, but I don't want to say anything until you show me the page.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So what?
Speaker 1: So there's this random page in the middle that has nothing to do with anything- The guy blowing the horn!
Speaker 1: It's just like you're reading this book and this stuff, Superman stuff happening.
Speaker 1: Then there's a page and there's a guy, there's a crazy alien blowing this weird ass fucking horn.
Speaker 1: And it has that note.
Speaker 0: It's like, want to know more about this mystery?
Speaker 1: Because for more on this mystery, you see Stormwatch number one, and then it just goes back to Superman.
Speaker 1: That horn blowing has nothing to do with anything else in any page in this book.
Speaker 1: It is a random page of an alien blowing a horn.
Speaker 0: And two, it's not a mystery anymore if I read that other comic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, uh, we had Stormwatch number one.
Speaker 1: I read it already, didn't we?
Speaker 0: I don't remember that in Stormwatch.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the fuck this alien blowing a horn has to do with Stormwatch.
Speaker 1: I mean, maybe I'll go back and check it out, but why did you- it's like they took a page out of Stormwatch, ripped it out, and just shoved it in a Superman book, just randomly in the middle for no reason.
Speaker 0: Probably to get you to read Stormwatch.
Speaker 0: I know the plots are going to collide, but again, DC, why you do this?
Speaker 0: This is what I hate about comics.
Speaker 1: And there's more subtle ways you could have done it.
Speaker 1: Maybe not even have the Stormwatch comic, and then maybe sort of introduce a plot where Stormwatch has to deal with Superman somehow, and then sort of bring it around back.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of ways they could have done it, but the only thing I like about Superman right now is either the Superman in Frank Miller's Dark Knight Returns, or the action comic Superman.
Speaker 0: If this is neither, I don't care.
Speaker 0: And it just heaped insults upon those already weak foundations.
Speaker 0: I'd give it a bed.
Speaker 1: I would have given it meh, but that horn page brings it down.
Speaker 1: Brings it down into bad territory.
Speaker 0: So not to bring in stuff.
Speaker 0: I know about other stuff, but Teen Titans, that's not the Teen Titans.
Speaker 0: Who are these people?
Speaker 1: I don't know much about Teen Titans at all, really.
Speaker 0: I know there was the mediocre cartoon, and that's all I know, and you know what?
Speaker 0: This wasn't the same people.
Speaker 1: So you've got this super boy, right?
Speaker 1: Is he super boy or is he not?
Speaker 1: Because isn't super boy the astro boy?
Speaker 0: Yes, the astro boy and super boy.
Speaker 1: So who's this guy?
Speaker 0: Fuck if I know.
Speaker 1: So he's super kid, super dude.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Other super boy, super boy two, super whatever.
Speaker 0: And then- Remember, Queen Tits and Ass is supposed to be in the Teen Titans, but she's not.
Speaker 0: She's in Tits and Ass, the comic book.
Speaker 1: You've got Kid Flash, who I sort of know.
Speaker 1: That makes sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know who that is.
Speaker 1: You got Robin.
Speaker 1: Which one of the four Robins is this?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure this is the one.
Speaker 1: The one who takes it in the ass or the one who sucks Batman's dick?
Speaker 0: This is like Red Robin or something.
Speaker 0: It's like yet another Robin.
Speaker 1: Is it different?
Speaker 1: Was he not ever a regular Robin?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Was he only a Red Robin or was he a real, plain old Robin at some point?
Speaker 0: I don't know and it doesn't tell you.
Speaker 0: I watched the cartoon a little bit and it was just Robin and the cyborg guy.
Speaker 0: I don't know who these people are.
Speaker 1: And then you've got Wonder Girl, right?
Speaker 1: And the weirdest part for me was Wonder Girl says, "Wonder
Speaker 1: Girl."
Speaker 1: It's like,
Speaker 1: "What?".
Speaker 1: You say- You know, it's like you don't say your weird name.
Speaker 1: No one goes around saying their own weird-ass name.
Speaker 0: I kind of like the dynamic between the Robin and Wonder Girl because she's like, "Don't call me
Speaker 0: that.".
Speaker 0: And then he's like, "I can block these bullets.
Speaker 0: You're on your
Speaker 0: own.".
Speaker 0: She's like, "Whatever.
Speaker 0: I got
Speaker 0: magics.".
Speaker 0: And he's like, "Whoa, you got
Speaker 0: magic.".
Speaker 0: And she's like, "Shut
Speaker 0: up.".
Speaker 1: Oh, no, wait.
Speaker 1: I think that the Superboy is the Astro Boy Superboy because if you look on the final two pages, it's that girl with the orange hair who was cool and then released the Superboy.
Speaker 0: I was holding my notes in my hand and actually looked, but what I wrote was, "Oh, Superboy is here.
Speaker 0: I wonder
Speaker 0: why.".
Speaker 0: Basically, I was complaining that, yet again, they're mixing all my comics up.
Speaker 1: Also, The Enemy was an evil acronym organization.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: And I think at some point someone made a joke about Robin being homeschooled, and I was like, "Haha.
Speaker 1: He does act homeschooled.
Speaker 1: Wait.
Speaker 1: All these people act
Speaker 1: homeschooled.".
Speaker 1: Okay, so that Superboy is the Astro Boy Superboy, but it's like, "No, wait.
Speaker 1: Why are they releasing the Astro Boy Superboy in a comic?
Speaker 1: that's not the
Speaker 1: Superboy?".
Speaker 0: I give it a mad just because it's not as bad as all the things I've said are bad.
Speaker 0: I didn't like it, but I didn't particularly dislike it.
Speaker 1: I actually gave it bad because there was absolutely nothing.
Speaker 1: The other ones that I gave mad, it was like, "Oh, there was amazing art, but there was nothing
Speaker 1: doing.".
Speaker 1: This, it was just nothing doing across the board.
Speaker 1: There wasn't one awesome thing to say.
Speaker 1: there was an awesome thing to push it up into mad.
Speaker 0: I guess I kind of enjoyed some of the banter, and the dialogue wasn't that bad.
Speaker 1: I did comment about the, "You were homeschooled" part.
Speaker 1: It was a little better than others in the dialogue department, but still not good dialogue, just better than the others.
Speaker 0: By this point in the slog, it didn't take much to impress me.
Speaker 1: It's all relative.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: We're finally at the end of our slog.
Speaker 0: Voodoo.
Speaker 1: AKA.
Speaker 1: TNA.
Speaker 0: Not only TNA, but let's have- Tnist Aonist.
Speaker 0: The majority of this comic take place in a strip club and keep showing all the strippers and play to the stereotype that all the strippers are in fact working moms and college girls just trying to get by, and that is totally not sleazy.
Speaker 0: This is like, it's almost like misogyny trying to pretend it's not misogynistic by stereotyping misogyny and then trying to cast it in a good light.
Speaker 1: So the art, I thought the art was actually kind of, it was cool that they tried to do something different, right?
Speaker 1: But it looks like a high quality kamipo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 1: So it's not actually good, but I give them points for doing something different and minus points for doing a bad job.
Speaker 1: The cover was a little- Minus points for TNA.
Speaker 0: The cover was a little- The cover doesn't fit.
Speaker 1: And then here's the notes that I wrote down.
Speaker 1: You ready?
Speaker 0: Boobs.
Speaker 1: Nice setup.
Speaker 1: Boobs.
Speaker 0: It was all boobs.
Speaker 1: All boobs.
Speaker 0: Nothing but boobs.
Speaker 0: I did not, the first time I read it, I did not actually catch that it was the same guy.
Speaker 0: Like I didn't notice that that guy was back.
Speaker 1: Oh, you didn't notice that?
Speaker 0: Because he was drawn derpily.
Speaker 0: Kind of.
Speaker 0: Like his face went off model.
Speaker 1: I didn't notice that much.
Speaker 0: Like I didn't notice it was him.
Speaker 0: I read it again, I was like, "Oh wait, it's the same
Speaker 0: guy.".
Speaker 0: I don't know if I just didn't read those last pages the first time I read it.
Speaker 0: But seriously, they're all strippers.
Speaker 0: You focus on strippers and sex, the whole comic, and you like go out of your way to talk about how all the strippers are totally cool and totally okay with being strippers.
Speaker 0: and they're just like, you know, working moms, trying to get by, trying to make do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, but I mean it's, the thing is, is like you're like, "Oh, it's the same
Speaker 1: guy.".
Speaker 1: It's because Voodoo turned into the guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But then Voodoo also walked away.
Speaker 1: I think she's basically just like the thing, you know, the thing from another world or whatever.
Speaker 0: Maybe she's bad at it, so she was off, that was why he was off model.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I gave it man.
Speaker 0: I gave it bad because I just didn't care.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right, so that concludes this.
Speaker 1: I hope this helps somebody even though it's a thousand years late.
Speaker 1: Just sort of summary things.
Speaker 0: I think we can sum it up by pointing out that it took us this long to do this and I was really excited.
Speaker 0: Like, it's only 52 single issue comics.
Speaker 0: I'm going to read them all with an open mind and I liked some of them, but it became such a slog.
Speaker 0: Like the ones that I didn't like, I would put to the back of the pile and then I'd gotten through all the ones I liked and I had this gigantic pile of comics that I did not want to read.
Speaker 1: 52 comics.
Speaker 1: That's a lot of different comics.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: But it's like so many of them were just the same shit.
Speaker 0: I mean, all the Green Lanterns blurred together to where I really, the only ones that stood out was.
Speaker 0: there was Green Lanterny bullshit and then separate from that there was Green Lanterny bullshit where the evil looking guy is in space brooding.
Speaker 1: See, what I would do if I was them, right, is it's like, okay, obviously if I was them I would throw out the whole thing and make a completely new way of doing things, but just to make, you know, if you're going to keep things the way they're doing it, but you know, just make slight modifications to improve, right?
Speaker 1: What I would do is all this Batman stuff, you really got to sort it out and have there be just one Batman.
Speaker 0: Here's what I would do.
Speaker 0: I'd have all the different Batmans.
Speaker 0: I'd make the equivalent of Shonen Jump, but it's just Batman Jump.
Speaker 0: It's just like.
Speaker 1: Well, that's changing the whole world, right?
Speaker 1: I'm talking about just the slight change, which is, you know, get rid of all these different Batman comics, like Batman Dark, Batman Light, Batman Purple, Batman this, and just make the one comic Batman and release four issues every month, Batman one, two, three, four, and month two, five, six, seven, eight, and if you have to, make them bigger with more pages like a 48 page.
Speaker 0: Or, or, or if you have to, have a second Batman.
Speaker 0: that is no story.
Speaker 0: Every one off is a one off story.
Speaker 1: So there's the one off story, B-Task, and then there's the other one that is Batman, Hell, just make more B-TAS in comic form.
Speaker 0: That style of Batman is my second favorite, third favorite after the original Frank Miller Dark Knight Returns and Michael Keaton Batman, which nobody else likes.
Speaker 1: You know, numbers wise, I wrote, I got to put this spreadsheet out there.
Speaker 1: So you know, most of the comics had 21 pages of content.
Speaker 1: I counted the cover as content that you had around, you know, four or five, six, seven pages of ads, but actually the number of ads went up over the weeks.
Speaker 1: Like the early weeks had like four or five, six pages.
Speaker 1: The later weeks had seven, eight, nine ad pages.
Speaker 0: I wonder if they thought we wouldn't notice.
Speaker 1: Well, I think part of it also was that they had house ads, right?
Speaker 1: The house ads are the ads for other DC shit.
Speaker 1: So the house ads started off as like 10 house ads for all 14 pages of house ads, right?
Speaker 1: And they went down.
Speaker 1: So they, over the weeks, over these four weeks, at least of starting, they had more house ads in the beginning and they replaced them with paid ads as time went on.
Speaker 1: And yeah, charging three bucks for any one of these is a ridiculous amount of money.
Speaker 1: Think about this for one of these flimsy ass things that gives you only 21 pages of story.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much a disposable thing.
Speaker 1: You read it once and chuck it.
Speaker 1: You could get three one dollar iPhone games that you'll probably play every day on the subway.
Speaker 0: Three Angry Birds.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You're telling me that this Batman is worth three Angry Birds?
Speaker 1: Are you crazy?
Speaker 0: The only I mean, maybe Animal Man, just because if that was the only way to read it, I kind of want to read it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's not worth that many.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's like, oh, my God, it's unbelievable.
Speaker 1: And some of these are four dollars.
Speaker 1: All Star Western was a longer book with more pages at twenty nine pages of content.
Speaker 1: Guess what?
Speaker 1: Four dollars.
Speaker 1: It's like, wait, you only added eight more pages of content, you know, over the twenty one that were already in the other ones.
Speaker 1: And you added a whole extra dollar, a thirty three percent price increase for a less than thirty three percent content increase.
Speaker 1: That is not cool.
Speaker 1: So the pricing is all fucked up, but everyone knows that most of them were bad or mad, but hey, most of everything is crap.
Speaker 0: But in our opinion, I mean, I know there are people who love the shit out of all of them.
Speaker 1: Well, if you're the kind of person who loves the shit out of us, you know what we think and you know that you disagree with us.
Speaker 0: No, didn't you know that you like it?
Speaker 0: Didn't some of these already get canceled by the time we finished all this?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not sure exactly which ones were canceled because you keep going through your statistics.
Speaker 0: I'll find out which ones got canceled.
Speaker 1: I think Omak was canceled and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that would be the Jack Kirby-esque one.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: It was pretty bad.
Speaker 1: But, you know, all in all, there were some good ones.
Speaker 1: If you make if you throw enough shit against the wall, you're going to have some golds, right?
Speaker 1: You know, Animal Man.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: The action comic Superman.
Speaker 1: You know, there were some of these comics in here that we kind of liked.
Speaker 1: Aquaman.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Totally cool and awesome jerk guy.
Speaker 1: You know, All-Star Western kind of OK-ish, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, not all these comics were absolutely awful.
Speaker 1: There are some that are worth reading and they'll probably be paying for the trade.
Speaker 0: Well, there is a whole section in the Wikipedia article on the New 52 on accusations of sexism.
Speaker 1: How about that?
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot of information here.
Speaker 0: Doesn't say which ones got canceled.
Speaker 1: Did you press control F and type the word cancel?
Speaker 0: Not yet.
Speaker 1: OK, here we go.
Speaker 1: On January 12, 2012, DC announced that after their eighth issue.
Speaker 1: So there's going to be eight issues of the following comics and then they will all be canceled and replace.
Speaker 0: Yep, I see it with six new titles.
Speaker 1: So here are the ones that are going away.
Speaker 1: Black Hawks, which was, you know, we put our logo on our truck, Hawk and Dove, which is Rob Liefeld.
Speaker 1: Men of War.
Speaker 1: That was the war one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at least.
Speaker 1: Hey, but the thing is, if there's only eight issues of it, you know, there'll be one trade and that's it.
Speaker 1: So it's not even a big commitment.
Speaker 0: I'll read the trade.
Speaker 1: So you could buy that and then sell it to book off or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Terrific.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: Oh, Mac, no shock there.
Speaker 1: And static shock again.
Speaker 0: No shock.
Speaker 1: So those six title after their eighth issues, those six titles will be canceled and they're going to be six new titles.
Speaker 0: So six new Batman, no, five new Batman and one new Green Lanterns.
Speaker 1: Should we buy the number ones of those six new?
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It won't be for a while.
Speaker 1: The eighth issues of those ones still have to come out.
Speaker 1: And then the month after that.
Speaker 0: We probably should.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it could be like half an episode going over just six issues.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But then I feel like, well, if we're going to do that, we have to.
Speaker 1: we should be buying Marvel number ones.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So I don't want to go, you know, down this huge rabbit hole.
Speaker 0: So if we're going to do anything Marvel, you need to watch Wolverine and the X-Men so we can do a show on it.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: It's really good.
Speaker 0: It is really good.
Speaker 1: I got other things to be doing.
Speaker 0: I just got to point out, you know, for all the hate I get for all the a lot of these comic books, you can do superhero stuff that I'll really like.
Speaker 1: It's possible.
Speaker 1: It's very it's you know, it's just.
Speaker 1: you just can't do the typical shit.
Speaker 1: I really like the superhero stuff that gets sort of like existential and weird.
Speaker 1: or like you remember I was talking about my idea for the Flash where he sort of has like mental problems or, you know, you make it real sci fi, like for real sci fi, the way Ghost in the Shell is for real sci fi.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: If they if they got some of the artists or like Demon Knight was real fantasy, right?
Speaker 0: It's got to take the artist who did this stuff like the good ones and make a Ghost in the Shell like color comic.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That isn't just Ghost in the Shell 2.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that isn't just Ghost in the Shell 2.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, or you know, you could do.
Speaker 1: none of these are comedies.
Speaker 1: Have you noticed that?
Speaker 0: Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So Keith Phillips and two people who are talking about the sexism stuff agreed with the observations on Catwoman and Red Hood and the Outlaws, quote, but opine that Voodoo was a positive example of how to incorporate a female character's sexuality as relevant aspect of the story without appearing
Speaker 1: exploitative.
Speaker 0: Oh, I got.
Speaker 0: who said that?
Speaker 0: Who said that?
Speaker 0: The Comics Alliance and I don't know, Keith Phillips.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: You could say that with a straight face.
Speaker 1: I guess the guy believes it.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you tried to go argue that in some forum, there'd be a flame war.
Speaker 1: What are you going to do?
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: This is why you have a podcast.
Speaker 1: No replies.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.