Speaker 0: It's Thursday March 22nd, 2012.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Sky.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, I talk a bit about my trip to India.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So, you know, we're always kind of hard up more of a Tuesday thing to play hardcore board games.
Speaker 0: Like, it's funny because I remember there was a time when we'd complain about the people who complained about that because we could always just get a game going.
Speaker 0: But, uh, it's surprisingly more difficult just with doing more stuff.
Speaker 0: So we have our own, like, private board game night independent of all these other, like, board game things we do in the city.
Speaker 1: And even then it's still hard to get real games.
Speaker 0: Because basically one person shows up every other week.
Speaker 1: Or too many people show up.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, the thing with hardcore games is that to play, it's weird.
Speaker 1: It's like, most people have the problem of they have no friends.
Speaker 1: At least most nerds.
Speaker 1: Or they have very few friends.
Speaker 1: So if they want to play anything for reals, it's very difficult.
Speaker 1: They can't even get a Mario party going on.
Speaker 0: Even if they have a lot of friends, the friends are not in the same physical location.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So, you know, to even have anyone is already lucky.
Speaker 1: But it's like, in order to, you know, certain activities require very specific circumstances.
Speaker 1: To play a hardcore board game, a German game, usually you need exactly three, four, five people.
Speaker 1: Usually four or five, right?
Speaker 1: Four is mostly the optimal number.
Speaker 1: And you need to be in the same place.
Speaker 1: You need to have, like, two or three hours of time set aside specifically for this without distractions.
Speaker 1: And you all need to be dedicated and saying, "Yes, this is what we're gonna
Speaker 1: do.".
Speaker 0: But, at the same time... You know, we tried to make the hardcore, like, semi-private, like, it's like the high-class club, like, "Oh, you, sir, are a distinguished board gamer.
Speaker 0: We will invite you to our private, fancy board game
Speaker 0: party!".
Speaker 0: *sad noises*.
Speaker 0: But, uh, all the people we invite are just as busy with stuff as we are.
Speaker 0: It's like, "Oh, I can't come.
Speaker 0: I'm going to the night
Speaker 0: market.".
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Which is actually pretty cool.
Speaker 0: And anyway...
Speaker 1: Or they show up and they just want to play, like, spot it and dix it and they don't want to play for serious.
Speaker 0: So we tried the Geek Night Strategy, also known as the Penny Arcade Strategy.
Speaker 0: If we scheduled our private board game night every other week, and we held it no matter what, and sometimes me and Scott would sit here, the two of us playing games.
Speaker 0: Usually, Chase would come, we'd have three.
Speaker 0: But, uh, for whatever reason, last night was, like, the night.
Speaker 0: We had the exact right number of people to play two simultaneous sets of games.
Speaker 1: Well, even so, the hardcore game only half-finished.
Speaker 1: But it's a great game, by the way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Brass looks pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's pretty great.
Speaker 1: And the other game was not hardcore.
Speaker 1: It's Dixit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we played some Dixit, and we played, uh, Cameltron.
Speaker 1: Cameltron's somewhat hardcore.
Speaker 1: That's respectable.
Speaker 0: The thing is, you know, the board game night also had a large social element, 'cause it'd been a while since we had a lot of people together, 'cause everyone's been busy.
Speaker 1: Indeed.
Speaker 1: But it's gonna be PAX real soon.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Basically...
Speaker 1: I've been basically practicing.
Speaker 1: You know how most people, they're gonna do something.
Speaker 1: Like, they're gonna be in the Olympics.
Speaker 1: They train.
Speaker 0: I play Carcassonne four times a day.
Speaker 1: I was playing Tini twice a day.
Speaker 1: I'm playing Medici once or twice a day.
Speaker 1: I'm basically pumping board game iron to prepare for PAX.
Speaker 1: And you notice I was winning at Bonanza, right?
Speaker 1: I was doing, uh, I'm pretty much doing excellent all across the board.
Speaker 1: So, at PAX, I am keeping hard score on everything.
Speaker 1: I might even make a little app or something.
Speaker 1: That's bullshit.
Speaker 0: Will you?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna use a notepad and keep track of all the scores.
Speaker 1: I will.
Speaker 1: I will you.
Speaker 1: I'll use a pencil and a paper and a camera to remember all the winnings and losings of PAX.
Speaker 0: Should we do it like Magfest, where we tweeted each victory?
Speaker 1: We're gonna do even harder core than Magfest.
Speaker 1: And I'm gonna win.
Speaker 0: Are you?
Speaker 1: I've pumped the most board game iron.
Speaker 0: Uh, it's not just board games.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: Granted, actually.
Speaker 1: But I've also been playing Punch-Out.
Speaker 0: The trouble is, PAX is the one gaming con where I basically do no video gaming.
Speaker 1: I do a tiny bit.
Speaker 0: I'll walk into, like, the old, the retro table, or the retro, uh, like, uh, consoles and play, like, a game of Punch-Out or something, like, for five minutes, but...
Speaker 1: I wanna, I wanna see if they set up the Bomberman High Ten.
Speaker 0: I mean, PAX, I love it, but the one thing it lacks is an actual arcade.
Speaker 0: Magfest is where I go to play video fucking games.
Speaker 1: It technically has one, but it's really small.
Speaker 0: I know, like, I made that montage video to pump people up for PAX, and it shows that arcade makes it look really badass.
Speaker 0: The secret is that in the Magfest video, I showed maybe a quarter of the arcade.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Because there was so much arcade.
Speaker 0: That two-second shot from my PAX video is the entire PAX arcade.
Speaker 1: You could fit one to, like, at least ten or twenty or thirty PAX arcades in the Magfest.
Speaker 0: Dude, the PAX arcade would fit in my apartment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it would.
Speaker 0: In the Geeknight studio, you could fit a good chunk of the PAX arcade.
Speaker 1: Probably, yeah.
Speaker 0: Why don't I do that?
Speaker 1: You're gonna have to remove all your stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and replace it with... Air hockey.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, air hockey.
Speaker 0: I would, if there were a time when somehow air hockey were the Omega-Thon finale, I might just have to rush the stage, naked, challenging everyone.
Speaker 0: Do it.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's all you.
Speaker 1: But imagine if we had an air hockey table, all that time we spend, like, laying around going, "Yep, yep,".
Speaker 1: instead it'd be click, click, click, click, click, click, click, click, click, click, click, until we were gods.
Speaker 0: I think I would finally master the two-finger, which I'm worried about breaking my goddamn wrist when I try to play that way.
Speaker 1: I would watch so many YouTube videos and study every single aspect and all the minor, you know, like, everything.
Speaker 0: You know what we gotta find?
Speaker 0: Let's try to find a bar in the city that has, like, a real air hockey table.
Speaker 1: Alright, New York City air hockey.
Speaker 1: Photon air hockey.
Speaker 0: None of that, uh, non-regulation shit.
Speaker 1: Air hockey New York, let's see.
Speaker 1: A point finally to the air hockey table.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's not one.
Speaker 0: There are multiple high-class bar lounges dedicated solely to table tennis.
Speaker 1: Well, hold on.
Speaker 1: There's one for table tennis.
Speaker 0: No, there's more than one.
Speaker 1: There really is more than just spin?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's more than spin.
Speaker 0: I'd go to spin because spin is the highest class one.
Speaker 0: They have servants who will walk around handing you balls.
Speaker 1: Alright, so there's Boulmore, which is bowling, right?
Speaker 0: Boulmore's overrated.
Speaker 0: There's better places.
Speaker 1: I know, but I'm just saying, it's a relatively fancy bowling bar.
Speaker 1: It's like spin.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: There's the place in Brooklyn, which is the skeeball place.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: They have leagues, uh, this barcade, obviously, right?
Speaker 1: But there is not an air hockey bar.
Speaker 1: If we had enough money to open a bar and get a liquor license, we could open up the air hockey bar and we'd probably make just as much money as the skeeball bar does.
Speaker 0: Easily.
Speaker 1: Perhaps more.
Speaker 0: Oh, my gosh.
Speaker 1: They just let people play free skeeball and they make all their money by selling alcohol and then they have leagues, which bring in a whole bunch of people.
Speaker 0: You know what I'll do, Scott?
Speaker 0: I'm going to see if Magfest, because, I mean, we got Katsu-Kan to get us that goddamn Rampart machine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got to pester Magfest.
Speaker 0: I'll go to Magfest and be like, look, if you get a Rampart machine...
Speaker 1: And an air hockey table.
Speaker 0: Or an air hockey table.
Speaker 1: And/or...
Speaker 0: Either one of those, I will promise them that magic will happen around that table, meaning I will play it the entire time.
Speaker 1: The thing is, it has to be a real table.
Speaker 1: It has to be balanced evenly.
Speaker 1: It has to work and it has to, you know, it can't be like damaged goods.
Speaker 0: I'm worried, though.
Speaker 0: The reason I almost don't want a Rampart machine to appear is that I've maintained my undefeatedness.
Speaker 0: It's like the only area I have left where I am undefucking defeated.
Speaker 0: If we actually have access to another Rampart machine, like that whole Katsu-Kan where we had it, I was so afraid I was going to lose, and one game I almost lost...
Speaker 1: Well, you didn't, you sort of avoided any game you might have lost.
Speaker 0: Well, no, the one game I almost lost, but Scott Johnson was pretty drunk and he basically threw the game in my favor by accident.
Speaker 0: But there was this really good guy who almost beat me.
Speaker 1: But it's like, you know, if we played it, me and Scott Johnson would just walk up to it and be like, "Alright, listen, Rym's bragging about it being undefeated.
Speaker 1: Team up on Rym.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Do-do-do-do-do-do.
Speaker 1: We
Speaker 1: win.".
Speaker 0: Uh, you see, you say that.
Speaker 0: But when we play games, usually what happens is you say that and everyone kind of looks at you and I'm like, "Scott's just saying that to try to win
Speaker 0: himself.".
Speaker 1: Well, you know that I would definitely not... I would definitely apple it up.
Speaker 1: I would not orange.
Speaker 1: And if Scott Johnson oranged, which he may well do...
Speaker 0: I'd give it a 50/50 shot.
Speaker 1: I do also.
Speaker 1: I would go and just get, like, Pete or someone who would not call orange.
Speaker 0: You think Pete wouldn't orange on you?
Speaker 0: Pete would orange all over you.
Speaker 1: There has to be someone who would not orange.
Speaker 0: Pete would get his orange all over your business.
Speaker 1: Who would go all out and attack only Rym until he was dead to make sure that he was no longer undefeated at Rampart?
Speaker 0: It's one thing.
Speaker 0: Like, last night, right?
Speaker 0: We had the board game night.
Speaker 1: I'll just pay some stranger.
Speaker 1: I'll be like, "I'll give you five bucks.
Speaker 1: All you gotta do is only attack that guy.
Speaker 1: And then once he's dead, we'll play you and me fair and
Speaker 1: square.".
Speaker 0: I'll go to the guy and be like, "Ten
Speaker 0: bucks.".
Speaker 1: Twenty.
Speaker 1: Thirty.
Speaker 0: Fifty.
Speaker 0: Hundred.
Speaker 1: Two hundred.
Speaker 0: Scott, I have more money than you, and this is one area that means a lot to me.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what?
Speaker 1: I would employ the secret technique, which I will not reveal.
Speaker 0: Punch me in the face.
Speaker 0: Hack the machine.
Speaker 1: Something along those lines.
Speaker 1: Like, put my hand over and spin your trackball around while you're trying to play some pieces.
Speaker 0: Scott's fastest Ramparting strategy.
Speaker 1: Hit your buttons a whole bunch to play some pieces.
Speaker 0: So, last night, right?
Speaker 0: You know, this is why... I'm always able to pull it off on you.
Speaker 1: People are dicks.
Speaker 0: Not enough people will listen to this episode from Tuesday to know that I said this, but look at last night, right?
Speaker 0: Our friend Kat was playing the Cameltron with all our other friends, and they all learned the game.
Speaker 0: And they're playing, you know, as derpily as first-time players can play.
Speaker 0: But Kat had to go outside, so she couldn't finish the game.
Speaker 0: So I took over for her, and I sit down, and I look, and she's actually in a really good position.
Speaker 0: So I immediately sit down and say, "Oh, alright, I gotta figure out...".
Speaker 0: "Oh my god, what was Kat
Speaker 0: doing?".
Speaker 0: "Oh my god, I can't win!
Speaker 0: Look at this!
Speaker 0: That camel doesn't have
Speaker 0: anything!".
Speaker 0: And I bitched about it for, like, ten turns.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, I was winning by, like, thirty points.
Speaker 0: And no one noticed because I was bitching so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what happened to me?
Speaker 1: We started playing Brass, right?
Speaker 1: And I'd never played this game before, and I wasn't quite sure what the strategies were or anything.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I make a move.
Speaker 1: I'm just sort of fooling around.
Speaker 1: I'm like, "I'll build a coal mine,
Speaker 1: whatever.".
Speaker 1: I'm just, like, feeling it out.
Speaker 1: Just trying stuff.
Speaker 1: Whatevs.
Speaker 1: And then I realize, "Oh, you should,".
Speaker 1: and I say it out loud, "You should sell cotton immediately to up your income, otherwise you're stuck at
Speaker 1: zero.".
Speaker 0: I heard you say it.
Speaker 1: Then Steve is like, "Oh," and he sells cotton immediately, thus making it harder for anyone else to do it.
Speaker 1: He gets a big boost in income before anyone else, and I'm like,
Speaker 1: "Ugh.".
Speaker 0: I was the one who thought of that.
Speaker 0: Because, Scott... And now I lose.
Speaker 0: The way to win the PAX who wins the most game games is to pull out games that no one's played before and just captain it up.
Speaker 0: Craft captain, craft captain, craft captain.
Speaker 1: The thing is, I don't feel bad doing that.
Speaker 0: Bushels in the castle, biscuits in the baskets.
Speaker 1: I want to win legitimately.
Speaker 1: I want to play games.
Speaker 1: everyone knows how to play and out-power everyone.
Speaker 1: Because that is much more satisfying.
Speaker 0: All right, games everyone knows how to play.
Speaker 0: Teeny, we're deadlocked.
Speaker 0: Puerto Rico, we're deadlocked.
Speaker 1: Like, if I win a Bonanza, that's a big fucking deal.
Speaker 0: Oh, Bonanza, Ro is going to kick the shit out of both of us.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, that's the point.
Speaker 1: It's like a game everyone's good at.
Speaker 1: If you win a Dominion, it's like,
Speaker 1: "Boom!".
Speaker 1: Yes!
Speaker 0: If she wins a Dominion, it's like, "Saw that
Speaker 0: coming.".
Speaker 1: That's a different story.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you got to win at a game that people know, and then it's like, "Yeah, that
Speaker 1: counts.".
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: Otherwise, it's like, if you're Michael Jordan walking out playing against the high school kids, it doesn't mean anything.
Speaker 1: For it to be a real championship, it's got to be the best of the best.
Speaker 1: playing for serious.
Speaker 0: So, a little bit of news.
Speaker 0: It's Thursday, it's The Lounge.
Speaker 1: You and your lounge.
Speaker 0: Talk about whatever we want.
Speaker 1: You know what's in my lounge?
Speaker 1: Air hockey table.
Speaker 0: There's a pretty good article in The Atlantic, actually, and I want to call attention to it.
Speaker 0: I won't talk about it a lot, but it argues that The Daily Show, of all shows, people always say The Daily Show provides more news to people than it should.
Speaker 0: People watch it to get the news, even though it's a comedy show.
Speaker 0: It is interesting how vaguely obsessed Fox News is with The Daily Show, when The Daily Show is ostensibly comedy and Fox News is ostensibly news, but I digress.
Speaker 0: This isn't new news for any of you.
Speaker 0: It's old news.
Speaker 0: We're talking about news.
Speaker 1: Century old news.
Speaker 0: So, this article takes it from a different light.
Speaker 0: It talks about the whole UNESCO fiasco.
Speaker 0: Are you familiar with this, Scott?
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 0: Okay, so here's the deal.
Speaker 0: This is old news.
Speaker 1: I might know it once you start talking about it.
Speaker 0: I followed it because I was really pissed off about it, but the media basically didn't care.
Speaker 0: UNESCO is the UN organization that basically tries to provide clean water to people in starving countries.
Speaker 1: They didn't seem to be doing a very good job in India.
Speaker 0: They focus on the places that are worse off than India.
Speaker 1: Okay, where they can't even get the bottled water.
Speaker 0: They also work in India.
Speaker 0: It's an organization to where no one can say anything bad about them.
Speaker 0: They are nothing but a force for good.
Speaker 1: All they do is give water to people who have no water.
Speaker 0: So, the members of UNESCO voted to allow Palestine in.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: Do they need water?
Speaker 1: Are they people?
Speaker 0: No, they provide aid to people who aren't even in.
Speaker 0: If you're in, it means you're helping with humanitarian efforts.
Speaker 0: You have a vote in UNESCO to where the money goes.
Speaker 0: Stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: So, they wanted to bring Palestine in, and there was a huge majority of votes in UNESCO to allow Palestine to join this purely humanitarian organization.
Speaker 1: If they want to give money to help people, including themselves and others, and then have a small one vote in deciding who gets help, what's wrong with that?
Speaker 0: So, I believe 12 or 13 members of UNESCO voted against this.
Speaker 1: All the Jews?
Speaker 0: Pretty much Israel, the US, and all the Israel allied countries.
Speaker 1: Right, okay.
Speaker 0: So, the US pulled all funding from UNESCO.
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: $70 million gone.
Speaker 1: Obama was just okay with that?
Speaker 0: Obama's actually really pissed about it.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: But he can't do anything.
Speaker 0: It's Congress.
Speaker 0: So, Congress passed a law a long time ago, '90s, saying any UN organization that recognizes Palestine as a state, we will not talk to them.
Speaker 0: We will not help them.
Speaker 0: We will deny all funding.
Speaker 0: We'll basically fuck them.
Speaker 1: Dude, the thing is, if you think about it, it's like a board game.
Speaker 1: What they should do, all these people in the UN should just be like, "Hey, let's fuck the US.
Speaker 1: Let's put Palestine in every organization forcing the US out of
Speaker 1: everything.".
Speaker 0: Scott, the Republicans and a lot of people in the US would love that, because basically all it means is the US stops funding humanitarian programs around the world.
Speaker 1: Well, no, they could do it in all of the other things that the US wants to be on.
Speaker 1: Like, the UN could vote Palestine onto the Security Council, which would be crazy.
Speaker 1: And then he's like, "Oh, US can't be on the Security Council
Speaker 1: anymore.".
Speaker 1: China makes all decisions.
Speaker 0: It's a little more complicated than that, but anyway.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, crazy shit.
Speaker 0: So, the law is there, ostensibly, to force Israel and Palestine to negotiate directly and to not let anyone else influence that in any way.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 0: Now, the reasoning behind that, and this whole situation, is basically absurd.
Speaker 1: Duh.
Speaker 0: And this article talks about how all the news coverage of it basically toed, not the party line, but the kind of status quo line.
Speaker 0: The news all said, "Yep, well, they reported very matter of fact.
Speaker 0: This organization voted to let Palestine in.
Speaker 0: The US has a law that says that they can't fund it, so the US had to stop funding it at the
Speaker 0: end.".
Speaker 0: So, The Daily Show did a double feature on how bullshit this is.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: It's like, this is one of those things where it's like, "Oh, there's a rule that the US can't do
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: It's like, a rule is just something that's made up by people.
Speaker 1: You can just fucking change that shit.
Speaker 0: It's a rule made up by Congress that they can trivially change.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You can just change that shit.
Speaker 1: It's not like the law of thermodynamics.
Speaker 1: You can't change.
Speaker 0: John Oliver on The Daily Show interviewed a senator and was like, "So, we can't do anything about
Speaker 0: this.".
Speaker 0: The guy's like, "Yeah, our hands are tied.
Speaker 0: We can't fund
Speaker 0: them.".
Speaker 0: And he was like, "Because of the law you
Speaker 0: passed.".
Speaker 0: He's like, "That's
Speaker 0: right.".
Speaker 0: He's like, "So, Congress doesn't have the power to change laws.
Speaker 0: That's good to
Speaker 0: know.".
Speaker 0: And the guy's like, "Well...".
Speaker 0: Basically, he punked him.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: So, this article, you know, not to get into the UNESCO thing, even though it's absurd, but the article points out that The Daily Show scarily is actually the only major news show in the world, or at least in America, even though it's not a news show, that when it covers the news, does not cover it from the status quo perspective, but covers it from actually a more objective standpoint than actual news does, because actual news and trying to be objective doesn't actually talk about the ramifications of anything and really just focuses on the facts and assumes a lot of these things that are status quo, when really the news story isn't that the U.S.
Speaker 0: had to follow this law.
Speaker 0: The news story is that this is a fucked up situation that's hurting people.
Speaker 1: Dope.
Speaker 0: And it's actually a really great article.
Speaker 1: But that's why The Daily Show's comedy, right?
Speaker 1: Comedy is truth.
Speaker 1: Have you read friggin' Stranger in a Strange Land or not?
Speaker 0: Or perhaps the court jester is the only one who can call the king fat.
Speaker 0: No kidding, right?
Speaker 0: Except we live in a place where there's free speech.
Speaker 0: The news could call the king fat and the king can't do shit about it.
Speaker 0: The news just doesn't.
Speaker 1: Why don't we just start a news where we say that we have the same smart perspective, but we don't present it as comedy?
Speaker 1: And we just put it on YouTube every day and we'll do one news story.
Speaker 0: Let's put that in the hopper with the other thousand things in the hopper.
Speaker 1: Why isn't someone listening to the show?
Speaker 1: just do it?
Speaker 1: We don't care how shitty it is.
Speaker 1: It could be like elementary school CCTV news quality.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: We have Project
Speaker 0: S.T.,
Speaker 0: Project C.R.L.
Speaker 0: They're all Project S.T We have Project T.T.I.
Speaker 1: But anyone out there who's got a camera, just sit in front of it every day, pick a news story, and just be like, "Today, UNESCO, whatever, funding cut.
Speaker 1: Because of this rule, the government is stupid and they could just change it, but they refuse
Speaker 1: to.".
Speaker 1: In other words, all your congressmen are basically taking clean water out of the mouths of starving people.
Speaker 1: They're disgusting.
Speaker 1: End of story.
Speaker 0: So, this is an interesting article.
Speaker 0: I highly recommend you read it.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 0: So, you have anything?
Speaker 1: Oh, I did.
Speaker 1: I remember my news now.
Speaker 1: I didn't have a link open for it, so I couldn't remember what it was.
Speaker 1: So, check this out.
Speaker 1: There's this crazy dude, and he went to a casino.
Speaker 1: Now, usually, going to a casino is not a good idea, right?
Speaker 1: It's a way to lose all the money.
Speaker 1: Because casinos, the house always wins.
Speaker 1: Always.
Speaker 1: And, you know, there was card counting at one point, but today, card counting doesn't work.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Forget it.
Speaker 1: But this guy, he was, you know, a big time gambler.
Speaker 1: And apparently, I wasn't totally aware of this, but if you're a big time gambler, you don't just walk into a casino and play.
Speaker 1: You talk to the casino, and because you have so much money, they talk to you.
Speaker 1: So, like, if you and me walk into a casino, you know, you walk over to the craps table and it says, like,
Speaker 1: "5x.".
Speaker 1: You can't change that.
Speaker 1: That's just the rule for the game.
Speaker 1: And if you don't like the rule, you don't play there.
Speaker 1: If you're mad rich, you can walk in and be like, "Hey, can you set me up a craps table with these
Speaker 1: rules?".
Speaker 1: And they'll be like, "Well, actually, we don't like those rules because then the house doesn't always win.
Speaker 1: How about these
Speaker 1: rules?".
Speaker 1: And you can negotiate on the rules and, like, how much money you're going to spend and all this stuff.
Speaker 1: So this guy went in, and he negotiated with these casinos.
Speaker 1: And, by the way, the casinos are the desperate.
Speaker 1: Like, actually, Foxwoods is even in big trouble.
Speaker 1: Because, you know, there's basically more casinos, the love's getting spread around, there's online poker and stuff, right?
Speaker 1: So, casinos are not doing well lately.
Speaker 1: So they're basically more desperate than ever to get people to come in, especially the high rollers.
Speaker 1: Because, you know, a whole bunch of low rollers, you know, a bus full of people coming from the city isn't going to help.
Speaker 0: Well, it's old ladies nickel at a time.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And if you want, you know, but one high roller, if he comes in and loses all his monies, your casino's good for, like, a whole month or two.
Speaker 1: So it's like, "Yeah, we need
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 1: So they're desperate to get this guy in the door.
Speaker 1: So, you know, the guy's figuring out which casino he wants to go to.
Speaker 1: So they're sort of competing as who's going to set him more favorable rules to get him in the door.
Speaker 1: They also actually are not technologically stupid.
Speaker 1: They actually have this computerized system that works and is good, where they can type in the rules.
Speaker 1: Like, "Guy wants to play blackjack with six decks and wants to allow double splitting and wants to allow this and that rules for this minimum bet on this and
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 1: And then it'll pretty much tell the casino owner, you know, once he types in those rules, "Thumbs up!
Speaker 1: We'll
Speaker 1: win!"
Speaker 1: or "Thumbs
Speaker 1: down!"
Speaker 1: "No, this is a bad idea if we let him play this
Speaker 1: game."
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: So apparently, whoever was at this casino totally fucked up and didn't use the software properly or who knows what.
Speaker 1: And they basically let this guy play at what was almost, like, 50/50 odds on blackjack.
Speaker 1: So he walked in with, like, "He's mad
Speaker 1: rich.".
Speaker 1: So he was just like, "Million
Speaker 1: dollars."
Speaker 1: And he got mad lucky and he got, like, four eights and he split it four ways.
Speaker 1: And there was also some weird rule about, like, you know, usually in blackjack it's, like, the house, like, has to hit in a certain situation and has to stop in a certain situation.
Speaker 1: And it's usually the same rules all the time.
Speaker 1: Those rules were even different in this game.
Speaker 1: So it was basically a situation where, like, he had four hands and the house went over and it was like, "Oh, one hand with millions of
Speaker 1: dollars.".
Speaker 1: "Ha ha ha ha
Speaker 1: ha.".
Speaker 1: And this guy just-- It's a pretty good story.
Speaker 1: The dude friggin' rolled the casino without cheating.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Without cheating.
Speaker 1: He didn't count the cards.
Speaker 1: He just played blackjack smartly and normally.
Speaker 1: And had the rules of the game changed, but the casino agreed to it.
Speaker 1: So, uh, this is just another one.
Speaker 1: I wanted to bring this up, though, because it's not, you know, it's an example of smart nerdiness.
Speaker 1: A guy knowing the rules, doing the math, using his smart brain to get ahead.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Which is laudable.
Speaker 1: But it's also another example of, if you want to get more rich, and you already are rich, it's real easy.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: But if you're poor, you can't get more rich as easily as someone who's already rich.
Speaker 1: Even at the casino.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day!
Speaker 0: So, I was born in 1982.
Speaker 0: Me too.
Speaker 0: And this video is from 1982.
Speaker 1: Me too.
Speaker 0: It is a video, volume one, of how to beat home video games.
Speaker 1: I wonder how much that shit cost on VHS, like 30 bucks per-.
Speaker 1: I have no idea, but this is- And it probably cost like 30 bucks for one VHS tape, and it probably was like 50 dollars for the Atari games.
Speaker 1: This is how to beat- You're paying 30 bucks to learn how to beat- How to beat Atari Circus, and there's something about- The one with the seesaw?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know how to beat it.
Speaker 1: Always make sure the seesaw's under the falling dude.
Speaker 0: He has some good strategies here, but the thing is, it's interesting to watch because it's a blast from the past, and it reminds me that I didn't own Circus Atari.
Speaker 1: But I had this catalog- I borrowed it for a short time.
Speaker 0: When I was a kid, that listed like every Atari game you could buy and like a review of it, and I was obsessed with all the games I didn't have.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 0: Circus Atari's actually not that good of a game.
Speaker 1: It's not the worst though.
Speaker 0: It's not the best.
Speaker 1: There are a lot worse Atari games, but it is not exactly one of the Atari greats like Pitfall and such.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but these strategies- These videos are pretty interesting to watch, and they really take you back to, you know, the early '80s were more like the late '70s than you might realize.
Speaker 1: I have a VHS tape because when the TurboGrafx-16 was coming out, they had a big promotional thing at the mall, at the shopping mall next to us.
Speaker 1: And I went over there and played a bunch of demo stations before like you could even buy one.
Speaker 0: Ah.
Speaker 1: And I got a VHS tape that is basically an advertisement for TurboGrafx-16, and I must have watched it like two or three times.
Speaker 0: I have the VHS tape.
Speaker 0: It's not that old.
Speaker 1: I should dig it up and try to get it onto YouTube if it's not on there already.
Speaker 0: Dragon Strike, that D&D-ish game that was released with the VHS tape that came with it.
Speaker 1: Never played it, but I knew about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had it.
Speaker 0: I had the VHS tape.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 0: Never played it though because no one would play it with me.
Speaker 1: I was a bigger fan of the one.
Speaker 1: I can't seem to find it anywhere, but it came- remember the second- No.
Speaker 0: Or Haunted Mansion.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: No?
Speaker 1: I'm talking about this D&D game where it was basically- you had no GM because there was a big box full of cards.
Speaker 1: that was the GM, right?
Speaker 1: And like the box was basically- remember when they reprinted the second edition stuff, it was in a different graphical style where it was black, right?
Speaker 1: With the, you know, the picture in the middle?
Speaker 1: You know what I'm talking about?
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 1: And basically this box was in that style and had a big red dragon on it.
Speaker 1: And basically you had a fold-out dungeon and you would move your guys around the dungeon sort of like HeroQuest, but it was TSR D&D brand.
Speaker 1: And it had a, you know, there was this big box full of cards and basically you would move around and then instead of, you know, being a GM or anything, you just went to the box and it told you what was in the dungeon and stuff.
Speaker 0: Oh, so I found your video.
Speaker 0: There were multiple versions of this apparently.
Speaker 1: That's the one.
Speaker 0: I got it.
Speaker 0: I'll link to it.
Speaker 0: Bonus thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: So anyway, my actual thing of the day- Yup.
Speaker 1: Is, uh, everyone's probably seen this already because it was all over the internets and I'm pretty sure there's a whole, probably a whole bunch of things like this, so it's not unique at all.
Speaker 1: Um, and it's, you know, but whatever.
Speaker 1: It's got four million views.
Speaker 1: It could use a few more views.
Speaker 1: It's something called the Wrecking Crew Orchestra.
Speaker 1: And this is actually pretty recent from February 8th, 2012.
Speaker 1: So even if these guys have been around a while, this is a recent performance.
Speaker 1: What they do is they're basically a dance troupe, but they perform in the dark and they wear suits covered with lights and, you know, like strip lights and LED lights.
Speaker 0: Now, think about the ramifications of what you can do with that.
Speaker 1: And yeah, and the lights are basically pre-programmed or controlled by someone from a central location or something.
Speaker 1: So they dance and they appear and disappear and shift and they do all sorts of cool, you know, performance tricks going on here.
Speaker 1: Uh, and it is fun to watch.
Speaker 1: I mean, it wouldn't probably be fun to watch, like, you know, a whole bunch of these, but watching one if you haven't seen one is really awesome.
Speaker 1: And if you've seen it already, alright.
Speaker 1: If you haven't seen it already, must see.
Speaker 0: So in the meta moment, uh, two weeks to PAX.
Speaker 0: It's a-coming.
Speaker 0: We're doing a whole bunch of panels and a bunch of our friends are doing a whole bunch of panels and workshops.
Speaker 1: Playing a whole bunch of games.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be at PAX in force.
Speaker 1: Pretty much, I gotta apologize, PAX Fever is in full effect as it is twice a year.
Speaker 1: Maybe it'll become three times a year, we have no idea.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a cure.
Speaker 0: If you are so hyped about PAX that you can't get over it, I'll link to a video.
Speaker 0: I made a montage of how awesome PAX was last year.
Speaker 0: And if you watch it, it might excite you so much.
Speaker 0: you'll die and then you won't have to worry about it anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not gonna help.
Speaker 0: That's like, hmm, cure for AIDS?
Speaker 1: Unprotected sex with someone with AIDS?
Speaker 0: Last night during the board game night.
Speaker 1: Cure for flu?
Speaker 0: We were talking about ponies and I was like, oh, there was a bunch of ponies at PAX.
Speaker 1: Going outside in the cold naked, that's a cure for flu.
Speaker 0: They were like, what?
Speaker 0: And I'm like, yeah, so I pull up that montage video and I skip to where all the pony stuff was and then I'm like, oh shit, PAX.
Speaker 0: Oh shit, PAX.
Speaker 0: Uh, you wanna make predictions now as to what the Omegathon's gonna be or save it for Tuesday?
Speaker 1: I told you, I'm sticking with, cause they already said- It's East, so it's gonna be teams, most likely.
Speaker 1: It's East, so it's co-op, guaranteed.
Speaker 1: And, you know, they had to have something built for this.
Speaker 0: I'm going with Double Dare.
Speaker 1: It can't be Double Dare.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: It could be the Double Dare challenge at the end.
Speaker 1: I am thinking- No, I'm still going with my Rock 'Em Sock 'Em robot until, you know, it is no more.
Speaker 0: Scott, you know what would be the ultimate, I realize.
Speaker 0: As much as I want, you know, the Double Dare, the Aggro Craig- Crossfire.
Speaker 0: Crossfire.
Speaker 1: But that's not co-op either.
Speaker 1: But they could easily make any of these things co-op.
Speaker 0: Would be, if it was straight up American Gladiator.
Speaker 1: They did make an Aggro Craig, it's Guts.
Speaker 1: They have all, full Guts, built into the thing.
Speaker 0: The thing is, depending on the nerds who get to the finale- How can they possibly keep it secret?
Speaker 0: It might be Guts.
Speaker 0: And the book is The Hunger Games, because it seems to be spreading faster than Twilight on Cancer.
Speaker 0: And it's pretty good actually.
Speaker 0: Not great, but pretty good.
Speaker 0: I liked it.
Speaker 0: So we'll do a show on it whenever.
Speaker 1: Yet, I haven't read it yet, but I have a copy.
Speaker 1: But people say that it's basically Battle Royale, the ripoff, plus some Arnold Schwarzenegger running man mix in there.
Speaker 0: And some 1984.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that's what people say about it, so maybe that sounds good to you.
Speaker 1: I don't know, but that's what people say.
Speaker 0: It exceeded expectations by a surprising amount.
Speaker 1: It'll probably actually be a "soon" book club, because once I actually start reading it, it shouldn't take very long at all.
Speaker 0: Dude, it's like a two and a half hour read.
Speaker 1: Right, so as soon as I actually get around to it, it'll be like
Speaker 1: "bam!"
Speaker 1: and we'll do this book club right away and get a new one going.
Speaker 1: It'll be much less weight than the previous book club, which took a while.
Speaker 0: Kineticon is coming up.
Speaker 0: We run the panels and workshops department.
Speaker 0: If you submit a panel, I will link to the farm, and you're a Geek Nights listener.
Speaker 0: There's a good chance you'll get one, because you guys give us some of the best panels we get, normally.
Speaker 0: Nepotism!
Speaker 0: But yeah, submit your panels.
Speaker 1: It's not nepotism, they're not in our family.
Speaker 0: They're an extended family.
Speaker 0: The Geek Nights family.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We got an internet, we got a YouTube channel, got a website, got a forum, all that stuff.
Speaker 0: It's all there.
Speaker 0: So it might be kind of a cop-out, but I figured I'd just talk about my experiences in India, because I'd never been to India before.
Speaker 1: Alright, do you want to get any sort of prejudice, racist, out of our system now?
Speaker 1: Like, "Oh, a dalsib and great
Speaker 1: tiger.".
Speaker 1: Oh, so basically, when I was there- Hello, I am a poo.
Speaker 1: Thank you, come again.
Speaker 0: Everybody breathes fire.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry, everyone from India.
Speaker 0: In fact, if you got food from a street vendor, he breathed fire on it before he gave it to you.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry, everyone from India.
Speaker 1: I'm sure that when you can do a show about your trip to America, make fun of us, please, because I want to hear that.
Speaker 0: Actually, the best joke someone made, and it was actually an Indian guy that I was hanging out with while I was there, was like, "Where are all the Native
Speaker 0: Americans?".
Speaker 0: Yeah, I heard there are many of them here.
Speaker 0: He was a funny guy.
Speaker 0: He was one of my cab drivers.
Speaker 1: He tried to do too much with it.
Speaker 0: He was the same one who was really proud of the slum, kind of how in America, if you're showing something around New York, you'll be like, "Yeah, that's a New York bum.
Speaker 0: Check him
Speaker 0: out.".
Speaker 0: Or, "See how there's no one in that subway car?
Speaker 0: Yeah.".
Speaker 0: It smells like pee.
Speaker 0: This guy was like, "That's our slum.
Speaker 0: There's at least two million people in
Speaker 0: there.".
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: "It's pretty
Speaker 0: big.".
Speaker 0: And he's like, "You want to take a
Speaker 0: picture?".
Speaker 0: He was really just like, "Check it
Speaker 0: out.".
Speaker 0: But anyway, I was there on business, so I actually didn't get to do ... I had evenings and a couple of times to myself where I could wander around, but I was actually mostly beholden to a whole bunch of corporate-style meetings, and I had to go to this conference there, like a convention, and deal with booths and stuff.
Speaker 0: But it was the first time I traveled extensively on corporate money as opposed to my own money, and that's a very interesting experience.
Speaker 1: It's the opposite of we go to a convention, and they're like, "$10 hot
Speaker 1: dog.".
Speaker 1: You're like, "Are you
Speaker 1: crazy?".
Speaker 1: Now it's like, "$10 hot dog.
Speaker 1: Who gives a shit?
Speaker 1: It's not my money.
Speaker 1: I want a hot dog, and I don't want to walk anywhere.
Speaker 1: Give
Speaker 1: me.".
Speaker 0: Even better, what's interesting is that when you're in this position, you're kind of obligated to take other businessmen out to eat and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: So basically, it's expected that you're going to spend a ton of money on room service and cocktails and all that kind of crazy stuff.
Speaker 0: But I'll try to skip the business-y stuff, but I flew to Mumbai.
Speaker 0: You may know it as Bombay.
Speaker 0: Now what's interesting is it's Mumbai.
Speaker 0: That's the official name of the city.
Speaker 0: That's kind of what you're expected to say.
Speaker 1: So it's written on all the things?
Speaker 0: And I'd gotten the impression that everyone called it Mumbai.
Speaker 1: No, they say Bombay.
Speaker 0: So when I got there, the only people who said Mumbai were foreigners and rich people.
Speaker 0: And everyone else that I met called it Bombay.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I've heard that already.
Speaker 0: But what's really funny is we got to meet some executives from the Bombay Stock Exchange, the BSE.
Speaker 0: They call it the BSE now because they don't want to change the name to the Mumbai Stock Exchange or change the acronym or anything.
Speaker 0: Because imagine how much of a pain in the ass it would be if you have all these network things named something publicly and you have to rename everything.
Speaker 0: Imagine if you had to rename all the variables and class names in your code because of some BS.
Speaker 0: But the cool thing was...
Speaker 1: It's called SED.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that may or may not work well depending on...
Speaker 1: You got to do it right.
Speaker 0: Well, one of the worst things in the world is when you're trying to fix some code and you find out that the name of a class was actually spelled wrong in the first place.
Speaker 0: That's like the worst.
Speaker 0: But I digress.
Speaker 0: I got to meet a bunch of people who run the Bombay Stock Exchange and we went up to their tower and I realized at the top that it was really the only tall building in that area of Bombay.
Speaker 0: And the guy introduces us and we realized we can see the entire city out these windows.
Speaker 0: And I look and I see all this military stuff.
Speaker 0: He's like, "That's the entire Indian Navy.
Speaker 0: Don't take any pictures.
Speaker 0: We'll get in a lot of
Speaker 0: trouble.".
Speaker 0: And apparently after the Mumbai terrorist attacks, India's got some problems like many places in the world do.
Speaker 0: So you're not allowed to have tall buildings in that area because you can basically spy on the military.
Speaker 0: And the buildings are targets for attacks, which is actually a concern there.
Speaker 1: That reminds me of this dude.
Speaker 1: There was a photo an astronaut posted and it was like, "What was the craziest thing you saw from
Speaker 1: space?".
Speaker 1: And he's like, "Look at
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 1: And there was this line on the Earth and it was this glowing line.
Speaker 1: And he's like, "That's the India-Pakistan border.
Speaker 1: It's a glowing
Speaker 1: line.".
Speaker 1: You can see it more easily than you can see the Great Wall of China.
Speaker 0: Actually, the Great Wall of China is one of the hardest things to see.
Speaker 0: It's not visible from space.
Speaker 1: Right, but you could clearly see this thing.
Speaker 1: It looked like a string of light bulbs that were just ridiculously long.
Speaker 1: And I was like, "Whoa.
Speaker 1: That's for serious,
Speaker 1: yo.".
Speaker 1: So by law, you can't really see the other contentious borders around the world, but you can't really see them from space.
Speaker 0: Well, you can see the implicit North Korea-South Korea border.
Speaker 1: Well, that's different.
Speaker 1: You can just see it at night because it's dark and then South Korea actually has lights.
Speaker 0: So they can't have legally tall buildings there, but the government was kind of smart about it.
Speaker 0: They're like, "Yeah, we're not going to make you tear down the only already existing tall building.
Speaker 0: Don't let people take pictures of the Navy.
Speaker 0: You'll get in
Speaker 0: trouble.".
Speaker 0: But it was a really great view and I wish I could have taken a picture.
Speaker 0: It was really...
Speaker 1: You should have just taken one illicitly and then posted it anonymously on like, Imgur or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't want to deal with that, especially because I may or may not be trying to do business with the Bombay Stock Exchange.
Speaker 1: No, you just don't post it until the business is done.
Speaker 1: You obviously wouldn't go home and post it immediately.
Speaker 1: Then they know it was you.
Speaker 1: You do it like months later when it could have been anyone who visited in any of those months or even like a year later.
Speaker 0: Nah, because think about it.
Speaker 0: So I take a picture of the Indian Navy, right?
Speaker 0: Say the picture gets out and there's some bullshit.
Speaker 0: Some Navy intelligence guy over there is going to look at the picture and be like, "All right, these are the ships that were in
Speaker 0: part.".
Speaker 1: Didn't he say it was the whole Navy?
Speaker 0: Well, no, that's the Navy part.
Speaker 0: I'm sure a ship or two were out doing stuff.
Speaker 0: They move them around in the part.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: But it was a really impressive view.
Speaker 0: But the funny thing, so I flew Air India and it wasn't a coach.
Speaker 0: It was actual Air India.
Speaker 1: Well, Air India isn't exactly Lufthansa.
Speaker 0: So the domestic flights within India were way more comfortable than JetBlue, like way nice.
Speaker 0: That's nice.
Speaker 1: But were you first class?
Speaker 0: No, God no.
Speaker 0: God no, our company's doing well about that one.
Speaker 1: But the thing about JetBlue is it's not supposed to be the crazy comfortable.
Speaker 1: It's supposed to be everything's the same, it's simple, it's cheap, it works.
Speaker 0: The on Air India domestic flight was way comfortable.
Speaker 1: It was way more monies too.
Speaker 0: No, it was actually way cheap.
Speaker 0: The international flight was literally the most uncomfortable chair.
Speaker 0: that was actually a chair I've ever sat on in my entire life.
Speaker 1: Was it just like a wooden stick that shoved up your butt?
Speaker 0: There was this bar like shoving its way into my ass through this thin ass cushion.
Speaker 1: Was it a broken chair?
Speaker 1: Were all the chairs the same?
Speaker 0: I think they were all the same because the guy next to me was squirming the whole time.
Speaker 0: And then I look at him and I'm like, "Is there a
Speaker 0: bar?".
Speaker 0: He's like right in my butt.
Speaker 0: And I was like, "Okay, it's not just
Speaker 0: me.".
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: But I engineered a solution.
Speaker 1: I asked for like- A pillow and you put it under your ass?
Speaker 0: They didn't have any extra pillows.
Speaker 0: So I asked for like eight blankets and I manufactured a device of blankets that worked okay.
Speaker 1: You know what the answer is?
Speaker 1: If you were to go to India- First class.
Speaker 1: Or a seat cushion.
Speaker 1: Just bring a seat cushion like the kind they use at football stadiums.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I try to travel really light and not carry stuff on me.
Speaker 1: Or you can get the neck pillow and just put it under your butt instead.
Speaker 0: The other important thing about the flight is that I now have ample evidence to say that I do not in fact suffer from jet lag and/or jet lag is a myth.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm very happy about that.
Speaker 0: I got there and everyone who flew with me like all the other people were wicked jet lagged.
Speaker 0: And literally I fly into India, it's evening, I get some dinner, I wander around, I go to bed, I wake up the next morning feeling great.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And everyone else like couldn't eat and bleh and bleh and bleh and bleh and I was fine.
Speaker 0: It was awesome.
Speaker 0: I think it's psychological.
Speaker 0: No, it actually is a real thing.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But some people are apparently immune to it.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: And- I've never had much of a problem with it.
Speaker 1: It's not a noticeable one.
Speaker 0: When was the last time you flew?
Speaker 0: more than five time zones?
Speaker 1: More than five times?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so when was that?
Speaker 1: Uh, 2000.
Speaker 0: Okay, that was 12 years ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: But the only problem that I have when I fly, because the same thing happened to Japan, is every day around 9, 30, 10 o'clock at night, I'm so tired.
Speaker 0: The second night I was there, I got out of this conference, go to my room and I'm like, "I'm going to check some
Speaker 0: internet.".
Speaker 0: And I literally opened my laptop and I remember starting to type my password in and then I woke up the next morning in the chair.
Speaker 0: The laptop was still sitting on my lap and I hadn't finished typing my password.
Speaker 1: Are you sure that wasn't jet lag?
Speaker 0: Scott, it was like 10 o'clock at night.
Speaker 0: So if that was jet lag, then jet lag's fine because it meant I went to bed at a reasonable goddamn hour.
Speaker 0: And I woke up at like 7 o'clock, which was when I wanted to wake up.
Speaker 0: Jet lag means you're not hungry and you can't get up in the morning and you're way tired all day.
Speaker 1: I definitely don't have that problem.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I get to Mumbai and I get a driver and he takes me to the fancy hotel.
Speaker 0: And the fancy hotel, Mumbai is weird because it's like ultra luxury, like this, like, "Shall I warm so's crack
Speaker 0: pipe?"
Speaker 0: fails to describe the opulent care that was taken of me when I showed up at this hotel.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, outside of the hotel were some straight up shantytown, sea of gods slums.
Speaker 1: It's basically Monaco, only bigger.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and more distributed.
Speaker 0: Like the slums are integrated and they're not all slums.
Speaker 0: Some of them are just very, very dense populated like residential areas.
Speaker 0: Some of them are shantytowns, but then like right next to it is like ultra luxury like hotel or ultra luxury condos.
Speaker 1: So, you know, in Monaco it's pretty much rich stuff in the middle, rich stuff in the water, and then the poor stuff is like on the outskirts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Mumbai is so dense.
Speaker 1: This is all intermingled, which is kind of great because in the US, right, we got rich and poor, but they're all super separated.
Speaker 1: Rich people live in the woods on long roads with gates.
Speaker 0: And in New York, like in New York City, there's ultra rich and there's the American equivalent of very poor, but you don't get to the level of the shantytowns in our cities.
Speaker 0: Our equivalent of that is like Appalachia.
Speaker 1: Or you live in like one of the, you know, projects, you know, public housing, whatever.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I give the hotel...
Speaker 1: It's not a shantytown.
Speaker 0: Of course, every building that I went into for this entire trip had even like malls and everything had metal detectors and security at every door and like crazy security everywhere.
Speaker 0: But the security was actually effective.
Speaker 0: They just made you walk through a metal detector and they were smart about it.
Speaker 0: Like every time I walked through my cell phone and my wallet would beep and the guy would like grab it outside my pocket.
Speaker 0: And he had this look on his face like this is a white guy and it's obviously a cell phone.
Speaker 0: He didn't like freak out about the bulge in my pocket.
Speaker 0: It clearly was not a gun.
Speaker 0: But the security was pretty reasonable.
Speaker 0: Like it amazes me how the countries that have actual terrorism have reasonable security.
Speaker 1: We had actual terrorism.
Speaker 0: We had actual terrorism over a decade ago.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And yet we have security theater that is both more intrusive and less effective than what goes on in like India.
Speaker 0: I'm so pissed off about that, but I'm not going to... This isn't a show about me complaining about security in the TSA.
Speaker 1: No, that's every show.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: But so I, you know, I get some dinner and then I decided to wander around Mumbai.
Speaker 0: So I go to walk out of the hotel.
Speaker 0: They were a guest like, where is Sir going?
Speaker 0: Where is Sir's driver?
Speaker 0: Like they were insistent like, where's your driver?
Speaker 0: Should we get your driver?
Speaker 0: Should we get your car ready?
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: you're walking out?
Speaker 0: Where are you going?
Speaker 0: And I was like, I'm just going somewhere.
Speaker 0: I'm walking out.
Speaker 0: I'll be back.
Speaker 0: And I kind of walked by over all their protests and wandered out in the streets.
Speaker 1: Did like Google Maps work?
Speaker 1: Could you find your way back with that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I didn't have data there because of my CDMA phone.
Speaker 1: But you had your, oh, everything there is GSM.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: You couldn't get a temporary phone with your corporate credit card?
Speaker 0: I didn't bother.
Speaker 0: I had a temporary phone, but I hadn't hooked it up yet.
Speaker 0: Like I hadn't gotten the data plan going.
Speaker 1: But it was just a regular phone.
Speaker 1: or was it a smartphone?
Speaker 0: It was a smartphone.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: So what I did is I turned on Google tracks and I started tracking because GPS works fine.
Speaker 0: So if I got lost, I could at least see where I started and navigate back to that.
Speaker 0: And that actually works.
Speaker 0: I wandered way, way off into Mumbai.
Speaker 0: I wandered through some of the.
Speaker 1: But if it was night, how did you like not get hit by cars and shit?
Speaker 0: So that was actually a concern.
Speaker 1: No kidding.
Speaker 0: So you see videos of like India and you see, you know, basically a three lane road in India is actually a five lane road plus two motorcycle lanes, you know, sidewalks.
Speaker 0: And it is amazing.
Speaker 0: There is literally no such thing as traffic laws there as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: Or at least if there are traffic laws, no one cares.
Speaker 0: But you get this impression watching those videos.
Speaker 0: that is totally safe.
Speaker 0: And like everyone because everyone's going so slow and paying so much attention that, you know, it just kind of works.
Speaker 1: Like in the videos, it's like you see crazy shit.
Speaker 1: But you also see people, you know, they're slowing down.
Speaker 1: They're taking their time.
Speaker 1: They're waiting for the spot.
Speaker 1: Then they move in.
Speaker 0: No, thousands die.
Speaker 0: The roads are death traps.
Speaker 0: Road deaths are one of the biggest problems in India.
Speaker 0: So many people die.
Speaker 0: It is crazy.
Speaker 0: So I walk out into the street and I'm on this kind of sidewalk and it's fine, except occasionally shanties were like built into the sidewalks.
Speaker 0: I have to like get around them.
Speaker 0: And that's a big problem in India, encroachment.
Speaker 0: People will like have a building.
Speaker 0: And then one day they put like some corrugated steel like around like a foot out from their store.
Speaker 0: And then they quietly take down the wall inside their building.
Speaker 0: And then they put the wall back up right at the edge of the steel.
Speaker 0: And then they move the steel another foot out.
Speaker 0: Stuff like that happens all the time.
Speaker 1: Why would you want to make your building longer?
Speaker 0: Oh, you want more space.
Speaker 0: Eventually you make up enough space to have an apartment in there or another store.
Speaker 1: You give it a whole store in the sidewalk space?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like there are some stores that were literally the size of like a closet.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 0: That's just how it is.
Speaker 0: It's very, very, very dense.
Speaker 0: I mean, India is a nation of more than a billion people.
Speaker 1: It's like if you can get a square inch, you're good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, but I wandered around through the streets.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, everyone was like, I was kind of impressed at how friendly everyone is.
Speaker 1: Why wouldn't they be friendly?
Speaker 0: Because, you know, in New York, everyone's not friendly.
Speaker 0: They're trying their best.
Speaker 1: The thing is, right, is like when you're packed in with a lot of people, you got to be friendly because not friendly doesn't work when you're so packed in with them.
Speaker 0: But I think because you're more packed in, there's like this extra onus to be friendly because you're really like in it together.
Speaker 0: Something goes down.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's like you're.
Speaker 1: just you're basically, you know, it's like you're when you're on the subway, you know, you're friendly because you're packed in like sardines, right?
Speaker 1: You're not going to be a jerk on the subway unless you're crazy.
Speaker 1: But you know, you can be a jerk when like, you know, you can go home and be all alone and not have to deal with the people yelling at you for being a jerk.
Speaker 0: So the way I figured out to walk around is I kind of watch what everyone else did and kind of followed crowds.
Speaker 0: Like I didn't walk anywhere that I didn't see someone else walking first.
Speaker 0: I was always following someone.
Speaker 0: And good strategy probably saved my life because there were straight up death traps.
Speaker 0: Like you could walk and without realizing it be in the middle of like train tracks or like crazy highway.
Speaker 1: Not death traps.
Speaker 1: Like someone's going to kill you.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: Death traps like a motorcycle is going to hit you because there's a thousand of them and none of them have headlights and no one has helmets.
Speaker 0: I rode some motorcycles, my co-workers, you know, they took me around town like when I was in a hydro bed later and I just got to ride on the back of motorcycles through this crazy traffic.
Speaker 0: No one wears helmets.
Speaker 0: It was it actually made me reminded me how awesome motorcycles are and I kind of want one again.
Speaker 1: Well, if we go to India, you know, I can do first thing at the airport, get a driver, buy a helmet where I did not see a helmet for sale anywhere.
Speaker 1: We could bring one.
Speaker 0: I guess you could.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't need I wouldn't necessarily bring like a crazy one like door if you're going to go around India.
Speaker 0: Here's the trick.
Speaker 0: It costs maybe 20 or 30 bucks to have a driver for an entire day who will drive you anywhere you want.
Speaker 1: But the road is still a death trap.
Speaker 1: You can get killed and still drive.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: And if you're in a car, you're basically safe because you're not going to get hit hard.
Speaker 0: The people who die or the people on motorcycles are in the little tuk tuks or the pedestrians.
Speaker 0: But in a car you're safe.
Speaker 0: And for like 20 or 30 bucks, a guy will drive you around all day, wait for you anywhere you go, take care of all your all your like baggage and everything.
Speaker 1: And the cars must be cheap or what?
Speaker 1: Like what kind of car is this?
Speaker 0: Well, because the exchange rate is interesting.
Speaker 0: It's about a thousand rupees.
Speaker 0: Like a thousand rupee note is like a 20.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: Twenty dollars.
Speaker 1: That's not bad.
Speaker 0: But the prices because of this, like half the country, like the country is modernizing so quickly.
Speaker 0: And yet there's this huge like mass of population that the disparity between rich and poor and the economies of these different areas are diverging so rapidly that in the five star hotel, I drop the equivalent of like a hundred bucks on dinner.
Speaker 0: And then the room service was actually.
Speaker 0: what do you think was the rooms?
Speaker 0: What do you think?
Speaker 1: Indian room service.
Speaker 1: I'm usually I'm usually the best at room service guessing game, but not when it's a foreign country.
Speaker 0: Five star hotel designed for foreigners who are rich businessmen at a conference.
Speaker 0: What do you think?
Speaker 0: Two eggs over easy and some toast would cost room service delivery.
Speaker 1: So in the US, that's like 40 bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If you're lucky.
Speaker 1: If you're lucky.
Speaker 1: Right now, because I'm not going to it is a five star hotel and it's fancy.
Speaker 1: So not going to be like one dollar.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And I'm not going to.
Speaker 1: it's got to be more expensive than like the diner here, which is like five bucks.
Speaker 0: It was cheaper than the diner.
Speaker 1: It's got to be like room service was cheaper.
Speaker 1: It's like seven, eight.
Speaker 0: No, Scott.
Speaker 0: I use the mini bar in my room because it was cheaper than what I pay for some of those things that a convenience store in the US.
Speaker 0: Are you kidding me?
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: I opened it.
Speaker 0: I was I wanted a Red Bull.
Speaker 0: I really need some cat.
Speaker 1: They had it there.
Speaker 0: There was Red Bull in the mini fridge and I'm like and I pick it up, I'm like, all right, this is going on the corporate card, but I'll get in trouble if I have a ten dollar Red Bull.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: And I look at the sheet and it's like a dollar.
Speaker 0: seventy five like a white.
Speaker 1: You should just ask for a case at that price because so there are two bucks here.
Speaker 1: I know you should be like, hey, how many Red Bulls can you guys get me?
Speaker 0: But yeah, room service was cheap, but like outside, like.
Speaker 0: I went to a restaurant like a normal restaurant to get dosa, which is basically like a crepe.
Speaker 0: It's the one Indian food I've never really seen in the US, but it's whatever.
Speaker 0: it is for breakfast.
Speaker 0: It's like a crepe.
Speaker 1: So was the Indian food there like?
Speaker 1: is our Indian food like the way Chinese food is or it's not the same?
Speaker 0: or is it the same stuff like, you know, it's actually well in New York, it's actually mostly the same.
Speaker 0: Other than that, the meat there was so much more tender.
Speaker 0: The last like.
Speaker 1: I mean, I imagine there's less food regulations.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But here's the thing.
Speaker 0: The most of the places I ate at just because the nature of my travel were like ultra fancy five star restaurants.
Speaker 0: So it's hard to compare because I was having the five star Indian food versus the three star equivalent in the US.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Because when we get Indian food, it's just like regular restaurant.
Speaker 1: We don't go to the five star Indian restaurant.
Speaker 0: So that really good Indian place where I used to go to and fish kill.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The meat was a thousand times more tender than that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I bet they just probably like.
Speaker 1: this is a five star restaurant, though, and it's in India.
Speaker 1: They probably just like, you know, they got that Tandoori Rock.
Speaker 0: They really care about the chicken.
Speaker 0: When I was in Hyderabad, there were so many like stalls, like a shop that was like, look at our chickens.
Speaker 0: We take awesome care of them.
Speaker 0: Check them out.
Speaker 0: Here's some of them.
Speaker 0: Here's why our eggs are so great.
Speaker 0: Here's videos of how we take care of our chickens.
Speaker 0: like eggs are a big goddamn deal with so many vegetarians and such.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's cool.
Speaker 1: And the culture there.
Speaker 1: So it's like if you're going to eat meat, you know, people are only.
Speaker 1: you know, a lot of people probably won't eat the meat unless it's like so in America.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like smoking or not is like the question you get in, I guess, backwater shitty places in the U.S.
Speaker 0: because, you know, that's gone in modern places like New York.
Speaker 0: But that question, that equivalent in India is basically veg or non veg.
Speaker 0: So everything you get from fast food everywhere like McDonald's there has veg and non veg options for everything.
Speaker 0: KFC has half the menus vegetarian and actually KFC there is pretty good.
Speaker 1: Wait, what is KFC vegetarian menu?
Speaker 1: They don't have any vegetables.
Speaker 0: Yes, KFC there does because it's just potato and potato.
Speaker 1: I mean, what else do they have?
Speaker 0: They have other vegetables like a whole bunch that you can get, like green beans, beans and potatoes.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 0: I've got you've eaten Indian food, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's vegetables in that shit.
Speaker 1: But this is KFC.
Speaker 1: What is KFC?
Speaker 0: have the same vegetables that Indian food has prepared in various different ways?
Speaker 1: I want to see the menu.
Speaker 0: They have like veggie sandwiches and things, but like I was at the airport, like I was really hungry.
Speaker 0: So I got like a Domino's pizza because I was in a hurry.
Speaker 1: I actually had Domino's.
Speaker 0: So the pizza options are great.
Speaker 0: It was veggie pizza, non veggie pizza, spicy pizza or spicy veggie pizza, spicy non veggie pizza.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: That spicy veggie pizza must have been so spicy, right?
Speaker 0: Wasn't that spicy?
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, that's what you ordered.
Speaker 0: But that was the spiciest thing I ate because I didn't end up going to a restaurant that actually had vindaloo.
Speaker 0: Just because, you know, I was only there for a week.
Speaker 1: That's a lot of days.
Speaker 0: But the baseline Indian food is about as spicy as so-called spicy Indian food here.
Speaker 0: Like I got some chicken biryani because of Hyderabad, like the chicken biryani is supposedly like famous.
Speaker 1: Always get the local specialty.
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: That was the best biryani ever.
Speaker 1: Always get the local specialty.
Speaker 0: But that biryani was way spicier than any biryani I've ever had.
Speaker 0: Go to Rochester and get the garbage plate.
Speaker 1: That's how it works.
Speaker 0: So I asked the coworkers, I was like, so how spicy is this?
Speaker 0: They were like, what do you mean spicy?
Speaker 1: It's not spicy.
Speaker 0: You want spicy?
Speaker 0: You'll die.
Speaker 1: Do they have like, every restaurant has like a bottle of pure cap in the back and they're just like, you know, using like a turkey baster and going squirting it all over the place.
Speaker 1: I mean, what are they doing?
Speaker 0: But so in a normal restaurant, I got an entire meal, like a meal that I could not finish for 40 rupees.
Speaker 1: When you said a thousand rupees is a
Speaker 1: 20? 40
Speaker 1: rupees is like a dollar.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So the despair, basically you can go around India on a ton of money or effectively no money.
Speaker 1: Well, see, I think this is the thing, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you.
Speaker 1: look at the U.S.
Speaker 1: and everyone, you know, we're all complaining about like the disparity of wealth, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the gap between the rich and the poor in the U.S.
Speaker 0: basically doesn't exist compared to most of the world.
Speaker 1: Well, no, no.
Speaker 1: It's like this gigantic disparity.
Speaker 1: But everyone in the U.S.
Speaker 1: has the same prices, mostly, right?
Speaker 1: It's not like poor people get cheaper.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 0: Scott, they do.
Speaker 0: Here's an example.
Speaker 0: In Rochester, me and Scott Johnson, we're at like, I think it was Astronomicon.
Speaker 0: Remember, we used to go and like do events for the anime club.
Speaker 0: So we go because no one else would fucking go and help us.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't go.
Speaker 1: Why would I go?
Speaker 0: So we were really hungry.
Speaker 0: And remember, I was kind of poor and Skodro didn't have a lot of money on him at the time either.
Speaker 0: So we're walking around and we see this little place, like a hole in the wall, like "restaurant" in quotes.
Speaker 0: So we go in and for 80 cents, we could get like a sausage, egg and cheese and like hash browns and toast and stuff.
Speaker 0: Where was this?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, Scott, there's places like that in America.
Speaker 0: You forget because you're in New York.
Speaker 0: There are places in the Bronx where you can get an entire meal for like two bucks.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, it's like, you know, Walmart is really just as low as it goes, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You can get it.
Speaker 0: Scott, I think you forget how cheap some food is just because...
Speaker 1: But like rich people also go to Walmart or Amazon or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they have they have options.
Speaker 0: They can go really cheap or really expensive anyway.
Speaker 1: But I mean, the difference.
Speaker 1: But I mean, like those prices are ludicrously low, right?
Speaker 1: Like 80 cents for the bacon, egg and cheese versus like you're talking like one cent.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's that's crazy.
Speaker 0: So the interesting thing is I had thousand rupee notes, which I use multiple of when I bought stuff in like the fancy parts of town.
Speaker 0: And people like literally would not have changed for that, for anything I might buy in other parts of town.
Speaker 0: So every denomination, a one rupee coin is actually directly useful and there are things you can buy for one rupee.
Speaker 0: Every denom, every like scale of the money from the from one to a thousand is directly useful all over the place.
Speaker 1: So in one rupee is the lowest, right?
Speaker 0: They don't have pennies.
Speaker 0: Like some people I would tip like five or ten rupees and I would buy like snacks and drinks for like twenty rupees.
Speaker 0: But then I'd have a dinner for like seven thousand rupees.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 1: It's like link.
Speaker 0: I actually have.
Speaker 1: Do you have any big shields?
Speaker 0: I actually have about ten thousand rupees with me because I didn't change it back yet.
Speaker 1: Well, you can just change it over like any place.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm waiting because the rupee is actually pretty low right now.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to hold out.
Speaker 1: Hold your weight.
Speaker 1: You're playing the market.
Speaker 1: I'm playing the market.
Speaker 1: You're waiting for the ten thousand rupees.
Speaker 0: Partly because I'll probably go back to India in May or June.
Speaker 1: Oh, OK.
Speaker 0: Which apparently is the hot season.
Speaker 0: It was like ninety five degrees there while I was there.
Speaker 0: Oh, baby.
Speaker 0: And that's the cold season.
Speaker 1: Did you see any bicycles that weren't motorized?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I saw a lot of mountain bikes.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: I saw one guy on like a road bike, but everyone was riding like mountain bikes.
Speaker 0: But the lens on everyone who was biking, pretty much everyone is riding motorcycles or Vespas or scooters or things like that or little took took like pseudo motorcycle cabs.
Speaker 0: So Mumbai was awesome, like walking around, though.
Speaker 0: What's interesting is if you go to the districts where foreigners might go, like in Hyderabad, we went to like a whole bunch of like.
Speaker 0: I saw Golconda, which is this ancient, like 14th century, 13th century fortified city that is in ruins.
Speaker 1: It was actually, you know, I like the old shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I got a ton of pictures of that.
Speaker 0: And two of my awesome co-workers like took me around and they were like explaining stuff.
Speaker 0: We went to all these temples.
Speaker 0: We did the touristy stuff.
Speaker 0: But because they're locals, like they knew with a worthwhile touristy stuff versus the stuff that's not worth bothering to see.
Speaker 0: So I got a really good and they were explaining stuff.
Speaker 0: And what was interesting is when I was walking around like a shanty town, nobody bothered me at all.
Speaker 0: Like I wandered into what the average American would probably fear for their lives.
Speaker 0: But really, everyone was just kind of chill living their lives in there.
Speaker 0: But no one bothered me.
Speaker 0: But in the tourist areas where foreigners might go, it's kind of sad.
Speaker 0: But I literally there were beggars like clawing at my clothes and like grabbing me and like demanding money and like putting their hands in my pockets and just like they were pick pockets.
Speaker 0: And it was.
Speaker 0: it was crazy.
Speaker 0: And basically, my two friends, the co-workers followed me around and were like at one point pushing beggars away from me and like shouting people away, like leave him alone.
Speaker 0: He's not going to give you any money.
Speaker 0: We're not going to let you rip him off.
Speaker 0: In Hindi, like there's yelling at these people and I keep them away from me.
Speaker 0: And it was.
Speaker 0: it was an interesting experience, but it was kind of like scarily stereotypical.
Speaker 0: Like it's.
Speaker 0: it's the kind of thing I didn't really expect to happen.
Speaker 0: And yet it actually happened exactly like it does in the movies.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But I got to see like the Gate of India.
Speaker 1: You should watch the relevant Galaxy Express episode.
Speaker 0: Or the the train station in Mumbai is like from the relevant Galaxy Express episode from the colonial times.
Speaker 0: It is opulent.
Speaker 0: Like it is as beautiful as Grand Central, but in a very different way.
Speaker 1: Well, the British made it right.
Speaker 0: It is an amazing building, you know, like extra amazing.
Speaker 0: But in the touristy areas, too, and I actually have no problem with this, like a museum I went to.
Speaker 0: It was five rupees for anyone who was an Indian, a Pakistani.
Speaker 0: And there's like a list of other countries.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Even a Pakistani.
Speaker 1: I thought they hated them.
Speaker 0: No, actually, the average people don't care at all.
Speaker 0: They really wish like they're actually really chill about the Muslims.
Speaker 0: There's a huge Muslim community in India.
Speaker 1: I know that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But like that slum, like the like the one slum that I saw that the cabbie was talking about.
Speaker 0: Two million people live in that slum.
Speaker 0: And apparently it's like ninety nine percent Muslim.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: But.
Speaker 1: But like that that number of rupees to get into the museum, that's like it might as well be free.
Speaker 0: So it's like five hundred rupees for anyone else.
Speaker 1: So that's still almost no money.
Speaker 0: So I paid 10 bucks to get in and a poor Indian or a normal Indian can pay five rupees to get in.
Speaker 0: It's the same as the New York museums.
Speaker 0: I go in for free.
Speaker 1: Well, I go in for a penny.
Speaker 1: One penny.
Speaker 1: You know that guy?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But the you know, the tourists basically pay the tourist tax.
Speaker 0: I'm OK paying the tourist tax.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, like, you know, if I'm in New York and I want to go to the museum, I pay one penny.
Speaker 1: If I go to some other place and it's not free museum day, I pay the suggested donation, whatever, because I'm not paying for it with taxes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's not you know, it's not.
Speaker 1: this is a federal museum like Smithsonian.
Speaker 1: that are not paying.
Speaker 1: I'm paying the minimum.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But like the ruined city was really, really interesting, partly because it wasn't curated in the same way.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like how everyone says, if you want to see Greek ruins, go to Turkey.
Speaker 0: Because in Greece, they're curated differently and or, you know, the city's kind of built up around it.
Speaker 1: They didn't have like little description plates on it.
Speaker 1: No, it was just.
Speaker 0: it was just here's a gigantic old ruined city fort.
Speaker 0: Wander around.
Speaker 0: Check it out.
Speaker 1: There aren't like ropes running from touching shit or it's not like don't sit here.
Speaker 0: And I hate to say it.
Speaker 1: But doesn't that make people ruin it?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: With their touching?
Speaker 0: Well, it kind of does.
Speaker 0: It's getting more ruined as time goes on.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 0: But it was actually really cool, like we just kind of wandered around it and like poked into these buildings.
Speaker 1: It's always, you know, it's always like a tough tradeoff.
Speaker 1: It's like you want to preserve this really old thing so more people can enjoy it.
Speaker 1: But you could also give up some of its preservation to have the people who are enjoying it now enjoy it more.
Speaker 0: I think you have to have a balance.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, and it seems like, you know, we got two extremes.
Speaker 1: But it's like, well, what can you do?
Speaker 1: that would be a balance?
Speaker 1: It's like, well, some museums in the U.S.
Speaker 1: were like, OK, don't touch anything.
Speaker 1: Here's one spot we want to let you touch.
Speaker 1: And it's like, of course, that thing gets touched to death exactly because you get all the touching is concentrated in one area.
Speaker 0: No touching.
Speaker 1: It's like instead of having the touching spread out over the whole thing, you concentrate in just one area, completely destroying that area 100 percent way faster than any of the other areas.
Speaker 0: So apparently, Golconda, though, is this huge, like fortified city with a big wall around it.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it has a Wikipedia page.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the neat things about it were it had this system where you could say things or clap like way down at the gates and you'd hear it all the way up at the top in the throne room.
Speaker 1: Whoa.
Speaker 0: So they could warn like, hey, shit's going down, go hide.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like really neat stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Did you go to the throne room and one of your friends stayed at the front and you played a little game?
Speaker 0: I just went up there and listened to people doing stuff down there.
Speaker 0: We didn't actually play the game because otherwise there were people who were trying to grab us and give a free, like give a tour, like, hey, I'll show you around.
Speaker 0: Then at the end, they were going to demand money and make a big scene.
Speaker 0: So we had to avoid those people like the plague.
Speaker 0: And also there was a tunnel, it's gone now, like it collapsed, I think a hundred years ago, between Golconda and Hyderabad, the city itself.
Speaker 0: And apparently you could escape.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the rulers would live in the city, but if shit went down, they'd escape into the tunnel and hide in the fortress.
Speaker 1: Oh, so they didn't live in the fortress.
Speaker 1: No, they didn't live in the city.
Speaker 1: Because it sucks to live in a fortress.
Speaker 0: Unless shit went down.
Speaker 1: Oh, not bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of neat stuff like that.
Speaker 0: I think I'm going to kind of cut this short because we've actually gone on a long time.
Speaker 0: I'll share other anecdotes whenever I have time on Geek Nights because I haven't even really talked about like 90% of what went on in India.
Speaker 1: It was only there for a week.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I did so much in that week that I'm still struggling to like tell the whole story.
Speaker 0: And I might get to go to Turkey and Germany like right after PAX.
Speaker 1: I got to go places.
Speaker 1: See, it's like I need vacation so I can go places.
Speaker 1: I want to go places real bad, but you don't have any vacation, but you're just getting business trips.
Speaker 1: That's cheating.
Speaker 0: So, Scott, you want to come with me?
Speaker 1: How can I come with you if you had to hire me or something?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you want to work for my company?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: All right, if my only job is to travel, then yes, official traveler.
Speaker 0: Your job is going to be writing Java code.
Speaker 1: My job will be the carrier of the corporate card.
Speaker 1: I'll be the wallet.
Speaker 0: Scott, you're going to be writing complex interfaces in Java.
Speaker 1: No, I won't.
Speaker 1: I don't want to do that.
Speaker 0: But then you'll get to go to Java.
Speaker 1: No, I don't want to do that either.
Speaker 1: I just want to go to Java without writing any Java.
Speaker 0: Hah.
Speaker 0: Pax is coming.
Speaker 1: Yeah, going there.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando Kay for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.