Speaker 0: It's Tuesday July 10th 2012.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm sky and this is geek nights tonight Pokemon conquest.
Speaker 0: Let's do this aka no bungas ambition with Pokemon.
Speaker 0: So we've.
Speaker 0: you might yell at me Scott for saying an old joke, but it's not a joke It's an anecdote so long ago, right guys We uh, we're doing like early geek nights and we might have talked about this on the show once And someone find what episode it was.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I figured out came up but also we at a convention.
Speaker 0: we're talking about video games and We brought this up as well.
Speaker 0: I think we were talking about like mispronunciations and how Like before the internet had audio and stuff like half the people who play D&D said dro and the other half said drow And sigil and sigil and those sorts of like mispronunciations.
Speaker 0: Manga Otakon are being quashed by the fact that there's an internet.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That was at least the argument.
Speaker 1: and Well, the Internet's also hurting it too because people are reading a lot on the internet and there's not always talking.
Speaker 1: and true So you can people are learning words that they wouldn't have learned without the internet, but they're not hearing the words.
Speaker 0: There's also a weird like resistance culture Like I know people who have been to more Otakons than we went to who to this day Despite hearing tens of thousands of people say Otakon and being corrected by us tens of thousands of times We'll say Otakon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm like, no that's a character in Metal Gear Spelled with the C and you're an idiot.
Speaker 1: It's the thing that I don't understand right?
Speaker 1: sometimes Let's say you're having conversation with someone.
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: if I if someone's talking to me and they've mispronounced a word Oh, you probably end up using the word because it's we're having conversation involving that topic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I'll pronounce it correct.
Speaker 0: you do what I do.
Speaker 0: I don't correct them.
Speaker 0: I just now.
Speaker 1: here's the thing.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing.
Speaker 1: I use it correctly.
Speaker 1: if I do that I know that I am thinking.
Speaker 1: I will use it correctly and hopefully teach this person to connect pronunciation.
Speaker 0: Maybe they're thinking the same thing.
Speaker 1: Maybe they're thinking the same way that lady.
Speaker 0: I was biking the other day and you know, we always complain about people who don't know how to use gears on their bike.
Speaker 0: And this lady is like you can change gears.
Speaker 0: and I realized she's yelling at me Because she doesn't know how gears work and she was giving the opposite advice.
Speaker 1: She was she knew that you could change them.
Speaker 1: that's a big step up.
Speaker 1: for most people she gets points.
Speaker 0: I had that problem when I've got my first geared bike when I was like eight.
Speaker 1: It's like I knew I could change them.
Speaker 1: But when do you change?
Speaker 1: which one do you use when people don't know?
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's a car where it tells you this up like at a panel or something.
Speaker 0: and then as an example I was like, so if any of you you know, just believe this how many of you played?
Speaker 0: Bunga's ambition on the NES and the audience was like, oh No, Bunga was a very common Pronunciation.
Speaker 1: you don't because when it's written out on the screen if you don't look at it closely You don't see that other a there.
Speaker 0: so you think I know Bunga and if you don't Watch it like if you're not an anime fan where you just kind of like you start to poor historian.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anime or Japanese person Like if you hear a lot of Japanese and you don't speak it you'll start to recognize that no the guy's name is not It's yeah, yeah, but you don't notice this.
Speaker 0: a Pokemon those from Tenchi manga.
Speaker 0: in high school I was hanging out with someone and someone's like blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Yeah kids.
Speaker 0: We're all like Yeah, okay So, yeah, no Bunga.
Speaker 1: what the worst thing is is I hate it when people admit there's some people who know the right pronunciation right.
Speaker 1: so they'll know that it's manga and not manga and And They will.
Speaker 1: there won't be arguing that it's that they're right.
Speaker 1: They'll say yeah, it is manga, but they won't say Manga, they'll say yeah, you're right and then they'll continue to say manga even though they're.
Speaker 0: every time I have those I always interrupt and it.
Speaker 1: the thing is are now I'm questioning.
Speaker 1: Sometimes I do that.
Speaker 1: I'll say Titan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: Are they doing the same?
Speaker 0: Well, that's why it's tricky.
Speaker 0: I mean, how often do we say Chipotle?
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: It's been like wow a friend of ours a few weeks ago was like you guys realize it's Chipotle right and I was like Yeah.
Speaker 0: And I didn't like.
Speaker 0: I didn't know what to say other than to explain in a very like laborious sense.
Speaker 0: We mispronounced it on purpose because we find it vaguely funny.
Speaker 0: Is that not hipsterism?
Speaker 1: I learned something today.
Speaker 1: you learn what is specifically a Chipotle pepper.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: I know what it tastes like but I don't know what it looks like, do you know What anything about it?
Speaker 0: I know that that Chipotle flavor is what is in for example Chipotle sauce.
Speaker 1: It's Chipotle.
Speaker 1: Yeah is a smoked jalapeno.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: It's not actually a different pepper.
Speaker 0: I didn't know that.
Speaker 1: I just learned that today.
Speaker 0: I learned today.
Speaker 0: like I always make a so did you?
Speaker 0: I learned yeah, it's okay And you I make enchiladas right like all the time.
Speaker 1: I like enchiladas So with the chicken and the sour cream.
Speaker 0: Anyway, enchiladas however are way harder to make than quesadillas.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes, so usually I'll be like I'm gonna make quesadillas like yesterday.
Speaker 0: I was like I'm gonna make quesadillas, and then I was thinking about it.
Speaker 0: I was like you know what.
Speaker 1: nah fucking in fact ate lunch at Chipotle today.
Speaker 0: Nah.
Speaker 0: Did you have a quesadilla?
Speaker 0: No But So I was like wait a minute Why don't I just put roasted poblanos in there, and I never thought to do that before and it was awesome.
Speaker 0: That story doesn't go anywhere.
Speaker 0: I was just.
Speaker 1: no I was trying to end this all right.
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 1: news all right.
Speaker 1: So gaming time right.
Speaker 0: it is gaming time.
Speaker 1: check this out.
Speaker 1: I'm checking.
Speaker 1: everyone heard about this steam green light coming soon.
Speaker 1: There's not a whole lot of info so we can't we're not gonna heavily analyze.
Speaker 0: Does this mean that captain dicks and the dick squad is gonna be on steam now?
Speaker 1: So is the thing right?
Speaker 1: so The way steam works now is you submit your game to valve and they have like a panel of people to decide What goes on steam and what doesn't go on aka dartboard?
Speaker 0: Yeah?
Speaker 1: What they want to do is they want to change it to.
Speaker 1: basically it seems like They're gonna have like a reddit of game submissions, so if you have a game you submit it to You know steam and then Users of steam game players will go and vote like yeah that game.
Speaker 1: We want to be able to buy that game as fuck that one right and vote games up and down and the high and then You know the valve people.
Speaker 1: I think they still make the final decision, so if everyone votes up poop on a stick It doesn't mean it's gonna show up on steam, but they're gonna greatly take into consideration What games gamers want to be on steam and what games they don't want to be on steam?
Speaker 0: It's a nice sort of save.
Speaker 0: I mean it'll be.
Speaker 0: it's easy for something to admit.
Speaker 0: I mean how many times even do we as connected to the internet as we are like miss out on a big boat That's about to set sail.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing I don't understand.
Speaker 1: all right We have this problem where it's like.
Speaker 1: okay We don't want to just accept everything in the universe to be on steam because it'll be an Atari problem.
Speaker 1: And also you know iOS problem.
Speaker 1: right you search for any apps on iOS, and it's impossible.
Speaker 1: But I think that part of that problem with iOS even though they do have a panel approving things is Just it's impossible to search and organize.
Speaker 0: right Because categories and things are arbitrary and usually way too broad.
Speaker 1: exactly I think this is actually you know the real problem is why don't they just let every game on steam?
Speaker 1: that isn't Sarah for example viruses and malware and games that don't work.
Speaker 1: I think what they should do is they should let almost everything on steam and Then have the voting.
Speaker 1: so if a game.
Speaker 1: It's on steam you could buy it right, but it's never gonna be on sale.
Speaker 1: It's never gonna be on the home page.
Speaker 1: It's never gonna be promoted, but it's there if you dig way.
Speaker 0: But Maintaining this vote.
Speaker 1: know the but the users are voting which games are gonna be on the steam home page.
Speaker 1: Right control it that that's a separate thing because main main still have the user voting But have the voting after the game is in Maintaining the games on steam.
Speaker 0: if you let everything in adds a lot of kind of back-end work and grooming and mate.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that's the thing.
Speaker 1: is you?
Speaker 1: they need to give the game developer more control?
Speaker 0: No, no because then it's too easy for malware and bullshit to slip in.
Speaker 1: Obviously you know you would approve the people individually.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: yeah, that's maybe.
Speaker 1: I improve the people as opposed to the game.
Speaker 0: I do not want that to happen because well one I don't want to make more work for them and two I don't care because I Already have too much information available in all senses on the internet at all times, so I need Good gatekeepers and valve is really good at being a gatekeeper of gaming right now.
Speaker 1: Maybe I should make that.
Speaker 1: I'll just make generic download stuff store.
Speaker 1: Anyone can sign up and oh, but you're just curate it.
Speaker 1: No I don't curate at all.
Speaker 1: anyone who wants to can upload things into the store.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be child porn porn spam and viruses and sell them for money.
Speaker 0: child porn spam viruses.
Speaker 0: And then you use nothing, but child porn spam viruses.
Speaker 1: the users will vote and report spam and viruses.
Speaker 0: And then what are you gonna?
Speaker 0: Do go manually delete the thousands of.
Speaker 1: no it'll work the same way.
Speaker 1: that like you know red and all those other things work so full of garbage except for the.
Speaker 0: It won't work.
Speaker 1: nobody why read it works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because there's no overhead to hosting some text that no one up votes.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: There's a little bit more overhead to hosting 100 megabyte files.
Speaker 1: I'm not hosting your files for you I'm just writing the store part.
Speaker 1: all right so and the listing part.
Speaker 1: you have to host the file somewhere And then when someone buys it takes the link that you gave and gives it to the person.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's any money in that.
Speaker 1: I take the cut in between because everyone's gonna be coming to my site to buy stuff.
Speaker 0: No, they're not.
Speaker 0: they're gonna be going to the more curated walled gardens.
Speaker 0: Even my stupid x230 has this Lenovo like marketplace.
Speaker 0: I had to uninstall internal.
Speaker 0: Oh god They're like.
Speaker 0: hey you want to buy apps for your laptop.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 0: I'm like.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's called software on a computer.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's.
Speaker 0: I'm waiting for Monday to really talk about that, but you don't reminded me of it reminded me of Packard Bell Navigator.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the other thing about this green light is I'm kind of wondering You're gonna get into a situation Eventually where there's like some indie game studio, and they make a game and maybe people like it But it doesn't get enough support And it doesn't get in.
Speaker 1: and then like you made a game And now you can't get it on Steam because no one likes it even before it's been out.
Speaker 1: It's like oh That'll be drama.
Speaker 0: I think the bigger drama there will also be drama.
Speaker 0: be drama because if no one likes it No one will notice or care Like it, but not enough yeah, so there won't be drama.
Speaker 0: Drama if there is a game that enough people want in that is offensive to the vast majority of people.
Speaker 1: What about a situation where you get a game?
Speaker 1: That's like pretty big and it's in there But like no one wants it in there like rail the train simulator right something like that comes along where it's high production value a lot Of money, but that train simulator imagine if green light was around before the train rail whatever rail works.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling you're putting green light was around before rail works.
Speaker 1: You think rail works that have made it in.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling you're putting a lot more power in the hands of this thing that I think is actually Doesn't have a lot of power then why is it?
Speaker 1: why they've been doing it.
Speaker 0: I think all it is very simply Not not just no not PR.
Speaker 0: I trust valve more than that.
Speaker 1: let us see what's coming on the pipeline.
Speaker 0: I think it's nothing more than a Check to make sure that valve does not miss out on a ship that is sailing because they're too busy making games to pay Attention to what's going on in the Internet?
Speaker 0: That's all it is.
Speaker 0: it would be the equivalent of if we had a thing like we'd set up a Twitter thing.
Speaker 1: So someone's got a hot new indie game, but valve doesn't know about it because they haven't heard about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's got a following coming out of like left field in some community somewhere.
Speaker 1: So now it's easier to submit it to steam and it gets a bunch of up votes.
Speaker 0: if there's an organized community They'll get it on the radar, so it's right Goes on here and votes up like you know.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: valve has the final say apparently and you know what hello kitty game that could be good.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying they'll go vote up.
Speaker 1: some nonsense of course.
Speaker 0: the thing is that stuff's been going on forever.
Speaker 0: I mean the UF.
Speaker 1: is valve gonna put their own games in here to fear what they should work on.
Speaker 0: I Would do that if I was valve.
Speaker 1: I would launch green light and then half-life 3 like the first thing in there And I'd be like when it gets enough votes.
Speaker 1: Maybe we'll work on it.
Speaker 1: I would say that would get everyone to sign into green light.
Speaker 0: I would set the threshold of votes it requires to something like 95% of the world population.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 1: the other thing is that oh?
Speaker 1: Right the only people are gonna go to green light are Hardcore people or people who are sent from another community to go there specifically for a specific game.
Speaker 1: So a lot of the games that have the appeal mostly to an audience that is not green light users is going to be missed.
Speaker 1: But then again those people probably aren't steam users But some of them are.
Speaker 1: so so that's a lot of games are gonna get missed even in green light because the huge audience For those games isn't green lighting.
Speaker 0: thus I think the only real use of this in the end is to make sure that valve does not miss something that has a Dedicated following, but otherwise would be off the radar.
Speaker 0: Yes, so in much more really kind of ludicrous news Kickstarter is great.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about the penny arcade thing.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: That's Wednesday.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of kick-starting going on.
Speaker 1: Kickstarter was sort of like all right.
Speaker 1: it peaked and it was sort of well.
Speaker 1: No it's peaking again.
Speaker 1: Well keeps making new peaks it is but news wise not any other wise.
Speaker 1: yes.
Speaker 0: now the penny arcade Kickstarter Just to get it out here.
Speaker 0: I think is both fine and a good idea, and I'm not giving any monies - no I'm not giving money to it either probably But that's not gaming news.
Speaker 0: That's culture and whatever.
Speaker 0: I want to talk about a different Kickstarter that Got as it was at $500,000 when I looked at it at work, and then when I got home.
Speaker 0: It's at 1.3 million dollars.
Speaker 1: What the fuck.
Speaker 0: and It's nothing.
Speaker 0: It's I I am Our people.
Speaker 0: well.
Speaker 0: No I was about to ask our people this naive.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes I we know that because of what kinds of kickstarters do?
Speaker 0: very well.
Speaker 0: This is a Kickstarter to make the A new kind of video game console.
Speaker 0: Why a like?
Speaker 1: oh, yeah, I think it's oh, yeah except I Maybe it's more like.
Speaker 1: you know if you look you can see the word you in there.
Speaker 1: So maybe it's like instead of you.
Speaker 1: uh it's oh, yeah, I think it's oh, yeah like Because it would be like you if the Y was in front.
Speaker 1: so be like ooh.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, all right, so it's got 10,800. and well let me refresh Eleven thousand three hundred and ninety backers and it got another hundred thousand dollars in like the last two minutes.
Speaker 1: so it's a basically one and a half million.
Speaker 0: as of this podcast recording make what is essentially an Android phone with no data plan that plugs into your TV to play shitty Android phone games on your TV.
Speaker 0: That is what this is.
Speaker 0: I see no indication that is a game controller.
Speaker 1: Also, I guess HD output yeah up to 1080p and it can do a few other things such as I guess can it like stream video or something right Netflix or website?
Speaker 0: so far no it'll have an app store that looks suspiciously like the Xbox 360 interface and It's basically the netbook of game consoles.
Speaker 0: not even it's not even that No one's.
Speaker 0: this isn't powerful enough to make good games.
Speaker 1: No, it's just play the mobile phone games, but on your TV instead.
Speaker 0: not a lot of people are going to go for this.
Speaker 1: man I really need I really need a game controller to play anger birds on my TV And and I need to buy a whole console just for that.
Speaker 1: so so here's anger birds on Xbox, huh?
Speaker 1: you think if anger birds needed to be on TV would already be on Xbox Live.
Speaker 0: and How come there's no touch screen interface for the kinds of games?
Speaker 0: It'll probably be on it.
Speaker 1: I think that has a controller.
Speaker 1: so they're gonna make controller.
Speaker 0: you know they.
Speaker 0: they think that people are going to make dedicated games for this thing and The examples they show.
Speaker 1: can I just use any Android game?
Speaker 0: that where the inputs can be slightly modified like for they think people will Design games for it, and it'll be easy to do so because you develop in the same way.
Speaker 0: you develop a game for an Android phone Now or an Android tablet.
Speaker 0: they show Minecraft as an example of a game.
Speaker 0: They want on here, okay Yeah, minecraft with a controller would be great.
Speaker 1: minecraft is already on the Xbox I know with a controller.
Speaker 1: I know so it's already.
Speaker 1: you can also get it for iOS.
Speaker 0: So there's so many things wrong with this project that I don't even know where to begin.
Speaker 1: Why do you even want this?
Speaker 1: why?
Speaker 0: it's first off.
Speaker 0: 1.5 million dollars for a business venture like this is Not even small peanuts 1.5.
Speaker 0: Million dollars doesn't exist in terms of like real company venture capital.
Speaker 1: yeah Also, how are you gonna even though?
Speaker 1: This is cheap hardware?
Speaker 1: How many of them do you think you can make?
Speaker 0: Not even just that like.
Speaker 1: the controller is probably right if it's any if it's a good controller.
Speaker 1: It's probably 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: Here's what the Kickstarter gets.
Speaker 0: one They will convert their prototype into production ready models and get all the regulatory approvals to deliver developer kits.
Speaker 0: So we can have you know even though the console will include an SDK at launch.
Speaker 0: Three place production orders to build the things and for ideally fund some first-party games.
Speaker 1: Yeah people seem to Really Latch on to these things.
Speaker 0: This is not one.
Speaker 0: if this happens There's no use for it.
Speaker 0: I can't conceive of a world where I would use this.
Speaker 0: my laptop is more powerful than this.
Speaker 0: my old laptop is more powerful than This.
Speaker 1: I think it's.
Speaker 1: you know what's weird.
Speaker 1: usually when you see these things right the projects like this Raspberry Pi Arduino type things right there always Development things right.
Speaker 1: it's like hey everyone buy the Raspberry Pi cheap super cheap Linux computer.
Speaker 1: That's barely powerful enough to do anything, but it's super open.
Speaker 1: you can buy this and develop for it.
Speaker 1: It sells a lot, but it sells to programmers and hobbyists.
Speaker 1: This is super open, but it's like why does this need to go to?
Speaker 1: Hobbyist do we really need this?
Speaker 1: it's called a computer Right.
Speaker 0: so I'm gonna read some text from this cuz it's just.
Speaker 0: it reeks of this.
Speaker 0: It doesn't reek of a scam like the Phantom console.
Speaker 0: this reeks of naive idealism hmm, but it's working.
Speaker 0: because One point I mean it read five again.
Speaker 0: All right it got another $50,000.
Speaker 0: all right in the time we were talking.
Speaker 1: kickstarter good website auto Frequently updating that number.
Speaker 1: unlike YouTube can't update its view number about this project.
Speaker 0: We love console games.
Speaker 0: There's something about a big HD TV and digital surround that fills up a living room.
Speaker 1: So I have a computer.
Speaker 1: platformer.
Speaker 0: sports games arcade classics and experimental indie games just feel bigger on a TV screen.
Speaker 0: It's how most of us grew up gaming, but some people are missing out.
Speaker 0: We get it.
Speaker 0: smart phones and tablets are getting all the new titles Because I can care and they're what's hot.
Speaker 0: yeah The console market is pushing developers away And we're seeing a brain drain.
Speaker 0: some of the best most creative game makers are focused on mobile and social games because these platforms are more developer friendly.
Speaker 0: I Think the computer is the most developer friendly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think so.
Speaker 0: So I don't know what to say.
Speaker 0: all of you who bought into this.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna make a prediction.
Speaker 0: I predict That you will not get your Within a reasonable time.
Speaker 1: I have kick-started right the hex bright estimated delivery.
Speaker 0: oh, okay, sorry estimated delivery for September was Reserving your username in their app store.
Speaker 0: Oh here's where this is extra bullshit.
Speaker 0: quote.
Speaker 0: We're handing the reins over to the developer with only one condition at least some gameplay has to be freed.
Speaker 0: We borrowed from the free-to-play model from games like League of Legends.
Speaker 0: Anyway, triple town and many others.
Speaker 0: developers can offer a free demo with a full game upgrade in-game items or powers Or ask you to subscribe.
Speaker 1: this isn't even open if they're forcing developers to do certain things.
Speaker 0: And as we've talked about on gig nights There is evidence that if you provide a demo of your game your games not gonna sell.
Speaker 1: Well Xbox also forces every game to have a demo.
Speaker 0: I know anyway, but Borrowed from the free-to-play This it's not even like.
Speaker 0: this is just an open console like that makes it easy to make indie games on the computer.
Speaker 0: They're basically really yeah.
Speaker 0: Getting this at the same kind of bullshit That's on phones.
Speaker 0: people only play those games because they're waiting for like their subway sandwich to get done, right?
Speaker 1: I do see a space.
Speaker 1: if someone could move in to where if you could actually get enough developers on board Beforehand pre not post to where.
Speaker 1: if you made a console for the television That was open where anyone can make a game for it That you could make a move because you'll get a bunch of games that Microsoft and Sony will not have.
Speaker 1: and if you can maybe do a steam greenlight situation You know then you could maybe you know work your way in especially since the consoles That are big now are dated and they're letting them go too long.
Speaker 0: Well, I if I did that it would be a software console as in it'd be software like boxy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that run is a platform for running games a little you mean like steam a little more.
Speaker 0: I was about to say Curated and walled garden and like self-contained because steam really is launching his external applications.
Speaker 0: I'd have it all embedded.
Speaker 0: and yeah more like a phone app store.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but that's not what this is.
Speaker 1: No, it's not not at all.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know why you would give money to this But the point I was making before is I can't really 11,000 Started this flashlight and I why did you kick start that?
Speaker 0: it's not even that cool.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty awesome flashlight.
Speaker 1: I needed a flashlight.
Speaker 1: It's super durable and is super LED super bright.
Speaker 0: You can buy super durable LED flashlights for less than you kick started by now.
Speaker 1: Anyway, they still haven't received it.
Speaker 1: So if those guys can't even make a flashlight they do keep updating there.
Speaker 0: That was the hex light, right?
Speaker 1: Right hex bright, whatever you they haven't delivered the flashlight yet.
Speaker 1: Then when you think you're getting a fucking game console from these other guys now Here's my other.
Speaker 1: who even are these people that are doing this?
Speaker 0: I'm going to oh A video game project in Los Angeles by oh, yeah, so they also called themselves.
Speaker 0: Yeah Okay There's not a lot of information about them.
Speaker 0: They've got some quotes that are great.
Speaker 0: so they got like people in the industry to talk about them.
Speaker 0: and Here is a quote from oh they changed the quotes.
Speaker 0: I had a quote I was gonna read.
Speaker 0: that was there before and it's gone.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's a wrong quote.
Speaker 0: No, it was a right quote.
Speaker 0: Basically.
Speaker 0: It was our friend who made karate ka and oh wait Here it is Jordan.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes Who wouldn't want a beautiful piece of industrial design that sells for $99?
Speaker 0: plug straight into your TV and gives you an access to?
Speaker 0: a huge library of games.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: That's a true statement.
Speaker 0: I would love that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think this is it Does that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, what's their library of games right now?
Speaker 1: no games I just I don't even Whatever, let's move on.
Speaker 0: Okay So anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: so, you know in the morning, you got your wallet got your sleeves Got your I forget whatever else.
Speaker 0: he said heaves and I guess he meant clothes.
Speaker 0: He was holding up a tie And then you can't find your goddamn keys and you're late for work while the phone keys, yep the mantra of the everybody everybody in the whole world There are people who don't have phone.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, it's or key modern society world.
Speaker 0: So anyway, not anyway this is just a kind of This.
Speaker 0: the song sounds like the kind of thing that Lonely Island would do.
Speaker 0: the animation is actually pretty good.
Speaker 0: This is clever pretty original Pretty funny and I think what sells it is the face that the guy is making when he's looking into the places where his keys Aren't.
Speaker 1: yeah, I watch this.
Speaker 1: I enjoy it.
Speaker 1: We'll watch again.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: He just the guy has such a pissed-off face.
Speaker 0: It's perfect.
Speaker 0: Now I'll warn you this is a tangential discussion.
Speaker 0: You know, those are.
Speaker 0: there are ghettos on the internet like especially in YouTube.
Speaker 0: like once you click on like you get to certain videos and then the Recommendations like suddenly turn into a certain set of videos and they kind of all funnel you eventually toward that he-man.
Speaker 0: So, I think that's the end.
Speaker 0: that's that's like you'll end up there no matter what.
Speaker 0: but anyway this video You can learn on your own like it's for like a webcomic and the guy has a ton of other animations and things.
Speaker 0: But it is very close to the dog-headed girl ghetto on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Just warning.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you start clicking on videos that are related to these videos You will get into interestingly furry territory in a hurry.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all I'm saying.
Speaker 0: I want it.
Speaker 0: I want to do a show on.
Speaker 1: I guess you found this because you were browsing the furry things.
Speaker 0: actually, you know how I got to this from ponies From friendship is witchcraft stuff.
Speaker 0: All right, and I got to that from face cow.
Speaker 1: Yeah Calfery, huh?
Speaker 1: Bovine no file no furry cow fucker Highland cattle Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Oh There's some cow furries right there.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Okay, go on.
Speaker 1: so check this out, you know the old D&D cartoon the incredibly old Old-old school D&D cartoon that was on Saturday morning.
Speaker 0: It's a shame the guy who made it died before he made it.
Speaker 1: Okay, anyway These guys took that cartoon and I think they edited a bunch and they have a 13-minute clip here.
Speaker 1: That is hilarious.
Speaker 1: Where what they did is they redubbed the whole thing and what they redubbed it with is their own voices and they did a pretty Good job, but it's not the voices of the characters.
Speaker 1: It's the voices of People at a D&D tables.
Speaker 1: like you hear the dice rolling whenever they get pop.
Speaker 1: whenever guys about to cast a spell or something or Attack the bill pause you'll hear a dice rolling sound effect and the guy would be like you take a ticket hit.
Speaker 1: And I'm like wham right and it's like it's.
Speaker 1: it's really funny.
Speaker 0: It's actually pretty great.
Speaker 1: It's awesome.
Speaker 1: Great job.
Speaker 1: Great idea winners.
Speaker 1: I think it's actually.
Speaker 1: this is pretty old.
Speaker 1: It was uploaded to YouTube in January 2011 but I haven't seen it before or I don't remember it.
Speaker 1: It could have even been a thing of the day before who knows but here it is again or the first time Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment kinetic on this weekend Hartford, Connecticut I'm gonna hear it again about it again for a whole year.
Speaker 0: Convention Center, July 13 14 15.
Speaker 0: We scheduled a metric fuck ton of panels and I got the numbers.
Speaker 1: the rest of the convention not our responsibility.
Speaker 0: However While we say that don't think they were denigrating it because for example or games best board games.
Speaker 1: at any convention I have ever been and that includes all that includes packs every convention.
Speaker 1: Best board games.
Speaker 1: you come you play the board games.
Speaker 1: They're the best biggest best baddest library.
Speaker 1: plenty of tables No waiting you friggin play.
Speaker 1: when you return the game you get tickets.
Speaker 1: You can use the tickets to get games real games.
Speaker 1: It doesn't take that many tickets like five tickets.
Speaker 1: awesome game for free Just for you get busy get paid in games to play board games.
Speaker 1: You could just come to Connecticut and do only that and you'll basically pay for your badge in board games.
Speaker 0: And there's other stuff to do like I don't know super hard five.
Speaker 1: You can't miss that you got but you better take out a game right before super our fight.
Speaker 1: Bring it up to super our fight.
Speaker 1: play it and after super our fight return.
Speaker 0: You mean in the absolutely crowded main events all that's right.
Speaker 1: bring spot it.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: that aside We will be at the petty arcade expo prime labor 2012. this year We will be doing at least one panel.
Speaker 0: Let me pull up the details because I can tell you right now Where I got the email that says you are allowed to talk about this.
Speaker 0: All right as opposed to the emails that didn't say that yet.
Speaker 0: all right Love them.
Speaker 0: I love how you know years ago.
Speaker 0: I Responded before like we knew any of the people over there.
Speaker 0: like we're like come on packs.
Speaker 0: Please let us do a panel.
Speaker 0: We'll be super good.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: We're just we were gonna go to the first packs.
Speaker 1: Oh wait anyway.
Speaker 1: No matter what yep.
Speaker 1: And so it's like well if we're gonna go let's apply for a panel.
Speaker 1: so we did.
Speaker 0: yep We looked at the site were like oh there this seems to be only for professionals.
Speaker 0: fuck it Let's go for it anyway doesn't hurt.
Speaker 0: They'll fly.
Speaker 0: yeah, and now we've Presented every packs you've ever been to.
Speaker 0: but so what the after that one I emailed I was like so when are we allowed to talk about it?
Speaker 0: cuz you know you know some cons are dicey about that stuff.
Speaker 0: Since then every time you get the official email it says in red You are free to tweet talk whatever you can say anything you want.
Speaker 0: It's totally okay.
Speaker 0: It's not a secret.
Speaker 0: Say what you want.
Speaker 1: This is a thing that I hate.
Speaker 1: right is like you know I'm the kind of person where if you tell me secrets like if I worked at a company that Apple I would just tell everything and I'd be fired, but I would just tell everything.
Speaker 0: I don't tell something.
Speaker 0: if it if I don't see a need to depends like if there's malfeasance I'll tell.
Speaker 1: if I owned a company like Apple.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't keep any secrets right.
Speaker 1: I just be like tell everyone I just all those secret procedures.
Speaker 1: I just get rid of them.
Speaker 0: well I think I think what I'm gonna do next year for kinetic on scheduling This is super.
Speaker 1: not that might have consequences, but that's just how you know I am scheduling next.
Speaker 0: next year is set a begin date like January for submissions and Set a final submission date of like X. But I'm gonna set a second date in like April or maybe even March or yeah March.
Speaker 0: and the idea is once that date comes.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna start scheduling stuff Live.
Speaker 0: like I pick one panel and approve it.
Speaker 0: it appears on the website with its slot like right then.
Speaker 0: So the website will show live from like March through July.
Speaker 0: Every schedule change as it happens.
Speaker 1: The point is is that I get into that you get into a situation like this right where for example if I was working at Apple and I was an employee and I told secrets they'd fire me and I'm like oh whatever You know cuz like how badly do I want to keep that job?
Speaker 1: not so badly right, but if Pax tells me a secret It's like this horrible dilemma.
Speaker 1: It's like one hand Do not keep secrets other hand do not want to be banned from Pax.
Speaker 1: the way I get around Cuz I it's like you know fired from Apple and whatever banned from Pax.
Speaker 0: no I don't know what I do if I get banned from Pax, dude I should try.
Speaker 1: we should do a fake ban from Pax.
Speaker 1: I obviously can't do this now right But I could get so.
Speaker 1: I could go with some enforcers and they could pretend to ban you from Pax And you would be like Scott.
Speaker 0: if I were the enforcers I?
Speaker 0: would Actually make you think that they for real banned you for doing the banning son, maybe That's also good, but the point is I can't do that to you now.
Speaker 1: You can't do it to me now, but we can do it to someone else.
Speaker 0: It doesn't listen to show hey Dave Riley You're banned from Pax.
Speaker 0: He's not gonna.
Speaker 1: Is he gone to pet.
Speaker 0: I don't know Connecticut.
Speaker 0: oh Yeah You know what.
Speaker 0: next year.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna get my tool.
Speaker 0: Oh shit cuz he was.
Speaker 0: he's expressed some interest But it was too late to work it all out.
Speaker 0: We're gonna try to get him next year because there was a need.
Speaker 1: or anime content.
Speaker 0: There was a dearth of anime content submitted and Two of my biggest anime content providers both had unrelated personal problems and had to bail at the last minute.
Speaker 1: Kinetic on is lacking many forgotten dubs Mike.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I'll put that shit in main events.
Speaker 1: anyway We can.
Speaker 1: we've only we controlled the main event so I do not want to you such good.
Speaker 1: I know I know just to schedule it.
Speaker 1: I just be like what cosplay chess.
Speaker 0: nope Anyway We will be doing a new triple threat this time called short subjects in gaming on Friday August 31st at 3 30 p.m.. In the Wolfman theater.
Speaker 1: That's met.
Speaker 1: a moment has been going on for much longer than a moment.
Speaker 1: But we do have to say you should visit us on the internet and all the places for our crew.
Speaker 1: calm Twitter Google+ Facebook's etc.
Speaker 1: etc.
Speaker 1: we have a newsletter now You can sign up to it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna maybe email the second newsletter soonish.
Speaker 0: We have a sister show called radio free equestria.
Speaker 0: That's on YouTube all about ponies.
Speaker 1: yep, and the book club book is still Qteen84.
Speaker 1: we finished it.
Speaker 1: we are gonna do a show on it.
Speaker 1: We just sort of been missing Thursday shows lately because of holidays and Kinetic on Thursday.
Speaker 1: So on is this Thursday, so no show.
Speaker 0: you guys know Generally in the winter when we do a lot of extra shows and in the summer is when we miss a lot of show.
Speaker 1: So probably the next Thursday show which is probably two weeks from now is gonna be Qteen84.
Speaker 1: Read that book is a good book.
Speaker 1: rim pick another book club.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna tell you guys right now I'm deciding between two books.
Speaker 1: What are the two books?
Speaker 1: the two books?
Speaker 0: I'm deciding between are the Great Gatsby Because I've never actually read it and the movie that's coming out looks Super good.
Speaker 1: I will gladly read any book.
Speaker 1: that is a famous classic that I have not read which is most of.
Speaker 0: so here's the other Option.
Speaker 0: this book was referenced Numerous times in Deus Ex so there's a nerd connection and It looks really interesting.
Speaker 0: It's called the man who was Thursday.
Speaker 0: never heard of it Colin a nightmare written in 1908. all right, it's about an Edwardian era London police officer who pretends to be an anarchist to infiltrate an anarchist group and Ends up taking over that group because he's more charismatic and persuasive about anarchism than anyone who runs it.
Speaker 0: and Shit goes crazy from there.
Speaker 0: Supposedly this book is famous and great in literary circles, but a lot of people otherwise haven't heard about it.
Speaker 0: there's a BBC radio adaptation and Those are my two choices.
Speaker 0: I'm completely ambivalent.
Speaker 0: so guys.
Speaker 1: I'll take either one.
Speaker 0: Tell me which one.
Speaker 1: are you gonna do a vote?
Speaker 1: No, it's your pick so you can do whatever you want.
Speaker 0: you guys tell me you may or may not sway me I might do the great Gatsby just because the movies coming and I want to read it before that movie comes out.
Speaker 1: I'm considering for my next pick crime and punishment.
Speaker 1: I've already read that.
Speaker 1: I have not.
Speaker 0: I would read it again.
Speaker 0: I've read it like three times.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what it's about.
Speaker 0: You don't know what.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you what.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: it's about a guy who commits a crime and gets punished.
Speaker 0: Oh, so actually no It's about a guy convinced crime and doesn't get punished and as a result ends up.
Speaker 0: That's actually worse.
Speaker 1: Oh, I kind of also.
Speaker 1: I know that there's you might not know this There is an Osamu Tezuka crime and punishment manga.
Speaker 0: I know about that.
Speaker 0: I've not read it.
Speaker 0: I've never seen anything from it.
Speaker 1: I saw I saw the Japanese edition of one volume of it.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to read that too, but it's not in English.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so anyway No, Bunga's ambition with Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Okay, so here's the deal.
Speaker 1: You might not know about this or you might because we talked about it In Japan, they make a lot of games.
Speaker 1: Don't come out here and we're pissed because we don't get them.
Speaker 1: and they're usually these quirky games that are awesome on paper.
Speaker 1: for example, you know What's the game like, you know Phoenix Wright was a great example of a game That was awesome on paper and then they brought it here and oh wait It was actually awesome, but sometimes they have games over in Japan that are awesome on paper that we don't get like super robot wars Evangelion vs Voltron vs Macross vs every robot all the games not actually that fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever haters.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know.
Speaker 1: so on the one hand We always want every game every piece of artwork period that is made to be released to the entire world.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand sometimes you're disappointed because like someone will go to the effort of translating something and we won't buy it Because it's not that good You know, so it goes both ways.
Speaker 1: So when we knew that they were making a Nobunaga's Ambitions X Pokemon mashup, we're like goddamn Awesome on paper.
Speaker 1: I must have it.
Speaker 1: and then they're like we're at.
Speaker 1: Nintendo didn't do the stupid thing They usually do.
Speaker 1: I actually translated to English and brought it out in the US.
Speaker 1: Hallelujah, praise be Nintendo for getting something right once in a while.
Speaker 1: So, of course, I even went to the.
Speaker 1: I didn't go on Amazon.
Speaker 1: I went to the Nintendo store and just bought it with cash.
Speaker 1: I was like it sold out on Amazon.
Speaker 1: I know here is your reward for doing the right thing.
Speaker 1: Nintendo.
Speaker 1: do it again And you'll.
Speaker 1: I'll be back in this store.
Speaker 0: So sometime soon now we geek-bited it and you know before.
Speaker 0: so we said it was pretty fun.
Speaker 0: We hadn't played it a lot yet.
Speaker 0: We still haven't beaten it.
Speaker 0: We haven't beaten it yet either but I played it a lot like nine hours.
Speaker 0: I'm almost Almost halfway.
Speaker 0: Yep, and we try the multiplayer.
Speaker 0: So now we can actually properly review it.
Speaker 0: You know what still pretty fun.
Speaker 0: It's okay.
Speaker 0: So here's the deal.
Speaker 0: It is a Babies-first Nobunaga's ambition which it makes me want to play.
Speaker 1: non babies Nobunaga's ambition.
Speaker 0: You may or may not like it.
Speaker 1: I know that but it still makes me want to try.
Speaker 0: Well, no, I'm gonna put it this way.
Speaker 0: It's more like baby's first gemfire Gemfires baby's first Nobunaga's ambition.
Speaker 0: Nobunaga's ambition is Not for babies not for babies, but also not what you might expect.
Speaker 1: in terms of how I played it I think I might have it on my Mac Plus.
Speaker 0: I should turn my Mac Plus on and I'm a big fan of those Koushibusawa kind of games.
Speaker 1: Well, those are your arrow biz.
Speaker 1: That's your jam.
Speaker 0: Yeah arrow biz gemfire.
Speaker 0: Then all these games are Koushibusawa.
Speaker 1: That's your favorite guy.
Speaker 0: It is my favorite guy.
Speaker 0: Those games are my jam to say what you just said.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: So anyway But it's it's really babies first like your options.
Speaker 0: You know, you have all these towns are basically Dump guys into like a mine to get some money, but money doesn't do fucking anything.
Speaker 1: You could buy items with money.
Speaker 0: gives a shit.
Speaker 1: I give items to your pokemons.
Speaker 1: I don't do so.
Speaker 1: they can you.
Speaker 1: they have an extra option per Pokemon in battle.
Speaker 0: I've never used an item.
Speaker 0: Trivial he's the post never used a potion never used anything.
Speaker 1: I used one potion cuz I wanted like hey, oh an item use.
Speaker 0: I've never used an item.
Speaker 0: Okay, and You can't like level up a place in a way that matters like in other Koushibusawa kind of games.
Speaker 0: Your options every round for each province are things like recruit more troops Buy a third unit like especially, you know a fifth unit, I guess develop my agriculture Develop my defenses, you know stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Here are your options are basically fucking nothing.
Speaker 0: or Play the real game in a real city with real generals.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm actually more fan of the might.
Speaker 1: here is a might and magic style with the towns and the battling, you know That is more real time ish and less of the turn-based grid like it I guess the except for when you get into a real battle.
Speaker 0: My trouble is that the overland part of this game is Extremely fiddly and difficult to use.
Speaker 0: like you get a new trainer who's awesome.
Speaker 0: Well, you're full the mechanics of moving that trainer to another place and then you're forced to move them back because you wanted in the first Place originally, it's really easy to accidentally delete your guys Like Scott did and it just sucks and it's super fiddly and it doesn't even matter.
Speaker 0: None of that shit matters.
Speaker 0: Just ignore it.
Speaker 1: The biggest problem I have with the game is that it has a lot actually has even though it's babies first.
Speaker 1: There's actually kind of a lot of stuff going on, right?
Speaker 1: Yes, and none of it matters.
Speaker 1: Well, none of it matters, but they also don't explain any of it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they don't even explain to you At least maybe I'd skipped it in the tutorial that the the facing of the Pokemon matters.
Speaker 0: No, they don't.
Speaker 0: well that was obvious.
Speaker 0: any game where you can face it matters.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But even realize that I was facing until someone pointed it out and then it's like you didn't even tell you.
Speaker 1: well How much does it matter?
Speaker 1: how much damage do I take from the side versus the back?
Speaker 1: What is the exact penalty?
Speaker 1: You know You'll go into a new arena to fight and they'll be like some water or something and they don't even tell you how the map Works like it's like.
Speaker 1: oh, I didn't know if I walk, you know There's like you go into a map of these balls.
Speaker 1: They don't even tell you that you can that if you hit the balls They bounce straight in a straight line and attack.
Speaker 1: they don't tell you that you started to figure it out.
Speaker 1: There's other stuff like.
Speaker 1: they're like, okay your Pokemon they increase link percentage when they level up But it's like well, what does link percentage exactly mean?
Speaker 0: It just makes them better.
Speaker 1: But yeah, they don't tell you that It's like a lot of the items are very poorly or not explained.
Speaker 1: my first What your guys abilities are.
Speaker 0: evolution starts?
Speaker 0: I'm like what the fuck and I hit a and then it cancels it.
Speaker 0: There's no way to start it up again.
Speaker 1: Like ah, oh Yeah, how did I even know that that you know kind of thing was going on?
Speaker 1: It's like they have all this stuff going.
Speaker 1: you go into a town and there's this energy thing with like pony geary And you're why isn't pony geary a thing in my little pony?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: but like next to each Pokemon They'll be like this arrow that's pointing up or down showing you like whether the Pokemon is currently high energy or low.
Speaker 1: I think they do more damage and I guess it's better to go into a battle when the arrows are pointing up then down.
Speaker 1: So you want to sort of play this mini game of keeping the arrows of your army in sync.
Speaker 1: So they're all pointing up together and you attack and then they're pointing down and you wait until they're all pointing up again using pony gearies to synchronize them right here and then you attack again and it's like They don't explain that really at all.
Speaker 1: So that's my biggest complaint What exactly did the arrows do?
Speaker 1: how much effect do they have?
Speaker 0: The game is full like the places in towns seem to be able to level up but nothing explains what that means.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it doesn't seem to matter.
Speaker 0: Anyway, thus my only like my primary complaint with the game is this It's extremely fiddly on the overland map and all the management stuff yet.
Speaker 0: None of that stuff matters for a good god Damn, no, they the enemy.
Speaker 0: It's like ever attacks you know.
Speaker 1: never have they tell you like yeah the enemy might attack you.
Speaker 1: It's never attacked me.
Speaker 0: yet I put all this effort in like making sure I had like a B team like on my border ready to like to fan and defend.
Speaker 0: It doesn't fucking matter doesn't mean shit?
Speaker 0: and winning battles.
Speaker 0: The AI is so derpy.
Speaker 0: You'll win every battle no matter what?
Speaker 1: The battle has something like take all the banners and you can just sort of trick the bad guys into messing up.
Speaker 0: You can only lose a battle if you go into it like doubly overpowered in terms of levels and Pokemon or like All geodudes can't lose.
Speaker 0: It's just the overland stuff is boring pointless bullshit, but that's fine.
Speaker 0: the actual combat single-player Be.
Speaker 0: it's like one pinky's worth of the tactics of Final Fantasy tactics, which itself is a pinky's worth of the tactics of advanced wars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean there's a little there's a lot.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of rock versus going on as is Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's actually surprising how much the combat resembles at Pokemon even though it's a turn-based thing where you move around a grid Because it's the same things that matter.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm higher level than you I win my I have water you have fire I win right as a. and where you move the guys Really doesn't matter all that much or it's more.
Speaker 0: It's not about guys moving like you.
Speaker 0: think of an advanced wars.
Speaker 0: It's more like formations.
Speaker 0: Like you'll have six Pokemon.
Speaker 0: What are the formation or formations?
Speaker 1: you put them in based on their ability because every guy attacks in a different pattern of hex of?
Speaker 1: Squares.
Speaker 1: so if like a guy has a ranged attack you keep them in the back And you put the strong guy who can only attack one space in front of him up front.
Speaker 0: so basically well let's just talk about multiplayer combat.
Speaker 0: then because here's the deal.
Speaker 0: the way the multiplayer combat works is you pick a link limit and It let all the Pokemon you pick no matter what are raised or lowered to that link limit.
Speaker 0: the only limitation on that is if You set it very high and a trainer has a link limit with a particular Pokemon They only go up to that limit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I said it to a hundred and a guy's derpy and can only link with like 30% on one Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Well that Pokemon is 30% don't use them.
Speaker 1: Yeah so the problem is if you set it to a hundred and you only have like one Pokemon that could be at limit a Hundred and the other guy has six Pokemon that could be limited 100.
Speaker 1: He's gonna win cuz higher level than you.
Speaker 1: So you want to set it to a lower limit where everyone is basically maxed out across the board.
Speaker 1: But even that is still a problem.
Speaker 1: because okay Let's say I go in with a maxed out 30% draw teeny and rim has a dragonite that gets limited down.
Speaker 0: That's basically what happens.
Speaker 0: Scott came in with his you know first and maybe a few second evolution Pokemon cuz
Speaker 1: I'm all I'm not as far through the game as and
Speaker 0: I'm like hey rapier
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's like even though my guy gets boosted up to 40% and his guy gets brought down to 40.
Speaker 0: Yeah, your pichu is no match for my Pikachu.
Speaker 1: exactly his guys have better stronger abilities, right and have you know?
Speaker 1: Hit point whatever my Pokemon could one hit all of your Pokemon and it wasn't even like a type situation really.
Speaker 0: Oh, I did a not very effective one hit kill.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, you know Even though that level even though you're limiting right exactly.
Speaker 1: I mean you're limiting the level.
Speaker 1: level matters.
Speaker 0: I mean some Pokemon are just better than others.
Speaker 1: So you right you really want to only battle someone who's beating the game and you've also beaten the game.
Speaker 1: then the battles will be Less stupid but still really simple and not well, you know what?
Speaker 0: They're fun though.
Speaker 1: Despite being stupid a little bit fun.
Speaker 0: I have fun with it in the same way that I don't like leveling up.
Speaker 0: I can't play like single-player Pokemon games anymore unless it were an MMO.
Speaker 0: But there's a separate thing.
Speaker 0: But the combat in this or combat in Pokemon like playing Pokemon battle with a friend It's actually really fun.
Speaker 0: Even though it's kind of random It tickles a lot of the same itches that.
Speaker 0: well, it's sort of land to me bullshitty kind of war games.
Speaker 1: It's like playing Yomi.
Speaker 1: you get like rock-paper-scissors going on, but also some other stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I actually I think this will be a fun game to play with other people at PAX when we're hanging out.
Speaker 1: Yeah I don't think I can see.
Speaker 1: the problem is is that if you're hanging out with people and you're going to play portable multiple-layer DS games the winners still are Tetris Tetris Mario Kart Bomberman.
Speaker 1: Do we need any other ones sometimes advance or so?
Speaker 0: No, no one will play advance wars with me.
Speaker 1: The point is there's a whole lot of.
Speaker 1: it's actually quite a bunch of DS games that have some sort of multiplayer going on But most of them is you know, there's no reason to play them.
Speaker 0: And yeah, so this is an okay game.
Speaker 0: But um, I would only buy it if you're a Pokemon like hardcore, dude And you want more.
Speaker 1: you want this you want this kind of Pokemon or if you really want to give your money to send a message Nintendo to yes bring over the next weird Japanese game because that one will be better than this one Maybe.
Speaker 0: so if you don't already own this game Wait for it to be cheaper and then pick it up and even then you buy you copy.
Speaker 0: Don't also don't get it.
Speaker 0: If you really like advance wars or Final Fantasy Tactics and are good at those games You do not want to play this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah this game You got to like Pokemon.
Speaker 1: if you like Pokemon You're more likely to like this game than if you like Nova Naga's ambition.
Speaker 0: now if you like Pokemon and you don't like games Like advanced wars and Nova Naga's ambition final fantasy tactics by all means get this game.
Speaker 0: And if you have fun with what's going on and level up you should level up to the other games, right?
Speaker 1: I also just want to say it's kind of awesome that in this game.
Speaker 1: You're like a Pokemon trainer.
Speaker 1: You got Pokemon you're battling and doing all this stuff.
Speaker 1: The bad guy is Nova Naga straight up.
Speaker 0: He's like yo dog.
Speaker 0: I'm Nova Naga.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to wake up the Pokemon that'll destroy the world.
Speaker 1: That is pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: His generals got like you There's.
Speaker 0: it has.
Speaker 0: what the fun of the early advanced wars games that disappeared in days of ruin of The characters saying dumb stuff to each other before battle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you look at the facts online There's actually a bunch of side quests involving characters that you can sort of get going on if you do the right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: I Literally in my life.
Speaker 1: I read look at all the fucks I give.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can see them all through this podcast.
Speaker 0: No problem I read the.
Speaker 0: I have the fact that tells you exactly how to get those things and I couldn't be asked To get to do what.
Speaker 1: the facts, you know What that reminds me of that bullshit and fire emblem where you have to get the characters to stand next to each other.
Speaker 0: Hey, advanced wars one to unlock certain things.
Speaker 0: You had to use the right person in the right map at the right time That's true but this isn't fire emblem like it'd be like.
Speaker 1: okay make the girl on the Pegasus stand next to the guy with the horse and have them talk and Then you'll get some plot and advanced wars - if you put Eagle and Sammy in the final battle together They they confess their love to each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah That was a big deal.
Speaker 0: Okay, what else can I say about this game?
Speaker 0: It's it's pretty fun to play with someone else as a like, you know dick around fight, but it's Pokemon.
Speaker 0: So if I've got all spirit tombs, you've got all Eevees.
Speaker 0: Well, guess who's gonna win?
Speaker 1: Yeah Six year dudes.
Speaker 0: The thing is it's because it's so fiddly.
Speaker 0: It's hard to get the Pokemon you want I know.
Speaker 0: so my team is like half cuz I play.
Speaker 0: you know what I did play.
Speaker 1: If there's a Pokemon you want good luck finding a trainer that it goes with right because the way it works is every train you Get these trainers and every trainer can have one active Pokemon at a time and they have a link percentage with that Pokemon.
Speaker 1: So like for example Scott, I have my main guy has dratini and Eevee.
Speaker 1: his link percentage of the Eevee is way high And dratini is kind of low.
Speaker 1: So it's like well no reason to use dratini there.
Speaker 1: I just stick with the Eevee the and he also has a max percentage.
Speaker 1: So it's like, you know Eevee on Eevee the Eevee Scott combo can go up to 100%.
Speaker 1: the dratini Scott combo can only go to 70%.
Speaker 1: so There's no reason to use the dratini Scott combo because it only goes to 70% unless you play with the cap of 70% That's true.
Speaker 1: So you got it.
Speaker 1: want to mix the dratini with somebody who will be a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: Well, that's why what you do is you watch for that symbol.
Speaker 0: That means there's a trainer who's with his best Pokemon already and capture him exactly You know.
Speaker 1: So it's like you to figure out who which Pokemon is go with which trainers and you can switch Pokemon on trainers.
Speaker 1: So it's too much effort to deal with that too much effort to do So.
Speaker 1: it's like you I was when I was playing.
Speaker 1: I would be like, alright, my guy is in a fire town So he should be a water guy so he can kill the things in the town easily doesn't fucking matter doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: I'm also thinking like okay, my guy is there.
Speaker 1: he's next to a fighting town So I don't want to put any normal guys in this town.
Speaker 1: in case they attack right doesn't fucking matter.
Speaker 1: Yep All right.
Speaker 1: So don't worry about like type matching or any bullshit.
Speaker 1: worry about that in the battle more.
Speaker 1: So right if there's a water guy in the battle Don't put your fire guy in range of his attack and you'll be okay.
Speaker 1: There ain't no reason to bring him out of the battle because you know There's probably gonna be something that's weak against water that you'll need your water guy in there and you shouldn't keep them out Just as a fire guy.
Speaker 0: now the only passwords I put in Where you can get guys to appear and then you have to go catch him in game.
Speaker 0: and so I typed in the password for Gyarados and the password for Sneasel because I really like sneasel like I always have I always use sneasel and there's like 30 or 40 more that I just don't give a fuck.
Speaker 0: type in like mr.
Speaker 0: Eavis.
Speaker 0: I could get but whatever it just doesn't.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the password thing is kind of weird.
Speaker 1: It's basically you type in a password and then it'll be like on the next turn.
Speaker 1: It'll be like the Pokemon has appeared in this town.
Speaker 1: So you had to go to that town and capture that.
Speaker 0: you can type that password in once per like reset your cartridge.
Speaker 0: Yeah whatever, yeah, but I got my.
Speaker 0: so I got like five sneezles and They suck cuz.
Speaker 0: I didn't have any trainer who could 100% with them.
Speaker 1: So you got to look up online like which trainers go with which Pokemon?
Speaker 0: Yeah, fuck that noise.
Speaker 0: The thing is I in real Pokemon.
Speaker 0: I like.
Speaker 0: I like to play dark like dark Pokemon ground metal psychic And grass.
Speaker 1: I like evil ghosty Pokemon like spirit - I like psychic ground.
Speaker 0: on our team I've won for a while.
Speaker 0: I had a team that was all dark and metal and also dragons.
Speaker 1: And then I hang tonight is the only one that's a real dragon.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Char Matt Charles ours kind of dragon.
Speaker 1: You never seen the Dragonite video on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Oh But yeah, I'm like Dragonite Gengar spirit oom, you know, and then I also like cute Pokemon like combi, but they're useless.
Speaker 0: I love combi, but I don't use combi.
Speaker 1: I saw the best cosplay.
Speaker 1: I think was a combi.
Speaker 1: Was it?
Speaker 0: Oh, I saw that.
Speaker 0: I remember that there was an old account.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it was a great female combi cosplay.
Speaker 0: But despite not having you know, despite it being such so is actually a combi cross play to get all the stuff you know to get particular Pokemon I Ended up with the team.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much all the dark psychic kind of stuff that I like.
Speaker 0: So it's okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I don't know how much I'll play the game though.
Speaker 1: I Beat it, but I'm gonna beat it one, but it's like I'm not really motivated to play it.
Speaker 1: I got other games.
Speaker 1: I'm playing like I had.
Speaker 1: I decided I was like, oh, I'll play Metroid - I haven't played.
Speaker 1: I've only played that like once or twice.
Speaker 1: So I haven't played it in a long time either.
Speaker 1: So I started playing that and I really want to play Metroid - a lot more than I want to play You know Pokemon.
Speaker 0: I've really been doing nothing but kinetic on bullshit for the last few days.
Speaker 1: I'm ready guys.
Speaker 1: I got all the clipboards.
Speaker 1: I got the schedules.
Speaker 1: I printed the stuff out.
Speaker 1: I'm ready.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's coming soon.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.