Speaker 0: It's Thursday, May 31st, 2012.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, I'm finally back from Istanbul, and I got stuff to say.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: About the TSA.
Speaker 0: Actually, I don't.
Speaker 0: Remember when I went to India?
Speaker 0: Pretend I said the exact same thing again.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Seriously.
Speaker 0: The only anecdote I have on that front is that...
Speaker 1: Well, cause didn't you fly from like Turkey to Germany at one point?
Speaker 0: I flew from the US to Istanbul.
Speaker 0: From Istanbul to Munich.
Speaker 1: Right, so that Istanbul-Munich flight, the security was probably nothing, right?
Speaker 0: The security took maybe five minutes total.
Speaker 1: And you didn't have to take off shoes?
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: Or open bags?
Speaker 1: Or any nonsense?
Speaker 0: So, the flight from Munich to Dusseldorf... Dusseldorf?
Speaker 0: I won.
Speaker 0: There was basically no security.
Speaker 1: I use a Swedish accent.
Speaker 1: Pretty German.
Speaker 0: Yet somehow they checked it out more thoroughly than the TSA ever has.
Speaker 0: It took literally less than a minute to get through security at that airport.
Speaker 0: I could have shown up to my flight at the airport, as in the front of the airport, five minutes before I had to be on the plane.
Speaker 0: And I would have made it on the plane with about three minutes to spare.
Speaker 1: How about that?
Speaker 0: It was amazing.
Speaker 0: Seriously, fuck you.
Speaker 0: The TSA.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you might say, "Oh, well, how many hijackings have there been on German-Turkish
Speaker 1: flights?".
Speaker 1: And Turkey isn't exactly the most stable place.
Speaker 1: There's angry people there.
Speaker 0: Well, even more interesting was that when I was in Terminal 1 at JFK to fly out to Istanbul in the first part, that's like the international terminal.
Speaker 0: It's mostly just airlines that go to other cities.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not nearly as nice as the JetBlue one.
Speaker 0: Nah, it's pretty crappy.
Speaker 0: But it was mostly foreigners flying back home when I happened to be flying out.
Speaker 0: And the security line, at one point, basically this TSA guy had to keep pulling an Otacon staff.
Speaker 0: "You must remove your shoes before you can get...".
Speaker 0: And no one would take their shoes off.
Speaker 0: Like, they didn't get it.
Speaker 1: Because they didn't understand English, a lot of people probably.
Speaker 0: And when they got it, the looks on their faces ranged from disgusted to aghast.
Speaker 0: This one British lady was just like, "What?
Speaker 0: Ugh, these fucking
Speaker 0: Americans.".
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: Fuck us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it sucks.
Speaker 0: To the rest of the world, I apologize.
Speaker 0: anytime you have to fly here.
Speaker 1: Grandma's always trying to say, "Do not conflate my opinions with
Speaker 1: Scott's.".
Speaker 1: Nah, nah, nah.
Speaker 1: In this case... Do not conflate our beliefs and opinions with the behaviors of our government.
Speaker 0: Specifically the TSA.
Speaker 0: Because I signed... Rand Paul, for those of you who aren't American, is a crazy idiot, but he's in our political system.
Speaker 0: He's the son of Ron Paul, who is also a crazy idiot.
Speaker 0: So, Rand Paul is trying to put forth real legislation to literally abolish the TSA.
Speaker 0: I signed his petition, and I think he is one of the craziest people I have ever seen in American politics.
Speaker 1: You can go around to the craziest of crazy people, right?
Speaker 0: You can take a clock and fucking break it, and it'll still be right at least once a day.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: A clock depends how it's broken.
Speaker 1: If it's stopped... See, everyone says a broken clock is right twice a day.
Speaker 1: That's not correct.
Speaker 1: A stopped clock is right twice a day.
Speaker 1: A fast or a slow clock is never right.
Speaker 0: Actually, it will be right.
Speaker 0: There's modulus math involved.
Speaker 1: Yeah, once a year or month, depending on how slow it is or something like that.
Speaker 1: But it's right less often than twice a day.
Speaker 0: I argue that you're wrong.
Speaker 0: Do you want my argument?
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: Alright, I'm gonna make a clock that moves four times faster than it should.
Speaker 1: Oh, then it's right even more often.
Speaker 0: How many times right is it per day?
Speaker 1: But let me ask you this question.
Speaker 1: Rand Paul, Ron Paul, take your pick, right?
Speaker 1: Fast clocks or slow clocks?
Speaker 0: I'd rather a clock be fast.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying they are slow clocks.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: To say that they are slow clocks is an understatement.
Speaker 1: They are not fast clocks.
Speaker 0: Not the fastest clocks in the chat by any stretch.
Speaker 1: Indeed, they may be stopped clocks, which are right twice a day.
Speaker 1: But they are neither fast nor are they accurately keeping time.
Speaker 0: They are either slow or stopped.
Speaker 0: I think Ron Paul's is slow.
Speaker 0: And/or maybe stopped.
Speaker 0: Probably just slow.
Speaker 0: Because he's trying to hold his back.
Speaker 1: Well, slow is actually right less often than stopped, right?
Speaker 1: Stopped is right twice a day.
Speaker 1: Slow is right, you know, depends how slow it is.
Speaker 1: It could be so slow, right, that it actually goes backwards.
Speaker 1: And then it's right pretty often.
Speaker 0: I think Rand Paul is more the erratic clock.
Speaker 0: Where the hands just materialize at random positions over time.
Speaker 1: Well, then there's absolutely no way to know how often it's right.
Speaker 0: You know what the Rand Paul clock does is periodically it says, "See, what you've got is fiat
Speaker 0: time.".
Speaker 1: Okay, let's move on here.
Speaker 0: The only reason I even brought up stupid Rand Paul TSI is that I was reading FARC at the airport on my way on the trip, right?
Speaker 0: And there was an article.
Speaker 0: It was a technology article.
Speaker 0: I forget even what it was about.
Speaker 0: And the first comment was three paragraphs.
Speaker 0: And I have a new...
Speaker 1: The first post or just the top comment?
Speaker 0: The first post.
Speaker 0: And I have a new... I think this might be a law of the internet, but I need a lot more data on it.
Speaker 0: If someone is a Rand or Ron Paul... I could make a regular expression.
Speaker 0: R dot star...
Speaker 1: R star Paul?
Speaker 0: Yeah, some sort of regex.
Speaker 0: If you're one of those supporters, you cannot post anything on the internet without mentioning fiat currency and Eurozone, Global Reserve, or Federal Reserve, or IMF.
Speaker 0: At least two of those things within two sentences of any post on the internet.
Speaker 0: So anyway, what did I miss?
Speaker 1: Not much.
Speaker 1: So the only news I got, at least it was the first news that I found when I was looking through my news list here, is that Toonami has returned.
Speaker 0: Ah, is it the turn of the tide?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: So here's what happened, right?
Speaker 1: So on May 26th, Adult Swim posted a message that was like, "Toonami's actually coming back for
Speaker 1: reals.".
Speaker 1: Because remember they had the adult... They had the April Fools comeback.
Speaker 1: that was sort of like the fake comeback, you know?
Speaker 1: But now it's come back for reals.
Speaker 1: So they brought it back for reals.
Speaker 1: And basically what they did is they took their existing sort of Adult Swim anime block, and they added two shows, Casern Sins and Deadman Wonderland, and they put them up at midnight on some day for a bunch of hours.
Speaker 1: And there was a tweet today, or yesterday, I think it was today, of the guy who runs it, I guess, and he was like, "The ratings were okay.
Speaker 1: Not the greatest, but they were
Speaker 1: okay.".
Speaker 1: And it's like, "Oh,
Speaker 1: People were clamoring because I don't know about you, but I would get home from school and watch Toonami every freaking day.
Speaker 0: Ah, but that's the problem.
Speaker 0: What did you just say?
Speaker 1: It was on at midnight.
Speaker 0: You would get home from school to watch Toonami.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: It was on when normal people watched things.
Speaker 1: Exactly, right.
Speaker 0: In an era when television and time mattered.
Speaker 1: So yeah, not only does television no longer matter in this day, as opposed to the day when I was in high school and middle school, right?
Speaker 1: But in addition, you want to make a particular kind of thing popular, it's gotta be on when people are watching, and when do kids watch when they get home from school, right?
Speaker 1: "Bring Back Toonami" doesn't mean, "Okay, show some shows that you're already gonna show probably, and the bumpers in between those shows have Tom the Robot in
Speaker 1: them.".
Speaker 1: That's not what "Bring Back Toonami" means.
Speaker 1: "Bring Back Toonami" means that between like 2.33 and 6.7 night, every single weekday, you show a block of nerdy programming ranging from, you know, Herculoids, Hanna-Barbera, Space Ghost to B-Test, to Gundam, to Dragon Ball, to brand new animes, you know, who knows what.
Speaker 1: Bleach, I don't even care.
Speaker 1: You got it.
Speaker 1: Show it.
Speaker 1: That's what "Bring Back Toonami" means.
Speaker 0: Well now, that's what "Bring Back Toonami" means to people who understand the importance of Toonami.
Speaker 0: Most people are on a weird nostalgia trip, and this is not targeted at what the original Toonami did, which is getting people into these things.
Speaker 0: This is targeted at making those people who have nostalgia for Toonami become marketable too with ads on TV.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sell some slightly more expensive ads and maybe a few more spots at a time period where we're not selling so many ads.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: They put it on a bad time period because they're only selling to people who want to watch Toonami.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: remember,
Speaker 0: when the TV executives
Speaker 1: are looking at the program schedule, they're looking at dollars per second across the whole board, so if there's an area that's weak in dollars per second, that's the area they reprogram to get the dollars per second of advertising money in that time slot on that day to go up.
Speaker 1: That's what they do.
Speaker 1: So anyway, but I just want to reiterate a point that I have made many times, you know, that is a more general point, and this is just another example of it, so whenever you find a new example of something, you gotta, you know, is that companies these days, especially companies that have existed for a while, they like to pretend to try new things and then say that they did or did not or partially worked or partially didn't work based on only dipping the toe in the water.
Speaker 1: So for the greatest example, of course, is the digitization of things, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, "Okay, guys, we will sell you, you know, music
Speaker 1: digitally.".
Speaker 1: So they dip the toe in the water, and it's like, "Okay, we sold you a few of the tracks for $5 each with some DRMs and only in this one place, and it only worked on
Speaker 1: iPods.".
Speaker 1: It's like, you only dipped the toe in, of course it didn't fucking work, and then they try to say, "Oh, some digital music doesn't work,".
Speaker 1: 'cause you didn't jump in the pool.
Speaker 1: If you actually jump in the pool and go whole hog on something, that is the only time you can determine whether it does or does not work, but there is no dispute you risk drowning when you jump in the pool, right?
Speaker 1: So everyone's so afraid of drowning, they won't jump in the pool for anything, and because no one jumps in the pool for anything, no one can actually prove or disprove that things do or do not work.
Speaker 1: If you just want to say, "Bringing back Toonami would or would not work," you cannot say that unless you do exactly what we said, which is every day, after school, for a long period of time, at least long enough to get an audience, to build an audience, these things don't happen overnight, you know, it takes investment and, you know, risking of drowning, and that's the only way that you can make a determination of it will or will not work.
Speaker 1: Unless you do that, you can't be like, "Oh, the rainings are okay, you didn't do
Speaker 1: it!".
Speaker 1: You're putting your pinky toe in the water and saying, "Oh, I can't swim, I'll drown if I
Speaker 1: swim.".
Speaker 1: You don't know that, you just put your toe in the water.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is they don't need to, the majority of people don't think of this or care.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, I'm not giving that particular example, but I mean, in general, companies like to say, "This works, this doesn't work,".
Speaker 1: but you haven't done it, so you don't know, right?
Speaker 1: You know, Hasbro, make toys that don't have brushy hair, right?
Speaker 1: They just have solid hair that looks exactly like the show.
Speaker 1: You won't know if they will sell or won't, even though they will.
Speaker 0: Well, we know they will because of the sheer amount of bootlegs.
Speaker 1: Right, but, you know, why, you know, even though we do know that, mostly, we're pretty sure, you don't know because you haven't done it.
Speaker 1: So, you know, there you go.
Speaker 0: So, you know, not too long after I got back, I actually went out because people were losing their shit about The Avengers, the new movie, so I figured, you know what, I'll go see it.
Speaker 1: You went to see it in the theater?
Speaker 0: So I went to see it in the theater.
Speaker 1: Whether they were screaming babies or kids or loud people or tall people in the way?
Speaker 0: Nah, it was mostly full.
Speaker 0: It wasn't that bad, I went to a nice theater, it was okay.
Speaker 0: But, uh, it was okay.
Speaker 0: It was a mediocre to average, like, okay, pretty enjoyable movie.
Speaker 0: But it was literally nothing special and I can't imagine ever needing to see it again.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, I haven't seen any superhero live-action movie, except...
Speaker 0: Oh, you would have hated it.
Speaker 1: That wasn't Batman.
Speaker 0: I know you would have hated it.
Speaker 1: I saw the first Spider-Man one, recent one.
Speaker 0: You hate quips, you hate one-liners, you hate Joss Whedon, you would hate everything about this movie.
Speaker 1: Well, I like one-liners if they're good, but a one-liner can't carry a movie, right?
Speaker 1: One-liners are for, you know, Simpsons episodes, Futuramas, or...
Speaker 0: Don't forget, uh, Total Recall.
Speaker 0: See you at the party, Richter.
Speaker 1: Right, but I mean, Total Recall.
Speaker 0: He could have said, "Do you need a
Speaker 0: hand?".
Speaker 1: It has one-liners.
Speaker 1: I mean, I haven't even seen this, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like, are you telling me that one-liners are what carries the movie?
Speaker 1: That's all it's got.
Speaker 0: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: What I'm saying is that the one-liners that were there were really good and there were a lot of great scenes that were very satisfying.
Speaker 0: It was a fun movie, but it was about 45 minutes too long and it had two extra Avengers and the soundtrack was, I can't even say forgettable, it was garbage.
Speaker 0: I literally...
Speaker 1: Like, you hear the music and you're like, "Ah, turn this music
Speaker 1: off.".
Speaker 0: So, during dramatic scenes, I'm listening to the music and I'm like, "Wow, this is what, like, a high school kid would think was...".
Speaker 1: Like it stands out as sort of cheesy and misplaced?
Speaker 0: It stands out as, "This is the dramatic song.
Speaker 0: This is the song between scenes.
Speaker 0: This is the song when an action scene is about to start.
Speaker 0: This is the ominous
Speaker 0: song.".
Speaker 1: You know what I'm gonna do?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna make a live action US movie with English speaking people, maybe even superheroes, and I'm gonna get Yuki Kajiro or Yokohama to do the music, right?
Speaker 1: No one, you know, these people, they don't work crossways, you know?
Speaker 1: Why don't we get Joss Whedon to write some anime and have Japanese studio IG or production IG make the show, right?
Speaker 1: Mix it up.
Speaker 1: We gotta get some cross-country workings going on, 'cause we got, you know, we got talented peoples in particular areas.
Speaker 1: They gotta team up with talented peoples in the other areas.
Speaker 0: Yuki Kajiro could've saved that movie, because the thing is, I watched one and three quarters awful shows and I thought they were good just because of that music.
Speaker 0: Like, it took me a while to realize the shows were garbage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: Noire and Dot Hack.
Speaker 1: I watched half of Dot Hack.
Speaker 1: I watched all of Noire.
Speaker 0: I watched all of Noire.
Speaker 1: Two episodes of Kazuto or whatever.
Speaker 0: There was a point at like 12 or 13 episodes into Noire when I was like, "Eh, this isn't really that good,".
Speaker 0: but then the music would play and I'd be like, "Oh, this is the best show ever.
Speaker 0: This is
Speaker 0: great.".
Speaker 0: But the soundtrack was like nothing.
Speaker 0: Dragon Heart, which actually had a pretty shit soundtrack.
Speaker 1: Dragon Heart or Dragon Heat?
Speaker 0: Dragon Heart.
Speaker 1: I'm the last one.
Speaker 0: I had a better soundtrack, even though it was mostly songs that are also in other movies.
Speaker 1: I don't remember any songs from Dragon Heart.
Speaker 0: There's one particular one that's in a lot of movie trailers, just for random movies.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this movie was just average, okay, literally nothing special.
Speaker 1: It's because, I'm telling you, I haven't seen it, so I don't know.
Speaker 1: There is a non-zero chance that I would like it, but I've never liked anything Joss Whedon's ever done, so I doubt it.
Speaker 1: But, the point is, it's obvious that nerds, a great majority of nerds, I'm among them, I know them, they seem to like a thing just based on these surface elements.
Speaker 1: And people even come to me like, "Scott, you should like this.
Speaker 1: It has this character in it that you
Speaker 1: like.".
Speaker 0: Well, they tried to pull that on Avengers.
Speaker 0: They're like, "Scott, Thanos is in it at the end.
Speaker 0: He's gonna be in the next
Speaker 0: movie.".
Speaker 1: And it's like, why would that mean that I'm going to like it?
Speaker 1: What are some of my favorite characters and things?
Speaker 0: Kenshiro, Lupin.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I always say Kenshiro and Lupin, right?
Speaker 1: So you come to me and say, "Hey, Scott, there's a comic and Kenshiro is in
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: Well, I like Kenshiro.
Speaker 1: He's a cool dude, but that doesn't mean I'm going to like that thing.
Speaker 1: But for some people, it seems like that is true.
Speaker 1: You could make some piece of crap and put ponies in it and some bronies in it and think it's the best thing ever, even though it sucks.
Speaker 1: And that's what it is.
Speaker 1: I think that a lot of nerds, you can just take something, and as long as their favorite characters are in it, there's a good chance that they will like it, as long as it's not blatantly awful.
Speaker 0: Who's favorite character is Hawkeye?
Speaker 0: He might as well have not even been in that movie.
Speaker 0: He served zero purpose.
Speaker 1: There are people who like that.
Speaker 0: Hawkeye is a pointless character.
Speaker 0: He literally, in this movie, they could have just cut him out and no one would have noticed.
Speaker 1: Well, do you know about Hawkeye in the comics?
Speaker 0: Uh, bow and arrow guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's a bow and arrow guy.
Speaker 0: That's what I know about him.
Speaker 1: His typical thing is he was the bad guy, he was also the good guy, he was also the bad guy.
Speaker 0: Oh, in this movie they brainwashed him and then he got to be the bad guy for most of the movie.
Speaker 0: See,
Speaker 1: that's what I was trying to discuss earlier, but I held it, right, is that in the comics, it's actually cool, or somewhat cool, at least the first time, that he basically goes back and forth between good guy and bad guy because they replay the same story because they have no new ideas, but the original story is that he wasn't a bad guy because he was brainwashed, he was just a bad guy, right?
Speaker 1: And then when he becomes a good guy, he's still a bad guy, it's sort of like having a guy on your team.
Speaker 1: that's like, you know, Locke the thief, only sort of evil and jerky, right?
Speaker 1: And you should have put him in jail.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like when the X-Men will team up with Magneto or, you know, they'll have to work with Doctor Doom this time, except it's different from that because he's always there.
Speaker 1: It's like if Doctor Doom joined the Fantastic Four permanently, and he's just always there with them and when they're looking at him, and he's always doing the right thing, but he's still Doctor Doom and he
Speaker 0: used to be
Speaker 1: and he's still evil and he still says evil things and talks like an evil guy and has evil ideas and he used to be an evil, horrible dictator.
Speaker 1: It would be like if you were like, you know, marching in to fight and like, Stalin was there right next to you, and it's Stalin, it's like what the hell are you doing here?
Speaker 1: It's like you want to shoot him, but he's his actions at this moment are noble actions, even though all his thoughts, words, and past actions are evil.
Speaker 1: All of his present and future actions are good and you're keeping an eye on him.
Speaker 1: and that's the cool part of Hawkeye, and very few comics actually draw that cool part out but that's the cool part.
Speaker 0: Well anyway, my biggest complaint, and then we can move on.
Speaker 1: So brainwashing him completely defeats that purpose.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: well he served no purpose in the movie anyway, he was completely pointless but the movie was crazy long and there's this gigantic action scene at the end, you know, like a superhero movie, summer blockbuster but it
Speaker 1: had all these
Speaker 0: vignettes where they'd like, save particular civilians around the city, like in the course of everything, and it went on forever like, this scene just wouldn't end, and the way it played out all those vignettes in the middle of the fight, literally didn't matter at all, like they had no effect, they might as well have not been there.
Speaker 0: That fight could have been half as long, and it did the typical cut around all the time, there's no real choreography which is more and more common like in the Transformers movies, that I just I can't stand that kind of action scene like.
Speaker 0: I hate it when there's, you know they use fast cuts to cover up the fact that they didn't actually choreograph anything in three dimensional space.
Speaker 0: It was just a mediocre movie, that's all I can say and I predict that the next Avengers movie not gonna be received as well as this one, because they're going full Thanos space bullshit as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: See the thing is, if you do the space bullshit right, and I'm a big fan of that I've read a large.
Speaker 0: I think you're gonna say the same thing Emily said, so continue.
Speaker 0: I've
Speaker 1: read a large number of Marvel outer space cosmic
Speaker 0: comics Thanos, Infinity Gauntlet,
Speaker 1: I've read all those and I actually like those a lot even though I recognize they're not exactly the greatest but I like them a lot, and the reason that I like them so much, is because they're crazy, psychedelic, and weird.
Speaker 1: right, it's like everything is sort of like Jack Kirby crackle all over the place, crazy colors and it's not people, it's not a whole lot of just fighting, and you know, I mean when they do fight they just sort of blast energy beams at each other.
Speaker 1: but you know, it's not really usually a matter of just I'm stronger than you or whoever wins is for the plot or something like that, right it's usually okay, you know we're shooting energy beams at each other, but what really is going on, is this sort of weird, tripped out, sort of LSD mind battles, right, that go on.
Speaker 1: you know, it's like, you know even though on the page it's a drawing of like Adam Warlock shooting like a beam out of a scepter like a Merlin the Wizard against.
Speaker 1: you know, I don't know you know, Eternity, well what's Eternity?
Speaker 1: Eternity is this huge guy who is the living embodiment of the entire universe and all of existence, and he's like.
Speaker 1: he's just sort of like this outline, and of this big gigantic guy with like weird tentacle hair, and like tentacles coming out of the sides of his body sort of like Washington's you know, dicks coming out of his legs but they used a bucket tool to paint him, and the bucket tool drew stars and planets and galaxies and all sorts of stuff, and it's like they're not putting that shit, that
Speaker 0: fucked
Speaker 1: up mind trippy shit in no live action mainstream movie.
Speaker 1: they might try, no they're not, they're not gonna have a giant guy who looks like outer space.
Speaker 0: they're not gonna have Ego the living planet, you know floating around talking to Quasar with his quantum bands, I think the reason I think the movie's gonna be bad is more that, so they go the road of Thanos, which one, they show him but nobody knows who.
Speaker 1: that is right, and you know what, the other thing is well, nerds know who he is, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah the stinger is.
Speaker 0: they show a guy, and if you know alright,
Speaker 1: so let's talk about what Thanos' deal is, Thanos is a guy from Titan, you know the moon Titan, right where there was a society of Titans, but he was sort of like right, he was sort of a runt right, sort of like a deformed runt, he's all purple and nasty and sort of giant chin, and you know you could tell he was a Titan from that planet, but he didn't fit in and he was sort of evil, so he's actually a worshipper of death, as in the Grim Reaper, except death is a god a literal existing god, who's like this lady who wears a dark robe, who's a skeleton, and she never speaks and he literally worships her.
Speaker 1: literally, like goes to.
Speaker 1: oh, there's death, the Grim Reaper and she's the god of death of the entire universe, and there's this dude worshipping her, and as a sacrifice to her, you know he wants to bring about a lot of death, so he goes and gets the infinity gauntlet, and to kill half the population of the universe with a snap of his fingers, cause he wants, you know death to like him, so he'll make out with him.
Speaker 0: so here's the problem that's gonna happen, right?
Speaker 1: that kind of fucked up shit is not gonna go in a mainstream movie, the thing is they're bringing him in.
Speaker 0: so what are they gonna do?
Speaker 1: my problem is he's gonna be generic alien powerful bad guy.
Speaker 0: my problem is, what's the plot gonna be?
Speaker 0: you've got the crazy existential space stuff you know, and then you've got Hawkeye.
Speaker 0: they're
Speaker 1: gonna remove any of the existential parts
Speaker 0: if they would just remove Hawkeye
Speaker 1: you know in the infinity gauntlet, when all the, basically the not dead superheroes, cause half of everyone died, right go to fight, you know Thanos, up on this giant floating castle he made, that looks go to light castle grayskull for death to live in and hang out, you know even Spiderman goes up there, and Spiderman is like, oh what the fuck am I gonna do?
Speaker 1: he's like, well look, this guy is pretty much omnipotent, omniscient, et cetera et cetera, so even you know, your tiny web shot.
Speaker 1: we gotta basically all punch him at the same time otherwise this isn't gonna work, so you know, everyone goes, the cosmic guys with the real powers like Silver Surfer make the real difference, but your one bow and arrow shot might do something, it couldn't hurt to have it in there.
Speaker 1: you know, we got no one else.
Speaker 0: we're bringing everybody, so what I was amazed by though, was in our forum, I basically said it was a pretty good movie, but it had some flaws and people treated that like I said it was the worst movie ever, and they were bad.
Speaker 0: people like people defended this movie to a degree.
Speaker 1: Firefly sucks.
Speaker 1: Firefly was pretty good, I like Firefly.
Speaker 1: this is welcome to my world.
Speaker 0: I think you're wrong about Firefly, but I digress.
Speaker 1: if a majority of nerds sorta agree on something for whatever reason, and you disagree they act like, you know, and then they yell at you for doing the same
Speaker 0: thing, I think it's more a situation of the lady doth protesteth too much, that when flaws are pointed out in something, that someone cause remember, I watched it after everyone else had already seen it and they were posting things like I'm gonna go see it a third time, oh my god that was the best movie ever, and I was like eh, it was okay, they either have to accept the flaws I pointed out, or defend their previous opinion, this is what
Speaker 1: I'm gonna understand, it's like either a) defend your opinion which people often refuse or fail to do, or b) do what we do, which is when you like something and you know, deep in your heart, or you know, well out shallow in your heart, or in your mind that it's not that good, just admit it.
Speaker 1: I like Initial D, it sucks.
Speaker 1: if I liked Avengers enough to see it five times, I wouldn't be like all shy about it.
Speaker 0: well, before we go any further I should make it clear to people who read the film, I don't necessarily agree with all Scott's opinions here, don't conflate me with him.
Speaker 1: I'd be like yeah, I saw it five times.
Speaker 1: it's okay, but I love it, it's up my alley it's my thing.
Speaker 0: but I had people defending like why Hawkeye was in the movie, I was like really?
Speaker 0: really?
Speaker 0: you could cut him out and not change any of the dialogue and it would still make mostly the same
Speaker 1: sense, you should make a Hawkeye cut,
Speaker 0: I think I could, I won't, I don't care enough but I could,
Speaker 1: I mean it would take, it would be very long and it would be pretty, right, but you
Speaker 0: could
Speaker 1: do the opposite.
Speaker 0: the movie was so long, I almost fell asleep during the last fight and even though there's a bunch of stuff after the credits, a lot of the audience just got up and left because the movie was so long.
Speaker 1: did they not know?
Speaker 0: no, there was a guy, as soon as the first credit comes up, like it's over this guy's like don't leave, don't leave.
Speaker 0: there's shit after the credits, don't leave, don't leave, don't leave.
Speaker 0: and he got like really agitated when people started leaving.
Speaker 1: did you leave?
Speaker 0: no, because I wanted to see what the stingers were.
Speaker 1: was it worth it?
Speaker 0: so the first one, spoilers, was the Thanos great, the second one was actually pretty good.
Speaker 1: was it just like a funny joke?
Speaker 0: yes, it was just a joke, but it was actually the way, it was really funny.
Speaker 0: I was really pleased with it.
Speaker 1: if it was so funny, why don't you put it in the movie?
Speaker 0: it was better that it wasn't in the movie.
Speaker 0: it wouldn't have been the same joke had it been a scene in the movie and they get points for hypnototing it a little bit as in, the scene happens, and you're like oh I get it and it just sits there for a while, you just keep watching it.
Speaker 0: Thor's like picking it, I'm not saying what it is picking his nose?
Speaker 0: no they're all just out eating shawarma silently.
Speaker 0: they're just sitting there eating it in the kind of place you get cheap shawarma in New York,
Speaker 1: sort of like when Aquaman goes in that bar,
Speaker 0: basically yeah and there's a guy in the background mopping and they're just sitting there and Thor takes a bite and he kind of just looks at it like he takes another bite and they're just sitting there.
Speaker 1: yeah, that's how they do it see.
Speaker 1: that's the kind of superhero movie I wish they would make, which is those are the parts of the superhero comics I like the most which is, guy happens to be a superhero but he's just hanging out.
Speaker 0: he's not necessarily jumping around, punching, saving the universe all up the ante, you know what superhero movie I want?
Speaker 0: I just want Batman Dark Knight Returns the movie eh, too much Batman.
Speaker 1: we need to go and take the superheroes that nobody knows about, no one cares about.
Speaker 0: Raccoon Girl?
Speaker 1: You mean Squirrel Girl?
Speaker 0: Whatever?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: No, no, she's only a joke.
Speaker 0: she's not really okay, how about that Raccoon Guy?
Speaker 1: What Raccoon Guy?
Speaker 0: There's a little Raccoon Guy.
Speaker 1: Oh, Rocket Raccoon?
Speaker 1: Yeah The guy's actually a raccoon?
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's make a movie for him.
Speaker 1: yeah, he's also outer space and sort of.
Speaker 1: well, he's more pulp outer space like Flash Gordon style.
Speaker 0: let's make a crossover between him and Howard the Duck.
Speaker 1: you could actually make a really good movie that was like the Rocket Raccoon movie and you could use Beatles music if you could afford it and it could just be like sort of a Flash Gordon kind of like duh duh duh eh, right?
Speaker 1: maybe.
Speaker 1: All like action packed and, you know, sort of a little bit cheesy on purpose because he's a raccoon with a laser gun.
Speaker 0: but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: so, you know, every now and then I pull out the hockey fights and it's definitely the hockey season.
Speaker 0: Go Kings!
Speaker 0: Devils suck.
Speaker 0: This is one of the best Stanley Cup seasons I've been paying attention to in a long time.
Speaker 1: Burn in hell, Devils, Go Kings!
Speaker 0: So many Game 7, so many overtimes.
Speaker 1: It's Kings and Devils.
Speaker 1: How could you possibly not root for Kings?
Speaker 0: Well, one, gotta root for the underdog.
Speaker 0: Two, Kings... No one's an underdog in the Stanley Cup Finals Scott, when was the last time the Kings won a Stanley Cup?
Speaker 1: Did Gretzky win a Stanley Cup on the Kings or did he win them all in Edmonton?
Speaker 0: That's what I'm asking you, when was the last time the Kings got a Stanley Cup To the Wikipedia?
Speaker 0: When was the last time the Kings were in the Stanley Cup Finals?
Speaker 1: That is also an excellent question.
Speaker 1: Stanley Cups for the Kings, zero.
Speaker 1: So even though Wayne Gretzky was there for how many years he won all his cups with Edmonton?
Speaker 0: That is why I'm rooting for the Kings because I remember how crazy Detroit was when we broke our streak in '96, '97.
Speaker 0: The only thing I can say bad about the Kings is that they're in Los Angeles, which is well below the latitude at which hockey should be permitted might burn down Like the city will spontaneously erupt with passion.
Speaker 1: Okay, so conference championships, they were in '92, '93 season, they were in the finals.
Speaker 1: So there you go.
Speaker 0: I'm rooting for them, also I don't want anyone else.
Speaker 0: Devils, pieces of shit.
Speaker 0: Devils knocked the Red Wings out a couple of times in my life So they were already on my shit list, then I moved to New York.
Speaker 1: Devils.
Speaker 0: Good hockey.
Speaker 0: But, you know There's all this talk about football and how football is actually super bad for people, not to get into all that Hockey is also really bad.
Speaker 0: Hockey is pretty bad for people and hockey fights.
Speaker 0: As much as I like hockey fights, I would actually be okay if they got rid of that.
Speaker 1: It's tough, because I like watching a hockey fight but at the same time, I cannot come up with a single argument to defend the continued existence of hockey fights.
Speaker 0: Well, one argument against continuing them is that we have YouTube.
Speaker 0: now I can see pretty much every video recorded hockey fight that ever happens.
Speaker 0: I think that's still the best one ever.
Speaker 0: I've never seen a hockey fight that is better than that, but for anyone who doesn't know, on March 17th 1991, there was a Chicago and St.
Speaker 0: Louis hockey game.
Speaker 0: It was before HDTV, obviously, before any of that stuff.
Speaker 0: and I'm going to read a quote from Adam Oates about this fight.
Speaker 0: Quote, "It was weird I was pretty scared, I'll tell you that Let me rephrase that, terrified Grimson Manson, Paluso and they had ten bodies on the ice.
Speaker 0: So this is an almost five minute long video of one of the most famous and spectacular bench clearing hockey brawls of all time.
Speaker 0: It's pretty amazing.
Speaker 0: At one point, it looks like they're going to drag someone from the stands into the fight.
Speaker 0: There's so many independent fights that the refs can't do anything about it.
Speaker 0: I just watch it.
Speaker 0: It's amazing.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there are people who remember this particular fight, maybe even as a name or something.
Speaker 0: The St.
Speaker 0: Patrick's Day Massacre.
Speaker 1: There you go, right?
Speaker 1: But it's not nearly all that famous even though it was a gigantic fight, huge guys beating each other up all over the place.
Speaker 1: But yet in basketball fights are extremely rare.
Speaker 1: So rare, in fact, that there's really only one famous basketball fight, which is the Malice at the Palace.
Speaker 1: Now the Malice at the Palace, fight-wise between the players, was really not all that bad as the St.
Speaker 1: Patrick's Day Massacre, yet the Malice at the Palace is extremely famous, mostly because at one point, a dude gets hit with a cup of liquid that was thrown from the stands, and then the fighting goes in with the fans.
Speaker 0: Think of it this way If there were no walls at a hockey game Imagine Already, that glass is barely keeping the crowd out of the ice.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying, there's no glass.
Speaker 0: You know what you'll get?
Speaker 0: You'll get what happens at soccer games.
Speaker 1: I know, it would be unbelievable.
Speaker 0: The only difference is, the people in the stands, drunk and full of passion as they are, are not wearing skates and probably have forgotten that ice is slippery.
Speaker 0: So it would be great, but not for the reasons that you'd expect it to be great.
Speaker 1: No, but at the Malice at the basketball, the players went into the stands.
Speaker 0: I remember at RIT, when they were taunting a guy in the box and he actually tried to hit someone in the stands with his stick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in between the panels of glass Yeah, he got in big trouble.
Speaker 0: This is a pretty good hockey fight Very good.
Speaker 1: Oh, thing of the day, right For those of you who don't live in the US, you may not know, we have these two holidays Veterans Day and Memorial Day.
Speaker 1: So Veterans Day is for people who were in the military or war and/or war and are no longer in the military And Memorial Day is for people who are dead because of war.
Speaker 1: There is a distinction between the two holidays.
Speaker 1: Someone asked me, "Why do we have two holidays for
Speaker 1: this?".
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Because they're not the same".
Speaker 1: It's Memorial, you're in memory of dead people, and veteran, a person who was formerly serving Well, as opposed to President's Day where we took all these other days.
Speaker 0: and we're like, "Alright, you just get one day off".
Speaker 1: So, here is a video of, you know, in our So Memorial Day was on Monday, which means you didn't go to work.
Speaker 1: It's bank holiday for UK types.
Speaker 1: So, we have a cemetery in Washington, DC.
Speaker 1: It's actually, I think, just outside of I don't know if it's technically DC, I guess it's Arlington Maryland, or whatever And it's Arlington Cemetery.
Speaker 1: It is the, you know, national military cemetery, and it's just basically most of it is just a sea of small white crosses, as far as you can see.
Speaker 1: And there is a place at the cemetery where I've been.
Speaker 1: that is the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier And it's a dead US soldier in a tomb, and we don't know who it is.
Speaker 1: So it's symbolically, you know it's nobody and everybody at the same time And there's a guard who walks back and forth in front of this you know, thing with a gun.
Speaker 0: Now, it's America, so tourists do what tourists do.
Speaker 1: So, you know, in Britain, there's those guards.
Speaker 1: what are they called at the palace?
Speaker 1: With the funny hats?
Speaker 0: The Royal Palace Guards.
Speaker 1: I don't know what they're actually called, they have a name.
Speaker 1: But, you know, people always make jokes about how you can mess around with them, and they'll never do anything, right?
Speaker 1: They just sort of keep minding their own business and being perfectly still and silent, right?
Speaker 0: The Queen's Guard.
Speaker 1: So, the guard, the singular guard at the, you know Tomb of the Unknown Soldier paces, you know, back and forth, or marches back, whatever the word is Back and forth.
Speaker 1: And then occasionally they have a changing of the guard which is a ceremony, that, you know.
Speaker 1: cause you can't, not one person can't do that for that long, right?
Speaker 1: So they have, and you can't just sort of walk off and have another guy walk in and start doing it, it's sort of lame, right?
Speaker 1: You got a little ceremony, and that's what you do when you go to the cemetery, is you watch the ceremony?
Speaker 1: Now, the thing is unlike, you know, the guards in Britain.
Speaker 1: if you dick around this guard is actually guarding, and he will yell at you He'll be like, you're not
Speaker 0: allowed to talk
Speaker 1: near the thing you're not allowed to go on the platform where the tomb is, you're not allowed to go over the railing, you're not, you know, you're pretty much, you have to stand during the ceremony, you can't sit unless I guess you're in a wheelchair or something, right?
Speaker 1: You know, you have to maintain, I guess he said, an atmosphere of silence and whatever at, you know, at all times.
Speaker 1: So, if you fuck around, the guard yells at you and I don't know what they'll do if you keep fucking around, but since so many tourists go there, there's a lot of yelling This guy does a really good job of telling tourists to stop being dumbasses.
Speaker 1: Yes, there's a video montage here of multiple different guards yelling at stupid tourists in many different ways.
Speaker 0: So, why can't...
Speaker 1: I kind of want to go there for like a couple days and just sit there and film any time that he has to yell at someone because I'll probably pick up like ten more that I can add to this montage.
Speaker 0: What I would like to know is, if there's any soldiers who are bored, I would love for you to just patrol around New York City.
Speaker 1: You know, sometimes like I wish you could sign up for the military just to get this sort of job Right?
Speaker 1: It's like I don't want to have to be shot at or kill anyone Right, but I would love to get like the ceremonial job, the thing is the ceremonial job is usually like a great honor that you have to earn by being a real soldier.
Speaker 1: It's not just something that like, okay, we're going to let the guy who sucks so much do the easy job.
Speaker 0: It's like, no, you earn the easy job.
Speaker 0: When we asked, there was the kart racing club, and we were like can we join the club as racers and train to drive the car?
Speaker 1: No, you have to earn that.
Speaker 0: And we were like, yeah, nevermind, I got more important things to do.
Speaker 1: There's other things that I will, you know, because you really only have enough effort in your life to earn one thing or two things that are worth earning, right?
Speaker 1: You know, there's a lot of things you want to earn but you can't buy them, you know, you can't just walk into them, so just pick your battles Right?
Speaker 1: If you try to earn, if you try to do all those great things, you know, drive the F1 car and guard the tomb and you're not going to make it.
Speaker 1: It's not going to happen, no matter how awesome you are.
Speaker 0: So very briefly in the meta moment, Kineticon is coming up, check out the website.
Speaker 0: Most of the schedule is up, most of the rest of it will be up in the next day or two.
Speaker 0: We'll be there doing stuff.
Speaker 0: Dave Riley will be there doing stuff Nice karate Good stuff.
Speaker 1: Also in the meta moment, the book called Book is 1Q84.
Speaker 0: I'm going to start calling it Qteen84.
Speaker 1: You can do that because you think it's clever.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's correct.
Speaker 1: though I think it's correct, I think it works.
Speaker 0: I think it's a worthwhile translation, that's how you would say that number.
Speaker 0: And in the context of the book, that's how it's used.
Speaker 1: anyway The actual title of the book is Ichikyu Hachibyon.
Speaker 1: It's the four numbers separately.
Speaker 1: So you shouldn't say 1984, you should say I said 1Q84.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so 1Q84 Yeah, I still think it's going to be Qteen84.
Speaker 1: Anyway That's the book.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty damn good book, I'm mostly done with it.
Speaker 1: I already finished it because it was so good.
Speaker 1: But we'll give you some more time before we do an episode because while I don't think it's long, it is It's only three volumes, 900 pages.
Speaker 1: To make up for the fact that I did a bunch of baby books.
Speaker 0: The one thing I will say is that I went into it.
Speaker 0: I literally knew nothing about what it was.
Speaker 0: I didn't even read the back of the book or anything.
Speaker 1: This is the only thing that I knew going into it.
Speaker 1: It was written by Haruki Murakami.
Speaker 1: I know that that is a person who is an extremely famous Japanese author so famous that his books are translated and sold across the world.
Speaker 1: I knew Emily had read another work that was "weird" And that almost every anime person and lots of other people are always citing this guy as an influence.
Speaker 1: He's so important and amazing.
Speaker 1: I should probably know what this guy is all about.
Speaker 1: This is his latest, greatest, super popular work that I see everyone reading on the subway and such, let's read it.
Speaker 0: What I want to say is that I got halfway through, literally the 50% mark on the Kindle.
Speaker 0: Halfway through the second book.
Speaker 0: I realized suddenly that normal novels it was like building up to the kind of climax that ends most books.
Speaker 0: I realized that that was literally the halfway point.
Speaker 0: I'm getting near the end now as I'm starting to see where this is going It's going to be hard not to discuss before the episode.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should record the episode while it's fresh and then put it up later after people have had time because I understand not everyone can read 900 pages in five days.
Speaker 0: like I can Not to brag I might have to fly to Toronto next week, Monday and Tuesday.
Speaker 1: You don't want to go there.
Speaker 0: Children have cigarette ads instead of faces.
Speaker 1: Don't bring wicker goods with you.
Speaker 0: Wicker goods are taxed there, I don't want my wicker goods to be taxed.
Speaker 1: Don't look at the donut ads.
Speaker 0: I wonder how many people get that.
Speaker 0: I wonder how much hair that actually is.
Speaker 0: The funny thing is.
Speaker 0: I remember at RIT I was looking for that song to get an MP3 of it and I found a different song about Toronto that has the same moral but is very different.
Speaker 0: Anyway I might be out of town those two days meaning you guys should play the Burning Wheel game without me because we missed one already.
Speaker 1: We could also play an alternative game.
Speaker 1: I suggested that last time.
Speaker 0: If you want to play Burning Wheel I'll just figure out some pre-rolls I would want to do and I can roll them with a witness for things I want to do like link tests and all that and then my character is off doing that shit.
Speaker 1: You could also practice hours.
Speaker 0: Nah, I want to roll things.
Speaker 1: You don't get things that matter.
Speaker 1: if you don't show up, you get practice hours.
Speaker 0: I could lose link tests.
Speaker 1: now I'm not the GM, it's not my call, but that's what I would do if I was GM.
Speaker 0: You get practice hours But if I have to go to Toronto next week I pretty much guarantee I'll finish the book on the flight there.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you should bring a second book with you.
Speaker 0: I also learned something weird.
Speaker 0: I've never flown to Toronto.
Speaker 0: I've always lived near enough to just drive to it.
Speaker 0: I guess I could have taken that fast ferry.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess there's really no reason to fly there.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess maybe now there is Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I learned that if you fly out of Newark which sucks because now I've got to fly out of Newark You can take this little porter air thing that lands at this tiny little airport in the middle of downtown Toronto Really?
Speaker 0: And you take this little ferry right to downtown and there's no security there.
Speaker 0: It's like the best little airport and I had no idea this existed.
Speaker 1: and while I have to deal with Newark Well, isn't it going to be like a tiny plane like propellers?
Speaker 0: If it is, whatever, I've got noise isolation earbuds and you know what, I've flown puddle jumpers before.
Speaker 1: You should probably team up with some people.
Speaker 1: get the private jet so it's quieter.
Speaker 0: We're not sending that many people Gulfstream, ten people.
Speaker 0: It'll be maybe two people.
Speaker 1: No, nine people from other companies.
Speaker 1: Team up, charter.
Speaker 0: There is a financial event there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure there's other financial people who are going that have a seat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so final meta.
Speaker 1: I upgraded the whole website.
Speaker 0: Oh, I haven't even gone to it since you upgraded it.
Speaker 0: So I upgraded the whole website.
Speaker 0: You can see how busy I've been with Connecticut.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, there's a lot of words.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I know nobody goes to our website and you can if you want to but it's not necessary because basically the new website is merely, it's mostly just there for Google to see it.
Speaker 1: It's way more words than before And people who like to visit it.
Speaker 1: As soon as you add videos, there'll be a video on the homepage.
Speaker 0: You also gotta add in the old.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna try to get them automatically from the YouTube API.
Speaker 1: And you can also add in the book clubs that are missing.
Speaker 0: I think they're all in the regular website.
Speaker 1: No, when I loaded the database the latest one was I added all my books.
Speaker 1: I did add them.
Speaker 1: Look at it.
Speaker 0: later I added them, I typed that shit in.
Speaker 0: I remember sitting there and doing it.
Speaker 1: The latest one was I think the, I forget.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the main thing this website does the new version of the website is automatically linking things together.
Speaker 1: It posts things to Facebook automatically and it posts things to Twitter automatically and it posts things to the forum automatically and it's going to.
Speaker 1: We're going to do even more stuff along those lines.
Speaker 1: We can't do G+ automatically.
Speaker 1: We still have to do it by hand Because Google doesn't have an API.
Speaker 1: It's not because I didn't write it.
Speaker 1: I'm going to add a mail newsletter And I'm going to automatically connect it to YouTube.
Speaker 1: So basically Wherever you are, I might even connect it to a Tumblr and have a Tumblr.
Speaker 1: that is an exact copy, right?
Speaker 1: It's going to be like a dandelion Just spread your seeds all over the fuck.
Speaker 1: So no matter what thing it is you like to use Google Reader, iTunes Whatever you like to use to connect to us, just keep using that thing you like and you can come to our website if you want, but our website is going to publish everything everywhere as much as possible to get our content out to as many people as possible and you're going to see a lot more from us in terms of when there's a YouTube, when you make a YouTube video, it's going to get put out on all those places or when there's a new book club announced.
Speaker 1: So go to all those places.
Speaker 1: So I'm even thinking of making a Geek Nights Reddit and every time we post something on the website a new link is added to the Geek Nights Reddit.
Speaker 1: Just go all out like this.
Speaker 1: See how it works, see how much we can spread the community around And if you want to go to the website, you can do that too.
Speaker 1: It's improved.
Speaker 1: I think it's easier to navigate.
Speaker 1: It has more information on the front page.
Speaker 0: Don't forget that if you go to our website, every episode back to October 31, 2005 is on the website for download, still, free And I'm going to keep adding more stuff to it at about the rate of a feature per week.
Speaker 1: probably I've got a whole list of awesome features that I'm considering, I've already mentioned a few Reddit integration and such.
Speaker 1: Our website doesn't suck anymore as much and you should go to it And expect a lot more stuff to come.
Speaker 0: Maybe we might start doing these live, pre-roll, post-roll of just doing Geek Nights More content, more YouTube videos, more Radio Free Equestria more stuff I guess.
Speaker 0: also to all you people who complain about us not consuming media you've asked us to consume or doing things you want us to do, it's because we're doing stuff like this.
Speaker 0: You know how long we've been talking about this stupid website change?
Speaker 1: Speaking of Memorial Day, it took four days to do this shit and I had already done a great deal of it in advance.
Speaker 1: It just took four days to finish it up and there was a lot of stuff that I just sort of bailed on and didn't do.
Speaker 1: that you might not notice.
Speaker 1: I have to go and do Like.
Speaker 1: I disabled all the sitemaps because they stopped working, I had to go reprogram them.
Speaker 0: I'm still editing HD video for, I don't know, two packs worth of stuff I've got videos for.
Speaker 1: I haven't even tested if the episode uploading works, I'm gonna have to sit here while we're in.
Speaker 0: We're gonna find out in a few minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we are Alright.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So we've gone on a while so I don't think I'm gonna try to tell the entire tale of my travels.
Speaker 0: This was basically the show about...
Speaker 1: Well, that's the thing whenever we don't have an episode for a while It's sort of like when you don't get your groove on for a while.
Speaker 1: It's sort of an explosion of pent up energy.
Speaker 0: We also didn't talk in person for a while because I was in Istanbul and we've been busy in this Kineticon.
Speaker 1: It's a very busy time here with the Kineticon coming up.
Speaker 0: Yep, like believe me, the week before I went to Istanbul, every night it's just like hours and hours and hours of pouring through panel bullshit and typing stuff in and suddenly now that the deadline has come is when all the emails come out of the woodwork from staff who say things like "Oh, by the way, here's six hours of content I need scheduled" and stuff from panelists who were like "Hey, I didn't submit any panels, but I kind of expected you'd give them to me and what panels am I
Speaker 0: doing?".
Speaker 1: Why didn't you submit them?
Speaker 0: You're not getting any Slowly trying to grandfather that stuff out and new website and everything but I had to get all that as much done as possible before I flew to Istanbul.
Speaker 0: so for like two weeks before that trip I was in La La Land doing that work.
Speaker 1: I think what we need to do is we need to make a mailing list on MailChimp that has all the people who have ever done Kineticon panels who aren't blacklisted and sort of send them out a thing like "Attention!
Speaker 1: Panel registration is now open".
Speaker 0: I did that this year.
Speaker 1: He does that for PAX.
Speaker 0: I did that this year and I think it worked because a lot of the people responded to that.
Speaker 1: And then we could be like "If you do not submit then you will not get a panel no matter what".
Speaker 0: We're getting better every year but this is like crunch time for that.
Speaker 0: And it's summer so I gotta go outside.
Speaker 1: That's the one for one thing keeping me from getting stuff done.
Speaker 1: The sun's out, I'm going biking.
Speaker 1: I've run out of places to bike in Manhattan that I haven't been yet.
Speaker 0: You should go up into the Bronx or something.
Speaker 1: I did that the other day.
Speaker 0: How far up?
Speaker 0: Go to Yonkers.
Speaker 1: I didn't go to Yonkers.
Speaker 0: Route 9 is a bike path all the way north.
Speaker 1: That's a little too far.
Speaker 1: The thing is I gotta go far enough so that I can actually get back home on the same day.
Speaker 0: You can go far north and take the train back Metro north.
Speaker 1: I don't wanna take the train, I wanna bike the whole time.
Speaker 0: Depends Bike to Cafe Maya, eat at Cafe Maya, train home.
Speaker 1: Not too bad I need to buy a train pass at Grand Central before I leave.
Speaker 1: It's five bucks and never expires But you can't buy the train pass at Eakins.
Speaker 0: No, you know what I did?
Speaker 0: Seven years ago I bought a bike pass and I always keep it in my wallet.
Speaker 1: Next time I'm near Grand Central I'll buy one.
Speaker 0: Actually I don't know where it is right now but it was in my wallet.
Speaker 0: at one point I might have to buy another one.
Speaker 1: So let's talk about Turkey gobble gobble.
Speaker 0: So Istanbul, the first thing I should say is that it is.
Speaker 0: People might have different visions of what a city like Istanbul is like because they imagine other foreign cities and strange places.
Speaker 1: People who haven't traveled have all these imaginations.
Speaker 0: Istanbul is Other than the fact that people are speaking Turkish and there's old stuff around.
Speaker 0: You might as well be in London or New York or DC or Tokyo, it is a completely modern, like subways and taxis and everyone takes credit cards and everything's normal and everything's chill and it's safe.
Speaker 0: It was literally like a completely modern city Except that it didn't smell like piss.
Speaker 0: I was amazed by this.
Speaker 0: The entire city.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like India where people were littering everywhere There was almost no litter anywhere and everything smelled either neutral or of the sea or of flowers.
Speaker 1: You've got seas on both sides here The divide of Asia and Europe The Bosphorus river The golden ore and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: The wind can blow in four different directions and no matter which direction it's going, it's probably picking up some sea air Every time I get to PAX, it's like the fresh air.
Speaker 0: This air is going to go through a bunch of America before it gets to me.
Speaker 0: in New York Basically I had one whole day when I flew in just to wander around.
Speaker 0: It was kind of humbling.
Speaker 0: I've visited old places before but I stood on a road that was a thousand years ago.
Speaker 0: that road was already ancient and the origins of it had been mostly forgotten.
Speaker 0: There were just normal houses on that road.
Speaker 0: today It was the same road that a thousand years ago armies marched on, emperors might have ridden on a chariot down In Connecticut.
Speaker 1: the best you could hope for is some revolutionary militia marched down this road or defended here.
Speaker 1: When was that?
Speaker 1: 17 something It's like, yeah, okay See this road?
Speaker 1: Alexander the Great was on this road.
Speaker 0: I mean, there were columns.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of columns around Just like randomly, walking down the street Like a normal street, there's a tramway there and a subway entrance And there's a little fence.
Speaker 0: In the middle of the fence is a giant Roman column that at one point held something up And it's got the original But it's not holding up anything anymore.
Speaker 1: They did a really good job of making columns and a really bad job of making the other parts.
Speaker 0: The other parts got torn down to build normal buildings because the city is still being lived in.
Speaker 1: But if you had a working aqueduct why would you tear it down?
Speaker 1: Even an old Roman aqueduct is still really freaking useful if it works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, to a degree And it's really awesome looking, you shouldn't tear it down.
Speaker 0: But, you know, wars happen.
Speaker 0: Turkey, I mean Istanbul, as you may recall was Constantinople.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, King of Kings Look upon my works, you might All you listeners, we've talked about this a lot many years ago, but there's a podcast called 12 Byzantine Rulers And it's pretty much the best podcast you're ever going to listen to.
Speaker 0: Forget Geek Nights, you should just listen to this thing.
Speaker 1: Why are you listening to us?
Speaker 1: I mean, you should not listen to us, as in you should not have this podcast in your iTunes, but you should listen to us as in, if you are listening to this podcast right now, you should do as we tell you That meaning of the word.
Speaker 1: listen.
Speaker 0: But most people in America don't really know about the Eastern Roman Empire.
Speaker 0: Like, they know, alright, Rome fell in 476.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're like, there's Greeks and then there's Rome, and in 476 Rome fell and then Dark Ages, and then Renaissance.
Speaker 1: Most people don't even know that.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know that much
Speaker 0: And I remember I have a Western Civ textbook and I think the last time we talked about this, I pulled it out and quoted from it, because it devotes one paragraph saying that the Eastern Roman Empire lasted much longer and was called Byzantium
Speaker 1: and actually said something.
Speaker 0: So, people forget that 476, Western Roman Empire fell A thousand years later around that time is when the rest of the Roman Empire fell.
Speaker 1: Well, it's sort of one of those situations where it's like.
Speaker 1: you know, let's say Virginia was wiped off the map, people would be like, yeah, West Virginia stuck around for a little while, right?
Speaker 0: Except in this case, the Eastern Roman Empire was arguably greater in extent and everything than, you know, the Western Roman Empire.
Speaker 1: Well, West Virginians would say the same thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we kind of Except they're wrong To be fair, the West Virginians did side with the Union in the War of Northern Aggression.
Speaker 1: I didn't say they didn't.
Speaker 1: It's still a really shitty, meaningless state.
Speaker 1: Perhaps the only more meaningless state is North Dakota, but at least the thing is North Dakota leaves well enough alone.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing about North Dakota is that it's so meaningless that you sort of pay more attention to it, because it's like being in last place.
Speaker 1: West Virginia is sort of like second to last place, so it's like you're completely ignored.
Speaker 0: No, North Dakota is not last place.
Speaker 0: They may be irrelevant, but I point out North Carolina, Alabama, Tennessee Georgia...
Speaker 1: No, those are the worst.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about the least noticeable, not the place with the worst people.
Speaker 1: Neither one of those is even close to being the place with the worst people.
Speaker 1: It's just the smallest, least thought about by other states, insignificant forgotten state.
Speaker 0: But I mean, the Eastern Roman Empire was basically the progenitor of the Renaissance when the intellectuals fled when the greatest city in the world finally fell.
Speaker 0: I think the quote from Twelve Byzantine Rulers was some French night when the Crusades happened and Constantinople finally fell, at least once and the guy said something to the effect of "I think more houses burned down in this one fire in the middle of this battle than exist in all of France".
Speaker 0: But I digress.
Speaker 0: This is an ancient city.
Speaker 0: A thousand years ago the city was already ancient and already the center of what many people considered to be the civilized world if not the entire world And I saw columns that were ancient a thousand years ago and the coolest part was that some of those were even more ancient.
Speaker 0: There's one called the Serpent Column.
Speaker 1: Has a serpent engraved on it?
Speaker 0: I didn't know about the Serpent Column.
Speaker 0: I'm going to pull up Wikipedia to make sure I don't say anything wrong But basically I'm going to pull up Wikipedia to make sure I don't say anything wrong.
Speaker 0: I was standing there and I was looking at it and there was a little plaque that explained that it was from.
Speaker 0: Okay, it looks like the plaque is correct.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't always trust plaques Like, I was in Jerusalem and there was a plaque Like, this is the tomb of David.
Speaker 1: That is not the tomb of King David.
Speaker 0: The Serpent Column was relocated to Constantinople by Constantine the Great in the year 324.
Speaker 1: As in the Constantine Not some other guy named Constantine.
Speaker 0: Constantine won The Great.
Speaker 1: He picked up this column somewhere else because he thought it was awesome And he had slaves or who knows who carried it.
Speaker 0: So here's the deal.
Speaker 0: This column in the year 324 was ancient history and was brought as an artifact to be put in the greatest city in the world Sort of like how he brought the pyramid and put it in our museum in the middle of our city.
Speaker 0: Not the pyramid, the Egyptian column I point out next to the serpent column Is a similar Egyptian column to what we have in New York that the Byzantines stole from Egypt.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Theirs is in much better condition than ours is.
Speaker 0: So, this column was ancient history in the year 324 and they brought it to make a monument about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's the year So we have a cloister here.
Speaker 1: It's like a castle FDR, I think, built that.
Speaker 1: It's not even 100 years old at best Not even 100 years old This thing, the year 300 The year 2000 So 1700 years And it's already ancient at that point.
Speaker 0: So Scott, 1000 years ago The serpentine column had been in Constantinople since before anyone could remember.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, so I think we've done enough talking about how old and awesome old things are.
Speaker 1: But I mean, yeah, old things are the awesomest, so we could just call this episode the old things episode and talk about the rest some other time, because we could talk about old things all day.
Speaker 0: Scott, the column is 2500 years old.
Speaker 1: Old things are worth talking about.
Speaker 1: We should just do every episode of Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: It's no going on Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: It's the old things podcast.
Speaker 1: Alright, so next episode, Scott Johnson Old man Scott There are other things we could talk about that are pretty old.
Speaker 0: Do you want to talk about Encore Watts?
Speaker 1: Encore Watts is probably not as old as that serpent column, but it's still pretty old.
Speaker 1: It's pretty old.
Speaker 1: There's older stuff though.
Speaker 0: You can read about the serpent column and what it's made out of and why it's extra cool, but it was just there Just kind of hanging out.
Speaker 1: It's got to be made out of stone, right?
Speaker 0: But there was a much newer object that really got to me.
Speaker 0: It was a column and it had inscriptions on it from the era of Justinian and earlier and they were kind of faded but visible, and you look at them and they're basically carvings of Romans.
Speaker 1: It's the kind of carving we make today.
Speaker 1: I was going to say it's Latin, I'm like, how can you read it?
Speaker 0: So that's the thing.
Speaker 0: This was the Eastern Roman Empire.
Speaker 0: Many things are in Greek But the inscription at the bottom of this column was in Latin and I could read it other than the fact that I don't read Latin.
Speaker 1: That's what I was saying.
Speaker 0: The letters were there, and I kind of had this moment of someone, you know, history is so ancient I can't even fathom it chipped those words there and at that time there were things in this city that were themselves as ancient to that guy as the thing I'm looking at now that he made is to me Otherwise, Istanbul.
Speaker 0: I just wandered around and I kind of I grew a beard before I went on the trip and I dressed in a blazer and nice pants and a dress shirt every day, walking around the city.
Speaker 0: As a result, the sharks that go after tourists left me alone, which was amazing because basically there would be ten people who would descend upon anyone wearing cargo shorts who was obviously a middle-aged American and just try to rip them off.
Speaker 0: They completely ignored me.
Speaker 0: The few people who did try to bother me didn't try English first.
Speaker 0: They tried German, Arabic, and French but they never tried English, it was amazing.
Speaker 0: and the few people?
Speaker 1: But hey, that guy is that multilingual?
Speaker 1: Yes The thing is, you think oh no, he just learned how to give his sales pitch in those languages.
Speaker 1: No, if he hits at you with Arabic, or French, and you start talking to him, he's got to be able to converse.
Speaker 1: Exactly This guy is that multilingual, yet the only thing he can find to do with his life is to pull some scam on the streets.
Speaker 1: Dude, you could be translating comics or something.
Speaker 0: Scott, do you know how much money I could make from tourists in Istanbul?
Speaker 1: Is he making more money than he could make as a UN translator?
Speaker 0: Probably The only people who actually tried to rip me off is a few times that they'd be really persistent and they'd try so many languages because they spoke so many languages.
Speaker 0: I couldn't get away with trying to use any of the languages I know words in.
Speaker 0: because what if they respond?
Speaker 0: Now what?
Speaker 0: I responded to people who were really persistent.
Speaker 0: I said, "Ma'alaman Verhoten".
Speaker 0: I figured no one would speak Finnish, and no one did.
Speaker 1: That's a rare one But the thing is the way you say it.
Speaker 1: if the guy is so multilingual he's got to be smart.
Speaker 1: He might be like, "Yeah, that's not your native language, dude I got you".
Speaker 0: Maybe not.
Speaker 0: I did it pretty confidently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could do it confidently.
Speaker 0: I might as well have said, "Baff my dad".
Speaker 0: But they basically completely left me alone, no one tried to rip me off and I think it was just because I didn't dress like an American tourist.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably It's the same way.
Speaker 1: When I walk around outside my office there's the people trying to sell you comedy show tickets.
Speaker 1: They used to bother me just because there used to be different guys who would do it and they would bother every single person.
Speaker 1: But now it's like, I walk out there.
Speaker 1: I don't have a camera on me.
Speaker 0: most days I'm not, you know No one even ever tries to hand me whatever it is.
Speaker 0: they're trying to hand me.
Speaker 1: I'm not walking slowly looking up at the buildings.
Speaker 1: I'm obviously not a tourist.
Speaker 1: There's this guy standing there, he's like, "Where are you from, man?
Speaker 1: Where are you
Speaker 1: from?".
Speaker 1: "Hey, how you doing there?
Speaker 1: Hey, big guy, what's
Speaker 1: up?".
Speaker 0: "Hey, rap CDs, rap CDs".
Speaker 1: Yeah, he doesn't even look at me because I'm not a tourist.
Speaker 1: You can tell by looking at me.
Speaker 1: If a tourist walked down the street wearing my clothes at my speed, he also would not be bothered.
Speaker 0: But a lot of people spoke English even, you know, way away from touristy stuff.
Speaker 0: so I could get around just fine on my own and I saw a lot of really cool stuff.
Speaker 0: I'll either talk about another show, get my pictures uploaded or whatever, but I felt safer and more comfortable walking around even very poor and remote neighborhoods in Istanbul in the middle of the night than I do in some places in the Bronx As the Bronx, right The poorest.
Speaker 0: I walked through some of the slummest parts of Istanbul and they were actually a lot nicer than some of the poor parts of New York City.
Speaker 0: They were way nicer than a lot of parts of Baltimore Baltimore?
Speaker 1: Oh, damn Bronx is like a palace compared to Bemore.
Speaker 0: Turkish coffee is a big deal.
Speaker 0: They think American coffee habits are ridiculous.
Speaker 0: No kidding They have this perception of us drinking 7-Eleven style big gulps of watery ass decaf coffee.
Speaker 0: Well, a lot of people do And I was like, yeah, that's pretty much what people do.
Speaker 1: But most people, I think, now at least get big gulps of Starbucks as opposed to big gulps.
Speaker 0: Those might not be legal anymore in New York at those stupid law places.
Speaker 1: I was wondering, is that law going to apply to Starbucks?
Speaker 0: It covers coffee.
Speaker 1: It does cover coffee.
Speaker 0: Coffee is sweetened, but it does not cover milkshakes or milk-derived things, nor does it cover espresso-based drinks So some of the beverages at Starbucks can't be vented.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so here's the deal.
Speaker 0: Here's the stupidity of this law.
Speaker 0: It bans a 20-ounce soda from a bodega because the bodega also serves food But it does not ban a 4-gallon milkshake.
Speaker 1: Nice Dude, let's open up a restaurant.
Speaker 0: 4-gallon milkshake is all we got.
Speaker 0: You know what we should do?
Speaker 0: Let's come up with a cup that is actually two cups, but they're banded together And you sell that to restaurants.
Speaker 1: Well, you got the straw with the split straw.
Speaker 0: No, we don't know.
Speaker 1: We don't even have to sell the cups that are attached to each other.
Speaker 1: We just sell the split straw and that's it.
Speaker 0: No, you gotta sell a thing that makes two cups into one so I can walk around.
Speaker 1: Oh, so it's got a handle with two holes in it?
Speaker 0: Kind of like how every hotel that wants to get around are actually very important.
Speaker 0: water conservation laws.
Speaker 0: Two shower heads Daddy.
Speaker 1: two shower heads Exactly.
Speaker 0: Oh, also, you know what?
Speaker 0: You can just drink the water It's fine, you can eat any food.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a lot of water there.
Speaker 1: Did you figure out where the water came from?
Speaker 1: Are those fresh water?
Speaker 1: Those are seas, right?
Speaker 0: There's also fresh water.
Speaker 1: Are they fresh?
Speaker 0: No, there's the sea and there's the Bosphorus and there's other lakes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's the Bosphorus, what is it?
Speaker 0: It's got the tap water, tasted as good as New York tap water.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it did, but I'm wondering where it came from.
Speaker 0: How many New Yorkers know where our water comes from?
Speaker 1: I know exactly where it comes from.
Speaker 0: How many New Yorkers know?
Speaker 1: Probably not that many think about it.
Speaker 1: So, the restaurants I ate at There's an aqueduct from the Catskills.
Speaker 1: It's actually the longest underground tunnel.
Speaker 1: The seafood was so good Because they catch it right there.
Speaker 0: There's a million people fishing on the river, connecting.
Speaker 1: That's probably a way to make a fuck ton of money.
Speaker 0: So I had fish that they brought them to the restaurant.
Speaker 0: They were still wet when they dumped them out And I ate those fish.
Speaker 0: They were like these little river fish.
Speaker 1: Oh, little fish?
Speaker 1: So it was like head comes off tail comes out, here's the fish Knife goes in, guts come out.
Speaker 0: To quote a friend that I have now in Turkey Americans are afraid of heads and eyes on anything they eat.
Speaker 1: I'm not afraid of the head, I've been on it still.
Speaker 1: I'm just not gonna eat that part.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so he was like, are you afraid of heads?
Speaker 0: I was like, fuck no They realized early on that I'm not a typical American.
Speaker 0: So they regaled me with their perceptions of Americans And my job was to say yes, they're like that Or no, they're actually not like that.
Speaker 1: That is a good thing to do.
Speaker 1: A few people in the world will be more understanding of other countries in both directions.
Speaker 0: At one point they were like So really, the imperial system.
Speaker 0: And I was like Alright, so here's the deal.
Speaker 0: Americans actually only use like three or four kinds of units for anything, and they don't use.
Speaker 0: It's not that they don't use the metric system.
Speaker 0: They don't use the imperial system either.
Speaker 0: They just don't talk about volume, ever.
Speaker 0: And if they do, it's gallons Like, Americans don't need a unit of mass Because they never use mass for anything.
Speaker 1: Except how much do you weigh?
Speaker 1: That's the only thing.
Speaker 0: That's weight and not mass.
Speaker 0: So they use pounds, because that's a unit of weight.
Speaker 0: But they don't use slugs The mass unit.
Speaker 0: But it's not that they use metric.
Speaker 0: They just don't use a unit for mass.
Speaker 0: And if they're a scientist, they use the metric system Because they're not stupid.
Speaker 0: So once I explain that And how we also think the system is stupid And most of us don't even use it Or know how it works.
Speaker 0: They were very surprised by that, and it kind of made sense.
Speaker 1: See, the thing is, we have this sort of When anyone goes to another country Even, I assume, really ignorant people There is sort of a cultural exchange That happens no matter what, even if it's a very small one.
Speaker 1: But the thing is We're coming to this world Where, you know, there's still a great deal Of international cultural boundaries.
Speaker 1: But we're having cultural boundaries Even within countries The nerds versus the whoever's.
Speaker 0: We've said this before, a nerd in Istanbul Has more in common with you and me And some nerd in Tokyo Than we do with people who live 20 miles north of New York City.
Speaker 1: We need more cultural exchange between The non-country cultures.
Speaker 1: The nerd culture is Really willing to share And teach other people about nerd culture But no one's really interested in hearing And no one really feels the need to share Their culture with nerds either.
Speaker 1: We need more exchanges Of this nature in the other Areas That are not simply country borders Alright, so hey Are you a homophobic guy In a really rural part of the country?
Speaker 1: Listen to Geek Nights and learn something We want to learn about you and your guns.
Speaker 1: Some of that stuff's pretty cool Blowing stuff up in the backyard.
Speaker 1: We're on board.
Speaker 0: I feel like telling them what we really think wouldn't matter If we went to them, we're like, you know what?
Speaker 0: We really don't care.
Speaker 0: if you have guns We literally go nuts.
Speaker 0: We don't care.
Speaker 0: But you have to not hate gay people In your laws, that's all we want.
Speaker 1: For a small amount of time, you hang out With guys like that, I feel like we could get along On some common grounds.
Speaker 1: Even the most hickest racist guy Go in the backyard Set food on fire, set things on fire.
Speaker 0: Very few people can resist the allure Of blowing something up in the middle of the woods.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Anyone can get along with anyone Even if I went to Turkey and it happened to be Crazy, fundamentalist guys I was working with.
Speaker 1: Actually what was funny is We could get along for a short time if I wasn't Jewish.
Speaker 0: By and large, the people I talked to in Istanbul Really Really are sick of the religious people Fucking everything up.
Speaker 1: I think that's because it's the same situation we have here.
Speaker 1: We're in the city, out of the city.
Speaker 0: What was funny is a lot of them would complain about Muslims The way atheists in America complain About Christians Just because Muslims are the guy next door Beating a drum in the middle of the night because it's Ramadan Or whatever.
Speaker 1: At least no religious practice At least not many in the US that are common Involve bothering neighbors.
Speaker 0: Well, church bells, but at least they're kind of pleasant.
Speaker 1: Church bells are nice, I like church bells.
Speaker 0: One guy I was talking to at a restaurant was like "Oh my god, the call to prayer just shut up, it's so loud".
Speaker 0: And I gotta tell ya The call to prayer Is really goddamn annoying But not for any religious reason.
Speaker 1: Doesn't it sound good?
Speaker 0: It would if it wasn't primarily Blasted through the worst possible speaker PA system?
Speaker 1: Like the horn shape thing?
Speaker 0: It sounds like they got A RadioShack speaker and put a megaphone In front of it.
Speaker 0: It would be beautiful.
Speaker 1: But for that You know what you could do?
Speaker 1: You could actually start a thing Where the Muslim people would probably donate to it.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, just go around the world and replace Those speakers with nice speakers And you just upgrade their sound system And you could partner with an audio Scott, I think you're a genius.
Speaker 1: You partner with a speaker company Right?
Speaker 1: And you find a Chinese factory And mass produce a perfect Speaker.
Speaker 0: just for that I think making speakers for mosques To do the call to prayer that were good Would do more for Muslim Non-Muslim relations than anything else In the world we could ever do.
Speaker 1: It would be great And the religious people would pay for it partially.
Speaker 1: They would be happy to donate Cause the way we'd sell it to them Is in addition to upgrading We would also add new ones so it would reach further To places where you maybe couldn't hear it.
Speaker 1: You know, like bathrooms.
Speaker 1: It's a way to sell more speakers too.
Speaker 0: But anyway Istanbul was awesome.
Speaker 0: And to cut the show short, I'll talk about it more later.
Speaker 0: Germany, the only thing they'll say is They served beer by the leader.
Speaker 0: It just kept coming.
Speaker 1: Do you get any wieners?
Speaker 0: If they bring you bread or pretzels on a table They check how many you ate And charge you for them.
Speaker 1: at the end It's bullshit, but there's no tipping though, right?
Speaker 0: People didn't seem to care about tipping.
Speaker 0: I asked a taxi driver, how much did I tip?
Speaker 0: He was like, you're over 2, it doesn't really matter, no one cares.
Speaker 0: And he actually didn't want a tip Because he was Turkish A Turkish taxi driver in Germany?
Speaker 0: So in Munich There's so many Turkish people.
Speaker 1: Oh, interesting They took the same flight you did.
Speaker 0: Well he's a taxi driver, he's lived there forever And he's like, I'm going to Istanbul next week To see some family.
Speaker 0: So we talked about Istanbul And he actually complained about a lot of the same things.
Speaker 0: It was funny.
Speaker 1: That's how you know, right?
Speaker 1: If a taxi driver in Munich Complains about the same things in Istanbul As a guy in Istanbul complained about That's a valid complaint Because these two unconnected people Were going on the same thing Or they were both the same guy with the disguise of the CIA.
Speaker 0: So I have three final anecdotes.
Speaker 0: we'll end One, in Germany I overheard more people Speaking English than I do on the streets of New York.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 0: And everyone I met who spoke English Their English was.
Speaker 1: They wouldn't know every word.
Speaker 1: Did they have German accents though, right?
Speaker 0: No, that was what was interesting.
Speaker 0: When they spoke English, it was perfect And had the exact Midwestern Neutral accent.
Speaker 1: They weren't like Erde Koster.
Speaker 0: It sounded perfectly natural And the only way you would know They were a non-native speaker Is when they struggled for a word they didn't know.
Speaker 0: But if they knew a word, they spoke it In a very neutral accent.
Speaker 0: That was kind of surprising.
Speaker 1: Did you help people out with the words they didn't know?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and two Because you could usually tell what word someone's going for.
Speaker 0: The majority of young people I overheard Speaking in English And every young person was speaking in English Was talking about video games Because they were internetting.
Speaker 0: probably They were talking about Modern Warfare 2 CoD, Call of Duty Games like that And I talked to some of them a little bit.
Speaker 1: I played video games Land parties over there PC game world.
Speaker 0: I was talking to one of my partners there In English about gaming stuff.
Speaker 1: Emily, he's got partners in other countries.
Speaker 1: Watch out.
Speaker 0: And basically this little kid I overhear him in the next row He's like, that foreign guy's talking about video games.
Speaker 0: Oh my god What name is he talking about?
Speaker 0: I don't know Some board game.
Speaker 0: Kid didn't know any of the board games.
Speaker 1: Did you bring Spot It and Jungle Speed?
Speaker 0: I didn't have any time to play games with anyone At all.
Speaker 1: We didn't continue our pattern of board game cultural exchange.
Speaker 0: So that was anecdote one.
Speaker 0: Everyone in Germany speaks English just fine.
Speaker 0: Anecdote number two in Munich Is that I went to many sorts of gardens and things.
Speaker 0: They have a park like Central Park.
Speaker 0: that's way bigger than Central Park In the middle of the city.
Speaker 0: Not hard to be bigger than Central Park But entirely within a major city It's one of the few that's bigger than Central Park actually.
Speaker 0: But The gardens In Germany Have a symmetry that is Almost disturbing.
Speaker 0: I was walking down the middle of this big Garden And I realized it was so symmetrical That I felt like I was in a Counter Strike 1-6 map.
Speaker 1: Who made this garden?
Speaker 0: How old was it?
Speaker 0: Germans, I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's not Constantine old.
Speaker 0: Is it Holy Roman Empire old?
Speaker 0: All I can say is that Any garden I entered Had a frightful symmetry and a frightful Artificiality.
Speaker 0: It didn't have streams.
Speaker 0: It had perfectly straight Manicured canals with straight bridges over them.
Speaker 1: You sure it wasn't just that one?
Speaker 0: I went to several in Munich and they were all like that.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's Munich.
Speaker 1: Maybe there was some king near Munich.
Speaker 0: As Luke Burish said, no that's not Germany That's Europe, but we'll see.
Speaker 1: Maybe in the 800's some king near Munich Had this garden made.
Speaker 0: So the third and final anecdote With one exception, every cab I took And the entire time I was in Istanbul Tried to rip me off.
Speaker 0: Now I knew, I read online That there is a specific con they will do.
Speaker 0: Now there's some basic ones.
Speaker 0: They'll run the night rate instead of the day rate.
Speaker 0: So I learned those Turkish words for day and night And I'd be like, no no no!
Speaker 0: Change it to day, I know exactly what you're trying to do You ass.
Speaker 0: And they'd always be like, oh sorry They tried to pretend.
Speaker 1: Just be like, dude Don't have to pretend that you weren't Trying to rip me off.
Speaker 0: You're getting ahead of my anecdote.
Speaker 0: So the most common one Is they will Take your money And you'll have like a 50 lira note Which is like $26.
Speaker 1: Oh it's like 50 cents for a lira?
Speaker 0: A lira is like about half a dollar Like 1.8 something.
Speaker 0: So they'll take your 50 lira note And they'll do really good sleight of
Speaker 1: hand
Speaker 0: And show you like, no you gave me a 5 Because tourists are like, oh sorry They don't want to make a confrontation
Speaker 1: And
Speaker 0: this is such a common thing that I was ready for it.
Speaker 0: You took a picture of the bill and then So I did that once But basically I held it out to him And he goes to take it and I didn't let go.
Speaker 0: And I took my phone up and I took a picture and I made it make the click And I looked at him and he sighed And then he gave me my right change.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 0: Another guy did it and I didn't take a picture because I was tired.
Speaker 0: And I looked at him and I was like Dude, don't bullshit me I know exactly what you're doing.
Speaker 0: You do this to everyone.
Speaker 0: I'll call the police.
Speaker 0: And he pretended he didn't understand a little bit.
Speaker 0: And I was like, dude I know you understand me.
Speaker 0: It's obvious you understand every word.
Speaker 0: I'm saying Just give me my change and I'll give you a tip anyway.
Speaker 0: And he was like, uh It usually works.
Speaker 0: He said that in English and he gave me the tip.
Speaker 0: I reported him anyway But I did give him a 5 lira tip.
Speaker 1: If I got in a cab and I knew that everyone was scamming I'd be like One cabbie.
Speaker 0: when I sat down I looked at him and I was like I'm not a tourist.
Speaker 0: Don't try to rip me off.
Speaker 0: I'm going to the Sheraton in Maslach.
Speaker 0: Don't pretend you don't know where that is.
Speaker 0: And he looked at me.
Speaker 0: Then he sighed and then he drove me to the hotel.
Speaker 0: One cabbie was this punk kid.
Speaker 0: He must have been like late 20s.
Speaker 0: I get in the cab and I tell him Sheraton Maslach, that's just where I was staying But there was a subway station right in front.
Speaker 0: It was like the equivalent of staying in Queens Like Astoria, next to Manhattan.
Speaker 0: So I told him, Sheraton Maslach.
Speaker 0: And he was like, Maslach I know He didn't speak English that well, it was obvious Sheraton, I'm not so sure.
Speaker 0: So I was like, alright, I'll tell you how to get there.
Speaker 0: And he was actually, he really didn't know He was super earnest Or he was the best actor in the universe.
Speaker 0: He didn't try to rip me off He didn't mess with the meter.
Speaker 0: He was the only cabbie who did not try to rip me off And was earnest the whole time.
Speaker 0: And you know, company dime.
Speaker 0: anyway I gave him like a $30 tip Because with the $30 tip Would have been cheaper than the guys who tried to rip me off.
Speaker 0: And he was like, are you sure?
Speaker 0: When I gave him the extra money?
Speaker 0: Like are you sure you don't want change?
Speaker 1: I was like, yeah I know I'm trying to teach you that you're doing it the right way.
Speaker 1: Every other cabbie in the whole city tries to rip everyone off.
Speaker 1: You did not try to rip me off.
Speaker 0: This is your reward.
Speaker 0: I explained to him, I was like, look, you're the first person I've gotten into a cab with the entire time I've been here Who did not try to scam me?
Speaker 0: Thank you And I think he understood it at that point And he had a huge smile on his face when I got out of the cab.
Speaker 0: Kind of like when I was in India, but that was different.
Speaker 0: That was when I gave the guy, I gave a tip to one cabbie.
Speaker 0: At the end that would be the equivalent here Of giving a guy like a couple hundred bucks But that was a whole different situation.
Speaker 1: But there's a different exchange rate involved there.
Speaker 1: Like if I went to Thailand, I could be like I had currency shock Because I was in Istanbul.
Speaker 0: Then I get to Europe and I'm like Oh shit, euros, my stupid weak ass.
Speaker 1: American dollar God damn it.
Speaker 1: The problem is if you do that too much You get in big trouble the other way Because you draw this attention.
Speaker 1: Imagine if someone walked down the street just throwing Benjamins around Whoa, shit son You'll be mobbing him.
Speaker 1: So you can't do that when you go to places that have cheap money.
Speaker 0: But it was super fun.
Speaker 0: And now I might have to go to Toronto soon.
Speaker 1: I don't want to go to Toronto.
Speaker 1: How's the Canadian dollar doing?
Speaker 1: Isn't it slightly stronger than the US dollar?
Speaker 1: US dollar is not looking so good right now Not to look so good Better than the, well The Greeks are lucky they don't have a Greek.
Speaker 1: Yeah, was there any Greek spillover going on there?
Speaker 0: Most of the Greeks were expelled from Turkey Not that long ago.
Speaker 1: But I mean like obviously But I mean like.
Speaker 1: you know It's right there.
Speaker 1: So didn't the situation in Greece have any effect In Turkey?
Speaker 0: In Turkey people just laughed Like that's Greece Like who else.
Speaker 0: but quagmire There was just a Pew Study and it was the funniest thing.
Speaker 0: I just read it today while I was at work.
Speaker 0: They interviewed everyone in Europe, like in Germany and Italy and all these countries And they asked What, like what country in the Eurozone is the most corrupt?
Speaker 0: What country is the hardest working?
Speaker 0: You know, whatever.
Speaker 0: Most people like in Germany Said that Italy is the most corrupt.
Speaker 0: Every other country Said that their own country Was the most corrupt Which was telling.
Speaker 0: But in one column the question was Which country in the Eurozone is the most hard working?
Speaker 0: Every single country In Europe?
Speaker 0: the overwhelming majority Of people said Germany Except Greece Which said Greece.
Speaker 0: I found that hilarious.
Speaker 0: It is to a degree that I cannot express.
Speaker 1: That is hilarious.
Speaker 1: I think Germany is the most hard working.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Germany is starting to become like the leader of Europe In a lot of ways.
Speaker 1: They do have car factories and stuff like that That other people really don't have.
Speaker 0: Munich was super nice, I gotta tell ya This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music Kat Lee for web design And Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com For show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio And no audience But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.