Speaker 0:
Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, March 14th, 2012.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, the order of the stick.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh, this morning, I had a pleasant surprise.
Speaker 1: I woke up, and who should be at my door?
Speaker 1: but BK?
Speaker 0: Uh, that's not a surprise.
Speaker 0: I checked the weather.
Speaker 0: I knew that there was smooth sailing, so the pirates would definitely be in town.
Speaker 1: But I woke up late, so I thought, eh, maybe I shouldn't, uh, you know, my bike's not even ready.
Speaker 0: Why me?
Speaker 0: BK shows up at your door, you get on his boat.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute, what the fuck?
Speaker 0: If you don't do that, you're stuck at, like, the beginning of the game.
Speaker 0: You can't get anywhere.
Speaker 0: 'Cause my boat- Where you gonna get in life if you don't ride the pirate ship?
Speaker 1: My boat wasn't ready.
Speaker 0: You're never gonna get, you're never gonna see the Silver Sword shop, even if you had a thousand coins to buy.
Speaker 1: I actually, it took me a while.
Speaker 1: I had to, like, pump my tires up and do greasing and all this stuff to my bike.
Speaker 1: I did that in advance.
Speaker 1: I did not.
Speaker 0: 'Cause I checked the forecast.
Speaker 1: Ah, but I was busy burning characters.
Speaker 0: As a good sailor should.
Speaker 1: So we'll see, it's biking season, and, uh, Scott and I are actually in the, uh, like, New York Five Borough tour thing.
Speaker 0: It's not a race, it's a tour.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but people do- Like, little kids are in it and shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but people do treat it as a race, but they put those people in a group by themselves.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there's some people who can try to race.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go as fast as I can, I'm gonna try to set a time.
Speaker 1: It's only, like, 40 miles.
Speaker 0: Like, it's not even that far.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna go and go.
Speaker 1: I am gonna try to get a time lapse of the whole thing with the GoPro.
Speaker 0: Uh, I should try to do the same thing.
Speaker 1: Actually, you know what I'll do tomorrow morning?
Speaker 1: I'll get a time lapse of my commute.
Speaker 0: I'd do the same thing, but how are you gonna attach your GoPro to your bike?
Speaker 1: Uh, I have a thing that mounts it to my handlebars.
Speaker 0: You got these special extra handlebar mounts?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was like, it was like eight bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I noticed is I bought it and then they didn't come with that handlebar mount and I was like, "What the
Speaker 0: fuck?".
Speaker 1: Oh, so you bought it too?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was like, "None of these fucking things will go on
Speaker 0: handlebars.".
Speaker 0: And they go on Amazon and I type it in and I'm like, "Oh, you make me buy an extra fucking thing, you piece of
Speaker 0: shit.".
Speaker 1: I'm not sure, like, I wanna try a time lapse with the handlebar and then a time lapse on the helmet to see which one, like, works better.
Speaker 0: The thing is, I don't even need to do a time lapse, I can just do a full lapse.
Speaker 1: I could do that too.
Speaker 1: But, who's gonna watch 25 minutes of me biking through Williamsburg?
Speaker 0: No, in post you speed it up, fast forward.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what happens when you speed it up?
Speaker 1: It drops frames, so why even bother taking them?
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: You can adjust in post and get it exactly the right length you want it to be, as opposed to pre-setting the length.
Speaker 0: and who knows what'll happen.
Speaker 1: Alright, you try that and I'm gonna do it the way I know, editing video.
Speaker 1: But with our powers combined now, we can do the 3D thing.
Speaker 1: once they release that.
Speaker 0: Uh, it's gonna be dumb.
Speaker 1: Well, it'll do real 3D, just do we wanna do real 3D or not?
Speaker 1: Do we need to?
Speaker 1: No, it's dumb.
Speaker 1: How is it dumb?
Speaker 1: What if you wanna do, like, mocap or something?
Speaker 0: Nobody can watch it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they can, actually YouTube supports 3D.
Speaker 0: Nobody has the glasses in the shit to watch it.
Speaker 1: Uh, you know, the sad thing is, you forget because you're old.
Speaker 0: Except for when you go to PAX at the Nvidia booth and they have the little demo machine, no one has that shit.
Speaker 1: No, Scott, you forget because you're old, but punk kids who are into PC gaming seem to all have that.
Speaker 0: So an audience of like 10 dudes has that shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So it's worth it, we're gonna make a special video just for those 10 dudes who bought the crazy Nvidia goggles and have the right video card.
Speaker 1: We'll make one particular 3D video or two.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, you know what it is?
Speaker 0: It's me giving you the finger.
Speaker 1: I just wanna try it out.
Speaker 0: 3D finger!
Speaker 0: I also wanna try stuff like, uh- You don't even have the goggles, you don't even know if it works!
Speaker 1: I also wanna try stuff like doing two cameras in the same event, like a lot of snowboarders putting one on their helmet and one on the snowboard looking back up at them.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, that's necessary.
Speaker 1: So we can do stuff like that, we can, uh, lend and lease.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah, we're biking to work because it's warm out.
Speaker 1: And cons are coming up, so in the news, our friend Daryl Surratt is going, not to PAX, and not to Anime Boston- How could you not go to PAX?
Speaker 0: Nerd card revoked.
Speaker 1: And not to Anime Boston, where he is a fixture, but he's going to Sakura Con.
Speaker 0: Well, he's never been to Seattle, I mean, you know, trip to Seattle, not bad.
Speaker 1: But he could go to Seattle for PAX!
Speaker 0: That's when he should be going.
Speaker 1: Because I love Daryl, and we're super into anime, Daryl's super into anime, but Daryl is also super into gaming.
Speaker 1: But, uh, I do forgive him a little because the reason he's going is to see Kawajiri Yoshiaki.
Speaker 0: Well, that's his jam.
Speaker 1: That is his jam to a degree that I cannot fault him.
Speaker 1: Though, I would not skip PAX if Lincoln, Kennedy, Imhotep, and Jesus.
Speaker 0: Why would I skip PAX for any of those guys?
Speaker 0: I wouldn't even skip frickin' like Zenkai Con for any of those guys.
Speaker 1: I can't think of, really?
Speaker 1: You wouldn't defeat Imhotep?
Speaker 0: No?
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: What would I say to Imhotep?
Speaker 1: How'd you build the fuckin' pyramids?
Speaker 0: And what would he say?
Speaker 1: I don't know, whatever he, however he fixed the pyramids.
Speaker 1: He wouldn't understand what I was saying to him, and he would probably say- Clearly, if there's a convention where they're all there, there's a moderator on the panel who speaks ancient Egyptian.
Speaker 0: Who on earth, currently living, speaks fluent ancient Egyptian?
Speaker 1: Imhotep.
Speaker 1: In this case, we've got Imhotep.
Speaker 0: And also speaks another human language.
Speaker 1: So I'm assuming that if they were able to fly Imhotep out, they have someone who can translate.
Speaker 1: Because otherwise, how did they convince him to come to the con?
Speaker 0: They did, and the museum just fuckin' kidnapped him.
Speaker 1: So, anyway.
Speaker 1: Besides, Jesus is fictional.
Speaker 1: You didn't harp on that, you harp on-.
Speaker 1: So, Kalajiri, if you didn't know, and you should know, you know, we haven't done a lot of anime shows lately, and when we have, we've just reviewed shows.
Speaker 1: But, uh, he is famous for anime that you shouldn't watch, but you probably should watch.
Speaker 1: Like, I don't know, Wicked City, or maybe Demon City, Cyber City Oedo, Vampire Hunter D, the new one, not the old one.
Speaker 1: Well, recently, I don't know if he did anything on the old one.
Speaker 1: I actually don't know much about the old one, now that I think about it.
Speaker 1: I feel bad about that, and wrong.
Speaker 1: But anyway, this is Daryl's jam, so I can see why he's going, but-
Speaker 0: It would cost him money to go to PAX, but this is free Seattle trip, so, you know, as I say, cost nothing, go to convention for your jam, or, I'd still go to PAX, but even if it cost all the money.
Speaker 1: You can tell there's not so much anime news lately.
Speaker 0: No, so, I'm gonna do a geek bite, because there's no news.
Speaker 0: So, I was trying to think of what comics I read recently, and really, I haven't read that many comics recently, although I've still been buying plenty of them.
Speaker 0: Mostly because I've been watching Running Man, but now that it's done, I'm reading again.
Speaker 0: So, anyway, I read Princess Knight by Tezuka, which is famous Tezuka shoujo manga.
Speaker 1: I have not read it yet, though I know the end.
Speaker 0: Did you know- I know how it ends.
Speaker 0: It's not a surprise.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Did you know it's only two volumes?
Speaker 1: Oh, uh, let me borrow it, like, now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's only two volumes, that's it.
Speaker 0: One, two, done.
Speaker 1: I guess I kind of had this impression.
Speaker 1: there was a lot of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had a feeling- I also thought that it was a big, long manga, like Astro Boy with a bunch of volumes, but it's not.
Speaker 0: It's only two volumes, and that's it.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Like, it's got a lot of cool stuff, it's got some cool characters, the pirate guy is the best, there's an awesome pirate, and also there's an evil witch, but the evil witch's daughter is actually kind of awesome, because there's this whole thing going on where, like, the evil witch wants the daughter to be an evil witch, but the daughter's like, "Eh, whatever, I don't really want to be an evil witch.
Speaker 0: Hey, my mom's making me do this evil witch shit, but come on, let's go and have fun or do whatever,".
Speaker 0: you know, she's pretty cool and awesome.
Speaker 0: The thing is, but it's not the best ever, it's not the best Tezuka, at least, not in my eyes, because the plot goes and goes and goes, and it's going a good direction, and then it sort of meanders a bit, like he doesn't know where to take it, and then he wraps it up.
Speaker 0: And that doesn't know where to take it.
Speaker 0: kind of wishy-washy part, about 70-80% of the way through is kind of, "Eh, what's going on here, alright,".
Speaker 0: you know, this kind of cool stuff, but it doesn't really, it's not in the same, it sort of gets you out of the flow that you had going with the beginning parts.
Speaker 0: But yeah, Princess Knight is Tezuka, it's excellent, and because it's only two volumes, you should buy that shit.
Speaker 0: So I suppose I will read it.
Speaker 0: It's also historically significant.
Speaker 1: And it'll give us a Wednesday show.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: If that's not redundant with the Geek Fight I just did, which was barely much of a Geek Fight at all, I just, you know, since it's only two volumes, what do you want me to say about it?
Speaker 0: It's a story about this girl who, when she's born, right, God and all the angels, right, God's standing up there, and all the angels are like, "Alright, make sure you give the boy hearts to the boys and the girl hearts to the
Speaker 0: girls.".
Speaker 0: The angels are distributing the hearts.
Speaker 0: And one of them, by some circumstance, gets a boy heart and a girl heart.
Speaker 0: But it's a girl, but it has both hearts.
Speaker 0: So she's total badass, right?
Speaker 1: Because girls can't be badasses.
Speaker 0: Well, it's sort of sexist, and it's also not at the same time, right?
Speaker 0: Because on the one hand, it's like, "Okay, the boy heart makes you courageous and awesome at fighting and stuff like that, and the girl heart makes you pretty and beautiful and
Speaker 0: sweet.".
Speaker 0: And it's sort of like, "Alright, that part is
Speaker 0: sexist.".
Speaker 0: But at the same time, it's like, "Well, they're both in this girl, so it's still giving you this girl who's also badass and kind of
Speaker 0: whatever.".
Speaker 0: But anyway, so she's like the princess, but totally pretending to be the prince so that she can be the king or whatever eventually.
Speaker 0: And of course, people try to find this out and uncover the secret so that other people can be the king instead, and all this sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: And then she meets boys, but then she's switching between being in a costume, dressing as a girl and dressing as a guy, and going in disguises.
Speaker 0: The guy she likes hates her when he thinks it's the prince, but is madly in love with her and thinks it's this beautiful girl who went to the dance, Cinderella-style.
Speaker 0: That kind of stuff's going on, so that's what it's about.
Speaker 1: That's how that is.
Speaker 0: The angel, because he fucked up and gave two hearts to one person, he's coming down trying to correct the mistake, but it's like, "Well, you don't really want the mistake
Speaker 0: corrected.".
Speaker 0: There's all kinds of situations where she loses one heart and now she's all girly and she can't really fight, but then she has to fight because she's dressed as the prince and a guy shows up with a sword.
Speaker 0: And then maybe the heart switches back the other way, and now she's not girly anymore, so the guy wants to get with her, but she's like, "Whatever.
Speaker 0: I've got a boy heart now.
Speaker 0: I don't want
Speaker 0: you.".
Speaker 1: I feel like this would be very different if it was, instead of hearts, it was genitalia.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Pretty sure she has the girl genitalia the whole time.
Speaker 0: Pretty sure?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of Rose of Versailles going on.
Speaker 1: So, things of the day.
Speaker 1: This is pretty great.
Speaker 1: Way greater than you would expect a video like this to be, and all I want to say is it's funny right away, but if you wait for it, it is amazing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just watch this whole video and just don't get bored and try to fast-forward or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Just wait for the payoff.
Speaker 0: Trust me, there is a payoff.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll bet you some money.
Speaker 1: I will bet you all that it is impossible to not start laughing.
Speaker 1: There is no way you can watch this video and make it past the 40-second mark without laughing out loud at least a little bit.
Speaker 0: Unless you're a dupe.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: I just tried to combine doofus and derp, so maybe a derpus.
Speaker 0: I don't know what I said.
Speaker 0: It's recorded.
Speaker 0: You can go hear what I said.
Speaker 0: Some new word.
Speaker 1: When I was a really little kid, I remember I was mad at my little brother.
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 1: I have no idea what I was mad about.
Speaker 1: So, I wanted to call him a scumbucket, but I kind of also wanted to call him a scum-sucker.
Speaker 1: And I said scumbucker, which sounded like scum-fucker, and I got sent to my room for saying fuck.
Speaker 0: So, in first grade, I don't know if I told this story, right?
Speaker 0: You know, I knew some bad words, but I didn't know all the bad words.
Speaker 1: Every kid had a repertoire, like you collected them, like you had this little folder of bad words in the brain.
Speaker 0: Didn't know all the bad words, though, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know, sitting in the back of the room, having a discussion about bad words with some of the kids.
Speaker 1: When children share gnosis.
Speaker 0: Alright, and this kid's like, "Hey, you know that bad word?
Speaker 0: It's like itch, but there's a B in front of
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: I'm like, "Bitch?
Speaker 0: That's not even a
Speaker 0: word."
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: And he's like, "Well, there's also, there's another one.
Speaker 0: It's duck.
Speaker 0: You replace the D with an
Speaker 0: F.".
Speaker 0: I'm like, "Fuck?
Speaker 0: Fuck is absolutely not a word.
Speaker 0: There is no way that that's a
Speaker 0: word.".
Speaker 1: Wait, so what bad words did you know?
Speaker 1: Like pee-pee and doo-doo?
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: All I knew is that I didn't believe that those were real words.
Speaker 0: So then, you know, the teacher's like, "What are you
Speaker 0: saying?".
Speaker 0: I'm like, you know, the teacher thought I was just trying to get away with saying the words.
Speaker 0: But I was like, "No, really.
Speaker 0: Fuck is not a word.
Speaker 0: There is no way that that's a word.
Speaker 0: It's not in the
Speaker 0: dictionary.".
Speaker 0: I actually went and got the dictionary.
Speaker 0: I was like, "Look, it's not in here.
Speaker 0: It's not a word.
Speaker 0: Fuck is not a word.
Speaker 0: This is
Speaker 0: bullshit.".
Speaker 1: I'm glad that our society is rapidly getting past that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no kidding.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: And of course, in the meta moment, we are going to be at the Penny Arcade Expo and Anime Boston, but mostly the Penny Arcade Expo.
Speaker 0: Do we even have to say this?
Speaker 0: We're going to be at every Penny Arcade Expo that ever happens, ever, unless we are dead.
Speaker 1: Unless we die or it ends.
Speaker 0: Or unless somehow we are banned from it or something like that weird crazy happens.
Speaker 0: or there is something even more important.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I posit that we could not get banned because after that late show, they did not ban us.
Speaker 0: Something could happen.
Speaker 0: For example, I could be offered a free trip into outer space that happens to be on the same day as PAX.
Speaker 1: Would you take outer space over PAX Prime?
Speaker 1: Not East, but Prime.
Speaker 1: So the line is space.
Speaker 0: I mean, it would take a lot, but it's possible, right?
Speaker 0: There are things that...
Speaker 1: Alright, so here's the question.
Speaker 1: Would you at least contact the space guy and say, "Hey, can you wait a
Speaker 1: week?"?
Speaker 0: I would ask, sure.
Speaker 0: But you know, launches, they tend not to move.
Speaker 0: Or maybe I get a horrible disease and I'm not dead yet, but if I don't get this treatment instead of PAX and the treatment's only available somewhere far away from PAX, then I'll die.
Speaker 0: But if I get the treatment, I'll live.
Speaker 1: That is a nice game theory conundrum there because you'd miss one PAX, but get more than one PAX worth compared to dying.
Speaker 0: Of course, even with the treatment, if I wasn't going to live to the next PAX, I'd just go to the PAX and die.
Speaker 0: I mean, obviously.
Speaker 1: Scott was the one who famously said in our forum, "I would skip my own wedding for
Speaker 1: PAX.".
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, if the person wasn't okay with that, I wouldn't be marrying them, right?
Speaker 1: But yes, we will be there.
Speaker 1: We are doing a Let's Play money-making game.
Speaker 1: We are doing the Geek Nights tabletop workshop, where over the course of two hours we will teach the entire audience in the tabletop workshop room, which is a classroom with tons of seats and tables in the audience.
Speaker 1: We're going to teach Agricola and Carcassonne and a third secret game.
Speaker 1: Spot it.
Speaker 1: Probably.
Speaker 1: I haven't decided yet.
Speaker 0: Oh, let's play the trigger game before I go.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: We will also be doing a whole bunch of other stuff at PAX along with all of our friends.
Speaker 1: We will have a schedule of the good stuff to go to.
Speaker 1: Meaning, our stuff, Luke Crane's stuff, Jared Sorensen's stuff.
Speaker 0: The stuff that we approve of and is done by our friends.
Speaker 1: Yep, Lorian Green's screening of Going Cardboard, which I haven't watched yet.
Speaker 1: Which we're in.
Speaker 1: I have it.
Speaker 1: It's sitting right here.
Speaker 0: It is a documentary about board games and we are in it.
Speaker 1: So is Rainer Canizia.
Speaker 1: Therefore, we are...
Speaker 0: We probably shouldn't be featured in it as much as we are, but we are.
Speaker 0: And two of the special features are mostly us.
Speaker 1: You know, I didn't think it'd be this early in my life where I was a special feature on a DVD.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Move the GloW to the menu item to open the special feature of the DVD.
Speaker 0: I guess to at least put us down a notch.
Speaker 0: It's not a DVD they sell in Best Buy, right?
Speaker 0: Yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Best Buy.
Speaker 1: I haven't been inside of a Best Buy in years.
Speaker 0: I've been to some of the Manhattan ones while waiting to do something because I happen to be.
Speaker 0: I was like, "I'm standing on the street.
Speaker 0: I have to be somewhere in 15 minutes, but where I have to be is right next to me.
Speaker 0: What am I going to do for 15
Speaker 0: minutes?".
Speaker 0: There's a Best Buy here.
Speaker 0: And there's nothing else here.
Speaker 0: Alright, let's go inside.
Speaker 0: So yeah.
Speaker 0: And let's walk out without buying anything.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we will be at PAX and Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Anime Boston, we're doing one, two, or three panels.
Speaker 1: I gotta check my scheduling and all that.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the book club book, which we'll do a show on announcing shortly, will be The Hunger Games because everyone's making a big ruckus about it.
Speaker 1: I read enough to realize that it's not... I started reading it thinking it was going to be a bad book and I was going to make fun of all my friends for recommending some kid's book.
Speaker 1: But now, it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: Pretty 1984.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll still end up making fun of it.
Speaker 0: You may.
Speaker 0: It could be a Firefly situation.
Speaker 1: But it was pretty good.
Speaker 1: I don't think you'll dislike it.
Speaker 1: Unless you want to dislike it.
Speaker 0: I don't, you know.
Speaker 0: I just go into it.
Speaker 1: It's hard to say.
Speaker 1: All that aside, this Friday, there's a NerdNYC board game night.
Speaker 1: We've missed several between me going to India and conventions.
Speaker 0: I went to the last one.
Speaker 1: I've missed several.
Speaker 0: Well, I missed... They had some bonus ones lately.
Speaker 0: Like, there was one on a Tuesday.
Speaker 1: I would have gone, except I had stuff to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I did not go to any bonus ones.
Speaker 0: I only went to regular ones.
Speaker 1: Trouble is, it's bike season.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Also...
Speaker 1: I can't leave my bike at the NerdNYC night unless I ride my shitty bike to work.
Speaker 0: I just ride my bike home, then go to NerdNYC?
Speaker 0: Or not ride my bike that day.
Speaker 1: Ah, but I want to ride my bike.
Speaker 1: I think I'm going to ride my shitty bike to work on Friday morning if it doesn't rain.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so, you should also remember, the internets exist, and we are on the internets.
Speaker 0: So if you Facebook, Google+, Twitter, iTunes, websites, anything like that, you can follow, subscribe, join, grab... whatever, us, and get our stuffs, and hook up with us in a social way, and follow our shit, and you'll be notified about all our goings on, internet-wise.
Speaker 1: Most of them are pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Most of them.
Speaker 0: Most.
Speaker 1: So, way back around 2003, which was a decade ago, almost, we discovered, and...
Speaker 0: had already died, but there were some other ones.
Speaker 1: I think that might have been before, when it came back and died again, though.
Speaker 0: No, because it was all freshman year.
Speaker 1: No, it was sophomore year, some of it, because we were in Colony.
Speaker 1: I will look it up, old man, with your Alzheimer's.
Speaker 1: Introduce Order of the Stick while I look this up and prove your Alzheimer's.
Speaker 0: So, you know, we played the D&Ds in those days, because you didn't know better, and there was no better in those days.
Speaker 1: I know, we had not yet met Luke Crane.
Speaker 1: I knew the alternatives to D&D were, like, Shadowrun, Palladium Books, Call of Cthulhu, White Wolf, Legend of the Five Rings, Rifts, 7C, and older versions of Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 1: I said Legend of the Five Rings.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 0: The thing is, you said Legend of the Five Rings, I said L5R, so it didn't match up.
Speaker 1: I remember D20, there was a bunch of D20 stuff, like Star Wars D20, Cthulhu D20.
Speaker 0: Right, anyway.
Speaker 1: Old paranoia.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, paranoia, true.
Speaker 0: Okay, so anyway, we played D&D, and, you know, D&D jokes are funny, like jokes about rolling D20s, and, you know, casting Magic Missile at the Darkness, and all those types of jokes.
Speaker 0: They were good jokes.
Speaker 1: I mean, very often- Very often you would say something like, "Guess he didn't make his saving throw against flatulence," or whatever the issue was.
Speaker 0: Jesus saves, and takes half damage.
Speaker 0: Classic.
Speaker 1: Alright, so- The Boys of Guter Science was dead in 2003.
Speaker 0: I told you.
Speaker 1: But it went through summer of 2002, where we were not in fact freshmen at RIT, and where we were in fact living in colony.
Speaker 0: Oh, whatever.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so- So you were all- you're an old man, you're wrong.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna read these VVOCSs while you- That's a good idea.
Speaker 0: Not you too, Tribes 2.
Speaker 0: Alright, anyway.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, I remember every one of these strips.
Speaker 0: Of course you do.
Speaker 0: Why wouldn't you?
Speaker 0: So, in the webcomic heyday, right, one of our friends discovered this webcomic called Order of the Stig.
Speaker 0: So he told us about it, we started reading it, and it was basically- it started out as just this party of adventurers, you know, pretty typical, the big fighter leader guy, but he was also smart, so he wasn't so stereotypical.
Speaker 0: The thiefy girl, all rogue you like.
Speaker 0: The stupid bard, as opposed to the spoonie bard.
Speaker 0: Well, he's also spoonie.
Speaker 0: You know, the really stereotypical Thor dwarf cleric guy, and the evil hobbit kind of guy.
Speaker 0: Halfling, whatever.
Speaker 0: Oh, and then the elf wizard, who is sort of androgynous.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they made a big deal- that was like one of the running gags was, "Well, is it a man or a
Speaker 1: woman?".
Speaker 0: They haven't really answered that either.
Speaker 1: It's obviously a man.
Speaker 0: And the spouse is also androgynous.
Speaker 1: Obviously a woman.
Speaker 0: Anyway, well, former spouse.
Speaker 0: Oh, spoilers.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so they're adventuring, not really for any particular reason.
Speaker 0: so much, at least not that I can remember.
Speaker 0: And basically the whole comic just starts out with this sort of, you know, not the greatest artwork, you know, pretty much circle heads, and I almost could draw it if I put enough effort into it.
Speaker 0: And making all the D&D jokes in the world.
Speaker 1: Jokes about flumps, jokes about- Jokes about the conversion from second ed to third ed.
Speaker 0: Oh my.
Speaker 0: Second one- So pretty much when we got to RIT is when third ed came out, so this, you know- Fail listen check joke, singing to tell a guy to jump over the pit, and then singing to bluff- Jump, jump, jump over the pit.
Speaker 1: Bluff, bluff, bluff the stupid ogre.
Speaker 0: Bluff, bluff, bluff the stupid ogre.
Speaker 0: You got the banjo the clown, you know, deity jokes.
Speaker 1: My favorite spell in all of newer D&D, Expeditious Retreat.
Speaker 0: Ah, I forgot about that one until just now.
Speaker 0: Excellent.
Speaker 0: It's a good spell.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: So, telling D&D jokes pretty much with web comics.
Speaker 0: But then, as time went on, you know, of course it starts out with boring dungeoning.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you know, not boring dungeoning, just silly dungeoning.
Speaker 0: And, you know, there's an awesome bad guy, Zykon the Lich.
Speaker 0: Can't do better than the Lich, especially since he's awesome with his skull head and his phylactery and his robes and his- Ah yeah, Zykon is the best.
Speaker 0: So, you know, they're fighting the Zykon or whatever.
Speaker 0: And then, over time, he's like, "Well, we sort of finished this dungeon.
Speaker 0: Let's start to build a plot
Speaker 0: here.".
Speaker 0: And he starts to build up this plot going on.
Speaker 0: And he just kept going with it and getting it bigger and bigger and bigger.
Speaker 0: And it rolled up into something kind of epic and awesome.
Speaker 0: And he managed to somehow continue to tell D&D jokes while also keeping the plot going.
Speaker 0: While also having the strong characters.
Speaker 0: So then, in addition to the D&D jokes, it also has its own humor, just character humor.
Speaker 0: And I didn't realize how popular it was until he just kickstarted for like a zillion dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's one of those things where you're not gonna see a lot of- like, people don't cosplay that much as it.
Speaker 0: I've never really- I've never seen or ordered this to cosplay in my life, but now I'm cosplaying Zykon.
Speaker 1: I don't see mashups, you know, it's one of those things that's just solidly popular.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you never see, like, a thread in the forum about it or anything like that, right?
Speaker 0: But- Rich Berlew never- he never did, like, the kind of publicity stuff- He would have long hiatuses where he wouldn't put out too many comics that frequently.
Speaker 0: You know, I met him once, he was kinda shy, whatever.
Speaker 1: Like, in the whole webcomic boom, he always felt very tangential to it.
Speaker 1: Like, he was making a solid comic, but he wasn't involved in all the drama of the webcomic world.
Speaker 0: He wasn't one of the major webcomics, like Penny Arcade and PVP and, you know, even the ones that people hate so much.
Speaker 0: Like, Control Delete or, you know, Questionable Content or Aqua- you know, all the big- you know, Mega Tokyo, all the big webcomics.
Speaker 0: The ones that come out swinging and, you know, the ones that people think of, good or bad, right?
Speaker 0: He was just sorta like, "Successful webcomic.
Speaker 0: People read it.
Speaker 0: It's off to the
Speaker 0: side.".
Speaker 0: You know, but it's not one that comes to mind when you talk- you know, if you're gonna do a documentary on webcomics, now you'd put him in there.
Speaker 0: But if you were making this documentary, like, three years ago, maybe you wouldn't put him in there, you know?
Speaker 0: You'd have to, like, go hunting around, maybe, or be really in the know.
Speaker 0: But I guess not, because I guess it's really popular.
Speaker 0: So, in addition to the webcomic that he did- he's still doing- he also, you know, printed the whole webcomic in books.
Speaker 0: And he even printed up, like, whole books of stuff that isn't online.
Speaker 0: Like, these prequel books, like, volume minus one, volume minus two, volume D. Like, they're not on the internets, as far as I know.
Speaker 0: I mean, they might be pirated on the internets, but they're not, you know, on his website, you know, except for the purchase link.
Speaker 0: Which is a pretty interesting thing.
Speaker 0: Like, if Penny Arcade did that, how awesome would that be?
Speaker 0: Like, hey, he has, like, 50 Penny Arcade strips in a book that aren't on the internets.
Speaker 0: I'd be like, "Oh my god, pre-order all the
Speaker 0: copies!".
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So yeah, so he Kickstarted, because, you know, he didn't really have that much money from this, I guess.
Speaker 0: You know, other than the book sales, you know, which I think were steady.
Speaker 0: But he sort of sold out of all the books, and he wanted to keep them all in print, so that anyone who wanted one could get them.
Speaker 0: Because only a few of them were in print.
Speaker 0: So he put the Kickstarter out there, and somehow the Kickstarter *usploded* a bajillion dollars.
Speaker 1: Now, it's very telling that this is a comic that grew out of, basically, making fun of D&D.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, D&D jokes only get you so far.
Speaker 0: It's like, how many times can you tell the same joke about, you know, saving throws or Mage Hand?
Speaker 1: But the fact that those jokes are still there, in this plot, I still enjoy it.
Speaker 1: And I know a lot of people who never played a lot of D&D who found this comic hilarious.
Speaker 0: Well, he does a good job of making the jokes still be D&D roleplaying jokes, without having them to be so specific to any particular rule system that you won't get them, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like, you can still get them even if you just understand the general idea of D&D, and sort of like the basics.
Speaker 0: You know?
Speaker 0: That, hey, bard sings songs, and, you know, when a bard sings a song, it has a magical power that influences people and helps them.
Speaker 0: You know, gives them boosts.
Speaker 0: You don't need to know the specific rule that, like, bard's song gives +1 to your skill roll, whatever it is.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I mean, what else, what can I say, really?
Speaker 0: Uh, I guess we can talk about some of the awesome stuff that's in it.
Speaker 0: Particulars.
Speaker 1: Well, you just want to talk about Zykon.
Speaker 0: Uh, I was about to talk about Zykon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we'll try to- Let's talk about someone besides Zykon.
Speaker 1: We'll try to not spoil a lot, because, really, you should read this.
Speaker 1: If you're at all into comics, forget webcomics.
Speaker 1: This is just a comic that happens to be on the web.
Speaker 0: Uh, let's see, what part of this deck can we talk about?
Speaker 1: I guess we could spoil.
Speaker 1: Go past the spoiler line.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: So, the basic idea is that, you know, at least the characters believe, and the reader believes, there's some sort of impending doom, right, against the world.
Speaker 0: That in the olden days, the really strong magic dudes, sort of, you know, there was a horrible monster that sort of ruined, you know, that was going to destroy the whole world.
Speaker 0: And the, uh, the really powerful historical dudes from the way past managed to seal it up, right?
Speaker 0: And they're like, for these, they're like these gates into the other dimension that it could come through, but the gates are sealed, so the world is safe, right?
Speaker 0: But, that first dungeon they were in, in the whole story, and also some of the subsequent places, were at these gates, and, you know, Zykon and whoever wants these items of power, because everyone has different beliefs about exactly what the deal is, like, you know, some horrible spell you can cast at the gate to get powerful, or do evil, or whatever, or maybe do good.
Speaker 0: So, it's like the good guys want to keep the gates sealed, and the bad guys want to open it.
Speaker 0: It's actually kind of similar to Golden Sun, where like the towers, where at first it's like the good guys are like, "No, we can't let the bad guys fuck with the
Speaker 0: towers.".
Speaker 0: And then it's like, "Alright, let's just go fuck with all the towers now, and see what
Speaker 0: happens.".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But, you know, they don't want to let, you know, the evil thing get in and destroy the whole world.
Speaker 0: They want to keep, you know, the thing sealed out and whatever.
Speaker 0: And in the course of doing this, they travel all over the world, and characters sort out their personal dramas, and you discover all sorts of, you know, "Oh, that was really that!
Speaker 0: Oh,
Speaker 0: snap!".
Speaker 1: kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: Well, I think what really what I like about the comic is that, one, it's clever.
Speaker 1: Like, it's cleverly written, the writing's good, the dialogue's good, the characters are good.
Speaker 1: But specifically, the characters are very deeply fleshed out, and actually react in interesting enough ways to where I'll actually put up with similar jokes being repeated, just because the characters themselves are kind of existing in this space and progressing through their shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it has that strong character thing I like.
Speaker 0: You know, like a lot of animes and stuff, or, you know, like superhero comics, it's like, "Okay, you have this guy, and who is
Speaker 0: he?".
Speaker 0: We talked about this a lot in DC 52, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like Legion of Superheroes.
Speaker 1: They're just a bunch of stereotypes.
Speaker 0: Well, there were two guys that weren't stereotypes.
Speaker 0: The really smart guy, the brainiac guy, and then the other guy, right?
Speaker 0: And everyone else was just a costume that said something, and didn't have any character to them.
Speaker 0: They didn't have a personality.
Speaker 0: All the order to stick characters, even side characters, and villains, and all kinds, they all have personalities.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, he's not afraid to change the personalities either, and the thing is, he doesn't so much change them, but he has this clever- Evolve them.
Speaker 0: Right, he'll evolve them or reveal them.
Speaker 0: It's like, "Okay, this guy hasn't really had a personality.
Speaker 0: Let's do a reveal, like, oh, he's actually been up to something this whole
Speaker 0: time!".
Speaker 0: So now you can retroactively apply that personality so it all makes sense, as opposed to the character didn't suddenly, you know, change their mind.
Speaker 0: It's just, they were acting that way because, and now they're acting, you know, and now since they're revealed to the reader, you know, now you get to see them acting the way they really act.
Speaker 0: And the character has suddenly changed, even though plot-wise they didn't change.
Speaker 0: You're just being able to see the character, whereas before it was hidden.
Speaker 1: Now the final thing that really, I think, draws me to the comic is that, and I don't know if it's a side effect of Berloo's storytelling, or just a side effect of the fact that this is a story built in a world that follows Dungeons & Dragons rules directly, and specifically, and explicitly, but-
Speaker 0: We didn't do things of the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we did.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess you didn't.
Speaker 1: Oh well, you missed it.
Speaker 0: Oh well.
Speaker 0: So- I'm sitting here looking at my thing of the day and I'm like, I didn't talk about this.
Speaker 0: Okay, so this thing of the day is actually, is actually a really good thing of the day.
Speaker 0: So it's a shame if I would have had to skip it, but I guess we'll just throw it in here for LOLs.
Speaker 0: So, Where the Wild Things Are, it's a book.
Speaker 0: It's a good book.
Speaker 1: Great book.
Speaker 1: Good.
Speaker 1: There's an animated version.
Speaker 0: Yep, there's a live action movie, which I haven't seen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I heard it was good.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But anyway, here is on YouTube a reading of the book.
Speaker 0: It's about 10 minutes long.
Speaker 0: It is read by Christopher Walken.
Speaker 0: And because it's a short book, he sort of has to elaborate and he describes all the pictures and all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 0: And while he's reading it, of course the YouTube video is showing you the pages.
Speaker 0: And that's about it.
Speaker 0: It's the awesomest.
Speaker 1: You don't want to say?
Speaker 0: It's Christopher Walken reading.
Speaker 0: The Wild Things Are.
Speaker 1: Christopher Walken.
Speaker 0: There's not really much else into it.
Speaker 0: That's all you need.
Speaker 0: And he keeps calling Max a jerk.
Speaker 0: He's like,
Speaker 0: "What?".
Speaker 0: And he's like, "What's he doing?
Speaker 0: beating that beast over the head with his king
Speaker 0: stick?".
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So anyway, but because the world is so kind of deeply entwined in these very specific rules, the writing is such that every tiny little detail is perfectly cross-referenced with every other detail.
Speaker 1: Superhero Comics has got nothing on the continuity of the Order of the Stick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 0: It has extreme continuity.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, it's not just character continuity.
Speaker 1: External continuity.
Speaker 1: He'll mention a spell.
Speaker 1: And you bet that if you look, the characters are the right level based on everything going on.
Speaker 1: And the thing is, he's got so many aspects, right?
Speaker 0: The political realm is covered.
Speaker 0: He's got the fantasy history.
Speaker 0: The lore is covered.
Speaker 0: He's even got shit with the kind of weird breaking the fourth wall shit.
Speaker 1: Summon plot element.
Speaker 0: Right, the girlfriend who's a fairy from another plane who comes with the lawyers ends up being legit.
Speaker 0: Even the cockroaches, which are sort of like the old guys of The Muppet Show, are actually part of the plot for reals.
Speaker 0: And it's like every little thing, even stuff that seems like it's only there for jokes or props or whatever, is actually for reals and it counts and it's always there.
Speaker 1: There is a thing that happens.
Speaker 1: Remember, there's a girdle of gender changing that they find.
Speaker 0: I bet someone's wearing it right now and you don't even know.
Speaker 1: In the first ten strips and it comes back way later than you'd expect out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: But the thing is, if you've read the whole comic, when it comes out you're just like, "Oh yeah, the girdle of gender
Speaker 0: changes.".
Speaker 1: The best way I'd put it, in a Guy Ritchie movie, the number of bullets that people fire matters.
Speaker 1: In the order of the stick, the number of seventh level spells that someone casts matters.
Speaker 1: And it's weird.
Speaker 0: It's like some guy would be like, "Oh, I didn't memorize that today.
Speaker 0: I actually used all my spells
Speaker 0: already.".
Speaker 0: And if you go back and check, yeah he did.
Speaker 1: And it's weird because I don't like that sort of thing in certain kinds of stories.
Speaker 1: But I think it's because this is a story that's also kind of making light of Dungeons and Dragons and fitting inside of these rules.
Speaker 1: Like characters living in a world where they know the rules of the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the thing is because you've been in that world with those rules, you can really identify with them.
Speaker 0: When they're sitting there being like, "How do we tell this person about this horrible thing that
Speaker 0: happened?".
Speaker 0: Well, you can't use sending because that doesn't work because then I need to have something that belongs to them or some shit.
Speaker 0: Do you have anything?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's that same problem solving, the same exact discussions.
Speaker 1: Alright, I can only send 25 words.
Speaker 1: Well, I can cast it three times.
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 0: These are the same discussions that you have out of character when you're playing D&D.
Speaker 0: Only these are the characters having them in character, but they're the exact same discussion.
Speaker 0: And it's like, "Oh my god, that's
Speaker 0: awesome.".
Speaker 1: It's a great comic.
Speaker 1: You should read it.
Speaker 1: It's all online free.
Speaker 0: Even if you don't like D&D.
Speaker 0: Well, not all online except for the volumes that aren't online.
Speaker 1: Except for those.
Speaker 1: But the main story, you don't need to read Superman, Special Edition, and X Factor.
Speaker 0: No, not at all.
Speaker 1: But it's all online and the art is simple.
Speaker 1: It sticks.
Speaker 0: It's not just sticks.
Speaker 0: It's squares and circles and triangles.
Speaker 1: The art really serves the kind of story that it is.
Speaker 1: And two, despite its simplicity, it actually gets noticeably better as the story goes on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can actually see even though it's still the same character designs, the same circles and sticks, he gets better at it.
Speaker 0: He adds in the shading and the coloring.
Speaker 0: The actual graphical quality improves.
Speaker 0: And in fact, he does a lot of stuff that's sort of artistically experimental.
Speaker 0: Like there's the crayon comics and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: So it's not just some poorly done sprite crapo stick comic.
Speaker 0: It's actually good.
Speaker 0: The same way the XKCD is good, despite it just being sticks.
Speaker 1: Now what's interesting is, for me personally, we found this comic right away.
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: It tells how old I am.
Speaker 1: I do not remember how I found it.
Speaker 0: Pretty sure someone else found it and just told us to read it.
Speaker 1: I don't know how I found Penny Arcade.
Speaker 1: I couldn't tell you how I found real life.
Speaker 1: I found Megatokyo because Slashdot linked to it.
Speaker 0: That is correct.
Speaker 0: I found Megatokyo because Slashdot linked to it.
Speaker 1: And then we all read Megatokyo religiously and talked about it after every update for a while.
Speaker 0: Even though it really made no sense.
Speaker 1: That was the early days of webcomics being a big thing.
Speaker 1: But we found Order of the Stick and I know we found it right away because I remember thinking, "Hey, this is pretty
Speaker 1: good.".
Speaker 1: And I hit back to the beginning and there were only like eight or nine strips.
Speaker 1: And then I was up to the current time.
Speaker 0: I definitely started reading it while they were in that first dungeon.
Speaker 0: So I've been reading it for a long time, which means I'm better than you.
Speaker 1: But I remember there was a time like a year and a half ago, where for whatever reason I kind of stopped reading all my webcomics.
Speaker 1: All of them?
Speaker 1: As in the only ones I was still reading.
Speaker 0: I wake up and read them every morning.
Speaker 1: It was Penny Arcade and, you know, like the super car.
Speaker 1: And I kind of forgot about Order of the Stick and Dr.
Speaker 1: McNinja for a while.
Speaker 0: Whoa, if I forget about Dr.
Speaker 0: McNinja, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: And then I corrected the Dr.
Speaker 1: McNinja problem.
Speaker 1: Like one day I was like, "Oh shit, Dr.
Speaker 1: McNinja!".
Speaker 1: And I read all the strips I'd missed.
Speaker 1: So like four months ago, I was like, "Oh right, Order of the
Speaker 1: Stick!".
Speaker 1: And I went back and until I found the point where I'd stopped reading.
Speaker 1: And I just started reading again.
Speaker 1: And the next thing I knew, I was all caught up.
Speaker 1: And that was like hitting a brick wall.
Speaker 1: Now like every morning I check, like, "Did he update?
Speaker 1: Did he update?
Speaker 1: Oh
Speaker 1: shit!".
Speaker 0: He's been updating more now that he doesn't need to worry about monies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also the plots pick it up in a big way.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, something exciting is going to happen real soon.
Speaker 1: Yes, Icon!
Speaker 0: So it's a good time to get on this ball, right?
Speaker 0: While the, you know, the rising tide.
Speaker 1: Yep, and unlike some webcomics where maybe you don't want to go back to the very beginning and read, this is one where you do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you definitely do.
Speaker 1: If you haven't read it, just literally start at number one and go.
Speaker 1: There's no reason to skip the beginning, it's great.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.