Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, October 2nd, 2012.
Speaker 1: I'm Rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: We're back, and it's time to talk about Faster Than Light.
Speaker 1: AKA my favorite new game.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I realize you have this problem here.
Speaker 0: How many opening bits you think we have now, not having done a show in weeks?
Speaker 0: Ten billion opening bits.
Speaker 1: So let's assume that my entire trip to India is only one.
Speaker 0: I mean, and I was here not doing Geek Nights for a couple weeks.
Speaker 0: How many opening bits you think I piled up?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then I was also after PAX.
Speaker 1: Remember, I came back and I had that week where you were still off doing stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I realized you had this problem.
Speaker 0: I started off just before the show started.
Speaker 0: I told Rim we gotta ration the opening bits.
Speaker 0: Hold on to them so we can dole them out slowly over the course of the next bunch of episodes, but there is a flaw.
Speaker 0: This has happened before.
Speaker 0: We have had gluts of opening bits.
Speaker 0: You know what happens?
Speaker 0: We go into a show, we use probably the best of the opening bits that we could remember at the time, and then we immediately forget every other opening bit that's been piled up.
Speaker 0: When it's time for the next show, the only things that can come to mind are things that have happened since the last show.
Speaker 1: Sometimes I realize we're like that fish in Finding Nemo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we just... It's gone.
Speaker 0: It's gone.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know how many times we'll be at work and I'll be like, "Scott, let's do the show tonight on
Speaker 1: X.".
Speaker 0: But there's always one thing we can remember.
Speaker 1: We'll do the show tonight on X.
Speaker 0: For 1957 or '58.
Speaker 1: Because a man's got to remember.
Speaker 0: I remember something about six Geodudes.
Speaker 1: It was in fact most memorable, but you cannot live ten memories.
Speaker 0: And that's it.
Speaker 0: In Sydney?
Speaker 1: It is a Tuesday show.
Speaker 0: It's actually not Sydney, it's in Melbourne.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: Well, it's funny.
Speaker 1: I saw a lot of people who don't live in Melbourne trying to argue that that was in fact a red herring.
Speaker 1: That it was mere speculations.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I remember how you're talking about how Munich was like the bad place in Germany.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except, well, other people said that.
Speaker 0: Have you seen all of the videos and photos that were posted of Oktoberfest?
Speaker 0: People just like lying all over the place?
Speaker 0: Vomiting all over themselves in Munich?
Speaker 1: Or Muncken?
Speaker 1: Muncken?
Speaker 0: Whatever you want to call it.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 1: There is a Munich-themed beer house now in Manhattan, in midtown.
Speaker 0: Interesting.
Speaker 1: So it's a Munich-style beer garden.
Speaker 0: Is it for real or is it just they say that on the, you know.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean, because like right next door there's a Chinese restaurant that says it's Szechuan style, right?
Speaker 0: Right on the side, Szechuan style.
Speaker 1: So how many aspects does that Kung Po chicken have?
Speaker 0: Negative 10 aspects.
Speaker 0: They would need to add 10 aspects before you could even detect that it was aspectless.
Speaker 1: But he's named after a famous general.
Speaker 0: Famous general did not eat that.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Also, I want my last.
Speaker 1: So I would like to point out if we're talking about beginning, now that we're back from our long hiatus, I hope you guys still remember we exist.
Speaker 1: But we put out the call for guest episodes.
Speaker 1: We got one really good episode that we put up.
Speaker 1: And now that we're both back, we have like four more guest episodes on the way.
Speaker 1: So we'll use them because there's more travel coming up.
Speaker 1: I think I'm going to Moscow.
Speaker 1: now is where I'm being aimed.
Speaker 0: So, yeah.
Speaker 1: So before we get to FTL, I do.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about a game that I played.
Speaker 1: I beat.
Speaker 1: I'm done with and it is so cheap that everyone should play it because whatever, it's a few dollars.
Speaker 1: Oregon Trail.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we saw we saw this in the Kickstarter room at PAX.
Speaker 1: I saw it and I was like, Oregon Trail, is that just a zombie themed Oregon Trail?
Speaker 0: And the answer is yes, that is exactly what it is.
Speaker 1: Now, this is actually Oregon Trail director's cut, which is different.
Speaker 1: Oregon Trail was originally from what I read.
Speaker 1: I've never played it or three web game.
Speaker 1: I played it and it was just a like note for note homage to Oregon Trail.
Speaker 1: Oregon Trail, while it is like Hammond, Oregon Trail is also like the heart or the liver.
Speaker 1: We should do perhaps the brain.
Speaker 0: We should make Oregon Trail.
Speaker 0: It's about Oregon's and the musical instrument and not the body part.
Speaker 1: So is the opening just a like eight bit representation of that opening scene and punch drunk love with a Hammond organ?
Speaker 0: No, it's the whole track, right?
Speaker 0: The whole path is from one side of the organ to the other.
Speaker 0: And the guy walks all the way across and then he walks all the way back to top row.
Speaker 0: That would sound horrible.
Speaker 0: Then he walks all the way back on all the knob parts.
Speaker 1: So Oregon Trail and then the mini game is all on the pedals down on the floor is I was never good at that.
Speaker 1: Many game is not just an homage, but it is a good game in its own right.
Speaker 1: It actually adds as many games.
Speaker 1: It has fun little Easter eggs.
Speaker 1: I think I've had a few dollars for it and I'm not going to play it on hard.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to try to get a high score.
Speaker 1: In fact, I think the scoring mechanism is pretty broken because I got a higher score one time when I died halfway there than I did when I made it to the end with like three family members alive.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But it's super fun.
Speaker 1: And the main reason it gets points, the main reason I like it is that if someone gets bit by a zombie and you want to put them down, you're like, I got to put rim down or I got to put Rainbow Dash down.
Speaker 1: I did have to put Rainbow Dash down once.
Speaker 1: Chase made it to the end with me.
Speaker 1: In fact, Chase and Emily were the only people who made it to Oregon with me in the time I actually beat the game.
Speaker 1: You fucking got a broken arm and died before I even got like three checkpoints in.
Speaker 1: But anyway, is that if you put someone down, you want to kill him before they turn into a zombie, it makes you actually play a mini game of shooting them in the head.
Speaker 1: And you have to use a bullet.
Speaker 1: If you're out of bullets, you can't put them down.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Better get some.
Speaker 1: The game's beginning sort of conceit is pretty great to this dude.
Speaker 1: Clements kind of.
Speaker 0: he's in DC.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And he teaches you how to play the game.
Speaker 1: And basically he gets a broken arm, gets disinterrogates bitten by a zombie, tells you how to play.
Speaker 1: And then you have to put him down.
Speaker 1: He's basically shown you the entire game.
Speaker 1: I don't know what else I can say without spoiling it.
Speaker 1: You should buy this game.
Speaker 0: You're going to spoil Oregon.
Speaker 0: There are things.
Speaker 0: you travel across the country.
Speaker 0: Everyone's zombies now.
Speaker 1: So there's a bunch of kind of interesting little like texty Easter egg things to discover.
Speaker 1: And some of them are pretty meta.
Speaker 1: Like at one point it'll stop every now and then and say like, there's something interesting happening outside of your car.
Speaker 1: Do you want to go check it out?
Speaker 1: And they're all different.
Speaker 1: Like one of them just says Northwest South or East.
Speaker 1: And you just pick and then stuff happens.
Speaker 0: Northwest Southwest.
Speaker 1: So I did Northwest Southwest and I found a thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I don't want to spoil all those little bits.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to review it any further other than you should buy this game for your smartphone.
Speaker 1: You should play it on normal difficulty until you beat it.
Speaker 1: And once you've beaten it, there's no reason to ever play it again.
Speaker 1: Also, don't bother with that cloud swarm, a high score tracker, whatever.
Speaker 1: There's no point.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So I played a different phone game other than Super Hexagon.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God, I can't play Super Hexagon.
Speaker 0: And that game was ten million.
Speaker 0: Ten million is basically bejeweled.
Speaker 0: You get you know, you swipe to get three things in a row.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But it's slightly different because in Bejeweled, you can swap any two gems that are adjacent orthogonally.
Speaker 0: In this what you ten million, what you can do is you can take any row or column and slide it infinitely.
Speaker 0: And it wraps around like Pac-Man, either a top bottom or left right.
Speaker 0: And then you let go.
Speaker 0: when there's any three things that are lit up in, you know, vertically or horizontally or more than three, you can get five.
Speaker 1: So I have to let go.
Speaker 1: I can't just be like.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So basically, what you do is you pick a column or row and you you spin it all the way around with your finger until something lights up and then you let go.
Speaker 0: Now, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: The things that you can match are swords, magic wands, shields, rocks, wood and treasure chests.
Speaker 0: Those are the the symbols that you can match.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And what happens is while you're playing this Bejeweled at the top of the screen, this little man is running to the right and he bumps into something.
Speaker 0: Oh, keys.
Speaker 0: There's another one.
Speaker 0: Keys, keys.
Speaker 0: Let's say he bumps into a monster.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, you want to match swords and match magic wands and he'll start hurting that monster with swords and magic wand damage.
Speaker 0: And if the monster dies, then he'll start running again.
Speaker 0: Now, when he takes damage, he moves to the left and when he succeeds, he moves more to the right.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So you if he goes all the way to the right of the extreme right, you actually sort of like get a bonus and he snaps back to the normal position.
Speaker 0: If he goes all the way to the left, you die and you go back to the beginning and you can play again.
Speaker 0: And all the stone and wood and gold you get, you use to upgrade your damage and magic power and armor and your shield shields to write your shields.
Speaker 1: Fanatical devotion to the Pope.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Use it to upgrade all your shit like an RPG so that when and then you go back in the dungeon, you play more Bejeweled and to get more stuff.
Speaker 0: And then you level up your guy and you keep doing this.
Speaker 0: And the idea is that you keep playing until you get over.
Speaker 0: You cross the 10 million threshold and then you escape the dungeon and you win.
Speaker 0: But then you can keep playing on free mode.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But you do win.
Speaker 0: You do win.
Speaker 0: And you see some credits roll that are cute.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Uh, the thing is, is since it's just Bejeweled, it's like while I'm playing it, I'm like, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: And when you do treasure chest, you're like, got to match keys, got to match keys.
Speaker 0: And you match some keys to unlock the treasure chest.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And if you match keys while you're like fighting a monster, it doesn't do shit.
Speaker 0: That does nothing.
Speaker 1: It's like, when you, so when you stop playing it, you just feel dirty.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: When you, when I, when I got, when I basically what happened is it got to like 6 million and then I picked it up when I woke up in the morning, I'm like, I'll play around.
Speaker 0: And it was the mega round because I had almost upgraded everything all the way.
Speaker 0: So I was just like, boom, boom, boom, blowing everything up, match, match, match, match, like crazy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And I got like four, four plus million points in the one round.
Speaker 0: And I played like many, many rounds to get up to this point.
Speaker 0: And then in one round I got more than halfway through and I just beat it.
Speaker 0: I sold the credits.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh, and then I was like, well, there's no reason to, I went to play the free mode.
Speaker 0: And now I'm like, oh, I'm just matching things for no reason.
Speaker 0: Now that is not reason.
Speaker 0: I mean, you can, if you want uninstall and reinstall the games to reset it because there's no reset button on purpose.
Speaker 0: But I'm like, why would I want to do that?
Speaker 0: And just like, I've just deleted it.
Speaker 0: And that's it.
Speaker 1: You know, it's funny you bring that up because I, while I was in India, one thing I did is I read a book now at PAX dev.
Speaker 1: I was introduced to this book and the people who introduced it and talked about it said very good things about it.
Speaker 1: It is called characteristics of games.
Speaker 1: And this is a book that is written by a number of people.
Speaker 1: But the one that you probably all know is Richard Garfield.
Speaker 0: That's the guy who made magic, the gathering, also known as money, the wasting.
Speaker 1: And one, I know this book is legit because he references in the book specifically, for example, who are the other people that wrote it?
Speaker 0: Like how much was his contribution?
Speaker 1: Freshly opened booster pack.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: George Scott Elias, K. Robert Guschera, Peter Whitley was the illustrator and Eric Zimmerman wrote the forward.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So there were pretty much three authors, right?
Speaker 0: So does it actually tell you which parts are written by which guy?
Speaker 1: It was a collaborative work, but here's the deal.
Speaker 1: So I read this book and I realized that what Richard Garfield and these people have done is taken everything that matters on the core level for game design and given us a lexicon to discuss those topics.
Speaker 1: So I'm not saying I'm smarter than Richard Garfield.
Speaker 1: I'm clearly not, but for now on, anytime you ever disagree with me on a point about like game design, read this book first.
Speaker 1: The book agrees with me and then argue with the book.
Speaker 1: And if you defeat the book, then we'll talk.
Speaker 1: I hereby defer to this book for pretty much everything I think when it comes to games.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's kind of weird.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, you sort of discover something on your own.
Speaker 0: Like maybe you're one of those people who lives in the woods all alone.
Speaker 0: You never went to school and you sort of discovered calculus on your own.
Speaker 0: And then you start reading like a book on calculus and you're like, whoa, a derivative.
Speaker 0: That's what they call it.
Speaker 0: But I know what that is.
Speaker 0: That's the summer flash.
Speaker 1: For example, Scott, here's the difference.
Speaker 1: What he refers to now, this is a term I'd heard before.
Speaker 1: People have referenced it in game theory, the chip taking game.
Speaker 1: You know what we call that?
Speaker 1: The vote who wins game.
Speaker 1: Now I have homework for all of you out there.
Speaker 0: Boy, isn't the chip taking game?
Speaker 0: No, thanks.
Speaker 1: Uh, not quite.
Speaker 1: So here's the deal.
Speaker 1: This book is great.
Speaker 1: If you design games, play games, care about games, you should read this book.
Speaker 1: It is a, it's an introduction.
Speaker 1: There are two ways to learn the things that are inside of this book.
Speaker 1: One read the entire book cover to cover or to play German board games for 10 years, PC games for 20 years, console games for 20 something years.
Speaker 0: Do what we did.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: One of these two things, you'll get to the same conclusion.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 1: So I have homework for all of you because there is something in this book that will matter to more to Scott than anyone else.
Speaker 1: If you can explain to me and Scott, why in vote who wins games, also known as the chip taking game, also known as political games, how come whenever there's a game where basically all the players do things, but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Really.
Speaker 1: There's a voting who to attack and really they're just voting who wins.
Speaker 1: How come room always wins?
Speaker 0: And I say to the people, look, everybody, this is a vote who wins game.
Speaker 0: Cast your vote for yourself and also for me.
Speaker 0: But at least if you're not going to vote for me, at least do not vote for a vote for anyone but rim.
Speaker 0: And I tell this, I can recognize when we're playing this kind of game, for example, the zombie mall game.
Speaker 1: Oh, the zombie mall game.
Speaker 0: And I'll wreck it.
Speaker 0: I'll say, guys is voted wins game.
Speaker 0: Nobody vote for him.
Speaker 0: And I say this like explicitly yet.
Speaker 0: What do people end up doing?
Speaker 0: They vote for him.
Speaker 0: Do they not know how to vote?
Speaker 0: Like hanging Chad?
Speaker 1: What's going on?
Speaker 1: I remember a distinct time and Wildwood where you weren't playing.
Speaker 1: You were sitting on the couch, like playing Pokemon or something.
Speaker 1: We were playing.
Speaker 1: A bunch of us were playing the game every round.
Speaker 1: You yelled rims winning.
Speaker 1: Fuck him.
Speaker 1: He's going to win.
Speaker 1: You're voting for him.
Speaker 1: You weren't looking at the game.
Speaker 1: And then I won.
Speaker 1: So the thing is, the people Scott tells this to don't disagree.
Speaker 1: They wreck it.
Speaker 1: They recognize.
Speaker 1: They know that even if Scott is trying to act in his own self-interest, they know that.
Speaker 1: it is true from personal experience that I win these games pretty much all the time.
Speaker 0: So do they not know how to vote?
Speaker 0: Is that what it says?
Speaker 1: If you read this book, your homework is to tell us why I win these games, because it actually says straight up why I win these games.
Speaker 0: Well, you had that book around here somewhere, right?
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 0: So let me check it out.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, I'll just give it to you.
Speaker 1: Seriously though, I cannot express to you how useful.
Speaker 0: How long is it?
Speaker 1: A week of reading.
Speaker 1: A deep, careful reading.
Speaker 0: Let's move along.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: So anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: Much like how when ponies were big, we did a lot of pony things the day, but now we backed away because, you know, people know you can find all those things on your own.
Speaker 1: And long time ago I did a series of things of the day that were related to Hitler and or being born to be alive.
Speaker 0: So send your Nazi complaints to.
Speaker 1: the new thing.
Speaker 1: Of course, is Gangnam style.
Speaker 0: How come you can't say it properly?
Speaker 1: I can't make everything of the day just be a mashup of it because that there'd be too many things like ponies.
Speaker 1: There's a thousand.
Speaker 0: I want to do a thing.
Speaker 0: How can no one can pronounce Gangnam properly?
Speaker 1: People have no bungas.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you're basically, it's like, you know how it's pronounced.
Speaker 0: Somebody just said it and you're like Gangnam.
Speaker 0: It's like, no, there's another N in there.
Speaker 0: It's Gangnam.
Speaker 1: I think what it is is that even if you know how it's pronounced, if everyone else around you is pronouncing it wrong, you will start to reflect the way they say it even if you know better.
Speaker 0: Subconscious doesn't happen to me.
Speaker 0: I listen to someone say something and then I say what they said and then, but it's like people like be talking to someone who says the thing properly.
Speaker 1: So Scott, I'm just going to warn you.
Speaker 1: It is highly likely if I go back through the geek nights archives that you say Gangnam style more often than Gangnam.
Speaker 0: No, maybe you're just hearing it improperly.
Speaker 1: I'm just, you want to bet?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You want to bet that you've never said Gangnam style on geek nights?
Speaker 0: I have not.
Speaker 1: How much do you want to bet?
Speaker 0: A lot.
Speaker 1: How much money?
Speaker 0: I don't think I've said it that often.
Speaker 0: When have we said it on the show?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying I might have secret knowledge.
Speaker 1: So I'm just going instead of giving you every mashup with it because it would be the pony situation.
Speaker 1: This one had me laughing out loud and is also related to Hitler.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 1: It's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: Okay, so October 2012, what month is October 2012?
Speaker 0: Well, it is many months, but most importantly, it is the month of the flexagon.
Speaker 0: Now, you might be saying, what the fuck is a flexagon?
Speaker 0: Here's a handy YouTube video that will show you what a flexagon is.
Speaker 1: That's the same girl who did snake, snake, snake, snake, snake, snake.
Speaker 0: That's exactly right.
Speaker 0: The same person she, which is a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Many, many, many, many moons ago, I think in Beacon Times.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: She has done many similar videos that are basically this mix of mathematics and adorableness.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So watch this video about flexagons.
Speaker 0: Yay.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment, we're back from Pax Prime.
Speaker 1: We're back from Pax Dev.
Speaker 1: We didn't even talk about it in the news, but Pax Australia was announced.
Speaker 0: I can't even remember the last episode we did, what we talked about.
Speaker 1: And there's a good chance we'll go because it doesn't directly overlap with Kineticon.
Speaker 1: It's the week after Kineticon.
Speaker 1: So here's what we're going to have to do.
Speaker 1: Go to Kineticon, run the panels department as always.
Speaker 0: Do you want to go to Australia immediately after Kineticon or do you want to go to, you know, to the Pax Australia and then stay in Australia after?
Speaker 1: If I go to Australia, I am definitely staying there for a while.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But are we good?
Speaker 0: We could go immediately after Kineticon and then stay there until the Pax and then leave.
Speaker 0: Or we could go there, get there.
Speaker 1: You act like these are mutually exclusive.
Speaker 1: If I go to Australia, I'm staying there at least two weeks.
Speaker 0: Are you going to say the before and after the Pax?
Speaker 1: No, I'm probably going to go there with just enough time to be ready to do Pax.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: See, that's a you're using option number one.
Speaker 1: But then I'm going to stick around for like two or three weeks.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying, where do we go?
Speaker 0: Because we could leave immediately after Kineticon.
Speaker 1: I'm going to leave like a day or two after Kineticon.
Speaker 1: But I need to, like, get my shit together.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying, you know, do we?
Speaker 0: you know, the timing of the leaving was all the question was about.
Speaker 1: I mean, if Pax starts what, Friday?
Speaker 1: Kineticon ends Sunday night.
Speaker 1: There's not that many days because it takes a full day to fly there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But you cross the date line to actually go back in time.
Speaker 1: You get one of the days back, which remember, Scott, one of the ways we're going to lose an extra day and one of the ways we're going to get the day back.
Speaker 1: So which side of the trip do you think those two are on?
Speaker 0: I can just it's the lines pretty close when you're out there.
Speaker 0: So you can just sort of sail in a boat and get the day back if you want.
Speaker 0: I mean, it only takes a couple hours to get out there.
Speaker 0: You know, you take a couple hours in the boat, you go out there, you reset in one day.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It's like it's like Half-Minute Hero, right?
Speaker 1: Quite a bit of consternation, because as you guys know, for many years now, me and Scott run the panels and workshops department at Kineticon.
Speaker 0: And when Robert Coo said that Pax would require difficult decisions, I assumed he meant it would be during San Diego Comic Con, which was going to make it during Pax, but it meant it would be very likely overlapping with Kineticon, which also often overlaps San Diego Comic Con.
Speaker 0: But in fact, this year, Kineticon does not overlap San Diego Comic Con, but Pax OS does.
Speaker 0: My guess was correct.
Speaker 0: However, it often is not a difficult decision.
Speaker 0: No, considering we've never been nor will we likely go to San Diego Comic Con.
Speaker 1: I mean, honestly, I'm not even going to the New York Comic Con this year.
Speaker 0: I'm not either.
Speaker 0: I was half considering.
Speaker 0: So get this.
Speaker 0: I was half considering going for a day just to check Scott.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But number one, there was nothing that I need to see.
Speaker 0: Like last year, there was the Kota Shinkai.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: But this year there's nothing like that.
Speaker 0: I got to go see.
Speaker 0: And two, when I went, I'm like, oh, I should go back a one day Sunday badge and I go and it's like all sold out.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh, fuck it.
Speaker 1: So I've never paid for a badge to New York Comic Con or the New York Anime Festival, but I've been to all of them up until this point.
Speaker 1: You didn't go to the first New York Comic Con, the one that was a disaster.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But I went to all the other ones.
Speaker 1: But this year I didn't even bother.
Speaker 1: Like, I got the press stuff and, you know, we've gotten a press badge every year for years now.
Speaker 1: I didn't even bother because I literally could not think of anything I wanted to cover there.
Speaker 1: The only thing I could think of that I wanted to cover is show all the empty panel.
Speaker 1: Yes, because I have all this video from last year and the year before where I walked around and all the panel rooms were empty.
Speaker 1: It was all like a publisher announcing a game or announcing like some book or comic that no one gave a shit about to an empty room.
Speaker 1: so they could just say that they announced at the con.
Speaker 1: And if anyone doubts me, no, I have video.
Speaker 0: It's like, dude, if you have a booth, you just you could just announce it at your booth.
Speaker 0: I need to get the panel for.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: The New York Comic.
Speaker 0: I also have a feeling right that maybe in general they don't want panels because if there's panels, then people who are going to stay there for the duration, no matter what, are going to spend their time not buying.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: There is a very specific incentive at the New York Comic Con and events like it to funnel people in and funnel people out.
Speaker 1: New York Auto Show style for the counts.
Speaker 1: But yeah, this is maybe we'll do a show on that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: Anyway, suffice it to say, we're not even going to go to the New York Comic Con, but we will probably be around in the city.
Speaker 1: So if you guys go to it, we may show up in an after party anyway.
Speaker 0: Oh, by the way, the New York Comic Con is not this weekend, but next weekend.
Speaker 0: It's October 11th through 14th.
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 1: Fuck that noise, because shortly thereafter, right before Halloween is Burning Apocalypse Con 2012.
Speaker 0: I think it's just called Burning Con.
Speaker 0: Is it?
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: I signed up.
Speaker 1: I haven't even looked at the website.
Speaker 1: If there is a website.
Speaker 0: It.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Just burning.
Speaker 0: That coincides nicely with the sixth, seventh anniversary of Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Wait, wait, wait.
Speaker 1: So it's just Burning Con.
Speaker 0: The seventh anniversary of Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: It's just Burning Con.
Speaker 1: But Vincent Baker is going to be there.
Speaker 0: Yes, it's Burning Con 12 colon the Triad Umbert.
Speaker 0: That's why it is because it is the Triad Umbert because it includes Luke Crane, Vincent Baker and John Harper.
Speaker 0: That's the Triad Umbert.
Speaker 0: The three games by those three game designers are acceptable.
Speaker 1: I am running in a scenario that I've run at many events to date, and I think it's getting pretty solid.
Speaker 0: I thought you ran it once.
Speaker 1: No, I ran it at Burning Con.
Speaker 1: I ran it at two recesses.
Speaker 0: Oh, OK.
Speaker 1: And I got to say, running Burning Wheel at a recess really sucks.
Speaker 0: Oh, how was it at the second?
Speaker 0: I don't even hear about how it was at the second recess.
Speaker 0: But not as bad as the first one, though, with the guy who is adversarial, sits down.
Speaker 1: He's like, so I hate these fucking indie RPGs.
Speaker 0: So why did you sign up for one?
Speaker 1: He's like, so what's Burning Wheel got for me?
Speaker 1: One guy in this game was like, you know what I fucking hate?
Speaker 1: When a game has a bunch of rules for everything.
Speaker 1: Please tell me this game doesn't have like social conflict or any bullshit like that.
Speaker 1: Another guy sits down.
Speaker 1: He's like, I only care about procedural mechanical resolution of conflict.
Speaker 1: And these two guys just stared each other down the entire game.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I'm running that again and I think it's going to be awesome.
Speaker 1: But more importantly, Kehil White, our good friend, really important at PAX Prime and East, you know, read pop and all that.
Speaker 1: He's going to be there doing baby's first Burning Wheel.
Speaker 0: Why are you?
Speaker 0: why are you making announcement?
Speaker 0: That's like saying it's like usually you say someone's going to be at a thing when the person is going to run a thing or if they're, you know, an important.
Speaker 0: He signed up just to go to it like everyone else.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know what else is going to be there?
Speaker 1: Most of our friends not going to be there because they're all wusses who are afraid of running a game.
Speaker 1: Because here's the thing.
Speaker 1: Burning Con makes you a badass because you are required to run a game.
Speaker 0: But this year there is a beginner's track.
Speaker 0: It is more expensive, but don't think the beginner's track gets you out of running a game because it doesn't.
Speaker 0: You just get taught on day one by Luke Crane on day two.
Speaker 0: You run the game and you could try to be a pussy and show up on day one and learn and not show up on day two.
Speaker 0: But then, you know, what happens?
Speaker 0: Luke Crane shows up at your house and you know what?
Speaker 0: It's not called Burning Wheel for no reason.
Speaker 1: I just picture Luke Crane wearing like some Scandinavian metal black T-shirt and his red rim glasses with a burning wheel KKK style on the lawn.
Speaker 0: So, but yes, if you've never even played a tabletop RPG in your life, sign up for a beginner's track.
Speaker 0: It'll be totally awesome.
Speaker 0: I'm not allowed to sign up for a beginner's track or else I totally would.
Speaker 1: In fact, he makes a big deal about how if you are caught being in the beginner's track and you are a beginner.
Speaker 1: Not only are you forced to move to the normal track and you don't get the extra money back, but I think it says that Luke will sit in your game and pester you.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's like a bonus though, except for the burning part.
Speaker 1: They also have rules about hacks, which I think is very important.
Speaker 0: I'm not a hack fan, I gotta say.
Speaker 1: I am done with hacks at conventions.
Speaker 1: I don't know why everyone loves hacks so much.
Speaker 0: It's like, just play the game by the fucking rules, all right?
Speaker 1: The reason I'm messing with the wheel or inspectors or some indie RPG is because I'm sick of taking a shitty system and hacking it to make it good.
Speaker 1: Most people who hack games, not good game designers, the hacks are worse than the actual game.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, quick meta moment.
Speaker 0: Are we meta momenting right now?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're meta momenting.
Speaker 1: It's long.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, so much meta has piled up.
Speaker 1: All right, so I got one more and then you can go.
Speaker 1: So we did our lecture at PAX, PAX Prime, and I can't obviously upload video of our stuff at PAX Dev, but I did upload the first of our three mini lectures.
Speaker 1: when the game plays the player, AKA, we talk about DDR for 20 minutes.
Speaker 0: Don't hate the player, hate the player.
Speaker 1: And we realized, you know what this panel really is?
Speaker 1: How to be an effective hater 101.
Speaker 1: It's a good panel, and we got to try out our multi-camera angle.
Speaker 1: There are one, two, three, four, five distinct, six distinct camera angles in the video.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so you know how we have all our things all over the Internet.
Speaker 0: We have websites, we have emails, we have an email newsletter, which I'm going to start mailing again once we start doing something to mail about.
Speaker 0: We got Facebook's, we got Twitter's, we got all these things.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, I have two news is on this front of having things all over the Internet.
Speaker 0: News number one, apparently Facebook is even didn't realize this sort of scammy and shitty.
Speaker 0: What Facebook has been doing is if I post something on the night's Twitter, everyone who follows the nights on Twitter sees that if they read their Twitter often enough.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: If I post something on Geek Nights Facebook page, apparently it will not be guaranteed to show up in everyone's newsfeed who subscribes to the Geek Nights page.
Speaker 0: It will only subscribe.
Speaker 0: It will only show up in some small percentage of those people's news feeds.
Speaker 0: And Facebook wants you to pay them money to get like a sponsored page or whatever to guarantee that that message will show up on every on the pay the newsfeed of every person who follows your page.
Speaker 0: So if you are using following Geek Nights on Facebook as your primary means of Geek Nights news updates.
Speaker 0: Stop it.
Speaker 0: Well, don't stop it.
Speaker 0: But you may not be seeing everything that we post there in your newsfeed.
Speaker 0: You may actually have to go to Facebook dot com slash, you know, front row crew in order to see everything that is posted there.
Speaker 0: So we recommend you also follow us with some other means.
Speaker 0: Number two news.
Speaker 0: We are testing the addition of a new place on the Internet for us to be.
Speaker 1: I downloaded Merck for the first time.
Speaker 0: You should use IRS's.
Speaker 0: I don't use that.
Speaker 1: But I know Merck doesn't.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't use that.
Speaker 1: Merck is hardcore using.
Speaker 0: No, it's not hardcore.
Speaker 0: Use IRS size what you use.
Speaker 1: Well, the hardcore is Telnet.
Speaker 0: Yes, we have an hour.
Speaker 0: I made an IRC channel as perch.
Speaker 0: If it still exists, you're going to use IRS's.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So I see you're so fucking stupid.
Speaker 0: It's not nineteen ninety nine anymore.
Speaker 1: So you want to feel old, Scott?
Speaker 1: We got to RIT.
Speaker 1: I use Telnet and Elm to read my mail.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I use pine because they actually had pine in those computers despite the licensing issues.
Speaker 0: So if you want we have an IRC channel that is currently temporary beta ish.
Speaker 0: If it fails, you're just going to stop it.
Speaker 0: But if it doesn't fail, I guess people will be chatting in there.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: This is the best Web page ever.
Speaker 0: Anyway, going is the second time cube.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: I'm linking to this.
Speaker 1: What is IRC?
Speaker 0: So the channel?
Speaker 0: it's on the phonetic network, which is the same place that has the XKCD IRC chat room.
Speaker 0: So you got to you connect to IRC dot phonetic dot net and then you go to, you know, channel geek nights.
Speaker 0: And there might be some people in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I haven't used it yet.
Speaker 0: Maybe because you're not using IRS.
Speaker 1: Maybe because I looked at it, no one was there.
Speaker 0: That's also true.
Speaker 1: The thing is, what was I remember a long time ago, I said something and someone else said this and I was just paraphrasing.
Speaker 1: It was basically IRC, the place where people turn on bots to idle until they die.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: We actually have one bot in there.
Speaker 0: All it does is keep logs of the chat room and put them on our website.
Speaker 0: You can go to front row crew dot com slash IRC slash logs.
Speaker 1: You know, if we if we if we want to go old school, we need a bot.
Speaker 1: that every time someone types Ubuntu, it writes phonetically Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: You can write whatever kind of bot you want.
Speaker 1: I've never written an IRC bot.
Speaker 0: There's plenty easy ways to do that.
Speaker 1: I imagine there are.
Speaker 0: It's actually one of the easiest things to program.
Speaker 0: You want to learn to program.
Speaker 0: That is not a bad project to start with.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Let us move on.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So FTL.
Speaker 0: So there's this game Faster Than Light and it had a Kickstarter in the.
Speaker 0: in the time period when I was kick starting like crazy, I saw the Kickstarter page and I was like, damn, that game looks pretty cool.
Speaker 0: I'll drop you some dollars.
Speaker 0: I'll give you the minimum amount of money required to get this game.
Speaker 0: So I did.
Speaker 1: I saw it, forgot about it promptly.
Speaker 0: Of course, I forgot about it.
Speaker 0: And then they messaged me and they, you know, and they were like, hey, the game came out.
Speaker 0: Here's your code.
Speaker 0: Go on Steam.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, OK, I guess so.
Speaker 0: And I got it on Steam and I played it and I was like, oh, shit, this game is actually, whoa, this game is stupid fun and it runs on anything.
Speaker 1: So on my laptop, like the one like idle game, if I'm like on a plane or something was Binding of Isaac, because it's basically an actiony kind of roguelike.
Speaker 0: And you can when a room is empty, you can start to hang out.
Speaker 1: This is basically the same.
Speaker 1: It fills the same niche for me, except I actually really like playing it the entire time I'm playing it, except the time when I get fucked over, which is every time.
Speaker 1: But Scott is not the point of a game like this in the losing.
Speaker 0: No, I think there should be a mode that they should have three modes right now.
Speaker 0: They only have two modes, easy and normal.
Speaker 0: And I think number one, that's wrong.
Speaker 0: They should have learned from Super Hexagon.
Speaker 0: If you don't have a true easy mode, don't call it easy mode in Super Hexagon.
Speaker 0: The easiest mode is called hard faster than light.
Speaker 0: They should have named the modes normal and fuck you.
Speaker 0: And then they should have added a third mode winnable and they should have added a fourth.
Speaker 0: They should have added a fourth mode nightmare because everyone knows what that means.
Speaker 1: But Scott, easy mode is actually really fucking easy.
Speaker 0: Easy mode is not winnable.
Speaker 0: Try to win the game on easy mode.
Speaker 1: I haven't really tried that hard.
Speaker 1: I've never actually played easy mode.
Speaker 0: I don't think you can.
Speaker 0: Oh, you just said easy mode is actually really easy.
Speaker 0: And then you said you never played it.
Speaker 1: Because normal mode is not that.
Speaker 0: And it's on tape.
Speaker 0: Easy mode is not easy.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: Try to beat the game.
Speaker 0: I can get to the boss on easy mode pretty reliably with a particular strategy I've come up with, but I cannot beat the boss with that strategy because it was a very good strategy for getting to the end and a very bad strategy for beating the end.
Speaker 1: Watch us work forward as fast as possible.
Speaker 0: The problem is, is all the strategies for beating the end, like building my ship up along the way, are very, very bad for getting to the end.
Speaker 1: Got to get that crystal ship, man.
Speaker 0: I don't have the crystal ship yet.
Speaker 1: Do you know how to get it?
Speaker 0: You got to do some unlucky bullshit.
Speaker 0: You have to get this too much luck.
Speaker 0: This is the first thing I talk about in this game.
Speaker 1: Why do you need too much luck?
Speaker 1: The game, that's the point of this game.
Speaker 0: That's bullshit.
Speaker 0: I want a no luck version.
Speaker 0: It's called the winnable edition.
Speaker 1: The point of this game is that it's a rogue like Star Trek simulator.
Speaker 0: You can have rogue likes that where you can, there's people where no matter what luck they get in a game of net hack can still go get that amulet at the bottom, whatever it is.
Speaker 1: No bullshit.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you usually get fucking killed.
Speaker 0: No, there are people who no matter what, right?
Speaker 0: You get two guys, set them up with the same dwarf fortress.
Speaker 0: that's in the exact same thing, right?
Speaker 0: And one guy will kick some ass and one guy might die right away because there's no one's doing right.
Speaker 0: There is a non luck element that is very significant in rogue likes.
Speaker 1: Yes, and you know what?
Speaker 1: In FTL there is too, because I've already, there's a fucking, let me find some speed runs on YouTube.
Speaker 0: FTL speed run?
Speaker 0: No, why do I suck?
Speaker 1: I'm not saying I'm great at this game, but, uh, I don't think you found any.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't.
Speaker 1: All right, I'll look for the, Oh, here we go.
Speaker 1: FTL speed run.
Speaker 1: No scope.
Speaker 0: No scope.
Speaker 0: Is it final destination Fox only?
Speaker 1: So Scott, what is this game?
Speaker 0: So fast and light is basically it's sort of Star Trek, but it doesn't have the whole bridge thing going on, right?
Speaker 0: It's, it's sort of an RTS, right?
Speaker 0: You, all you see on the screen is your ship and the guys in it and you control them and give them orders.
Speaker 0: And in RTS mode, you click on them and you right click to tell them where to go.
Speaker 0: And depending on which room they're in, in your ship, they'll do different things.
Speaker 0: You can also have complete control of the energy in your ship, right?
Speaker 0: So you can say, you know, and your ship produces only so much energy and you only have so many places to put it.
Speaker 0: So if you have more places to put it, then you have energy available.
Speaker 0: You have to decide what to turn on and what to turn off in real time.
Speaker 0: So you might say divert energy from the weapons to the shield or turn off some shields to turn on some weapons and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Look what's going on here.
Speaker 1: It's, it's doing the good game design thing of when you think about like Star Trek or any kind of, you know, thing like this, what's, what's always happening in the show, divert power to the engines, right?
Speaker 1: You get to do the thing that you always think about and see in these media.
Speaker 0: Well, unless you spend enough, your new resource points to get enough power, that everything is powered all the time.
Speaker 1: You don't have any other stuff to power up.
Speaker 0: So then you need to spend some resource points to make things consume more power.
Speaker 1: The reason this game shines is that you will never have enough fucking anything ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You'll be looking, you'll be like, if I turn off the oxygen, I can power up that missile one more time.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Or I'm out of missiles.
Speaker 0: Let me power those fuckers down.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: I'm going to turn off the med bay cause nobody's hurt right now.
Speaker 0: And that gives me enough energy to temporarily boost the shield.
Speaker 1: Now, the most important thing is that this game would be bullshit, but for the fact that you can pause with no penalty at any time and redo all your cause.
Speaker 0: it's a single player game, even though it's an RTS, you can pause and it's like, Hey, why doesn't single-player star craft?
Speaker 0: just let you fucking pause, give orders and then unpause because then it's such a completely different game, right?
Speaker 0: But it's only in the single player part, you know, it's like, Hey, there's no micro to worry about.
Speaker 0: There's no fast clicking penalty, right?
Speaker 0: Because you can pause, give the guys orders, unpause and you can do it as much as you want.
Speaker 1: The guys follow their orders, you know, slowly or quickly.
Speaker 0: If they're fucking rock guys, they're fucking so slow.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: Rock guys.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: I have some Mantis guys.
Speaker 1: I had a rock guy.
Speaker 0: Mantis guys are the best.
Speaker 1: So four fucking Mantis guys came into my O2 room and started fucking it up.
Speaker 0: Just everyone runs to the med bay and wait.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: They fucked it up and then they moved room to room and fucking it up.
Speaker 0: That's what happens.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And I vented and eventually they destroyed all my systems and then the ship that was there destroyed me.
Speaker 0: Oh, well you have to see.
Speaker 0: the thing is you have to keep, uh, yeah.
Speaker 0: See, usually when someone attacks my ship and they bored me, I just let them destroy all the systems and then they get to the med bay and they lose there because the med bay heals my guys.
Speaker 1: They destroy your shields and then the lasers from the ship take you out.
Speaker 0: I've actually been rather lucky in that they sort of avoid the shield room.
Speaker 0: They go to the med room first.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: Uh, I'm going to feel dumb.
Speaker 1: The room with the door control, I didn't realize what that was until it got destroyed.
Speaker 0: Oh, good job.
Speaker 1: So I was fine.
Speaker 1: I'm playing my game.
Speaker 1: Everything's going okay.
Speaker 1: And then these Mantis fuckers come on my ship to fuck my shit up and I'm like, all right, I'll just vent.
Speaker 1: So I opened up all the doors to vent those guys out and my guys are hiding in the med bay.
Speaker 1: And then that room with the two vertical things broke.
Speaker 1: And then I took out the Mantis and then I couldn't close the doors.
Speaker 0: And what you do is you send two of the guys into the door room to fix it.
Speaker 0: And then they, the room that had no oxygen, right?
Speaker 0: But they have to keep running in and out a whole bunch because it's right next to the med bay and the normal ship.
Speaker 0: You keep running in and out a whole bunch until it's repaired.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I was one, not in a normal ship until, uh, it didn't work out.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: But yeah.
Speaker 1: And then you can, uh, yeah, it's not a good situation.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: I also have the trouble of rock man defense.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: Rock man cannot catch Mantis man.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: Mantis man's actually the strongest at fighting damage wise, at least indoors.
Speaker 1: I like how some weapons you can target your own ship and try to shoot a guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But the biggest problem in this game is that you level up right either by, you know, you find equipment, you get what's scrap, which is basically money used to buy upgrades.
Speaker 1: Also your dudes get better by whatever they're doing.
Speaker 0: So if a guy does this, you want to make sure the same guy is always doing the same job, but like the same guy is always in the engine room.
Speaker 0: Then he becomes the engineer and gets really good at it, which gives you a slight bonus to engineering.
Speaker 1: Now it's also a super fun sort of mini game of like, you have a guy like this guy's my engineer.
Speaker 1: He's going to do my engines, my repair.
Speaker 1: You kind of like specialize your guys.
Speaker 1: Then you're fuck is one of them dies.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's like, so far, this is a nine minute speed run and the guys doing okay.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: The biggest problem I have in the game is number one, even on easy, you don't get enough scrap.
Speaker 0: That's good to buy all that.
Speaker 0: You can't fully upgrade all the things you wouldn't be able to, otherwise it'd be boring.
Speaker 1: It'd be like cow click winnable.
Speaker 0: Uh, two, right.
Speaker 0: The other problem is that even if you get the scrap, you know, go to the shops and they just might not have the thing you want to get.
Speaker 0: It's like, it's no consistency.
Speaker 0: So it's like, I got a strategy that involves stealth and it's just, you can always spend that on the ship instead.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But it's like you go to the first shop and there's no stealth and you go to the next shop and there's no stealth and you're already like halfway through the game and you still haven't found the stealth device.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: If you still think that stealth is going to be your thing, you should give up on it.
Speaker 0: But that it's like.
Speaker 0: then you need the stealth because the final boss, he shoots you with this fricking, you know, fricking multi-drone attack and you need to enable stealth right then.
Speaker 0: That's the way to beat him.
Speaker 1: To me, the point of this game is that you can't do everything.
Speaker 1: It is so hard.
Speaker 1: It's just make do with what you got and see how far you can get.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The fact that the end is so unattainable and so difficult actually adds a lot of the fun.
Speaker 1: When I finally beat this game, I'm going to throw whatever I'm holding in my hand at the nearest wall.
Speaker 0: Here's why I disagree, right?
Speaker 0: You look at a roguelike, like say the Dwarf Fortress, and there is no win in Dwarf Fortress.
Speaker 0: Like what's the goal of Dwarf Fortress?
Speaker 0: You play until you lose and the losing is spectacular.
Speaker 1: Actually, that's the one main gig.
Speaker 1: night's lecture we have no video of.
Speaker 0: In Faster Than Light, there is a goal.
Speaker 0: It is get to the end and beat that boss.
Speaker 0: And it's not fun to not beat the boss.
Speaker 1: To me it is.
Speaker 1: I don't care if I don't beat the boss.
Speaker 1: It's like Oregon Trail.
Speaker 1: When I finally beat that fucker, it was great.
Speaker 0: But I'm never going to beat that fucker.
Speaker 1: Well then you're not willing to invest enough into it.
Speaker 1: I've already played this game.
Speaker 0: like how many times?
Speaker 1: How good are Counter-Strike?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty good.
Speaker 1: So Scott, this is still a speedrun.
Speaker 1: I'm watching this guy beat the game.
Speaker 0: He got lucky.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: He got real lucky.
Speaker 1: Right now his shields are still down.
Speaker 1: Go on.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The other thing is like not even memorization will help you beat this game.
Speaker 1: Whoa, that's all Nebula.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you've never been to an all Nebula?
Speaker 0: I have not.
Speaker 0: I guess because you've only played a normal, you've never gotten to one of those.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's whole quadrants that are just sectors that are entirely Nebula.
Speaker 0: The purple ones.
Speaker 1: I usually go straight for like Rockland.
Speaker 1: Hoping to get a right guy.
Speaker 0: I just go all green as much as possible.
Speaker 0: What was I saying?
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: F this game.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: He just died.
Speaker 1: Wait, what?
Speaker 1: Oh, it's over.
Speaker 0: He lost.
Speaker 0: What a speedrun.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No scope.
Speaker 0: No scope is why he got shot, Rimden.
Speaker 1: I am fine with the fact that this game is goddamn impossible because that adds a lot of the fun to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Wait until you're pissed.
Speaker 0: he can't beat it.
Speaker 0: What's the point of this game?
Speaker 1: What do you get?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're going to see.
Speaker 0: You're going to get good enough to get to the point where you can get to the final boss reliably and then wait till you see what that final boss is like and then you're going to agree with me.
Speaker 0: The only reason you don't agree with me now is because you haven't seen the final boss.
Speaker 1: I enjoy games.
Speaker 0: You don't know what the final boss is like at all, do you?
Speaker 1: I know he has three stages.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what else do you know about him?
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is why you are not in agreement with me.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to assume that you actually do agree with me because you don't know what happens at the end.
Speaker 1: Scott, I enjoy that kind of bullshit.
Speaker 0: No, you don't understand.
Speaker 1: Remember when we played Crystal Chronicles for the first time and we beat that first stage and that second and that third and they're just carrying more stages.
Speaker 1: That was like a four hour boss battle.
Speaker 0: Well, that was the square, square, square, square Tesseract boss.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember dying at a later stage and realizing we had to go back that four hours and start over.
Speaker 1: So, yes, I do know what that is like.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: Bring it.
Speaker 0: No, baby.
Speaker 1: This game is stupid fun.
Speaker 1: Everyone should buy it and play it.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's true.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: So everyone should buy it and play it.
Speaker 1: It's stupid fun.
Speaker 1: Yet you hate it.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.