Speaker 1: It's Tuesday July 24th 2012.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and my name is Inigo month.
Speaker 1: So my fun, so you're making a difference to the princess bride.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's like saying the cake is a lie Randomly at a convention.
Speaker 0: Yep It sure is.
Speaker 1: And you thought of this just now?
Speaker 0: no, I thought of it days ago.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Anyway tonight we're talking about talking Oka.
Speaker 0: I don't think you said this is geek night that precocious panda.
Speaker 1: So actually we learned about this game for the main bit at nerd NYC, you know the board game night We always go to.
Speaker 0: yeah, Ryan the guy who sort of runs the show there.
Speaker 0: He usually shows up at the same sort of set of default games that you go to if no one else brought anything or if you've Played everything else.
Speaker 0: I've played all of those games With him, yeah, he brings, you know loco and Siro and settlers and whatever.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like if he was our friend chase, he'd be there with spotted right banana grams, but this time he got a new game.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh my god, he got a new game.
Speaker 0: He brought.
Speaker 0: it was called Taka Noko.
Speaker 0: We're gonna we're like, so what's this game?
Speaker 0: We're advancing we save it for the main bit.
Speaker 0: Jesus Christ.
Speaker 1: So, uh, but after that we had to play another game and Emily was there.
Speaker 1: So and we had a some cool internet person.
Speaker 1: We had a bunch of people.
Speaker 1: we played Carcassonne.
Speaker 1: So as I'm teaching everyone Scott and Emily are like don't listen to anything.
Speaker 1: rim says he always wins this game like 90% of the time.
Speaker 1: seriously, don't listen to him.
Speaker 1: and Jeremiah who's playing with us is there and he's like 90 whatever percent.
Speaker 1: me pause.
Speaker 1: He's like how many games have you played?
Speaker 1: He's super dubious.
Speaker 1: He was really like, uh, this is bullshit.
Speaker 1: You're just yeah, I totally won.
Speaker 0: Yeah Despite Scott and Emily telling everyone else to watch out for my bullshit Because it only works if everyone knows right they they have to know you or else they won't believe.
Speaker 0: Imagine if you go to play a game with two strangers, right?
Speaker 0: You're at PAX and two strangers are gaming with them, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, one of them says watch out for my friend.
Speaker 0: I'm serious.
Speaker 0: He always wins.
Speaker 0: We have to team up on him.
Speaker 0: I'm not shitting you.
Speaker 0: What do you do against these two strangers?
Speaker 0: You don't know anything about.
Speaker 1: ah, but what if it is three?
Speaker 0: How do you know?
Speaker 0: it's not a team grift?
Speaker 0: That would be your first guess wouldn't it?
Speaker 1: But if it is three strangers and two of them are saying watch out for that, you know, it's not it's a four-player game.
Speaker 0: How do you know?
Speaker 0: it's not a team?
Speaker 1: Actually Scott, I would have lost except that you of all fucking people ended up king making with me.
Speaker 1: You were like rim Apple and I was like Apple and we started playing and the two of us pulled away.
Speaker 0: No, cuz I was trying to Apple you in the city and orange you in the farm But I and I fire fuck up the farm every time cuz I don't know how to do the farm.
Speaker 1: You know, well, you know my real strategy is to win because carcass own it was base carcass own like without any expansion.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's nothing.
Speaker 1: while I have that game memorized statistically it is Pretty random among skilled players like winning or losing if you're playing well Like if I'd lost that game there was no decision.
Speaker 1: I could have made differently to alter that.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so to enhance my likelihood of winning I Do the same thing every time and I'm gonna reveal the secret.
Speaker 1: right now when there are novice players I teach everyone how to play and I give accurate honest very good advice to everyone at the table.
Speaker 1: Yeah for the first two-thirds of the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't lie in the last two-thirds.
Speaker 1: I just start bitching how I'm losing because I gave everyone else good advice Which is usually true at that point because I give everyone else good advice and simultaneously I'm setting up farms and things that don't score right away.
Speaker 1: So I look like I'm way behind And I'm.
Speaker 1: everyone else knows that I'm giving good advice.
Speaker 1: They listen to me.
Speaker 1: then I kind of stop giving advice toward the end and just bitch about how I'm losing it.
Speaker 1: ah, ah, I can't win this game and somehow that always works even though you guys know I do it.
Speaker 1: use the first warning sign with rim.
Speaker 1: if you see.
Speaker 1: if I ever Say well, I can't win that is code for I am definitely winning and you know what the scariest part is.
Speaker 0: Even though you say this you you tell everyone exactly what you're doing.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter It's like.
Speaker 0: this is the thing that our government and most governments of the world have learned.
Speaker 0: they used to Right.
Speaker 0: the governments around the world used to be evil, but would hide their evilness.
Speaker 0: They'd like oh we can't let anyone know about this corrupt evil wrongdoing scandal nowadays.
Speaker 0: They're just like Scandal.
Speaker 0: yes, we did that scandal mm-hmm and what and We're gonna do it again, and you're not gonna do anything about it next time either.
Speaker 0: That's rim Yep, but you know what.
Speaker 0: the same thing that call governments of where it's like.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, you can have freedom of speech.
Speaker 0: We don't need to censor you get.
Speaker 0: tell everyone about It's not gonna matter.
Speaker 1: I've been on a roll lately though I want everyone told everyone all the evil things you did.
Speaker 0: guys the government is doing all these bad things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we know.
Speaker 1: remember that.
Speaker 1: what was it?
Speaker 1: You said it a hundred times.
Speaker 1: was it mall of horror?
Speaker 1: the vote who vote?
Speaker 0: who wins game?
Speaker 0: vote who wins zombie mall.
Speaker 1: I remember the one time I played that Scott is yelling across the room at us every turn.
Speaker 1: Don't vote for rim in the vote who wins game and guess who won The game is literally vote until someone wins yeah every time.
Speaker 0: I was simply I'd be like let us vote Not rim every time guys seriously.
Speaker 0: And then once rim is eliminated and has no more zombie survivors then play normally, but no they eliminate you instead stupidly The only game they're smart about.
Speaker 0: and you know if we played it again if they listen to this podcast And then immediately played that game They would still be stupid.
Speaker 1: now It's interesting because the one game that doesn't work for any of us is Mafia.
Speaker 1: those fuckers murder you me and Scott Johnson without even.
Speaker 0: yeah, why is it in Mafia?
Speaker 0: It's a vote.
Speaker 0: also vote who wins game?
Speaker 0: do they vote against?
Speaker 0: but in the other vote who wins game They vote for.
Speaker 1: what I find funny is every time they like Lynch you me or scojo in a game like that We're never the Mafia ever.
Speaker 0: Anyway anyway, let's talk about actual stuff.
Speaker 1: so steam summer sale.
Speaker 0: steam sale Let's talk about.
Speaker 0: so I bought.
Speaker 0: basically I made two purchases really right.
Speaker 0: well three I bought.
Speaker 0: I pre-ordered torchlight 2 and they gave me a free copy of torchlight 1. shit I forgot about torchlight 2, but I already had it.
Speaker 0: so it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: I can't play it yet, but the game should be out September.
Speaker 0: October is basically Diablo 3. yeah, it's a clicking game, but you know without real money without any bullshit.
Speaker 0: in fact I talked to them at PAX and they the things.
Speaker 0: I didn't have to ask them questions.
Speaker 0: really when I spoke to them This is last packs prime.
Speaker 0: They their pitch was look at all the bullshit We don't have and I was like I will give you $20 for your game.
Speaker 0: That is nothing but clicking.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I bought fallout, New Vegas because they had the ultimate with all DLCs for a very low price, and I bought Oblivion which is the previous elder scroll before Skyrim because it was also all DLCs very low price.
Speaker 0: So I started.
Speaker 0: I bought New Vegas first because that deal was earlier in the week.
Speaker 0: I started playing it, and I was expecting it to be more Fallout 3. well Even though it's the same engine as Fallout 3 is not as good as Fallout 3 I thought it was gonna be more of the same which is Game that is fundamentally broken, but has interesting enough stuff in this world that it is worth spending some hours to explore it.
Speaker 0: It was actually Much more boring than that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could have told you that I didn't know that.
Speaker 0: I mean you know I figured just be more.
Speaker 0: follow three.
Speaker 0: But the thing with New Vegas is that?
Speaker 0: You know without did you get to Vegas?
Speaker 0: no?
Speaker 0: not yet anyway is that it's just?
Speaker 0: you know that the structure of the quests and the layout of the world is not so great and the things that you find are You know it fall out of three and a lot of things you would find to be sort of this procedural boring stuff like oh This is exact same place as that other place.
Speaker 0: It's just the lockers are in a different orientation.
Speaker 0: this has less of that.
Speaker 0: But the things you find aren't really even though they're less procedurally generated They're more boring, and there's not really that sort of.
Speaker 0: you know it sort of has that funky fallout style in places But it's mixed with the Wild West style But it it's not as cool and kitschy is like - on.
Speaker 0: the kitchen is also The main kitchy.
Speaker 1: populux is the only reason to play fallout right.
Speaker 0: and you know the main plot of Fallout 3 was Significantly you know had that whole you're in the vault and you play that whole beginning part And it sort of had that weird secretive space.
Speaker 0: you would go out of the vault and you enter this weird world right in New Vegas, it's.
Speaker 0: it's so typical western with no weirdness whatsoever It's.
Speaker 0: you were a guy delivering a message.
Speaker 0: some guys stole the message from you Which was a poker chip that had must have had something in it.
Speaker 1: as usual It didn't get far enough to find out.
Speaker 0: and then you wake up in a town where a doctor heals you up and ask you a bunch of questions to determine your stats and Then you're welcome the Wild West town.
Speaker 0: there's some bandits And it's just like you know.
Speaker 0: nothing is just exciting at all And I don't know how much more I might play just to go see what the Vegas looks like and see if you can play all the casino games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not exciting.
Speaker 0: The oblivion however right I feel kind of dumb.
Speaker 0: I had thought that these old scrolls games.
Speaker 0: You know not having you know played too many of them I was under the impression that they were basically the same as those other D&D type games like Baldur's Gate and such only 3d FPS.
Speaker 0: I Did not know until just now feeling pretty dumb that oblivion is pretty much the fallout 3 engine.
Speaker 0: in fact It's more accurate to say fallout 3 is the oblivion engine upgraded.
Speaker 1: so the same damn game only fantasy So semi procedural fetch quests.
Speaker 0: yes, however You know all these games.
Speaker 0: You know have the same since they're on the same engine and have mostly the same rules.
Speaker 0: They all have the same problems.
Speaker 1: game wise combat is walk backwards attacking.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much You know stuff like that at least.
Speaker 0: actually in in oblivion a lot of times There's these imps that shoot fireballs at you pretty slowly, so it's the same as doom where you're dodging imp fireballs.
Speaker 0: They're really slow anyway And it doesn't have that sort of pause to shoot guys in the head that fallout 3 has which is actually kind of nice because I hate that.
Speaker 0: But I got to say the oblivion The game that they made on the engine right you know in terms of the non game parts as in you know These story parts and art parts and all the music not so much, but all the other parts lore and all those things is Really great.
Speaker 0: So I can see why those people who really don't give a shit about Games as far as we can you know care about them, but you know care about lures and arts and graphics and stories.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's why they're in love with these.
Speaker 0: You know old girls because usually when I go to like a fantasy thing all right, and it's not a world.
Speaker 0: I already know It's hard for to make me you have to do a really good job to make me give a shit Right it's like you know Prince of nothing.
Speaker 0: It's like a new fantasy world.
Speaker 0: Why should I care?
Speaker 0: Oh, I care cuz it's really good Locke Lamora.
Speaker 0: I kind of care cuz it's pretty good ish right, but forgotten realms.
Speaker 0: I really don't.
Speaker 0: I really don't care I don't even is is freaking all Elder Scrolls even in like Forgotten Realms or something or just its own world?
Speaker 0: No, I don't even know What.
Speaker 1: where do you?
Speaker 1: where would you show them?
Speaker 0: This is how I don't even know.
Speaker 0: What world is it is it?
Speaker 0: is it its own world?
Speaker 1: It's not a Dungeons & Dragons world.
Speaker 0: it's not Dungeons & Dragons at all no, but it's really old yeah, so it's just its own place.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right anyway.
Speaker 0: So anyway yeah, but they just you know.
Speaker 0: the the job of world making in it is You know like I don't really care about the Elder Scrolls world, but I kind of care A little bit.
Speaker 0: I think the things that make me care less are the fact that you like you make your own character And it has that horrible much giving the player too much control over what your character looks like thing Which is really annoying because you can never make something you're really Happy with but you don't have not willing to put in the time and effort to twiddle all of the hundred knobs to make The guy look the way you want him to look.
Speaker 1: Oh my god Here's a forum argument of people trying to decide which is a better fantasy setting forgotten realms or the Elder Scrolls universe.
Speaker 1: Okay, except the majority of the posts are people saying what the fuck is forgotten realms.
Speaker 0: Okay, interesting very interesting but anyway Yeah, I wish that they would just like.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah Why is everyone so afraid of making a game like this?
Speaker 1: that just doesn't have the bullshit FPS e combat e game part.
Speaker 0: That's exactly.
Speaker 1: just make it a. choose your own adventure and explore game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because the rules and the numbers and the stats and the you know, all right, it's like I'm you know There was this awesome quest.
Speaker 0: I went on right where there was a crazy hermit and I talked to the crazy hermit and he ranted And raved.
Speaker 0: but then it gave me a quest and it was sort of annoying that it gives you like the text instructions.
Speaker 0: But it's sort of impossible if they don't You know the Mega Man Mega Man, but anyway, even though they gave text instructions I'm like, I'm gonna go see if what this hermit has to say is true.
Speaker 0: So I go and I look for the nine Alters out in the world that he gave me a map to and I'm visiting the altars Right and at one of the altars I meet another guy who's also visiting the altars right and he talks about how.
Speaker 0: yeah, he's looking for him too and he has a You know, he has a squire who's actually a character and not just a guy who's standing there with you know stock, you know talking and everyone is voice acted and everyone has you know, pretty complex dialogue.
Speaker 0: and After I get all these altars I go, you know to this other place and there's these ghosts and I have to fight them.
Speaker 0: And then then they're like here's another quest.
Speaker 0: you have to go and get the pieces of the Crusaders armor to you know Bring to revive our you know, our basically equivalent of Knights Templar Organization.
Speaker 0: so I go and I get all the Crusaders armor and I meet that same guy.
Speaker 0: He's looking for him too, but he died along the way and his squire is there and he's like, hey man, what's up?
Speaker 0: he's like the other guy died and I'm like, whoa, this is crazy that they made this work.
Speaker 0: and then when I get back and I finally read, you know birthed this organization that squire joins the organization.
Speaker 0: He's like, hey, can I join?
Speaker 0: I'm like, yes arise sir Knight and he's all excited.
Speaker 0: He's like, yes, and I'm like man, whoever wrote this is really good writing.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I actually feel like a hero.
Speaker 0: I went on an epic quest and it's just like the beginning of the game, right and that part is great.
Speaker 0: But I didn't need to play this FPS of hitting with swords and worrying about how encumbered I am.
Speaker 0: Your armor dude, the leveling up is.
Speaker 0: so yeah guys quest for glory.
Speaker 1: Use that mechanic in infinity number of years ago.
Speaker 1: We can move past it.
Speaker 0: the leveling up is so dumb.
Speaker 0: So you use a skill to increase it, right?
Speaker 0: So you swing your sword and your sword goes up in quest for glory one.
Speaker 1: I remember feeling outside Throwing knives at a tree for like an hour one day.
Speaker 0: Yeah And the way it works is to get an actual level an actual full level.
Speaker 0: you have to ink you have to get ten points In skills, but they can only be your major skills.
Speaker 0: So I'm a mage.
Speaker 0: so my major skills are all the different magical schools and alchemy.
Speaker 0: So I really only ever use the destructive magic spells and I never used any conjuration burning wheel or illusion anything But shards.
Speaker 1: exactly.
Speaker 0: the illusions are so useless.
Speaker 0: I mean I'm sure someone's gonna tell me they're useful but who gives a shit?
Speaker 0: I can.
Speaker 0: I can beat the game with just the fireball Projectile thing that does 15 damage.
Speaker 0: So what do I give a shit about casting shield or whatever?
Speaker 0: Right, exactly.
Speaker 0: So I Also the game, you know that it is cool that I can be the armor mage.
Speaker 0: I'm wearing this full heavy armor like full plate with a helmet.
Speaker 0: You can't even see my face and I'm a mage.
Speaker 0: So I'm just like casting fireballs and like my hand is holding the most magical enchanted sword And I just put my fist forward while holding the sword and a fireball comes out of it.
Speaker 0: That's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: But it's it's so annoying.
Speaker 0: I'm like, I'm only using one school of magic.
Speaker 0: So I never got any levels.
Speaker 0: So the game scales the difficulty based on your actual levels.
Speaker 0: So I've leveled up all these other skills really high like heavy armor, which is not a mage skill.
Speaker 0: So bad guys can't really hurt me But they're cuz.
Speaker 0: they're so low level bad guys cuz I'm only level three.
Speaker 0: But then I had learned that you could only access certain things when you got certain number of real levels.
Speaker 0: So I went to the mages guild and I cast summon skeleton like 50 times.
Speaker 0: I just basically used a rubber band and a rock to hold the button down on my keyboard.
Speaker 1: Did you actually use a rubber band and a rock?
Speaker 0: Yes, I did.
Speaker 0: I used a rubber band like a little pebble Oh And to hold down the cast button and I set summon skeleton to be the spell.
Speaker 0: and a guy just stood there summoning Skeletons until his mana ran out.
Speaker 0: but the mana recharges really fast because I put max Skeletons.
Speaker 0: do they just stand there cuz any order.
Speaker 0: there were no bad guys.
Speaker 1: I picture in the far future of this.
Speaker 0: every time you summon a skeleton another one disappears.
Speaker 0: I only have one skeleton at a time.
Speaker 1: I was gonna say I picture some adventurer comes into a house someday and finds a mage dead and a thousand skeleton.
Speaker 0: Oh, so that so that leveled up my conjuration a whole bunch of times and as soon as you get ten points in any Combination of your major skills you get a real level.
Speaker 0: So I got like four or five real levels Holding down this button.
Speaker 0: So I didn't get any levels going on this epic quest to reform this ancient order of Knights designers take note Story alone.
Speaker 1: if you have a good story, you remember we did that money.
Speaker 1: It's not a game, but it could still be where we were like you can And a monetization model.
Speaker 1: you can't make them both in vacuums.
Speaker 1: games like this seem to do that But it's with game mechanics and I really want to get else.
Speaker 0: I really want to get a copy of the engine that they use to make these fallout 3 oblivion the Skyrim games and Make a game such that all you do is walk really fast because the walking is way too slow.
Speaker 0: At least they have fast travel and they give you a horse pretty early on whatever.
Speaker 0: But you don't have.
Speaker 0: there's no Fighting and the stat there's no stats.
Speaker 0: just remove all the stat parts So they don't even matter and it just be quest items Right and all the different actions you do are just all equal.
Speaker 0: or maybe just start completely maxed out.
Speaker 0: But I had nothing.
Speaker 0: none of the stats ever really matter in the game.
Speaker 0: It's just you're.
Speaker 0: you know The world and the story and has different places.
Speaker 1: it can because we've we've shown from you know, Mass Effect Dragon Age.
Speaker 1: people Actually do want what amount to really really complex.
Speaker 1: choose your own adventures and I see no reason for that to tag Person shooting RPG number thing.
Speaker 1: No, some people like the first person, you know, they like that.
Speaker 1: But the thing is these implementations suck balls.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's not the greatest I mean, it's basically.
Speaker 0: it's tolerable enough that it's worth it.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like if it was.
Speaker 0: if they didn't have that bullshit in there I would probably do every quest in the game.
Speaker 0: I would explore every nook and cranny right.
Speaker 0: but because I know like I'll walk by a Fort and it'll be like you have discovered the fort of the ancient blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: And it's like a part of me says who?
Speaker 0: what's in the fort of the agent?
Speaker 0: It's probably full of all kinds of goodies and mystic not nuts.
Speaker 0: I want to see what's in there.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll learn about some horrible ghost or tragedy that befell to something and it'll you know Knowing the writers who wrote the other part really well This part might be good too and I can even bring my knights with me in there to do a lot of fight.
Speaker 0: It'll be cool, right?
Speaker 0: But then I'm like, wait a minute I'm gonna go in there and I'm gonna have to sit through a bunch of FPS bullshit Dodging fireballs and whacking guys with swords and saving a lot and loading if I get killed and all that.
Speaker 0: and it's just like Yeah, I'm not going in there paying attention only to main quest ignoring side quests completely not worth my time So whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so move on.
Speaker 1: I bought a bunch of games But I can't.
Speaker 1: I looked at my list and I realized I do not know which ones I bought now versus before.
Speaker 1: you can look At your email from yeah, but the point was I cannot tell from my steam list alone.
Speaker 1: That is how little regard I put into what I bought.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I know I know for a fact.
Speaker 1: I acquired VVVVVV for legit.
Speaker 1: I probably bought a bundle or two to round out my list of bundle games.
Speaker 1: I've never installed But of the games I played a little bit of I played some sim city for well you bought that.
Speaker 0: Which was it?
Speaker 1: some piddly amount is a few dollars.
Speaker 0: How does it compare to sim city 2000?
Speaker 1: So I'm not sure yet.
Speaker 1: I played it for a while.
Speaker 0: It has like extra stuff right like garbage collection and 3d ness, right?
Speaker 0: More 3d ness.
Speaker 1: So here's the deal.
Speaker 1: playing it for a little bit It felt slightly dumbed down and it had this sort of weird Alternate game where you can zoom in to an individual person and check out their life.
Speaker 0: Oh like the Sims.
Speaker 1: yeah, and I don't know if it's actually a good or fun simulation game because I Stopped playing it after like 45 minutes.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not hard for us.
Speaker 0: Just play sim city 2000.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they kind of automated a lot of stuff like.
Speaker 0: and you know what sim city 2000 if you put it on cheetah mode in our computer.
Speaker 1: So it's the year 99 99.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like you do cheetah mode for a second.
Speaker 0: You're like, oops You know, you know how to get around it.
Speaker 1: keep the newspaper on that way the newspaper will stop you at the end of the month, yeah But it like here's one did one big difference because you can tell the last sim city I played was I think some city Three.
Speaker 0: I didn't play some city.
Speaker 1: I played it a little bit and I didn't like it.
Speaker 0: I never played it.
Speaker 1: But anyway you if you zone like industrial or residential or whatever the little side streets inside of there are Automatic and just kind of appear and scale.
Speaker 1: Oh, so you only have to make the real roads so only to make highways and One really big nice day if you build a school or a fire department It shows the radius of effect on the map as you're placing.
Speaker 0: Oh, so a lot of UI improvements.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of you're like.
Speaker 1: the UI still is.
Speaker 1: It reminds me of sieve - in that it's really low res and really really I thought it was 3d and cool.
Speaker 1: No, it's a pretty old game.
Speaker 0: actually See what would be cool is someone made a hack for sim city 2000 that added some of those nice tees like when you made a road.
Speaker 0: it would show how far the road reach.
Speaker 1: you know I could never play some city 2000 again.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: because some city to fill a screen with our colleagues and that's it the game.
Speaker 0: That's because your goal was to max out and sort of win.
Speaker 0: What you have to do is you get.
Speaker 0: your goal has to be to make a beautiful city.
Speaker 1: There wasn't enough granularity of simulation for that to be as I'm saying mods.
Speaker 0: Someone can mod it and add all sorts of more stuff minecraft.
Speaker 0: I guess yeah minecraft is that game right?
Speaker 0: make a beautiful city We'll see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some say for Scott came out in 2003.
Speaker 0: What is the remind you how goddamn what is the current sim city then?
Speaker 1: fuck if I know is there a newer one Or is that any series?
Speaker 1: This is what you know remember.
Speaker 1: when you know.
Speaker 1: remember like five years ago when we would Complain about old people talking about games there was a sim city on the iPhone, but it was basically Updated graphics a new game called sim city is Coming soon as in in 2013.
Speaker 0: Sim city there's but it's gonna be 50 bucks when it comes out.
Speaker 0: I'll wait for that in a steam sale for three dollars.
Speaker 1: There is Sim City Societies, which is not.
Speaker 0: that sounds like a spin-off and not the real deal, which is not what we would consider Sim City.
Speaker 1: It's about social energies and societal values at a Facebook game.
Speaker 1: No, there's that Sim City Facebook game, which if you play that I'm sorry, you're kind of stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a terrible.
Speaker 0: Well, there's also city Ville and a hundred other Ville's which are the same bullshit.
Speaker 0: There's also a civilization Facebook game Which is also.
Speaker 1: the problem with sim city 2000 is that it was a solved game if you went for these stated goals, right?
Speaker 1: Sim City 4 is the same thing except because I haven't played Sim City games in forever.
Speaker 1: I don't know the actual optimal solution.
Speaker 1: So I think it'll scratch more of the itch of what like civilization for but not civilization 5 was able to do.
Speaker 0: I think I would like to see a Sim City where not only is it just like you know commercial zone But it's like you have to build the specific things.
Speaker 1: Oh that but that's not how city planning works.
Speaker 1: that breaks from the metaphor Yeah, but it wouldn't.
Speaker 0: I don't want to play city planning.
Speaker 0: I want to play.
Speaker 0: city planning is the only thing I want to play.
Speaker 0: I want to play design the entire city.
Speaker 0: Yes, even as a we need a dry cleaner here.
Speaker 0: I we need a garbage.
Speaker 1: you're saying that you'd rather play bullshit fantasy.
Speaker 1: Here's my Taco Bell instead of I'm Robert Moses.
Speaker 0: Well, because the thing well, I mean the two different games, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Robert Moses is the only game.
Speaker 0: It'd be more like Legos.
Speaker 0: only one building is one Lego so Minecraft Sort of.
Speaker 0: but it's like it's already a building.
Speaker 0: So it's more about Arranging all these, you know thousands of different building pieces.
Speaker 1: But at that level the game basically becomes a macro version of sim tower.
Speaker 0: I like some just a shit game.
Speaker 0: I like the tower.
Speaker 1: I think we see where the divide is.
Speaker 0: You don't like some tower.
Speaker 1: I hated some time.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, it's the tower.
Speaker 0: It was Japanese Sim tower.
Speaker 0: It was a Japanese game called the tower and it was brought over and renamed and branded with the Sim tower.
Speaker 0: It's like when they put Carcassonne on games that are not Carcassonne.
Speaker 1: So I also bought Dragon Age, but we'll talk about that.
Speaker 0: I bought that too.
Speaker 0: It won't run first.
Speaker 0: This is the first time that I can say Oh Well, then Scott is the first Does not work.
Speaker 0: My computer has always worked.
Speaker 0: This is the first time it has ever not worked.
Speaker 1: What kind of process if you have core to do?
Speaker 0: Oh, it's not.
Speaker 0: No, that's not the reason it won't run.
Speaker 1: Ram do you have like four gigs or something?
Speaker 1: What kind of video card?
Speaker 0: It's a GTX 460.
Speaker 0: Wow the.
Speaker 0: It's not because it's not powerful enough.
Speaker 0: My computer is way more powerful enough to play this game.
Speaker 0: It's just like there's some glitch in the game.
Speaker 0: That's all over the steam forums.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah when I press play nothing happens.
Speaker 0: It just disappears.
Speaker 0: and I have this problem.
Speaker 0: and it's the first time that I ever have the problem as opposed to everyone else having The problem in my shadow around.
Speaker 1: just fine for me.
Speaker 1: So I don't know what you did wrong.
Speaker 0: It's finally fuck something.
Speaker 1: this is the first time ever clearly Ruined your computer sucks you.
Speaker 0: clearly there is something I'm doing wrong because it does work for a lot of other people But not me and not some other people on the scene.
Speaker 1: but anyway, whenever Scott man's up and fixes his computer then we'll talk about we're gonna play Dragon Age and I also bought amnesia the dark descent and you know what?
Speaker 1: It's pretty fun actually, but it does the To a degree that I almost wanted to stop playing.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 0: Can you turn it off?
Speaker 1: No Like you see a cool device with all these funnels and you look at it you're like, huh?
Speaker 1: I wonder if that does something.
Speaker 1: but if you look at it a few seconds later text appears That's like you don't have the four reagents to use this like, oh, I guess I gotta go find four reagents.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, this gave me a great idea.
Speaker 0: We should take the game.
Speaker 0: that is the.
Speaker 0: what game is the opposite of Mega Man Mega Man Ultima?
Speaker 1: No, are you kidding Ultima Quest of the Avatar?
Speaker 0: Yes, it is literal opposite One of the opposites.
Speaker 1: but the game I don't know Ultima Exodus is even more obtuse.
Speaker 0: that is true.
Speaker 0: But the game I was thinking of was missed.
Speaker 0: We should make a missed remix that has Mega Man Mega Man Mega Man.
Speaker 1: That would be hilarious.
Speaker 0: It would be hilarious, right?
Speaker 0: You go up to like, you know the sundial and it's like you do not have the Thingy to.
Speaker 0: you know, you need to set this to three o'clock at the whatever.
Speaker 1: what did you ever beat missed?
Speaker 1: No, how many hours did you spend playing it?
Speaker 0: I didn't even own it.
Speaker 0: I played at a friend's house for like an hour.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 0: All I did was walk around to all the places you could walk around to and click on all the things I solved randomly randomly to see what would happen and I never bothered to actually try to figure it out.
Speaker 0: my friend who owned the game had figured out quite a bit and was Actually using the journal in the back of the book to write down.
Speaker 0: I think he may have beaten it legitimately or and or Got a fact, I don't know.
Speaker 0: But yeah.
Speaker 1: But anyway enough talking about games that we don't know anything about because you know, we haven't paid attention to Sim City in ten years.
Speaker 1: It's time for things of the day and my thing of the day is something very simple is not much to it.
Speaker 1: You should watch it.
Speaker 1: not Space Marines, but space marine.
Speaker 0: Is that it?
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Space Marine.
Speaker 1: IR Space Marine.
Speaker 0: So there's this blog called Splitsider.com.
Speaker 0: I thought for a second you were gonna say Space Marine No, and Penny Arcade Report linked to them because they did this story Keeping score with Nick arcade.
Speaker 0: It is an in-depth Exploration of all that went into Nick arcade.
Speaker 0: It's really long and also fascinating.
Speaker 0: if you know what Nick arcade is Scott you probably do listening guys Omegathon finale.
Speaker 0: I've said that before.
Speaker 1: I know if it were actually a Nick arcade.
Speaker 1: I know that would be really anticlimactic actually watching it, but I think that would be the point.
Speaker 0: But yeah You got to read this article.
Speaker 0: if you know what Nick arcade is.
Speaker 0: and if you don't know what Nick arcade is Go find on the internet somewhere an episode of Nick arcade and then read this article.
Speaker 0: You only really need to watch one or two episodes.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, Nick arcade.
Speaker 1: Those kids were almost as dumb and the kids of as the kids on legend of the hidden temple.
Speaker 0: In the article is actually a video.
Speaker 0: they embedded a YouTube video.
Speaker 0: That is dumbest Nick arcade player I have seen.
Speaker 1: is that the girl who just doesn't go and get the thing and win exactly.
Speaker 1: Yep He's even like just go get the thing.
Speaker 0: You've got you're starting to run out of time.
Speaker 1: Just go get it.
Speaker 1: It's right there just up out of time.
Speaker 1: I guess you get poor kid.
Speaker 1: But anyway, those are things of the day.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment, we're going to be at pecs prime and pecs dev.
Speaker 1: At pecs prime we were doing a new triple threat called short subjects in gaming.
Speaker 0: on Friday We really need to cover the new title that people come to.
Speaker 1: Hey, a lot of people came to the triple threat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it wasn't full.
Speaker 1: It was a big room.
Speaker 1: It was mostly full.
Speaker 1: There weren't that many seats empty in the back.
Speaker 1: But anyway, Friday 3 30 p.m.
Speaker 1: Wolfman theater.
Speaker 1: We are doing a Competitive test of skill.
Speaker 1: We are doing when the game plays the player and we are doing on the ethics of mind control three 20-minute lectures.
Speaker 1: on Wednesday at pecs dev we are moderating Academia versus reality psychology game theory and games.
Speaker 1: It's myself Scott Lou Crane.
Speaker 1: you might know him from burning wheel and mouse garden such Jared Sorenson.
Speaker 1: You might know him from lacuna.
Speaker 1: I figured I'd name the game.
Speaker 1: No one knows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually castle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the action castle guy.
Speaker 1: I'm making quotes now.
Speaker 1: I'm making torches.
Speaker 1: Yeah Avery Alex a product manager for popcap games and Alex Avery, uh, so on LinkedIn, it's Alex.
Speaker 1: Avery Everything that he's ever written.
Speaker 1: He signs that Avery Alex with a comma.
Speaker 1: No, just Avery Alex All righty, so I guess that's and that's when I asked for his headshot to put on the pecs dev side.
Speaker 1: he specifically sent it as Avery Alex, so I put that up and He was you might recall Possibly to attend magfest last year as part of the gaming intellectuals.
Speaker 1: But he had to not attend due to some unrelated things.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna get to debate him on the things we didn't get to debate him on at magfest at pecs dev.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not the same topic.
Speaker 1: No, but everything we ever talked about gets to this topic in the end.
Speaker 1: Yes, exactly I think it's gonna be a pretty good discussion.
Speaker 0: It's like it doesn't matter what the actual, you know title of the the panel is.
Speaker 0: It's like what will be discussed game theory solipsism, you know Psychology, yeah all the same things.
Speaker 1: perhaps a Pareto frontier or three Some Colonel Blotto, but that is the Monte Carlo extent of the meta moment because There's no other conventions other than packs.
Speaker 0: The book club book extra doing a book club book this Thursday guarantee.
Speaker 0: This isn't like before.
Speaker 0: we said Guaranteed.
Speaker 0: this is for real guaranteed.
Speaker 0: QT 1984 Thursday.
Speaker 0: The next book club book.
Speaker 0: I just started reading is the man who was Thursday.
Speaker 1: You may remember it as being referenced more than once in deus ex.
Speaker 1: Okay, that was how I found.
Speaker 0: I bought it actually bought the penguin books edition.
Speaker 1: I bought a dollar 95 Kindle edition.
Speaker 0: the reason I bought this edition?
Speaker 0: I think it's actually public domain possibly right?
Speaker 0: But the reason I bought the penguin edition is Because a penguin classic always does a bunch of extra shit in it.
Speaker 1: You also might have thought back to when I bought the little prince and got that bootleg janky ass shit also.
Speaker 0: But the other reason is that the cover is so awesome on the penguin books edition.
Speaker 0: I wanted to know some small fraction of the money will go to whoever made that cover and they deserve it.
Speaker 0: Oh, and also it smells really good.
Speaker 0: They use really good paper on those.
Speaker 0: I think I was reading a lot of Kindle books lately and it's like you don't get any smell.
Speaker 1: You know, we need to invent a device.
Speaker 0: you stick on your candle and it spits up book smell.
Speaker 0: It has to smell and it comes with different book smells.
Speaker 0: It has used book new book and magic card magic card Nintendo cartridge.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, dude, we should make a video game and sell it and inject in the box Nintendo card.
Speaker 1: No, we should make a perfume that smells like Nintendo cartridge and sell that at conventions and make all the money.
Speaker 0: How do we we gotta have?
Speaker 0: I know this perfume companies that can make stuff smell like anything just like they can make anything Taste like anything.
Speaker 0: How do we hire those people and how much do they cost?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: We should add that to the hopper perhaps.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll put it in right now.
Speaker 1: Also magfest, you know forums in January.
Speaker 1: We got a forum or we got videos.
Speaker 1: You got twins.
Speaker 0: check out our things on the internet.
Speaker 0: I know a lot of people possibly just subscribe on iTunes and listen to us.
Speaker 0: If you're not listening now that I'm not talking to you obviously because it's not possible.
Speaker 0: But if you are listening to us You should go to our things on the internet that we have like our website and our whatnots because that is how it rolls Like our newsletter, which is pretty cool
Speaker 1: or a rockin forum, which right now there are 7004 comments in the my little pony thread.
Speaker 0: That's really gonna make people want to join.
Speaker 1: there are 5671 in the Republicans thread and that thread is currently the fastest rising.
Speaker 1: now We'll never talk about the forum like that again on the show.
Speaker 1: But if you subscribe to the geek nights newsletter that Scott has been putting together We do talk about the forum and all that meta crap that you people seem to love that.
Speaker 1: We always avoid on the show.
Speaker 0: Oh another thing about the newsletter is that you know a lot of other podcasts.
Speaker 0: they do stuff for like you email in and they'll Emails on the podcast and because we weren't ever really good about responding to them or making that a Permanent segment.
Speaker 0: We never really got a lot of emails asking us things or such.
Speaker 0: Right because people only really want to do it.
Speaker 0: as somebody who writes into things You know that you only do it because you want to hear your thing on the show.
Speaker 1: Well, we did get eight paragraphs and a YouTube video on the.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah from someone.
Speaker 0: we did but anyway So but in the newsletter.
Speaker 0: We are going to answer one thing in the newsletter from now on so You can send it.
Speaker 0: if you subscribe to the newsletter then you can send in questions and whatnot And then we'll answer them in the newsletter starting with the next one.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So we were at Nern NYC and our good friend as we started to tell whipped out this game And it had a really cute panda on the cover a precocious panda.
Speaker 1: It is called Taki Noko and I Or straight off the bat I'm gonna say that this is an equivalent game in terms of the way you can use it as a person who owns games and needs to present games for other people, you know to play as Zula Redo.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not just because it has animal no, but yes similar level of complexity Similar level of how difficult it is to teach how quick it is to play how easy it is to socialize while playing.
Speaker 0: Also, you know this while the theme is animals and that but that's not has anything to do with their similarity.
Speaker 0: But what is similar in the theme is the theme is accessible and friendly right which does matter if you got a new player Right.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: I mean looking bust out something like, you know, st.
Speaker 0: Petersburg.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay It's got this theme with old European dudes all over it.
Speaker 0: That's not enticing to someone who's never played.
Speaker 1: Yeah I was gonna say go to go to some of our friends to be like.
Speaker 1: you want to play a game that simulates the Plantation crop trade in Puerto Rico, right?
Speaker 1: or Panda game.
Speaker 0: you take the exact same game and you put zombies on it.
Speaker 0: suddenly people want to play because they're shallow and don't wow.
Speaker 1: You could just reskin.
Speaker 1: Takanoko is a zombie game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 0: pretty trivially you could reskin any game as any game trivially Some what game?
Speaker 0: what game can't I reskin can't reskin?
Speaker 1: All right, try to reskin Puerto Rico, all right as Tic-tac-toe.
Speaker 0: okay, so There's not enough things in tic-tac-toe.
Speaker 0: Tic-tac-toe is not really.
Speaker 0: if I chose the stupid example, that's not it.
Speaker 0: That's that's tic-tac-toe isn't really a theme It's more of a game right?
Speaker 0: You need to pick a theme.
Speaker 0: it like tic-tac-toe Theme it like tic-tac-toe.
Speaker 0: Okay, so there would just be I'd need more than X's and O's though I'd have to like, you know make like X's with an O around them and you know Like Puerto Rico.
Speaker 1: the theme of the game is Pretty deeply tied to the metaphor of the mechanics like the.
Speaker 1: it is a metaphor for the mechanics in a sense.
Speaker 0: Well, and yeah in some games that's more or less tied right and when it is really closely tied It's pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: Right when they're pulling like when a Dominion card the thing it does make sense considering what it is That's always on.
Speaker 1: but when it doesn't make sense, it literally just confuses players and causes you to cock up rules.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when it's like militia make the other guy discard two cards, it's like oh I get it The militia attacks the other guy's hand.
Speaker 0: it makes sense, right?
Speaker 0: But when it's like Chapel trash, you know zero to four cards.
Speaker 0: It's like what is chapel have to do?
Speaker 1: I'm confessing my sins and getting rid of them lightning my load, I guess but that's stretching it.
Speaker 0: you see It's more of a stretch.
Speaker 1: why would the militia attack my hand instead of my town?
Speaker 0: You don't have a town but you see how it's more of a stretch.
Speaker 1: yeah, I do.
Speaker 1: I have all these problems.
Speaker 0: Yes, he's the perfect one.
Speaker 0: That's not a step in a state.
Speaker 1: Why didn't they attack that?
Speaker 0: the moat, you know defends against attacks.
Speaker 0: perfect metaphor, right?
Speaker 0: It's a moat.
Speaker 0: It's a defensive structure.
Speaker 0: It defends against anything cuz it's a moat perfect.
Speaker 1: But how about how does it defend against the witches they fly?
Speaker 0: It just does.
Speaker 0: they don't like getting wet But they fly.
Speaker 0: they don't like getting wet.
Speaker 0: But if you have a moat you can splash them.
Speaker 1: So it should be moat and splasher.
Speaker 0: no, you're the splasher.
Speaker 1: But then how am I gonna manage my estate?
Speaker 1: I have a shit ton inside the castle.
Speaker 0: It's protected by the moat.
Speaker 1: Do you know how many estates I have?
Speaker 1: three?
Speaker 1: So Takei Noko is a pretty simple game.
Speaker 1: The story of the game is actually pretty cute, too.
Speaker 1: You've got this precocious panda Takei Noko and you might think wait a minute.
Speaker 1: These guys confuse China and Japan.
Speaker 1: cuz pandas are from China and Takei Noko is the Japanese name.
Speaker 1: That is what everyone who came up to the table to see what we were playing said when we told them what the game was Called.
Speaker 1: yep but no the story is the Emperor of China in a show of good faith gives the Emperor of Japan as a gift a precocious panda.
Speaker 0: But it was a trap gift.
Speaker 1: the Emperor of Japan doesn't know what to do So he gives it to the poor gardener and the gardener doesn't know what to do.
Speaker 1: and the guard.
Speaker 1: there's a little miniature of a panda and There's a miniature of the gardener.
Speaker 1: The gardener has this look on her face.
Speaker 1: Like what the fuck am I gonna do with this panda?
Speaker 0: I Don't know what the fuck I would do with a panda.
Speaker 1: play with it and feed it bamboo.
Speaker 0: apparently Where would I get enough bamboo for the panda?
Speaker 1: Apparently grows pretty easily.
Speaker 0: Where am I gonna grow it in your luscious Japanese garden?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know how much frickin bamboo you need to feed anyway.
Speaker 1: The metaphor of this game actually does not link too closely to the reality of the game mechanics.
Speaker 1: The game is a pretty abstract game of sort of pattern matching territory control with card objectives kind of like Take it to ride But you don't really control territories so much as try to construct a territory that will match While other people are trying to match on similar things.
Speaker 1: you can have momentary control by putting things on territories that augment them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like there's a shared space right?
Speaker 0: So in ticket to ride.
Speaker 0: It's like these are your trains.
Speaker 0: These are someone else's trains and you're trying to get your trains to meet your goals.
Speaker 0: in this game There's a shared space and everyone can modify that space in different ways.
Speaker 0: And you're trying to get these shared space to match your goals and everyone has goals.
Speaker 0: So you might inadvertently help it match someone else's goal.
Speaker 0: You might.
Speaker 0: you know someone else might do something that makes it not match your goal anymore and make it more difficult for you to make the space match your Goal, so you modify the shared space and you get cards and you need the space to Go in line with what your cards say and then you can play the cards to get points.
Speaker 1: So I should back up.
Speaker 1: you can't really control the territory so much as you can control access to the territory at a given time.
Speaker 1: There's actually for such a simple game to learn.
Speaker 1: there's a surprising number of mechanics when I think about trying to mention them all here.
Speaker 1: Basically, the pen.
Speaker 1: there's three ways to get victory points and you get them from these cards.
Speaker 1: one deck of cards has a series of configurations of colored tiles that can.
Speaker 1: that can basically constitute the board.
Speaker 1: There's pink ones and yellow ones and green ones.
Speaker 1: I think it's only three colors.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think so, too.
Speaker 1: so if If there's like two pinks in a row or three in a row or three in a circle and That's on the board at any time on your turn.
Speaker 1: You can reveal that.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I have that pattern.
Speaker 1: I get that many victory points, however many are on the card, right?
Speaker 0: But it's really easy to set these up because just the tiles isn't to be on the board.
Speaker 0: So you just choose the action for place tiles on the board and you really only need like a few tiles.
Speaker 0: So you can if you choose that action enough, it's easy to score on these cards very, you know quickly.
Speaker 0: But these cards aren't worth very many points.
Speaker 0: They're worth like two three four points based on their difficulty.
Speaker 0: But if you get enough of them quickly enough You could end the game because playing a number of cards is the game ending condition.
Speaker 0: So if you can get seven of these before other people have a chance to score big point cards You can win.
Speaker 0: so it is.
Speaker 0: it is a good strategy.
Speaker 1: So here so he the way to win the game is there.
Speaker 1: when a player has revealed Seven matching victory point cards that they have actually done they reveal them They've got them out.
Speaker 1: The game will end.
Speaker 1: every other player gets one final turn.
Speaker 1: You can only reveal cards on your turn But if you have more than seven revealed That's okay.
Speaker 1: So say Scott Reveals the seventh one and immediately ends the game.
Speaker 1: the game is I get a two-point bonus for being the guy who to first reveal And then we all get to take our turns say I already had six revealed and I have five more cards in My hand which is the hand limit that actually have matched.
Speaker 1: But I had not revealed yet because I didn't want to end the game on my turn.
Speaker 1: I can reveal all of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you have a hamlin.
Speaker 1: I now have 11.
Speaker 0: the hand limit is five.
Speaker 0: so you can have five cards in your hand have six on the table And then if you can somehow manage you get all five of those to do be scored at once.
Speaker 0: You just play them all at once.
Speaker 1: So my I won this game like handily but in the way I did it was pretty simple.
Speaker 1: I looked at the board and figured out how to get as many of these cards as possible.
Speaker 1: I didn't care how many points they were worth.
Speaker 1: I just wanted to match match match and I did that and then I held them all in my hand.
Speaker 1: I only revealed like one or two at a time.
Speaker 1: So I was on par with everyone else, but then one turn Every card in my hand was also matched and I could just end the game.
Speaker 1: So I just dropped all my cards and no one was even close to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I tried to get more of those cards, but there's also this die factor, right?
Speaker 0: So at the beginning of your turn you roll a die sort of like settlers And that die determines the weather and the weather pretty strongly influences your turn.
Speaker 0: if you roll they think the rain.
Speaker 0: If you're all the wind you can do the same action.
Speaker 1: Let's back up a little bit.
Speaker 1: So basically on your turn is simple.
Speaker 1: you take you roll the die and get a bonus action and then you take any two actions.
Speaker 1: you have a list of actions like Plant place some tiles on the board or draw a card any one you like or move the panda or move the farmer and then the die determines what your third special action is and they range from.
Speaker 1: Your two actions can be the same action.
Speaker 1: or get a third action or those are Right or get one of these modifiers to tiles that I don't care about exactly.
Speaker 0: if you roll the one that gives you three actions and the one that lets you double up on actions or the rent the one That lets you choose and then you can choose or the rain.
Speaker 1: The rain was really good.
Speaker 0: The rain is okay, but a lot of these other ones kind of suck depending, you know I'm sure somebody says oh no if you roll though, here's what you do, right?
Speaker 0: But you know, it's like I'm already going in a particular direction.
Speaker 0: You know, I don't know what my future rolls are gonna be.
Speaker 0: So if one person rolls, let's say theoretically the get three actions thing They're probably gonna win.
Speaker 1: if someone keeps no because you can't take the same action twice and there's a big return.
Speaker 0: You also have to roll the one.
Speaker 0: the thing is if you get three actions You can always use that third action to draw a card and still get two actions Unless your hand is full of things that you can't lay down.
Speaker 0: But if you're using two, the other two actions to fulfill the cards, you can lay them down Ah, but you're also helping everyone else out and actually But you don't know if you're helping anyone else out.
Speaker 0: You could be hurting other people.
Speaker 0: You don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 1: The way I won is I only did things that other players couldn't fuck with and that I could not help other players with.
Speaker 1: I got one because you know, there's three decks of the cards with these quests.
Speaker 1: One of them is basically configuration of the board.
Speaker 1: One of them is configuration of growth of bamboo on a particular tile Which is much more difficult to pull off.
Speaker 1: And then one of them is Some combination of bamboo that Takinoko has eaten.
Speaker 1: No one else was going for that.
Speaker 1: So I just went for that like a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: I went for that a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 1: So how come I had five cards with those points on them?
Speaker 1: And you had what one?
Speaker 0: because you I kept rolling the thing.
Speaker 0: that gives me the stupid modifier tokens And you often rolled the wind thingy that let you choose the take card action twice.
Speaker 0: I only rolled wind once in the game.
Speaker 0: I was not able to draw enough of those cards even though I wanted to see if you have those modifiers.
Speaker 1: You really should be going for the high point one cards instead of the panda cards.
Speaker 0: I also went for the high point cards But the thing is you can't play the modifiers unless it's on an empty tile completely empty.
Speaker 0: So I had these modifiers I couldn't use for anything.
Speaker 0: We're completely useless.
Speaker 0: So basically other people are getting bonuses on their turn by the luck of the die.
Speaker 1: The game is a little random in that regard.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's not perfect.
Speaker 0: It's slightly less random than settlers But it's similar in its randomness to settlers in that you're playing a game where you make a bunch of decisions But every turn you roll a die.
Speaker 0: that determines something.
Speaker 0: it determines a third action, right?
Speaker 1: But the mechanics are.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of like interesting things going on to make the game Not nearly as simple to play optimally as say zularetto.
Speaker 1: for one.
Speaker 1: There's the game of the odds of what different cards of people drawn or will they draw and will I give someone else victory points?
Speaker 1: And is someone else close to ending the game and all that stuff?
Speaker 1: There's also this mechanic of if you move the panda He'll then eat bamboo from wherever he ends up.
Speaker 1: if you move the farmer Then all the tiles of the same color as where he is that are adjacent to him The bamboo grows up and there's these cool pieces of stacking bamboo like on the board like these big stacks But both of them pieces
Speaker 0: in this game are really awesome in
Speaker 1: a straight line Which doesn't seem like it's that big of a deal but because of the way the board grows It actually is a huge deal.
Speaker 1: because in order to go for a particular strategy like I wanted one particular spot to grow bamboo And it was incredibly obvious.
Speaker 1: This is what I wanted to happen because it was so difficult.
Speaker 1: I had to take multiple actions to set it up to grow over there Meaning everyone knew I really wanted it to grow and just totally dick me on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like I sort of tried to pay attention to that.
Speaker 0: It was the first time but it's like I knew that someone wanted to put something somewhere and I was like Move the farmer to that spot.
Speaker 0: that way He can't.
Speaker 0: it can't move it in a straight line to the spot He wants to move it to and it won't be what he wants because he made it obvious to what he wants.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that's what happened.
Speaker 0: does Killing the other guy making him lose an action or lose points Taking him out of the game Whereas whenever I was my turn the panda and the farmer always happened to be in just the right spot for me?
Speaker 0: Uh to move them where I wanted to move them But I couldn't get enough cards to draw so I only could score, you know, so many points.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it mattered but basically that spot I was going for was the only card I ever held that I didn't play And I knew I wasn't going to get it.
Speaker 1: So whenever I had an extra action that I could not do anything useful with what I did is go for making that grow To convince everyone.
Speaker 1: at least I was hoping to think I really needed that and waste their action stopping me from achieving Whatever it was.
Speaker 1: they thought I was.
Speaker 0: yeah, that's another thing is I never did an action to screw anyone.
Speaker 0: That was not also an action to benefit me But you could by bluffing, you know, and depending on how many cards you've played already, you know to convince people that like you're ahead Or whatever.
Speaker 0: convince people to spend actions trying to hurt you and maybe they will hurt you or hurt your bluff or who knows what?
Speaker 0: Thus actually helping you by by hurting them But because they waste their actions now.
Speaker 1: that part is interesting because this game mechanically would be Incredibly simple like baby's first ticket to ride, but there's just enough mechanics interleaved with each other to actually give a surprising amount of strategic depth.
Speaker 1: despite the randomness and four skilled players playing this game It'll actually turn into a twilight struggle anticipation and card counting.
Speaker 1: game Like it really will become a game of bluffing and second guessing right because it's like rim I know in his hand.
Speaker 0: He has the hex cards, right?
Speaker 1: Yes, three.
Speaker 0: I have three of them and I can see on the board.
Speaker 0: I know what the possible hex cards are.
Speaker 0: It's usually three and a cook or three in a row and or four and a blob.
Speaker 0: So where I will make sure I will not draw any hex cards his hand has a limit on it.
Speaker 0: He can't play them unless he scores them.
Speaker 0: I'm going to choose the hex action.
Speaker 0: I'm going to put hexes down that I need of the right color to eat the panda or whatever But i'm going to put them in spots that make it impossible for any of those hex cards to score.
Speaker 0: Now what's rim gonna do with his handful of cards?
Speaker 0: He can't score.
Speaker 0: He's pretty much done.
Speaker 1: But maybe I was bluffing on that because I have three hex cards in my hand that are worthless And I have two high scoring ones that you're ignoring now
Speaker 0: Maybe but I have four high scoring ones and now I think I can score on four of mine and you'll only score.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe
Speaker 1: but I just got really lucky in one anyway
Speaker 0: It's possible
Speaker 1: now, I guess my point is just that the game Is more complex than you might think on the first play in that it'll have plenty of staying power even for skilled players, but It is not the main event.
Speaker 1: It's like zularetto.
Speaker 1: It's fun to play but I would play it as the warm-up before I played puerto rico or tigris new freddy's.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: The brain feel is not that strong.
Speaker 0: It does not engage the brain, but I think but what's great about it, right?
Speaker 0: Is that it has a lot more brain feel than you know.
Speaker 0: Your typical warm-up game like spotted but it only takes like 30 minutes.
Speaker 0: This game is fast.
Speaker 1: This game is faster than zularetto.
Speaker 0: It's yeah, it's way faster than zularetto or settlers and just as you know Has just as much going on but it's over like that which is totally awesome in terms of you know overall brain power It's not the highest on the charts, but in terms of brain Power to time it takes to play an entire game.
Speaker 0: The ratio may be the highest i've ever played ever Can you?
Speaker 1: that's?
Speaker 1: that's a tough one.
Speaker 1: I have to think on that.
Speaker 0: We could do a whole show on what game has more brain feel per minute Right.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah sure eclipse is awesome, but it takes forever, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's plenty of other war games.
Speaker 0: They also take forever.
Speaker 0: what game has you know, and this is not as it doesn't have as much as puerto rico But it has a line.
Speaker 1: it has as much as settlers battle line has a pretty intense Brain feel and is over pretty quickly, but I don't think it's quite on the ratio of this game.
Speaker 0: No, I don't think so either.
Speaker 1: i'll have to think on that.
Speaker 1: I feel like there's a show there something about What what we mean by brain feel because that's a term that me and scott have been using lately talking about games.
Speaker 0: You've been using it for the last five minutes.
Speaker 1: No, i've been using it for a few weeks now and i've been hearing it off and on.
Speaker 1: No one else uses that term talking about bar games.
Speaker 1: I feel like we might need to clarify what we mean by that.
Speaker 1: Pretty sure someone else has maybe but I think I think we could do a show on something like that.
Speaker 1: But anyway, takinoko is Equivalent to ticket to ride or zularetto in terms of hey, here's a pretty easy to teach game that we can play while we socialize As opposed to the silent game of puerto rico, but it's not a completely worthless game that you know.
Speaker 1: that has no intellectual component whatsoever and Simultaneously is not a light game like spot it which while spotted is very light mechanically.
Speaker 1: It wears the brain out.
Speaker 1: for one because of the type of test it is and two you can't actually socialize while playing spot it.
Speaker 0: This game is also short so you can socialize And then bail quickly as opposed to be, you know Even if it's a socializable game, you won't be evicted from the party because the game's over quickly and you're back partying exactly.
Speaker 1: So i'm probably gonna buy it.
Speaker 0: Why wouldn't you?
Speaker 1: Well, if you bought it I would not.
Speaker 1: why would you not?
Speaker 0: Because I don't want to.
Speaker 1: well then I won't buy it.
Speaker 1: So now we can't play it.
Speaker 1: Okay We'll say This has been geek nights with rim and scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music cat lee for web design and brando k for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech mondays gaming tuesdays anime comic wednesdays and indiscriminate thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.