Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, November 13th, Dateline November 1st, I'm Rym, I'm Scott, and this is Geek Nights Tonight, the Burning Con 2012.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Shows up a little bit late, Scott was too much of a wuss to bike through the hurricane to come over to the studio to do Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, listen, you know.
Speaker 0: I was out biking both those days, and running.
Speaker 1: Uh, listen, you have hair warming your head.
Speaker 0: There's things called hats, in fact it's Tuesday, Team Fortress 2 might have taught you about them if you didn't know otherwise.
Speaker 1: Do you own any hats?
Speaker 1: that also, that go underneath helmets in a safe fashion?
Speaker 0: They make a couple of different kinds of hats that do that.
Speaker 1: How much do those cost?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see, I went to REI.
Speaker 1: You could just not wear a helmet.
Speaker 1: And also EMS.
Speaker 0: Just put on a knit hat instead.
Speaker 1: And I was looking at the prices on equipment that would allow me to bike, see I don't want to bike in the snow, even though I looked into that too, you can get studded tires.
Speaker 0: No, it sucks.
Speaker 0: It sucks.
Speaker 0: It's not fun.
Speaker 0: Never, ever bike in the snow.
Speaker 1: If you had the right kind of bike.
Speaker 0: No, it's still not fun.
Speaker 0: I've had the right kind of bike.
Speaker 0: It's not fun.
Speaker 1: I don't want to bike in the rain or snow.
Speaker 1: I mean, for no other reason.
Speaker 1: At least I've biked a lot.
Speaker 0: You okay with sleet?
Speaker 1: In any sort of precipitation.
Speaker 0: Dark of night?
Speaker 1: Especially not hail.
Speaker 1: Uh, cause I have biked in the rain, and even though it's perfectly fine in a lot of ways, the mere fact, even if you have a fender, you're gonna get water spraying up on you.
Speaker 1: Oh no, you're gonna look like shit when you get wherever you're going.
Speaker 1: Alright, so whatever you're wearing is ruined if you have to bike in the rain.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I don't want to do that, but I thought, hey, I do want to bike no matter how cold it is, even if it's like below zero.
Speaker 0: So get a nice warm helmet.
Speaker 1: I should be able to bike if it is not raining or snowing or precipitating.
Speaker 0: You could just not wear a helmet.
Speaker 0: I often don't wear a helmet.
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: I went and I looked at the equipment, well, even if you don't wear a helmet, there's still the issue of, you know, the part of your body covered in coats will melt cause you're sweating in it and the part of your body that is exposed will freeze cause there's wind blowing
Speaker 0: on.
Speaker 0: You have a really terrible coat.
Speaker 1: You gotta go and get specialized coats that is made for this.
Speaker 0: All the stuff I use for skiing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I went to REI EMS and investigated the situation to see what kind of equipment I could get that would allow this sort of activity.
Speaker 1: And they had some of that equipment and that equipment was horrendously expensive.
Speaker 0: I don't recall it being that expensive.
Speaker 1: Oh, Mr.
Speaker 1: Vice President doesn't think a five hundred dollar coat is expensive.
Speaker 0: I spent three eighty on my jacket.
Speaker 1: That is more than hundreds.
Speaker 0: That ski jacket is going to last me another 15 hundreds now.
Speaker 1: And that's just the jacket we're talking about.
Speaker 0: We're not even started talking about a jacket that expensive for what you're doing.
Speaker 1: We're talking about the under clothes too.
Speaker 1: Well, remember, this is retail price in Manhattan.
Speaker 0: Get some like stupid Uniqlo Heat Tech T-shirts.
Speaker 0: They work great and they're like 15 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I was looking a lot of this stuff.
Speaker 1: And to buy enough to wear every day to go to work all the time would add up to many hundreds.
Speaker 0: Or you could just not care and show up to work looking like whatever.
Speaker 1: Or I could just not bike when it's fucking cold out.
Speaker 0: That sucks.
Speaker 1: It doesn't suck too bad.
Speaker 1: Anyway, no frostbite here.
Speaker 1: Pretty good.
Speaker 0: The only time pretty good.
Speaker 0: Almost got frostbite when I was hiking out in the woods and the blizzard got lost, fell through a creek and my boot broke.
Speaker 1: I'm scoring 100 percent on the no frostbite scale.
Speaker 0: OK, but I did go biking yesterday.
Speaker 0: But anyway, this episode is a little bit late.
Speaker 0: As I said, Dateline November 1st.
Speaker 0: But we missed Tuesday's show due to various reasons we just discussed.
Speaker 0: So this isn't actually going up for all a week and a half from when we're recording this.
Speaker 1: Oh, well.
Speaker 0: So Tuesday, I heard a game came out, heard a couple of games came out.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: After waiting for over a decade, perhaps.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Longer than longer than the Team Fortress 2.
Speaker 0: I waited longer for Team Fortress 2.
Speaker 1: Well, we haven't really, you know, I've been waiting so long because this one is, you know, unlike, say, Duke Nukem Forever, Duke Nukem Forever, it would be like there'd be some screenshots and there'd be nothing.
Speaker 1: There'd be E3, there'd be nothing.
Speaker 1: And then it kept coming and disappearing, coming and disappearing and appearing and reappearing and then disappearing for long periods of time.
Speaker 1: This game has appeared and stayed, appeared without disappearing, you know, with with relatively frequent, you know, news updates and no black holes or mysteries for about a decade.
Speaker 1: And now it is out.
Speaker 0: I have the fancy black armor because I gave them forty dollars.
Speaker 1: It is 100 percent out natural selection, too.
Speaker 1: And actually, I haven't played it in months.
Speaker 0: Neither have I.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I want to.
Speaker 1: But I'm busy on other things.
Speaker 0: I haven't even played Counter-Strike.
Speaker 1: Me either.
Speaker 0: I wonder why.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about it in weeks.
Speaker 0: We'll talk in the meta why that is.
Speaker 0: But yeah, we haven't played NS2.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: Every time I played it had been a market improvement.
Speaker 0: over the previous time I'd played it.
Speaker 1: Now it has like mechs and shit.
Speaker 1: And wow, man, it's off the hook.
Speaker 1: It was several months ago and apparently all kinds of network issues are fixed.
Speaker 0: It reached the point where it was actually at that point more fun than the original NS, which took a while to get to.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Well, it was.
Speaker 1: it was equal ish, different but equal ish.
Speaker 0: Yeah, different.
Speaker 0: But it was more fun to play, partly just because a lot more people.
Speaker 0: It was easier to get a game going.
Speaker 0: There's other factors there.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'd still be playing weapons factory, but you know what?
Speaker 0: There's no goddamn way to play weapons factory, except with nut jobs who were so much better than me.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't even matter.
Speaker 0: Be like if chess were a forgotten art and I wanted to play.
Speaker 1: Well, only the hardcore crazy dude, if everyone else, if everyone else on Earth forgot chess, but me, I could be the best because I'd still remember the rules and I played it more times.
Speaker 0: And that might not actually be to your advantage.
Speaker 0: And to you and I should play Bobby Fischer chess because that eliminates all opening study as a factor.
Speaker 0: You know, Bobby Fischer chess, that's how you know what it's in that book.
Speaker 0: that wouldn't matter what you should be.
Speaker 1: that wouldn't matter to me because I've never learned any of the chess openings.
Speaker 0: I have learned three to a reasonable degree.
Speaker 0: I am partial to the Polish opening, but everyone good I've ever played with told me I'm stupid for using it and I don't understand it well enough to understand why.
Speaker 0: But yeah, do you know what Bobby Fischer chess is?
Speaker 1: It's something where you shuffle up all the pieces.
Speaker 0: No, you shuffle the back row only.
Speaker 0: So that row is just randomized and equivalent on both sides.
Speaker 1: Well, shuffling up the front row wouldn't really do much.
Speaker 0: But you can shuffle up everything.
Speaker 0: So maybe there's a pawn in the back.
Speaker 1: We kind of I'd like that, but then upon would not be able to do shit if it was caught behind the scenes, can barely do shit in the front.
Speaker 0: I've also realized that most people I've known in my life, like everyone who's a gamer, seems to know the rules of chess and that they know how the pieces move.
Speaker 0: But I'm starting to realize that most people I know don't actually know all the rules of chess.
Speaker 0: They cannot describe how castling works, nor have they ever heard of all.
Speaker 1: If they're OK, so castling is when the rook and the the king, right, are sort of don't have anything in between them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: In which case, then you move the rook two spaces to the right and then you move the king to the other side of the rook, like jumps over him.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Here's the trick.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: That's all the castle is.
Speaker 0: Can you castle if the rook had moved out of that position and later returned to it?
Speaker 1: I have no idea, but I will guess no.
Speaker 0: So more important, not more important because it never happens, but more crazy.
Speaker 1: Can you castle if the king moved out of the position to move back into it?
Speaker 0: I'm looking up because I actually remember.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But the thing is, castling never comes up among.
Speaker 0: it's weird.
Speaker 1: Like, do you really do pros ever castle?
Speaker 0: So from what I gather, yes.
Speaker 0: What I've noticed and I read an article about this, really inexperienced players castle way more often than anyone, because if they know about the rule existing, you got to try it.
Speaker 0: They go for it because it seems cool.
Speaker 1: Of course, wouldn't you?
Speaker 1: That's the reason that you buy all the weird buildings in Calus.
Speaker 0: But en passant is the rule that I think most people who play chess in the world have never heard of.
Speaker 1: Isn't that the one where like all the pawns are lined up against each other so you can kill the pawn in a weird way?
Speaker 0: It has to do with the fact that way back in the day, you know, there's no original rules of chess, really, but basically there was no move upon two spaces at the beginning of the game rule.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So the game took longer.
Speaker 0: So eventually this was kind of a house rule where you could say, all right, you can move upon forward twice.
Speaker 0: But again, around the fact that that could actually change the game.
Speaker 0: If upon moved to and there was another pawn like in front of it, it can move at an angle to where the pawn would have been if that rule weren't in place and capture it like that instead of landing directly on it.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: I don't think that comes up much in professional play, if at all.
Speaker 1: I don't know anything about really professional chess.
Speaker 1: Oh, I don't know the opening.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty shit at chess, partly because I studied those openings, but I don't really play.
Speaker 1: I recall like the few very few times you played chess.
Speaker 1: I've actually won despite not knowing anything except the rules and how to move guys.
Speaker 0: Ah, castling is important goal in early parts of chess, according to Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so another game is to do you shave.
Speaker 1: You really haven't bought it already.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the hell is wrong with you or what podcast you've been listening to.
Speaker 1: But really, we're talking.
Speaker 1: if you're the kind of person who is dying in Counter-Strike all the time, maybe you don't like it.
Speaker 1: I mean, really, you know, and sometimes you're not in the Counter-Strike mood.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you need something a little different.
Speaker 1: You should really have Counter-Strike go and NS2 and that will pretty much satisfy all of your multiplayer team based FPS needs for the rest of your life.
Speaker 0: There was a time in my life when I would play Counter-Strike until I was sick of it and then I would just immediately play NS until I was sick of it.
Speaker 1: And go back to Counter-Strike.
Speaker 1: Pretty much.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So just have those two games.
Speaker 1: If you have any two games on Steam, have those two.
Speaker 1: And really, dude, I mean, you could almost argue you don't need any other games except maybe Super Metroid and Mega Man 2.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you don't really need FTL, but it's good.
Speaker 0: I need FTL.
Speaker 0: I really like FTL.
Speaker 0: I look forward to some sort of expansion or versus version.
Speaker 1: Well, let's just say this a year from now, FTL play not going to get so many hours a year from now.
Speaker 1: And as to in Counter-Strike, still going to get clicked on.
Speaker 0: But they're different classes of game entirely.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying these games have their own like these are.
Speaker 1: these are life games.
Speaker 1: These aren't those games where you buy them, play them and put them away.
Speaker 1: These are life games.
Speaker 1: There's only two of them.
Speaker 1: One of them just came out.
Speaker 1: This is a big deal.
Speaker 0: Castling is permissible if and only if the following conditions still hold.
Speaker 0: Here we go.
Speaker 0: One, the king has not previously moved up to the chosen rock has not previously moved up.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, that's that.
Speaker 0: I guess so.
Speaker 1: I guessed right.
Speaker 0: Three, there are no pieces between the king and the chosen rock for the king is not currently in check.
Speaker 0: Five, the king does not pass through a square that is under attack.
Speaker 1: You can't do it when you're in check.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Oh, but that's like the best time when you'd want to do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's bullshit.
Speaker 0: The king does not pass through a square that is under attack by enemy pieces.
Speaker 0: Six, the king does not end up in does not pass through a square that is under attack.
Speaker 1: So if one of the spaces between the king and the rook could be hit by, say, a knight, you can't castle.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's.
Speaker 0: that's very similar to the opposite rule that it prevents you from.
Speaker 0: you know, you get this extra move to speed up the game.
Speaker 1: But what are these rules of chess?
Speaker 1: I didn't know that are bullshit.
Speaker 0: Six, the king does not end up in check, which I guess is a rule.
Speaker 1: That would be funny if you did that.
Speaker 1: You're fucking stupid.
Speaker 1: OK, go seven.
Speaker 0: The king and the chosen rook are on the same rank.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: So you can.
Speaker 1: What do you mean on the same rank?
Speaker 0: The row.
Speaker 1: So you can actually move them both forward and then do it.
Speaker 1: I don't understand that part, because then they would have moved, which would have invalidated the first thing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I mean, you can only do it in the back row from their starting positions when neither of them have moved.
Speaker 1: So how could they not be on the same rank?
Speaker 1: I don't know, actually, that's a really that's a redundant rule.
Speaker 0: Here's a handbook.
Speaker 1: A handbook all about just castling, and that's it?
Speaker 0: I will continue to investigate this later, because the point I was making wasn't that I'm so smart and everyone else doesn't know chess.
Speaker 1: Well, you're clearly not that smart if you had to read Wikipedia to know this.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying that you're no smarter than me.
Speaker 0: Gamer nerds, I found, don't actually know chess.
Speaker 0: that well.
Speaker 0: And it's not.
Speaker 0: chess is not popular among gamers.
Speaker 0: And people who like chess do not like other games.
Speaker 1: It's because there is a chess community and in fact, the Go community sort of also to some extent doesn't cross over with the rest of the gaming community.
Speaker 1: It's like the gaming community is super inclusive.
Speaker 1: We'll have you chess people, we'll have you go people, but they don't want us.
Speaker 1: They don't want to hang out with us.
Speaker 1: Puerto Rico players and us, you know, power grid players, they just want to stay all by themselves like their game is its own thing.
Speaker 1: And I guess by having their game be its own thing, does it make them feel so how their game is above all other?
Speaker 0: So this is a roundabout way of once again recommending Richard Garfield's book because he talks about that and he equates chess to Counter-Strike in this regard.
Speaker 0: And he makes some very good points.
Speaker 0: I finished chapter one.
Speaker 1: I'm in chapter two.
Speaker 1: I read the whole section about heuristics just recently.
Speaker 0: Isn't that the directional heuristics versus positional heuristics?
Speaker 1: No, just how gamers use heuristics and how nubs can't really figure out any, you know, especially in a game.
Speaker 1: No one gives a bad.
Speaker 0: So we have terms for this, but basically his terms are a directional heuristic is a heuristic you have that tells you or helps you decide what move to make.
Speaker 1: That's the ones I use most often.
Speaker 0: And a positional heuristic tells you who's winning.
Speaker 0: That's the part that everyone who plays games with me fucks up.
Speaker 0: They think that because they're in the front in Mario Kart, that they're somehow in first place.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The directional heuristic is in power grid when I'm counting how much money I can bid on power plant.
Speaker 1: How much I have to save for the reason.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, the positional heuristic is, well, am I going to be in first or last and who's actually winning?
Speaker 0: Watch out for rim.
Speaker 1: Watch out for him.
Speaker 1: That's the only one you need.
Speaker 0: So many of our friends were from games.
Speaker 0: And, you know, we talked about this before, but Guns of Icarus online actually finally came out.
Speaker 1: Why so many games come out?
Speaker 1: Who has money or time?
Speaker 0: And I've been working from home all week because of the hurricane.
Speaker 0: So I've been playing a bunch of these games.
Speaker 0: I got to say, I played Guns of Icarus a bunch during the beta.
Speaker 0: It was pretty fun.
Speaker 0: It's like to imagine two on two like ships versus and your man and guns and run around like each team.
Speaker 0: It's ship has a captain and you can target.
Speaker 1: But there's no boarding.
Speaker 1: You can't board the other.
Speaker 0: Wait, I heard there was going to be boarding.
Speaker 1: No, there's not.
Speaker 0: In fact, I heard I heard a very, very credible rumor that there will, in fact, be boarding and Guns of Icarus online.
Speaker 0: I have a reliable source to be that hard is Emily's yelling.
Speaker 0: Fuck you from the other room.
Speaker 1: I don't know why it wouldn't be that hard to do would I think?
Speaker 0: I know why.
Speaker 1: Do you know why you got to work?
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: It's so easy.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: All you got to do.
Speaker 1: I mean, every FPS in the world, you jump from one platform to another.
Speaker 1: This ship is a no.
Speaker 0: It's not the game part of it.
Speaker 0: That's the problem.
Speaker 1: Ship is a platform.
Speaker 1: You jump now.
Speaker 1: You just press spacebar.
Speaker 1: He jumps.
Speaker 1: If there's another ship under your feet when you land, then you are.
Speaker 0: Have you ever written anything?
Speaker 0: Have you ever done anything in unity?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: So it's highly likely that player entities are tied to ship entities or something like that or two teams.
Speaker 0: So they're not independent objects that can interact completely independently.
Speaker 1: It's not just a floating platform.
Speaker 1: No, because it sounds like somebody didn't think about that in the beginning or they did.
Speaker 0: I would make a secondary argument that from a play perspective, how many games do you play that at a first person perspective in melee combat?
Speaker 1: Who says has to be melee combat?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So I jump onto the enemy ship and there's a dude there.
Speaker 1: We can shoot him.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 1: In a world, the most basic thing in a first person shooter, you have a gun and you're pointing at someone and you go bang, the simplest possible thing.
Speaker 0: But it's a world where not everybody has these handheld guns.
Speaker 0: As far as I can tell, the only guns are giant ship mounted guns.
Speaker 1: Maybe they should.
Speaker 1: It's not that hard to add a handgun to an FPS.
Speaker 1: That is the most baby FPS tutorial thing to do.
Speaker 0: But it messes up the kind of rhythm of the game because that is a serious problem.
Speaker 0: Think about what happens.
Speaker 1: That is a very serious problem.
Speaker 1: One guy's on your ship.
Speaker 1: You're trying to fly it.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, he's really good at FPS.
Speaker 1: No, I mean, it goes around your ship killing you all the time.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: I was ready.
Speaker 1: You respawn on this flying boat.
Speaker 1: Do you respawn on it?
Speaker 1: So I was going to just steal your boat.
Speaker 1: Can he pile?
Speaker 1: Can he use the guns on your boat to shoot at your, you know, in disguise to shoot at the friendly boat?
Speaker 1: Them thinking it's a friend, but really it's a bad guy got on there and killed everybody from boarding.
Speaker 1: So what this basically comes down to is we did that lecture and then there'll be no reason to use the big boats because someone would just steal them with their skills and jump off the tiny boat and just board the big.
Speaker 0: So, Scott, maybe you get around that by doing a Team Fortress 2 thing and gimping the FPS part, but then it's not nearly as fun as people like.
Speaker 1: there is a huge game, completely broken flaw if you allow the boarding.
Speaker 0: So what I'm getting at is that we talked about that concept of like in mega, mega, mega factory, mega TF or weapons factory, how one asshole who's just better at head clicking than everyone else literally can dominate an entire team.
Speaker 1: Indeed.
Speaker 0: So you're going to get to a chapter that talks about the same thing.
Speaker 0: It's like factors of play.
Speaker 0: So like if I'm playing Puerto Rico, actually, he used some other game as an example.
Speaker 0: Hearts was the example.
Speaker 0: He's like one.
Speaker 0: If I use zero factors or zero heuristics, I'm playing randomly, if I use one heuristic paying attention to how many hearts are in my hand, suddenly I have a much higher chance of winning.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: Say I use another additional heuristic paying attention to whether or not the Queen of Spades have been played yet.
Speaker 0: That's another huge advantage for relatively little effort.
Speaker 0: Let's say now also I use a third one.
Speaker 0: I also keep track of the king and ace of spades.
Speaker 0: Not as much of a return, not as common to pay out, but gives me a higher chance of winning, just less of one.
Speaker 1: Well, I pay attention to them if I fucking have them.
Speaker 1: So get rid of their asses.
Speaker 0: So as you keep applying, what if I start counting cards like count the number of hearts played by anyone, count the number of points taken by anyone.
Speaker 0: Every factor I add, every like thing or skill I use takes additional effort and gives me an additional chance of winning.
Speaker 0: But there is a diminishing return.
Speaker 1: What if you're playing hearts and you have the queen, king and ace of spades all in your hand all at once?
Speaker 0: Ah, usually if that's the case, it depends.
Speaker 0: Do I have any other spades in my hand?
Speaker 1: Well, the only really hope you have is if you can get rid of another suit very quickly and then play all three of those.
Speaker 0: See, this is we think we think about hearts on very different levels.
Speaker 0: I have two questions in that situation.
Speaker 0: One, do I have three questions?
Speaker 0: One, do I have any other spades?
Speaker 0: And if so, how many?
Speaker 0: Two, is the person I am giving cards to an idiot or not?
Speaker 0: And three, am I low on a suit that is not spades or hearts?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're low on a suit that's not spades, you can just play.
Speaker 1: You can just empty your hand of that suit and then hope someone else plays that suit, allowing you to dump all there.
Speaker 0: Now, I would not do that if I had the queen and a small number of spades.
Speaker 1: Well, you only really need to not have the ace in the game.
Speaker 1: You only need to dump the queen.
Speaker 1: You can dump the other ones later.
Speaker 0: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: The thing is, if I have the queen having the ace is great and the king is great.
Speaker 0: You know why?
Speaker 0: Shooting moons?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: I rarely shoot the moon.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying it'd be really easy to shoot the moon because, you know, when you play the queen, there's no chance of someone else being forced to take it by, you know, having the king or ace be the only card remaining in their hand.
Speaker 0: I would disagree because usually I don't shoot the moon that early.
Speaker 0: By the time it's at the point where someone gives me the queen, it's usually not apparent that I'm shooting the moon yet.
Speaker 0: It just looks like I'm sucking.
Speaker 0: But no, it's because if I have the king and the ace or at least one of them and someone else is trying to force me to queen myself by playing low spades, I can take the trick with the ace or king, maybe take a hard if I'm forced to, and then
Speaker 1: switch it up to something
Speaker 0: and leave with something else and delay the inevitable fucking that I'm about
Speaker 1: to get.
Speaker 1: But you're only delaying the inevitable.
Speaker 1: You're going to get 13 points.
Speaker 0: Well, this comes down to an interesting quirk of game theory among a wide spread of players.
Speaker 0: Stuff like that works really well.
Speaker 0: If I just play perfectly optimally and conservatively, there's a chance other people will fuck up and I'm very likely to win.
Speaker 1: I always play hard.
Speaker 1: It's 100 percent conservative.
Speaker 0: If four skilled players play hard conservatively, it's random.
Speaker 0: So instead, you can only augment your chance of winning by playing aggressively.
Speaker 1: The original point with the boarding was simply that this is another case of the counter strike.
Speaker 1: Everyone says remove the AWP.
Speaker 1: Everyone says add boarding.
Speaker 1: Don't do it.
Speaker 1: You'll mess the game up like tribes do.
Speaker 0: Yo, dogs, game design, wah, complicated deaths.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So in gaming, as you all know, especially people who played games with me before, I'm a huge fan of the trash talking.
Speaker 0: No, I mean, back at RIT, we used to always do the trash talk Mario Tennis Tournament where you were obligated to trash talk the other team while you played and you were graded on your trash talking independently of the tennis match
Speaker 1: is one that is the best trash talk.
Speaker 0: Trash talking is also a difficult subject because, for example, that is the poo noise.
Speaker 0: Some people enjoy trash, the noise of victory.
Speaker 0: But if there is someone who can't deal with trash talk in your group and they want to play a game, if you trash talk, don't be friends with them, you make them feel bad.
Speaker 1: Don't be friends with them.
Speaker 0: If you don't trash talk them, you make them feel equally bad.
Speaker 0: But anyway, this is a video of what can happen.
Speaker 0: You see, there are two important kinds of trash talk backed up and not backed up or pre hoc and post.
Speaker 1: Those are the same kind.
Speaker 0: I am a fan of the post hoc trash talk that is rims.
Speaker 0: I will be very quiet during the game until my victory is assured.
Speaker 0: And the more likely it is that I'm going to win, the more I ramp it the fuck up.
Speaker 1: See, I'm the pre hoc nature.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And that is the pre hoc.
Speaker 1: See, I view post hoc trash talk is sort of invalid trash talk.
Speaker 1: It's like you've already won and now you're talking shit.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're so brave to talk shit after you.
Speaker 1: It's like you beat your ass and you beat a guy up.
Speaker 1: He's bleeding on the floor and then you start talking.
Speaker 1: It's like what kind of what kind of pussy are you?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: A real man, someone who is, you know, and I don't mean the gender man and just mean someone who is who is brave and awesome at gaming will trash talk and hype themselves up before the challenge.
Speaker 1: That is to say, I'm about to kick your ass.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can take you.
Speaker 0: See, here's the problem.
Speaker 0: You use the pre hoc too much.
Speaker 1: So when you because if sometimes I go in sometimes I go in with the pre hoc and say, bring it, and then they bring it and I get my ass kicked.
Speaker 0: See, if I trash talk after the fact and I lost, well, that just means I'm stupid.
Speaker 0: But if I trash talk before and I lose, I have lost doubly, which is why my pre hoc trash talk is very rare.
Speaker 0: But when I bring it, usually all I do is I just do the Babe Ruth point right before the game.
Speaker 1: See, the thing is, I win more often than not.
Speaker 1: So except that's not true pre hoc talking like the pre hoc talking I just did one sentence.
Speaker 0: I will be I'm Babe Ruth thing.
Speaker 0: I will beat you in the next competitive ortho game that you and I play together.
Speaker 1: Whoever's name is Scott wins.
Speaker 0: I didn't agree to play that game.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: I won.
Speaker 0: I will win the next ortho game that you and I play.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: Did you get to the part of the book where he says what an ortho game is?
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: Chapter one.
Speaker 1: I told you.
Speaker 0: I forget where that is.
Speaker 0: It was a while ago when I read it.
Speaker 1: So how does this trash talk discussion relate to a video from a fight as in people punching each other and it won't do which fighting sport is it?
Speaker 1: Is it boxing?
Speaker 1: Is it punk craze?
Speaker 1: Is it what is it?
Speaker 0: It's boxing esque.
Speaker 0: OK, but basically one dude is way cocky and the other guy punches him a whole bunch and he basically just doesn't even defend himself and walks over like, what, what, what?
Speaker 0: Bring it, bring it.
Speaker 0: And the other guy brings it.
Speaker 0: And that's the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: it's a beautiful thing.
Speaker 0: To behold.
Speaker 0: And it has the tags, ouch, fail, fights, fighting and cocky.
Speaker 1: OK, so check this out.
Speaker 1: There's a game coming out called Apotheon or Apotheon or whatever.
Speaker 1: And this game, from all intents and purposes in the video that you look at here, seems to be a completely average platforming combat ish kind of game where you jump and throw spears and block things with a shield and that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Not too much exciting is going on here.
Speaker 1: 2D platformer.
Speaker 1: It seems like it's going to be on Steam on Windows and then maybe other platforms later, whatever.
Speaker 1: But the stylings, the visual aesthetic stylings of this game are looking like one of my favorite stylings, the ancient Greek stylings that you love, nothing more than depictions of old Greek men.
Speaker 1: There are things I love more, but I love this a lot.
Speaker 1: So it looks like, you know, your dude has like the shield with the snake on it, the big circle shield.
Speaker 1: He throws a spear.
Speaker 1: Everything's orange and black and white.
Speaker 1: And you have those little sort of square spiral things going on on the borders of the terrain.
Speaker 1: And you fight like, you know, it's pretty much like you're looking in the in the Greek history section of the museum and it's come to life.
Speaker 1: And that's the video game.
Speaker 1: So this video is pretty much all you need from this game, since it looks to be a pretty boring game, you don't need to actually play.
Speaker 1: Maybe it'll be really cheap on Steam one day, but because it's pretty tight, if you like that sort of game.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah.
Speaker 1: But because the styling is so good, the video promoting the game is thing of the day worthy and hence it is my thing.
Speaker 0: It looks exactly like the art on the sides of Amphora.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: My favorite kind.
Speaker 0: You mean carrots?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I wonder if anyone will get that.
Speaker 1: Nobody will get that.
Speaker 0: So in the meta moment, the book club book is still the name of the win by Patrick Rothfuss.
Speaker 0: I'm most of the way through it.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 0: But the only complaint I have is that it was just rocking through scenes and drama and everything really great.
Speaker 0: I have one on one kind of complicated complaint that I'm going to say for the book club show.
Speaker 0: But he's been in the school for a long time and the school isn't short.
Speaker 1: How long were you in school?
Speaker 0: But the school, the school boy drama is just the same bullshit.
Speaker 0: The jackass guy keeps being a jackass.
Speaker 1: How long were you in school for?
Speaker 0: Well, the wizard school, five years.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So how many years has he been in the wizard school?
Speaker 0: I don't need every detail.
Speaker 1: How how many years have you been reading this book?
Speaker 0: I'm just saying that's a lot less than it takes.
Speaker 0: I don't think most of what happened to him in school is all that important.
Speaker 1: Well, finish the book and then we'll do an episode and we can discuss this again.
Speaker 0: I mean, I get it.
Speaker 0: He's the Kellis Mary Sue Golden Child of the world, the smartest, that's the best person that's ever born.
Speaker 1: But isn't that the book I always say I want to read?
Speaker 0: Well, now you get it.
Speaker 1: We always end up reading a book about like, you know, freakin who?
Speaker 0: Kellis?
Speaker 1: Kind of.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But how come we don't get to read a book about Seswatha?
Speaker 0: We're going to get to, I think.
Speaker 1: Or Kelmomas.
Speaker 0: In fact, I think things are repeating and you get the same story told again.
Speaker 0: Maybe that book's coming out soon.
Speaker 1: And how come, you know, we get this story about like, oh, Sauron, right.
Speaker 1: But if you want the real story, you got to read the Silmarillion, which is not as boring as far as only because it was a mishmash of a whole bunch of shit.
Speaker 1: We could have gotten the real story of, you know, the nine kings and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we didn't get that thing.
Speaker 0: Is that plays out like.
Speaker 0: instead we get a story like the same burning wheel game you play, except everyone's white instead of black.
Speaker 1: So instead we get a story about like, yeah, those kings.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, here's some statues of them.
Speaker 1: It's like, no, tell me the story about the king who was so awesome that they made a giant statue of him pointing.
Speaker 1: King.
Speaker 1: That's who I want to hear about.
Speaker 1: I don't want to hear about some fucking hobbits.
Speaker 0: King Awesome did a W seven wound to the beast as opposed to a B seven wound.
Speaker 1: I love that shit.
Speaker 1: Hook me up where who tell me?
Speaker 1: anyone who reads a lot of fantasy novels.
Speaker 1: Alex, where is the?
Speaker 1: where is the fantasy novel that is about the great?
Speaker 1: I guess Earthsea is about the great wizard, right, of all time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even in Earthsea, there was a past, you know, time that is alluded to where dragons were all over the fuck.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Where is the story about the time when dragons were just all over the fuck?
Speaker 0: Hopefully we'll get a flashback to Star Swirl.
Speaker 1: And like there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And there weren't any amazing castles yet.
Speaker 1: because guess what?
Speaker 1: The great king built the fucking castle.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: You're going to be real disappointed when that king built the castle upon the ruins of the even greater, older castle.
Speaker 1: No, I want to hear the story of the greatest, oldest castle.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: It's castles all the way down.
Speaker 1: It's not castles all the way down.
Speaker 1: There is a pre castle era.
Speaker 0: Are you giving me some castle trash talk?
Speaker 1: In which case it was not a castle, but a hut.
Speaker 0: You're going pre castle now or a, you know, a mead hall.
Speaker 1: So, uh, magfest, we're going, we're going to, that's a while from now.
Speaker 0: We're probably going to be doing a revamped version of losing should be fun.
Speaker 0: And we will probably be on one or two of the gaming intellectuals things.
Speaker 0: We're still working on the details.
Speaker 0: Uh, I guess anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Whoa.
Speaker 1: Future.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Connecticut.
Speaker 1: PAX East, PAX OSS.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: And PAX OSS is sold out of three day badges.
Speaker 0: So if you didn't buy them, that's a shame.
Speaker 0: You've learned your lesson.
Speaker 0: Now, I hope about not buying a PAX badge the day it goes on sale.
Speaker 1: It's a shame.
Speaker 0: We'll probably be there unless something bad happens.
Speaker 1: And I'm very, very likely to be there.
Speaker 0: And I want to put it on the record that we have suggested perhaps the best possible names for the theaters that they could have down there.
Speaker 0: I think they should just take the names of the theaters from regular packs, append them with the right poisonous.
Speaker 1: I heard from a very extremely reliable source.
Speaker 1: There will only be three theaters at PAX OSS.
Speaker 0: I had a list that said there'll be a total of 80 panels.
Speaker 1: Possibly.
Speaker 0: That sounds about right.
Speaker 0: Based on, you know, we had 300 Kineticon across 11 rooms.
Speaker 1: So, all right.
Speaker 1: Let's uh, Oh, I think we had enough meta here.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Uh, let's move on to our show show.
Speaker 0: So before we do the show show, so, you know, burning, burning count is pretty great, but I would like to point out that a long time ago we may or may not have told this anecdote, but it is very relevant to what we're about to do.
Speaker 0: So I feel like it must be repeated.
Speaker 1: Repeating the anecdote.
Speaker 0: We knew a guy.
Speaker 1: Let it be written.
Speaker 0: We knew a guy at RIT.
Speaker 1: Do you remember his name?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: I remember his first and last name.
Speaker 0: And I remember the last time I saw him.
Speaker 1: Are his initials
Speaker 1: A.W.?
Speaker 1: ?
Speaker 0: They are indeed.
Speaker 1: And when was the last time you saw him?
Speaker 0: When he was working at Pita Pit.
Speaker 1: We have seen him at the same time as last time.
Speaker 0: So, uh, he's a dude.
Speaker 0: I won't get into anything else about him because it's not really about him.
Speaker 1: It's about all of us.
Speaker 1: It's not about him at all.
Speaker 0: This is a story for all men of all times.
Speaker 1: Do you want to tell the story entirely on your own or shall we share in the telling?
Speaker 0: So I'll just get right to the point.
Speaker 0: One day, dude comes up to me very early.
Speaker 1: We only met this guy a few times at this point.
Speaker 0: And we were talking about Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 1: Who doesn't at nerd school?
Speaker 0: Yeah, because we're playing Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 0: With Dammit Dwayne, which I think is his legal name.
Speaker 0: So it is now we're playing D&D, talking about D&D.
Speaker 1: We're actually at Anime Club talking about D&D.
Speaker 0: So the AW comes over and he's like, ah, I play D&D as well.
Speaker 1: Ah, don't we all.
Speaker 1: It's nerd school.
Speaker 0: Now, we were talking about when we were going to play the next game or something, some like meta detail.
Speaker 0: He goes right in with, let me tell you about my character.
Speaker 0: He's a 17th level barbarian named Thag.
Speaker 0: It's funny because it sounds like fag.
Speaker 1: Alrighty.
Speaker 0: This went on.
Speaker 0: Oh, did this go on?
Speaker 1: It went on far too long.
Speaker 1: I don't know why other people stood standing there.
Speaker 1: I sort of meandered and slinked away with the back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I think at that point I drew aggro.
Speaker 1: But because he was loud, I still heard most of the details.
Speaker 0: So I got to hear all about that.
Speaker 1: I had forgotten as many as I could.
Speaker 1: There was something about the weapon he uses was particularly gay.
Speaker 0: So I got to hear all about Thag and his somewhat, I don't know, bigoted adventures through the Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 1: Extremely bigoted adventures.
Speaker 1: I would also like to point out, perhaps this is relevant, perhaps it is not.
Speaker 1: A.W.
Speaker 1: may be the biggest Sailor Moon fan I've ever known.
Speaker 0: Uh, no.
Speaker 0: No?
Speaker 0: Hoagie Steve.
Speaker 1: Was he, he really liked it more?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think he liked it more.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: He was also a stand up dude.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, nothing wrong with Hoagie Steve.
Speaker 0: I will stand by Hoagie Steve and his legacy.
Speaker 1: Hoagie Steve is totally awesome.
Speaker 1: Much more awesome than A.W.
Speaker 1: with his bigoted D&D characters.
Speaker 0: If any of you who are there are listening and feel bad, don't feel bad.
Speaker 1: Uh, no.
Speaker 0: So the moral here is simple.
Speaker 0: Nobody wants to hear about your D&D character.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: Even if you both play Dungeons and Dragons, even if Dungeons and Dragons is the only thing either of you care about.
Speaker 0: If you're not in the campaign together, no one cares.
Speaker 1: Right now, there are things that you can discuss about D&D with other people or any RPG you can discuss, you know, general ideas, you know, the mechanics, rules, you know, you can even tell interesting stories.
Speaker 1: Don't tell about the character, but you can tell the story.
Speaker 1: For example, here is a story example.
Speaker 1: The one I like to tell so often from summer camp.
Speaker 1: You know, the GM had created, you know, by hand this big ass dungeon with an evil wizard in it on the top and a castle on top of a cliff like Castlevania and shit.
Speaker 0: Notice Scott has not told me the name or level of a character so far.
Speaker 1: No, I have not.
Speaker 1: We were all to be fun and because we were middle school kids, really high power leveled guys, right?
Speaker 1: One of our players was a druid.
Speaker 1: He cast Summon Big Ass Monster.
Speaker 1: He could and he selected from the monster's manual of second edition the earthworm, which proceeded to eat the ground from under the castle and it fell into the sea, thus making it completely unnecessary to go through the dungeon, meet the evil wizard or anything of the such.
Speaker 1: The GM probably should have captured someone to be in distress that we had to rescue from the castle so that wouldn't have happened or not, but the castle on a cliff.
Speaker 1: And that is a funny story.
Speaker 0: Lessons were learned all around.
Speaker 1: Right now.
Speaker 0: Allow me to tell a story and I'm going to tell it in the incorrect way.
Speaker 0: Oh, so I was playing Elaeth Redere.
Speaker 0: He was a 16th level blade singer.
Speaker 1: This is all true.
Speaker 1: people just want to let everyone know.
Speaker 1: I can verify for one hundred percent that everything he's telling you in this story is true.
Speaker 1: in that rim did play this character.
Speaker 0: Now, I converted him from second head to third head and he got a lot less powerful in third head because the way they changed the rules.
Speaker 0: But in second head, he had up to four or five attacks per round, depending on the no one cares.
Speaker 1: You're not going to get going.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not going to keep going.
Speaker 1: But don't you really?
Speaker 1: But see, I just want to verify one thing.
Speaker 1: While we agreed, no one wants to hear that and no one cares.
Speaker 1: Do you or do you not enjoy telling those things?
Speaker 0: It feels real good.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: And this is why people do not learn this lesson, because everyone loves to tell you about their character.
Speaker 1: No one likes listening to anyone else.
Speaker 1: So here talk about their character.
Speaker 0: It is possible to talk about your characters if you tell what is actually an amusing anecdote.
Speaker 0: So mechanical details like if I'm telling Luke Crane, the creator of Burning Wheel, about something crazy that happened in my game.
Speaker 0: If I say like OBS 10, eight dice success, the mechanical details actually will be relevant and interesting to him in the context of the story.
Speaker 0: For most other people in the world, that is not true.
Speaker 0: If you cannot gauge whether or not your audience cares about what level your barbarian was, you should probably leave that detail out and get to the meaty part, like when he killed the dude.
Speaker 1: So with that being said, we both went to Burning Con where we did nothing but play our tabletop RPGs for a weekend.
Speaker 1: Let us tell you about the games we played when.
Speaker 1: there is one great exception to this rule.
Speaker 1: And that is you can say whatever you want if you have a podcast.
Speaker 1: And there's another great exception to this rule.
Speaker 1: If you don't like listening to us talk about it, just turn this podcast the fuck off.
Speaker 1: In fact, why are you even listening to this podcast?
Speaker 1: What is wrong with you?
Speaker 1: Don't you have something better to do?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So Burning Con is the third Burning Con.
Speaker 1: It was the Triad Umbert featuring the games of Luke Crane, Vince Baker and John Harper.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: So, of course, when you go to Burning Con, you must run a session.
Speaker 1: And there are a total of five sessions.
Speaker 1: Despite hurricanes, all of the sessions happened.
Speaker 1: And I played in four sessions and ran the final session.
Speaker 0: I did the same.
Speaker 1: And it was like you ran the first session and played four sessions after.
Speaker 0: But I played the same number of games.
Speaker 0: I had the same basic experience in a slightly different order.
Speaker 1: So let us briefly discuss the sessions that we have played.
Speaker 0: Let's start with the one that we both did, because that actually was pretty great.
Speaker 1: OK, so this is run by our friend Matt from NerdNYC.
Speaker 1: And it's kind of funny because I knew Matt.
Speaker 1: I saw that he was there.
Speaker 1: I knew him from NerdNYC.
Speaker 1: He's an acquaintance.
Speaker 1: He's a good guy.
Speaker 0: He had played in my game just before.
Speaker 1: And I was looking at the schedule and I saw this Burning Wheel game about dwarves.
Speaker 1: And I said, I'll play a Burning Wheel game about dwarves.
Speaker 1: Who's Matt?
Speaker 1: something?
Speaker 1: I didn't know his last name.
Speaker 1: I go over to the table.
Speaker 1: I see Matt sitting there.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, oh, yeah, OK, it's the same guy.
Speaker 1: This is what I get for not learning people's last names.
Speaker 1: But then knowing him, I'm like, I know he plays the RPGs, but I've never RPG'd with Matt.
Speaker 1: I wonder if he is any good.
Speaker 1: And in fact, he was very good.
Speaker 0: Well, I think his game was very nice is what I'm glad.
Speaker 0: One of the most important things about Burning Con is that they had a very strict rule about no hacks, no bullshit.
Speaker 0: I changed the rules of Burning Wheel because I do have hacks.
Speaker 1: It just says parentheses hack.
Speaker 1: So a lot of games said parentheses hack.
Speaker 0: So what?
Speaker 0: to to be allowed to run a hack of one of the games, you had to submit all the weird rules and everything possible about your quote hack to the people running the convention for review.
Speaker 0: And they had full veto power.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: If you did not do this, they offered dire consequences.
Speaker 1: Burning Con is a curated convention.
Speaker 1: They beat the three.
Speaker 1: You know, the triad Umbritt will decide which games will be run when.
Speaker 1: So we played in Matt's game, which was not a hack at all.
Speaker 1: It was Burning Wheel with dwarves.
Speaker 0: Burning Wheel is pretty damn good.
Speaker 0: The strength of Burning Wheel, the best convention scenarios are the very straightforward ones, usually involving dwarves.
Speaker 1: That's why I played in five great games.
Speaker 1: And I blame that on always choosing the straightforward Burning Wheel game most of the time.
Speaker 1: So his game was pretty much about these dwarves.
Speaker 1: And the deal was there were two dwarven castles and two complete asshole dwarven princes, two dwarven princes, one dwarf assholes.
Speaker 0: That's very important.
Speaker 1: One dwarven prince had been there for a long time.
Speaker 1: The other one had only appeared recently and they were both competing to dig up precious things from the same mountain range in different mountains.
Speaker 0: It was versus Dwarf Fortress.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: To see, you know, which one their father would approve of more than the other.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: When we were selecting characters, I actually did something that I usually do not do.
Speaker 1: Usually I choose, rim can tell what kind of character I will choose.
Speaker 0: Scott usually wants to choose either the guy who's not related to the game at all.
Speaker 1: That's a good one.
Speaker 0: Or he wants to choose like usually like the standoffish thief or the guy who's like the super powerful in his particular little realm, like support character.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: I like merchants.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, something like that.
Speaker 1: I want to choose like when he played Inheritance, who did I choose?
Speaker 1: The dwarven mystical guy with the magic rings.
Speaker 1: The magic rings.
Speaker 1: The off to the side guy.
Speaker 1: But this time I said, you know what?
Speaker 1: I'm going to choose the number one guy.
Speaker 1: Give me the dwarven prince.
Speaker 1: I demanded it.
Speaker 0: So and I received it was not an asshole when the character she was handed to Scott.
Speaker 1: Yes, it was.
Speaker 0: Well, yes.
Speaker 0: Yes, it was.
Speaker 0: The moment you touched it, he became perhaps the second greatest asshole in that game.
Speaker 1: There's nothing on that character sheet that said nice guy on it.
Speaker 0: There was nothing on it.
Speaker 0: Do you have the trait asshole?
Speaker 1: It was they had the trait of greedy.
Speaker 0: I also had the trait of greedy.
Speaker 1: OK, I had not only the trait, but also the emotional attribute of greed.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: All my beliefs were all about digging up as much shit as possible.
Speaker 0: So this broke down pretty well.
Speaker 0: I was Scotty.
Speaker 0: I was like the super engineer, like I managed all the mining and all the bullshit.
Speaker 1: That is what you were in.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I kind of played that kind of guy, which I usually actually like playing a guy like that.
Speaker 0: But it was a kind of an aside because usually I play the big bad like leader type.
Speaker 0: So Scott played the asshole and I played the engineer.
Speaker 0: And of course, bullshit goes down in the mine.
Speaker 0: A bunch of dwarves disappear.
Speaker 1: Well, there were two other players.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: They were playing whatever.
Speaker 1: Actually, they were really good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: One of them was the.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to remember what their dwarves did.
Speaker 0: It was only a few days ago.
Speaker 1: Scott, I know.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: So we had the advisor, the smart guy.
Speaker 1: No, the advisor was the was an NPC.
Speaker 1: The seneschal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, basically one of the characters ended up effectively being the advisor to Scott.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: And the story is pretty simple.
Speaker 0: The mines, some bullshit happens, bunch of dwarves disappear.
Speaker 0: So he goes to investigate and it turns out there's a huge spider army and a spider princess.
Speaker 0: Nobody would roll seduction.
Speaker 0: I was actually really pissed off about that.
Speaker 0: You should have.
Speaker 0: And we wanted to wait.
Speaker 0: Well, no.
Speaker 0: Scott wanted to kill all the spiders.
Speaker 1: I didn't want to kill the spiders.
Speaker 1: I wanted to safely extract all of the riches from the mountain, which would not have been possible with a spider presence.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So he basically wants to get the spiders out of the way and get all these gems and rubies and whatever.
Speaker 0: The other dude wants to negotiate with the spiders because they actually seem pretty chill.
Speaker 1: I was willing to allow negotiations to occur.
Speaker 1: But I did not have faith that they would be successful.
Speaker 0: It took a deeds point in a duel of wits to convince you to let us do this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is very important because you see, when everything fell apart and the shit hit the fan, all Scott did was turn to the character who made this happen and say, this is your deeds point.
Speaker 0: You wanted this.
Speaker 0: This is what you wanted.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: So the spiders wanted a sacrifice of a dwarven prince because we owed them some debt.
Speaker 0: So, of course, immediately all of us underling dwarves are like, Scott's really an asshole.
Speaker 0: Let's just sacrifice him to these spiders and then make an alliance with them.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 0: So Scott tries to instead sacrifice his worthless brother.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: I was perfectly willing to help.
Speaker 0: And when I asked you to just fund me for the ability to do it.
Speaker 1: Wait, you asked for unlimited funds.
Speaker 1: You were a traitor as you were willing to turn against, you know, and throw away your dwarven loyalty and your dwarven oath in or in for money against.
Speaker 0: You were asking me to turn those ballista around at the true prince of the land.
Speaker 0: No, I just sacrifice him to a spider when I was perfectly willing to sacrifice you instead.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And that is why I tried to slay the eye for your disloyalty and dishonor.
Speaker 0: Like a gold piece.
Speaker 0: I would have been like, OK, you said unlimited funds.
Speaker 1: If you had asked for like, you know, 10 gold or something, we could have maybe gotten to negotiations.
Speaker 1: But you could have had since your demand was so extreme.
Speaker 0: I offered a suggestion.
Speaker 1: that was like walking into a discussion with a crazy creationist.
Speaker 0: I was even going to you were golden gems and your counteroffer was cold, hard acts to my neck.
Speaker 1: And did that act strike true?
Speaker 0: No, because you suck at axes.
Speaker 0: And I ran into the castle and barricaded against you and proceeded to try to murder you and everyone around you.
Speaker 1: And who turned out the winner at the end of the day?
Speaker 0: So basically, fuck you.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: It wasn't so bad because one, you see, here's how much asshole Scott is.
Speaker 0: So he tries to kill or steal his worthless brother and sell him to spiders anyway.
Speaker 0: He fails at it due to incompetence.
Speaker 0: He comes back dice.
Speaker 1: I failed that to do a dice.
Speaker 0: So meanwhile, these two dwarven princes are fighting.
Speaker 0: The rest of us go to the spiders.
Speaker 0: Well, I tell you what, Daddy, two dwarven princes.
Speaker 0: That's what you did and didn't go so well because Scott sucks and stuff went wrong.
Speaker 1: I got the dice turned to my favorite.
Speaker 0: So finally, basically he murders me, imprisons my wife, murders in cold blood the spider princess and both of her innocent retainers.
Speaker 1: Innocent spiders trying to eat me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, based on a deal your granddaddy made with the spiders.
Speaker 1: Yeah, nothing to do with me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, dwarven blood and all.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: So he does that.
Speaker 0: And thus he has no real army or way to defend the fortress.
Speaker 0: And then the spiders come in the night.
Speaker 1: It's moving to my dead brother's fortress, which is a castle and not just a fort.
Speaker 0: The denim was kind of sad.
Speaker 0: I think you guys survived, but it wasn't great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I survived.
Speaker 0: I just I take issue with your.
Speaker 0: A tactical decision to murder the head of both your artillery and your mining operations the mere hours before the spiders were going to invade.
Speaker 1: You were just upset because that was you.
Speaker 1: If it was not you, those being murdered, you probably wouldn't have felt bad about it at all.
Speaker 0: It was a pretty great example.
Speaker 1: If the Senate shawl had been a player character and that was you and the engineer was an MPC and I wanted to kill the engineer, you would not have given two shits.
Speaker 0: I like how the Senate was like, no, but I'm a reasonable man.
Speaker 1: The Senate was the greatest because I had this.
Speaker 1: I had this instinct.
Speaker 1: He betrayed whoever.
Speaker 1: There's the MPC, the Senate shawl, who was like the old wise dwarf to ask for advice.
Speaker 1: I had an instinct to always ask him for advice.
Speaker 1: So I always did.
Speaker 1: And he and then Matt always did good.
Speaker 1: Matt always came in like, oh, I'm the old dwarf and you should do this.
Speaker 1: When you were like, I said, and whenever he said I did, I was like, yes, I'll do that.
Speaker 0: You were like, I'm going to betray my brother and feed him to the spiders.
Speaker 0: And the Senate shawl was like, that seems like the most wise course of action.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So in fact, you can blame some of my jerky actions on the advice of the GM who told me exactly what to do.
Speaker 1: So that was a good game.
Speaker 0: It was a great game.
Speaker 0: I got to tell you, if you ever need to run a short, like four hour one off burning wheel game, you cannot go wrong with just burning up four dwarves and giving them beliefs.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: What are the games you play?
Speaker 1: And I played in this game.
Speaker 1: The first game I played in was with Rachel.
Speaker 1: Hey, Rachel, are you listening?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe Rachel's totally awesome.
Speaker 0: Rachel is pretty badass.
Speaker 0: I played in several games with her.
Speaker 1: Her game was like, you know, I had first priority in that slot.
Speaker 1: And I'm thankful because that is the game people were piling on because people know.
Speaker 1: And Rachel, she like, you know, I prepared by burning up characters.
Speaker 1: Rachel fucking prepares.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: She had little stand ups, little faces and little name thingies that little, you know, tense for each character.
Speaker 1: And she had like little she had a little stack of paper with a bunch of like people's photographs printed on them.
Speaker 1: And whenever a new character, NPC came into the game, she'd write their name on the paper and lay it on the table so that you could remember all the different characters that were going around.
Speaker 1: And oh, man, she she's got the shit going on.
Speaker 0: Actually, you know, I did my games.
Speaker 0: I'm going to do it from now on forever.
Speaker 0: I brought sticky name tags that I wrote the names of the characters on.
Speaker 0: I didn't put them on the people because that doesn't work.
Speaker 0: I taped into the table in front of each player.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: She did the same thing with the tents, with the pictures, though.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: She really prepared.
Speaker 0: So I didn't have pictures.
Speaker 1: The game we played, she called it the wreck.
Speaker 1: And basically the idea was it was a prison ship and it was going to a prison colony.
Speaker 1: And we were all thieves that had been caught.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And we were in the prison ship.
Speaker 1: But then the ship crashes on the shore.
Speaker 1: It's on the same island as the colony, but it's not at the colony.
Speaker 1: It's like around the other side of the island.
Speaker 1: So, of course, we're mostly free except for some shackles.
Speaker 1: Most of everyone else is dead except for the PCs, a couple of NPCs and like the captain.
Speaker 1: And then shit goes down and shit went down pretty well.
Speaker 1: And it was sort of weird.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm playing.
Speaker 1: And I sort of felt like I was coasting along, you know, getting fair amount of spotlight time.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, I was feeling good about what I was doing, but I really felt, you know, you know, I wasn't the main person.
Speaker 1: I was.
Speaker 1: I was sort of, you know, maybe secondary.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But the plot got in a really good way.
Speaker 1: You know, we managed to get some disguises and get, you know, trick people into thinking that we weren't prisoners and then going into town and taking care of all the NPCs who might have wanted to send us to the prison colony.
Speaker 1: And sort of set up a new life of, you know, thievery and thieves guildishness on this island.
Speaker 1: That was sort of a brand new colony, you know, and things actually turned out pretty well for us.
Speaker 1: But, you know, there were not a lack of conflicts along the way, meeting strangers in the woods.
Speaker 0: Whoa, wait, wait, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Conflicts and a burning wheel game.
Speaker 1: No, you know, he was.
Speaker 1: he was overall a most excellent game.
Speaker 1: It didn't really have any of those too many killer, crazy, exciting moments like trying to kill him.
Speaker 1: But great moments, nonetheless, like tricking the guy in the woods and the thinking that one of us was the captain and just stabbing the captain in the fucking neck.
Speaker 1: Shit like that, you know, good stuff.
Speaker 0: So the first game I played after the dwarf game was a peak role playing experience for me.
Speaker 0: It was actually one of the greatest role playing experiences I've ever had in my life.
Speaker 0: So the first actual burning wheel I ever played, you know, when the scary loot crane wasn't that wasn't just a demo.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So this loot crane motherfucker tricked me into playing this demo and then he tricked me in playing this other demo and then it was on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the first real burning wheel game I played was that Ubercon.
Speaker 0: Scott was there.
Speaker 1: Was there an episode about this?
Speaker 0: There might be, but it was inheritance.
Speaker 0: It was a larvish burning wheel scenario for a whole shit ton of people.
Speaker 1: It's about a Viking funeral.
Speaker 0: So he's been keeping this in his head and mulling over for a long time.
Speaker 0: And he ran it and he's run it several times in this format.
Speaker 0: He ran it at burning con for nine people as a straight larp, no dice, and he changed himself.
Speaker 0: He got rid of the dwarf.
Speaker 0: This magic runes.
Speaker 1: No, it's the most important guy.
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 1: No, I think actually merging.
Speaker 1: I mean, I love the dwarven runes guy, but merging the role of the dwarven runes guy with the Christian priest guy really streamlines it.
Speaker 1: That is an excellent move.
Speaker 0: So you could tell this was big because despite having nine player slots and being the last slot on Saturday, I was the only number two priority person in the game and everyone else was priority one.
Speaker 0: I only got my slot because I got there first and because I had the GoPro.
Speaker 0: So I think they kind of wanted that to get my GoPro.
Speaker 1: You got in with.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think so.
Speaker 1: Got in with my camera.
Speaker 1: So what if I should not brought it?
Speaker 0: So here's the deal.
Speaker 0: I had mine with me, too.
Speaker 0: I just didn't set it up.
Speaker 0: So here's the deal with this game.
Speaker 0: He talked a bit about, you know, we talked a bit about those sort of hardcore Danish role playing games and the room had a big table in it in these areas.
Speaker 0: And he used these very interesting rules.
Speaker 0: The only rules were body language and envelopes weren't allowed to open.
Speaker 0: So the way it worked was you just walked around, you're in the big house and, you know, like a Viking house.
Speaker 0: And I think the year eleven hundred or something.
Speaker 0: And if you are in a conversation, you have to stand like in the circle of the conversation with your name tag visible.
Speaker 0: If you are eavesdropping on a conversation, you stand a little bit back and hold your hand over your name tag.
Speaker 0: No one can engage you, but you cannot interact with the scene at all.
Speaker 1: Oh, but eavesdropped.
Speaker 1: But you can always enter the scene by taking your hand off.
Speaker 1: No, no.
Speaker 0: If you are eavesdropping, you cannot enter as your next scene, the scene on which you are eavesdropping, which is actually I don't want to get in all the details of why, but watching it play out is a brilliant rule that this game would not work without that rule.
Speaker 1: That is a clever rule.
Speaker 0: So the other rule is if you are in a scene and it is a confrontational or adversarial thing, you stand shoulder to shoulder angled slightly inward with the people you are allied with, sort of encircling the person you are against.
Speaker 1: So anyone looking at the scene, just glancing even can see very obviously, even if they're in another scene and not eavesdropping, they can still see the other scenes and how they are constructed.
Speaker 0: They can see who is outnumbered or like who's confronting who.
Speaker 0: Even more importantly, all information learned while eavesdropping officially can be used openly.
Speaker 0: Your character knows it.
Speaker 1: So there are three and no one can catch you eavesdropping, prevent you from dropping.
Speaker 0: And there are three areas outside the house, in the private rooms of the house and in the great hall in the middle.
Speaker 0: So if you're in the great hall, everyone in the great hall is all together all the time.
Speaker 0: You walk around the great hall and can interact.
Speaker 0: And it's the story of the prodigal son returning.
Speaker 0: The Viking grandfather has died.
Speaker 0: They're burning his body in the traditional way.
Speaker 1: All the sons have returned.
Speaker 1: Which one will inherit, you know, inheritance?
Speaker 1: Which one will inherit?
Speaker 0: So the two families are there.
Speaker 0: The one son is a worthless, coward, baby loser.
Speaker 1: One's the badass, awesome, real Viking guy, right?
Speaker 0: So the other son.
Speaker 1: And one's the Christian guy.
Speaker 0: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: So the other, you don't remember this.
Speaker 1: They changed it.
Speaker 0: No, you just don't remember.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So the other son actually wasn't there because he was exiled for murdering his fucking brother.
Speaker 0: He was exiled by the father himself from the family.
Speaker 0: So the exiled son returns on the night of the grandfather's funeral to claim his inheritance.
Speaker 0: I played the former Varangian guard, strong man who shows up with him to make sure the family doesn't just murder him outright bodyguard.
Speaker 0: I played the bodyguard.
Speaker 1: I mean, when we played inheritance in the burning wheel fashion many years ago, the bodyguard was actually one of the more not exciting characters.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: So he was updated a little bit.
Speaker 1: And it's like.
Speaker 1: his only purpose is a mechanical purpose, which was to prevent the prodigal son from being a meat.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the character, she'd said when the person played the thug before, because he was still a thug.
Speaker 0: He is a consummate badass in every.
Speaker 1: But now he has the purpose of his own in addition to just protecting the prince from death.
Speaker 0: Sort of I kind of.
Speaker 0: I don't know what he might have had that in the game we played and the guy just didn't really play it up.
Speaker 0: But basically I was worldly.
Speaker 0: I'd been around.
Speaker 0: I'm a badass.
Speaker 0: And I wanted to marry a girl who my friend wanted to marry.
Speaker 0: And simultaneously I wanted my friend, you know, the exiled prodigal son, to claim the inheritance because he's my friend and I'll also be rich.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to skip a whole bunch of details.
Speaker 0: What happened?
Speaker 0: And I can safely say that I won this game.
Speaker 0: That ended with everyone dead.
Speaker 1: I like how we always say you can't win our winning and losing.
Speaker 0: Everyone came up to me and they were like, wow, you won.
Speaker 1: And I won in a game where there's no inheritance.
Speaker 0: Yes, I got the inheritance from both families and I got to marry the girl.
Speaker 0: I had an army.
Speaker 0: I had everything.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, there's no winning in RPGs, but if that's true, that's about as close to winning as you can get.
Speaker 0: If it was the game we played before, it meant I had all the gold, everything in the will.
Speaker 0: I married the girl.
Speaker 0: Every enemy was dead and the priest.
Speaker 0: Now, the best part of this is I didn't kill anyone.
Speaker 0: They all killed each other.
Speaker 0: All I did was stand.
Speaker 0: There's this moment the whole time.
Speaker 0: Luke Crane keeps coming up to me and whispering in my ear.
Speaker 0: He's like, Rem, you've got to make your move.
Speaker 0: You're going to lose it.
Speaker 0: You're not you're not being active enough.
Speaker 0: You're you're going to lose it.
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 0: Be you know, do something.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, no, no, I got this.
Speaker 0: Shut up.
Speaker 0: And yeah, I had that.
Speaker 0: I basically just told everyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you talk to him.
Speaker 0: You hate him.
Speaker 0: You kill him.
Speaker 0: And I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's just because most of the people in this game don't know me that well.
Speaker 0: Everyone took my advice.
Speaker 0: Everyone did exactly what I told them to do.
Speaker 1: Good job.
Speaker 0: And it came to this climactic moment where I whip out a sword and go to betray the guy I'm with.
Speaker 0: If I kill him, I'm not going to get the inheritance.
Speaker 0: Like I basically would fuck everything up.
Speaker 0: I put a sword to his throat and I threatened his life in front of his dad.
Speaker 0: And I waited.
Speaker 0: I was totally bluffing.
Speaker 0: You know what happened?
Speaker 0: Everybody fucking stabbed each other all at once.
Speaker 0: And I was standing there alone and alive.
Speaker 0: So when you watch the time lapse, you're going to see like 20 or 30 frames of everyone sitting around a table while the will is being read.
Speaker 0: One frame of everyone standing up suddenly with all the chairs like thrown to the ground, one with everyone standing with swords through each other's throats, and then one with everyone dead but me.
Speaker 0: And I'm standing there going, why did you do this?
Speaker 0: You stupid people.
Speaker 1: It was the greatest experience of my life to put together the time lapse such that, you know, some frames last longer than others.
Speaker 0: It is it is brilliant.
Speaker 0: And if you ever get a chance to play Luke Crane's Inheritance LARP, it will be a peak role playing experience for you.
Speaker 0: However, it is brutal to play.
Speaker 0: You've got to be 100 percent without exception in character for a full two and a half to three hours in a room with eight other people who are also role playing in the same capacity.
Speaker 0: There is no break.
Speaker 0: There is no delay.
Speaker 0: And there are only three scenes.
Speaker 0: It was it was exhausting.
Speaker 1: So while you were playing in that game, I was playing in a game of Dungeoneers.
Speaker 1: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: You hadn't played that before.
Speaker 1: So if you don't know, this game is a somewhat maybe going to be official, something modification of Mouseguard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when I played it last time, they basically were like, yeah, don't really talk about it and don't record it.
Speaker 1: No one said anything to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so go nuts.
Speaker 1: So if they you know, that's not my problem.
Speaker 1: So basically what it and it was on the schedule.
Speaker 1: Just people know the game exists.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: So it's basically it's a modified mouse guard that is basically just for straight up dungeon crawling in the old school D&D way.
Speaker 1: But it is rough.
Speaker 1: It is like, wow, you are struggling the whole time because it's mouse guard.
Speaker 1: You're struggling to get checks.
Speaker 1: You're struggling to succeed at fucking anything.
Speaker 1: But he's struggling not to just get killed.
Speaker 0: You're struggling when you finally get the loot to fit it in your goddamn backpack.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anything you do, you know, gives you, you know, statuses like, you know, oh, I'm now I'm angry.
Speaker 1: No, no, I'm exhausted.
Speaker 1: Oh, and I'm sick and I'm and it just brings you down so hard.
Speaker 1: And you need to earn checks to get it to get it back.
Speaker 1: But you can't earn checks that easily.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, we had really bad stuff happen.
Speaker 1: Like I think at one point, like everyone was got like tired simultaneously.
Speaker 1: It was like, oh, no, everyone got hungry simultaneously.
Speaker 0: So it's got with three exceptions, all games in the schedule, had a number of players, four players, five players, nine players.
Speaker 0: One mouse guard game had guard mice instead of players.
Speaker 0: One game had brave souls instead of players.
Speaker 0: And the Dungeoneers and Dragonslayers that you played had five greedy fools.
Speaker 1: That is what it had indeed.
Speaker 1: So the five greedy fools went into this dungeon and tried to get as much loot as possible and get out.
Speaker 1: Little bit less role playing, a little bit more dungeoning going on here.
Speaker 1: But really, this game was just.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you think, you know, I've complained about brutal games like, say, FTL or Ninja Gay Day.
Speaker 1: This was brutal.
Speaker 1: Not only do you struggle not to die, but the inventory Tetris is worse than any inventory Tetris I've ever played.
Speaker 1: We even had a bag of holding and it's effectively a bag of holding.
Speaker 1: And it's still fucking sucked.
Speaker 1: We could not fit the shit.
Speaker 1: We had to dump the coins out of the bag of holding to put other shit in there.
Speaker 1: And then we just like left a pile of coins there.
Speaker 1: And then like I had a two handed sack.
Speaker 1: But to use the two handed sack, I had the large sack.
Speaker 1: I mean, I had to carry it.
Speaker 1: I had to carry the large sack in both hands.
Speaker 1: I had a two handed sword.
Speaker 1: Thank you, character maker.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Which means I had a small.
Speaker 0: You realize he was cackling while he made those characters.
Speaker 1: I had to drop every time I need to stab something.
Speaker 1: I had to put the two the sack on Jersey, drop this sack that was in my other hand to hold the sword with two hands.
Speaker 1: And after the fight, pick the sack up again.
Speaker 1: But to use the large sack, I had to throw away the small sack and the sword.
Speaker 1: Because there's nowhere to put them in the inventory slots because of how many slots they take up.
Speaker 0: Inventory Tetris is one of those weird mechanics.
Speaker 0: And for whatever reason, just gets me going.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's like we go in.
Speaker 1: We got all these treasures.
Speaker 1: We carry them.
Speaker 1: We figure out how to between us, carry them all.
Speaker 1: And then we had to leave and we had to leave a bunch of stuff behind.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know, you play Oregon Trail and you kill all the buffalo.
Speaker 1: And then it says, sorry, good.
Speaker 1: You only get to carry back 200 pounds of meat.
Speaker 1: This is like, yo, dude, you killed two thousand pounds of meat.
Speaker 1: You get to carry back five of those pounds.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And I just like you want to kill some.
Speaker 0: Oh, and you're tired now because you spent the day shooting.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: By the way, minus two D to all rolls.
Speaker 1: And if you want to get some of those rolls back, you could drink some wine.
Speaker 0: So it's got some food.
Speaker 1: But guess what?
Speaker 1: If you eat the drink, the wine, it only empties your wine skin.
Speaker 1: And it's not like you can put coins in there.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't help you to clear out the inventory.
Speaker 0: So correct me if I'm wrong.
Speaker 0: But when I played this last time in Mouse Guard, you get one free check and you only have to earn extras.
Speaker 0: When I played this, you didn't get any free checks.
Speaker 1: It is true that in Mouse Guard, everybody gets a free check.
Speaker 1: every time it is the player's turn in dungeoneers and whatever.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You get no checks at all.
Speaker 1: You need to earn every check that you use, but you can share checks.
Speaker 1: So when I had two checks, I gave checks to some other people who really needed them when I did not need them.
Speaker 1: And vice versa.
Speaker 0: So so I should clarify one thing.
Speaker 0: in the LARP, I said I didn't kill anyone.
Speaker 0: So it's kind of an inside joke and almost no one will get it.
Speaker 0: So the people are there.
Speaker 0: So Vincent Baker himself played the priest and the will was read.
Speaker 0: And basically, people of the swords turned to the priest and said, you should leave.
Speaker 0: Here's a bag of gold for your troubles.
Speaker 0: Walk quickly on the road and hope we don't catch up.
Speaker 0: So Vincent Baker, being the constant role player, decided that he won and said, see you and exited the game with a pile of gold.
Speaker 1: Nice.
Speaker 0: At the very end of the game, when I'm the last man standing, I go to the crazy witch played by her friend Cat Gefion, the crazy witch I played last time.
Speaker 0: And she's like, you can't marry my daughter unless you actually worship Thor.
Speaker 0: Which is tricky because I had claimed to be baptized like nine times.
Speaker 0: All the story shenanigans.
Speaker 0: So I was like, I will go murder that priest.
Speaker 0: I will catch up to him on the road and bring you back a bag of gold and his head.
Speaker 0: And Vincent Baker, who'd been sitting there like enjoying the denim out of the game, turns to me and says, really?
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: And then looks like we're going to play this out.
Speaker 1: To prove that you worship Thor.
Speaker 0: So the Ukraine made us play it out.
Speaker 0: So the final scene was he.
Speaker 0: it was like a month later, he was like getting on a boat to go to the new world and he had this bag of money and I was going, well, I show up in his house and I'm just like, so nothing, no offense to you or your God if he answers your prayers.
Speaker 0: But I'm going to kill you and take your head and give it back to that crazy witch so I can marry her daughter.
Speaker 0: And he looks at me and I say, make whatever rituals you have to make, and then I'm going to come back to the room and kill you.
Speaker 0: And it's Vincent Baker.
Speaker 0: So I'm curious how he's going to role play this.
Speaker 0: He fucking tried to stab me.
Speaker 0: The priest at the very end had had enough of this Viking bullshit and tried to kill me.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So the mechanic Luke had for this was if you actually tried to kill someone, you had an envelope and he never told you what it was the whole time.
Speaker 0: You try to kill someone.
Speaker 0: You open your envelope and you find the name of the person you tried to kill and it tells you the results.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: So it's basically as though you'd pre-rolled all the roles.
Speaker 0: So he looks like, well, open your envelope and look up Arvandale's name and Vincent Baker dutifully opens the envelope, looks at it and says and looks at it and goes, well, that was expected.
Speaker 1: Well, your character was the big, strong, dangerous guy, the baddest of all.
Speaker 1: Is it bodyguard?
Speaker 1: So I imagine on most people's sheets, it said if they fought you, that you would win.
Speaker 0: I also had the best instinct ever.
Speaker 0: Always look for trouble.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 0: So when we were talking about we had this whole like rap session at the end and I was like, I won and I didn't kill a single person.
Speaker 0: And Vincent looks at me and says, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: OK, so there's besides the sessions that we ran as is a law of burning.
Speaker 0: My game went OK.
Speaker 0: Wasn't great.
Speaker 0: I was there as well as I could.
Speaker 1: There was one more session.
Speaker 1: I played it.
Speaker 1: And as you know, there was a beginner track.
Speaker 0: One more.
Speaker 0: I had two more.
Speaker 0: One, two.
Speaker 0: You missed the game.
Speaker 1: Engineers, am I missing a game?
Speaker 0: Because I played in a zombie apocalypse game and like modern burning wheel.
Speaker 0: It was a hack.
Speaker 0: It was OK.
Speaker 1: Let me see that schedule.
Speaker 0: It was pretty fun, but I don't have anything notable to say about it, except that I died and I died taking, I think, a G-16 wound.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: I played in Rachel's game, Matt's game, Dungeoneer game, the beginner track game I was about to talk about, and then I ran my game.
Speaker 1: That's five.
Speaker 1: Oh, all right.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So the beginner track.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So this burning con featured a new feature, featured a new feature, the beginner track.
Speaker 1: If you had not GM before, you could do the beginner's course on Saturday and then you would be required to run a game that you just been trained to run on Sunday.
Speaker 1: So being all adventurous and also, you know, wanting to sort of walk the walk and say, hey, look, you know, I always say people can't learn to be GMs because they need when they suck.
Speaker 1: No one wants to play in their games.
Speaker 1: They can't practice and get better because no one wants to play.
Speaker 1: So they and it's sort of catch twenty two.
Speaker 1: I said, I'm going to go play in a beginner track game.
Speaker 1: So I went and actually the GM of this beginner track game was one of our listeners and the game he ran was not too bad.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Last game I played was something I never played before.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to remember what happened in it.
Speaker 0: I played the schedule.
Speaker 0: I played in Ajit's Lady Blackbird game.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: Do you know anything about Lady Blackbird?
Speaker 1: I'm still not bringing up the schedule about me.
Speaker 1: Oh, you need the schedule that I can't remember what the game was about.
Speaker 0: I only pull it back up.
Speaker 0: I got the schedule around.
Speaker 1: I have heard people talk about Lady Blackbird.
Speaker 1: And all I know is that it is a game where that is, quote, easy to GM because the players do not have to do so much.
Speaker 0: So here's the deal.
Speaker 0: Lady Blackbird is steampunk, the role playing game.
Speaker 0: And the way it works, as far as I can tell, is you have traits.
Speaker 0: And under each trait, you have a bunch of things.
Speaker 0: Your character will see something like cunning and under cunning.
Speaker 0: It has like six or seven other descriptors.
Speaker 0: You can if you want to accomplish something, it's burning wheel style obstacles.
Speaker 0: You know, one, two, three or four, five, six success or failure.
Speaker 0: So what you do is you choose.
Speaker 0: you get one die because you're a person.
Speaker 0: You're you.
Speaker 0: You get one die for the trait you use and you get one die for every one of those aspects that you also are using and attempting to accomplish something.
Speaker 0: And then you're given an obstacle.
Speaker 0: And that's the primary core mechanic of the game.
Speaker 0: Now, to augment that, you have a pool of seven dice.
Speaker 0: You can draw from that pool at any time.
Speaker 0: If you fail the roll, you get all those dice back and an extra die to the pool.
Speaker 0: If you succeed at the roll, you lose all the dice you pulled from the pool.
Speaker 0: So basically, the more you fail, you build up this buffer of eventually succeeding and being awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though oftentimes you keep failing roles because you keep trying to do increasingly desperate things.
Speaker 0: But when you succeed, you're back to nothing.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of like an inverse dread.
Speaker 0: So it is one other mechanic.
Speaker 0: It's very inspector.
Speaker 0: If you want to refresh your pool, you can call for an aside and you basically do the equivalent of turning to another player character and say, yeah, this is just like that time we did the whatever and then role play a flashback like Arabian Nights.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Or like inspectors with the asides.
Speaker 0: It basically is a role playing heavy game and the dice just come out every now and then to decide if you succeed or fail.
Speaker 0: Succeeding means you get what you want and the plot progresses.
Speaker 0: Failure just increasingly makes things desperate.
Speaker 0: And the ship is also a character.
Speaker 0: It's really, really fun.
Speaker 0: I played Lady Blackbird, of course, and I was told that I took a very interesting take on Lady Blackbird and the game turned into romantic comedy.
Speaker 0: I ended up dating the captain.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Also, Lady Blackbirds, the consummate badass and also a wizard.
Speaker 1: In a steampunk setting.
Speaker 0: So I was like trying to use lightning to take out the security cameras.
Speaker 1: The setting sounds a little bit fan service.
Speaker 0: Now, you know, the setting is an endless blue sky with a dying star in the middle of it and a bunch of landmass.
Speaker 1: How is that not fan service?
Speaker 0: and a bunch of land masses?
Speaker 0: The ships are all airships, the evil empires, kind of like Star Wars, the Thrawny kind of people.
Speaker 1: Again, how is it not fanservice?
Speaker 0: And remember, we played Air Action Weekly.
Speaker 0: It kind of has this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a radio channel.
Speaker 0: Fucking everyone in the entire world can hear it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was great.
Speaker 1: I'm remembering.
Speaker 0: It is also one of the better game masters I've ever played with.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I talked to him a bunch.
Speaker 0: He is super cool and he's super good at this.
Speaker 0: And some people from Inheritance were around in this game, too.
Speaker 1: And I got to say, I actually talked to him at the party and he said he was like a relative nub.
Speaker 0: And I was like, well, the thing is, Lady Blackbird, he has not played most of these indie RPGs.
Speaker 0: I felt bad.
Speaker 0: I was the one who booted him out of Inheritance.
Speaker 0: But he the all you have to do to run Lady Blackbird is know how the rules work.
Speaker 0: And every time a character says something, just turn to any other character and say, how do you feel about that?
Speaker 0: How do you feel about you're a you're a noble?
Speaker 0: How do you feel about how the captain just kind of overruled you?
Speaker 0: Captain, how do you feel that this noble just overruled you?
Speaker 0: No matter if I said something or he said something, he just turned to the other person and said, how do you feel about that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a luke crane trick.
Speaker 1: You probably learned that in the beginner's track.
Speaker 0: It works really well.
Speaker 1: You definitely learn that beginner's track, maybe.
Speaker 1: OK, so the the game I played in with the Nub GM, it was this sort of typical Burning Wheel scenario.
Speaker 1: And the situation was that there was a tomb, right?
Speaker 1: And someone like the, you know, like the Lord's son had recently passed away.
Speaker 1: But we don't know why.
Speaker 1: And he was.
Speaker 1: he was in the tomb waiting.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: We were the grave robbers and we were going to go rob that grave.
Speaker 1: And each of us had different reasons for wanting to rob the grave.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Some of us wanted to get in and out fast with treasure.
Speaker 1: Some of us wanted to get the body and bring it out.
Speaker 1: Some of us wanted to, you know, keep the body in there.
Speaker 1: And because there was a sorceress who was also coming to get the body, but we got there first and my character wanted to wait till she got there to negotiate with her and all this stuff.
Speaker 1: And there was something creepy going on.
Speaker 1: And then it became a zombie situation where the dead were rising all over the place.
Speaker 1: And then we're all confronting the sorceress at her palace.
Speaker 1: And, you know, this sort of typical town goes nuts.
Speaker 1: There's something supernatural going.
Speaker 1: How did this guy even die?
Speaker 1: What is the Lord Duke up to?
Speaker 1: kind of situation, you know, with a lot and the character conflict is pretty good, too, because it's all like, you know, the other guy just wanted to, you know, just like destroy the body or something, whereas I was like, no, no, no, we need to, you know, wait here for the sorceress to show up.
Speaker 1: But I didn't say that.
Speaker 1: And I was, you know, I was trying to yeah, I was trying to delay by like letting the thievy people.
Speaker 1: I was like, yeah, let these guys steal some more treasure.
Speaker 1: Hey, maybe there's another room with more treasure to steal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's go, you know.
Speaker 1: And he's like, no, no, we got to get out of here now.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, no, let's steal some more treasure.
Speaker 1: Look, there's all this gold here.
Speaker 1: It was fake gold.
Speaker 1: It was, you know, it was it for enough GM.
Speaker 1: He did rather well.
Speaker 1: And he was also very enthusiastic about, you know, doing better the next time.
Speaker 1: And all the devices that people were throwing out, he was like, oh, and writing it down.
Speaker 1: So I definitely feel that the beginner track was very helpful and that those people that you were beginners now at future burning cons will become Matt's and Rachel's of the future.
Speaker 1: And you will want to sign up for their games.
Speaker 0: There were some high caliber role players.
Speaker 0: I mean, during inheritance, multiple characters broke out into legitimate tears in the course of the game.
Speaker 0: People like when the will was being read, Vincent had this quiver in his voice when a certain fact was revealed.
Speaker 1: And it was the fact that I know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, that same fact is the same fact.
Speaker 0: It's a little more nuanced because of some other bullshit.
Speaker 1: But let's just say, well, because well, because his character is reading it right.
Speaker 1: Whereas the character that I played, the dwarf with the runes and he reads, he was like, oh, these fucking humans.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But if that guy reads that will not knowing the content, Luke made us pass the will around to check the seal.
Speaker 0: So everyone held it physically in their hand and had a real seal with wax.
Speaker 0: No, he didn't have a real sale.
Speaker 1: Basically, we were like a piece of scotch tape.
Speaker 0: There were a lot of great moments, like when the prodigal son came, he went to put like a burning brand into the fire of the grandfather.
Speaker 0: And Kat, who was playing Geffian, fucking knocked it out of his hand.
Speaker 1: Nice.
Speaker 0: It was that it was so peak.
Speaker 1: That was peak.
Speaker 1: So the final thing to talk about is the session that I ran or the session that you ran.
Speaker 1: But you didn't seem like you want to talk about it very much.
Speaker 0: I could just we've already gone for over an hour.
Speaker 1: OK, well, let me quickly just say this about the session I ran.
Speaker 1: It was the last session.
Speaker 1: A lot of people weren't there because of Hurricane.
Speaker 1: I thought there might be no players and I could go home and watch football, which was.
Speaker 1: I did get home for the end of the game, which is aggravating.
Speaker 1: And at first I only had one player who was the beginner GM listener who really wanted to play in my game.
Speaker 1: He told me so, but no one else was in.
Speaker 1: Then I got a second player and then out of which was, you know, no, then the second player left.
Speaker 1: And I'm sitting here thinking football, football, because I wasn't you know, I was confident in my session.
Speaker 1: I had increased in confidence, but my level of confidence in it had wavered over time.
Speaker 0: But funnily, there were three games in the room and every GM was like, well, I'm OK.
Speaker 1: And the confidence that I had in my game was not at the maximum.
Speaker 1: So I was.
Speaker 1: I was glad not to run.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Then suddenly Lou Crane appears to play in my game.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, oh, fuck no.
Speaker 1: Fuck no.
Speaker 1: So then I go into the second room.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: He's like, well, we're going to play.
Speaker 1: And suddenly I'm running the game with Lou Crane and I'm like, shit.
Speaker 1: Suddenly we go into the second room.
Speaker 1: He bails on the game and I'm like, yes, all right.
Speaker 1: And income Shervin.
Speaker 1: And I was like, Shervin, what's up?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: You know, so now I got, you know, listener and I got Shervin.
Speaker 1: And then almost almost as bad as Lou Crane, but not quite as bad incomes, John and Lamar, who are.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, oh, crap.
Speaker 1: What am I going to do now with these expert role players stepping into my game?
Speaker 1: This is not good in a scenario where I do not have full confidence.
Speaker 1: I've never even run a practice run.
Speaker 1: I've never done anything.
Speaker 1: And I'm sitting there thinking, right.
Speaker 1: Basically is the gist of my scenario that I came up with.
Speaker 1: You're in a normal ass town.
Speaker 1: There is a monster up in the hills, a legend of a monster up in the hills.
Speaker 1: No one knows if it's really there or not.
Speaker 1: But the legend is, you know, don't go in the cave.
Speaker 1: No one's ever returned.
Speaker 1: If you go near it, there's weird noises, that whole thing.
Speaker 1: The night, the night, like Lancelot, famous night throughout the realm shows up.
Speaker 1: He says, I'm going to take care of this monster everyone's heard about.
Speaker 1: He goes off.
Speaker 1: You the players are for normal as townsfolk.
Speaker 1: The innkeeper, the steadfast innkeeper.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, the one that's the MPC in all the video games.
Speaker 1: The bard who plays music in the inn, the town drunk who is a shopkeeper.
Speaker 1: and a foreign merchant who has a caravan that is in town and is sort of, you know, the innkeeper doesn't like it because, you know, business competition.
Speaker 1: So these are the four normal, boring as weak as normal townsfolk.
Speaker 1: And the story is the night returns to the inn while all the four players are in it.
Speaker 1: And he's wounded, but he's carrying mad loot, big time loot.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I got this idea because the previous year I played in a game that was about.
Speaker 1: I think we might have talked about it.
Speaker 1: The four players just killed the dragon and come to town with the loot.
Speaker 1: And I was thinking, what if the four players are normal people in the town and someone else comes in with the loot?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's sort of the opposite instead of the players being the people, the loot, the players, people trying to get the loot from the player who is the night.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I dropped these beliefs and these character sheets on these four people.
Speaker 1: That's all I dropped on them.
Speaker 1: I wasn't as prepared as Rachel.
Speaker 1: I wasn't right.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, what am I going to do?
Speaker 1: What's going to happen?
Speaker 1: And of course, expert role player John immediately before I could even make the I'm thinking, all right, we got to start the game.
Speaker 1: I got to make the night show up before I can even make the night show up.
Speaker 1: John goes full on with the singing, attacking the shopkeeper, trying to he hit in the first.
Speaker 1: he immediately begins the game and hits all his beliefs on a single role before anything has even happened.
Speaker 0: I'm reminded of the moment way back when we first played the sword, when Luke came found us arguing and said, no, I'll go on.
Speaker 1: That is exactly what occurred.
Speaker 1: And actually, I started running this game and a lot of it I cannot deny a significant portion of it must have been due to the excellent skills of all.
Speaker 1: four of the players at the table were a plus playing.
Speaker 1: I could not ask for easier people to run a game for, but I was actually surprised looking at myself with the third person view at the quality of my game running.
Speaker 1: I said, man, I wish I was playing in this game.
Speaker 1: Why am I doing a good job?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but I'm just going to keep doing what I'm doing.
Speaker 1: How is this happening?
Speaker 1: So now I just kind of want to run this game for other people's because I feel good about running it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And I'm what I'm really wondering, though, could I run a campaign game that goes on as well as I was running that one time game?
Speaker 0: You could try again.
Speaker 0: We could try to do Dwarf Fortress again.
Speaker 1: But I don't know if we do Dwarf Fortress.
Speaker 1: We'll do something.
Speaker 0: I like Dwarf Fortress.
Speaker 1: I really want to do townsfolk because I'm liking townsfolk.
Speaker 0: I'm liking dwarves lately.
Speaker 1: I like townsfolk.
Speaker 0: Thing is, I'm playing.
Speaker 1: it proves me right.
Speaker 1: That the thing I've always wanted to play was boring as townsfolk and I was able to make it work.
Speaker 1: So it was.
Speaker 1: it was just like, yeah, no one else wanted to play boring townsfolk but me.
Speaker 1: And look, I was right.
Speaker 1: Boring as townsfolk is a great game.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: So fag.
Speaker 0: Sadly, the after party, I did not go.
Speaker 1: I went to watch football.
Speaker 0: I went to the after party and then I literally rode the last train out of Dodge because the hurricane was coming in and all the subways were closing down.
Speaker 0: I got on the last train out of Manhattan, literally like the like.
Speaker 0: we walk up and everything's roped off.
Speaker 0: I'm like, fuck, did we miss it?
Speaker 0: And then there's this crazy guy.
Speaker 0: He wasn't crazy.
Speaker 0: He was just one of those guys.
Speaker 0: Anyone who talks to you in the subway who isn't an official is probably crazy.
Speaker 0: And he starts explaining what's going on.
Speaker 0: But in a kind of crazy way and how it's the government conspiracy, like that's why the hurricane's coming in, why they're shutting everything down.
Speaker 0: But whatever.
Speaker 0: So we wait.
Speaker 0: And then sure enough, the last train out of Dodge pulls up and then the person in the booth turns off the light, locks the door to the booth, opens the exit door.
Speaker 0: We all walk through with her.
Speaker 0: We all got on the train together and we left the subway station empty and the lights all turned off behind us.
Speaker 0: Well, it was awesome.
Speaker 1: So today on the subway, they're making all these announcements about the limited service and one of the announcements.
Speaker 1: You know what the guy said on the train?
Speaker 1: He said the end trains go to thirty fourth street where you can transfer to the BMT or IND.
Speaker 1: Whoa.
Speaker 1: And as soon as I heard that guy must be like as soon as I heard that, I was like, how old is the dude who is freaking running this train?
Speaker 1: Because it's true.
Speaker 1: The IRT wasn't running.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I was like, how old is the guy who is, you know, conducting this train or engineering this subway train?
Speaker 1: That is epic.
Speaker 1: He didn't say it again.
Speaker 1: I kept listening to his announcement.
Speaker 1: He only said it once.
Speaker 1: He said BMT, IND.
Speaker 0: And I was like, that's how you know if someone's actually an immortal.
Speaker 1: And I was.
Speaker 1: I was like, am I the only one on this train who understood what that guy just said?
Speaker 0: The thing is, we never lived through it.
Speaker 0: We just know it thanks to Wikipedia because that's the only reason I know anything.
Speaker 0: I learned a little bit from our and I repeat that fact often, but apparently no one learns that.
Speaker 1: That's they keep thinking I'm smart.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Burning Con was great.
Speaker 1: If anyway, if best burning con yet, five excellent sessions past burning cons have had four or three.
Speaker 0: If any of you did not go because you were afraid of running a game, you're a fool.
Speaker 1: I pity you fool.
Speaker 0: This was this is one of the better conventions I've ever been to.
Speaker 1: I played five sessions of role playing through a hurricane over two days and all five of them were a plus.
Speaker 1: You can't you can't get that kind of shit at like fucking Gen Con.
Speaker 1: This was in New York City and it was so cheap.
Speaker 0: I, as Lady Blackbird, cast off my disguise 10 seconds into the scenario and broadcast my love of the Pirate King to the world.
Speaker 1: I think I'm just going to run my scenario straight up again next year.
Speaker 0: Watch out.
Speaker 0: You know what I'm going to do?
Speaker 0: Plan it.
Speaker 1: No, you can't.
Speaker 0: Well, it'll be like me, Lou Crane, Tor.
Speaker 0: Not allowed.
Speaker 1: I actually played in two games of Tor this week.
Speaker 0: It's really fun to play in a game with Tor.
Speaker 1: I've never had the shipwreck game and also the.
Speaker 1: we played inheritance with him last year.
Speaker 0: I played this like mouse guard Victorian thing that he was in.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And he also played the Dungeoneer's game.
Speaker 1: But the day he really busted out in that thief game hardcore.
Speaker 1: I was like, you know, this one point where he sort of unexpectedly busted out and I was like, his character got mad angry.
Speaker 1: And I was.
Speaker 1: I was like, whoa, watch that.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: Hi, to the bone, to the bone, to the bone, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, The man you do in the shed.
Speaker 0: The deputy of the villa at the end.
Speaker 0: The family family kiss him.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
Speaker 1: no, no, no, no, no, no,
Speaker 0: no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
Speaker 1: no, no, no,
Speaker 0: no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
Speaker 1: no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
Speaker 0: no, no,
Speaker 1: no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
Speaker 0: no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
Speaker 1: no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,