Speaker 0: It's Tuesday April 4th, 2012.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is fuck it.
Speaker 0: It's Pax.
Speaker 0: Let's just go.
Speaker 0: Okay now Pax is coming.
Speaker 0: This is the last show you'll get until we recover from Pax.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we're talking about Angry Birds space and Pax space Obligatory space joke, which we don't do that kind of joke too often because it but it's actually relevant.
Speaker 1: It's like it's relevant but dumb and not funny.
Speaker 1: unless you're like a 12 year old in anime convention Let's do this.
Speaker 0: It's like if the cake was actually a lie.
Speaker 0: like you get like someone says hey you want to come over I've got cake and you get there and there's no cake.
Speaker 1: you go to the bakery and they say here's a cake I give you a box.
Speaker 1: you open the box poop or Cupcakes or pie.
Speaker 0: they give you a pie by accident.
Speaker 0: That's that those.
Speaker 0: those are the points where you can say the cake was a lie and it's it's okay.
Speaker 0: It may not be funny, but it's okay to say almost okay anyway.
Speaker 0: now The only happens bad is if you're that guy you're standing in line at a con and a guy behind you is like Cake is a lie.
Speaker 0: It's like that's the most social currency that guy's got.
Speaker 0: you realize that he just entered with his high note.
Speaker 1: Yep So anyway Because it's PAX is pretty much no game news because everyone's holding on to their game news until PAX and it would be redundant to Discuss any PAX news before the PAX part of the show in the news part.
Speaker 1: So all I got for you today is I'm gonna geek bite.
Speaker 1: previous thing I've discussed in the show which is that new tabletop internet TV.
Speaker 0: That is so barely a step above my idea of making the news about PAX.
Speaker 1: I know but it's still above.
Speaker 1: it is above.
Speaker 1: I will give you that anyway, so I watched the first episode which just came out.
Speaker 1: Apparently there's gonna be a monthly thing.
Speaker 1: It was Wil Wheaton.
Speaker 1: I believe you mean Some guy for Mythbusters, but it wasn't the two Mythbusters guys, it was one of the other guys.
Speaker 0: Do you know the names of anyone on Mythbusters?
Speaker 1: I'm scared.
Speaker 1: mustache guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah names Just curious busters.
Speaker 1: other guy who I can recognize.
Speaker 1: Okay, just check but I can't describe anyway The guard Mythbusters girl who I wouldn't recognize if I bump into her on the street.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, uh some dude who was like a Starcraft commentator and This girl who I forget what she does, but she's internet II and nerdy in some way.
Speaker 1: anyway Her name was Jenna.
Speaker 1: I remember her name though I don't remember the other guys names except for Wil Wheaton because I've seen him in person anyway.
Speaker 1: So these four people get around and they play a game.
Speaker 1: a small world, right?
Speaker 1: Relatively high production values, you know much better than us.
Speaker 1: You know, it's not say TV quality, you know necessarily but it's you know.
Speaker 1: I guess it's like cable TV quality for like middle of the day on Sunday kind of thing.
Speaker 1: It definitely does a good job of selling the game.
Speaker 1: It felt like it did a good job of explaining the game.
Speaker 1: It's like someone who had never seen small world in their lives before But that my view on that is tainted because I already know how to play small world.
Speaker 1: So like I don't know what it would have seemed like with someone who didn't understand the game at all.
Speaker 1: I've never seen it before.
Speaker 1: would they understand it watching the show?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: They don't show you the entire playthrough because that would take a while.
Speaker 1: All right, and this shows only a half hour.
Speaker 1: They sure do show you the highlights.
Speaker 1: They also did some stuff like they put some pandemic ponds on the board so that you know to highlight the areas where the action Is you know because if you just looked at the board you and you weren't knowledgeable you might know
Speaker 0: Because we tried to do some you know do a thing and film it and then make footage after the fact.
Speaker 0: Once in the past and it was a disaster and then we watched a hodgeman do a thing and we realized that it takes so much like fakery and Repeats and effort and bullshit to make any amount of reasonable video come out of any even reasonably live event.
Speaker 0: Yep, so it's that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: You have to do that.
Speaker 1: Yep So anyway, so they played a game a small world.
Speaker 1: They explained the small world pretty well as they were playing.
Speaker 1: they explained the moves as they were making them why they were making the moves.
Speaker 1: You know, they had a lot of sidebars, you know Those kind of things they do in reality shows where it cuts away from the action and you see just one person talking to the camera Like yeah, you know, it's like they got interviewed but you don't hear the questions.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, I made that move because blah blah blah blah blah, right?
Speaker 1: Uh overall, you know, I think the show is like if you're someone who is nerdy But you are not into the german games, you know You're the kind of person who likes you know, the sci-fis and the tv shows and whatever all this stuff that I don't like.
Speaker 1: Uh, this might do a good job of getting those people into board games and for that I think this is a good thing for it to exist.
Speaker 1: But as someone who is a hardcore already board gamer There's really no reason for me to watch the show because it's not teaching me anything.
Speaker 1: I already know how to play this game, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, it's not really that funny because it seems like they're all the jokes they're making and all the table talk Is somewhat genuine but also somewhat forced are you?
Speaker 1: because they know they're on camera?
Speaker 1: It's not that sort of natural table talk you get.
Speaker 1: there's also no smack talk.
Speaker 1: like all.
Speaker 1: their smack talk is Generally, like, you know, it's very light-hearted and friendly.
Speaker 0: I almost I really feel like we should.
Speaker 0: we got enough.
Speaker 1: I think the major difference right is like when we smack talk.
Speaker 1: It's like winner can glow and everyone else shame.
Speaker 1: second place is the first loser Whereas they were sort of like there was a winner, but they sort of had a everyone's a winner attitude.
Speaker 1: I can tell the girl was like at least I beat you.
Speaker 1: Hahaha.
Speaker 1: I do that feeling good even though she lost.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do that.
Speaker 0: I don't I feel good if i'm in second place.
Speaker 1: No, uh, but second place the first loser.
Speaker 0: But I know uh someone on the internet I've not seen the video yet said that they fucked up a rule and that the person who won the game only won because of That.
Speaker 0: fuck up.
Speaker 1: I didn't pay that close.
Speaker 0: So the ghouls apparently don't get to attack if they do their decline thing.
Speaker 0: That's true, but he attacked and declined.
Speaker 1: Oh, see, actually, I remember specifically that part where he goaled it up and that someone had mentioned.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, ghouls are awesome That's what you're supposed to do with them.
Speaker 1: And the guy was like, oh, I didn't even know that was you're supposed to do with ghouls You know, I just sort of you know, and he was like, no, that's exactly the way to use the ghouls for awesomeness.
Speaker 1: But I didn't actually pay attention apparently.
Speaker 0: No, that's not how the rules are.
Speaker 1: Uh, that's sort of a fail if you're making a show about a boy.
Speaker 0: No, I heard this.
Speaker 0: Like I said, I did not see the episode yet.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that's true.
Speaker 1: I don't know I didn't.
Speaker 1: I also didn't pay that close attention.
Speaker 1: I just remember that part.
Speaker 1: um You know.
Speaker 1: and also they weren't playing hard to win, you know It's like they were playing kind of to win but not hard to win the way we play hard to win.
Speaker 1: So if you're looking for like a competitive thing where you can root for someone to win Which is sort of what I kind of want which is you know What someone like me would be interested in it's this is not that this is for the nerd Who is not already a board gaming nerd to make you a board gaming nerd and maybe to sell you some games in that way.
Speaker 1: It does a good job.
Speaker 1: Now
Speaker 0: what I would love to see is an episode of this, you know If it goes on for a while and is popular I'd love them to get a group of actually hardcore board gamers Just to just to see what I think
Speaker 1: they're mostly powering it with the fame the nerd fame of the participants
Speaker 0: Which is fine.
Speaker 1: I mean think about it gets the viewership to sell the games, which is good.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, if this goes well, I mean imagine if they get like nathan fillian.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they're basically targeting the exact right group the people who are in nerdery.
Speaker 1: They're close to board game nerds, but they're not in board game nerds.
Speaker 1: You know some star trek guy is close to board game nerdery.
Speaker 1: He's not far off He's you're not.
Speaker 1: we're not reaching out to you know, you know, some guy at a nascar thing, right?
Speaker 1: We're reaching out to someone who's close to board game nerdery But is not there yet and trying to bring him in.
Speaker 1: and that's what the show is good for.
Speaker 1: I was slightly pissed off about one thing which was I don't know if this is just an honest portrayal of the girl on the show or if it was just You know the way she was portrayed But they she seemed kind of bleh in the show like she was like.
Speaker 1: they showed her like, you know, because it's edited right Once she made a comment like oh i'll take the sorcerers because I like to be a magic user And everyone but all the other guys are making comments like I did this because i'll get points that way.
Speaker 1: It's like whenever they cut to a guy they were commenting on why they made a strategy to win.
Speaker 1: When they cut to the girl she was like, I was glad I got to use the dragon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I hope sincerely That that was just the way the conversations went and it was not clever editing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that would that would that would actually be the worst possible thing if that was just clever editing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the girl also got the lowest score, you know, she wasn't that much lower.
Speaker 1: Well, obviously listen how she was playing right but it's like, you know, was that?
Speaker 1: you know, was that?
Speaker 1: Person right this jenna girl who I don't you know, remember what she does, but she's some semi-fame internet famous nerd Was she just not?
Speaker 1: You know, she was you know newer to the game than the other people obviously But it's like.
Speaker 1: was she just that way and that was honest portrayal or was it, you know?
Speaker 0: Well, there's a couple of possibilities.
Speaker 0: was she playing a persona?
Speaker 0: That's also true or was it edited to make her look like that?
Speaker 1: I think that you know and it's like, you know, it can't it's unless it was edited by you know Someone to make it look like that.
Speaker 1: It's obviously not sexist especially could be an honest portrayal of her.
Speaker 1: but in which case You know, maybe not have people like that representing the ladies, you know get someone on there who's gonna?
Speaker 0: Yeah, can you imagine roe on a show like that?
Speaker 1: Exactly, which is what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Give me that motherfucking cocoa bean.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: You know you get get nuri on there Right, you know the girls we know are not like that.
Speaker 1: the girls we know are like Smack you down and take all them points Right.
Speaker 1: So that's right, you know, and I know there are some semi-famous nerd girls who are like that.
Speaker 1: Veronica Belmont's pretty hardcore and i'm pretty sure she'll be on the show at some point.
Speaker 0: Well, let's do our.
Speaker 0: you know This is really shit talk one of our board game nights when it's just the hardcore people.
Speaker 0: Or maybe a pax.
Speaker 0: i'll get some video of what the frc the core the real frc is actually like.
Speaker 1: Let's film like an entire game of something that's not eclipse.
Speaker 0: We got enough hard drive space for eclipse almost almost.
Speaker 1: i'm just saying we'd have enough battery power for a clip.
Speaker 1: Let's get like a one hour game and film it.
Speaker 1: and you know, here's the two games Something like a grickle of puerto rico size.
Speaker 0: I would do puerto rico and bonanza because they show two different kinds of games Because i'm not yelling at the top of my lungs at puerto rico.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't want to film something that's like, you know soft like apple stacks apples or dixit, you know I want to film something.
Speaker 1: that's a hard game a strategy of winning, you know, but isn't too long.
Speaker 0: is dixit often soft?
Speaker 1: Yeah, dixits are pretty soft.
Speaker 0: So I gotta preface my news because there's a lot to say here and it's unfortunate that the article about it appeared on april 1st But I didn't.
Speaker 0: i'm assuming it's not in april fools.
Speaker 0: But anyway.
Speaker 0: So you may or may not if you play chess be familiar with the king's gambit.
Speaker 0: It's one of the openings Of of chess, you know, i'm not familiar with it.
Speaker 1: I know how to play chess, but i'm not familiar with any of the strategies Or anything like that.
Speaker 0: I don't enjoy chess, but I don't enjoy it.
Speaker 1: for the same I don't hate it, but I don't go out of my way to play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't enjoy chess for the same reason I don't enjoy Rts's or necessarily street fighter 4.
Speaker 1: I reinstalled starcraft.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna give it another go.
Speaker 0: I'm, i'm not like.
Speaker 0: i'm not at that level.
Speaker 0: I haven't memorized enough stuff But I know enough to be dangerous because when I was in high school one of my friends was a straight up chess Master and I played with him like all the time.
Speaker 0: I don't think I ever fucking beat him but I learned a lot and i'd often actually start with a polish opening.
Speaker 0: but uh, The king's gambit and i'll link i'm going to link to a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: You can actually step through what the king's gambit is and actually wikipedia.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: I'm going to read what wikipedia says because it says it better than I can.
Speaker 0: The king's gambit was one of the most popular openings for over 300 years in chess Has been played by many of its strongest players, uh, blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: There's a whole bunch of people writing about it And basically this was a very popular opening until uh, bobby fisher Uh who if you don't know who he is, that's a whole other.
Speaker 0: let's not discuss that now Let's just say that that's a rabbit hole.
Speaker 0: You can follow on wikipedia.
Speaker 1: You can watch the movie.
Speaker 0: So bobby fisher interesting dude published an article interesting a bust to the king's gambit in which he basically said It's stupid.
Speaker 0: Don't do it.
Speaker 0: Uh, it's.
Speaker 0: it always loses and there's a lot of arguments back and forth.
Speaker 0: So a dude vazic rajlik Claims to have a weak proof that it is in fact a losing gamble for white The.
Speaker 0: the actual king's gambit is pretty straightforward.
Speaker 0: So what you do is white moves.
Speaker 0: I won't use chess terminology in case you guys don't know what that means.
Speaker 0: He takes the pawn in front of his king moves it up to okay.
Speaker 0: if black wants to accept the gambit They take their black pawn in front of their king and put him two spaces forward the queen Because they're on the opposite side.
Speaker 0: uh No, they're not.
Speaker 1: Yes Yeah, I think I have.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I think I just discovered That i've been setting up chess boards wrong my whole life.
Speaker 0: You were so genuinely startled that I had to second guess myself.
Speaker 1: It's i'm not see now.
Speaker 1: I haven't played chess in so long So I don't even know if it's accurate like if it's just my memory is fucked up.
Speaker 1: But I was i'm pretty sure my whole life.
Speaker 1: i've set up chess boards where the queen is opposite the king and vice versa.
Speaker 1: So it's it's a diagonal, you know, it's symmetric But this one has both kings on one side of both and it must be correct if it's on wikipedia Kings on the right both queens on the left.
Speaker 1: Now I don't even remember If i've been playing right or wrong.
Speaker 0: uh That's that's amazing.
Speaker 1: Scott here is a picture of a but if you if you asked me to set up a chess board today.
Speaker 1: I would have set it up not according to that picture.
Speaker 0: so Yeah, and that's that's uh, that's uh something that's that's something indeed.
Speaker 1: Yeah Alrighty Yeah, I just you know, but the thing is right.
Speaker 1: Um Why not play it that way?
Speaker 0: Uh, all right, so the queen now Facing the other person's king, but your queen is also facing the other person's king also Yeah, so the game devolves immediately.
Speaker 0: In fact, it's probably Pretty directly solvable if the game's like that.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: it cuts down on the decision tree to a ludicrous anyway experiment.
Speaker 0: that was so the king's game.
Speaker 0: So you take the pawn in front of your king put him up to The other person puts their pawn in front of their king up to pawn against pawn pawn against pawn white.
Speaker 0: Then moves the kid the pawn to the right in front of their white bishop up to So.
Speaker 1: so this only situation only happens if all if both players agree and do those three moves.
Speaker 1: if anyone
Speaker 0: kind of like if
Speaker 1: I Like if anyone deviates
Speaker 0: and you block it in a way that I know you're gonna block it and we get into this pattern Right,
Speaker 1: so it's all if anyone deviates from this at all in any way that it everything it doesn't matter It's not the king's gambit.
Speaker 0: So a lot of people, you know chess unlike checkers checkers has a weak mathematical solution from many years ago And it'll probably have a complete mathematical solution soon.
Speaker 0: Uh, both sides can force the draw.
Speaker 0: so fuck check fuck checkers done game.
Speaker 0: But anyway chess is orders of magnitude more complex.
Speaker 0: So we're not going to have a complete solution to chess anytime soon though.
Speaker 0: I'll bet we will within the next 20 years.
Speaker 0: So what this guy did is constrained his brute forcing to just The follow-up to the king's gambit to try to figure out if the king's gambit is a worthwhile opening or not.
Speaker 1: So that's a very, you know, if you assume those three opening moves, uh, it's still basically unsolvable with modern computers Still is unsolvable, but you still have exp even though it's unsolvable.
Speaker 1: There's still a Gigantic number of strategies that follow from those three moves.
Speaker 1: It is still Exponentially less than the full game of chess.
Speaker 0: So he did a number of things.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like let's map every star in the universe.
Speaker 1: That's too hard.
Speaker 1: All right, let's map every star in the galaxy.
Speaker 1: That is sure go for it.
Speaker 0: That is Almost just as hard on the scale of infinity.
Speaker 0: Exactly, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like all right, i've got infinity and you've got infinity over two.
Speaker 1: Well, good job, dude.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's basically what's going on here.
Speaker 0: So What they?
Speaker 0: they analyze this they this guy.
Speaker 0: now I want to pause here to point out something that makes us even crazier.
Speaker 0: This guy was on slashdot before For plagiarizing gnu chess and another chess program in his own chess program And he's kind of hated by a lot of people.
Speaker 0: All right, but apparently his and he was disqualified from some big competition.
Speaker 1: So this is a sketchy chess dude, but you know what?
Speaker 1: Even though he may be sketchy in those ways, it's not as bad as the way he's bobby fisher.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, bobby fisher.
Speaker 0: All right, just watch the movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so anyway Uh, his solution is not even a weak mathematical proof.
Speaker 0: What it is is a statistical analysis of all the possible moves that pruned Branches where white had not white where black in this case had an overwhelming majority.
Speaker 0: Basically it proved any branch that was highly likely to not result in any different behavior.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if like, you know if he was going down one road one pattern of moves and it was looking like you know White had like a handful of pieces left and black had a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: It's like okay don't even bother calculating the rest of those patterns.
Speaker 1: We we can move on to other patterns that are more likely to be you know winners for the other side, right?
Speaker 1: So that you know Basically calculating as few patterns as possible when the probability of finding anything down that road is not looking too good.
Speaker 0: So there are a couple of moves.
Speaker 0: basically Uh, i'm debating whether or not I should actually tell you what the uh answer is or I should make you go to this website.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: You know what.
Speaker 0: go to the website and read it.
Speaker 0: the website explains how the guy did it.
Speaker 0: All the it's.
Speaker 0: it's a really interesting article That covers this is kind of how we try to solve board games.
Speaker 0: Just board games that we play have such a constrained decision space compared to chess or go That they're actually much more eminently solvable even by a human with a pen and paper and a calculator.
Speaker 1: some of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah Uh, you know, maybe not something like a curricula with a zillion cards.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is what humans are good at is pruning Branches of things that are highly likely to not pan out.
Speaker 1: Yeah But the thing is sometimes there's an awesome gem down those roads.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, but yeah now i'm just waiting for the forum to go and make fun of me for not knowing how to set up a Chest.
Speaker 0: that's fine because the beatles is like a music note like a beat as opposed to the bargain.
Speaker 0: That's right here I'll i'll.
Speaker 0: i'll read the uh, the sentence from wikipedia.
Speaker 0: two sentences from wikipedia.
Speaker 0: three sentences.
Speaker 0: four.
Speaker 0: Uh, blah blah blah claim to have proven it to a 99.9999999 Confidence level.
Speaker 0: the fisher's article was nearly but not entirely correct.
Speaker 0: Uh, blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: the search concluded that after accepting the gambit black can force a win against all white responses except A set of three highly unusual responses that at best allow white to force a draw.
Speaker 0: So the moral The king's gambit is the fool's errand.
Speaker 1: So if you're white don't make your first move moving the white pawn in front of the king to forward.
Speaker 1: now Something else.
Speaker 0: here's the problem with this.
Speaker 0: This is all assuming perfect play but in history the king's gambit has been very powerful.
Speaker 0: and uh The article actually points out that if you study games black tends to fuck up first compared to white just in real play.
Speaker 0: Like they'll make a theoretical mistake earlier in their play.
Speaker 0: So if you're playing white against a novice the king's gambit might do better than average, right?
Speaker 1: But the thing is even if you do it against a novice, right?
Speaker 1: So white is professional black is novice white knows this.
Speaker 1: white knows the king's gambit stupid.
Speaker 1: But he also knows that against novices is powerful because the other guy's gonna screw up which will make it not suck, right?
Speaker 1: So he moves that white pawn to forward from in front of his king.
Speaker 1: The novice isn't gonna do know to do this The same thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that move of the pawn is a pretty powerful position in and of itself It is.
Speaker 1: but i'm just saying the other guy's not gonna be smart enough to do the same thing.
Speaker 0: But he could do anything.
Speaker 1: he might move the knight first.
Speaker 1: who knows?
Speaker 0: I prefer the polish opening Even though I don't believe it's terrible.
Speaker 0: I don't think many people use it anymore But I use it partly because I tend to play against novices and they won't notice the power of my bishop.
Speaker 0: You know what I do in chess most of the time play randomly until they only have a few pieces left And then hold out to the bitter end.
Speaker 1: not at all.
Speaker 0: force a draw.
Speaker 0: No first you want to.
Speaker 0: you want to move the king in move the rook out castle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 1: I don't know any of the names of any moves or anything like that or any patterns, but you're not a castle.
Speaker 1: I just know all the moves here.
Speaker 1: I just know the rules except for how to set up a board properly.
Speaker 0: Do you know all the rules scott?
Speaker 0: Do you know about en passant?
Speaker 1: What are all the ways?
Speaker 0: i've heard that before what are all the ways a pawn can capture a piece?
Speaker 1: Uh, you can go diagonal yeah, or Diagonal onto the piece, right?
Speaker 0: There is one other very specific situation where a pawn can take a piece without moving on to it.
Speaker 1: Uh, yo when you're in front of it you move diagonal.
Speaker 1: it's like the side of it.
Speaker 0: But when can you do this?
Speaker 1: You can do it When you're like all when the guy's still in like his original place like all the way on the other end, right?
Speaker 1: Or something like that right now.
Speaker 1: No, no There's a time you can do it.
Speaker 0: It has to do when when it's only another pawn Yeah, yeah, not not if he's in his original place.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so anyway, but I know how all the guys move and such.
Speaker 1: So what I usually do is I move the candidates first because they move all cool And they get to jump over shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so basically so it's sort of like I get to send.
Speaker 1: it sort of feels good Right.
Speaker 1: This is how I play chess.
Speaker 1: Obviously, i'm not great my understanding.
Speaker 1: it feels good to move them out because you can still leave your army of Pawns up there and it feels like you're keeping your armor on while sending out missiles.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: You sound like hiding behind the shield.
Speaker 0: Here's what you sound like man.
Speaker 0: I really liked just hadouken all the time because it really works.
Speaker 1: I'm really glad I got to use the dragon And I like sorcerers because I like to be a magic user.
Speaker 0: A thousand hand slap.
Speaker 0: i'll just use it all day.
Speaker 1: I know right?
Speaker 1: What what what what?
Speaker 0: Okay I'll just sometimes i'll just back up in the corner and do it.
Speaker 0: Yep In fact, I go for that.
Speaker 0: Okay So things of the day.
Speaker 0: natural selection 2 as you know has gotten to the point where it's.
Speaker 0: it's playable.
Speaker 0: I've been playing it a lot.
Speaker 0: I Really like natural selection.
Speaker 1: Well, except it's still laggy.
Speaker 1: if they fix the lag, it'd be great.
Speaker 0: And I really like natural selection too.
Speaker 0: It's like 80 there to be in my go-to non counter-strike non tribes 2 game fps.
Speaker 0: but One interesting thing is that it's still in beta.
Speaker 0: i'm not going to talk about all the stuff around ns2.
Speaker 0: I'm going to link to a video showing how wall jumping works for skulks as of beta 201.
Speaker 1: Because this I think they just released 203 which is the pex build.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: There's a 203 They're gonna have a they're gonna have a big They're gonna have a big pex booth They're all gonna be there.
Speaker 1: so we can harass them and say hey Stop fixing this other shit like skull jumping and fix the lag because it doesn't matter how good the scope junking is If there's lag the skull jumping is pretty great.
Speaker 0: It is great though, and I I don't know what else I can say.
Speaker 0: But if you watch this i'm gonna say a few things that a few forum eyes got pissed off about.
Speaker 0: but the rest of you whatever.
Speaker 0: one Uh, see that constantly pulls up and see all those debug things he turns on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's in real pc games too.
Speaker 0: So, uh, fuck your xbox.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: and two Uh, I would love to see a game be able to implement something like this the way that it is implemented With the skill set that implements it with anything other than a mouse and keyboard.
Speaker 1: Oh rims bringing out the mouse keyboard smackdown.
Speaker 1: That's usually my job.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: It is not the best way for all first person view games.
Speaker 1: But for games that test metroid prime, right metroid prime Yeah.
Speaker 0: But for games that test these kinds of skills that are designed to be this kind of game There is no better way to play it short of some sort of like vr helmet display that we are.
Speaker 0: Oh my god I was thinking about vr5.
Speaker 0: I watched that show from day one till the end on tv.
Speaker 0: You know what vr5 is i've heard of.
Speaker 0: there's vr1 vr2 vr3 vr4 and then there's like vr7 where they talk to dead people.
Speaker 1: man I used to watch all these stupid shows on tv that looked all kind of sci-fi technology like but were kind of just dumb Yep, crap and they all got cancelled like you were watching mantis.
Speaker 0: I didn't watch it because it was always on sci-fi.
Speaker 1: while I was waiting for something else to come on I wasn't on side.
Speaker 1: I watched it on network tv.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was like I watched reruns.
Speaker 1: It was about like this crippled dude, but he had like an exoskeleton Armor thing that he would put on to go, you know, do do goody stuff Uh, and he was awesome.
Speaker 1: And then there was viper.
Speaker 1: There was a guy with an awesome car.
Speaker 1: It was like a rip-off of night rider But it sucked and it was mostly a dodge viper ad.
Speaker 0: I watched night rider.
Speaker 1: Well night rider is actually good.
Speaker 0: Is it?
Speaker 0: is it the hoff?
Speaker 0: When?
Speaker 0: so it's good, but it's good in a in a particular better than he-man.
Speaker 0: Uh You could say that about almost every.
Speaker 0: i'm just saying act of human.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of things you have nostalgia for that are worse than night rider.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 0: I have yet to find anything.
Speaker 0: I had nostalgia for that was worse.
Speaker 0: The disparity between what I remembered and what it was for he-man was literally the worst of anything ever.
Speaker 1: There are other things that weren't necessarily sci-fi directly, but they had sci-fi stuff like briscoe county got cancelled.
Speaker 0: I like briscoe county jr.
Speaker 1: And what was the other one?
Speaker 0: It was like there was young indiana jones.
Speaker 1: That was awful.
Speaker 1: Uh, there was the something.
Speaker 1: there was the something.
Speaker 1: something lives of so and so.
Speaker 1: or it was like the guy.
Speaker 1: Did he have a genie or I can't remember what the name of this was.
Speaker 0: I dream of genie.
Speaker 1: No, I dream of genie's.
Speaker 0: good though, um, not as good as bewitched.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was like the something.
Speaker 1: something lives of something.
Speaker 1: something mainly because the guy was stupid.
Speaker 1: I think he was like I have an all-powerful and loyal girlfriend.
Speaker 1: It was like about a guy who was like cursed and he had to save some number of lives.
Speaker 0: Uh mcgyver.
Speaker 1: No mcgyver wasn't cursed It was a guy had to save some number of people's lives.
Speaker 1: He lived in like a mansion or something.
Speaker 0: And okay, so not quantum league.
Speaker 1: It was like a disney show.
Speaker 1: It was on ebc.
Speaker 0: I have no idea what you're talking about.
Speaker 0: I gotta find.
Speaker 1: I think it's like the 99 lives.
Speaker 0: I said mcgyver.
Speaker 0: I was thinking quantum leap I like mcgyver.
Speaker 1: Yeah Nah, maybe it was like the 909.
Speaker 0: Did you see the mcgyver movie?
Speaker 1: No, I didn't even know there's such a thing to exist.
Speaker 0: It's actually pretty good.
Speaker 1: I think See now I can't remember how many lives it was.
Speaker 0: Well, anyway, what's your thing of the day?
Speaker 1: Oh, so usually right I hate april fool's day because april fool's day has become not a day of fooling uh people or pranking people but a day of let's ruin our website.
Speaker 0: Now some of those things are cool like the google 8-bit thing.
Speaker 0: I thought was really cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some of the things are cool, but they're not april fools.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: We have two holidays We have fuck the internet day and we have april fool's day.
Speaker 1: I was very happy that april fool's day landed on a sunday this year.
Speaker 0: I was very unhappy because I pull shit every year on april fool's day.
Speaker 0: But if i'm at home alone rendering video for packs and anime boston There's no one to fool.
Speaker 1: Well, that's actually fooling i'm talking about.
Speaker 1: I was glad for the internet because it meant that a A lot of websites those people aren't working sunday and this will usually internet activity goes way down on the weekend Which meant less bullshit internet faking activity less fake news stories and nonsense.
Speaker 1: good Uh, you know, but at the same time it meant that well, you know, you're internetting less on sunday.
Speaker 1: So if there are any good things that are fake you might miss them, right?
Speaker 1: Uh so far from what I can tell there was only one good thing that was on the internet in april fool's day.
Speaker 1: Now it's on youtube.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter whether its association with april fool's day is good or bad or not.
Speaker 1: It is in itself a good thing no matter what day it came out.
Speaker 1: Mccris did a pony song.
Speaker 1: It's awesome.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I did not know this was a thing.
Speaker 1: go to youtube.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, and you listen to that shit.
Speaker 1: How do you?
Speaker 0: how did you beat me to a pony?
Speaker 1: Ah?
Speaker 1: All right, mccris did a song about ponies.
Speaker 1: he must be a brony i'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: Uh, he's awesome.
Speaker 1: Anyway Oh my god, check this shit out.
Speaker 1: thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Uh, you yell at me for pony things in the day.
Speaker 1: granted mccris thing.
Speaker 1: It is video game day.
Speaker 1: Take that mccris thing.
Speaker 0: last time I saw Concert was at katsu khan and I remember because during the concert he said I will stay And shake hands with as many of you as will line up to shake hands with me.
Speaker 0: and he stayed At the end of his encore shook hands with thousands of people, you know I've heard some gossips about him that are you know positive or negative?
Speaker 0: i've heard both ways.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when I met him, but I mean, you know regardless of those gossips I mean dude shaking hands with everyone at the concert and when I met him he seemed like his music.
Speaker 0: Actually, the only bad rumors I heard had to do with dealing with him on a professional level.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like as a person I heard he was awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: Uh, mccris.
Speaker 1: He made a good song about ponies.
Speaker 1: That's all that matters right now.
Speaker 0: so In the meta moment i'm gonna be at packs.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah packs east 2012 There's pretty much no other news and then right after that packs prime 2012 in seattle in september.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh.
Speaker 0: So we're also going to be at anime boston 2012 for approximately three and a half hours than saturday.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 1: Probably enough time.
Speaker 1: What time is that?
Speaker 0: So here let's talk about packs.
Speaker 1: first go over the whole schedule our our schedule so that I know what it is All right, the entire geek night schedule.
Speaker 1: So tomorrow including our friends.
Speaker 0: So tomorrow on wednesday i'm packing my shit And i'm going to.
Speaker 1: i'm going to work i'm coming home and i'm packing my shit.
Speaker 0: I'm ironing my kilts I'm putting all the videos on usb sticks.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna clean my.
Speaker 1: I don't have that many clothes that are dirty But i'm gonna do some laundry tonight tonight Because if I wash the kilt, it'll be dry in time.
Speaker 0: All right, so thursday We're gonna be in boston from like noon onward now mostly eating Lounging friending and swimming gaming and gaming.
Speaker 1: I got bathing suit.
Speaker 0: I got bathing suit on the checklist, but we're gonna game.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna play some games.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much what we're gonna do for four days.
Speaker 0: luke crane and jared sorenson will be about play some games with them playing games and the frcf playing games.
Speaker 0: But uh that aside eclipse so all night.
Speaker 0: first event friday At noon In the tabletop.
Speaker 0: friday at 10 30 keynote, uh, oh, yeah I don't have the schedule of pack stuff.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about things we're involved in.
Speaker 1: Oh, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Is that noon panel that we're doing friday?
Speaker 1: We're not doing it.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's good.
Speaker 0: No, we're not doing that one.
Speaker 1: I was like, wow, does that overlap q a number one?
Speaker 0: All right, guys, if you want to know what to do at packs other than our stuff.
Speaker 0: We've done like four shows.
Speaker 0: It's the same thing.
Speaker 0: Line up like three hours early.
Speaker 0: go to the key.
Speaker 1: This is the riven scott switch episode.
Speaker 0: stay for the q&a because it's great.
Speaker 0: Ask a really weird question because it'll be funny.
Speaker 0: bring something from your foreign country Yes Then play games until you pass out.
Speaker 0: if you haven't been to the pecs concerts before.
Speaker 0: Line up forever and go to them because they're fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: If you've seen them a bunch of times skip them and play games.
Speaker 0: Yep That's it that's packs.
Speaker 0: go to the omega-thon finale.
Speaker 0: Go to the last two rounds of the omega-thon because they've been pretty good the last few years.
Speaker 1: go to expo hall once.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now don't line up to go to the expo hall.
Speaker 1: It's a cool stick starter room.
Speaker 1: Check it out.
Speaker 0: Yeah actually Our friend laurine green will be in there A lot of cool stuff as will the company that emily and a bunch of the frc people and friends all work.
Speaker 1: Josh macy newman's gonna have mobile frame zero in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's gonna be.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be the happening room.
Speaker 0: Oh, he's on a panel that's not on our schedule here along with luke but oh well.
Speaker 1: Oh, well,
Speaker 0: so friday noon uh luke crane of uh, sorin crane guy who made burning wheel is doing a panel called what is Burning wheel
Speaker 1: nice panel
Speaker 0: at 6 p.m Oh, no, wait, so at 4 30 p.m on friday In Uh panel 309 at anime boston we are performing the how to run a panel panel, but We are performing via telepresence because we cannot actually be there for it.
Speaker 0: So we will not actually be at anime boston in in the flesh on friday at 6 p.m On friday at pax in the tabletop workshop theater We will be doing the geek nights board game workshop where we will teach you not just how to play now the motherfucking win Agricola carcassonne and one other game.
Speaker 0: It's going to be awesome.
Speaker 1: It will be pretty great Theater.
Speaker 0: it has a raised stage seats for like 60 people and it has tables ready to play games.
Speaker 0: It is a workshop room for tabletop stuff.
Speaker 0: There's a huge schedule all con in there.
Speaker 1: We need to set up some sort of ghetto elmo with the webcam type situation.
Speaker 0: I'm on top of that.
Speaker 0: All right, the the con might also be on top of that nice.
Speaker 0: so At 10 p.m on friday in the arachnid theater Rachnid going cardboard the documentary on board games by our friend Lauren green of tcat productions will be screened and there will be a q a Either before or to follow.
Speaker 0: I forget which we may.
Speaker 0: we might show up and say hi answer some questions Shake some hands.
Speaker 0: Don't ask us to autograph it.
Speaker 0: We didn't make it.
Speaker 0: Lauren green made it.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Ask her and or we were in it for like five minutes Don't you know?
Speaker 1: and we don't even deserve that.
Speaker 0: so saturday's the big day.
Speaker 0: at 10 a.m Jared sorensen is doing spooky manner in the tabletop workshop.
Speaker 0: That's like action castle but way fun.
Speaker 0: Not that action castle.
Speaker 1: I think it's one of the hardest ones too.
Speaker 0: I think so, too.
Speaker 0: I think space station space station's the hardest.
Speaker 0: I like it a lot though At 4 30 p.m.
Speaker 0: We are doing our one lecture at packs as opposed to a panel or a workshop.
Speaker 0: Let's play money making game in the cat theater.
Speaker 0: We will be talking about how you have a vision.
Speaker 0: you want to make a game But you also need money And the way you make money will totally the money making game will totally fuck up your vision.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Then at 6 p.m Luke crane In the tabletop workshop theater is doing the dnd.
Speaker 0: You never knew.
Speaker 0: his argument Is that you know, we indie rpgers trash on dnd Legitimately, but if you play old dnd As it's written no one ever plays dnd as it's written like second ed or earlier.
Speaker 0: he's talking about early dnd.
Speaker 0: It is way fun.
Speaker 0: It is just not the kind of game people try to make dnd Play it by the book and it is a way fun game in and of itself.
Speaker 1: I really always want to play it by the book, but no one else does.
Speaker 0: So overlapping with that at the penny arcade expo at six o'clock p.m.
Speaker 0: We are doing motivational anime at anime boston.
Speaker 0: It is we're talking about like initial d and drops of god and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: You know how when you read those shonen mangas that are about a thing Like golf or something and it makes you really want to do that thing.
Speaker 0: Maybe if you shouldn't do that thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're talking about all those.
Speaker 0: and then right after that in the same room We're doing diamonds in the rough all the all the anime that either was just shy of glory But you should watch anyway or the anime that is perfect for you, but you would never even think to watch.
Speaker 1: This is all early saturday, right?
Speaker 0: Uh 6 p.m.
Speaker 0: And 7 30 p.m.
Speaker 0: Are those two?
Speaker 1: Oh and saturday?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's it on saturday.
Speaker 0: All right on sunday.
Speaker 0: Uh jungle adventure and z ward two uh parsley games are at 2 p.m.
Speaker 0: And 4 p.m respectively in the workshop theater going late sunday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we will be at the omegathon finale.
Speaker 0: That's right after getting some uh, some tasty brunch.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh pax.
Speaker 1: Uh, I feel like there's just so much going on the weekend.
Speaker 1: I'm, not gonna have enough time to do the everything I want to do which is making me almost be like no Don't worry.
Speaker 1: We need a fourth day.
Speaker 0: There's another pax in like six months and you know what?
Speaker 1: Not that long after that is magfest at least that pax won't have an enemy of boston at the same time or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, if it does well, we'll deal with it All right.
Speaker 0: So angry birds space It's pretty fun It's pretty good, uh It's about the same.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I enjoy it in the same way that I enjoyed the original angry birds.
Speaker 0: I find myself playing it When i'm pooping when i'm waiting for the subway to take me somewhere while i'm listening to a podcast.
Speaker 1: That's the same time i'm playing.
Speaker 1: actually I beat it beat it.
Speaker 0: I am most of the way through the ice world because I haven't played it that much.
Speaker 1: Well beat it depends on what you.
Speaker 1: uh, You know scott.
Speaker 0: I mean clearly you've gotten three stars on everything and all the golden eggs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no i've never done that nor would I. no I know people who have.
Speaker 1: It's the thing about angry birds.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, you can sort of play it any way you want, right?
Speaker 1: You know some people they just play it to beat all the levels.
Speaker 1: That's what I do.
Speaker 1: All right other people Uh, they actually play and they try to get three stars and everything and it's like are you kidding me?
Speaker 1: That would take so much time Forget it.
Speaker 0: What are you just terrible at angry birds?
Speaker 1: Maybe if I had see is the thing.
Speaker 1: i'm playing it on an iphone.
Speaker 1: you're playing it on your you know, nexus s right?
Speaker 1: If you were playing it on A tablet like an ipad.
Speaker 1: It's so much bigger.
Speaker 1: You have so much more precision in the control.
Speaker 1: because you have such a larger area.
Speaker 1: It's like lower mouse sensitivity.
Speaker 0: So scott if you want to do it, you can actually get a much higher score.
Speaker 1: I think scott you want to really do it with iphone.
Speaker 0: play the html5 version on a pc.
Speaker 1: That's right mouse You could you could click click.
Speaker 1: Yep That's the the way to get the highest score, but I don't think that they have an html5 version of anger bird space.
Speaker 0: So i've never paid for an angry birds.
Speaker 0: i'm just playing the one where occasionally a stupid ad pops up.
Speaker 1: No, I always pay.
Speaker 1: it's a one dollar right and I think about it.
Speaker 1: I'm, like should I pay the one dollar?
Speaker 1: and then I think about it and i'm like, you know what?
Speaker 1: Uh, i've thrown away a dollar.
Speaker 1: like isn't even a bagel and it's like I bought a bagel this morning.
Speaker 1: It's like what am I getting more pleasure from that bagel that I got from a street cart?
Speaker 1: For a dollar or so scott is angry birds the new.
Speaker 1: uh, so it's worth it for me to buy the bagel for a dollar.
Speaker 1: It's worth it to buy anger birds.
Speaker 0: It's got the deli that opened up downstairs.
Speaker 0: I can get a breakfast that is like Pancake home fries some meat like bacon or sausage and coffee or juice for like for exactly two dollars.
Speaker 0: Two dollars.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh my two motherfucking dollars.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, because like for me I go get bacon egg and cheese on an everything bagel.
Speaker 1: That's 345.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the place downstairs is uh way cheap.
Speaker 1: Is it good?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: The uh lunch is okay, though Even so right.
Speaker 1: if i'm gonna spend two dollars on that even though that might be good I can send two dollars in that you're not gonna play with that food while you're pooping.
Speaker 0: And that is where angry birds fills a niche.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: Angry birds is just this nice.
Speaker 0: Uh, I don't know.
Speaker 0: confluence of good character design with simple gameplay and a really effective pricing and marketing model.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 1: it's also You know, it's sort of in this weird in-between space right like.
Speaker 1: it's not stupid farmville where you're not actually doing anything.
Speaker 1: You're just clicking and upgrading things with no skill or knowledge, right?
Speaker 0: It is a game of skill.
Speaker 1: there is but it's a very.
Speaker 1: The skill matters only a little bit right because it's a little bit.
Speaker 1: it's mostly problem solving skill Which is where should I shoot which bird in which direction?
Speaker 1: To you know.
Speaker 1: get the most damage done, you know, so that all the pigs are destroyed by the time i'm done with these birds You know, so you started to figure it out based on the lay of the land.
Speaker 0: it taps into that the same urge That makes you smash a lego thing as soon as you build it.
Speaker 1: But there is some sort of randomness and luck, right?
Speaker 1: You'll do the same exact thing three or four times But you'll be slightly off a little bit.
Speaker 1: and it makes all the difference in the world because of the physics engine Is so, you know, it's the box 2d physics engine.
Speaker 1: So it's.
Speaker 1: it's not some precise thing where there is an exact answer and you can do the exact same move over and over again.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like you'll do the exact same strategy and you just happen to hit like a micro spec higher And that causes a boulder to fall a different direction.
Speaker 0: timing matters.
Speaker 0: One extra dynamite goes off in the new angry bird space than the old one because there are things that move.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and i've watched him just keep moving.
Speaker 0: I've had to time my birds around like I bust something and it's like wagging back and forth.
Speaker 0: I got to shoot a bird over it.
Speaker 1: There's also a lot of situations.
Speaker 1: the gravity is the biggest thing, right?
Speaker 1: Not you think.
Speaker 1: obviously the gravity of the planets affects the trajectory of the birds orbiting the planets.
Speaker 1: doing a slingshot.
Speaker 1: That's the obvious thing, right?
Speaker 1: You can tell that right from the first screen.
Speaker 1: the thing That's key that people don't realize is the gravity crushes the pigs as they get pulled into the planets.
Speaker 1: There'll be pigs floating between a planet.
Speaker 1: If you just nudge them so they get into the gravity field they'll slam into the planet and die.
Speaker 0: Yep, or i'll like bop a rock into the atmosphere and it'll circle around and kill them all.
Speaker 0: I don't have to hit any birds in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or there'll be a meteor outside the gravity field.
Speaker 1: You'll bump the meteor into the gravity or the asteroid into the gravity field.
Speaker 1: then it will accelerate.
Speaker 1: Just say accelerate towards the planet not around the planet.
Speaker 0: Well, it'll go around in the spiral and then smash everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's also the new ice bird.
Speaker 1: anything He touches turns to ice and you think and then of course, obviously that opens things up for the bluebird who's excellent at smashing ice.
Speaker 1: So you ice something that's like heavy rocks, then you bring the bluebird in and he smashes it up.
Speaker 1: But there's another thing you can do with the ice thing.
Speaker 1: if you ice up some stuff that's under some heavy rocks And it's in a gravity field Now those heavy rocks will crush the ice immediately bringing the whole thing down towards the planet.
Speaker 0: He also has much better timing than similar things in the first game where you can skim him off of something.
Speaker 0: It'll ice it a little and you've got some leeway before.
Speaker 0: you have to.
Speaker 0: you know, make him go full ice.
Speaker 0: So you can skim one thing have it like skip off leave some ice and then smash into something else into the full.
Speaker 1: You can get some extra ice out of him.
Speaker 0: He doesn't just you know ice and kind of like how you in the old game you drop the white bird With your little egg like you drop it.
Speaker 1: I'm so glad the white bird is not in this game.
Speaker 1: I love that bird.
Speaker 1: He's my most hated bird.
Speaker 0: I hated the fucking boomerang bird.
Speaker 1: boomerang bird is also not in this game.
Speaker 1: good.
Speaker 1: Thank god Fuck those birds.
Speaker 0: No, but I love the white bird because I draw I want to make Under something and then drop the egg.
Speaker 0: So he'd fly up and hit something and the egg would fly down and hit something.
Speaker 1: if I may if I was working for Rovio, you know what I would come out with.
Speaker 1: I would come out with not a full game But just a level set and the level set would be angry birds.
Speaker 1: black nothing Nothing, but black bird, but to make up for the fact that it'd be too easy with nothing but black bird It's like the pigs have built the biggest fortresses like they're just like six rocks deep and like you got to smash your way in there.
Speaker 1: You know with all black birds, it would be the best I'm waiting for versus angry birds where you've got.
Speaker 0: imagine if you had two planets or two things And this wouldn't be a phone game anymore.
Speaker 0: I guess it could be yeah where i'm shooting birds at you.
Speaker 0: You're shooting birds at me in real time and I got pigs to protect.
Speaker 0: you got pigs to protect.
Speaker 1: No, that's not how I would do it.
Speaker 1: What I would do is I would put pigs in the middle right
Speaker 0: who kills the most and
Speaker 1: I would have simultaneously firing one two three go Right
Speaker 0: and you set a trajectory and then you both hit you'd go they go and then
Speaker 1: Right, but the question is let's say we both hit something right a tower and the tower collapses on a pig.
Speaker 1: who gets the points?
Speaker 0: Maybe it's co-op and there's some where you have to time everything right.
Speaker 1: co-op is excellent Excellent idea.
Speaker 0: I think that'll all come if they.
Speaker 0: uh, I would invest in them if I could.
Speaker 1: yeah Uh, is there anything else to say about angry birds?
Speaker 1: Oh, that's right.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I was sort of under the assumption when I paid my dollar for it that I was getting the whole game.
Speaker 1: But that was like, you know if you buy angry birds angry bird seasons You pay the dollar you get the whole game and you keep getting updates too like since i've gotten them They keep adding seasons to anger bird seasons and it costs nothing, right?
Speaker 1: They just keep adding them all the time Uh, and I suspect they will continue to add them for as long as they exist Which is awesome because they don't have to pay any more money.
Speaker 1: anger bird space.
Speaker 1: I paid a dollar and you got level one and you got level two, but then there's another level the danger zone.
Speaker 1: And the danger zone was not for it was not included in that first dollar.
Speaker 1: I paid.
Speaker 1: I had to pay another dollar.
Speaker 0: Oh my god now it's the cost of that breakfast exactly.
Speaker 1: Which is still.
Speaker 1: I paid the other dollar, you know, if they would have just said from the beginning anger bird space two dollars I would have paid the two dollars no question and I would not have been angry because I would not.
Speaker 0: scott's an angry Scott.
Speaker 1: now i'm not angry because it's two dollars or the two dollars wasn't worth it.
Speaker 1: I'm only angry because yeah anger bird, right?
Speaker 1: Because I was deceived right?
Speaker 1: They didn't tell me.
Speaker 1: Hey, you're paying a dollar for half of anger bird space.
Speaker 1: They said you're paying a dollar for angry bird space and then later they're like, oh just kidding You didn't actually pay a dollar for anger bird space.
Speaker 1: You paid a dollar for half of anger bird space.
Speaker 1: That's like if I went to the car dealership and they said here this car is a thousand dollars I say okay Here's a thousand dollars and then I go to pick up the car and the wheels are missing again.
Speaker 1: minus the wheel.
Speaker 0: That's exactly what they do Except instead of having things missing.
Speaker 1: if they would have said minus the wheels and the whole car actually cost fifteen hundred I would not have complained.
Speaker 0: They'll put extra stuff on there and be like, oh, yeah, you gotta pay for this, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's bullshit.
Speaker 1: Just freaking tell me that, you know, just tell me that danger zone is not included from the get-go.
Speaker 1: You know say one dollar angry bird space minus danger zone.
Speaker 0: So at least it's not false advertising anyway, but it's not much else to say.
Speaker 0: fun game It's worth the dollar or the free and we're gonna be packs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, fax is coming.
Speaker 0: Yep fax.
Speaker 1: All right, it's enough faxing.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: There's never enough faxing.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music cat lee for web design and brando k for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech mondays gaming tuesdays anime comic wednesdays and indiscriminate thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.