Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, January 10th, 2012.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: eclipse the board game.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh.
Speaker 0: We haven't done a show in for fuck ever But we have returned that geek nights is not over.
Speaker 0: when will it be over?
Speaker 1: when one of us dies?
Speaker 0: You think so like a 50 year old man.
Speaker 1: I'll put it this way if you die.
Speaker 1: I'll keep doing the show.
Speaker 1: great Thanks, but if I die will you keep doing the show?
Speaker 0: Maybe maybe eventually it will return.
Speaker 1: you might have to learn some audio editing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah We'll see all right, but we're back.
Speaker 1: geek nights is back on its regular semi-permanent schedule until other conventions get in the way.
Speaker 0: Thanks, East's back.
Speaker 1: Cease is coming and speaking of which backs East is sold out.
Speaker 1: So if you didn't do what we said why don't you know?
Speaker 0: he said we always steer you right?
Speaker 0: When have we steered you wrong?
Speaker 1: the fucking day that packs these badges went on sale?
Speaker 1: You should have bought them.
Speaker 1: It's been many days since then.
Speaker 1: you have no excuse.
Speaker 1: No badges.
Speaker 0: at this point It's not even gonna be like.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to teach you a lesson anymore now.
Speaker 0: I'm just going to admonish you.
Speaker 0: It's like well you deserve it you dumbass.
Speaker 1: however if you did not get a badge and you need a badge One way to do this is to submit a panel or lecture and get it accepted or below or sir Low of that.
Speaker 1: another way is to buy an exhibitor table.
Speaker 1: that gives you a bunch of badges.
Speaker 1: that also cost Thousands of dollars.
Speaker 0: depends on the size of the table depends.
Speaker 0: if you got any video game to pimp it could be prices significantly lower But bigger table you get the more badges it comes with.
Speaker 0: that is also true.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 1: I don't have the price sheet for this year.
Speaker 1: I should get that.
Speaker 0: it also gets you in the exhibitor room slightly early Cuz I.
Speaker 1: while you're setting up your shit You can look at everyone else's shit or as Scott was alluding to you can sign up to be an enforcer.
Speaker 0: That's a good move.
Speaker 1: They need enforcers for PAX East and let me tell you I've been staff for anime cons video game cons gaming cons generic cons that aren't generic on and PAX pretty much has the best deal for staff in terms of responsibility versus fun versus respect versus reward.
Speaker 1: and Well now see the thing is before The reward ratio was kind of skewed because you could spend some dollars to get a PAX badge Or you could enforce and get in for free, but have to work a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: now It's either in force or don't fucking go to packs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like if you're gonna enforce though and try to you know get in that way only do it if you're actually gonna be Serious and do a good job with the enforcing.
Speaker 0: don't try to enforce Just to get a badge and then do a shit ass.
Speaker 0: enforce cuz.
Speaker 0: yeah Robert who will come and kick you in the day?
Speaker 1: think you can pull off what most anime cons pull off.
Speaker 1: you get to be Quote-unquote gopher and do some grunt work, and then you're in now.
Speaker 1: You've pretty much got to be a badass to be an enforcer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can go watch this PA.
Speaker 0: There's a recent penny arcade television episode about enforcers.
Speaker 0: go watch that shit and then decide if that's for you.
Speaker 1: Yes If Aaron see looks like a man that you can respect and take orders from then I think he's identified in the video as airwolf.
Speaker 1: Ah, the thing is you know what he's identified as the man who looks smashing in a real kill not a you till a kill I killed.
Speaker 0: that's right Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but yeah PAX East it's coming.
Speaker 1: It's coming.
Speaker 1: We'll be there doing stuff.
Speaker 0: Are you gonna met a moment in opening bit because it's sold out?
Speaker 1: sure as was expected.
Speaker 1: There's one other bit I don't want to talk about though.
Speaker 1: PAX East is sold out.
Speaker 1: You're gonna see a lot of people at the con and on Craigslist selling packs badges.
Speaker 0: do not buy.
Speaker 1: the odds are I'm gonna say Pretty much like 70%.
Speaker 1: there's.
Speaker 0: someone tries to sell you a badge and they aren't someone you know And they're not selling it through an official channel or they're not being cool.
Speaker 1: They won't show you ID.
Speaker 0: They're not in the penny arcade forum.
Speaker 1: Like you don't have evidence that they're a gamer who legitimately like had a reason.
Speaker 1: now he can't go.
Speaker 1: It's probably counterfeit.
Speaker 1: We're gonna make a video later because I've got in fact in front of me a small pile of Counterfeit badges from the last time.
Speaker 0: they're not gonna let you the fuck in and you know what?
Speaker 0: So you're gonna buy a hotel room in Boston travel there try to go in and they're gonna say fuck Get the hell out of here, and I'll tell you what.
Speaker 1: if I see a counterfeit badge I'm just gonna tear it in half and keep walking because you know what.
Speaker 1: here's how to tell a counterfeit badge.
Speaker 1: You can tear them in half.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you can't tear it in half It's probably but I heard but accordingly that you know I have received information that this year They are still mailing badges, which will give counterfeiters time to copy them, but they have taken measures.
Speaker 0: They said this they're taking some measures.
Speaker 0: We do not know what measures.
Speaker 0: They are to make it harder to counterfeit.
Speaker 0: Imagine the badge is going to be harder to copy.
Speaker 1: the thing is once we knew there were counterfeit badges like once we knew that Was the thing and someone showed us one.
Speaker 1: you could pretty much spot him a mile away.
Speaker 1: like there's one There's one.
Speaker 1: There's one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I have it on good authority, but this is no way official.
Speaker 1: This is just me here saying from other people who may or may not know things That there will be no secure for people who have a counterfeit badge.
Speaker 1: You will not be let in if you were caught with it.
Speaker 1: They're probably just gonna take the badge away, and you're fucked anyway.
Speaker 0: So now who's?
Speaker 0: that's not metamoment nice.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about any packs in the meta moment now.
Speaker 0: Okay, so If you do not know right Kotaku, which is a blog that is much maligned because it is on the gawker network But at the same time it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: Well,
Speaker 0: I read it only because it's one of the only gaming blogs that has actual people mainly one person bright In Japan and they post a lot of posts that aren't even about games and stuff a lot of times But are about Japanese things that aren't really posted on other English language gaming blogs such as they'll have like cosplay photos from comic cat or they'll have something about like you know some idol who's playing some video games or This crazy game is coming out in the arcades in Japan like Gundam pods.
Speaker 0: You won't see that shit on joystick or IGN or pretty much anywhere, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that's why I still reads the Kotaku, but The guy the number one guy at least at Kotaku is Brian crescent e and he was pretty.
Speaker 0: he was a pretty good guy Pretty good guy, but he left and he didn't say where he was going, but the next day the news came out.
Speaker 0: Apparently there's some company called Vox.
Speaker 0: I don't know much about them, but what they did is They have pulled the ultimate coup in the world of games journalism.
Speaker 0: They went and they got Chris Grant.
Speaker 0: Chris Grant was Like the number one guy at the joystick from what I heard, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, then they went out and they got Justin McElroy also A guy who is from game pro PC gamer.
Speaker 1: Wow Two really good legendary guys is pretty good, isn't it?
Speaker 0: Then they got Brian crescent e from from Kotaku.
Speaker 0: Then they got Russ Pitts who was from gamers at jobs.
Speaker 0: I used to listen to his podcast the gamers jobs radio And He is used to be the editor-in-chief of the escapist So he's one of the awesomest.
Speaker 0: Russ Pitts is like probably the awesomest on the list.
Speaker 0: Then they got Chris planty who is a guy who did a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: escape his joy.
Speaker 0: It was this games editor at ugo.com.
Speaker 0: They got rush Rush dick from MTV News and a whole bunch of other things.
Speaker 0: six They got Arthur geez the previews editor joysticks And Griffin McElroy who has been writing about games for seven years.
Speaker 0: He was a contributing editor at Joystick and Eight people.
Speaker 0: God, yeah, they got all.
Speaker 0: they pretty much went out and they stole the a-list guys from every team.
Speaker 0: This is a Yankees situation all the free agents.
Speaker 0: Just get the best guy in every team and put them all in one gaming blog.
Speaker 0: The blog doesn't exist yet, but when it does it's gonna be the gaming blog.
Speaker 0: You can just delete joystick from your RSS reader.
Speaker 0: now This you can filter Kotaku's.
Speaker 0: the only see the post by Brian Griscenti.
Speaker 1: I mean that right Ashcraft because this tells us something very interesting though I mean we make fun of video game journalism a lot because it's kind of crappy by and large.
Speaker 0: the main problem I have with gert-game journalism is that there are plenty of good game journalists and a lot of these people have excellent Journalism skills and they have plenty of plenty good web journalism skills and a lot of them have a lot of knowledge of recent games.
Speaker 0: Which are the ones they talk about the most?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so they do a good job.
Speaker 0: The problem is very few of these people, you know actually have a deep knowledge of games Period.
Speaker 0: so their perspective is just like hey a new game came out.
Speaker 0: Is it fun?
Speaker 0: and it's like a lot of people that's what they want, but it's so shallow.
Speaker 0: and You know the real meat is someone who actually you know I mean Totillo who just took over for Kotaku because Griscenti left, right?
Speaker 0: He's also he's the perfect example excellent journalism skills.
Speaker 0: I've met him.
Speaker 0: He's a nice guy.
Speaker 0: He's well-meaning, but he just doesn't have game knowledge.
Speaker 0: I know ten times more about games.
Speaker 1: So why aren't we doing game journalism?
Speaker 0: I don't have journalism shittily don't have journalism skills But this tells us a couple of things.
Speaker 1: The most interesting thing to come out of this is that you know, we make so much fun of video game journalism.
Speaker 1: The fact that this coup was possible means that there either aren't Non-competes in that industry clearly or that people are betting that nobody has the wherewithal to follow through on them and That is a sign of a very immature industry Which means that we're kind of.
Speaker 1: this is a major turning point because now in the future in this industry There's gonna be a whole bunch of non-compete BS Which will actually make it more difficult for anyone to compete with this new offering.
Speaker 0: Well, I think what it's shown more than anything right is something that I knew but I didn't realize.
Speaker 0: it's like oh I knew that but you didn't think this is the opposite of the Peter principle.
Speaker 0: No, which is that in the?
Speaker 0: you know, if you look at for example the newspaper world, right?
Speaker 0: Very few people pay attention to who the writer is on newspaper articles, right?
Speaker 0: It's about the name of the newspaper.
Speaker 0: It's like oh it's an article in the New York Times about the blah blah blah right in game journalism.
Speaker 0: It's all about the person who is doing the reviewing because the you know, the it's it's not about where they are.
Speaker 1: Here's something interesting.
Speaker 1: It's not just game journalism.
Speaker 1: anime journalism is the same way and
Speaker 0: actually
Speaker 1: anecdotally Connecticut right, you know, we run the panels Department of Connecticut all the panels and workshops and The biggest question we got last year was people who didn't know the schedule was out all the titles everything was there But they wanted to know.
Speaker 1: I want to see the panel by Joey Jojo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't care what it's on I want to see panels by this guy.
Speaker 0: this is because the internet a lot, you know in the in the social media Especially, you know, you're not connecting with the brand.
Speaker 0: right you're connecting with this, you know Cuz when brands advertise themselves and market themselves these days a lot of them are just so corporate and have corporate Speak and you're not actually connecting with them, you know, for example Hasbro, right?
Speaker 0: It's like we are announcing the blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: It's like great.
Speaker 0: Thanks guys, but the Individuals when they're allowed to have the Twitter account that's associated with there Whatever you connect directly with the people doing the thing and especially in journalism We're pretty much they're tweeting and Facebook and like crazy more than any other industry Right.
Speaker 0: the consumers of the media are connecting with directly the producers and authors of the media.
Speaker 1: So this allows another principle to take fold to a degree that you can't see in technology.
Speaker 1: We always talk about how.
Speaker 1: in technology firms if there's a critical mass of smart people then Dumb people will be weeded out and that company will attract more smart people because smart people like to work as smart people.
Speaker 1: They don't like to deal.
Speaker 0: I think the only reason that any of these journalists need to team up at all Right because they could all just start their own blogs and forget working but with their power combined.
Speaker 0: But by combining they can sell.
Speaker 0: they can get more hits on the same page on the web Internet's to get and they can sell that one ad for more dollars than they could if they sold five ads that had 1/5 as many hits.
Speaker 1: but in technology, you know the other.
Speaker 1: the opposite is true.
Speaker 0: And also, you know the rate of content production.
Speaker 0: if you have one blog by yourself you get an article today But if you get a blog with eight people Get a whole bunch of articles per day.
Speaker 1: But back to my point.
Speaker 1: the opposite is true a place that has a critical mass of bad people will drive smart people away.
Speaker 1: But it's a slow process because it's hard to change jobs in a lot of industries.
Speaker 1: It so happens that this relatively immature industry Especially with the fact that you don't need an office to a degree
Speaker 0: Work from home people who send articles in and someone puts them in a blog some the
Speaker 1: cost of distribution and collaboration Everything is so low that the barrier to switching jobs is almost zero.
Speaker 1: So as a result all these factors combined and I'm actually excited about this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm looking forward to finally Of course, it might be that could potentially be better than all of the game might be bitter disappointment.
Speaker 1: You got to have guarded optimism.
Speaker 0: I think it'll be probably the best.
Speaker 0: it looks like it's gonna be the best gaming blog.
Speaker 1: That's not saying a lot but that's a high compliment.
Speaker 0: well, you know, we need one because you look around It's like which one really stands out as great.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's some that are good but they're only good in particular areas like you can get a rock-paper-shotgun and they'll do a really good job on like indie PC games and Not much else, but they do a really good job on that.
Speaker 0: or you go to like Gama Sutra And they'll do a really good job on some like, you know in-depth stuff.
Speaker 1: Well, like right now How did I learn about the next news we're talking about?
Speaker 1: I saw it on slash jot as an afterthought, right?
Speaker 0: But they won't really, you know be whatever.
Speaker 1: so speaking of the news I just saw on slash dot There's a Dungeons & Dragons 5th edition coming.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw like an inkling like maybe one sentence Nowhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is maybe on a Twitter I saw a sentence or maybe on a blog a comment or something.
Speaker 0: That was like announcement something something big and I was like whatever.
Speaker 0: and then Suddenly I see like today or yesterday like 5th edition and I'm like, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: So two interesting things.
Speaker 1: one Nobody in my circles was really talking about this.
Speaker 1: Nope, despite the fact that we're pretty deep in the role-playing community Like no one seemed to really notice.
Speaker 1: and to uh, I want to point something out.
Speaker 1: I'm stealing from Nighthawk 214 who put this little list together.
Speaker 1: 1974 first edition, that's right.
Speaker 1: 1989 so that is 15 years second ed.
Speaker 1: Okay 2000 third ed.
Speaker 0: 11 years.
Speaker 1: so it keeps getting shorter less time between editions 15 and 11 a third and a half edition sometime in between their fourth edition 2008 so eight years.
Speaker 0: so 15 11 8. what year is it?
Speaker 1: 2012 so by this rate has been four years in 40 years.
Speaker 0: Edition of Dungeons & Dragons every 16 seconds, but is the fifth edition coming out this year or next year?
Speaker 0: I mean, this is just an announcement.
Speaker 0: It does.
Speaker 0: I didn't get the feeling it's going to play testing now, really I was getting the feeling like that.
Speaker 0: They didn't even start it yet that they were just like the announcement was like We're gonna make it we're starting work now.
Speaker 0: No that it's play testing now They're.
Speaker 1: they're taking submissions to do play testing and stuff with them.
Speaker 0: Oh, I thought the submissions were really good for All.
Speaker 0: right now do I?
Speaker 1: I'm not one to be super like.
Speaker 1: when fourth edition came out I I was very I didn't like it But at the same time I didn't shit all over it because I thought my complaints were justified.
Speaker 0: Well, it sort of made sense for the times right?
Speaker 0: It's like hey, they're making Wow the tabletop RPG You know, no one feels useless.
Speaker 0: the game right was the third edition, you know, you did.
Speaker 0: you felt useless game.
Speaker 1: Where I look at and say here are problems, but those are only problems for XY and Z kind of gamers.
Speaker 1: They're not problems for our kind of gamer the letter R. so if our gamers want to play D&D fourth edition is exactly what they want, but fifth edition reeks of Being the last edition.
Speaker 1: it reeks of failure Right off the bat.
Speaker 1: and I'm really because one here's something really interesting.
Speaker 1: I'm looking at the slash shot comments.
Speaker 1: right you think slash shots a pretty big haven of like old-school D&D players.
Speaker 1: a Lot of the comments here aren't even about the fifth edition announced they're about Pathfinder.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: No There's one guy who's like, yeah Pathfinder.
Speaker 1: Most of the comments and the follow-up discussion in other places is people saying man I always want to play D&D, but I can't find anyone to play with.
Speaker 1: Yeah that in that today that is still the primary complaint of RPG people that they can't find someone to play with.
Speaker 0: It's because the people who most want to play RPGs are the people who just don't talk to people there is someone to play with In your town, even in the sticks,
Speaker 1: uh, not always
Speaker 0: almost
Speaker 1: always I think it's more that we're sheltered from that because if you live in a population center It's absolutely guaranteed that there are gigantic groups of people.
Speaker 1: But at the same time even at pretty hardcore events in New York City that we go to Most of the people there show up live in the city and say things like yeah I almost never get to play a role-playing game.
Speaker 0: You gotta set time aside for that shit.
Speaker 0: be consistent.
Speaker 0: actually fucking show up and talk to people human beings.
Speaker 0: But I heard a recess this week and they're actually gonna have a thing like get together and you know start games with people.
Speaker 1: Yep, they're gonna have open tables.
Speaker 1: They're gonna set that up.
Speaker 1: No, they're gonna.
Speaker 0: they're gonna have a thing That's like hey all you people get together and form gaming groups that will meet regularly on your own.
Speaker 0: So like gamer dating but not dating to go.
Speaker 1: We should do a show about this because they're gonna run into the problem.
Speaker 1: They always run into.
Speaker 1: The majority of players want something very different from the majority of game masters and there's already a shortage of game masters.
Speaker 0: Players.
Speaker 1: just fucking GM Jesus Christ or you're gonna have to play the weird indie games that the GM's all want to do.
Speaker 1: You can't get.
Speaker 1: no one wants to run D&D for you.
Speaker 0: You don't need someone to run D&D.
Speaker 0: Just take some fucking monsters and you're the player and the GM are basically the same.
Speaker 0: You're just monster fighting played descent instead, but that is neither here nor there.
Speaker 1: My worry is that the statements from Wizards of the coast About this.
Speaker 1: they seem to be talking about how they want the game to be more inclusive and more accessible.
Speaker 0: How is it not inclusive or accessible?
Speaker 1: I know they've pretty much streamlined everything to the point where it's almost trivial to play.
Speaker 1: I mean you could replace it with a computer game for them.
Speaker 0: You can make it, you know, like inspectors where it's a simple game where there's hardly any rules.
Speaker 1: So they seem to be going down this path where they're going to have a simple rule set that then you add.
Speaker 0: I mean, are they gonna make it like Raven long as you go along?
Speaker 1: Like oh, I want more complex rules for fighting BAM.
Speaker 1: I want more complex rules for XYZ BAM BAM.
Speaker 0: This is the fundamental problem with D&D compared to other you know, any game out there is that they seem to have this business model They won't get away from which is sell fucking tons of books, right?
Speaker 0: So we need to have a game that fits with the model of sell a lot of stuff and keep coming out with new stuff And keep selling more stuff, you know, every other RPG in the world is.
Speaker 0: I bought the book.
Speaker 0: I Have the game now.
Speaker 1: Here's a side analogy.
Speaker 1: This is a problem that Lego bricks have to this day.
Speaker 1: Pretty much every Lego brick in existence that wasn't eaten by a child or a dog is still in existence.
Speaker 1: They're pretty much indestructible.
Speaker 1: So there's a surplus of Legos.
Speaker 1: It actually becomes more and more difficult to sell Regular Lego because most people have a collection from childhood still that they give to their kids.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, I want to read some quotes from the actual announcement.
Speaker 1: official announcement from Hasbro.
Speaker 1: We seek to build a foundation for the long-term health and growth of D&D One rooted in the vital traits that make D&D unique and special.
Speaker 0: It's not unique or special.
Speaker 1: You want a game that rises above differences in play styles.
Speaker 0: Okay, that all right.
Speaker 1: I got to interrupt.
Speaker 1: I got that is the opposite of what you should say.
Speaker 1: and do?
Speaker 1: you don't want a Game that's so generic that it fits every play style.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's basically.
Speaker 0: yeah, this isn't even any rules here here.
Speaker 0: here I got it.
Speaker 0: I got it.
Speaker 0: I got the new edition of D&D.
Speaker 0: I found it.
Speaker 0: It's in my pocket.
Speaker 0: It's an index card.
Speaker 0: It says tell stories with your friends about dragons and dungeons.
Speaker 0: Sometimes roll dice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you see sometimes roll dice is key because we did our panel and you know what?
Speaker 0: That's the whole book.
Speaker 0: and then the rest ever is just expansions.
Speaker 0: buy whatever expansions you want.
Speaker 0: They had rules.
Speaker 1: They also want a game that rises above campaign settings and additions one that takes the fundamental essence of D&D and Brings it to the forefront of the game in shorts.
Speaker 1: We want a game that is as simple or complex as you please.
Speaker 1: it's action focused on combat.
Speaker 1: Yeah Intrigue, it's already focused on combat and exploration as much as you desire.
Speaker 1: now, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: They said they want a game that transcends all differences in play styles that is focused on combat intrigue and exploration these three specific things.
Speaker 0: So it's not really.
Speaker 0: it's only focused on the combat intrigue exploration play style and They've already contradicted themselves and again transcend editions.
Speaker 1: yet They're calling it fifth edition, but they're talking about a long term.
Speaker 1: So why didn't they call it final edition?
Speaker 0: or why don't they just call it?
Speaker 1: dungeons and dragons?
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe they brand it as the reboots the.
Speaker 0: What it's gonna be more like is it's gonna be a lot like they're very there.
Speaker 0: No, they're very successful like, you know You know like Ravenloft and a shard alone, whatever.
Speaker 0: I hate those games so much It's gonna be that sort of simplified rule set.
Speaker 0: those aren't.
Speaker 1: those are not by the definitions we use in lectures.
Speaker 1: role-playing games They're good games.
Speaker 0: They're gonna take a simplified rule set.
Speaker 0: They're gonna remove all the proper nouns and flavor Right to create this sort of generic system.
Speaker 0: So it'll just be like, you know Hey to fight roll numbers and dice and then there'll be books that are like Okay, you want to do Forgotten Realms or here classes for Forgotten Realms.
Speaker 1: I want Option.
Speaker 1: and then this elf book, right?
Speaker 0: So here's the setting that actually gives.
Speaker 0: here's a set of proper nouns if you want to play like this and here's a set of Proper nouns if you want to play like that, but all the rules are you know, here's the fight rule.
Speaker 0: Here's the escape from things and whether you're escaping from a dungeon of metal bars or a dungeon with laser Shields in the spaceship now same thing.
Speaker 1: That's pretty crap because there are already systems that are like that and Generic rule sets with different proper nouns do not different games make by any stretch.
Speaker 1: There's no like mechanism design.
Speaker 1: There's no like you need to gameplay that actually facilitates the kind of game you want to play.
Speaker 0: Well, we know that we know that but they don't know that the people gonna play this just want to fight things for the cost Of what they're doing.
Speaker 1: to make this mistake with D&D They could probably buy half of the indie RPG intellectual property There is in the world and just release it all under their brand.
Speaker 0: but that means it for said made money.
Speaker 0: Right a lot of you playing it.
Speaker 1: Um, yeah, but how much money did it really make?
Speaker 1: How many people do you know who pirated that shit?
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: how much money did it make?
Speaker 0: because if it was making more money wouldn't why would they be trying fifth edition?
Speaker 0: I think that a lot of people do play fourth edition because you know about as many as played third.
Speaker 0: It feels like that anyway based on just feeling which is nothing thing is.
Speaker 1: most people I see a gaming events are playing 3.5 or Pathfinder.
Speaker 0: Well, I think that they are much less successful at selling the tons of extra books for fourth edition.
Speaker 0: Which is the real reason they're doing fifth edition?
Speaker 0: because even though people are playing fourth edition, they're not making more money off.
Speaker 0: It's like they finish making money off it and they need.
Speaker 0: they can't get people to say buy another fourth edition supplement book for a new Palette ng whatever whatever right and they they're already did all the campaign settings They could do that people care about if they make up a new one.
Speaker 0: No one's gonna give a shit about it.
Speaker 0: They're also and that's why they've started making you know D&D board games like the Raven loft and such because they couldn't sell more for that book.
Speaker 0: So those have to go to fit that and those can't be pirated that easily.
Speaker 1: I mean they can be but it's pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: The only way to make more money is to come out with another Ed's.
Speaker 0: you can sell another book because so need to make money Every quarter because they're a business that's you know public.
Speaker 1: They're also committed to Getting play testing and building by consensus and getting you know criticism and it's gonna be focused group to shit.
Speaker 0: That's that's like listening to what the people in the tribes and counter-strike forums say to do.
Speaker 0: Guess what it counter-strike didn't listen to the people and they're still around.
Speaker 0: Listen to the people.
Speaker 0: they're dead quotes.
Speaker 1: by involving you in this process We can build a set of D&D rules that incorporate the wants and desires of D&D gamers around the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you listen, you don't.
Speaker 0: I think D&D needs to do the you know, Nintendo Blue Ocean, right?
Speaker 0: Fuck the D&D gamer.
Speaker 0: you got to make something that the non the other people will do.
Speaker 1: No, but then take D&D.
Speaker 0: gamers will do it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so take D&D and make the fucking beer and pretzels.
Speaker 1: that is what most people actually want out of D&D.
Speaker 1: because I want to point out at magfest where you're in this panel discussion on gamer motivations and The whole thing got turned around when we asked the open question to the audience along the lines of how many of you would Like want to play games where there is no conflict where you don't actually want a test of skill or competition of any kind We thought everyone in the room would say no.
Speaker 1: the majority of the people in the room said yes That's exactly what I want.
Speaker 1: Yeah D&D is kind of the same way.
Speaker 1: look at role-playing.
Speaker 1: All the game masters want to run these crazy systems that do very specific cool things.
Speaker 1: The average player wants beer and pretzels.
Speaker 0: D&D People do not actually you know Only hardcore people actually want to compete and test skills and battle for reals and have smart things.
Speaker 0: People just want to sit around to go lo lo lo lo, I'm dumb and I don't care Angry Birds.
Speaker 0: You know Farmville, we they should make.
Speaker 0: in fact That's what I think D&D should do.
Speaker 0: if they want to sell a lot don't make Wow D&D right.
Speaker 0: make Farmville D&D.
Speaker 0: just fucking level that shit up.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: There's money in that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but now I quote the D&D experience, which is an event will be moving to Jenkon in 2013.
Speaker 1: Okay So as the convention special this year, they'll be doing open playtesting.
Speaker 1: And then here's another bad quote.
Speaker 1: "Through our website...".
Speaker 0: So you won't have to buy tickets at Gen Con specifically for the playtest?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: "Through our website, we will release a growing set of rules, classes, monsters, and other materials for your study and
Speaker 1: feedback.".
Speaker 0: So it's still based on classes and monsters.
Speaker 0: It's still D&D.
Speaker 1: Well, they said it's still D&D.
Speaker 1: They want it to be uniquely still D&D while making it as generic and non-D&D as possible.
Speaker 1: Uh, guys, you're fucking this up.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: I have no choice but to shit all over this at this stage.
Speaker 1: So, things of the day.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: Why, Bidoof?
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 1: Why would you do this to me, Mr.
Speaker 1: Bidoof?
Speaker 0: Oh, he's got a knife.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, he threw it at me.
Speaker 0: Oh, but he missed.
Speaker 1: Oh, Bidoof.
Speaker 1: He's got a gun.
Speaker 1: I saw this a while ago and it was funny.
Speaker 0: No, I think that's enough.
Speaker 1: It was funny, but I forgot about it.
Speaker 0: Oh, Bidoof.
Speaker 0: He's so angry.
Speaker 0: It's as angry as Bidoof's ever been.
Speaker 1: Our friend Adam brought it up and we remembered it.
Speaker 1: And it's this kind of slow burn video where you watch it.
Speaker 1: It's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: You don't need to describe it.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: No, I can explain something.
Speaker 0: There's nothing to explain.
Speaker 0: There's an interesting phenomenon you'll see.
Speaker 0: Bidoof, why?
Speaker 0: Bidoof, the end.
Speaker 0: My thing of the day.
Speaker 1: It's pretty funny, right?
Speaker 1: But as time goes on, like, you're gonna... It's a slow burn.
Speaker 0: You're doing the.
Speaker 0: dub this, explain the joke, attend the panel.
Speaker 1: And it'll be funnier and funnier the more you think about it.
Speaker 0: Adam, why don't you add another panel to that bad webcomic?
Speaker 1: And I guarantee that within a few days, you will be doing the same thing that we did with Dinosaur Office.
Speaker 0: Hey, why did chicken cross the road?
Speaker 1: Which is talking just like the guy who got fucked up by Mr.
Speaker 1: Bidoof.
Speaker 1: To get to the other side.
Speaker 0: Oh, you see, it's funny because the answer was obvious.
Speaker 0: You thought it was gonna be like a joke answer.
Speaker 1: Scott, what did you think of the day?
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 0: The common sense thing.
Speaker 0: Why would a chicken cross the road?
Speaker 1: Come on, what did you think of the day?
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 0: So, you know, if you got an Apple computer, right, there's many ways to get softwares into it.
Speaker 0: You can do what I do sometimes, which is, I have this modem cable and it connects to a serial port in the computer.
Speaker 0: So the Apple thinks it's dialing the internets on a modem.
Speaker 0: Well, not the internets, but it thinks it's dialing the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it thinks it's dialing the modem and receiving software, but really it's my computer sending the software, pretending to be a modem on a serial port, sending software to the Apple.
Speaker 0: that's on a file on my hard drive.
Speaker 1: Now you kids are all thinking right now, "Why don't I do that to those ATMs that are plugged into a phone
Speaker 1: line?".
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: Yeah, go for it.
Speaker 0: Well, the modem cable on an Apple II GS is like this weird connector.
Speaker 0: It's not a phone connector.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway.
Speaker 0: Another thing you can do is you can get floppy disk drives, either the five and a quarter or the three and a half.
Speaker 0: You can also get hard drives.
Speaker 0: You can get all sorts of crazy shit, right?
Speaker 0: But one thing you could always do is do the tape recorder, where you get the tape recorder, you get software on an audio cassette, right?
Speaker 0: You type load and you push play on the tape and you wait for the tape to play.
Speaker 0: And then the software is loaded.
Speaker 0: And it's just like the modem.
Speaker 1: You can even do that with the Atari.
Speaker 1: I had a cassette that had a whole bunch of Atari games on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just like a modem because it goes... And if you basically put that tape recorder in a regular old audio tape player, that's what it sounds like.
Speaker 1: I don't actually know what format it uses.
Speaker 1: I imagine it's something like QAM, but I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: Right, so check this out.
Speaker 0: There's a website, askiexpress.net/gameserver.
Speaker 0: And what this website is is a list of Apple II games.
Speaker 0: So you go down the list and you click on a game here, Horizon V. So I clicked on Horizon V and it loads and...
Speaker 1: WAV file?
Speaker 0: Some WAV files and some Flash players.
Speaker 0: So what you can do is you can even get your iPhone or something, or your phone, you know, or just your laptop or whatever.
Speaker 0: Go to this website, take a regular old three and a half inch audio cable from your phone or whatever it is, audio device, turn the volume all the way up, connect this to the back of the Apple computer, you know, the Apple II GS, type load, press play on your phone, and the game loads from the internet.
Speaker 0: So you can basically download games from the internet to play them on your Apple II immediately.
Speaker 0: And I have an Apple II, so I might do this shit.
Speaker 0: And there's a lot of fucking games here, a lot.
Speaker 0: Super Othello, oh shit son, Stunt Cycle Tron, Xevious, Penzate, O'Reilly's Mine.
Speaker 1: All right, I found the interface.
Speaker 1: It's actually pretty interesting how it works, and it's way simpler than I expected.
Speaker 0: It's pretty simple, it's pretty much this noise for one, this noise for zero.
Speaker 1: The header consists of ten seconds of a seven hundred and seventy hertz tone, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 1: I'll link to this too because it's pretty interesting.
Speaker 0: All right, but yeah, I'm going to try this because I have an Apple II.
Speaker 0: If you don't have an Apple II, maybe try this with an Apple II emulator.
Speaker 0: It might work, maybe it takes like audio input from the microphone and you can just do an analog hole situation.
Speaker 1: Now, if you're hardcore, do a ROM hack on the audio to make the game different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, download the WAV file and then write a program that will convert the WAV file into the floppy disk file that you could then take an image of to run in the emulator.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment, we already talked about PAX, but suffice it to say, we will be at PAX East.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, we don't have any big conventions on the horizon.
Speaker 1: Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: Same weekend as PAX East.
Speaker 1: Same weekend as PAX East, there may or may not be a shuttle between the two.
Speaker 1: And Anime Boston does have one advantage over PAX East.
Speaker 1: There are more better restaurants near it, but they cost more money.
Speaker 0: But it goes later.
Speaker 1: It does.
Speaker 0: So when PAX is over at like 2
Speaker 0: a.m.,
Speaker 0: I think Anime Boston still might have some programming.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that one part, remember, is 24/7.
Speaker 0: A very small part.
Speaker 1: Including, I believe, their tabletop.
Speaker 0: Possibly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's go over to Anime Boston for some tabletop at 2 in the morning.
Speaker 1: But we'll be at both most likely, as long as we can arrange the schedules between the two.
Speaker 0: Which might be difficult.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we're working with them.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do our level best.
Speaker 0: Other meta things.
Speaker 0: Nerd NYC recesses this weekend.
Speaker 1: This weekend, Scott has to do laundry and wash his hair so he won't be there.
Speaker 0: But I... My non-hair.
Speaker 1: I will be there on Saturday only.
Speaker 0: I also have to watch football.
Speaker 1: Well, I might be there Sunday.
Speaker 1: I want to go skiing on Sunday, but it's like 50 degrees.
Speaker 0: It's not looking like you're gonna shush anything.
Speaker 0: It's not looking so good.
Speaker 0: Unless you want to shush the grass.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I went to the website for the one I want to go to.
Speaker 1: It was like, primary surface, lose granular, which is code for shit.
Speaker 1: Secondary surface, uh, dirt.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: secondary surface?
Speaker 0: As in what's ever under the snow?
Speaker 1: No, well, so primary surface is like what's on most of the trails.
Speaker 1: Secondary surface is like what's on the rest of the trails that aren't as good as that one.
Speaker 1: It's like where it's worn down or on the edge cases, like what's the worst condition you're gonna run into.
Speaker 1: The secondary surface appears to be dirt, as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: Maybe grass.
Speaker 0: We'll get those dirt skis.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've hit grass on my skis before.
Speaker 1: It's not pleasant.
Speaker 1: Usually you stop and then hit your face.
Speaker 0: Face.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, the book club book is still not one, but two books.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: It's The Little Prince.
Speaker 0: And also, the second book is Wind, Sand, and the Stars, both written by Antoine de Saint-Euperi.
Speaker 0: I'm almost done.
Speaker 1: The farmer is brilliant.
Speaker 1: The ladder is breathtaking.
Speaker 1: I am very impressed with Wind, Sand, and Stars.
Speaker 0: Are you done?
Speaker 1: Mostly.
Speaker 1: I'm like three quarters of the way through.
Speaker 0: So we're both about three quarters of the way through.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: Only, and the thing is, it's not that long.
Speaker 0: It's just I've been so busy.
Speaker 1: It's not that long.
Speaker 1: I kept rereading two sections.
Speaker 0: And the other thing is like I keep getting other stuff that I keep reading instead.
Speaker 1: Drops of God, maybe.
Speaker 0: Like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Let's do a show about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we should.
Speaker 0: Next one.
Speaker 0: We gotta get those DC comics out of the way.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh.
Speaker 1: DC comics.
Speaker 1: Why would you do this?
Speaker 1: The angriest DC comics has ever been.
Speaker 0: See?
Speaker 0: They're up in the sky.
Speaker 1: I told you.
Speaker 0: What they're doing up in that cloud.
Speaker 1: So Scott bought a game, and I just didn't even pay attention.
Speaker 1: I didn't notice this game came out or anything.
Speaker 0: Well, all he noticed is in our forum, Timo was like, "Hey, my friend made a game called Eclipse, and he predicted that it would be pretty popular on
Speaker 0: BoardGameGeek.".
Speaker 0: And then I go check it out, and I'm looking around, and suddenly a lot of people are talking about this game.
Speaker 0: So a listener of our show, who we know is really cool, had a friend who made a game that became ridiculously popular.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, "Whoa, it's so popular that if I go on BoardGameGeek...".
Speaker 1: It's an 8.53 out of 10 with over 1,000 rankings.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, it is ranked number 14 on BoardGameGeek.
Speaker 0: It's number two in its theme, and number seven in strategy games.
Speaker 0: That's every game there is, period.
Speaker 1: Now this list is a little skewed, because Twilight Struggle made its way to the top, and fuck that game.
Speaker 0: The average rating for, I think, it is the number one average rating, period.
Speaker 0: Let me check this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this game is in the ranks of things like Agricola, Puerto Rico, Le Havre, Power Grid, Calus, 7 Wonders, El Grande.
Speaker 0: Okay, it doesn't have the highest average rating, because there's a whole bunch of games that have a single rating of 10.0.
Speaker 1: Race for the Galaxy, T&E, some of the best games ever made.
Speaker 1: It is already up there, and you know what?
Speaker 1: It's pretty justified.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I put this game, having only played it three times, right?
Speaker 0: I put this game as my number three game currently.
Speaker 1: Now, I want to preface this very clearly.
Speaker 0: This game has some random bullshit in it.
Speaker 0: That's why it's number three.
Speaker 1: And as a result, it gives me the visceral enjoyment of like war games and such, but also with the mind feel.
Speaker 1: I've decided I'm gonna start using that term.
Speaker 1: You know how people when they review food, they're like the mouth feel?
Speaker 1: So the mind feel, and you know what I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: This feels in my mind, mostly like either a German board game or Master of Orion.
Speaker 0: I guess you could say that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so what is Eclipse other than the biggest fucking game we own?
Speaker 0: So it's not the biggest game we own.
Speaker 0: It just takes a lot of table space.
Speaker 1: Name a bigger game we own that we play.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, as in terms of table space?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, cause Shogun has more pieces.
Speaker 1: It's not bigger.
Speaker 0: Space wise, the box is bigger.
Speaker 1: Box is bigger game, not bigger anyway.
Speaker 1: Battle Masters, I guess we don't own Battle Masters.
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Battle Masters is the biggest game there is.
Speaker 0: So here's the deal with Eclipse, right?
Speaker 0: Is it is Master of Orion, the board game, and it plays sort of mostly like a German board game, right?
Speaker 0: On your turn, you take an action and, you know, and you go around taking actions sort of like, you know, Ticket to Ride or Puerto Rico or any of those games or Calus, right?
Speaker 0: On your turn, you take an action.
Speaker 0: You go around and eventually you pass and eventually everyone passes and you manage resources, you know, you've got, and you get victory points in order to win.
Speaker 0: It's not about who can conquer the galaxy or whatever.
Speaker 0: Just get victory points to win.
Speaker 0: The game is nine rounds.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So you know how long it's going to take.
Speaker 0: It takes a half hour per person, but that assumes set up time and learning time, which can be quite long depending.
Speaker 0: And basically it's totally awesome except for, right?
Speaker 0: The thing that makes it not German is that you have space combat and space combat is a lot like combat in a lot of other, you know, war games.
Speaker 0: But like it's very risk-ish.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm going to sell you on the space combat right now.
Speaker 1: The way this works, and this is what made this game awesome for me.
Speaker 1: You've got four classes of ships.
Speaker 1: Three of them are ships and one is the space station.
Speaker 1: They can't move.
Speaker 0: Starbase.
Speaker 1: You play inventory Tetris.
Speaker 1: Well, basically in this case, it's upgrade Tetris.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the little ship, if you build 10 of them, they're all of the same loadout, which is matching whatever loadout you've built on your character sheet.
Speaker 1: They come with like one kind of engine, one kind of gun, and you can put shit in this extra space.
Speaker 1: You can upgrade stuff.
Speaker 1: It's pretty flexible in what you want to build.
Speaker 1: And that alone is way fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and what's really, you know, it's also like incredibly like tense because you'll be sitting there ready to go into battle and you're like, I got this.
Speaker 0: The other guy upgrades his shit.
Speaker 0: And it's like, oh, that completely changed the odds.
Speaker 0: I don't got the first game.
Speaker 0: So now it's like, well, should I build more ships or upgrade my ships?
Speaker 0: Will that make it a winnable battle?
Speaker 0: And like there was the greatest thing happened, like in the last game I played, it was a three player game and that I won.
Speaker 0: Me and Pete were like, he was in the middle and I was just outside the middle.
Speaker 0: And I'm building up a big army and he's building up a giant army, just two adjacent hexes all in.
Speaker 0: And it's like putting in more ships, more ships, more sugar.
Speaker 1: That's a lot of ships.
Speaker 0: Upgrade the ships, anti-matter cannon, boom, boom, boom, make them real big.
Speaker 0: And then it's pretty much like, I was pretty much like, well, I just had to put enough in there that he wouldn't attack me.
Speaker 0: He, I only had to make it, I wasted only one action to bluff to make it look like I was going in no matter what, so that he would waste actions defending.
Speaker 0: And then I use the remaining actions to get victory points elsewhere because you win with victory points.
Speaker 0: It's not Shogun.
Speaker 0: You don't win by killing the other guy, even though that could get you some victory points.
Speaker 0: You win with victory points.
Speaker 0: I just explored some new space and got points elsewhere.
Speaker 0: And then it was just like, oh, no, that's it.
Speaker 1: The only game I ever played, I won and I did the same thing.
Speaker 1: Someone was going to attack me like pretty much straight up.
Speaker 0: Run away.
Speaker 1: No, I upgraded a bunch of ships and kind of like menaced him a little bit.
Speaker 1: And that caused a standoff.
Speaker 1: And then I just farm victory points elsewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because everyone's actually really afraid to lose their ships.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, it's the thing is, right, is that, you know, despite, you know, the fact that you can get victory points in so many different ways that you don't even need to do ships is that if someone comes on you with ships, they can take away, right?
Speaker 0: Number one, your hexes.
Speaker 0: Every hex that you control is worth at least one victory point.
Speaker 0: So having less hexes under your control is bad.
Speaker 0: Number two, when you lose hexes, the cubes on the board that are on that hex come off and that makes you weaker, which makes it harder for you to do anything.
Speaker 0: And number three, if you lose all your hexes, then you're out of the game, basically.
Speaker 1: So the first game of this I played, when I say mouthfeel, there's one other feel that I got a little bit, but it might have been circumstantial.
Speaker 1: And that was our old Battletech days because we started that game of Eclipse after midnight at Magfest.
Speaker 1: And we stopped at five in the morning.
Speaker 0: We stopped at four something and got.
Speaker 1: we stopped at five forty five or so.
Speaker 0: We got to bed at five.
Speaker 1: I tweeted my victory at five fifteen before I took a shower and passed out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's better.
Speaker 1: It was a pretty good game, though.
Speaker 1: So rather than, you know.
Speaker 0: But if you think about it, right, six people, right, playing half hour each.
Speaker 0: It's three hours teaching.
Speaker 1: We had to add in teaching and setting up.
Speaker 0: So it took us, you know, three hours and change.
Speaker 0: You know, we started at one something and we ended it for something.
Speaker 1: So we're not going to explain the rules because you can read the rules and play the game.
Speaker 1: I think we can bring up all the like the individual interesting mechanics.
Speaker 0: Here's the number one.
Speaker 0: Here's the number one awesome thing that I was like, oh, shit, son.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The cubes.
Speaker 0: You have these tracks on your board that have cubes covering them completely.
Speaker 0: And it tells you how much money, how much science and how much materials you make.
Speaker 0: Money's used for actions and science, used for science upgrades and materials used to build ships.
Speaker 0: And basically, as your empire grows, you put cubes on the board, their population cubes.
Speaker 0: So when you put a science population cube on the board, right, that decreases the number of population cubes on your personal board.
Speaker 0: So the number on your personal board that's bigger is now revealed because you remove the cube.
Speaker 1: So think about the elegance of this.
Speaker 1: Rather than most games that the exploration and exploitation, you will get a space and then get points out of it every round to spend.
Speaker 1: This is the same mathematical mechanic, but the mechanism of doing it in the board game is taking one cube off of your board and putting it on the space.
Speaker 1: Giving away cubes is tantamount to getting resources regularly.
Speaker 0: The physicality is reversed.
Speaker 0: Normally in another game, it'd be like, you got science points here.
Speaker 0: Take a fist full of science points.
Speaker 1: This physical or it would have, you know, sliders.
Speaker 0: This is like I put a scientist from my personal board onto a hex in outer space, and now I get more science every turn.
Speaker 1: This game, by using very clever physical design, was able to greatly increase the complexity of the board game without making it no longer a playable board game.
Speaker 0: It's not as complex as actual Master of Orion, right?
Speaker 0: Not even close, but it is plenty complex, and they've managed to compress compact it into less physical bits so that it's actually manageable as a board game.
Speaker 0: And you can actually get the whole game in your brain playing Master of Orion or even Civilization V or IV.
Speaker 0: It's hard to get the whole game in your brain.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of tiny, tiny stuff that can only be done on a computer.
Speaker 0: Like, how many grain are in that one city?
Speaker 0: I've got 20 cities, right?
Speaker 1: This is why I always recommend when people want to learn game theory or study games or game design or anything like that is to do board games because the physical limitations of the design force you to consider...
Speaker 0: When you're playing Master of Orion, you've got a thousand ships that all have different equipment because they don't automatically upgrade.
Speaker 1: Yep, so imagine trying to design a game like Master of Orion.
Speaker 1: You couldn't even get it in your head to design it.
Speaker 1: It would take so much playtesting and time.
Speaker 0: Let alone to even play the combat.
Speaker 0: It's like, how do you even make decisions, you know, in that kind of situation?
Speaker 1: Another really great mechanic is that the way your upkeep increases is that every time you take an action, you take a disc off of your board and put it on the action you took.
Speaker 1: You also take discs off the board and put them on hexes you control.
Speaker 1: The more things you control or do, the more upkeep there is because there are increasingly negative numbers under those discs.
Speaker 0: So the bigger your empire is, it's harder for you to take more actions unless you have a lot more money.
Speaker 0: You need money to do more actions.
Speaker 1: Or you can go for it by burning and losing other stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can.
Speaker 1: Yep, and there's a science economy of building resource enhancements and improvements and tracks and it's basically got one little piece of all those kinds of space explorer fighty games that everyone loves in one game.
Speaker 1: that is a board game that's actually playable.
Speaker 0: It's like when you want to explore outer space to conquer new territory, you flip over new hexes of outer space and add them to the board.
Speaker 0: When you want to, you know, every turn we grab more science tiles out of the bag as new sciences are available.
Speaker 0: So you might be playing with a particular strategy and that science just doesn't come up.
Speaker 0: or the one game I played, the wrench just never appeared, the nanobots.
Speaker 0: It's like I wanted to buy nanobots immediately in that game, but they weren't available till very late in the game, even though the most basic technology.
Speaker 0: And it's like, why?
Speaker 0: Because there's some randomness there that makes every game different.
Speaker 0: But, you know, the randomness, there is randomness, though, which is, you know, somewhat annoying is the hex draw, right?
Speaker 0: If you get a really good hex draw and you explore a lot, it's going to help you.
Speaker 0: If you if sciences come up that happen to help you and it happens to be you going first this time, it helps you.
Speaker 0: You know, if you're in a combat and the other guy happens to roll four sixes, it's happened already, even though you've only played three games.
Speaker 0: It's happened a few times.
Speaker 0: Well, you might get fucked even though your military is a barrier.
Speaker 1: This is a situation where typically games that have a lot of randomness are pretty crappy.
Speaker 1: And as the randomness goes away, the games get better.
Speaker 1: And then there's a point at which there's no or no functional randomness left in the game.
Speaker 1: And these are games like chess and checkers and go or Puerto Rico, where there's functionally other than the state of the plantations, no randomness.
Speaker 1: But then if you keep going, there's this whole other spectrum of games that have randomness because they're more like simulations of real things.
Speaker 1: I mean, war has a lot of random B.S.
Speaker 1: that happens in it.
Speaker 0: So even if you have the best strategy of war, you know, no matter what you do, shit could happen.
Speaker 0: And that's why, you know, football, real life football or sports, you know, all sports have the.
Speaker 0: we got the perfect game plan.
Speaker 0: We got the perfect players.
Speaker 0: We got the perfect matchups to get the perfect plays and randomness happen.
Speaker 1: And there's value in those games, too.
Speaker 1: I mean, war games and historical simulations are great kinds of games.
Speaker 1: And this game is just past that threshold where it's starting to have the randomness.
Speaker 1: that actually makes the game fun and interesting, even though it makes it less good of a game from a purely strategic mathematical game theory.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I still love the game and want to play it like crazy.
Speaker 0: But I am frustrated when I attack, you know, one measly alien ship with like four interceptors that are upgraded and I lose because someone rolled a fist full of sixes and I rolled a fist full of ones.
Speaker 0: And that was that.
Speaker 1: But Scott, aren't you also the exact opposite of that when your one interceptor takes out like the center square?
Speaker 0: Yes, but it's incredibly frustrating nonetheless, which makes it not as good as Puerto Rico or Tini.
Speaker 1: The only thing I can say about this game that is negative is that there aren't really a whole bunch of expansions yet for me to play with.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: He really needs expansions.
Speaker 0: I think the things that are negative about the game are number one, the setup time is kind of big and it's hard to clean up because you get a lot of pieces.
Speaker 1: I'd like more interesting things to run into on the hexes just for like a different flavor of game every now and then.
Speaker 0: Well, there is an expansion that was like.
Speaker 0: there's one thing that's like the supernova something that you got at Essen, which we're probably never going to get.
Speaker 0: No, but it added like supernova tiles and a supernova technology or something.
Speaker 0: There's also the discovery.
Speaker 0: tiles are usually where all the good action is in that department, There's also a really nice mechanic of the game.
Speaker 1: By default, everyone plays as humans.
Speaker 1: It's the Terran something.
Speaker 1: It's all like the Terran collective, the Terran Republic, the Terran dictatorship, the Terran democracy.
Speaker 0: There are six player boards, each a different color, and they all have Terran on one side and an alien race on the other side.
Speaker 1: Terrans are all the same.
Speaker 1: The aliens are crazy rule breakers, like they're totally all different from each other.
Speaker 0: So, for example, you know, Rims the youngest will say so he gets to pick first.
Speaker 0: So he picks green, green.
Speaker 0: That means he can either be the green humans, which are the same as all the other humans, or he could be the planta, which are the plant like creatures.
Speaker 0: Now someone else goes, they pick red.
Speaker 0: They can be the red humans, the same as all the other humans, or they can be whatever the red guys are, but they can't be the planta.
Speaker 0: and the planta are different from the red guys, which are different from the black guys, you know?
Speaker 0: So it's like, uh, it's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Like if you want to be humans, then you want to pick the color, not that you like, which is always going to be green, but that denies the aliens you hate the most from someone else.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty clever mechanic there.
Speaker 1: It is a way fun game and I highly recommend if you're into- It's a hard to get game.
Speaker 0: I recommend you go somewhere and pre-order it and pay whatever money they're asking.
Speaker 1: It's a game to get if you like long drawn out, dramatic, angry, you know, risk kind of games, but you want a real game to be there.
Speaker 1: Like at its core, you want it to be a real challenging, interesting game.
Speaker 0: I get the feeling it might be best to play with four player, but I've only played a six, a five, and a three, and the six and the five, more so the six, right?
Speaker 0: There was so much competition for hexes and resources that you really, you know, the hex draw mattered a lot more.
Speaker 0: If you drew like a bunch of, you know, alien ship hexes, you needed to spend some early actions upgrading your ships.
Speaker 0: Whereas someone else who drew a bunch of easy hexes that had a lot of spots to put cubes got basically easy free expansion and they could use an action to explore a whole nother tile while you had to use two actions to buy some ships and upgrade them or research technology.
Speaker 0: And as a result, you got less cubes on the board, which slowed you down for the rest of the game and is annoying.
Speaker 0: In five player, it was sort of the same as six, but a little less so, less annoying.
Speaker 0: In three, it was almost too easy.
Speaker 0: We didn't even explore all the hexes because, which might've been some strategic mistakes because it's only the third time we played, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The one game I played in, part of the reason I won is early on, I went way off into interstellar space and got a bunch of victory points.
Speaker 1: And one person next to me was walled off away from me by alien ships.
Speaker 1: And the other person, we shared diplomats right away.
Speaker 1: You want to talk about the trader card?
Speaker 0: I want to finish talking about the, uh, the explorey random bit, right?
Speaker 0: Is I feel like four players would be the best combination of?
Speaker 0: you're actually competing for the resources, right?
Speaker 0: Cause in three, you're not really competing so much.
Speaker 0: Like we didn't fight till the last turn and then we didn't fight, you know?
Speaker 0: But in five, it was almost too tight.
Speaker 0: It's like, I like tight competition, but it's almost too tight to where the randomness means more than the competition.
Speaker 0: I think four, I want to play a four player game because it would only take two hours with people who knew how to play.
Speaker 0: And I think the competition for resources would be, you know, the right tightness and they would be, the randomness would matter the right amount.
Speaker 0: And it seems like the internet agrees.
Speaker 0: They're like four players is besto.
Speaker 1: Well, it says best with four or six players.
Speaker 0: But it plays two to six and I'm curious to play the two as well, but I think it might be boring and weird.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they're weird, but I do want to try it.
Speaker 0: There is a one rule change.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure how much of a rule change it is, but we got to try it at least once.
Speaker 1: There's an official eclipse fact for errata and problems.
Speaker 0: I'll check that out.
Speaker 0: So talk about the trader mechanism.
Speaker 1: So if you want to make an alliance with someone, you can do it.
Speaker 1: If you share borders, you give them a diplomat and a cube and they give you a diplomat and a cube.
Speaker 0: So it lets you basically increase one of your things by one.
Speaker 0: You can increase your money, science or materials by one cube.
Speaker 0: That's a pretty good benefit.
Speaker 0: And you give each other a victory point.
Speaker 0: So it's basically king making.
Speaker 0: It's like we'll both go up and get one victory point each and we'll get ahead of all these other players by one point.
Speaker 0: So if you betray that alliance by attacking a person you have an alliance with, which means even putting ships in their hexes, you can't even fly through their space at all.
Speaker 1: You take the you re exchange the diplomats to take your cube back, put it back on your stupid sheet.
Speaker 0: You both give each other the victory points back and you get the trader card.
Speaker 1: that's worth minus two victory points at the end of the game.
Speaker 1: And you cannot make any new alliances.
Speaker 0: As long as you're holding the trader card.
Speaker 1: There's only one trader card.
Speaker 1: Only the last trader is punished like this.
Speaker 0: So if someone else is a trader, they take the trader card from you.
Speaker 0: Now you can make alliances again and you don't get minus two victory points at the end of the game, which means there's this huge incentive to basically never trader someone.
Speaker 0: because if you trader someone, you're going to get the trader card.
Speaker 0: And as soon as you get it, unless the only reason to do it would be if you were going to gain more than two victory points by killing that other guy, in which case, good, good job.
Speaker 0: But nobody, once you trader, no one else is going to try to take the trader card from you.
Speaker 0: Because let's say I attack one of your guys on the second last turn.
Speaker 0: It's a four point hex.
Speaker 0: I take the negative two.
Speaker 0: It's a plus two positive.
Speaker 0: And I have the nukes and on the last turn, I'm going to be able to just roll you over and get like a bunch more points, right?
Speaker 0: No one else is going to want a trader now because that'll basically be giving me two victory points.
Speaker 0: And it's like so basically the first trader is going to be the only trader unless they're going to get so many more victory points that it's worth it for them to take it.
Speaker 0: It's in, you know, but even if they do take it now, suddenly you can make alliances again and get even more points.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know, in other games that just have alliances and not alliances, you whether the alliances are enforced by the rules or whether they just agree to be friends like in risk, you actually have a real reason not to trade or someone in this game.
Speaker 0: And it kind of works.
Speaker 0: Rim was usually a dick and just traders everyone.
Speaker 1: Granted, I only had one trader card.
Speaker 1: And as a result, my plan was make an alliance with that person and then leave my rear undefended and explore interstellar space.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: I won that fucking game.
Speaker 0: I realize, though, if I'm playing someone in the future, because, you know, it's like, I think it's going to take a lot of plays to learn the best moves.
Speaker 0: If anyone leaves their rear undefended to me, I'm going to upgrade my drives.
Speaker 0: No one in any of the games I've played put a lot of effort into upgrading drives to make their ships move more open in my game.
Speaker 1: In fact, I had a gigantic army that could move one hex per turn.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: If someone leaves anything undefended, even if they're my ally, I'm going to get the four hex drives and the nukes.
Speaker 0: And then in one turn, all my interceptors will fly through all your empty space where there's nothing but cubes and there's no ships defending it and just kill all your.
Speaker 0: and I don't give a shit if I get two traitor victory points.
Speaker 0: If I take away four or five hexes from you, you are fucked.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So that's what I'm going to do.
Speaker 1: So I didn't want to bring this up in the meta moment because I think we're done.
Speaker 1: This is the salvage moment.
Speaker 1: I, as in, you know, my company, I'm looking for a good Linux system administrator.
Speaker 0: Hey, got to pay for that advertising.
Speaker 1: So if anybody is no advertising, a good Linux system administrator, I'm getting paid for I.T.
Speaker 1: I'd like you to know Windows.
Speaker 0: You got to pay double because there's no advertising show.
Speaker 1: I don't need any, you know, financial services software.
Speaker 1: I just need someone who knows networking and system admin, I.T.
Speaker 1: majors in particular.
Speaker 1: All you are I.T.
Speaker 1: kids I know who might be graduating soon.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at you to a million dollars is what it costs to advertise the show.
Speaker 1: So let me know.
Speaker 0: I'll set up for one hundred K and you would be working for me.
Speaker 1: I mean, you might enjoy that because we can be bought.
Speaker 0: But I've been told that I'm pretty cool.
Speaker 0: I promise not to advertise in the show ever again.
Speaker 1: I paid myself a million dollars for this ad.
Speaker 0: No, you got to pay me.
Speaker 1: I paid myself.
Speaker 0: It's also my show.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.