Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, April 25th, 2012.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, Lupin the Third, the woman called Fujiko Mine.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I got this paper in the mail the other day.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh.
Speaker 0: Mail is never good news.
Speaker 1: I rarely get mail.
Speaker 1: I actually have eliminated all junk mail.
Speaker 1: And just to tell you the strategy of eliminating all junk mail, right?
Speaker 1: This is the strategy, number one.
Speaker 1: There's a website.
Speaker 1: There's only one legitimate website.
Speaker 1: It's hard to tell it's legitimate because it doesn't look legitimate, but it's a real website.
Speaker 1: It's called Opt Out Prescreen.
Speaker 1: And if you go to this website, it's legitimate.
Speaker 1: It works.
Speaker 1: There's only one that works.
Speaker 1: Make sure you get the right one.
Speaker 1: Because it's fake ones.
Speaker 1: You can opt out of all credit prescreen.
Speaker 1: So no one out there can, like, prescreen your credit score to determine if they're going to mail you junk mail for bullshit like student loan consolidation.
Speaker 1: After going to that website, before going to the website, I used to get, like, letters constantly.
Speaker 1: Like, "Get a credit card.
Speaker 1: Get a this, get a that, get a
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: And as soon as I went to that website, within, like, a week, I haven't gotten any of that bullshit mail since.
Speaker 1: Number two, right?
Speaker 1: Whenever you do get a mail, for example, if you go to buy something in EMS with a credit card, they got you.
Speaker 1: Or Bed, Bath, and Beyond, they got you.
Speaker 1: And they start sending you coupons and shit in the mail.
Speaker 1: Specifically, go to each one of those places and say, "EMS, stop sending me shit.
Speaker 1: Bed, Bath, and Beyond, stop sending me
Speaker 1: shit.".
Speaker 1: And they'll stop sending you shit.
Speaker 1: And because of that, and also what I do, is every place I have a bill pay, I sort of, I choose the paperless option.
Speaker 0: As well one should.
Speaker 1: So it's internet only.
Speaker 1: So I hardly ever get anything in the mail except, like, tax forms.
Speaker 1: And Netflix.
Speaker 1: And that's it.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I got something in the mail.
Speaker 1: I was like,
Speaker 1: "Whoa.".
Speaker 1: And it wasn't just bullshit, so I was like,
Speaker 1: It was a student loan bill.
Speaker 1: And I was like, "Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: That shit's auto-pay, yo.
Speaker 1: And what's up with
Speaker 1: this?".
Speaker 0: Student loan?
Speaker 1: So I'm like, "Do I have to pay this?
Speaker 1: Or is it gonna
Speaker 1: auto-pay?".
Speaker 1: 'Cause apparently what happened is the government used to, like, direct federal, direct loan, whatever, used to be, like, the thing.
Speaker 1: But what they did is they found these other people, like Ed Financial, and now Ed Financial is managing the loans even though the loans are unchanged.
Speaker 1: So they, like, changed the management company.
Speaker 0: Fascinating.
Speaker 1: And the website, yeah.
Speaker 1: So anyway, so, uh, I, you know, I'm like, "Do I have to pay this?
Speaker 1: Or is auto-pay still
Speaker 1: working?".
Speaker 1: So I called up Ed Financial and I was like, "Hey, uh, do I have to pay
Speaker 1: this?".
Speaker 1: They're like, "No, auto-pay will still
Speaker 1: work.".
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: How do I make you stop mailing me
Speaker 1: shit?".
Speaker 1: And they're like, "Go to the
Speaker 1: web.".
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Are you gonna mail me something every time even though auto-pay is
Speaker 1: on?".
Speaker 1: And they're like, "Yeah, you have to go to the website to cancel
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Oh,
Speaker 1: great.".
Speaker 1: And then I was like, "Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: How much student loan do I have
Speaker 1: left?".
Speaker 1: And they were like, "Oh, a little less than
Speaker 1: $9,000.".
Speaker 1: And I'm like,
Speaker 1: "Hmmm.".
Speaker 1: So I paid that shit.
Speaker 1: Boom.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: It's gone.
Speaker 1: 'Cause it was two- one-.
Speaker 1: think about it this way, right?
Speaker 1: I was paying, like, $214 a month and the interest rate was, like, 2.11 percent.
Speaker 1: That's, like, guaranteed 2.11 percent no tax.
Speaker 1: So by paying that off, that's like investing $9,000 and getting a 2.11 percent return.
Speaker 1: And there's no way I could do that guaranteed in this environment, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, a savings account's gonna give you, like, 0.00000 percent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's pretty much the exact right move to make in your situation at this time.
Speaker 1: So now, it's like I got a raise, even though my bank account went...
Speaker 0: Unless the opportunity cost of that money was more...
Speaker 1: It was gonna sit in my checking account.
Speaker 0: Oh, there you go.
Speaker 1: But it's like, so now, it's like my checking account went... But I got a raise of, like, $200 a month.
Speaker 0: It was a big deal.
Speaker 0: When I paid off my student loan some years ago, the last one, like, I didn't really think about it 'cause they'd just been auto-paying forever.
Speaker 0: And then, you know, I got my first paychecks, like, for the two months after that and then I had this extra money and I was like, "Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: I could just spend all this extra money, not change
Speaker 0: anything.".
Speaker 1: $200 a month is actually a lot.
Speaker 1: Like, I can get Zipcar and profit or, you know, who knows what.
Speaker 0: Well, not technically profit, but anyway.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, I'm not gonna do any of that, but it's just like, yeah.
Speaker 1: And now, I'm also debt-free, which means I can run away at any fucking time.
Speaker 0: I've been debt-free for many years.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: How come you haven't run away?
Speaker 0: 'Cause I enjoy spending a lot of money.
Speaker 1: I'm telling you what, as soon as I get the opportunity and I rebuild that savings, I'm gone.
Speaker 1: See ya.
Speaker 0: The thing is, I think the moment of truth for me was the day when I realized that my average monthly credit card bill was equal to what I still owed on my student loan.
Speaker 0: And I was like, "Yeah, paying that
Speaker 0: off.".
Speaker 1: You got it way low.
Speaker 0: I paid it off a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what, though?
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure I still have a lot of student loan that my parents are paying, but that's their problem.
Speaker 1: And, you know, they would pay rent.
Speaker 0: Tell your mom to listen to the show and we'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they paid the rent for Colony and stuff a bunch of times.
Speaker 1: Not getting that back.
Speaker 0: I didn't pay the rent a bunch of times.
Speaker 1: Good job.
Speaker 0: Nothing really came of it.
Speaker 0: Actually, really, nothing.
Speaker 0: But anyway.
Speaker 1: Except for the car repo.
Speaker 0: That was a separate... So, not paying the rent had nothing to do with not paying the car payment.
Speaker 0: While they had the same root cause, the effects were different.
Speaker 0: The effect of not paying rent was zero.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: No effect.
Speaker 1: So, anything going on for you?
Speaker 0: This made the rounds.
Speaker 0: And I feel like I should talk about it, but I'm not that interested in the specifics of the actual event.
Speaker 0: Other than that, it's kind of hilarious.
Speaker 0: But the fact that this made the rounds is interesting.
Speaker 0: And it drummed up a whole bunch of secondary conversations.
Speaker 0: I figure I'll start with just this.
Speaker 0: Someone tweeted.
Speaker 0: Good old tweet.
Speaker 0: And the tweet was from AICNAnime.
Speaker 1: Ain't it cool news?
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 1: He's a really good tweeter.
Speaker 1: He tweets all sorts of obscure, awesome anime shit.
Speaker 0: He's right up there with Daryl Surrett in terms of people I follow and enjoy.
Speaker 0: He's awesome.
Speaker 1: I think his name's Scott, too, but it's not me.
Speaker 0: "Boston mayor's office of consumer affairs and licensing looking anime Boston attendee crime bad
Speaker 0: behavior.".
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Now, when I saw that, I sort of immediately noticed.
Speaker 0: It was getting retweeted a whole bunch, and there were discussions popping up everywhere.
Speaker 0: And when I thought about it, I thought about all the conventions I've been to in my entire life and based purely on either privileged information, where while I have some semi-reasonable backing, it is not information I can share because I got it from trusted sources, and also confirmation bias and completely anecdotal bullshit.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: I feel like the kinds of things that this article talks about happen way more at AnimeCon specifically than other kinds of conventions.
Speaker 1: Pretty much every convention you go to has some sort of, you know, drama or events.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm talking specifically about police involved, someone is taken away, like hospitalization due to something other than just, like, heat stroke or dehydration.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen a lot of hospitalizations.
Speaker 0: Scott, there has been an ambulance at some point at every AnimeCon we've been to.
Speaker 1: Right, but they're mostly, you know, I think most of them are that kind of, you know, there's a person who's sick legitimately.
Speaker 0: No, it's almost always for the rave.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sometimes.
Speaker 0: I've seen an ambulance.
Speaker 1: I've seen a few in my day.
Speaker 0: The majority of the Otakons I've been to that was involved with the rave in some fashion.
Speaker 1: Really, I was usually eating during this, I wouldn't know.
Speaker 0: I used to go to those things.
Speaker 0: You did.
Speaker 1: But, you know, police involvement, I mean, even PAX, the cops show up once or so, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, no matter what, even AutoShow, the cops show up once or something, because, you know, there was the PAX where someone tried to steal the source code.
Speaker 0: All right, so wait.
Speaker 0: That's a very different class of incident of one guy committing what I would call a real crime versus the underage drunken party.
Speaker 0: or someone flips out at the rave and passes out.
Speaker 0: Or a fire code violation crazy party.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, you know, some conventions don't have a rave, right?
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: If you have a rave, that's the kind of thing that might happen.
Speaker 0: I mean, my experience as staff at conventions through the years has taught me that the majority of incidents that involve the police and/or the likelihood of police at conventions are, it's like half and half between the rave and shoplifters in the dealer's room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, shoplifters in the dealer's room.
Speaker 0: Like 50/50.
Speaker 1: Yeah, theft is always a concern at every convention.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this incident in particular is interesting because, literally, according to the article, and I looked around, this is the only legitimate news source I can find on it, Bad Draw for Hotel Anime Party by Laurel J. Sweet and Dave Wedge.
Speaker 0: So it took two people to write this two paragraph, I guess they split it up, paragraph each.
Speaker 1: Well, because they couldn't just get something from the AP Newswire, they actually had to journalize and go and investigate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they didn't, so here's what I find hilarious about this.
Speaker 0: The first paragraph points out that the hotel has to testify now before the mayor's office of consumer affairs and licensing, which seems odd?
Speaker 1: We've thought about it.
Speaker 0: So the mayor's office for consumer affairs and licensing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because it's Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I think that the city sort of gives permission for these things, and it's the Boston, whatever, convention center, Massachusetts Convention Center authority.
Speaker 0: My point is that this is the branch that's investigating this, because they don't say what they're going to testify about specifically other than the incident, but the fact that it's this office as opposed to some other office.
Speaker 0: lets us read into a lot of what is going to be discussed there, because if it's licensing due to the fact that Anime Boston, the name, could reflect on the city of Boston, that is not a conversation I think Anime Boston wants to be involved in.
Speaker 1: No matter what you do, especially if you do something big that involves 20,000 plus people, there is at least one regulatory body of some government that has some control over you, and this happens to be one of them, and it's probably upset for PR reasons.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, the fact that this is the event that causes this, which was a hotel party, which in my opinion has nothing to do with the convention.
Speaker 0: The convention shouldn't even be involved in that.
Speaker 1: Well, was it the official rave?
Speaker 0: No, no, Scott, this incident is, let's see, see there are two incidents, there was a hotel room thing that happened.
Speaker 1: So it was in a hotel room.
Speaker 1: And there was the fact that the rave got shut down supposedly by the police.
Speaker 1: So the rave is Anime Boston's problem because that's their official event.
Speaker 0: Yes, but that's not what this article is about.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 0: This article is about, quote, here, "Police reported dangerous overcrowding, pot possession, a passed out party goer, and an assault at the FED for Anime Boston 2012 fans.
Speaker 0: The celebration of Japanese cartoons threw thousands of costume fans to the Heinz Convention Center, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: At 1 a.m.
Speaker 0: on April 8th, cops showed up at a party at the
Speaker 0: Sheraton.".
Speaker 1: But the thing is, that could be an official Anime Boston thing.
Speaker 0: Exactly, the article doesn't say.
Speaker 1: Oh, so was it an official Anime Boston party?
Speaker 0: The article doesn't say.
Speaker 1: Or, well, that matters a lot.
Speaker 0: I know, and the article doesn't say.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: Way to go, two people investigating.
Speaker 1: Can't even get the important information.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: What's funny is they reported, and I love this quote, "A clearly disturbed 20-year-old male who'd been kicking and punching
Speaker 0: EMTs.".
Speaker 1: Alrighty.
Speaker 0: "And less than an ounce of
Speaker 0: pot."
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: Why is that even... In the beginning, it's like marijuana possession, then it's like less than an ounce.
Speaker 1: That's one of those things where it's like you get someone for something, and then you search him for every other possible thing.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's like, "Oh, we caught this guy robbing a convenience store, and when we searched him, we found a gun and an ounce of
Speaker 1: crack.".
Speaker 1: It's like, "Well, add it to the list.
Speaker 1: It's
Speaker 1: there.".
Speaker 1: But the half ounce of weed wasn't the trigger.
Speaker 1: It was the punching and kicking of the EMTs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, well, and the quote, "dangerous overcrowding," whatever.
Speaker 0: But here's the other thing.
Speaker 0: We're picking apart this tiny article.
Speaker 0: I point out that it's not Anime Boston that is even testifying here.
Speaker 1: I know, it's the hotel.
Speaker 0: It's the management of the hotel, which, while is tied to the convention center pretty tightly, is a distinct entity in some regards.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: Now, what really makes this interesting is that, one, there's a discussion in the forum where someone's like, "Hey, why was the informal dance shut down?
Speaker 0: What
Speaker 0: happened?".
Speaker 1: Oh, informal dance.
Speaker 0: And the response from Anime Boston was, "We'll post more information
Speaker 0: later.".
Speaker 0: Uh, they haven't yet, obviously.
Speaker 0: Actually, oh, wait, wait, okay, great.
Speaker 0: Look at this.
Speaker 0: "Anime Boston staff will post information about this within the near future, sometime this week or
Speaker 0: so.".
Speaker 0: That was posted on April 8th.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: I don't see any further information.
Speaker 1: I don't think that many people care.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except, we can't tell how many people care, because, quote, "To prevent the spread of rumors and misinformation, I am locking this
Speaker 0: thread.".
Speaker 1: Uh, I guess, uh, okay, people, listen up, right?
Speaker 1: It's the internet.
Speaker 1: Anyone can post information they want anywhere on the internet, and you can't stop them.
Speaker 0: You're better off having it in your domain, where you can at least respond to it in a centralized place.
Speaker 0: And see all of it.
Speaker 0: Instead of having the discussion about the incident on the Geek Nights forum and the other one on the Fast Karate forum.
Speaker 1: Locking threads, banning, all that kind of stuff is stupid and only creates drama.
Speaker 1: You just allow people just to talk freely, and things will be much better off.
Speaker 0: I'll qualify that.
Speaker 0: You still ban the spammers, you know, the usual stuff.
Speaker 1: The spam is different from, right, some guy who's strongly disagreeing with you and fighting with you and you don't like what he's saying.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there are situations where I'm fine with the bans and all these things.
Speaker 0: Locking a thread that's just a shitfest, but in this case, it only bothers me when anyone, I'm not singling out Anime Boston here by any means, when there's a controversial thing, it's like their first go-to thing, especially fan-run conventions, is to hush it up as much as possible and lock and delete any threads in their own forums related to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, "No, just let it
Speaker 1: go."
Speaker 1: Even though, well, we'll see.
Speaker 0: So the other thing that's interesting is, in a related discussion, I'm going to quote an executive for Anime Boston from the forum.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay, so if they post in the forum, that's effectively an official statement.
Speaker 0: Now, this was an unrelated story about someone who claimed a drunken staffer banged on their hotel room door in the middle of the night and demanded to search it.
Speaker 1: We've had that kind of problem before.
Speaker 1: That happened to us at Anime Boston last year.
Speaker 1: It wasn't a staffer, though, it was just a dumb other kid.
Speaker 0: Who was also drunk.
Speaker 0: Quote, "As part of working with the hotel, they prefer to have us involved in things like this when the room is part of our block.
Speaker 0: I suppose it helps to make sure we're as in the loop as possible.
Speaker 0: Continuing most conferences, as in like professionals having a big meeting, involve a lot of drunk people.
Speaker 0: Handling situations like this is definitely not something that the hotel would be surprised by.
Speaker 0: If anything, allowing us to handle disturbance calls is something of a courtesy before hotel security calls the real
Speaker 0: place.".
Speaker 1: No!
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: Why do you, someone's in their hotel room, why should that have anything to do with your convention?
Speaker 0: Even if it's in your room block, you gotta stay as far away from that as possible.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that has nothing to do with you.
Speaker 0: And this is my main point.
Speaker 1: Let the real police come.
Speaker 0: This is my main point.
Speaker 0: There are incidents that happen at all sorts of conventions.
Speaker 1: Even like they said, ones with office guys at, you know, conferences for financial bullshit.
Speaker 1: Now, at the same time- Even when the president goes to Columbia.
Speaker 0: Those conventions, like for example, whatever drama happens at PAX, they're pretty open about explaining what happened.
Speaker 0: And two, they don't get involved in stuff that happens outside of the convention.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you make trouble in the PAX hotel, PAX has nothing to do with that.
Speaker 0: If the hotel kicks you out, well, that's your fault.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the thing is, I don't understand this hotel doing these kind of things, right?
Speaker 0: It's like- No, if I ran a hotel, I would never let the staff of a convention knock on rooms.
Speaker 0: Like, doors of rooms.
Speaker 0: Now, I don't know if that itself was allowed, because they basically said that wasn't allowed.
Speaker 0: And there's a whole other drama there.
Speaker 1: But the fact that- It's like the only people who are going to knock on any room.
Speaker 1: doors are police, people who are trying to visit, you know, just- Like, I'm trying to knock on Rym's door because I'm his next door neighbor or something, you know.
Speaker 1: Legitimate door knocking.
Speaker 1: Or, hotel staff.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: Not going to have convention staff.
Speaker 1: It's like, you're not hotel staff.
Speaker 1: You're not doing shit here.
Speaker 1: Whether you do have the convention staff clean some rooms, maybe have some hotel staff do some panels, it's like, come on, no.
Speaker 1: That's not how it works.
Speaker 0: So, I found that whole part of it really interesting, too.
Speaker 0: But I guess, in all this, I'm wondering if this will be a change just for Anime Boston, because if the hotel management now has to talk to the city about, you know, whatever incident, then that might force the hotels that are actually connected to deal with something that is a problem for pretty much every big anime con.
Speaker 0: Every room has 12 people in it.
Speaker 0: And if the hotels actually enforce occupancy- The convention attendance will go,
Speaker 0: "Ding!"
Speaker 0: Or, the hotels will all be full and there won't be rooms for anyone else.
Speaker 1: Also true.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: I've got a lot of other things to say about attendance and the way people act at cons, but that's not the thing I want to focus on.
Speaker 1: But then the thing about this, if you can't actually get seven people in a room because they crack down and they actually check, and you get kicked out, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, a lot of those punk kids couldn't afford the hotel room unless they have seven people's worth of money.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So they won't even be able to come at all, regardless of whether the hotel's full or not.
Speaker 0: Now, one final interesting piece of all this is that, of course, people are commenting on it.
Speaker 1: All over the place.
Speaker 0: No, no, out on the internet.
Speaker 0: The thing that was tweeted that was the progenitor of this whole conversation.
Speaker 1: Oh, so not the drunken staff story, but the-.
Speaker 0: Because we knew, I mean, people were texting me while I was at PAX saying, "Yo dawg, cops are at Anime Boston, shit's going
Speaker 0: down.".
Speaker 0: So it's not like that was news.
Speaker 1: That's not a "yo
Speaker 1: dawg.".
Speaker 0: They just said, "Yo dawg" does not necessarily mean "the yo
Speaker 0: dawg.".
Speaker 0: It does.
Speaker 0: I was not using "the royal yo
Speaker 0: dawg.".
Speaker 0: Sometimes, people colloquially will say, "Yo
Speaker 1: No, that's just
Speaker 1: "yo.".
Speaker 0: You can say "yo
Speaker 0: dawg.".
Speaker 1: No, not unless it's "yo dawg,".
Speaker 1: I put the X in your ex.
Speaker 0: Scott, that's the royal yo dawg.
Speaker 1: I heard you like eggs.
Speaker 1: I put it in your ex.
Speaker 0: One side thing, dances at anime cons are a cesspool of bullshit drama.
Speaker 0: And as much as I used to like them, I feel like the cons would be better served getting rid of them.
Speaker 1: I think you could just make them better.
Speaker 0: Well, I think you could.
Speaker 0: However, I don't think any fan anime con can, because it would require professionals.
Speaker 1: It would also require changing the existing culture and existing expectations.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, you could fix it without changing the culture top-down, but then you would have to have professional people managing the rave itself in a heavy-handed manner.
Speaker 1: Right, but what I'm saying is that you would have this rave, but you're gonna change the way, you're gonna change raves at cons, right?
Speaker 1: So you have your different rave.
Speaker 1: All these people show up expecting the usual.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: The first year, the people who expect that get kicked out.
Speaker 1: And they're gonna come in and do what they expect to happen there.
Speaker 0: And they get kicked out, and then the other people who generally avoid it come in.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna come in because they're also expecting the usual.
Speaker 0: Ah, no, because word travels fast in the modern era.
Speaker 0: I think top-down can work just as well as seated bottom-up.
Speaker 0: However, I think top-down is impossible at fan conventions, having staffed Otacon, Kinetacon, Katsucon in my time, among other cons.
Speaker 0: And I think seated bottom-up can't work, because I've been to anime cons for the last decade.
Speaker 1: So anyway, I got some news here.
Speaker 0: The only last thing is that people commenting on this are making the dumbest possible recommendations as to what Anime Boston should do.
Speaker 0: The most common one is you should make the dance 18+, and the badges should be coded like Magfest does with their wristbands, so I know if someone's jailbait.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so look at this whole shitstorm from this tiny tweet, and we still don't know what really happened.
Speaker 1: Whatever, who cares.
Speaker 1: Typical con drama bullshit.
Speaker 1: So, here's some real news.
Speaker 1: that's actually really good news.
Speaker 1: So, Tor, if you don't know, Tor is a sci-fi book publisher that is an imprint of Macmillan, right?
Speaker 1: So there's really only five big book publishers.
Speaker 0: Not Tor the Router or Tor the Guy, one with Burning Wheel.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: There's only really five or six big book publishers in the US, and all the other publishers are small, whatever, right?
Speaker 1: But all of those publishers are really big and have a bunch of smaller imprints and labels underneath them, right?
Speaker 1: And I think it's like Macmillan, Hachette, I don't remember all of them, right?
Speaker 1: But anyway, so Macmillan, their sci-fi books are published under the label Tor.
Speaker 1: Tor, coincidentally, is Cory Doctorow's publisher, right?
Speaker 1: But anyway, that's related to the story because they just decided to abandon all DRMs on their ebooks.
Speaker 1: Hooray!
Speaker 1: I can now buy ebooks legitimately instead of just, you know, pirating or only getting free Gutenberg books.
Speaker 1: So that's pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: And what's interesting is you read this article, and it's on Forbes, and it's actually a pretty long, significant article.
Speaker 1: It's funny because there's a picture of Neil Gaiman in the article, that picture of him with his white dog, but there aren't any quotes from him or even mentions of him.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the thing is, there's like multiple quotes in here from like book publishers and Charlie Stross and all these people, and one anonymous publishing executive, all talking about how, you know, "Yeah, DRM, we let Amazon and Apple control us,".
Speaker 1: and all, you know, they're saying all the right things, but it's like, "Why you do this now?
Speaker 1: In 2012, you should have had this shit in
Speaker 1: '98.".
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: You're only, oh, 10, 15 years too late?
Speaker 0: The thing is, the entire industry is just as late, if not, not even there yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're sort of, you know, I'm hoping that this causes a wave of DRM-free across the board.
Speaker 1: But what it's really, the thing this is really going to cause, right, is obviously piracy is not going to go up, right?
Speaker 1: That's just not going to happen because anyone who wants to pirate is already pirating.
Speaker 1: It's not going to change.
Speaker 1: Sales might go up because all those people, you know, sort of like me, who are like, "I'm not buying your no DRM book," might buy them.
Speaker 1: But they got to lower the price, right?
Speaker 1: I'm not paying.
Speaker 1: I was on, I went to Amazon the other day, I was looking at this book.
Speaker 1: The hardcover book, no, the paperback cover book price was $10.97.
Speaker 1: The Kindle price was $9.99.
Speaker 1: It's like,
Speaker 1: "No."
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Even if it's, and the thing is, in the article, they sort of talk about how, "Yeah, people weren't willing to pay as much because they weren't actually getting the book.
Speaker 1: They were just getting this
Speaker 1: license.".
Speaker 1: And I'm like, "No, I'm not willing to pay as much because I'm getting some file and not
Speaker 1: paper.".
Speaker 1: If you give me a file, whether it's DRM'd or not, you're getting, like, a dollar.
Speaker 0: The thing is, I don't want paper at all anymore.
Speaker 1: That's true, but I still, I'm not willing to pay, even though I don't want paper.
Speaker 0: Scott, the cost of the paper is the minority of the, you know, why it costs what it costs.
Speaker 1: I know, but I'm still not willing to pay a lot for a file.
Speaker 0: I think the argument's very simple.
Speaker 0: Regardless of piracy, even if piracy didn't exist, no piracy in the entire world and no secondary market for any new media because of crazy DRM.
Speaker 0: There's already enough books I haven't read.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: I could spend my entire life reading if I gave up all other forms of media.
Speaker 1: Right, the reason I'm not willing to pay so much is because there's just so many books, I could just spend the rest of my life reading Project Gutenberg and never have another book.
Speaker 0: Yet for the book club, you choose a relatively new and not super cheap for a free book.
Speaker 1: No, I don't.
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 0: Was that book, well, we haven't read it yet, so I can't say if it's worth it.
Speaker 1: You know how I acquired said book?
Speaker 0: You pirated it?
Speaker 1: With my friend, Captain.
Speaker 1: That's how I got that book.
Speaker 0: I might pay for it, just because.
Speaker 1: It's supposed to be a really good book, but anyway.
Speaker 0: You don't want to forgive that author any money, fuck that.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, you know.
Speaker 0: Well, well.
Speaker 1: Well what?
Speaker 0: You pirated it.
Speaker 1: I pirated a lot of things.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: That's how the world works.
Speaker 0: So what if the book's awesome?
Speaker 0: You gonna rectify that?
Speaker 0: You just gonna let it be not paid for?
Speaker 1: No, but I might buy other books by the author.
Speaker 0: Or just pirate those.
Speaker 1: Or maybe, maybe not.
Speaker 1: It's case by case basis decision making here, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it's how it goes.
Speaker 1: You know, I don't know if I'm gonna like it yet.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna pay for it before I know if I like it, right?
Speaker 1: Some land of mystery.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Uh, but yeah, this is good to see, right?
Speaker 1: Because the music industry already sorta did this.
Speaker 1: And now, you know, even though it didn't help them, because they're still stupid.
Speaker 1: And now, books are doing it.
Speaker 1: So, pretty much it's movies and, you know, video games sorta kinda, maybe, did it kinda.
Speaker 1: In some cases.
Speaker 0: Except Steam.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's sorta DRM, but sorta not.
Speaker 1: It sorta is.
Speaker 1: Well, it is.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: The only difference.
Speaker 1: There's no beating around the bush, it's DRM.
Speaker 1: The
Speaker 0: only difference is that Steam makes a very important point, not to shift the topic and dwell on this, that there is a kind of DRM that is permissive enough and safe enough from a company that we trust enough because they have enough goodwill with the right prices
Speaker 1: to where
Speaker 0: I'll do
Speaker 1: it.
Speaker 1: It's still bullshit, though, that you should be able to transfer any Steam game to someone else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that will not happen without the Supreme Court saying that we have a right to first sale on digital goods.
Speaker 1: Well, we've already had courts, like, one or two steps under that saying the very thing.
Speaker 0: Scott, the Supreme Court.
Speaker 1: Remember the AutoCAD case.
Speaker 0: The current Supreme Court.
Speaker 1: Autodesk vs.
Speaker 1: What's His Face.
Speaker 0: Scott, the current Supreme Court.
Speaker 0: What do you think they are gonna rule on something like that?
Speaker 1: That's why no lawyers have pushed it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: 'Cause they know it's not right, but anyway.
Speaker 0: They're not even gonna listen to a case like that.
Speaker 1: But this gives me hope that maybe within, like, a few years, the stupid movie people will come around, right?
Speaker 1: If I owned a big movie company, you know what I would do?
Speaker 1: This is what I would do.
Speaker 1: I mean, we talk about this all the time anyway, but it's like when a movie came out, I would have it out in the theater and on the DVD and digital and the Blu-ray and the TV pay-per-view and the HBO and everything and every country and every language
Speaker 0: simultaneously.
Speaker 1: And that would be it.
Speaker 1: It would just be the release.
Speaker 1: It's out.
Speaker 1: You want or you like Netflix?
Speaker 1: It's on Netflix.
Speaker 1: You like downloading an HD for five bucks?
Speaker 1: It's there.
Speaker 0: So Scott, you're gonna finish your thing, right?
Speaker 0: You're American.
Speaker 0: It's in English.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: You're gonna wait to release it until you translate it into every human language?
Speaker 1: The translation would be simultaneous with the production.
Speaker 0: So you're gonna hire people to translate it during production into every human language?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Any language which was profitable to translate it into.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 1: You're not gonna translate it into Swahili if you don't have a lot of fans and speak Swahili.
Speaker 1: But obviously, you know, French, Chinese, probably good bets, Spanish, probably a good idea.
Speaker 1: You know, there's big fans.
Speaker 0: Why not just Esperanto?
Speaker 0: That everyone in the world will understand you.
Speaker 1: Because nobody understands us.
Speaker 1: Portuguese, probably a good choice.
Speaker 1: A lot of people in Brazil.
Speaker 0: So there's one thing that apparently the entire world can agree on.
Speaker 0: With the exception of one people.
Speaker 1: That things of the day are awesome.
Speaker 0: Oh, you want me to say it?
Speaker 0: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: That Salmiakki is fucking awful unless you're Finnish.
Speaker 0: It's disgusting.
Speaker 0: So this is a real commercial, as far as I can tell, from Finland.
Speaker 0: And the catchphrase is...
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure that is the most popular Salmiakki brand, because that's the one that I see the most often.
Speaker 0: So the catchphrase is basically, "The world hated Finnish beloved.
Speaker 0: Mailman vihatwin, swoman
Speaker 0: rakatstituin.".
Speaker 1: Timo's probably like banging his head against the wall.
Speaker 1: I'm sure the Finnish listeners are just like,
Speaker 1: "Ah.".
Speaker 0: No, but I've learned that the word for "world" in Finnish is apparently
Speaker 0: "mailman."
Speaker 0: Like straight up.
Speaker 1: I think it's
Speaker 1: "maaliman.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's
Speaker 0: "mailman.".
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the commercial shows a whole bunch of non-Finnish people eating the Salmiakki-flavored ice cream.
Speaker 1: The ice cream looks like a Klondike bar and a stick, but it's a diamond, which is the shape of the Salmiakki.
Speaker 0: They are reacting.
Speaker 0: I think one guy says something like, "This is fucking horrible.
Speaker 0: Ugh.".
Speaker 0: Like they can't deal with it.
Speaker 0: And then it cuts to a bunch of Finnish people, and they're all like, "Oh, this is great.
Speaker 0: Salmiakki,
Speaker 0: yeah.".
Speaker 1: It's ice cream that tastes like Salmiakki, yeah.
Speaker 0: And they just keep eating it.
Speaker 0: I love the fact that the advertising campaign for the Salmiakki is basically, "Everybody hates this except
Speaker 0: you.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, "Be awesome Finnish people that like things the rest of the world hates.
Speaker 1: Aren't we better than the rest of the world?
Speaker 1: Ah, yeah, because we like this
Speaker 1: thing.".
Speaker 0: I also like this word "utus" that, as far as Google knows, means novelty, but it's got four U's in it and only two other letters.
Speaker 1: I gotta say, this commercial really has sort of balls, the same way those Domino's commercials have balls, where they're like, "Our pizza sucks, but come on, eight bucks, and we know it sucks.
Speaker 1: We tried to improve it.
Speaker 1: Just try it at least once.
Speaker 0: It reminds me a little bit of that Maasauhusets commercial.
Speaker 0: Maasauhusets.
Speaker 1: All right, anyway.
Speaker 1: So check out this thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I'm checking.
Speaker 1: Do you remember that video that was the thing of the day a long time ago that was so awesome?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that video that was the awesome thing of the day.
Speaker 1: That was how a differential works in a car.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Great video.
Speaker 1: This video is Mechanical Principles.
Speaker 1: It's a 1930 film by Ralph Steiner.
Speaker 1: It's four minutes long, and it shows you all kinds of really clever mechanical things to where it's like, "Oh,
Speaker 1: snap.".
Speaker 0: Those are sexy gears.
Speaker 0: They all have the same cadence where you watch it and you go,
Speaker 0: "Huh?".
Speaker 1: I'm looking at the video on YouTube right now, and the fourth suggestion is how differential gear works.
Speaker 1: Parentheses, best tutorial.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I always like these kind of videos, and I think this sort of mechanical engineering is not a lost art, because you can go to school and learn this if you want to, but it used to be sort of like the only thing, right?
Speaker 1: But now, there's a lot more kinds of engineering.
Speaker 1: Even in kinds of engineering, there's multiple levels, right?
Speaker 1: You might work on cars, but only work on computers in cars, or you might only work on combustion engine.
Speaker 1: It's like this sort of raw mechanical engineering thing, there's fewer and fewer people who know it, and it's so awesome.
Speaker 1: When you look at it, it's like, "Oh, shit, that's
Speaker 1: sweet.".
Speaker 1: When did people get so smart?
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, this weekend, the 28th and 29th is the Mocha Fest 2012 in New York.
Speaker 1: If you don't know, from past years, we've gone to this thing like five or six years in a row.
Speaker 0: It's one of my favorite things of the year.
Speaker 1: It's the Museum of Comic and Cartoon Art, which is a museum that you can go to.
Speaker 1: I'm a member.
Speaker 1: I think it hasn't expired, my membership.
Speaker 0: Mine did expire because I forgot to renew it.
Speaker 1: It's their festival, which is basically what they do.
Speaker 1: is that museum sponsors this festival, which is their biggest fundraiser of the year.
Speaker 0: It is technically a fest.
Speaker 1: Yes, they go to the Lexington Armory, which is their current location.
Speaker 1: Years ago, it used to be a different building.
Speaker 1: The Puck Building.
Speaker 1: They fill it with tables, and they sell those tables to indie comic publishers and indie comic artists, even some non-indies.
Speaker 0: You will have super professional, world-famous artists next to a kid who hand-drew something and stapled it together and cut it out himself.
Speaker 1: Some SVA student kid.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Most of the time.
Speaker 0: A lot of SVA and RISD stuff there.
Speaker 1: Those SVA kids are really good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they are.
Speaker 1: They stand out.
Speaker 1: We used to play the game.
Speaker 0: SVA?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right?
Speaker 1: Basically, what you do is you go to this thing, you buy a ticket, you just buy it at the door, and you walk around for two to three hours looking at every single booth, and it's all totally awesome, and you get a sack full of comics.
Speaker 1: Then you go eat lunch somewhere nearby, and then you go home, and it is the awesome weekend.
Speaker 1: It's two days if you're really obsessed, but you really only need to go for a few hours on one day.
Speaker 1: That's all that's necessary.
Speaker 1: It'd be too crowded if everyone stayed the whole time.
Speaker 0: Just walk around.
Speaker 1: There are some cool panels if you really want to wait in line and figure out where they are and such.
Speaker 1: I've never found it worth it, but there are amazing people at these panels.
Speaker 0: The key is to walk around the entire place methodically and stop at every booth and just look at what's there.
Speaker 0: I defy you, unless you don't bring money with you on purpose, to walk out without a pile of comics.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the thing is, a lot of times, people, especially people without a lot of money, are money conscious.
Speaker 1: At the mocha, the strategy is do not care about monies, except for crazy cases, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, just go around, and if you see something cool, just get it.
Speaker 1: The only times that you would hold back is giant, fancy, hundred dollar hardcover.
Speaker 1: Then you can start to think about maybe not buying it, but it's like, oh, a little foldy comic.
Speaker 1: Someone printed a Kinko's.
Speaker 1: buy that.
Speaker 1: Oh, a cute little turtle thing.
Speaker 1: Buy that.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's a comic about poop.
Speaker 1: Gotta buy that, right?
Speaker 0: I still have the diarrhea diaries.
Speaker 1: Just fill up your bag with all the goodies, and then when you get home, everyone you brought with you just spread the shit out on the floor and be like, oh, snap.
Speaker 0: I wish I could get more prison comics, though.
Speaker 1: And then just sort of roll around in the comics like, uh.
Speaker 0: So not the following weekend, but the weekend after that, May 11th and 12th is Zenkai-Khan in Pennsylvania.
Speaker 1: Why so soon?
Speaker 0: We will be there doing two panels or lectures.
Speaker 0: I forget what they are, but one of them is about both My Little Pony, Friendship is Magic, and Dude Bro.
Speaker 0: My shit is fucked up, so I got to shoot/slice you two.
Speaker 0: It's straight up dog time.
Speaker 1: At least you remember the name.
Speaker 1: How could you forget that?
Speaker 1: So basically rehashing an old panel that is good and...
Speaker 0: Mashing it up with another concept about mashups.
Speaker 1: Throwing ponies in there to get people in the door.
Speaker 0: Not just that, we got some points to make.
Speaker 0: And when we're not, we're only going to be there Saturday.
Speaker 0: When we're not...
Speaker 1: It's a Friday and Saturday con.
Speaker 0: Doing our thing at the convention, probably going to be...
Speaker 1: Scott Johnson knows we're only going to be there Saturday, right?
Speaker 0: I assume so.
Speaker 0: We're pretty much going to be hanging out in the little tabletop area playing German bargains.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they have a very tiny tabletop area.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it'll be changed this year and be less tiny, but that doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: What matters is they actually have... It's not the greatest game selection, which still goes to Kineticon as the greatest board game library.
Speaker 1: It's not as big as the PAX one, which, while not as good as the Kineticon one in terms of selection, is very large.
Speaker 1: But they do have choice stuff, and they have a large amount of it relative to the amount of people playing it.
Speaker 1: So it is definitely good time.
Speaker 1: tabletop at Zenkai Con.
Speaker 1: In addition to all their other great programming, which is mostly anime and sci-fi-ish stuff in nature.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: It's one of the few cons where if you want to hang out with us, we're kind of just chilling.
Speaker 1: It's one of the only small cons we go to, and we go because our friends run it.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Speaking of cons our friend run, we do all the panel programming for Kineticon, which is July 13th, 14th, and 15th this year.
Speaker 0: So make your panels, I'll put the link in.
Speaker 0: I'm already scheduling, so get your panel in as soon as possible, because the longer you wait, the less likely it is that I will accept your panel, or give you a time that isn't like 8am on Friday.
Speaker 1: But we do have a lot more rooms this year.
Speaker 0: 11 rooms!
Speaker 1: So we can fit a lot in there, so we do need as many applications as possible, because the more applications we get, the more we can pick out the chocolate and get rid of the shit.
Speaker 1: If we get like two applications and they're bullshit, well guess what, there's gonna be two shitty panels, end of con.
Speaker 0: So two weekends after that is Otacon, I'm just saying, you anime fans, if you want us to be at Otacon, tell Otacon that.
Speaker 0: Because we went to, we presented panels- We could just buy badges when we go.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna go as an attendee.
Speaker 0: Me either.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go because you guys want me to show you some anime.
Speaker 0: But I think seven years in a row we did panels at Otacon, so if we're not there, it's because they didn't want us, not because we did not offer.
Speaker 0: And of course Pax Prime, not too long after that.
Speaker 1: Badges went on sale for Pax Prime today.
Speaker 0: Pause Geek Nights now, go buy 'em.
Speaker 1: If you are going to go to Pax Prime in Seattle- If you think you might go- Immediately, this second, as in Pause Geek Nights and buy the badges, if you don't, then shut up, you're not going.
Speaker 1: Just assume you're not going if you don't buy them right now.
Speaker 0: So Scott, how long before it sells out?
Speaker 0: What do you think?
Speaker 0: What's the over-under?
Speaker 1: A month or two.
Speaker 0: I want to make a bet.
Speaker 1: They brought the site down today, there was so much traffic trying to register it.
Speaker 0: I'll bet you 60 days from today- That's what I just said.
Speaker 0: It'll be sold out, exactly.
Speaker 0: How much you willing to bet?
Speaker 1: I don't bet monies on things that I am not 100% sure of.
Speaker 0: So then you don't bet.
Speaker 1: What I can do is I will tell you this, I will go and look at the official Pax Twitter account, and I will look through the archives to last year to find the exact day they sold out last time and the day they went on sale last
Speaker 0: time- I think that will be a failing proposition
Speaker 1: for you.
Speaker 1: See how many days it took to sell out last year?
Speaker 1: I will bet that it will be less days than that.
Speaker 0: That's a sure bet.
Speaker 1: That's why I'm betting, I only bet when it's a sure bet.
Speaker 0: Considering how many people were denied access to Pax East and considering this time in particular, how many people panicked when they didn't get badges to Pax East, they went to the Prime website and saw they couldn't buy badges and assumed that was also sold out.
Speaker 0: And Pax Dev and other stuff, and then not too long after that, Pax East.
Speaker 1: Is Pax Dev even for sure?
Speaker 1: I'm trying to find that out.
Speaker 1: It wasn't an explosive success last time, it was just kind of cool, and they haven't officially said that they're doing it again, so it may or may not happen.
Speaker 0: The website is still up and there is a countdown to August 24th, 2011, but it is- I guess that means it's happening.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 0: But it is counting down.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: Interesting.
Speaker 0: Interesting, indeed.
Speaker 0: It's not counting up.
Speaker 1: Well, we don't know if there will be a Pax Dev 2 or not.
Speaker 0: I will probably go if there is, but we'll see.
Speaker 0: If I have vacation days, I would probably like to go- I will try to confirm, I'll do some investigative journalism for you if it is in fact happening or not.
Speaker 1: We could just email somebody we know and be like,
Speaker 1: "Hey.".
Speaker 0: That's investigative journalism, ask somebody, and then follow up on that asking.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: That's what you do.
Speaker 0: If that doesn't work, then you go and look at stuff.
Speaker 1: All right, so, animes.
Speaker 0: So Lupin the Third, the woman called Fujiko Mine, is the first Lupin thing in a long time.
Speaker 1: Well, the first Lupin thing in a long time that wasn't just one of those made for TV movies that they made for every year.
Speaker 0: That I did not ignore.
Speaker 0: Because it is common knowledge that the quality of a Lupin-related thing, and in terms of time from, what was the last good Lupin thing?
Speaker 0: It's got to be something after Momo that was at least decent.
Speaker 1: It was the movie where they were in Rio.
Speaker 0: The Secret of the Village, where Lupin keeps all his stuff.
Speaker 1: I don't remember what year that one was, though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: That might have been the last good one.
Speaker 1: Ignore what that one was named.
Speaker 0: There was the one where Lupin was dead.
Speaker 1: There's the one about where Zenigata loses his job, and he's eating ramen and he's all sad.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much Fuma Conspiracy and Cagliostro for me.
Speaker 1: Well, and the two TV series, the old one and the newer one.
Speaker 1: The second TV series, the one that was on Cartoon Network.
Speaker 0: The point is, Lupin recently has not been, shall we say, exciting and/or choice.
Speaker 1: He's sort of like one of those things where he's a popular, well-known character in Japan and they sort of bring him out every year.
Speaker 1: Maybe he's equal in popularity to Garfield in the US, something like that.
Speaker 1: Everyone knows him, but not too many crazy fans.
Speaker 1: Not super ultra-popular constantly, but he comes around all the time.
Speaker 0: It's like, imagine if James Bond's stuff in America were more prolific and not all that good, even though it's not all that good, though I think Timothy Dalton gets a bad rap and I digress.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so they bring out a new TV series.
Speaker 1: That's sort of a big deal.
Speaker 1: Because it's like, whoa, it's just been sort of like one made-for-TV movie per year.
Speaker 0: Now I heard this and I was like, "Oh, whatever, it's gonna be another shit,
Speaker 0: Lupin.".
Speaker 0: And then I saw the art and I thought, "There's no way the show looks like
Speaker 0: this.".
Speaker 0: Then I saw the trailer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was not a Wonder Woman situation.
Speaker 0: And in the trailer, I thought, "There is no way the show looks like this.
Speaker 0: It looks like
Speaker 0: that.".
Speaker 1: The show looks like the cover.
Speaker 1: It is great.
Speaker 1: It looks like the opener.
Speaker 0: I really like it.
Speaker 1: Well, the art, obviously, is astounding.
Speaker 1: I mean, I love it when anyone tries to do a unique style and they just went all out with it.
Speaker 0: But it is such a homage to the old '70s style Lupin and animation, but yet it's also got a modern sensibility.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the whole thing, is that what they've done with this show is they've taken the core of what Lupin is all about and applied the modern sensibility and mixed it up.
Speaker 1: So you're watching it and you see the old-school Lupin shine through this modern, totally brand new anime sheet.
Speaker 1: And it's like, "Aw, snap.
Speaker 1: This is
Speaker 1: awesome.".
Speaker 0: And it's telling that we are somewhat disconnected from the majority of anime fans because the first comment when this was first announced on the Funimation website is, and I quote, "Wassup,
Speaker 0: Lupin?".
Speaker 0: "I watched episode one and liked it.
Speaker 0: My one complaint is I'm not sure I like this animation
Speaker 0: style.".
Speaker 0: The thing that made me the most excited is the thing the first person who got off his butt to post about was, "Oh, I guess this is the last comment, not the first comment.
Speaker 0: It's sorted
Speaker 0: weirdly.".
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: That's the first comment.
Speaker 0: you see if you look here.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: So, Scotty, you want to do the one, two, three, even though I think we've tipped our hand.
Speaker 1: There's no point.
Speaker 0: I think we've tipped our hand.
Speaker 1: I really like this show, but not- I mean, it's good, but it's not, "Aw, yeah.
Speaker 1: You're the
Speaker 1: awesomest.".
Speaker 1: It's just like-.
Speaker 0: Well, Scotty, this is a preview.
Speaker 0: We've only seen three episodes.
Speaker 1: That's enough.
Speaker 0: And it's on the level of.
Speaker 0: I will watch the next episode when it comes out pretty much right away.
Speaker 1: What day does it come out?
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: I just check every day.
Speaker 1: I'll check like once a week, probably on the weekend, and just watch it.
Speaker 0: There have been three episodes, and if you have not watched this yet, one, if you're an anime fan, just watch it.
Speaker 0: Just watch it.
Speaker 0: Don't even ask about it.
Speaker 1: We should mention that in order to watch it, you need to go and get a free login at Funimation's website- But then it just works.
Speaker 1: And then you search for Lupin and then watch it.
Speaker 1: Now, the thing is, this show is not actually about Lupin, which every previous Lupin has been, or at least most of them.
Speaker 1: It's actually about Fujiko, right?
Speaker 1: And the thing is, so far, the three episodes, the first episode was Fujiko and Lupin.
Speaker 1: The second episode is Fujiko and Jigen, and the third episode is Fujiko and Goemon.
Speaker 1: So it's like, it's about Fujiko, but it's also about the other Lupin characters.
Speaker 1: Also, it's- I don't know what's canon and what's not.
Speaker 1: Lupin isn't the kind of thing- it's more like a- Lupin is more like a Matsumoto-verse kind of situation.
Speaker 0: I was about to say, well, was Kat and Harlock before or after Lupin?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Castle of Cagliostro.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: But this is, chronologically, an ultra-prequel.
Speaker 1: Episode one was the first meeting of Lupin and Fujiko, theoretically, even though that may have been portrayed in a manga or an anime previously.
Speaker 1: This is the beginning.
Speaker 0: The majority of anime fans in America probably have seen maybe one or two Lupin movies.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Maybe an episode or two of the TV show because it was on TV.
Speaker 1: I actually think newer fans, right, anyone, you know, have not seen any.
Speaker 1: And it's sort of like, you know, it's like, so there's like.
Speaker 1: the current generation of fan hasn't seen any Lupin, might not even know who he is.
Speaker 1: The previous generation, some of them saw it on Cartoon Network.
Speaker 1: And then the generation before that and before that- Watched every movie.
Speaker 1: They would only have seen it if they were like us with the anime club kind of situation where someone's exposing you to Lupin on purpose.
Speaker 1: But my point is that- And then, of course, the old school people know all about it.
Speaker 0: This show, it's a super-prequel that requires no knowledge of Lupin whatsoever other than the vague idea that Lupin is a thief.
Speaker 1: Well, okay, it doesn't require knowledge of Lupin, right?
Speaker 1: You can watch this and completely understand everything that's going on and it will introduce the characters to you.
Speaker 1: But, a lot of the enjoyment comes from already knowing, not, you don't need to know the plots or any particular previous Lupin show or movie, but you have to know the characters, personalities and what they're about.
Speaker 1: And if you know that, then watching this gives you that special extra enjoyment.
Speaker 0: Well, Scott, we've said the same thing about other things before, I mean, even the movie of Galaxy Express is like a compressed- Yeah, but I think- There's moments in it where you think about what happened in the show and it feels very different.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that if I knew nothing about Lupin and I watched this, it probably would have been okay and not really good.
Speaker 0: I think it still would have been pretty good because- Pretty good, but not really good.
Speaker 0: The characters that are presented are fascinating in their pathologies.
Speaker 1: They are, indeed.
Speaker 0: And that alone, I'd be really interested in following that thread.
Speaker 0: But of course, we have the knowledge of the way Lupin and her interact is special just for the sense that she is the one who straight up kills that guy.
Speaker 0: And Lupin is the one like, "Whoa, really?
Speaker 0: You killed him?
Speaker 0: Jesus.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'll kill people, but come
Speaker 0: on.".
Speaker 0: And the way that she interacts with Goemon is great if you have seen all the rest of Lupin.
Speaker 1: I think it's really cool in that even though it has the same visual style and the same sort of idea that's a prequel, it focuses on Fujiko, is that so far the three different episodes have been very different.
Speaker 1: The first episode, which was about Lupin and Fujiko, had a lot of that Lupin wackiness and zaniness going on, right?
Speaker 1: You know, like, "Oh my God, there's a dude riding a Buddha made of
Speaker 1: drugs.".
Speaker 1: That's so Lupin, riding a motorcycle on a clown face.
Speaker 1: That's what he does.
Speaker 0: We've talked about this recently a lot, that people think of Cagliostro as our typical Lupin.
Speaker 0: No, that is atypical Lupin.
Speaker 0: Typical Lupin is drug Buddha.
Speaker 1: The Jigen episode, right, was very serious and dark and a lot of killing people and serious But also it felt very Fistful of Dollars, kind of like a modern Western because of what he was doing.
Speaker 0: He's a bodyguard for the mob who killed his former boss.
Speaker 0: What's going on?
Speaker 1: And then the Goemon episode was sort of sweet and cute and sort of funny and a lot of ridiculous cutting of things.
Speaker 0: I have cut yet another trifling thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you don't know, that's like a catchphrase.
Speaker 1: You would sort of get it, but he's used that catchphrase before, forever.
Speaker 0: But here's the thing.
Speaker 0: This show, I feel like, if you don't know anything about Lupin, you'll see Goemon cutting all the clothes off people and watching just this episode.
Speaker 1: Did you notice that after he cut the dude's clothes off, then they ran to the next train car, the guy still had the clothes off.
Speaker 1: That shows you that they're paying attention in this show.
Speaker 0: But the fact that the sheer ridiculousity of that moment is very muted by everything else that is going on around it to where you almost just go with it.
Speaker 1: The thing is, I'm wondering, right, this fourth episode, is it out yet?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Is it going to be?
Speaker 1: Number one, it could focus on Zenigata, but Zenigata was sort of in the Lupin episode.
Speaker 1: He was, but he was after Lupin, not after her.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: It also, alternatively, right, even if it is or if it isn't, either the fourth or the fifth episode, is it just going to be a Fujiko doing something on her own?
Speaker 1: Are they going to start a plot that actually links the serial plot or is it continue to be episodic?
Speaker 1: or are they going to start bringing the characters together?
Speaker 1: Because it's still the show is supposed to be about Fujiko, right?
Speaker 1: Also, how many episodes is the show going to be in total?
Speaker 0: I didn't even look that up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So this is going to be pretty interesting, but I'm going to watch and continue to watch whatever they put out for as long as 12 episodes.
Speaker 1: I'm watching the whole thing, no matter what.
Speaker 0: And there are no titles yet for the rest of the episodes.
Speaker 1: Oh, keeping me in suspense.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Snap.
Speaker 1: But yeah, good job on them, you know, putting the episodes for free streaming on Funimation.com with subtitles right away.
Speaker 1: I can't complain.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, oh no, I have to log in.
Speaker 1: I made the account and you don't even have to verify email address, just works.
Speaker 0: So the one thing that I do want to touch on is that it is, shall we say, boob-tacular?
Speaker 0: Boob-tastic?
Speaker 0: Boobs.
Speaker 1: But... Lots of boobs.
Speaker 1: I mean, Fujiko has been known for showing off her gigantic, crazy boobs, which are even bigger than Naga the Serpent's boobs.
Speaker 0: What I can say about this, and I say this without any hint of irony, I'm not, you know, and they are two, like, exploitative boobs from '70s shows, or Old Lupin, what Black Dynamite is to black exploitation movies.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: But the boobs come out.
Speaker 1: all the, even in the Go-Mon episode, the boobs came out.
Speaker 1: But at the same time... The boobs are all, usually when you watch an opener to an anime, there'll be like one boob shot.
Speaker 1: This is nothing but boob shots.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: And it's not even like James Bond openers where you get a boob silhouette.
Speaker 1: It's just boobs.
Speaker 1: But... All over the place.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, it's starting to really fit in this narrative.
Speaker 0: Like, if you've seen a bunch of Lupin, but you haven't like read the manga and watched the entire, all the TV shows, so like, you know who these characters are, but you don't like really know the stories or the back history or anything, then Fujiko usually is portrayed as this kind of foil of Lupin, kind of a bitch, messes everything up, funny, like she comes in and messes stuff up at the last minute.
Speaker 0: But this is portraying her much more as someone who is deeply disturbed in the same kind of way.
Speaker 0: Like, you're getting this impression that she, Goemon, Lupin, Zenigata, and Jigen are deeply disturbed people with...
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's trying to seriously examine their actual characters while keeping their characters completely ridiculous as they were in the original show.
Speaker 1: Now some of the Lupins have gone into that.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like how they took Batman, right, and at first Batman was just, you know, detective or whatever, and then later on they tried to examine him like, "Oh, he's a crazy guy, his parents got shot,".
Speaker 1: you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: There have been some Lupins that get into...
Speaker 1: Is Bruce Wayne or Batman the mask?
Speaker 0: Why does the Lupin steal?
Speaker 0: Like the one where they have the village where he puts all the stuff he steals.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And it's the treasure, it's always something like that.
Speaker 0: But we haven't gotten that for the other characters, and this is sort of like...
Speaker 1: Also nothing's canon, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they probably just forget all that.
Speaker 0: No, but this show is sort of taking the other characters and putting their pathologies in stark relief and really focusing on them through the lens of following Fujiko and how pretty fucked up she is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, they're all fucked up, I mean, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but by using her as the focus, it's putting all of the other characters in a similar focus even though they're not the actual focus of the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean, because most other Lupins, the focus was always on the plot and the characters were just sort of being themselves the whole time.
Speaker 1: There was very little character development in most Lupin things.
Speaker 1: And even when there is, it doesn't necessarily stick, right?
Speaker 1: There might be something that explains... There might try to add something that someone's passed as part of the plot of a particular movie or episode, but that doesn't really stick and it's not really mentioned outside of that movie or episode.
Speaker 1: And based on the ending animation for this new show, it seems like they're going to explore Fujiko's past somehow, because they show all these pictures of her when she was young and such, so it's like, "Oh, they're going to tell us about what Fujiko was doing, how she got here,".
Speaker 1: because that's never explained in anything that I can remember ever watching.
Speaker 0: That closer definitely makes a very dark implication that she's always been this way.
Speaker 1: But it's also sort of, "Eh," because it's like, "Oh, 15-year-old Fujiko with boobies hanging out, sort of
Speaker 1: cowering.".
Speaker 0: I did not get the impression of cowering.
Speaker 0: I got the impression of doing the same kind of tricks that she pulls all the time.
Speaker 0: There is this dark implication in that closer that her pathology is a defect of the womb, that she has always been that way.
Speaker 1: Well, the ending is a little creepy.
Speaker 1: That's all I'm saying.
Speaker 0: So, the director, Sayo Yamamoto...
Speaker 1: What else have they done?
Speaker 0: It's one of those interesting stories of someone who hasn't really done a lot of straight-up.
Speaker 0: What's the studio?
Speaker 0: But has done a whole bunch of storyboards and unit direction and episode direction for a whole bunch of other stuff.
Speaker 1: And they got their chance.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, the only thing he directed was
Speaker 0: "Technolize."
Speaker 0: You sure it's a dude?
Speaker 0: No, it's not a dude.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 0: I tend to say "he" a lot.
Speaker 0: There's actually a picture of her right here.
Speaker 0: You fart at me while I'm talking.
Speaker 1: What's the studio?
Speaker 0: I can look it up.
Speaker 1: It should be right there on the page that you're on.
Speaker 0: I'm on the director page.
Speaker 0: Cricket.
Speaker 1: Good job.
Speaker 0: I found it.
Speaker 0: I just don't know these companies.
Speaker 0: The animation production is "potential," with a number 10, and TMS Entertainment...
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It has to be like Madhouse or Production I.G.
Speaker 1: or something.
Speaker 0: There's a difference in some of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of different stuff.
Speaker 1: You're not very good at this.
Speaker 0: NTV and TMS Entertainment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm not familiar with either of those.
Speaker 0: It's not any of the studios anyone knows.
Speaker 0: Tokyo Movie Shinsha.
Speaker 0: I know that.
Speaker 0: Don't you remember?
Speaker 0: It was about the first time.
Speaker 0: It was in Versailles.
Speaker 0: Ah.
Speaker 0: It was in Versailles, and it has it.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I found the gold mine.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: One, two, three, four, five.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: That's more than 10.
Speaker 0: So it's TMS Entertainment, Tokyo Movie Shinsha.
Speaker 0: They did one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten, eleven, eleven, a whole bunch of all the other Lupans.
Speaker 1: I guess that's who does Lupan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, The Last Job, Stolen Lupan, all the ones I haven't seen.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh, they did Pi-Cal.
Speaker 0: Remember Pi-Cal?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: You really don't?
Speaker 0: Green vs.
Speaker 0: Red, which I didn't see, actually.
Speaker 1: I didn't see that either.
Speaker 0: I wanted to.
Speaker 0: I thought it would be good, but I didn't.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I like it.
Speaker 0: I'm going to watch the rest of it.
Speaker 0: I can't really finally review it because, for all we know, it goes to crap after, you know, every episode we've seen.
Speaker 1: I doubt it'll go to complete crap.
Speaker 1: Also, you know, we've done shows on Lupan before, at least two of them, I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: You know, so maybe, you know, if you watch this, or maybe go watch some other Lupans.
Speaker 1: I recommend watching, of course, Castle of Cagliostro and Puma Conspiracy.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And the second- I would recommend watching Momo just to know what Lupan's really like.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can watch the second TV series.
Speaker 1: That's pretty good.
Speaker 0: That's a little more, like, campy, punny.
Speaker 1: Well, that's what Lupan's- A lot more lighthearted.
Speaker 1: That's what it's about.
Speaker 0: Nah, some of the other movies are less punny and campy and a little more weird.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but, you know, you can learn all about Lupan.
Speaker 1: The manga is, you know, way different than, you know, the first TV series.
Speaker 1: I never saw it.
Speaker 1: But, you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.