Speaker 1: It's Monday, August 13th, 2012.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Sky.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, paying for stuff in the new way.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Yesterday, I go to my friend's wedding who I've known since forever.
Speaker 1: Which guy?
Speaker 0: You met him once, Rick Cohen?
Speaker 0: You met him once.
Speaker 1: I do not remember that as even being a name.
Speaker 0: I think you went to a hockey game once.
Speaker 0: Minor League hockey game.
Speaker 1: I vaguely remember that, but I don't remember a person.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I've known him longer than forever anyway.
Speaker 0: But it was interesting because I didn't realize, I mean the wedding was in the temple, right?
Speaker 0: It was a, you know, Jewish wedding.
Speaker 0: So you go and you know, it's four o'clock, they do the service, but then all the party was in the same building.
Speaker 0: So it sort of dawned on me like, "Oh shit, this motherfucker's
Speaker 0: kosher.".
Speaker 1: You know, going to Christian-y weddings is the same thing.
Speaker 1: You're like, "All right, the wedding's born, whatever, it'll
Speaker 1: end.".
Speaker 1: And then we go to the reception.
Speaker 1: As soon as you find out the reception's also in the church, that means no booze most of the time.
Speaker 0: Oh, you kidding?
Speaker 0: There's open bars in every room of this place.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's how the Jews go, I guess.
Speaker 0: Right, but no one tips the bartender.
Speaker 0: There were, I think I had some tips.
Speaker 0: Not everyone was Jewish.
Speaker 0: So, um, what's it called?
Speaker 0: So I'm more, I'm like, "Oh shit, it's
Speaker 0: kosher.".
Speaker 0: And it was, so it was meat and there was no dairy.
Speaker 0: It's like there's a piece of bread on the plate when you go to sit at your table and there's something next to it.
Speaker 0: That ain't butter.
Speaker 0: Don't know what it is.
Speaker 0: It's not butter.
Speaker 1: Margarine?
Speaker 1: Is margarine kosher?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna find out.
Speaker 1: You keep talking.
Speaker 0: In the room, in the cocktail hour room, you go in and hidden in like the corner, there was some, you know, salmon and capers and onions and bagels.
Speaker 0: No cream cheese.
Speaker 1: Ah.
Speaker 0: And it's like, "Oh right, no cream
Speaker 0: cheese.".
Speaker 0: So the thing I was, you know, the thing is the food that they did have was excellente.
Speaker 0: There was, there was many very, very tasty foods and also lots of hidden foods.
Speaker 0: Like, they had.
Speaker 0: like, you know, it looked like an Ikea cabinet, you know, one of those like bookshelves with just a bunch of squares, like a whole bunch of them.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, five by five squares.
Speaker 0: And they had like fruits on plates inside this thing, just off to the side.
Speaker 0: You wouldn't even know if you didn't look.
Speaker 0: There were so many things to choose from.
Speaker 1: Alright, it's really hard to make margarine kosher because of the, like the practices involved.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but the one thing I was worried about the most was the wedding cake.
Speaker 0: Because you know wedding cake tastes better than regular cake.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the fuck they do with wedding cake.
Speaker 1: The wedding cake is one, more expensive.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: And is not a Betty Crocker cake, which is the majority of cakes you've ever eaten.
Speaker 0: Right, but I mean there's something about wedding cake.
Speaker 0: I think all the bakers have this conspiracy of like, "Oh, only make the right, cool, good kind of cake when you're for a wedding.
Speaker 0: Don't make good cake for anyone
Speaker 0: else.".
Speaker 1: Wait a minute, Scott.
Speaker 1: The next time we have a normal party, let's get a wedding cake.
Speaker 0: That would be amazing.
Speaker 1: Let's do it.
Speaker 0: A one layer wedding cake.
Speaker 0: New Year's wedding cake.
Speaker 1: Perfect.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: But, I was like, "Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: This wedding cake's motherfucking
Speaker 0: kosher.".
Speaker 1: Wait, now, why didn't they just not have the meat?
Speaker 1: Because I feel like if you got to give up one side or the other, and it's a party, why not go for the side that lets cake and breads be eaten more readily?
Speaker 0: There was Mad Tasty Meats.
Speaker 0: They brought out this meat on a stick.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, meat on a stick.
Speaker 0: I'm not complaining about the food.
Speaker 0: I'm just pointing out these funny "because it was kosher" bits.
Speaker 0: The food was great.
Speaker 0: It was just kosher.
Speaker 0: And as a result...
Speaker 1: We need someone to make that song instead of, "Because I got high, it's because it was
Speaker 1: kosher.".
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The cake looked pretty good.
Speaker 0: It was a nice cake, ample size.
Speaker 0: I was worried that it wouldn't taste good because it was a kosher wedding cake.
Speaker 0: I was correct to worry.
Speaker 0: It was less good than regular cake.
Speaker 0: Usually when you tell a story, you're like, "I was worried that X...".
Speaker 1: The story is always inevitably, "But luckily it wasn't
Speaker 1: X.".
Speaker 1: You just told me, "I was worried he'd
Speaker 1: die."
Speaker 1: And then he died.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was not... I didn't see too many other people eating it.
Speaker 0: I think I might have been the only person who even tried to eat it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it was like really thick frosting that was hard to make the decoration on the outside and it didn't taste good.
Speaker 0: And then the inside of the cake was sort of hard and crumbly.
Speaker 0: It's like, "Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: Kosher wedding cake, not...".
Speaker 1: Not to the best.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: So, if you want really good wedding cake, don't buy it from the Jewish baker.
Speaker 0: Or at least make sure you get a dairy cake from the Jewish baker.
Speaker 0: Don't get the meat part of cake.
Speaker 0: That's all I can say about that.
Speaker 0: No one else really cares about some wedding if someone they don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but most people don't care about weddings to people they do know.
Speaker 0: That's very true.
Speaker 0: It was actually, you know, I was... You know, whenever you go to a wedding, you're always like hesitant, like, "Is this gonna be
Speaker 0: good?".
Speaker 0: I don't know, even though I like these people and, you know, they're all good people.
Speaker 1: I've not had that problem because every wedding I've been to since I was a child has been for crew people where I know so many people there that the worst case scenario is I sit in the back and play Puerto Rico with people I know.
Speaker 0: One more thing to point out is they had a band instead of a DJ and the band basically played non-stop for the hours they were allotted and then as soon as their time was up, they just started packing up immediately, which, you know, you want to go home.
Speaker 0: Can't blame them.
Speaker 0: But it's like you sort of realize when you have a DJ, the DJ doesn't have to put forth effort to like put on music like the walk out of the room music.
Speaker 0: So it's like party's over.
Speaker 0: It's just quiet and it's kind of awkward.
Speaker 0: And like the caterers are all cleaning up immediately because they want to get their asses out of there, too.
Speaker 0: And, you know, everyone's still standing there because the music just sort of was like, "Oh, we're
Speaker 0: done.".
Speaker 1: You know, when I think back, most of the weddings I've been to, I've been that guy who was there to the end.
Speaker 0: No, I mean, you know, it was only from 4 to
Speaker 0: 10. 4.30,
Speaker 0: you know, everyone's tired.
Speaker 0: No, it was 4 to 10.
Speaker 0: You had to go to bed early.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it was way past my dad's bed.
Speaker 0: Marlon.
Speaker 0: Let's get out of here.
Speaker 1: Marlon, I'm starting the car.
Speaker 0: No, he went.
Speaker 0: He couldn't start the car.
Speaker 0: It was mandatory valet parking.
Speaker 0: So he went outside and was like, "Get in the valet to bring the
Speaker 0: car.".
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I'm not going to really dwell on this, but just because it's in the news, Facebook, as you know, not to looking so good.
Speaker 1: Not to looking so good.
Speaker 1: I still stand by my initial, from the very beginning, prediction that the Facebook IPO was little more than a crass cash grab.
Speaker 0: By the people who had bought it in the pre-IPO days.
Speaker 1: And by the people who ran the company, just for the sense that every big tech company before that point had been worth, you know, however many millions of dollars.
Speaker 1: And then was worth nothing by the time anyone could actually cash out.
Speaker 1: I feel like this is just Facebook saying, "You know what?
Speaker 1: Let's get our money from Wall Street, and then who cares what the fuck happens after
Speaker 1: that?".
Speaker 1: It's my guess.
Speaker 1: Just, you know, I'm not affiliated with Facebook, this is not stock advice, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: Strong sell, not stock advice.
Speaker 1: I will say that I do not own any Facebook stock, and I have actually considered shorting it, because I think it's going to go way lower.
Speaker 0: Do I?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I have a 401(k).
Speaker 0: that's sort of just this mystery land.
Speaker 1: None of my 401(k) mutual funds have Facebook.
Speaker 0: But I mean, I'm not even in, I'm like a layer away, I'm like the Fidelity something something, so I don't even know what fund it is.
Speaker 1: If Facebook drops below like $12, I might consider buying some.
Speaker 0: Buy?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so to add insult to injury, there's been all these articles talking about how all the ad clicks are fraudulent, and most of the accounts are fake, and people don't actually use it.
Speaker 1: So one more here.
Speaker 1: Apparently, a whole bunch of the high level staff of Facebook quit, possibly because they're rich.
Speaker 0: Oh, good job.
Speaker 0: Way to go.
Speaker 1: They lost four of its highest level managers.
Speaker 0: I salute you for doing what I would do.
Speaker 1: The director of platform partnerships, the platform marketing director.
Speaker 1: What the fuck do any of those jobs fucking do?
Speaker 0: Those are all bullshit jobs that don't do anything.
Speaker 1: I'm the director or vice president of product management.
Speaker 0: I'm the grand vizier of who knows?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: To be fair, it's the descriptive title.
Speaker 1: What do I do?
Speaker 1: I manage the products.
Speaker 1: So they've got a platform marketing director, and a director of platform partnerships, and a mobile platform marketing manager, and a design manager.
Speaker 1: And all those guys, well, girl, guy, guy, guy quit.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: But that's not my news, because that's boring.
Speaker 1: I just want to kind of kick Facebook while they're down, because I think Facebook has not peaked yet.
Speaker 1: But I predict between now and three years from now, the peak of Facebook will happen, and it'll be nothing but decline.
Speaker 0: I always think it's crazy how someone can be growing, but have a decreasing rate of growing.
Speaker 0: And as a result, the market just hammers them.
Speaker 0: It's like, they're fucking growing.
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 0: I mean, not in Facebook's case, but other cases.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe because you don't know those industries that well, and neither do I. We know Facebook.
Speaker 1: We're like, yeah, they're growing.
Speaker 0: But it's like, if I open up a dry cleaner, and in my first year, I get 100 customers.
Speaker 0: In my second year, I got 200 customers.
Speaker 0: In my third year, I got 250 customers.
Speaker 0: That dry cleaner's doing real fucking well, even though it didn't gain a hund- you know, its rate of customer increase was half of what it was in the previous year.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends.
Speaker 1: What am I looking for?
Speaker 1: Were they spending money on trying to increase?
Speaker 1: Is there a saturation of the market?
Speaker 1: What are the same store sales?
Speaker 1: Are other dry cleaners doing similarly well or poorly?
Speaker 1: There's all these other things, and we don't know them, because we're not businessmen like that.
Speaker 0: I just came up with a crazy idea, though, as I often do.
Speaker 0: Imagine, right, Facebook is still kind of big, the way MySpace, when it died, was still largest.
Speaker 1: I think Facebook is bigger than MySpace ever was.
Speaker 0: Way bigger, right, of course.
Speaker 0: But the stock just completely dies, and they're basically fucked, right?
Speaker 0: If the stock goes so low, like pennies or fractions of a penny, we can just buy it all and own Facebook when it's basically dead, the same way that someone bought MySpace when they were dead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and how's that working out for them?
Speaker 0: But think about it.
Speaker 0: Millions of people will still go to Facebook.com, and we can just change it to FrontRecruit.com, right?
Speaker 0: We just get 51% of those worthless shares.
Speaker 1: I just- Facebook's peaking because it doesn't offer what people- you know, people say they want social stuff, like social networking.
Speaker 1: That's like the big thing on the internet.
Speaker 1: But I feel like what Facebook has become is like the stereotype of what people expect from that kind of thing, as opposed to what they actually would do on a regular basis.
Speaker 0: Well, no, the real problem with Facebook is that they don't make fucking money, right?
Speaker 1: And G+ is gonna make money?
Speaker 0: No, but Google makes money by either- every product Google has either, A, displays ads that actually work, right?
Speaker 1: But the ad market's a big bubble, and it's gonna collapse any day now, too.
Speaker 0: Yes, but the Google ads are less bubbly because of their auction mechanic, and B, every other Google product generates data that allows them to improve things.
Speaker 1: What about the claims of manipulation by, for example, the thing we were talking about the other day, where I- They give you free money to spend on Google ads?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they gave me $100 to spend on ads, and it's free.
Speaker 1: You know, if I spend that $100 on ads, it doesn't cost them anything except ad time.
Speaker 0: That just shows you how much smarter Google is than everyone else.
Speaker 1: But it pushes up the prices of the ads that I try to buy, because I have all this free money to leverage.
Speaker 0: It sure does.
Speaker 1: But Facebook, I guess you let me finish.
Speaker 1: my point, is that think about what it really means to be social.
Speaker 1: It's talking to your friends, exchanging information in a useful sense, and Facebook became the thing of friend.
Speaker 1: everybody you know, so now it's very hard to do the things that people actually do in the real world, like invite these four guys to their party but not those other two guys.
Speaker 0: Facebook does that.
Speaker 1: Not as easily.
Speaker 0: It does it real easily.
Speaker 1: Look at how the drama that most people have with Facebook and the way they use it.
Speaker 1: The information leakage is inevitable.
Speaker 0: No one really has this kind of drama.
Speaker 0: You don't know normal people.
Speaker 0: You don't even have a Facebook account.
Speaker 0: You realize that you can be like, hey, event, invite, and you start typing people and it autocompletes all their names and you click okay, and then it invites those people.
Speaker 0: And you can say these people are family, these people are these.
Speaker 0: It's just like circles only with a crappier UI to organize the people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so here's what happens.
Speaker 1: People do that, they make the event, and then they post the photo from the event, and they don't direct it at those same specific people.
Speaker 1: And then Joey Jojo says, hey, how come?
Speaker 1: we had a party and I was invited?
Speaker 1: And the drama happens.
Speaker 0: Well, if you have that situation, you have drama anyway.
Speaker 0: No software is going to help you with that.
Speaker 0: Well, to be fair-- If you're all using Google+, you still would have had the same problem.
Speaker 1: No, because you say all the pictures from the thing, you put in the same set of circles much more easily.
Speaker 0: No, because if you were--on Google+, you have to consciously say post this picture to these circles.
Speaker 0: On Facebook, you could do the same damn thing.
Speaker 1: Or you reply to the original invite as a comment and it's the same people.
Speaker 0: You could do the same thing on Facebook also.
Speaker 0: You just have to be--it's up to you to do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Google makes it easier.
Speaker 0: The only thing Google makes easier is the interface of organizing the people.
Speaker 0: That is the only real difference.
Speaker 1: You seem to overestimate the average abilities of the average user.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying, if they can't do it on Facebook, you can't do it on Google+ either.
Speaker 1: But there have been a bunch of articles talking about the place that Google is starting to surprisingly get market share either parallel to Facebook, or not really replacing Facebook, but being used despite Facebook is the fact that everyone has a Gmail account, so everyone by default has this sort of--.
Speaker 0: That's what they tried to do with their Google Buzz originally.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so but what happens is you're sitting there and you want to like, "Hey, I should talk to these three friends," and you just kind of click on them in Gmail and suddenly you got a video chat going.
Speaker 0: The Hangout has definitely helped Google+ a lot.
Speaker 0: Facebook really should have had something like that a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I don't know why they never have bothered.
Speaker 0: They maybe could have bought Skype instead of letting Microsoft buy it, you know.
Speaker 0: But then again, there is a Microsoft-Facebook connection.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's the one place Facebook is really missing out.
Speaker 1: Well, Facebook also had the business model of be super spammy.
Speaker 1: Look at how much it killed Zynga when they cut back on that spam.
Speaker 0: Well, that wasn't Facebook's business model.
Speaker 0: That was people building on Facebook found value in being on Facebook because being super spammy allowed them to get stuff to be really popular.
Speaker 1: But without that thriving marketplace of spammy people, it cut down on Facebook's value proposition from the business side.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's really easy now on Facebook.
Speaker 0: There are some people that we know that play stupid Facebook games.
Speaker 0: So once a week, I'll see something like-- I'm not going to name any names.
Speaker 0: You know who you are.
Speaker 1: You should name some names because those people should know better.
Speaker 0: Jason Hawk, Laura, Bruce, Jared Sorenson playing Marvel Avengers Alliance.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: Jared, you know better.
Speaker 1: You make games.
Speaker 1: Maybe he's doing market research.
Speaker 0: You know, relatives of mine playing Slingo this or Bejeweled that.
Speaker 1: No Facebook account.
Speaker 0: So anyway, they'll play some stupid game and they'll be noticed like so-and-so is invited you to What's-a-ville, right?
Speaker 0: And it's never Farmville.
Speaker 0: It's always something else at the castle or something.
Speaker 0: And then you just click on this little arrow and you say-- you don't say block the person.
Speaker 0: You say block the fuck out of Marvel Avengers whatnot.
Speaker 0: And then you just never see that shit again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that kills a lot of the value proposition of Facebook.
Speaker 0: Well, if you are Marvel's stupid social game, yeah.
Speaker 1: And those things-- I mean, look, didn't Facebook buy a bunch of Zynga, have a very tied interest?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you got news?
Speaker 0: I don't have a news, but I want to geek back something because I've actually been reading a lot less internet.
Speaker 0: The only internet I read now, I cut out Reddit and Hacker News.
Speaker 0: I'm only reading Twitter, Google News, Forum, Gmail.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much it now.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: So I love how Twitter is on that list.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: I'm reading my tweets.
Speaker 1: I've actually been using Twitter a lot more than I used to lately, which is odd because we originally thought Twitter was stupid and used LaConica instead.
Speaker 0: Well, I didn't think that Twitter was stupid.
Speaker 0: I thought that the federated model-- and I still believe that the federated model is the correct model for pretty much all cloud services.
Speaker 0: It's just that.
Speaker 0: for some reason, if you look at history of internets, the cloud model-- the federated cloud model always wins.
Speaker 0: It just takes for fucking ever.
Speaker 0: How long did it take for Jabber to win?
Speaker 0: A decade?
Speaker 1: It only won because Google used it.
Speaker 0: No, but it's federated between Google and AOL.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know, I know.
Speaker 1: But it only even worked because Google owned it and forced it.
Speaker 0: But the fact that it was federated helped it work.
Speaker 1: Ah, but Twitter itself being federated would only hurt Twitter's monetization model.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: But if another federated Twitter-alike was around, sort of like AIM was around and Google Talk was around, Google Talk was federated and AIM wasn't.
Speaker 0: And then eventually, okay, they both get the federated going on and then, boom, everyone's federated.
Speaker 1: But you need critical mass.
Speaker 0: Of course you need critical mass.
Speaker 0: That's why I say it takes forever, but it seems to eventually win most of the time.
Speaker 1: Of course, LaConica died.
Speaker 0: It turned into StatusNet.
Speaker 0: LaConica's problem was not its federatedness.
Speaker 0: Its problem was the actual software.
Speaker 0: They had a goal of making it easy to install, like WordPress.
Speaker 0: And if they actually had achieved that goal, it would have actually probably, I think, been extremely successful.
Speaker 0: Their problem was is that setting that shit up, it was so broken and hacky and crashy and it was awful.
Speaker 0: It probably still is a piece of shit.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: We ran an official FRC LaConica server for a while.
Speaker 1: We did.
Speaker 0: If someone wrote a federated microblogging service or whatever you want to call it, I would definitely run it if it didn't suck like LaConica, Identica does.
Speaker 0: Well, now it's StatusNet.
Speaker 0: Sure, whatever.
Speaker 0: I could even write one if I wanted to.
Speaker 0: Anyway, right, so I started using, man, we're going all the way, huge tangent there.
Speaker 0: I started using the Amazon Cloud Music Play thingy, just like you're using the Google one, right?
Speaker 1: I've used the Amazon one, too.
Speaker 0: Oh, have you?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So the Amazon one came out with this thing.
Speaker 0: You pay, I love annual pricing, 25 bucks a year gets you a ridiculous amount of storage space and 250,000 songs, right?
Speaker 1: Now that's double what I pay for Flickr.
Speaker 0: I only have like 7,000 songs, so this is awesome.
Speaker 0: I don't know how many songs I have.
Speaker 0: That storage space actually only counts for the Amazon Cloud Drive.
Speaker 0: So if you upload, say, a song, a legitimate song that's like 10 megabytes, that just counts as a song, even if you upload it, right?
Speaker 0: We're not talking about, you know, and it will match songs, so if it sees a song you have and it matches a song in the Amazon MP3 library, they just give you a 256 kilobit version of that song, unless yours is better, and then you don't actually upload.
Speaker 1: I was about to say, unless yours is better is very important.
Speaker 0: Right, and you don't have to actually upload yours, they just give you one, but that only counts as a song, even if you're uploading.
Speaker 0: It only counts as one song, it counts as zero bits in the storage space.
Speaker 1: So what if I upload a 10 million hour Stag in a Graphic WAV file?
Speaker 0: They don't actually allow uploading in WAV files.
Speaker 1: Alright, MP3.
Speaker 0: They allow that.
Speaker 1: Alright, so I upload a 100 terabyte MP3 file.
Speaker 0: It has to actually be a song.
Speaker 1: It's a song.
Speaker 0: The importer thing sort of detects whether it's a song.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what, so it has an MP3 header?
Speaker 0: It'll probably let it through, but it was actually pretty intelligent in terms of saying, "Oh shit, that's a podcast, that's a song, that's a podcast, that's a
Speaker 0: song.".
Speaker 0: It knew.
Speaker 1: Oh, so it doesn't let you upload podcasts?
Speaker 0: I mean, it did accidentally upload a bunch of podcasts, because it's not that smart, but another time it actually said, "Oh, those are
Speaker 0: podcasts.".
Speaker 0: I think the difference was, is when I uploaded just a folder of MP3s by saying browse, check this folder out, it uploaded podcasts.
Speaker 0: But when I said, "Hey, look through my iTunes library and upload that shit," then it recognized what-.
Speaker 1: Ah, that makes sense.
Speaker 0: So I'm using this thing, and it's got a lot of good stuff to it, right?
Speaker 0: So the good stuff is, number one, there's three components.
Speaker 0: There's the downloader, the uploader, the importer, and the player.
Speaker 0: So the downloader has always been amazing.
Speaker 0: You couldn't really improve the downloader.
Speaker 0: It's amazing.
Speaker 0: It's the same one that you use if you buy music on Amazon, right, legitimately.
Speaker 0: It opens up this little program, downloads the MP3s from Amazon really quickly, and then automatically inserts them into your iTunes or Windows Media Player, or whatever it is that you use, with all the exact metadata, and it's awesome.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, with this, you could upload things into your cloud player, and then download them with the same downloader.
Speaker 0: So you can go to another computer, get the Amazon downloader, and download your own stuff that you just uploaded.
Speaker 1: See, that's the thing I can't do, because I use Spotify a lot right now, and I pay for the premium Spotify.
Speaker 0: I stopped paying for Spotify, but I still use the free Spotify for stuff that's on Spotify.
Speaker 1: I pay for it because I use the playlist generation for road trips and things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the cloud player is not the best.
Speaker 0: It does a very good job of, here's all your music.
Speaker 0: You can access it on your phone or your computer, and stream it just perfectly, or download it, or whatever.
Speaker 0: And in that respect, it is great.
Speaker 0: And you can search your music, and you can organize playlists, and in that respect, it's great.
Speaker 0: The problem is, it doesn't really let you edit metadata or organize, other than making playlists.
Speaker 0: So you basically have this gigantic list of all the songs.
Speaker 1: Not even by album.
Speaker 0: You can sort by album, kinda.
Speaker 0: You gotta search, really, is your only resort, mostly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's where Spotify- I mean, you can click the album button, and you'll get this screen full of a million squares with album covers, most of which are not actually album covers, just like Amazon logos.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, honestly, Google Play, that kind of whole thing, I only use Google Listen for podcasts.
Speaker 0: Google Listen's dying, I heard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was being pulled into- They're closing it out.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, and the third part is the importer, which is how you take music you have and put it into the thing, right?
Speaker 0: So, it's good and bad.
Speaker 0: It's good in that you can point it at your music, and it uploads it relatively quickly.
Speaker 0: It's bad because it's kinda glitchy and buggy.
Speaker 0: Like, I told it to upload a folder of stuff, and, like, for example, it's trying to upload the Matt Cross Complete soundtrack, right?
Speaker 0: Only three of those songs have English titles, the rest have Unicode Japanese titles, and it uploaded just those three songs, it ignored the rest.
Speaker 1: Ugh.
Speaker 0: And I was like,
Speaker 0: "What?".
Speaker 0: And I emailed them, and I guess they're working on it, right?
Speaker 0: Another time, like, I uploaded one folder, and it slowly but assuredly uploaded the whole folder, and then I uploaded this other folder, and it sort of got in an infinite loop of, you know, checking up, checking the files without ever actually uploading anything, and it did that overnight.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, "Whoa, okay,
Speaker 0: whatever.".
Speaker 0: But then, that was just telling it, you know, to browse for a folder.
Speaker 0: I started a thing where I said, "Look at my iTunes,".
Speaker 0: because what it is is I just dragged all my music into iTunes, and then I said, "Amazon importer, look at iTunes and upload everything you
Speaker 0: see.".
Speaker 0: And that seemed to work relatively well, and was actually seeing more of the non-English music.
Speaker 0: So I recommend using that mode.
Speaker 0: But yeah, as for how it compares to the Google or the iTunes match, or any of those things, I'm not too sure, because I haven't really used those that much.
Speaker 0: But the price is right, you know, 25 bucks a year, that's not too bad, especially since it's, you know, in terms of the number of songs, 250,000 songs, and then you get like 50 gigs, like a lot of gigs of just storage space.
Speaker 0: that is not, the songs don't count against that, that's pretty great.
Speaker 0: So I recommend trying out the free versions of all three, the Apple One, iCloud, Google Music, and Amazon Music, to figure out which one you like the most, and then pick one.
Speaker 1: And of them, honestly, I still just use Spotify, because the metadata is super good in Spotify, and that is the main thing.
Speaker 1: I use that music service for now, because I don't listen to music idly, like I never listen to music in the background, I listen to music as an activity in and of itself.
Speaker 1: Or driving, I will listen to it in the background, that's the only time, and I don't drive that often anymore.
Speaker 1: Like in the subway, I'm not going to listen to music, I'll listen to words, or read, or wear earplugs or something, because if I'm not giving it my whole attention, it feels like it's a waste.
Speaker 1: But that's me.
Speaker 0: I'm with you, I mostly listen to music with a mostly full attention.
Speaker 0: Like, I might have music on while doing dishes, and you might say, "Oh, that's background music,".
Speaker 0: but actually, the dishes are the secondary activity, not the music.
Speaker 0: So yeah.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day!
Speaker 1: So, Homestuck.
Speaker 0: Oh boy, woah woah, are you sure you want to talk about this on Monday?
Speaker 0: So, Homestuck is the thing- You sure you want to talk about this at all?
Speaker 1: On the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You could say that.
Speaker 1: It is either drivel, or it is the first thing that Scott and I are officially too old to understand, the kids who are into Homestuck are to us what we were to the people older than us.
Speaker 0: You forgot possibility number three.
Speaker 1: That the person who made it is crazy?
Speaker 0: No, all of the above.
Speaker 1: I don't like Homestuck.
Speaker 1: I tried to read it, I read thousands of these panels, and it actually would have been okay were it not for the fact that for almost all these panels, there's all this text.
Speaker 1: And the text reads like that crazy guy who lectured at Open Everything many years ago.
Speaker 0: The only thing that I don't like about it- What the fuck was that guy's name?
Speaker 0: Is that it's incomprehensible.
Speaker 0: You look at it, it's just a whole pile of gobbledygook, and it would take so much, it hurts literally my eyes and brain to try to look at it and figure it out, like neon colored text in a white background, and it's not even English, it's like, "Hargoblarga doobadoo," and I'm like, I can't even bother to, I can't go through with it.
Speaker 1: The strips themselves are fairly artistic, and that's an only story as far as I can tell, but those words read like something that came out of the mind of a disturbed, it's like lost without the cognitive levels that you get from one.
Speaker 0: I didn't interview the Homestuck guy.
Speaker 1: See, I start to ramble and just kind of go off into nowhere.
Speaker 0: All right, so anyway, why is this your thing of the day?
Speaker 1: So someone made a video that is just the first three years worth of Homestuck panels, none of these words that go off into gibberish no man's land, in a movie.
Speaker 1: And it's actually, in my opinion, pretty good in and of itself because it's interesting, and it gives you these sort of vignettes, or you'll see disturbing images or things or love stories, but you can't quite interpret them, so it gives the same experience as someone like me trying to read Homestuck without having to read that bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can sort of now tell, I watched this video, and I obviously can't tell you the plot of Homestuck, but I could sort of figure out, like, okay, now that it's going by really quickly, and I just see pictures, obviously I don't know any details, but I can see that these different kids, mostly this kid, but also other kids, and they're sort of communicating with each other over some internets, and some of them are in dark places, some of them are in light places, and some of them are doing things, and weird computer game-like things are happening to all of them, and at some point the candy corn horn trolls appear that I see cosplaying at all the conventions, and there's sort of battles occurring, so there's some sort of space battle with these trolls, and these kids are involved who only talk to each other on the internet, and at least don't meet up.
Speaker 0: within this video, at least not any panel I could see, and that's sort of what's going on.
Speaker 1: This gives you these sort of, like, emotional flashes of what Homestuck could really be about, and it seems cool.
Speaker 1: The thing is, this reminds me of when I saw a music video to the Utena movie many years ago, or to a Shematic Princess to anime many years ago.
Speaker 0: Shematic Princess, whoa, I remember that video!
Speaker 0: Let's do a Wednesday in Shematic Princess, go get the disc.
Speaker 1: I watched it a few years ago.
Speaker 0: I've never watched it.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: It's actually not that bad.
Speaker 0: Everyone had it lying on the floor, and I was like, nope.
Speaker 1: Shematic Princess and the Utena movie, I watched these music videos, and I was like, if these music videos are any indication of what these movies are like, or OAV in the case of Shematic Princess, this is going to be the best thing ever, and then I watched the things the music videos were based on,
Speaker 0: not
Speaker 1: Monika.
Speaker 1: Should have just watched the music video.
Speaker 0: Not Monika levels.
Speaker 1: So, this does that to Homestuck.
Speaker 1: The reason I make it the thing of the day is that everyone should watch it, because you will know enough about Homestuck to not need to know more.
Speaker 0: It's only five minutes of your life, right?
Speaker 0: It's not like, you know, the amount of time it takes is a worthwhile investment for this thing that is so ridiculously popular.
Speaker 1: Now, you say it's so ridiculously popular, and there is a perception.
Speaker 1: I was talking to someone like six or seven months ago, and they said something to the effect of, you go on and on about how popular My Little Pony is, or Venture Brothers is, or all these things.
Speaker 1: Homestuck is just as popular.
Speaker 1: Nobody talks about that.
Speaker 1: So, I did a little bit of internet forensics, because this video, as great as it is, and it was uploaded in May, doesn't even have 10,000 views.
Speaker 0: Well, why would this video have 10,000 views?
Speaker 0: Homestuck people are on Tumblr.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Tumblr, it's the same people in a circle, jerk.
Speaker 1: I went around, and there are fan works related to Homestuck, and fan stuff related to Homestuck.
Speaker 0: Tons of it.
Speaker 1: But I did things where I'd Google for a certain Homestuck something mashup, and then Pony something mashup, Venture Brothers something mashup, and I feel like Homestuck, while popular, is not nearly as popular as it is easy to think it is if you are someone who uses Tumblr and goes to conventions.
Speaker 0: I think it's just the traffic to the Homestuck site is off the charts, right?
Speaker 1: What numbers do you have?
Speaker 1: We don't have the third-party analytic measures.
Speaker 0: I've read articles about how big the traffic is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but compare it to Penny Arcade.
Speaker 0: I don't know how it is compared to Penny Arcade.
Speaker 1: Or, I don't know, Johnny Wander even.
Speaker 0: I think it's bigger than that.
Speaker 0: But it's basically, you just have this tremendous number of people just mostly hammering this site, and then, you know, it doesn't, it has a lot of, it's very sort of like this insular thing.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, everyone talks about like Harry Potter fan fiction or something like that, right?
Speaker 0: And that's pretty big, there's a lot of Harry Potter fan fictions out there.
Speaker 0: But no one of them is like ridiculously trafficked, or, and the community that is writing and reading these is not a broad spreading community that's going to bust out, right?
Speaker 0: Not like the pony community knows how to bring the ponies into everyday things, you know, to spread to the non-pony people, to spread over the whole internet, to branch out.
Speaker 0: So that, and no matter where you are on the internet, you'll fall into pony at some point.
Speaker 0: Whereas, you can go all over the internet in normal places, you know, like Reddits and whatnot, and never fall into Homestuck.
Speaker 0: But you can't avoid, say, pony, because, you know, the way in which it is used.
Speaker 0: Somebody should research this, Alex Levitt.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, we did that panel where we kind of talked about this.
Speaker 1: I want to expand that panel and add Homestuck to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway, this is my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I have a thing of the day too.
Speaker 1: This thing is pretty good, and you should watch it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay, it's okay.
Speaker 0: So, you know Reggie Watts, fuck shit stack.
Speaker 0: The awesome guy.
Speaker 0: That's a pretty good song.
Speaker 0: So this is actually an old video, but I've never seen it, and whatever.
Speaker 0: It's actually from November 2011, so nah, it's almost a year old.
Speaker 0: He was the performer, the final performer, on the Pop Tech 2011 stage, right?
Speaker 0: So in this performance, which is 30 minutes long, but well worth watching for the entire 30 minutes, right?
Speaker 0: He does a lot of awesome music, and he uses like a, you know, a sampling machine and a microphone to like mix his own beatboxing together, right?
Speaker 0: But mostly, sort of what he's doing is, he's basically making fun of all those typical inspiring tech conference speeches.
Speaker 0: And it's just the way he is like.
Speaker 0: lambasting and satiring them is so great, because whatever.
Speaker 1: I've usually heard that word pronounced lambast.
Speaker 0: Lambast, okay, whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I like bass because it's more like a turkey.
Speaker 1: Well, you're lambasting.
Speaker 0: Right, exactly.
Speaker 0: It sounds, you know, even if it's wrong, which it could be, because I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like, you know, if you're, you know, basting sounds more like an attack.
Speaker 0: You know, you're squirting meat juice on them.
Speaker 0: Anyway, whereas basting, it's like, okay, you've basted me.
Speaker 0: What is, is it like bastarding?
Speaker 0: It's like, it doesn't sound like the right verb.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but yeah, if you have seen like those sort of stereotypical, like when some like web designer gives an inspiring speech at the tech conference, you know, with all those buzzwords and, you know, vision and, you know, that kind of, you know, highfalutin kind of, you know, reach for the stars kind of bullshit.
Speaker 0: To see someone tear that apart the way that I always, I always try to tear it apart in quite a literal direct way.
Speaker 0: Like, yeah, that's just a bunch of bullshit.
Speaker 0: But to see someone tear it apart in this way is, is poetic.
Speaker 0: And the music is awesome too.
Speaker 0: So do not miss.
Speaker 1: The music in that Homestuck thing is actually pretty good.
Speaker 1: I wonder how much.
Speaker 0: Is it music from Homestuck or is it just a music that someone put on it?
Speaker 1: It's a music someone put on it.
Speaker 1: But that song won.
Speaker 0: Does Homestuck have music?
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm sure.
Speaker 1: As far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: These flash parts, they could easily.
Speaker 1: I never got to music in all, as far as I read.
Speaker 0: Because they could put music in there.
Speaker 0: Like you get to a flash movie, you push play and music happens.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I never got to music in anything.
Speaker 1: I read.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: But that song reeks of the song someone uses to make a super serial anime music video.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment book club book, the man who was Thursday, a book that is over a hundred years old.
Speaker 0: So it's free legally.
Speaker 0: It's about police and anarchists.
Speaker 1: And I bought the Kindle version and seeing what other people have highlighted in this book.
Speaker 0: Oh, you actually don't turn that shit off.
Speaker 1: I let it be there.
Speaker 0: I turn that shit off.
Speaker 1: It's interesting to see what people highlighted.
Speaker 0: Oh, you have the legal Kindle version.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Oh, see, I never, I never pay.
Speaker 1: It was like a dollar ninety nine.
Speaker 0: I actually paid for the paper, uh, penguin books edition because number one, the penguin classics always have fancy shit in them.
Speaker 0: But two, the book cover was just so good.
Speaker 0: I wanted to reward whoever the cover artist with whatever pennies and royalties they get.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I recommend even you should read it for free probably because most people don't have five bucks to just waste on a free book.
Speaker 0: You could spend that on another book like next book club book, but go to Amazon and look at the Oxford, you know, uh, not Oxford, penguin classics edition of The Man Who Was Thursday.
Speaker 0: And look at that cover.
Speaker 0: That is the cover.
Speaker 1: The book's OK, but I got to say, it reminds me of literally this is something a middle school teacher makes you read and write an essay on.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: I haven't.
Speaker 0: I've only read two chapters.
Speaker 1: Oh, you haven't even gotten to anything yet.
Speaker 0: I stopped and started reading comics because the comics are piling quite high.
Speaker 0: They're like maybe up to my head.
Speaker 0: It was Thursday.
Speaker 1: It takes like a day to read.
Speaker 0: Which day am I going to choose for reading?
Speaker 0: Thursday on Thursday?
Speaker 0: I'm going to be on the Atomic Tribute War 9000 podcast.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, Friday, Phil and Cher coming over, which is going to be aired some weeks later than that, maybe during the PAX week.
Speaker 0: So that'll give you something to listen to.
Speaker 0: I don't know how long it takes between recording and playing.
Speaker 0: That's up to someone else.
Speaker 1: I was on that a while ago and it was super fun.
Speaker 0: I think it's been my third time on it.
Speaker 0: I remember.
Speaker 1: I've only been on it once.
Speaker 1: I've been on more Friday night party lines because you really ignored that.
Speaker 1: But I kept doing it occasionally.
Speaker 0: Um, what are the meta moments do we have?
Speaker 1: We're going to be a PAX dev, academia versus reality, psychology, game theory and games.
Speaker 1: We're going to be at PAX Prime, short subjects in gaming and the Geek Nights board game workshop.
Speaker 0: Nice.
Speaker 0: What are we doing?
Speaker 0: Board game workshop.
Speaker 1: We are going to.
Speaker 1: So dive into tabletop gaming.
Speaker 1: Remin Scott, host of Geek Nights are here to teach you to play.
Speaker 1: And more importantly, to win.
Speaker 1: Agricola is a super popular resource management game with little wooden animals and surprising strategic depth.
Speaker 1: Carcassonne is a classic tile laying area control game that teaches you the fundamentals of optimal play and point denial.
Speaker 1: We're here to teach you both first the rules, then the strategy and a hands on workshop with no experience necessary.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Saturday, September 1st, 8 p.m.
Speaker 0: Room 302.
Speaker 1: I think that's in the Red Lion.
Speaker 0: You should subscribe to the newsletter because I'm about to send another one out.
Speaker 0: I remember the milk just said, hey, send the newsletter.
Speaker 1: There's some new videos.
Speaker 0: And also, if you want Geek Nights to be, if you want to follow us somewhere on the Internet, like we're not on Tumblr right now.
Speaker 0: If you want to like, you know, if that's the thing that you want, you know, if you want there to be like a Geek Nights Reddit or something, you know, a subreddit that is the Geek Nights subreddit.
Speaker 0: If you want these things, tell me and I will make them.
Speaker 0: If there's some new place on the Internet that just appeared that, you know, is like the new place and they have, you know, ways for us to post things like, you know, to make a Geek Nights page or account or whatever that you can follow.
Speaker 0: And you want us to be there because you like using that thing.
Speaker 0: Tell us about the thing and we will go there.
Speaker 0: But for now, we are on Facebook, Google Plus, Twitter, our website, RSS feed, iTunes and email newsletter.
Speaker 1: And if you want us to come to a convention because you do do a lot of conventions, there's videos of our stuff at conventions.
Speaker 1: Don't ask us to go to a convention if you're just someone who also goes to the convention.
Speaker 1: That doesn't help us.
Speaker 1: We go to.
Speaker 1: we go to so many conventions that we can't just add another one to our schedule willy nilly.
Speaker 1: So if you would like us to appear at a convention, ask the convention to invite us.
Speaker 0: That is correct.
Speaker 1: Because if they talk to us, then we can actually sort out the details like hotel or badges.
Speaker 0: when you compensate me for my unpaid vacation day.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I mean, if someone pays for everything, even the unpaid vacation day, I will go to any convention.
Speaker 0: I'll go to freaking Alaska, Saskatoon.
Speaker 1: There are conventions I would not bother with.
Speaker 1: I don't know, because I can't even think of them because they're so sad.
Speaker 1: I remember a time ago where there were more guests than attendees.
Speaker 0: But even if it is so sad, going to it generates the awesome stories, especially if it's far away.
Speaker 0: It depends.
Speaker 0: It's a free adventure.
Speaker 0: I don't give a shit if no one's there.
Speaker 0: That would actually be kind of awesome.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So you want to you want to fly to out of somewhere in Idaho, do a convention for one person?
Speaker 0: We would have after we did the panel for that one person and we left because we'd only be there for the one panel.
Speaker 0: We'd have all this free paid for time there in Idaho.
Speaker 0: The potatoes would be so unbelievable.
Speaker 1: You know, I travel a lot for work and I got to say it gets to a point when you're kind of sick of airports.
Speaker 0: I'm sick of airports now.
Speaker 0: What are you talking about?
Speaker 1: Granted, without the TSA, it's so much nicer everywhere else.
Speaker 1: But anyway, we digress.
Speaker 0: Let's actually do a main bit here.
Speaker 1: So I go to Starbucks a lot and not, you know, I had a Starbucks card because it actually just gets you free coffee.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So there's no reason not to have it.
Speaker 0: I have a reason not to have it.
Speaker 1: You don't go to Starbucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got it.
Speaker 0: I don't think they give you free apple fritters if I buy enough apple fritters.
Speaker 1: No, they give you one free drink of your choice.
Speaker 1: Every 15 times.
Speaker 0: If they had the apple fritter plan, I would sign up.
Speaker 0: But actually, I don't even want that.
Speaker 0: What I want is the bacon, egg and cheese plan at Toasty's.
Speaker 0: That's what I want.
Speaker 1: There's nowhere good to get a bagel near my office.
Speaker 0: Right under me is Toasty's.
Speaker 0: They got a big line and the guy even just he remembers everybody.
Speaker 0: So I just walk in.
Speaker 0: He's like, you want bacon, egg and cheese and everything bagel?
Speaker 0: I don't even say anything.
Speaker 0: He just makes it.
Speaker 0: And he's like, you know, it's like the one guy, he knows everyone's orders and everyone else makes the stuff.
Speaker 1: So I generally I don't like carrying cash because as soon as you know, I've got a 20 as soon as I buy anything, then it's a bunch of wads that get shoved in my pocket.
Speaker 0: You mean my ones that I leave on my desk at home?
Speaker 1: And so right now on my desk is easily like $40 in singles.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what I tell you is the five.
Speaker 0: What I do is I, you know, I keep the big bills in the wallet and then all the other bills just throw my bag.
Speaker 0: And then when I get home, I just, you know, put the change in the in the change.
Speaker 0: And I put the ones in the one pile.
Speaker 1: My change thing is full.
Speaker 1: There's easily like $500 and change in that thing.
Speaker 0: You gotta cash that shit in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's heavy and I got to dump it somewhere.
Speaker 1: So I hate carrying cash and I basically never use cash.
Speaker 1: In fact, I avoid any establishment that I can't pay with a credit card at.
Speaker 1: Like I almost never use cash.
Speaker 1: And when I do use cash, it's always this kind of like filthy experience.
Speaker 1: That's been my whole life.
Speaker 0: I actually use cash just to buy food, mostly like, you know, not the grocery store, but like bacon, egg and cheese or, you know, lunch or something like that.
Speaker 0: And then I know that since 99 percent of what I buy with cash is food, I basically look at how much money I took out of the ATM and how much money is still in the wallet.
Speaker 0: And I know how much I spent on food for when I do accounting.
Speaker 1: I get the same thing because my credit card tells me where I bought everything from and conveniently breaks it into categories like food.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a credit card does that as well.
Speaker 0: But I mean, just, you know, food is the only thing I spend cash on.
Speaker 1: I also don't get three percent cash back on cash.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: I hate using cash.
Speaker 1: And this is a problem that was solved technologically 20 years ago.
Speaker 1: And yet somehow we've still got these grubby ass one dollar bills.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, I mean, we can replace them with coins or better bills.
Speaker 0: That's one.
Speaker 0: Forget about that for now.
Speaker 0: That's not part of the show.
Speaker 0: But the other thing is that cash does have features that other things do not have.
Speaker 0: Anonymous.
Speaker 1: Untraceable.
Speaker 1: Non-transactional.
Speaker 1: Bearer related.
Speaker 1: It's like a bearer bond without cash.
Speaker 1: You realize Die Hard couldn't have happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Cash or at least bearer bonds.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: They don't make bearer bonds anymore.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: But another feature of cash is just that, you know, anyone can just grab it and use it without having to go through any sort of bureaucracy or other.
Speaker 0: non.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: If you're like a poor person or a person who was just born or a person who, you know, who is really old and doesn't.
Speaker 0: Anyone can just get cash and immediately use it.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, if I give you like a CD rom, for example, it's useless unless you already have a computer with a CD and the whole thing set up with all the right software.
Speaker 0: It's like this prerequisite.
Speaker 0: There is no prerequisite for cash.
Speaker 0: The dollar bill is the thing.
Speaker 0: It works all on its own.
Speaker 0: You don't need anything else to make it go.
Speaker 0: It just goes.
Speaker 1: But I personally have no need for most of those features most of the time.
Speaker 0: I agree.
Speaker 1: So the thing, the situation is in a lot of the rest of the world, we have these awesome things like just using your phone as your wallet, not even needing to carry cards, just dupe.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, food comes out of the vending machine or dupe and you paid for whatever.
Speaker 1: And somehow we've never gotten that in the US, but I guess I shouldn't say somehow.
Speaker 0: Do we want to discuss the reasons?
Speaker 1: Well, let's talk about why don't we have all these cool things that the rest of the world has in the US in regards to paying for things, because I have one more anecdote.
Speaker 1: The reason I'm pissed off about this is that I was just in Sao Paulo, Brazil.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: When you're sitting in a restaurant, every restaurant, the crappest restaurant you can think of on the table, the little button, if you hit it, your waiter comes immediately.
Speaker 1: Oh, and some restaurants have different buttons.
Speaker 1: One button says as a picture, clear the table.
Speaker 1: Another button is bring me the check.
Speaker 1: Another one is I want to order something else.
Speaker 0: If we make a restaurant, we'll put that shit in there.
Speaker 1: But that's that's a separate thing.
Speaker 1: That's a dark age of restaurants.
Speaker 1: The separate we the the.
Speaker 1: the cool feature was that when it's time to pay, they bring a little credit card machine over and they assume you're splitting the bill and ways, then being the number of people sitting at your table.
Speaker 1: And they already know who ordered what.
Speaker 1: So literally, you just toss your credit cards to the person.
Speaker 1: They swipe them all one by one and you all sign your receipts and you walk out.
Speaker 1: Done.
Speaker 1: To this day, no matter where I go, paying for the bill at a restaurant is a gigantic pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: No restaurant will split the bill.
Speaker 1: And in fact, they get pissed off if you ask.
Speaker 0: Well, not all of them.
Speaker 0: Most of them.
Speaker 0: But many, you know, it's like they can do it, but it's just easier for them not to.
Speaker 0: And the reason it's easier for them not to is because their point of sale systems are shit, right?
Speaker 0: Because you're expert at point of sale systems.
Speaker 0: You're not working at it.
Speaker 1: So you want to know why Brazil has these awesome point of sale systems?
Speaker 1: This is how it was explained to me by a native.
Speaker 1: He said that they bring the thing to the table because Brazil is a pretty violent crime ridden country, by and large.
Speaker 1: And credit card cloning was so endemic that everyone refused to let the credit card out of their sight.
Speaker 1: So they had to do the transaction at the table.
Speaker 1: But as soon as you had to make that ubiquitous, the transaction thing being at the table, then suddenly there's all these other things you can do because you can guarantee you'll have the thing at the table.
Speaker 1: So I guess we just need there to be a huge crime wave of stolen credit cards.
Speaker 0: I mean, we have this technology in the U.S.
Speaker 0: If you go to the Apple Store or Chipotle, it's like you can check out with just the people walking around with handheld point of sale credit card swipey things.
Speaker 0: And they want you to use those.
Speaker 0: They don't want you to wait in the line.
Speaker 1: I'm just sick of the fact that if I have 12 friends, we go to a restaurant, we can't just split the bill and I just pay for what I ate.
Speaker 0: I don't know why the credit card thing is just built into the table.
Speaker 1: So the credit card, all these transactions still are reliant upon the credit card, which means that there's a third party taking a cut somewhere along the way.
Speaker 1: Now, they don't take the cut from me, so I don't particularly care.
Speaker 0: And they also give me a bunch of benefits.
Speaker 0: So that cut is actually partially going to me.
Speaker 0: I'm getting a piece of the cut, but why wouldn't I want that?
Speaker 1: They do take the cut from the other side and also restaurant's problem.
Speaker 1: They cut out all those other features of cash, like the deniability and the untraceability.
Speaker 1: And that's why cabbies always lie to me and say, oh, credit card machine is broken.
Speaker 1: You pay cash.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: You let me pay credit card or I call through on one.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And the thing is, that's not just a problem in the U.S.
Speaker 1: In Turkey, in Germany.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: In Germany, every cab I took, the guy would be like, I do not speak English.
Speaker 1: I'm like, whatever, credit card.
Speaker 1: He's like, no card.
Speaker 1: And I just point as his credit card machine.
Speaker 1: And he's like, no work, no work.
Speaker 1: And one time I said, and I quote, you speak English.
Speaker 1: I know you speak it.
Speaker 1: I'm not an idiot.
Speaker 1: I know you're lying to me.
Speaker 1: I'm from New York.
Speaker 1: Scan my fucking credit card or I'm calling the police.
Speaker 0: And he scanned my credit card and I was on my way.
Speaker 1: A Turkish guy, when he tried to pull it out of me, I was like, look, I know exactly the scam you're doing.
Speaker 1: I'm from New York.
Speaker 1: Don't even try this shit on me.
Speaker 1: I'm going to call the police right now.
Speaker 1: And he was like, you got me here.
Speaker 1: No tip.
Speaker 1: Don't worry about it.
Speaker 1: You win.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we should.
Speaker 0: we should go with like, you know, like.
Speaker 0: I wonder, what do you wear to make someone look at you and say, yeah, New York.
Speaker 1: A middle finger raised at all times.
Speaker 0: I already wear that.
Speaker 1: A constant scowl.
Speaker 1: Particularly scowling at anyone who's slower than you or faster than you.
Speaker 0: I already got that down.
Speaker 1: But there's the problem.
Speaker 1: Me as a consumer, I have the selfish interest in using a card for everything, because like I said, cash is disgusting.
Speaker 1: But everyone else gets fucked by that because the credit card takes its share from everybody but me.
Speaker 0: I do feel the slightest bit bad about the merchants fee, because as much as I like receiving these benefits, you know, like Amazon points, I would rather have money go if I could choose how money was distributed.
Speaker 0: I would distribute the money to this nice restaurant that gives me delicious food and not to Visa, which is some nameless company that really isn't necessary.
Speaker 1: But I don't have to deal with.
Speaker 1: I don't want to have to deal with cash.
Speaker 0: I do not.
Speaker 1: So there's there's been this movement of all these attempts to make other systems to do this.
Speaker 0: Bitcoin lol.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, Bitcoin actually is being used a lot for mostly illicit bullshit and not for anything legitimate.
Speaker 1: But like Diwala and like Starbucks.
Speaker 0: Well Diwala is not different.
Speaker 0: But yeah, talk about the Starbucks thing.
Speaker 1: So the Starbucks thing, basically I put money into a Starbucks thing, but I do it with the credit card.
Speaker 0: So you're paying the merchant fee once, though.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And I put like a hundred bucks in this Starbucks card, but I don't even need the physical card because there's an app on my phone that displays the the code that I can use to pay so I can pay for Starbucks stuff.
Speaker 0: The next version of iOS is actually going to have a single app that any app that basically does that, which is the display a card app.
Speaker 0: All those display a card apps are going to be combined into one app.
Speaker 0: That is the display a card app.
Speaker 0: That is the official Apple one.
Speaker 0: So you won't have to like go make your own app.
Speaker 1: Well, the Starbucks one does one thing that it shows the status, like if you're a different status.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, that's that's all included.
Speaker 0: They're making one app that does all of those.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So until there's a company doesn't want to use.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, but it's the same way that the Apple will reject them because Apple's Apple, right?
Speaker 0: The same way they already have like the magazine app.
Speaker 0: So that's built into iOS.
Speaker 0: So if you want to make an app that's a magazine, you don't you make them a magazine thing instead anyway.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But the way it works is I just flash my card and no receipt, no nothing.
Speaker 1: Now, it saves them the merchant fees.
Speaker 0: Well, they still to pay a merchant fee when you put the money in the card.
Speaker 0: So it's.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah, as opposed to a merchant's fee on everybody It's a five dollar card.
Speaker 0: But isn't the merchant fee a percentage of the money you give them?
Speaker 0: so it ends up being the same?
Speaker 1: No, it actually depends.
Speaker 1: There are different merchant agreements, partly for different credit cards like Visa versus Amex.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: Amex is double.
Speaker 0: If you use an Amex, you're hurting the person you're buying from double.
Speaker 0: That's why Amex is accepted in so few or much fewer places than everywhere else.
Speaker 0: Because if you have like, you know, if you go into a place that, you know, is you're going to buy like something for a dollar and use an Amex, it's not even worth it for them to sell it to you.
Speaker 1: That happened to me once.
Speaker 1: I didn't have any cash.
Speaker 1: I wanted to buy one D20 a millennium.
Speaker 1: And back then, they couldn't turn me down because of the rules about credit cards.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the rules have changed, son of a bitch.
Speaker 1: So basically she was like, you know what, just take it.
Speaker 0: Free D20.
Speaker 1: Now, theoretically, I just have said I would like to buy every single die.
Speaker 1: you have one by one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they would have said, all right, you're paying for the rest of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could have come in each day or walk by one, walk out, walk back in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if you buy one, walk out, walk back in.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So if it's the emergency is four percent.
Speaker 0: Well, you're paying four percent of a D20 and then you're paying four percent.
Speaker 1: No, but it's not always a percent.
Speaker 1: It's all there.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you can have a set fee.
Speaker 0: There's all different ways to do it.
Speaker 0: That's rough.
Speaker 1: So Starbucks is probably better off having me put 50 or 100 bucks there every now and then.
Speaker 1: Then every four or 75 is a single.
Speaker 0: They're also better off because now that money is sitting with them.
Speaker 0: I gave the money.
Speaker 0: You're giving Starbucks a loan.
Speaker 1: Which is not that lucrative in the modern era when interest rates are basically zero.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: But Starbucks isn't using that money.
Speaker 0: See, if you have the money, you would be using it to try to get interest and it would not be very good for you.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 1: Starbucks is using... Mine's in a money market account or equities.
Speaker 0: But Starbucks is using that money in the coffee bean commodities market.
Speaker 0: They're not using that loan money to go try to get interest from a savings account.
Speaker 0: So Starbucks, when they get a loan from you, they're better off than you are having a loan from them.
Speaker 0: Because they can actually do something with that money.
Speaker 1: But we've never had the pay for stuff with cell phones that was ubiquitous in the U.S.
Speaker 1: Even though in Asia it's actually pretty common.
Speaker 1: And I feel like it's the way to go.
Speaker 1: I don't even want to carry my stupid wallet.
Speaker 0: Oh, yep, yep.
Speaker 0: So here's the reasons why it has not taken off in the U.S Number one, not everyone has a smartphone.
Speaker 0: Even though a lot of people do, not everyone, right?
Speaker 0: So if you put this thing on vending machines and stores and all these places, right?
Speaker 0: Why would a store go through the trouble of installing this thing that only a fraction of people will use, can use, and only a fraction of those people will use, right?
Speaker 0: You get this chicken and egg situation.
Speaker 0: Even people who have smartphones won't be able to figure it out or bother.
Speaker 0: They've had credit cards that you don't have to swipe, that you just sort of have RFID.
Speaker 0: People don't even use those.
Speaker 1: Well, those were extra stupid because they don't solve you anything.
Speaker 1: You have to carry the same thing and interact with it in the same way.
Speaker 1: Just more glitchily.
Speaker 0: And the other thing is, you're going to go through all the effort of signing up for this thing and maybe two places you go actually have it.
Speaker 0: And that place can't just, you can maybe get more people to use it.
Speaker 0: if a really popular place.
Speaker 0: Like let's say McDonald's said you must pay with your phone.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: OK, great.
Speaker 0: Now all the poor people who go to McDonald's can't go there anymore, period.
Speaker 0: So it's chicken and egg.
Speaker 0: McDonald's would never do that.
Speaker 1: The only reason Starbucks was able to pull this off, to get someone like me even to use it and to get it to be used a lot.
Speaker 0: Because the kind of people who go to Starbucks are smartphone kind of people.
Speaker 1: Not even that.
Speaker 1: It's simply that they had a rewards program and they just rolled it in.
Speaker 1: So it's basically the phone is just a convenience for the people who are already using their reward program.
Speaker 0: I have physical cards for the program if you don't have them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the app isn't something fancy.
Speaker 1: It literally just displays the code that's on my card.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have near field communications or anything.
Speaker 1: But I used it for the first time yesterday.
Speaker 1: I ran like over to Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: I went this long run and I want to carry my wallet because I'm out running.
Speaker 1: But of course I have my phone because you never fucking know.
Speaker 1: So I'm running and I'm thirsty.
Speaker 1: I had the phone.
Speaker 1: I went to Starbucks and bought water with the phone.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I love the idea that I want to do a separate show on this, but the guest we're going to have on to do the show couldn't come tonight.
Speaker 1: We'll get him some other time.
Speaker 1: There's all this debate about like phones and tablets and the features and all these.
Speaker 1: To me, it's not even a telephone.
Speaker 1: The thing I carry around is not a telephone.
Speaker 0: We only call it a phone because, you know, it was a device that came from the cellular phone.
Speaker 0: It's just that we attached the computer to the cellular phone and people stopped using the phone part.
Speaker 0: But we still call it phone because of its history.
Speaker 1: But to me, what it should be is this universal data platform that just does pretty much everything I need and is always connected to everything.
Speaker 0: Now, the other reason these things fail in the U.S.
Speaker 0: is actually because of geography, right?
Speaker 0: In Japan, you know, there's a lot of people there and a lot of stores, you know, or, you know, even in other Asian places, lots of people in lots of places.
Speaker 0: But it's physically not geographically large.
Speaker 0: There aren't that many square miles to cover.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So even though it's not a cell tower situation.
Speaker 0: Think about how many you have to set up, how many you have to make to deploy this kind of system with any kind of, you know, breath that will actually catch on in the U.S.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: If you want to try something out, I mean, like mini disk was successful in Japan.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like there's something about, you know, it would have been successful here had it not been for draconian copyright restrictions on its use.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: But I'm saying is that, you know, when you have to cover a big stretch of land, even when you're not covering a big stretch of people, you know, the distribution of things, even though you have this Internet connecting that space shouldn't matter.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, OK, so now this gas station in the desert needs to have Internet and it never has and it never will.
Speaker 0: Now is dial up.
Speaker 0: It doesn't even work.
Speaker 0: And yeah, cash actually works out there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So, you know, but when you're, you know, your whole country is basically one city.
Speaker 0: that's all squished up nice and tight.
Speaker 0: Everyone has, you know, Internet.
Speaker 0: You're all good.
Speaker 0: You don't have to worry.
Speaker 0: So the geography of the
Speaker 0: U.S.,
Speaker 0: even though our population is low compared to a lot of these people and our population density is low.
Speaker 0: How much intensity being low actually hurts when more people are in a smaller space?
Speaker 0: You can all get them to all adapt onto this new system and, you know, get the thing to spread more.
Speaker 0: It's like the same way that like an actual virus, if everyone's living all packed in, the virus will infect everyone real quick.
Speaker 0: But if everyone's spread out, the virus has a hard time infecting the people in the boonies.
Speaker 1: Now, there's also a kind of like even deeper technological hurdle that to this day, it is easier to hand someone a business card than it is to have two smartphones and go boop, because that boop never actually works.
Speaker 0: Well, that's, you know, because everyone has different shit.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And with the so forget the tech side.
Speaker 1: Let's look at the business side.
Speaker 1: The Starbucks thing only works because I already gave my money to Starbucks.
Speaker 1: So I can't have if I have a general purpose app.
Speaker 1: Now I have to give money to something or tied to a bank account.
Speaker 1: So there has to be a middleman again.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: There's no technological way to do that.
Speaker 1: That's safe.
Speaker 1: So we need something.
Speaker 1: And who has done that before?
Speaker 1: A horrible, evil PayPal that I hate, have never used.
Speaker 0: I use them, but they're evil.
Speaker 1: I have never had a PayPal account.
Speaker 1: Nice.
Speaker 1: I have only ever used them in terms of paying other suckers who have PayPal accounts and they take huge cuts.
Speaker 1: And there's all these problems.
Speaker 1: I hate PayPal.
Speaker 1: There's Diwala, which lets me transfer money because remember, the killer app here isn't buying stuff because I have credit cards to do that now.
Speaker 1: I can't swipe a credit card on Scott and give him money.
Speaker 1: I very often need to give a friend of mine like 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: You know, a lot of people are doing now is you can use, for example, on your phone, I can use like the Chase Bank app and try to give you money.
Speaker 0: But it's like we have to sit there with our phones typing in all this information and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: I can send money from Chase to an email address and then they can claim it.
Speaker 1: But even then, that's a pain.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, actually, I was at a restaurant recently with some people I had just met that day and I haven't spoken to them since.
Speaker 0: But whatever.
Speaker 0: It's New York.
Speaker 0: And we're like they were.
Speaker 0: they were all these.
Speaker 0: they were much younger than me.
Speaker 0: And they, you know, had that typical.
Speaker 0: how do we pay drama.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: So I'm just.
Speaker 0: I was just ignoring it and I was just waiting till whatever they were doing was done.
Speaker 0: And then I was going to take care of my bit and then get out of there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But one of the girls, she had square that little thing where you can accept payments, like if you're in an artist's alley.
Speaker 0: So basically everyone just swiped our credit cards on her phone paying her.
Speaker 0: She paid all these merchant fees through square.
Speaker 0: But that's not my problem.
Speaker 0: So basically everyone just swiped their credit card on her phone, typed in a number of dollars and she took money from everyone.
Speaker 0: And then she paid for the whole thing with her card.
Speaker 0: And, you know, but it's like, great.
Speaker 0: So now someone, you know, has to be a merchant.
Speaker 0: Everyone has to be a merchant.
Speaker 0: It's like, no, this is that what this is.
Speaker 0: It's another one of those cases where, you know, in the olden days, it used to be there was a music producer and then to be music listeners.
Speaker 0: But now everyone is both producer and listener.
Speaker 0: This is, you know, this old model is.
Speaker 0: there are merchants and then there are customers like, no, nowadays everyone's a merchant.
Speaker 0: It's flattened out.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: it doesn't have this to roll system anymore.
Speaker 0: It's everyone does all the roles and you just sort of change this dual view mentality going on and come with something new.
Speaker 0: The problem with that is that it makes it very hard for any middlemen to exploit, which is why the middlemen constantly fight against this flattening.
Speaker 1: But also simultaneously, we do still need a middleman.
Speaker 1: You have to have someone to actually make the money transaction happen.
Speaker 0: That is correct, because think about it.
Speaker 0: OK, what are we going to do if we don't have a middleman?
Speaker 0: I have my phone and my phone says how many dollars I have.
Speaker 0: Your phone says how many dollars you have.
Speaker 0: And we touch phones and the numbers change.
Speaker 0: I'll just it's my phone.
Speaker 0: I'll just hack it and change the number.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: No, there has to be some third party that says this is how much money Scott has.
Speaker 0: And it you know, I can't just go and change the number there.
Speaker 0: It can't be something that belongs to me or belongs to you.
Speaker 0: It needs to be some trusted third party somehow.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, theoretically, you could do it with a cryptographic.
Speaker 0: You could do the Bitcoin method.
Speaker 1: Yes, which has some problems in and of itself.
Speaker 1: It does.
Speaker 1: But even there, finances are not simple at all.
Speaker 1: I mean, I have my checking account, my money market account, my equities, you know, my 401k, all these different sources of money that are more or less liquid.
Speaker 1: And I have to be able to pull the money out of them.
Speaker 0: And they're in banks and places where you need to be able to move the money between all the different places you can put money.
Speaker 0: And so imagine if I turn all my money into bitcoins and I spent it as Bitcoin and even if all the restaurants and food places and everywhere took Bitcoin, I want to know I want to buy some stock with Bitcoin.
Speaker 0: I want to put my 401k.
Speaker 0: I got to pay the doctor with Bitcoin.
Speaker 0: It's like it's not going to work.
Speaker 0: It's not going to happen.
Speaker 0: You need to have some common format of exchange, which cash is still the only one.
Speaker 0: You know, we already talked about some places.
Speaker 0: still don't accept credit card, but everyone takes cash.
Speaker 1: And that credit card thing, though, is causing an interesting self-selection in that I personally really don't do business with anyone who only takes cash.
Speaker 0: But what about those really good hole in the wall restaurants?
Speaker 1: Those are the only places.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: But if I'm ordering food like I need to carry out, I'm only going to order not even someone who takes credit card, but someone who's on Grubhub.
Speaker 1: I don't have to talk to a person.
Speaker 0: Me, too.
Speaker 1: But at a convention even.
Speaker 0: Except for the Chinese restaurant.
Speaker 1: It's interesting how half the people in the artist's alleys actually can take credit cards these days.
Speaker 0: Like I said, they have square.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But it's costing them a lot of money to do that relatively.
Speaker 1: But more importantly, it's killing the people who don't have the barrier to entry of smartphone and the square device is pretty high for a lot of poor, like pre-college freshmen in college artists.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, why can't we just get to the cowboy bebop era or the shadow run era where I have a crutch is basically the same thing.
Speaker 1: And shadow runs a little more depressive because they're not.
Speaker 0: See, you know what I've always been curious about and I'm sure some nerd out there knows this, which is why I'm asking.
Speaker 0: And I don't want to.
Speaker 0: I could search for it on Google, but I'm not going to bother.
Speaker 0: What are you about to ask?
Speaker 0: Remember in Star Wars.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They have credits.
Speaker 0: And they paid Lando his credits.
Speaker 0: And you remember he was getting on to the Millennium Falcon when he was leaving, you know, Yavin.
Speaker 0: And he had like these ammo cases that presumably contained the credits that he was paid with.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The credits in Star Wars world were physical somehow.
Speaker 0: They weren't.
Speaker 0: They're not digital.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm wondering about.
Speaker 0: What is what is an actual galactic credit?
Speaker 0: Is it a piece of paper?
Speaker 0: Is it what is it?
Speaker 0: Because he was carrying those boxes, remember?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And he was like they were loading them onto the ship and you had to do they were.
Speaker 0: it was heavily implied that those were the credits the rebels paid him with.
Speaker 0: And he never gave.
Speaker 0: it didn't seem give those back either.
Speaker 1: Of course not.
Speaker 0: I mean, he we worked for them, but he didn't, you know, get the money anyway.
Speaker 1: Well, you keep that.
Speaker 1: There's a man not entitled to the sweat of his brow.
Speaker 0: Well, I think he took the sweat of his bro's sister more than the sweat of his brow.
Speaker 1: Well, at least we know my little pony.
Speaker 1: It's bits and then there's pennies and actual coins made of a precious metal of some kind.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably gold.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I feel like we can do a deeper topic on this down the road of kind of the specifics.
Speaker 1: But I just wanted to talk about as an overview, because it it annoys me that in this era, in the 21st century, in the year two thousand, we've invented better solutions and it takes a long time to actually get the solutions adapted.
Speaker 0: Welcome to all of history.
Speaker 0: Alexander Graham Bell invented the telephone.
Speaker 0: When did everyone actually start using telephones like crazy?
Speaker 1: Decades later, we cell phones weren't really ubiquitous until we had cell phones.
Speaker 0: Not everyone really.
Speaker 0: Not everyone had them until like the mid 2000s, late 2000s, you know?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There was a time when Scott was the only person in the front row crew who had a current working cell phone.
Speaker 1: When I got mine, that got us up to like three people.
Speaker 0: And this was in the century.
Speaker 0: It was not in the 90s.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rym and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.