Speaker 1: Hey, it's Tuesday December 11th 2012 I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: how to not suck at taking your fucking turn Jesus Christ Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Is that a good pooping?
Speaker 1: About to do the show we literally I record the opener than Scott's like gotta poop and just gets up and walks out of the Studio, okay, like okay.
Speaker 1: That was the exact moment you had a bowel movement.
Speaker 1: Neither not too soon not too late, but right.
Speaker 1: then the moment I said it's December 11th 2012 I'm rim.
Speaker 1: You're like I got a poke cuz.
Speaker 0: I just.
Speaker 0: I just have some power to control exactly when this happens.
Speaker 0: As I decide that is when the pooping move.
Speaker 1: Ah, but if I have a bowel movement is often not that urgent.
Speaker 0: This wasn't heard, you know incredibly urgent like I was about to put it.
Speaker 0: poop everywhere.
Speaker 0: that doesn't happen You know, but if I would have held that shit in I would have suffered through the the end of the show.
Speaker 1: It should not have been good Ah, but if the bowel movement would have been suffering then perhaps you should have dealt with it at an earlier bowel movement juncture in The day.
Speaker 1: that was the early the earliest implementer earliest manifestation of this.
Speaker 0: then perhaps I can't hold it for an hour.
Speaker 0: Hold you want to hold it in for an hour.
Speaker 0: That's not good for you.
Speaker 1: The first time I feel like hey got a poop is not the.
Speaker 1: if I hold it in for an hour I'm not gonna feel good.
Speaker 1: It's hey, you should poop at some time in the next 24 hours.
Speaker 0: You can help move in for 24 hours.
Speaker 1: It's never that urgent.
Speaker 1: I poop exactly what I want.
Speaker 1: I poop on the mound.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: it's not healthy to hold in poop.
Speaker 1: I don't have to hold it in.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling as I say rim From this point forward whenever you're ready, you can poop.
Speaker 1: However, if you wait more than like six or seven hours, I'm gonna come back and I'm gonna tell you it's a little urgent.
Speaker 1: I'm going to escalate the severity from a set of three to a set of two To shape your bowels are in Some sort of.
Speaker 0: you know Panama Canal locking system down there some shit.
Speaker 1: I just it's never urgent unless there's a problem and I poop once a day at like 845.
Speaker 0: it's not urgent, but you know like peeing it's like oh you feel poop in there.
Speaker 1: Suddenly suddenly, it's a slow rise.
Speaker 0: No, it's pretty much as like no poop.
Speaker 0: Hey poops in there Then you go poop it out instead of holding waiting around.
Speaker 1: so anyway Gaming day.
Speaker 1: See you got any news.
Speaker 0: I do indeed have news.
Speaker 0: This is the most amazing.
Speaker 1: No, you mean the thing you've been excited about and telling everyone about you're not as excited as Bruce is about key and peel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think anyone give you more excited about anything.
Speaker 0: No, but they usually.
Speaker 0: you know It is very hard to excite me especially in a world where I have 10 million video games 10 million animes Like it's one Right, and there's all these things that are unwatched unread unlistened unseen.
Speaker 0: Why would I be so excited about a new thing when I've already got so many awesome things that I have not experienced already piled up?
Speaker 0: is that thing would have to be pretty amazing to work its way so high up in the QE?
Speaker 0: we And that thing has happened.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so here's the deal.
Speaker 0: some dude in Singapore Made a fan-made game, but he did a real damn good job.
Speaker 0: such a good job That Capcom, you know, the the owner of the IP rights to the fan-made game he was making helped him out gave him the hooks up and they have gone so far as to specifically endorse this game and Release it for free on their website a week from yesterday Which means next Monday December 17th.
Speaker 0: Wow a free PC download for everybody.
Speaker 0: there is at Capcom unity website.
Speaker 0: They're releasing the game known as Street Fighter cross Mega Man cross Street Fighter.
Speaker 0: I don't know which order it goes.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter This game is not what you expect.
Speaker 0: like I was you know when I first heard the title I was like.
Speaker 1: I thought it'd be like Marvel vs.
Speaker 0: Capcom Fighting game.
Speaker 0: they just had instead of Marvel characters Just way more Mega Man characters bringing in zero bringing in Mega Man X bringing in all kinds of people.
Speaker 0: right would man?
Speaker 0: and you Know everything.
Speaker 0: but that is not what it is.
Speaker 0: It's actually an old-school 2d Mega Man game where instead of robot masters you have Gal Blanca Ryu Chun Li etcetera etcetera.
Speaker 0: Dalzim oh my god.
Speaker 0: You see the trailer for this shit Which is what we're gonna link you to and maybe we'll link you to the website that it will eventually be available as a download.
Speaker 0: So I have a suspicion kills guile sonic boom when he kills ryu Hadouken.
Speaker 0: oh my god.
Speaker 1: Do I get the thousand hand slap?
Speaker 1: That's all I can.
Speaker 0: I don't know which the nine guys are So I don't you know.
Speaker 0: I don't know all the nine guys.
Speaker 1: I know one thing I can say I will guess that this game will be not actually Nintendo hard like Mega Man 9 was Some guy Fan-made game.
Speaker 1: I think it'll be hard, but there's a certain special level of Mega Man hard.
Speaker 0: well I'm actually thinking about as soon as I beat some of the games on my plate going to do a Mega Man ATHON Mega Man 1 2 3 9 10 and then X 1 2 3 whatever it is.
Speaker 0: I don't know how many X's there are.
Speaker 1: I've only beaten.
Speaker 1: like Mega Man 2 3 4.
Speaker 1: I played a lot of them.
Speaker 0: You gotta play Mega Man 5.
Speaker 0: Mega Man 5 is the shit.
Speaker 1: I Rented Mega Man 5 from blockbuster a bunch of times But I never owned it.
Speaker 0: Mega Man 5 will play an emulator and beat Mega Man 5 because it's the proto man edition.
Speaker 1: No, I guess Mega Man 3 was my was my jam Partly because I liked fucking around with that hold left on controller 2 and the game fucks up code.
Speaker 0: Okay, okay, Mega Man is the best.
Speaker 1: You know I'm getting a vibe.
Speaker 1: This is gonna be like a step above the obobo game that came out a while ago.
Speaker 0: No you look at it.
Speaker 0: It looks like a real Mega Man game.
Speaker 0: watch that trailer.
Speaker 0: Did you watch a trailer?
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: it looks really good.
Speaker 1: The trailer of a Bobo's big adventure made it look equally good and the reality was it was pretty good But it was also way way easy.
Speaker 1: Well this has Capcom Hands on it true a Bobo had no one's hands, but a Bobo's.
Speaker 0: that's right.
Speaker 1: I could play a Bobo again.
Speaker 0: Me.
Speaker 1: yeah, did you ever beat it?
Speaker 1: No?
Speaker 1: No really?
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: Yeah?
Speaker 1: What could you beat it?
Speaker 0: I didn't even try.
Speaker 1: uh-huh wait a minute.
Speaker 1: It was really easy.
Speaker 1: How come you haven't beaten.
Speaker 1: It's like one playthrough.
Speaker 0: Why haven't I played any of the other hundreds team games?
Speaker 1: I haven't played because a Bobo takes less than an hour to beat Start to finish.
Speaker 0: I got a lot of games take less than an hour to beat.
Speaker 1: I don't think you can and I think you're having trouble.
Speaker 0: Yeah, every day.
Speaker 0: I've been going home trying to beat a Bobo for the past three years.
Speaker 0: why?
Speaker 0: So I can't.
Speaker 0: I meet you Bobo.
Speaker 0: That's what I've been doing all this time.
Speaker 1: We've learned that if we just shorted Nintendo's stock when the Wii U was about to come out we would have made a lot of money.
Speaker 1: Nintendo has been not doing so well stock wise and I have no intention of buying a Wii U anytime in the next six months Next six million years.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 1: There is a foreseeable what chance that I would buy one.
Speaker 0: that would be I win the lottery if One they're a dollar.
Speaker 1: they made it also Interact with the 3ds.
Speaker 0: yeah to the 3ds you don't have.
Speaker 1: I could use four of those controllers.
Speaker 1: Three.
Speaker 1: they made a new four swords crystal chronicles pac-man verse advanced wars Any yeah, they had to make Mario Party Mario tennis.
Speaker 0: They would need more than one of those because just one of those You know all of those combined.
Speaker 1: if all of those things come then it would be worth the price.
Speaker 1: Then I will buy a Wii U, but if I needed another reason not by a Wii U.
Speaker 0: So luckily this only make a really big Bomberman where on your screen You see only the area around you and on the big screen you can see the whole thing.
Speaker 0: But it's such a gigantic Bomberman.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: the possibilities are endless, but you know what.
Speaker 1: they were just as endless When the GBA connected to the Gamecube they were and when the DS should have but didn't connect to the Wii.
Speaker 0: the only thing the ideas ever connected to the Wii 4 is if you use the Nintendo store channel on Well the Nintendo channel on the Wii you could download demos of upcoming DS games to your DS over the air.
Speaker 0: that was only DS Wii connection that they've ever done.
Speaker 1: it also really took forever wasn't that good?
Speaker 1: Didn't really work that well?
Speaker 1: no So if you needed another reason to really kind of not be happy with Nintendo the Wii U won't let you look at or Purchase anything in their interactive system that is rated 18 plus between the hours of 3 a.m.
Speaker 1: And 11 p.m.. If you are in Europe.
Speaker 1: Okay, really that is such an oddly specific Weird Regulation rule.
Speaker 0: I don't understand how could none of the other consoles do this.
Speaker 1: I also don't understand that now.
Speaker 1: it is true Europe has really fucked up.
Speaker 1: free speech law depends on the country as a whole.
Speaker 1: Europe on average has much less free speech than the US Depends on the country.
Speaker 1: on average if you average all countries that are in what we consider Europe the average the the value of free Speech if you average them all together is lower than free speech in the US.
Speaker 1: I guess so also a lot of the individual countries like France has weird laws about What you can show on different kinds of TV at different times at the same time that you can see boobies on TV In certain times.
Speaker 1: yeah, so in some ways is less than in some ways more Except at the same time a lot of the regulations in the US really only actually apply to broadcast TV Which effectively doesn't matter anymore?
Speaker 1: But and radio simultaneously and radio, but yet in podcast I can say fuck all I want like fuck fuck.
Speaker 1: And I'm showing movies right now.
Speaker 0: It's up boobies on the podcast.
Speaker 1: In fact I'm playing the Dave Zader game.
Speaker 0: Apparently this podcast even has scared What I was about to say.
Speaker 1: when did Dave Zader ever, and then I'd yeah You did.
Speaker 0: you were the one who brought scat on to this.
Speaker 1: Well, I believe that you you were the the inseptor of that, and I simply brought it out.
Speaker 0: I didn't bring it out onto the show.
Speaker 1: well Yeah, hope you brought it out.
Speaker 1: Otherwise you failed in your end and not onto the show.
Speaker 1: you want to put it on the show here, but in particular For example Germany has a lot of restrictive free speech laws and there appear to be a number of laws and rules in the EU Which remember as of you know a while ago the European Union.
Speaker 1: there are?
Speaker 1: European laws now yep, and there appear to be a lot of your.
Speaker 0: I don't know how much they're enforced like.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: I don't really get it.
Speaker 0: I haven't looked it up.
Speaker 0: They it seems like a lot of them are regulations on companies like this as opposed to laws that police would enforce.
Speaker 1: so This is ridiculous and one this is one of the reasons why?
Speaker 1: While I'm generally a very sort of left-wing slash radical techno progressivist type of person when it comes to politics I really don't want the UN the EU or basically anyone, but the United States to maintain the Basically complete control of the Internet.
Speaker 1: because for all the things we've fucked up as a country The Internet is the one thing we have fucked up the least And relative to everyone else we're doing a pretty good job
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 1: but - It bothers me that there's this movement in a like Australia and Europe and there is a movement for this in the u.s.
Speaker 1: To put restrictions on things to protect children that also affect adults.
Speaker 1: I am fine with having any like computers like having operating system things where a User could lock things down for like a parent could lock things down for their children if they wish But the moment
Speaker 0: me
Speaker 1: as an adult Has no ability to interact with that system and/or disable it.
Speaker 1: that is bullshit.
Speaker 1: There is zero Rationale.
Speaker 0: yeah, it all should not be enabled by default.
Speaker 0: No, it's you something you have to turn on Right because it's like kids can't really buy things.
Speaker 0: So you don't have to worry about a kid buying a Wii and going he Because a kid can't buy things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so why?
Speaker 0: so it should be disabled by the fault and then the adult who purchased it would enable it.
Speaker 1: The kid immediately hacks it, but then the kid deserves it anyway, so fine, but the what this is so anachronistic.
Speaker 1: Did they really think whoever made this happen?
Speaker 1: Do you really think that if you can't buy these games between 11 p.m.
Speaker 1: And 3 a.m.
Speaker 1: That one kids aren't gonna buy them and the two no one's gonna have a problem with this that kids are asleep at those hours.
Speaker 0: Thing is well, I mean first of all, right It's like you've got.
Speaker 0: you know, if you look think of all the different categories of responsible parents responsible children Good bad everywhere in between on the gray scale, right kids who are more Responsible who are staying up late because their parents trust them and they're good kids.
Speaker 1: I'd sit down till till the Sun came up playing like sieve or right one or do not, you know They're gonna have access to these games.
Speaker 0: But it won't really matter.
Speaker 0: because just fine if they do.
Speaker 0: kids who are sort of in the middle Right, you know their parents make them go to bed.
Speaker 0: Maybe they're irresponsible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the
Speaker 1: hardware controls don't matter because the good parent with the troublesome kid or the kid who can't you know Shouldn't the kid who's 15, but you know, some people just can't deal with games like this when they're 15 a good parent The kid will listen to him and won't do what they're not supposed to do or they'll get caught if they try to do it.
Speaker 0: Right, and then you have just the irresponsible parents.
Speaker 0: It's like well those kids are gonna be up all night because the parents are responsible.
Speaker 0: So it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: but this is more of a Thursday thing, but in the meta in the general, I do not like it.
Speaker 1: I'm fine with regulations laws everything to help protect kids and to help parents and all those things depends on the specific Yeah, but the philosophically I have no problem.
Speaker 0: We don't like the safe playground actually not at all.
Speaker 0: But philosophically and playground should not be a bed of spikes and fire.
Speaker 0: All that would be pretty cool.
Speaker 1: I have no problem with the idea of something like this being debated.
Speaker 1: My problem is when I as an adult I have to deal with this stuff when I don't have.
Speaker 0: you know We don't live in Europe.
Speaker 1: Nah But if I live in Europe or if I don't if I go to Europe on a business trip and I have a Wii U I want to buy Assassin's Creed at 1105 p.m I can't and that's bullshit.
Speaker 0: You mean 1105 a.m.
Speaker 1: No, 11 p.m.
Speaker 1: To 3 a.m.
Speaker 1: Is the only time you can do this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you said if you want to buy it at 11 p.m.
Speaker 0: And you can.
Speaker 1: I said 1105 p.m I can't.
Speaker 0: oh What.
Speaker 0: oh, it's wait a minute.
Speaker 0: No, 1105 p.m.
Speaker 0: Will be late at night when you could.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I guess I could.
Speaker 0: you're backwards see like see what happens.
Speaker 1: You have confusing bullshit arbitrary regulations.
Speaker 0: I Was right the whole time but also Nintendo.
Speaker 1: how come?
Speaker 1: no one else does this stuff.
Speaker 0: Nintendo always does Extra shit for some stupid reason.
Speaker 1: I mean steam doesn't prevent me from buying a game at 11.
Speaker 0: This is why most of the world is PC gaming except for the US Yeah, where people are too dumb to plug a PC into the TV.
Speaker 1: I just thought this was kind of amazing.
Speaker 1: So I wanted to shed light on this sort of ridiculous star but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: so we were at an epic party at our friend's house over the weekend near Philly and Well, the YouTube party happened for a while downstairs.
Speaker 0: I was not invited to that YouTube party.
Speaker 1: No, you're busy doing other stuff.
Speaker 1: We also had the look at old pictures of rim and Scott and the front row crew from like a decade ago.
Speaker 1: I was at that party and we had the let's play Zendo with strangers party, which was actually really good.
Speaker 1: I can't believe that one of our friends used the Zendo rule of Something involving prime numbers of pants the one you're not supposed to use.
Speaker 1: and yet they got it.
Speaker 1: But I think they only got it because I always use that as the example of a bullshit rule You shouldn't use.
Speaker 1: yeah But at the same time we also have a lot of friends who are getting really good at Zendo and start upping the ante.
Speaker 1: so We watched this series of short animated videos little shorts about Starcraft.
Speaker 1: It is called Starcrafts.
Speaker 1: It's just adorable.
Speaker 1: It's little zerglings and protoss dudes running around with sound effects from the game being cute and They're super short and you should just watch all of these.
Speaker 1: They're by car bot animations and they're ridiculously adorable.
Speaker 0: This is funnier to me because I have recently actually beaten the Starcraft 2 campaign.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking about starting to play the Starcraft 2 campaign in the next six months and getting it into the queue.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm All right, you got a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 0: yeah, so, you know the board game lahav Which you've only played a couple times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz it's okay.
Speaker 1: Not great.
Speaker 0: It's good game These people.
Speaker 0: they're big board game nerds.
Speaker 0: They went to lahav.
Speaker 0: I would like to go there And what they did is they took the cards from the game And they went to all the places that are on the cards and took a picture with the card at the place.
Speaker 0: And here's a little imgur photo gallery of them holding up the cards from the places in front of the places.
Speaker 1: That's adorable.
Speaker 0: That is pretty good.
Speaker 0: I'm wondering I'm trying to think of like what else can we do this with Puerto Rico?
Speaker 0: What Puerto Rico doesn't have a deck of cards really with pictures as the buildings.
Speaker 1: you go find buildings that do those things than plantations.
Speaker 0: I don't think you're gonna find all those plantations.
Speaker 0: You find an indigo plantation.
Speaker 1: There's probably still.
Speaker 0: I'll bet there is still indigo planting in Puerto Rico You gotta find an indigo factory a large indigo plant and a small indigo play.
Speaker 0: you're gonna find both of them All right, fine.
Speaker 1: Let's do Eclipse.
Speaker 0: You gotta find a sugar mill.
Speaker 1: How about Eclipse?
Speaker 0: I'm up for that.
Speaker 1: if you can make it We could do it with El Grande.
Speaker 1: go to all those regions of Spain, yeah, but those aren't on individual cards.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you just go and take a picture of a Caballero in front of a Castile in each place.
Speaker 0: We're better off doing it with the D&D monster manual and Doing it with all the not all the monsters that actually exist.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: like rats like fantasy movies and TV shows we find one instance of everything in Fantasy movies and TV shows and put and make basically take the monster man.
Speaker 0: It will replace the art with a picture from the movie or TV show.
Speaker 0: We might be able to pull it off with Genoa You know, it doesn't also have cards with places or anything our grid.
Speaker 1: just go find power plants of each type.
Speaker 0: Anyway, well, you're stretching it here in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: Holy shit We launched an entirely new show called geek nights presents did we?
Speaker 0: Yes Why?
Speaker 1: because we're stupid and we committed to like 40 plus episodes of this bullshit and so far each one is taking us like It's like a half hour long.
Speaker 1: So too long And they're only gonna get longer because I was thinking about why don't you edit him down genius that is edited down.
Speaker 0: No So what we're doing Is a new show because we pretty much repeat the same thing over and over again so you can edit down.
Speaker 1: So we only say it once a YouTube show where we we take a media and we present it to you in a sort of Final thoughts format.
Speaker 1: So for example, we're starting.
Speaker 1: You know, we did radio free equestria is kind of like a test to get good at this kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: We're gonna keep doing radio free equestria.
Speaker 1: Don't worry.
Speaker 0: I got a huge backlog of episodes I just have to upload and luckily the new episode which we have not our feed yet had A lot of material when it should have had none.
Speaker 1: I know apparently The pony named Luna spies on kids dreams in their sleep.
Speaker 0: That gives us something to talk about
Speaker 1: kind of creepy
Speaker 0: as being scared in the woods gives
Speaker 1: us
Speaker 0: Although we could talk about the haunted the haunted stories Like what's up with the headless horse and the rusty horseshoe
Speaker 1: also the fact that there's rainbow Waterfalls, so I guess they could harvest rainbows in the old days and later they made machines to make it.
Speaker 1: That's natural rainbow.
Speaker 1: They'd be like hydroelectric rainbow.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah So we're taking that and doing the same thing to an anime called shoujo kakamei, otena because it's Incredibly complex full of allegory lots to analyze little a lot of shit.
Speaker 0: That's just fault, you know.
Speaker 0: Red herring.
Speaker 1: Yeah red herrings But also little bits like there's things.
Speaker 1: dudes say in episode one that an episode 38 you go Oh fuck, but you don't remember.
Speaker 0: but then if you watch episode one immediately after watching the final episode you go.
Speaker 1: So if and when we finish this or if we get it on long enough to where we can support doing multiple shows geek nights Presents is going to be a show where we take things and we don't just review them You know, we don't just preview them we don't just talk about our experiences with them we finish them Mmm, because really we only have done this for anime up to this point.
Speaker 1: So we're trying to do and I guess our book clubs are trying to do this for other kinds of things In other meta news Magfest, oh, it's real close now fast.
Speaker 0: I bought bolt bust I also.
Speaker 1: it's on I got.
Speaker 0: it is on so hard.
Speaker 1: I've got the second seat reserved on our bus to magfest.
Speaker 0: I got the first seat.
Speaker 1: Yeah Granted some motherfucker already booked return trips.
Speaker 1: I'm like a5 on the way back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, me too Oh, well or a6 or whatever doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: We're going.
Speaker 0: it's set in stone.
Speaker 1: It's coming.
Speaker 1: I think we're doing what we're doing a pay lecture beyond Candyland rewritten revised Scott.
Speaker 1: We got a rewrite and revise that.
Speaker 1: we are going to be on two panel discussion.
Speaker 0: I'm putting it on my to-do list right now.
Speaker 1: We're going to be on ethics in video games and we're going to be on video games Genres if those have not been announced publicly yet.
Speaker 1: Well, fuck you guys.
Speaker 1: We it's already all set.
Speaker 0: It's magfest.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: Magfest is one of the only conventions you can just totally hang out with us because we have very few Obligations to the con.
Speaker 0: All right Sunday.
Speaker 0: I put it on my to-do list.
Speaker 1: It's coming.
Speaker 1: Also, I guess Australia.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be there.
Speaker 1: paxies We're gonna be there.
Speaker 0: It's a long time from anime Boston.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be there panel submissions for anime Boston and soon.
Speaker 1: So if you want to submit a panel, and I know he needs panels submit your fucking panels.
Speaker 0: They had to be anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Kinetic on they have to be Con.
Speaker 1: panel submissions will be opening as soon as the people I have no control over.
Speaker 1: Oh turn it on and No, but here's the deal.
Speaker 1: Kinetic on.
Speaker 1: panel submissions are gonna open soonish and we're gonna start scheduling shit in January.
Speaker 1: so Don't wait like you did in the past.
Speaker 1: Okay, if you submit like April, we're probably already filled in all the good slots with good panels.
Speaker 1: We're really stepping up the game.
Speaker 1: if you thought we stepped up the game and Kinetic on last year We're gonna step up.
Speaker 1: this is so far for now.
Speaker 0: Let's heat them at a moment to things happening soon like magfa.
Speaker 1: All right, the book club book is the great Gatsby It is.
Speaker 1: Scott has irregular bowel movements.
Speaker 1: I don't did you poop at this time yesterday.
Speaker 0: I Don't remember then?
Speaker 1: you do not have regular bowel movements.
Speaker 1: You've never had to poop during a geek nights recording before You got home early.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I did this only 645.
Speaker 0: It's supposed to happen at the exact same time every day within a span of an hour or two.
Speaker 1: Do you always poop right after geek nights or right before it in my bathroom?
Speaker 1: Maybe that's why I always run out of toilet paper.
Speaker 1: You're using it all up every day before the show.
Speaker 1: It's cuz.
Speaker 0: you use half a roll every time you poop.
Speaker 1: I have a clean sphincter.
Speaker 0: your I also have a clean sphincter.
Speaker 1: apparently not if you don't use.
Speaker 0: well apparently you're using all my toilet paper and blaming it on me and I think there is clean and your roll was almost empty and It is still not a hundred percent empty and my sphincter is clean.
Speaker 1: That roll was almost full before it was almost into it Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So do I need to take a picture of the roll?
Speaker 0: every time I poop before and after it's gotten I have a problem.
Speaker 1: That'd be a good tumblr.
Speaker 1: Really big problem.
Speaker 0: Also, you should check us out and all the places on the internet.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, g-plus Twitter Google communities But you think Facebook page.
Speaker 0: currently I think the thing that automatically posts our stuff to the Facebook page is broken and doesn't matter because Facebook doesn't reliably send your Friends anyway, yeah, but we're gonna.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna fix it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but when I get a chance, don't forget your.
Speaker 1: it's likely You're not getting all of our stuff If you only follow us on Facebook.
Speaker 0: 100% likely because it's not automatically posting there right now.
Speaker 1: But even once we get it posting there again, you're still not gonna get everything Maybe due to the way Facebook works with organizations like us.
Speaker 0: It's possible and their attempts at monetization.
Speaker 1: Yeah So problem Scott and I have.
Speaker 1: we've had this problem for Ever 11 years.
Speaker 0: Our whole lives give or take.
Speaker 1: now because there was a there was a time at our IT When we really only played board games Inside of our own group and other than if we played a choir with Scott Johnson, there was never a problem.
Speaker 1: But then we brought in our horizons and decided we would bring our board gaming goodness to the world.
Speaker 1: We started playing board games with people we weren't already friends and family with and I learned something At a parapetia a horrible realization when I sat down to play Settlers of Catan and what should have taken 45 minutes took three hours Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It was in I think 2003 and I was playing Settlers of Catan at our wag with three people who I didn't know super well and had not played board Games with before and I realized at that moment Pretty much everyone else in the fucking world except me and Scott just never takes their turn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are exceptions.
Speaker 1: Those exceptions are mostly our own friends So all you FRC types and family that we play with.
Speaker 1: we're not talking about most of you.
Speaker 0: Yeah well, there's a lot of reasons for Taking a turn slowly, but there's only one way to take a turn quickly be smart Yep, so you might remember a long time ago.
Speaker 1: We had a series on geek nights called how to not suck Man, where did that happen to that?
Speaker 1: So we're bringing it back.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna complain.
Speaker 0: We're gonna complain about all the slow people constantly and say how stupid they are.
Speaker 1: in this episode we're basically going to tell you if you are or think you are one of those people who plays a board game and You're taking too long on your turn and other people are getting annoyed at you or odds are.
Speaker 1: or you play games with other people Who are doing this and it's frustrating you and you want to learn how to deal with them or?
Speaker 1: You want to get into the air hockey situation The air hockey conundrum.
Speaker 1: if you follow all of it by all of our advice and you're not having a problem Suddenly you'll start taking your turn in a tenth the time you normally spend and now you're gonna hate all the rest of your friends But you'll win a lot more games.
Speaker 1: So how to not suck at taking your motherfucking turn.
Speaker 1: We're just talking about board games.
Speaker 1: Oh these concepts can apply generally to other types of games.
Speaker 0: Alright, so the first thing you got to do right which is true in general for not sucking a board games Turn the page and then you wash your hands.
Speaker 0: Is know the fucking rules.
Speaker 0: a lot of people take so long in their turn because they're Not sure what the fuck they're supposed to be doing.
Speaker 1: now you know, let's assume you're you're learning the game.
Speaker 1: You don't know the rules.
Speaker 1: that well, that's fine.
Speaker 1: You can still take your turn quickly.
Speaker 1: The way to do that is if you're confused about a rule on your turn.
Speaker 1: What normal people do most people I've seen is they sit there going.
Speaker 0: hmm Like they're thinking like or ask to see the rules and start reading them.
Speaker 1: Yep So they'll be like, hey, can I see the rules for a second?
Speaker 1: They just sit there going.
Speaker 0: Why'd you just fucking ask?
Speaker 1: or they don't even ask for the rules.
Speaker 1: They go and then after five minutes of They look up and say hey rim What are victory points again?
Speaker 1: That's why I flipped the fucking table over and go home.
Speaker 1: Yeah to ask immediately and if you have to ask the same question every round.
Speaker 1: you Probably shouldn't be playing this game.
Speaker 1: You need to go home and read the rules because you obviously didn't pay attention When it was taught to you nor when everyone answered your questions.
Speaker 0: and maybe you should go home and play Candyland and work your way Up to whatever you.
Speaker 1: but the moral here.
Speaker 1: if you are confused about a point in the rules during the game ask Immediately and if asking the question is going to compromise your position in the game That's your penalty for not knowing the rules.
Speaker 1: You will.
Speaker 1: you will have a more fruitful experience by learning the rules by asking the question.
Speaker 1: if you're really worried about it Pick someone else at the table and say hey, can I ask you a question?
Speaker 1: show them the card?
Speaker 1: You don't understand.
Speaker 0: maybe find someone who's not actually playing the game but knows the rules and ask them.
Speaker 0: But if it's like a card in your hand you want to ask about maybe there's someone around who knows how the game works And you can just show them your card and you won't have to show anyone else at the table who's actually playing your card.
Speaker 0: All right The second thing you got to do is the most important while you're playing the game Pay fucking attention to the game the whole time you're playing the game.
Speaker 0: now a lot of people that sit down to play a game.
Speaker 0: Well, what do they do?
Speaker 0: They getting up?
Speaker 0: They're looking around walking around peeing Drinking talking about something.
Speaker 0: That's not the game not seeing what other people doing during the turns.
Speaker 0: now There are some games where you don't have to pay attention during other people's turns say Alhambra, right?
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter what the fuck other people do on their turns.
Speaker 1: when it comes to your turn well, there is a fifth or sixth order of strategy and Process you can do to be to have a slight advantage in Alhambra by counting the cards people take up But you really don't need to do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's nothing to do during other people's turns.
Speaker 0: So you can just wait till your turn then decide very quickly because there isn't much to decide.
Speaker 0: but in most games You should pay attention What's happening during other people's turns like in Puerto Rico.
Speaker 1: now many who play games or teeny especially might already be saying but rim You get up all the time and dick around with people and yet because I already know what I'm gonna do in my turn I the master Attention, I will not.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's it's do as I say don't do as I do right?
Speaker 0: I will not get up or take my attention off of a game Except in the case where I already know what I'm going to do on my turn.
Speaker 0: You know and my turn is going to take a very small amount of time But it is not yet my turn.
Speaker 0: unless I am in that situation Where my next turn was already planned and will be swift I am paying attention to the game and calculating the next turn.
Speaker 0: as soon as my turn ends I immediately begin calculating the next turn and this is point number three right parallel processing While other people are playing you don't get up and leave like at Alhambra.
Speaker 0: You pay the fuck attention and you think about what you're gonna do on your turn.
Speaker 0: During other people's turns you don't stop playing the game at any moment Right unless you can make no more meaningful decisions.
Speaker 0: Or you are waiting for new information to be able to figure out what to do when you're doing your turn in which case Sit there and wait for that new information to appear Which is why we get very frustrated when your turn takes so long because you're waiting for you to reveal the information We need to complete our calculations.
Speaker 1: now We talk about processing in parallel.
Speaker 1: well Let's say you do that.
Speaker 1: But even then there are some games where you can iterate and step through like acquire.
Speaker 1: as a game you can basically Calculate the perfect move, but it takes a while unless you reasonably go to math and pattern recognition.
Speaker 1: But you need to as a player, and this is where these get more complicated Recognize very simply don't worry about all this other stuff.
Speaker 1: recognize when a decision you are about to make is Arbitrary now.
Speaker 1: This is already this everything the high level technique.
Speaker 1: the next several steps that we're gonna talk about are Things you can do that are all under the sort of meta category of be better at games.
Speaker 1: if you are better at games Generally you don't have to write a specific game just better at games and generally learn master basic skills.
Speaker 1: Then you can do all these things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like there's some things you can do to speed up your turn that you don't need to be good at games to Do like the things we've already mentioned paying attention and things like that and if you don't do those things then there's a fucking Problem.
Speaker 0: there's another set of things.
Speaker 0: we need to have a low level of game skills.
Speaker 0: You need to have some amount of skills to do them.
Speaker 0: So and it's not necessarily a big fucking problem if you don't do those it's just slightly annoying.
Speaker 0: Then there are things where you can take your turn crazy fast if you're a master.
Speaker 0: No one's expecting that from you if you're not a master, but you should still strive for it.
Speaker 0: otherwise Why are you here?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like in teeny I'll just be like bam bam bam bam bam, but I've played teeny like a hundred times.
Speaker 0: It's also okay If a few turns during the game are slow and the rest are fast.
Speaker 0: when I play a game like teeny Most of my turns will be relatively quick, but maybe two or three times during the game There will be a tough situation where even when after it gets around to my turn Oh, I don't know what to do or something particularly devastating happens right before my turn and then I go off fuck And then I need to really figure it out or
Speaker 1: so This is a kind of an aside.
Speaker 1: if you want to get better at games Watch people who are good at a game play and pay attention to when they take a long time on their turn and when they don't because if we're playing if I'm playing a game that I know and I I'm taking my turns like that and suddenly I take a long time on my turn.
Speaker 1: if you can figure out why suddenly, I'm you know thinking really hard you're gonna start to figure out the game because aspect for Recognize arbitrary decisions is such low-hanging fruit that so many people I play games with just can't grasp.
Speaker 1: There are many decisions in games that are effectively arbitrary.
Speaker 1: either It doesn't matter what choice you make because it actually doesn't matter or it doesn't matter because you Lack the ability to calculate how much it matters to a degree that will actually affect the game.
Speaker 0: For example, who's gonna if you sit there and you're playing rock-paper-scissors and you sit there thinking he's chose rock last time He's not gonna choose rock again.
Speaker 0: Is he?
Speaker 0: or maybe he will.
Speaker 0: Oh, maybe he won't.
Speaker 0: Inconceivable, right?
Speaker 0: then You are stupid.
Speaker 0: You should know that it's arbitrary.
Speaker 0: which one you pick?
Speaker 0: just fucking pick one randomly as randomly as possible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: Do not use any psychology or any chain of logic, you know, if you can use all three at once That way you can't lose.
Speaker 0: you win two out of three times.
Speaker 1: now the same time there might be two options where you know Option a one and a half time trade a good To get money and option B is trade a good to get victory points.
Speaker 1: and maybe you're not like.
Speaker 1: you don't know.
Speaker 1: so you could try to figure it out, but if you have no direction to go on and You're trying to calculate it, but you don't understand what you're calculating.
Speaker 1: You'll think that you're working hard to win the game But really your brain just going in circles and you're not like.
Speaker 1: you're adding numbers up and you're not going anywhere.
Speaker 1: There are also some decisions so the decision is effectively arbitrary because while it could be calculated you like the capacity.
Speaker 1: as soon as you recognize that you will not be Able to come to the mathematical conclusion You're trying to get to in your brain in a reasonable span of time.
Speaker 1: You need to cut your losses.
Speaker 1: pretend It's an arbitrary decision.
Speaker 1: instead let the game go on and instead do a post hoc process of at the end of the game.
Speaker 1: Think back that time.
Speaker 1: I couldn't figure it out now that I've seen the end of the game.
Speaker 0: What should I have done for example in a game of Puerto Rico, right?
Speaker 0: There are certain things where I don't decide.
Speaker 0: I just go with it.
Speaker 0: For example, let's say it's the first time the captain comes out and all the boats are empty and I pick the captain and I got Three corn.
Speaker 0: do I go in the small boat the medium boat of the big boat?
Speaker 1: now there you could I.
Speaker 0: there's easy.
Speaker 0: It's possible to look at everyone's barrels and fucking figure it out.
Speaker 0: You know what I do.
Speaker 0: I just fucking pick a boat.
Speaker 0: I don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: that matters so little.
Speaker 0: ah now Here's the thing that claim might end up mattering but to time it would take to figure it out Versus how much it would benefit me in the game.
Speaker 0: I don't bother even though it's I really want to win.
Speaker 0: It's a skill based game.
Speaker 0: I'm very good at it.
Speaker 0: I don't bother thinking about that when I just put my stuff on whatever boat I feel like
Speaker 1: now while the iterative Calculation of that is basically impossible or useless because either you're gonna be in a tournament where there's gonna be some sort of time limit I mean or you're playing with friends where there's the punching time limit.
Speaker 0: I mean there could be something obvious.
Speaker 0: for example Let's say I have four corn and the person next to me has four corn.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna put my four corn on the sixth size boat to prevent them from.
Speaker 0: but that's so easy to see I can see that Immediately.
Speaker 0: So what I do is I look around really quickly and it takes me about three seconds to figure that one out.
Speaker 0: And if I don't see any of those types of situations, then I just pick.
Speaker 0: any fucking boat does not know.
Speaker 1: this leads into item six.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm gonna take a term.
Speaker 1: I we had other terms for this But I'm committed to using the terms in that Garfield book from now on.
Speaker 1: Okay, the characters of games Develop directional heuristics.
Speaker 1: what that means is look at Scott's situation.
Speaker 1: So which boat do I put it on?
Speaker 1: the decision is effectively arbitrary because I lack the ability to compute Reasonably all the possible outcomes into the future with odds that will actually have a chance.
Speaker 0: Yeah I have no idea what barrels if I bother to think about what barrels people could possibly have for the next captain Let alone two or three captains down the road.
Speaker 0: Fuck that.
Speaker 1: So I play the game a lot and Like I said before if there's a decision that appears are that appears like it is not actually arbitrary.
Speaker 1: But you it is effectively arbitrary for you because you can't figure it out.
Speaker 1: You have to put like a mental bookmark next to that and every time you have to think back every round Until it becomes apparent what you should have done.
Speaker 1: Eventually, you'll have this sort of soft skill this directional heuristic Directional meaning you can have recognized a pattern where oh if the board looks like this I should move in this direction.
Speaker 0: Yeah a directional heuristic is basically the method you use to decide what to do on.
Speaker 0: your term for is a perfect example of one of My favorite directional heuristics.
Speaker 0: right the way I play power grid How much do I bid on a power plant that I want in power grid?
Speaker 0: And this is very simple calculation I make.
Speaker 0: what I do is I look at how much the resources I'm going to have to pay To get the resources I want from the market that turn.
Speaker 0: I estimate that and I take that money and set it aside.
Speaker 0: No, then I look at how many houses I want to buy that turn based on the total amount of power I'll be able to make.
Speaker 0: how how many will I get be able to get houses up to that number?
Speaker 0: How much will it cost me right this round?
Speaker 0: I estimate and I remove that amount of money from my hand and then I look at how much money is left and that's the Maximum amount of money that I will spend on buying a power plant this turn and that is my directional heuristic the method I use to make a decision.
Speaker 0: the decision I need to make is how much do I am I willing to bid on the power plant?
Speaker 0: and There's a method to making that decision subtract the resource money subtract the house money count the leftover money All right.
Speaker 0: So these are directional heuristics and you had to develop these in particular games.
Speaker 0: You look at the decisions you have to make in a particular game and then figure out what will be the method I use to Make that decision.
Speaker 0: and then once you have that method Every time it gets to your turn anytime you had to make that decision.
Speaker 0: Use the method.
Speaker 0: use it as soon as you have enough information to use it.
Speaker 0: Figure.
Speaker 0: then you have your decision.
Speaker 1: some of these are calculated.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some some of them are crutches in calculation like if anything were really good.
Speaker 1: So in Tigris and Euphrates, I have a really simple heuristic of when I will attack someone else.
Speaker 1: I have all these other conditionals.
Speaker 0: I can't really get into what I have a plus three advantage or more if I will.
Speaker 1: you know if I'm if I get to The point of will I attack someone but yes once I am in the I have reached a decision tree of will I attack this?
Speaker 1: Person or not.
Speaker 1: It comes down to something so simple as do I have a three advantage or not?
Speaker 1: If the answer is yes, I attack no matter what?
Speaker 0: Well, I won't attack if a if winning won't get me a significant number of points.
Speaker 1: I know because I'm not gonna buy is fine - right, but I'm not gonna hurry up the end of the game if I'm behind What I said, I have all these other ones that get me to the point of if attacking is even an option Mmm.
Speaker 1: if attacking is an option So attacking is only an option for me.
Speaker 1: If one it is not likely to give a player who has a chance of beating me Points in a color that I know they're deficient in Mmm, if it is not if it is likely to give me points in a color that I am deficient in All the obverse like cases of that are also, you know They're like, I don't care.
Speaker 1: I'm not likely to attack or get to the point of deciding to attack if I don't need that color unless it causes disruption to A player who is likely to be me The treasure situation all these other factors.
Speaker 1: There's so many of them that I could probably enumerate them all But I've played the game so much that it becomes a little more than patterns to where and you'll notice this if you play a lot of games.
Speaker 1: Sometimes I'm calculating in power grid I have a gut feeling for what I should do and then I do a calculation to validate like Will I have enough money to do the thing that my gut heuristic tells me to do?
Speaker 1: if the answer is yes I just do it.
Speaker 1: if the answer is no Then I fall back on these more complex heuristics to figure out what I should do because my gut heuristic obviously was mistaken.
Speaker 0: Now if you don't have a heuristic either because you're new at a game or you're not sure right what you should try to do usually to come up with a heuristic right is What will get you the most victory points.
Speaker 0: most games are victory point games and if it's not a victory point game You got to think you know, what will help you win, right?
Speaker 0: So find the thing that makes you win whatever that may be most money most points get to the end the fastest and look at your options and Can you immediately tell which one of those will get you the most victory the closest to winning?
Speaker 0: if you can't tell?
Speaker 0: Just fucking pick one because you'll be able to tell after playing the game more, right?
Speaker 0: Don't sit around and try.
Speaker 0: if you can't immediately tell right away.
Speaker 0: Don't bother Right?
Speaker 0: that then think about it during other people's turns, you know, which one?
Speaker 0: that way you're not wasting everyone's time You know trying to cram in like multiple sessions of game learning into your first playthrough Now say you can't figure it out at all.
Speaker 1: Like you have nowhere to go.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter if you're acting randomly and you lose.
Speaker 1: you're just doing the best you can.
Speaker 1: the key there is pattern recognition.
Speaker 1: You start to notice.
Speaker 1: Hey rim always goes into the castle and Kayla's and he seems to win a lot.
Speaker 1: Oh look rim and Scott and all those guys seem to castle all the time.
Speaker 1: I should probably be doing that too.
Speaker 0: yep see now here's the thing.
Speaker 0: in a lot of games doing what someone else is doing just brings you both down because you're fighting over a Shared resource and this other player who's not fighting over that same resource and is doing something different will win.
Speaker 0: But that's okay because if you're a noob and you know You can't already play this game quickly and make your decisions quickly.
Speaker 0: You don't have your directional heuristic set up, right?
Speaker 0: Better to copy someone else to learn and get the feel for what they're doing Because you'll do a lot better than just doing whatever you feel like that's wrong and you'll just be in the shitter and then they Will be fighting for supremacy.
Speaker 0: now at least make a good placement and feel better about yourself and learn some of the patterns of movement by copying somehow in
Speaker 1: a super super generalized case if you go before Someone else in whatever sense that entails you are better off copying that person Then copying a person who goes before you whatever there
Speaker 0: is.
Speaker 0: if there is a game with some sort of turn sequence Right, you want to do the same thing as someone who goes after you.
Speaker 0: that for example Let's say power grid and you're you're going in with the coal power plants, right?
Speaker 0: Well, you want to buy your coal before the other guy who buys coal.
Speaker 0: if you have to buy coal second And the so other guy who likes coal is going before you don't do coal do oil or something else because it's gonna be worse For you if he steals all the coal out from under you.
Speaker 1: So back to more, you know non game theory ish sort of skills.
Speaker 1: Learn how to shuffle cards.
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's so many mechanical things you have to do in a game shuffling cards rolling
Speaker 1: dice uni if you want if you're serious about playing counting
Speaker 0: thing moving is moving a space, you know addition and subtraction moving upon and the Number of spaces in one jump and not sitting there going one, two, three, four five six unless it's a joke Just to piss people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if I in carcass own if I get a bunch of points in one go I go one two three.
Speaker 0: But that's just trash talk that's not slow play.
Speaker 1: Yeah I don't need to do that to calculate 17 plus.
Speaker 0: counting your money quickly handling bills and coins quickly and it Yeah being it if you're playing poker the ability just Neil be able to count the chips quickly and send them out into the Into the table instead of sitting there being like one two, right those sorts of things Really bother everyone because you've already made a decision.
Speaker 0: You know what you're gonna do, right?
Speaker 0: You're just like you just can't shuffle your cards and everyone is sitting there waiting for you.
Speaker 1: You think this might be obvious, but no I see people who literally not only can't shuffle cards, but never get better at it.
Speaker 1: They just like throw all their Dominion cards in a pile and I go On the table.
Speaker 0: that is not tournament acceptable.
Speaker 1: You at least need to know a proper card.
Speaker 1: shuffle or the like.
Speaker 1: drop shuffle.
Speaker 0: And if you don't know how to do some sort of card shuffling YouTube go to YouTube watch videos of people doing it.
Speaker 0: go to The drugstore buy a deck of bicycle cards.
Speaker 0: write a real card deck.
Speaker 0: Not a cheap-ass one.
Speaker 0: That's really not nicely coded.
Speaker 0: You know a nice smooth one.
Speaker 0: open it up and freaking.
Speaker 0: watch that video and keep doing it Over and over until you can fucking do it and don't give me that small hand big hand bullshit, right?
Speaker 0: I could shuffle cards and I was three years old and I can still shuffle cards and my grandpa showed me I just watch what he was doing and copied it until I could do it.
Speaker 1: So I was the same thing.
Speaker 0: if you need YouTube grandpa, then I once played in a magic tournament with a 300 card deck Mostly as a joke because the kids No deck limit, but you must have a deck that can be shuffled in a reasonable amount of time.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I Didn't win the tournament, but I got to the finals because everyone around me was scrubs and that was basically Trash talk the deck his kids to sit down.
Speaker 1: They'd be like they'd look at this deck and they'd be like, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Is that I'm like, it's got five colors bitches.
Speaker 0: You couldn't play anything for like the first ten turns.
Speaker 0: You're lucky.
Speaker 0: No one tried to set you on fire Just they didn't.
Speaker 1: they weren't good at the game.
Speaker 1: It was actually reasonably.
Speaker 1: It was actually only three colors and had a fuck ton of artifacts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because none of them had.
Speaker 1: it's like no magic tournament.
Speaker 0: I played him.
Speaker 0: I was a kid.
Speaker 0: people knew what the fuck they were doing except me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was in one tournament where I lost due to poison.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I almost I was really not happy.
Speaker 1: So similar to this learn a gaming lexicon because most board games are Very similar.
Speaker 1: if someone says there's going to be a card draft You should know what that means.
Speaker 1: Like it's one thing.
Speaker 1: if I'm gonna teach someone how to play a board game and like and I tell them Alright, so we start with a card draft.
Speaker 1: It works like this.
Speaker 1: Let's go versus explaining what a card draft is.
Speaker 1: Also, if I have to explain what the card draft is in a fundamental level then the people at the table seem to not Understand it even if I go through the mechanical stuff because now they're not just learning the game.
Speaker 1: They're learning all these other pieces.
Speaker 1: It's like if you have to learn how auctions work because you've never heard of an auction before now Can't play a bidding game because you've never heard of an auction.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're.
Speaker 1: now you're learning the auction game before you even get to the power grid part of power grid.
Speaker 0: Yeah So what's an auction?
Speaker 0: Oh fuck an auction is only one small part of this game.
Speaker 0: We are fucked.
Speaker 1: You've got to learn a basic gaming lexicon.
Speaker 1: Are you gonna take forever on your goddamn turn?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Honestly, if you do all those things your terms are gonna be like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean really the biggest one is when it's someone else's turn.
Speaker 0: Think about what you're gonna do in your turn and then if you're still paying attention, you'll be alert.
Speaker 0: I fail this sometimes, you know You'll be alert when your turn begins and as soon as your turn begins immediately start executing your turn and then as soon as your turn ends make sure the next person starts their turn and hopefully they will Be alert and just start taking
Speaker 1: up and if you can't figure out what to do and everyone's already groaning give up you.
Speaker 1: There's no way you're gonna figure it out.
Speaker 1: act randomly based on the simplest directional heuristic you can and go far Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: There anything else to say about taking your goddamn turn?
Speaker 1: I think we've covered.
Speaker 1: if you do those ten things You counted all the things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we came up with them arbitrarily as we were talking, but there ended up being ten.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: So yeah, so I guess there's one side discussion.
Speaker 1: How do you deal with if you're not me and Scott who are just perfectly willing to be assholes to people and you're playing a?
Speaker 1: Friendly game with someone who won't take their turn.
Speaker 1: How do you get him to take their turn?
Speaker 0: Well, you can say, you know, listen Can you hurry it up?
Speaker 0: Like, you know, you can get a stopwatch and show them how long their turn is taking.
Speaker 0: You can.
Speaker 0: you can just get up and ignore the game because you if you already decided your turn Because you got so much extra time to decide right?
Speaker 0: That's another thing.
Speaker 0: You gotta think about right?
Speaker 0: You might be thinking Oh, I'll win by taking a long time on my turn so I get the right decision.
Speaker 0: That is never the case What you're really doing is you're giving everyone else so much more time to think about their turns.
Speaker 0: So in power grid you want to take your turn faster to hurt the other players.
Speaker 0: they have less time.
Speaker 1: to power grid I have heuristics, but if you take five minutes on your turn, I'm gonna count every fucking electro.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm going to count out like exact actions and exact numbers of dollars I've got.
Speaker 1: you'll see if I play a game of power to people who are slow You'll see me like lining up multiple turns of bullshit in front of me.
Speaker 1: I'll be like making stacks of bills counted out for yeah
Speaker 0: Because you know unlike some other people who get distracted and go look at something else while the game is going on like some TV Or some conversation if you give me more goddamn time I'm gonna think about the next turn in the next turn in the next turn.
Speaker 0: You're only fucking yourself over.
Speaker 0: You're better off.
Speaker 0: The only way you're gonna have a chance is if you play your turn quickly, it might not be the best possible decision But it'll be.
Speaker 0: you know Good enough maybe and you won't give me time to make the ultimate best Humanly possible decision in the universe because I waited five whole minutes for you to do your turn.
Speaker 1: Now the reality is that if you're taking a long time on your turn your friends are taking long times on their turns.
Speaker 1: I hate to say it.
Speaker 0: basically just it's gonna make the game on fun.
Speaker 1: If everyone's slow That's why people hate like monopoly, but it also means that you and your friends are all collectively not that good at games.
Speaker 0: Mmm now play easier games until you get faster now.
Speaker 1: if you get better at these things and you find that like if say you Start you follow our advice and you start taking your turns faster You're gonna find that you start winning a lot more often and you're gonna get into the boat.
Speaker 0: You ever see the guy who takes slow on his turn be the guy.
Speaker 1: well except Scott Johnson in a choir, right?
Speaker 0: Well, okay.
Speaker 0: The other thing to think about right is you know exactly that the analysis paralysis.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it could be the game's fault that people are taking a long time.
Speaker 0: those games suck and I don't play them anymore Now, you know because the game is constructed in such a way that you know Like chess people take a long time on their turn if there's no chess, but look there's chess clocks to deal with that.
Speaker 0: But sometimes there aren't chess clocks and people take forever and because that gives them an advantage right what you need to do is Just not play those games or bring in the chess clock, right?
Speaker 0: And I think adding a timer to a games even if it's not part of the rules is perfectly Okay in a situation of an analysis paralysis game.
Speaker 0: if it's the game's fault that taking.
Speaker 0: you know There's this long, you know time to take your turn It won't hurt the game to throw a timer in there and it's pretty easy to come up with a rule for the timer Such as you know when the timer is up You must make a move or you lose.
Speaker 0: just if you can't think of any other rule like some sort of penalty that doesn't fuck The game up.
Speaker 0: just say you lose game over because someone took too long.
Speaker 1: It's not say you start taking your turns faster and none of your friends do and you start finding That's not fun to play games with your friends anymore.
Speaker 1: I hate to say this.
Speaker 1: it Means your friends are scrubs.
Speaker 1: Yeah in that sense this word air hockey problem.
Speaker 1: The term scrubs have been thrown around a lot.
Speaker 1: I'll try to find the article But if I can't find it then I'm not gonna link to it obviously But I read an article where a guy came up with a really good definition of scrub because I'd use the word forever.
Speaker 1: But this guy is a good definition.
Speaker 1: It's someone who plays games.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm a lot But never.
Speaker 1: but after a certain point basically never invest to get better than that point.
Speaker 1: Well simultaneously denigrating the skills it takes to get beyond that point.
Speaker 1: It's the Street Fighter guy who says you using, you know flowchart can is cheap.
Speaker 1: Or the Starcraft guy who's like, oh you're just doing you know, you're just APMing it up and microing me Like yeah, that's how you get that's how you're good at Starcraft.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: See I say yeah, you're beating me with your APM's.
Speaker 0: exactly.
Speaker 0: That's why you're better than me.
Speaker 0: I just do not feel like doing that.
Speaker 1: I don't call it cheap, but It's not cheap.
Speaker 0: it's hard as hell.
Speaker 1: if you Something's easy to do and wins if you move beyond Being a scrub to getting better at games and you take turns faster You will find that you just can't play games with scrubs anymore.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: It's fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: You realize when we want to play a board game we sit down 45 minutes later We're done with the game of Puerto Rico star.
Speaker 0: We can play a lot of goddamn games.
Speaker 0: It's so much more fun because you can play.
Speaker 0: you can learn new games quickly.
Speaker 0: You can play.
Speaker 0: exist games You already know much faster.
Speaker 0: modern art takes maybe 40 minutes Maybe maybe and modern art is a good example, right one technique to use.
Speaker 0: we talked about the auction thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, wait, I'll run my auction.
Speaker 1: All right, do I hear $1 going once going twice three top two.
Speaker 1: Alright, I bid three going once going twice or three to five.
Speaker 1: See how I'm forcing Scott to immediately jump on yep.
Speaker 0: But no if someone's having trouble in a complex game where there's a lot of different things Play a game that only has one of those things right.
Speaker 0: if people are having trouble with a card draft at the beginning of seasons Just play seven wonders instead so that then once they got the hang of that then you can move up.
Speaker 0: you know if someone's having trouble in auctions and power grid play modern art so they can just deal with Auctions only if people don't.
Speaker 0: you know, it's this progression of you know learning curve that people have to go through and it's you know Video games often since you know, especially long ones have this learning curve built in whether they teach you one skill at a time.
Speaker 0: They'll have a level where all you do is jump.
Speaker 0: then in the next level you jump and shoot right jump and shoot Jump and shoot man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then in the next level you slide.
Speaker 0: next level You change weapons.
Speaker 0: the next level you fly right.
Speaker 0: if you can't do that with a board game you play a board game.
Speaker 0: You got to play the whole thing at once.
Speaker 0: It's not like turn.
Speaker 0: one is easy turn and turn right.
Speaker 0: very few games are like that.
Speaker 1: In fact, if you want to get back to the Garfield book the term he uses for this called bushiness Which is a really nice bushiness was how much I'm getting at is that?
Speaker 1: bushiness is the basically the number of sort of Directions or decisions you could make.
Speaker 1: the first turns of games tend to be the most important and most difficult Mmm, and the decisions.
Speaker 1: actually you have fewer decisions as the game goes on after a certain point.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: But anyway, what you want to do is you want to play?
Speaker 0: Simpler games games that have less going on to where you can learn just one thing Right and make those you're starting game.
Speaker 1: I mean we talked a lot about how.
Speaker 1: you know, we don't like settlers.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I love settlers for like two years playing.
Speaker 0: It's someone's brand new to board games.
Speaker 0: Don't just be like, hey, this is the best one is Eclipse.
Speaker 0: It's like the same people do the same shit with anime like hey first Madoka first anime you should watch ever.
Speaker 0: It's like no probably not right.
Speaker 0: You got to watch something that teaches the fundamental parts before you go to hard mode.
Speaker 0: I don't you no matter who it is on this earth even incredible genius person Right if they do not have experience with a thing.
Speaker 0: They need to start an easy mode for the thing.
Speaker 1: We've played settlers of Catan for several years Regularly and toward the end.
Speaker 0: it teaches you trading and you know territory placement.
Speaker 1: after several years of playing this game We got to a point where we started to suspect that the game was random.
Speaker 1: Yeah In fact, we developed these position weird positional heuristics where we realized that whoever got a head first Always lost because they got robbed.
Speaker 1: all fuck.
Speaker 1: so everyone was shooting for second place to then try to have the stealth victory to occlude the positional heuristic and hide the fact that they were actually ahead like hoping.
Speaker 0: people don't realize that I am Two turns away from largest road longest better go for longest road and largest army, so no one sees my victory points.
Speaker 0: Right yeah, anyway.
Speaker 1: I think we're done.
Speaker 1: So you know what.
Speaker 0: take your turn or I will hit you.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website At front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.