Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, September 18th, 2012.
Speaker 1: I'm Rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, PEX Prime 2012.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: You know, we go to so many conventions now.
Speaker 0: I get the, and we're making less Geek Nights, so a greater proportion of Geek Nights episodes end up being convention episodes.
Speaker 1: Ah, but we've gotten kind of around that by not doing full episodes about most conventions we go to anymore.
Speaker 1: That's true, but I feel like- It's a red herring there, because the Mocha show is just a review of a whole ton of comics.
Speaker 0: I get the feeling we should make a separate show that is the, like, the geek convention show.
Speaker 0: That's not Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Well, we've got a- Then we'd be very, very short on Geek Nights show ideas.
Speaker 1: We've got a show like that in the hopper, but the thing is, convention season's basically over after MAGFest.
Speaker 0: Until?
Speaker 1: Until what, PAX East?
Speaker 0: Which is how far away from MAGFest?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Alright, four months.
Speaker 0: PAX East is in, like, April, and you know what, when's PAX Prime?
Speaker 1: Not that long after that.
Speaker 0: September, so it's September, MAGFest is January, PAX East is April, so they're all four months apart.
Speaker 0: So you get these little, and then New York Comic Con, if you count it, is in between PAX East and MAGFest.
Speaker 1: I have a funny feeling.
Speaker 1: we're not going to do a show on the New York Comic Con this year.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Just saying.
Speaker 1: I didn't even send my press credential crap in yet.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I will.
Speaker 0: KazuCon is pretty soon after MAGFest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when was the last time we went to KazuCon?
Speaker 0: I'm not saying we went to it, I'm just saying it's there, so it's still convention season.
Speaker 0: Not for us anymore.
Speaker 0: It's always convention season.
Speaker 1: We're old men now, we don't go to as many cons as we used to.
Speaker 1: When was the last time we went to, like, Anime Next?
Speaker 1: PenguinCon.
Speaker 0: We only went to Anime Next once, and PenguinCon once.
Speaker 0: So it's, you know, anyway.
Speaker 1: UberCon.
Speaker 1: Remember UberCon?
Speaker 0: We went to the two or three times.
Speaker 1: I went to three UberCons.
Speaker 1: I think it still happens.
Speaker 0: If you went to three, I went to two.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: But, yeah, we're back from PAX, but as you all know, we got other stuff going on, so we're in and out of town.
Speaker 1: There was a guest episode last week, there are probably more guest episodes to come, so don't be scared, we'll be back once.
Speaker 1: I'm back from India and Singapore and Turkey and Germany.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, worst case scenario, we both win lottery or some shit and just start traveling around the world.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights will not die, episodes will just happen whenever they happen.
Speaker 1: Plus, you know, we got all those video shows and things in the works, but they're not ready yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know what, the other thing you gotta understand is that even though there might be a dearth of Geek Nights episodes during one of our traveling times, when one of us is out of town, that means the other one doesn't have anything to do in town.
Speaker 1: Except play Counter-Strike.
Speaker 0: Except play Counter-Strike, but also maybe, you know, instead of spending like two hours on Geek Nights, it's one hour of Counter-Strike, one hour of making a video or doing something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we won't, we'll get past, that's all meta.
Speaker 1: We're back, we're bad, video games, talking about them, and one thing that we didn't talk about in all these missed episodes prior was Steam Greenlight, and the fact that it actually happened, it's going, and the community reaction has been surprisingly mixed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well I mean, there was, basically the idea of Steam Greenlight, if you don't know, is Steam has a problem in that they want the awesomest games to be on Steam, but they don't want it to be the Apple Store where all the crap in the universe is on Steam.
Speaker 0: They want to pick and choose, you know, the good stuff to be on there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, ever try to search for a game on the Apple Store if you didn't already know the name of the game you were looking for?
Speaker 0: Right, so, you know, but the problem is they don't have enough manpower at Valve to know which games are to look at, you know, there's so many games they can't look at 'em all, so what do they even do about that?
Speaker 0: You know, so they crowdsource it.
Speaker 0: They basically sort of make a Reddit-ish of, you know, game submissions, and the games that get voted all the way up are the ones they'll take a look at to see if they can get 'em on Steam.
Speaker 0: Great idea.
Speaker 0: Problem.
Speaker 0: Day one, they put this up, and it's full of crap.
Speaker 1: We're not talking crap like- We're talking like straight up spam, like Viagra spam that pretended to be a game.
Speaker 0: Like somebody posting Call of Duty in like Russia.
Speaker 0: It's like, what?
Speaker 1: It's not- Scott, I'm reminded, so I ask you this, is this Battletoads?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just Battletoads.
Speaker 0: So anyway, so they're like, "Shit, what do we do about this,
Speaker 0: guys?".
Speaker 0: So Valve decided what they would do, and this had nothing to do, as you might think, Valve did not talk to the Penny Arcade people about this at all.
Speaker 0: They just did it entirely on their own, 100%.
Speaker 0: They decided that if you want to submit your game to Greenlight, you have to donate $100 to Child's Play, and then your game will be listed on Greenlight.
Speaker 0: So that way, it's sort of a filter that only a serious submission will go on there.
Speaker 1: Now, the way it works is you pay Valve, and they just pass all the money to Child's Play.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So it's just a fee.
Speaker 0: There's no profit for them.
Speaker 1: Now, what amazed me was the gaming community's outrage at this.
Speaker 0: Well, basically their outrage was, "Look, these are indie developers.
Speaker 0: They have no money.
Speaker 0: Even if their game is successful, they'll have no fucking money, because it sucks
Speaker 0: balls.".
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: $100, if you're not serious, is a lot of money.
Speaker 0: And if you don't have a real job.
Speaker 1: Even then, if I was going to make t-shirts for Geek Nights, the few hundred dollars it costs to print the first run before I sell them, I'm not going to shoulder that burden.
Speaker 1: But seriously, pretty much everything but the bottomest, bottomest tier.
Speaker 1: If you make a game that's worthy enough to be on Steam, you can afford the hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: You're going to make the hundred bucks back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only thing I could say to that is it could be 20 bucks, right?
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: Who's going to ... But nobody ... 20 bucks is going to keep out the Call of Duty submission.
Speaker 1: So Steam is not the venue for everything.
Speaker 1: What is their other goal?
Speaker 1: To keep all the crap out.
Speaker 1: I hate to say this, if you cannot muster $100, your game probably not is above the minimum line of, "I would ever bother with it on
Speaker 1: Steam.".
Speaker 1: That's the level of game that I download from your website.
Speaker 0: You know, it's a tough call.
Speaker 1: Also, if a game is that diamond in the rough where it really is worth being on Steam, people You can get the hundred dollars from somebody else.
Speaker 1: Yes, and you don't have a hundred dollars, you could kickstart for that hundred bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like if you've got ... If your game is worthy and you got some demo video or something, you'll get the hundred dollars from somebody.
Speaker 1: So if you are too poor to get the money.
Speaker 0: Do think that you could lower it and still get the same filtration effect in it.
Speaker 0: Like 50 bucks, no problem.
Speaker 1: See, that's why I'm saying it's serving two purposes.
Speaker 1: Kind of like how a captcha that involves logic or reasoning of some kind serves two purposes.
Speaker 1: A regular captcha nominally exists only to keep robots out.
Speaker 1: But a slightly complex captcha also keeps idiots out.
Speaker 1: That is a very important function.
Speaker 1: If you can't afford the 20 bucks and you cannot get $20 from anyone, you cannot get anyone you know in the world to help you pony up a hundred bucks to get your game on Steam.
Speaker 0: What if you're from another country where a hundred dollars is literally like a fuck ton of money?
Speaker 1: Even then, you can't get someone.
Speaker 1: You can't get some person somewhere.
Speaker 0: From a rich country.
Speaker 1: Anywhere.
Speaker 1: I feel like it's just to cut down on the total number of even, you know, relatively okay or they are actually a game, even if they're a bad game submissions.
Speaker 1: Because green light is useless unless the submissions are low enough for one or two people to go through all of them all the time that make it to the top.
Speaker 1: And to curate it a little bit and make sure something crazy doesn't happen and whatever.
Speaker 1: The other thing is, you know, I kind of mentioned this before, but the gaming community seems to have completely missed the real reason for this.
Speaker 1: It's not so that a game that is great will guaranteed be on Steam because games that are great that anyone notices will get on Steam anyway.
Speaker 1: If there's any game that is not noticed, it's probably going to get on Steam.
Speaker 1: Let's say someone in a very poor country makes a game and they can't get the hundred bucks and there's no way, some magical world where they cannot in any capacity get anyone to believe in them enough to help them get a hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: If anyone even finds the game and realizes that it's good, it'll still get on there because Valve can just take a game and reach out to people and say, "Hey, let's do
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: This is only to catch games that Valve didn't notice.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: So, speaking of Steam, in the Steam beta, there's two really interesting things.
Speaker 0: One of them everyone knows about is big picture mode, which is Steam working on your TV.
Speaker 0: I tried it out.
Speaker 0: Did you try it out?
Speaker 1: I did not yet.
Speaker 0: So here's how it works.
Speaker 0: First, you've got to activate Steam beta.
Speaker 0: To do that, you go to Steam settings.
Speaker 0: Yes, I want to participate in the beta.
Speaker 0: You restart Steam and then in the top right of Steam, you can activate big picture.
Speaker 1: I saw that there's a Steam mover replacement in there.
Speaker 0: Well, hold on.
Speaker 0: That's the second thing I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: So, you activate big picture and then you push the button and the Steam takes up your whole screen and it's sort of like using your Xbox with your gamepad, right?
Speaker 0: It's like this user interface to navigate Steam from your couch.
Speaker 0: It has a web browser.
Speaker 0: It's not a good web browser, but it's the best web browser you can make with a gamepad, which is pretty impressive, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, man, this real user interface is really bad for browsing the web, but this is the best you could do.
Speaker 1: You know, I've always said, and as Yumi and Connor had talked about at length at PAX, if anyone's going to make a thing that will be the PC/HTPC gaming console that is generic, it'll be Valve.
Speaker 0: The best thing about it is the way you type without a keyboard.
Speaker 0: Basically, you enter a text box or something and this thing shows up on the screen and you use the left stick to select a blob and the blobs are in a big radius, so it's a radial menu.
Speaker 0: And each blob has four letters and the four letters map to the four buttons on the right side of the gamepad.
Speaker 0: So you hold into the top right blob and that'll have like H, J, K, L. So it's like red is H, yellow is J, blue is...
Speaker 1: Oh my god, that's really nice.
Speaker 1: I just had flashbacks to the days of trying to type in a Metal Gear password without fucking it up.
Speaker 0: Right, so it's like, man, if Nintendo would have come up with that back in the NES days for typing in passwords.
Speaker 0: But I guess it was only eight directions, not enough really.
Speaker 0: Eight times two buttons is only sixteen possible letters.
Speaker 1: So you make passwords that only have sixteen.
Speaker 1: The thing is, it's interesting, I feel like kids who were playing games in that era could not have dealt with that.
Speaker 0: No, and the user interface wouldn't have updated quickly.
Speaker 0: Maybe you could make it anyway.
Speaker 0: The point is, it's a really good typing thing.
Speaker 0: The rest of it, basically when you open a game that supports gamepads by default, and is full screen by default, it's beautiful.
Speaker 0: It's like you're using a console.
Speaker 0: It's like you go "boop" and a game opens full screen and your gamepad is still working and it's great.
Speaker 0: When you open a game that is default to opening in window mode, or maybe doesn't support gamepads at all, or you have to configure the gamepad before it'll work, then suddenly everything is immediately ruined, mostly, once you open that particular, launch that game.
Speaker 1: Well, one step at a time.
Speaker 1: It is a beta.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you can't do much about these games, though.
Speaker 0: You have to update all these games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well I feel like one of the killer apps for the complete replacement of these consoles like the Xbox, where you actually just have a Steam box of some kind, will be when Valve helps developers not be dumbasses.
Speaker 1: There should never be a game where I have to use Joy to Key on Steam.
Speaker 0: But I'm talking about if you open up some old existing game.
Speaker 0: Future games probably will be, you know, but it's an existing game.
Speaker 0: Well, two things.
Speaker 1: One, I would do something on Valve where any game could be certified to be compatible with the big box mode, the big screen mode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then you could easily filter those games out of the list that aren't certified.
Speaker 1: What I might do is offer, like, come up with some tools that will make it relatively easy for people to get that certification, like to take their old game and, like, re-edit it to make it work with the gamepad and the full screen and everything.
Speaker 1: And then I'd find some third party, because you know what, Valve wouldn't want to do this themselves.
Speaker 1: Find some third party to partner with and have them be able to offer a service of, like, we'll make your game work.
Speaker 0: All you really need to do to have a game work properly in big picture is, when you launch it for the first time by default after installing it with default config, it needs to be full screen.
Speaker 0: It should be probably 1080p or 720p, detect the resolution from the OS, but it doesn't matter as much as just being full screen, because you can change the resolution.
Speaker 0: And B, you need to be able to navigate all the menus and do everything in the game with the gamepad, with the default configuration from the get-go.
Speaker 0: And that's all you really got to do.
Speaker 0: You've got those two things and that's it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it was kind of nice, you know, and I'd probably use it for all of my Steam PC gaming.
Speaker 0: that was good for a gamepad.
Speaker 0: And I sort of organized all my Steam games into two lists, the gamepad HTPC games and the desktop games.
Speaker 0: And, you know, I realized most of those, one thing I realized is that most of those HTPC gamepad games were all, like, indie games.
Speaker 0: And most of the play-the-PC sit-down games, not all of them, but most of them were, you know, more for serious games that cost money and made by big companies.
Speaker 1: I guess without Valve helping people out, I mean, look, Binding of Isaac doesn't just work with your gamepad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I did put that one in the HTPC list.
Speaker 1: I would too, but you really can't play it without the mouse and keyboard, because you should not install garbage like Joy to Key.
Speaker 0: No, not at all.
Speaker 0: Alright, so yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, and that's the other thing, I forgot.
Speaker 0: That rim reminded me and I forgot and I remember it again.
Speaker 0: So, there's a hidden new feature.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is big.
Speaker 0: You have to activate the Steam beta the same way, right?
Speaker 0: And here's the deal.
Speaker 0: There used to be, well there is, this thing called SteamMover.exe.
Speaker 0: It hasn't been updated in a long time, but it still exists.
Speaker 0: And what SteamMover does is, if you're like me and you have program files on a solid state drive, and you install every Steam game you've got, that's gonna fill up that solid state drive really quick, and then you're in big trouble, and it's gonna take you back to the past.
Speaker 0: More importantly.
Speaker 0: Of the DOS days, where you gotta delete one game to install another game.
Speaker 1: Normal person, you install Steam, it's on your C drive, which has Windows and all your other bullshit.
Speaker 1: Then you edit video in Premiere, and you don't know better, so now it's caching all these HD video files on that same drive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you want, ideally, Steam games take up a lot of space.
Speaker 0: You want to install them on a separate drive.
Speaker 0: If you're a nerd, you've almost definitely got more than one drive in your computer.
Speaker 1: Now, if your computer is not already a tiny god, you want to install games that have high loading times and lots of disk crap onto an SSD so there's no loading times.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: You would be very carefully choose which games go on which drive.
Speaker 1: A lot of people still will do a slow hard drive that's enormous, and they put their media files there and all their big crap there.
Speaker 1: And then you have a fast disk, even not an SSD, maybe it's just a 10,000 or 70, 200 RPM drive.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the point is, you want to be able to install your Steam game somewhere that isn't program files because there are many and they are large.
Speaker 0: So the way you would do this up until now, the only way, safe way, was to use SteamMover, which is something some guy made that he hasn't updated but still works.
Speaker 0: And what it does is it moves all the, you pick a game, you click the arrow, it moves all the files from that game to the other drive, and then it creates symbolic links in your program folder pointing at the game so that Steam doesn't know, Steam is none the wiser, and it even has a feature to let you move the games back to where they started, which is very good.
Speaker 0: And it works.
Speaker 0: But, it is no longer necessary, because now there is a feature in the Steam beta, and how it works is this.
Speaker 0: We're going to link, obviously, to the instructions.
Speaker 0: You have to activate the dev Steam console, you have to run the install folder UI command.
Speaker 1: Hold on guys, it'll be production soon enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then you gotta add the directory to the installable folders list where you want to install things, so I made mine like, G colon Steam or something.
Speaker 0: And then, you can only change where a game is installed when you install it, so if you've got a game that's already installed that you want to move, you have to uninstall it, and install it again.
Speaker 1: You know what's funny?
Speaker 1: G colon is also my data storage drive.
Speaker 0: Well I mean, Windows starts at the same letters, so it's pretty likely.
Speaker 1: C is my system disk, D is a little hundred megabyte disk I use for some bullshit, E is my SSD that I had before, G is my data store, F is my DVD, H, I, J, K, and L are all these various removable disks.
Speaker 0: I have all these, I have so many drives now.
Speaker 1: M, X, Z, and Y are different drives.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone cares about your letters.
Speaker 0: I have so many letters, I don't even remember what all of them are, cause now I've collected, basically I keep, every time I get a new computer I bring up the drives from all these old computers, now I've got like, too many drives.
Speaker 0: I don't even need them all, and I got a NAS, so I moved so much data to the NAS, like most of these drives are empty now.
Speaker 1: I filled my two terabyte NAS, I gotta pull stuff off it onto a secondary drive.
Speaker 0: Now I've got like a mega NAS, I got four two terabytes, I got six terabyte NAS, effectively.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you follow these crazy instructions, then you uninstall a game and reinstall it, which should be okay, because your save games should either be A, in the steam cloud, or B, in your my games folder or something.
Speaker 0: They won't be saved in program files, so uninstalling a game should not delete save games.
Speaker 0: Then reinstall, in most cases, check, mileage may vary based on game.
Speaker 1: Whatever, I delete save games all the time these days, I just don't care anymore.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's like, you don't need to save your Counter-Strike save game, there is no Counter-Strike, right?
Speaker 0: You uninstall a game, reinstall it, and when you reinstall it, you'll be able to choose where you want it installed, and that it will be officially supported by Steam and totally awesome.
Speaker 0: And this works so well, in fact, the only feature missing is the ability to move already installed games.
Speaker 0: That I see no reason why it's even in beta, they should just move this up to the real release as fast as possible.
Speaker 0: Because I've had no problems with it whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll see.
Speaker 0: We will.
Speaker 1: So, one last thing, I just want to talk about this briefly.
Speaker 1: So, there is an article on Slashshot and a linked forum discussion on all this stuff, but the gist of it is that World of Warcraft, if you take screenshots within World of Warcraft...
Speaker 0: You have to use the World of Warcraft screenshot thing, if you use, like, fraps or something, this won't happen, right?
Speaker 1: As far as I can tell, yes.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: It has been, for pretty much ever, been watermarking your screenshots with all this information about you.
Speaker 0: So that way, when the Blizzard people can get screenshots, they find on, like, Google Image Search and then...
Speaker 1: So they can be like, "Oh, that's that troll," or, "Oh, these guys are running a private pirated
Speaker 1: server.".
Speaker 0: They can figure out who took the screenshot and all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 1: I bring this up, I don't have a lot, well, I do have a lot to say about it, but I don't really want to bog the episode down.
Speaker 1: Suffice it to say, check out this article.
Speaker 1: The people who figured this out and did all the research and decoded what the watermarks are also provide a workaround.
Speaker 1: If you take a maximum quality screenshot, there are no artifacts, presumably because people who are doing that big, gigantic screenshot might have noticed more readily.
Speaker 1: Because people didn't really notice this for a long time.
Speaker 1: And the sleuthing is how they figured it out and everything is awesome.
Speaker 1: And I bring it up, too, because if you are in any amount savvy to the ways of the internet in relation to piracy, security, nominal evil, hacking, all that kind of stuff, you realize there's watermarks like this and a lot of things you don't realize.
Speaker 0: Things your printer prints out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, laser printers will very often use yellow dots.
Speaker 0: Well, anything color printers will do this, usually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's lots of watermarky stuff like this.
Speaker 1: So read this article, check it out, because as a gamer, this might affect you.
Speaker 1: And if you've ever posted screenshots from World of Warcraft, I can learn some stuff about you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do want to say one technological thing is that Blizzard seems to have outsourced, they just bought watermarking software from some company.
Speaker 0: Right, and the way it works is it basically, in one area of the screenshot where there's a patch of the same color, it will slightly vary the color on a few of the pixels, right?
Speaker 0: Just so it'll be like this is a blue area.
Speaker 0: They'll basically, in that blue area, they'll make sort of like a QR code sort of thing by making some of the pixels like, OK, this one's like one darker than the one next to it.
Speaker 0: And this one is not right.
Speaker 0: And then you can sort of scan it and get data like a barcode.
Speaker 0: The way you should do this to make it so it's not detectable by somebody noticing, oh, look, this area has like these weird, slightly off colored dots and sort of a pixelated arrangement.
Speaker 1: Which to be fair, until recently, no one notices shit like that.
Speaker 0: It's true.
Speaker 0: It's hard to notice.
Speaker 0: But to make it impossible to notice is you basically find blue all over the screenshot and you scatter the pixels all about.
Speaker 0: And then you just have a system that knows where to read from.
Speaker 0: So it goes forward until it finds the beginning and then it goes through.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know, it'd be like if I took a barcode and sort of shattered it and put the pieces all over the screenshot in different areas.
Speaker 0: Because there wouldn't be enough different pixels in any one area for anyone to actually find it.
Speaker 0: So it's so I put like your name over here and I'll put your account username over here and the date and time of the screenshot.
Speaker 1: Stegonography is a very interesting subject.
Speaker 1: You could go even deeper and use but a variance of pixels.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: But I'm saying is that small modification enough?
Speaker 0: If they had done that, we would still not.
Speaker 0: this wouldn't even be a story today.
Speaker 0: Now, that would have been enough to keep it a secret probably forever.
Speaker 1: This was introduced, quote, immediately or soon after patch 2.1.0.
Speaker 0: That was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: If you're not a World of Warcraft person, that is 2007.
Speaker 0: World of Warcraft's old.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So check this out.
Speaker 1: But if you are one of those people who is not savvy to the Internet, I'll give you a little hint.
Speaker 1: If you're ever engaging in screenshots or audio or anything that could be compromising and you don't and you want to post it publicly somewhere or reveal it somewhere.
Speaker 1: But simultaneously do not want it traced back to yourself.
Speaker 1: You should lower the quality and run things like blurring filters, but not Gaussian blurring filters and slight crops and slight skews and transformations.
Speaker 1: Run audio compressors over things.
Speaker 1: Re-encode to JPEG.
Speaker 1: A couple of there's things you should do because stuff like this is way more common than you think.
Speaker 1: I mean, if Blizzard is doing it in World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But, you know, a lot of the times, though, let's be honest, you make a screenshot in World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: Do you really?
Speaker 0: It's like, OK, here's a picture of a guy wearing a fuck ton of armor.
Speaker 0: Here's a picture of a monster.
Speaker 0: Here's a picture of a brat.
Speaker 0: Ah, but so.
Speaker 0: Do you really care?
Speaker 1: This watermark is here.
Speaker 1: Say some smart dudes figured this out a long time ago.
Speaker 1: They could use information that you don't know is being watermarked.
Speaker 1: Like a lot of people upload pictures and don't realize they're uploading EXIF data, too.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: That's not a watermark.
Speaker 1: That's straight up.
Speaker 1: It's just like, here's the GPS location where I took this picture.
Speaker 0: Here's my camera and the lens I was using.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you want to upload EXIF data on purpose.
Speaker 0: Like, here's the camera and the lens I used.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the other.
Speaker 1: All right, here's a picture of my bunny.
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess people know my address now.
Speaker 0: Or they can, you know, know at least the building you're in.
Speaker 0: If you're in a house, they know exactly where you are.
Speaker 0: Suburbia.
Speaker 0: Security and apartment buildings.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, I'm in one of these hundred apartments.
Speaker 1: Anyone who ordered a T-shirt back when we were selling them, you have my home address.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I have a doorman.
Speaker 1: Doorman won't let you in.
Speaker 0: My address is on the stupid newsletter because MailChimp makes you put an address there.
Speaker 0: Oooh.
Speaker 0: What are you going to do?
Speaker 0: You want to come over and visit?
Speaker 0: Fine, let's play some video games.
Speaker 1: Hey there.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So this is kind of amazing, but it also makes me feel old.
Speaker 1: So I will preface this by saying the following.
Speaker 1: I do not recognize a single one of these Magic cards because I quit playing Magic when Fallen Empires came out.
Speaker 0: I started playing Magic when Fallen Empires came out.
Speaker 0: Because the community of Magic players and tournament people.
Speaker 1: I used to go to tournaments.
Speaker 1: I was really into Magic.
Speaker 0: I went to one tournament.
Speaker 0: It was Homelands would just come out.
Speaker 0: Or no, or Alliances.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Alliances had just come out.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: The last tournament I went to.
Speaker 0: And then I stopped playing Magic.
Speaker 1: Literally the last tournament I went to.
Speaker 1: I kind of quit Magic in quotes, but I kept playing.
Speaker 0: It was middle school.
Speaker 1: But the last tournament I ever went to, which was actually the last game of Magic I ever played.
Speaker 1: Not counting when we busted out those starter decks at PAX.
Speaker 1: Was a tournament where Alliances had been announced and come out like two days before.
Speaker 1: So the tournament, I remember there was a big sign that was like, "No Alliances cards.
Speaker 1: You will be
Speaker 1: disqualified.".
Speaker 1: I used to play when a type two tournament meant, I think, revised, the dark, and Fallen Empires.
Speaker 0: I played in a type two, which meant you couldn't use, you could only use certain things that are currently available.
Speaker 1: You could use the current main game, and you could use the...
Speaker 0: Which was fourth edition at the time.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, for me, I started playing before revised existed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I played when revised came into existence.
Speaker 1: I have a pile of beta cards.
Speaker 0: Like, when I read about beta, it was like, "Whoa, there were sets before
Speaker 0: this?".
Speaker 0: I just found out about this game, and I'm late.
Speaker 1: In fact, when fourth edition came out, I remember I was bitching.
Speaker 1: We were like, "The cards don't look as good anymore, and the game's stupid
Speaker 1: now.".
Speaker 1: This is bullshit.
Speaker 1: Fuck this game.
Speaker 0: I think the cards look better.
Speaker 0: They improved the printing process and made the colors brighter.
Speaker 0: And revised, they were all sort of faded.
Speaker 1: No, see, that's because they were old.
Speaker 1: Hold a revised card that's freshly printed.
Speaker 0: No, you open up a brand new revised package.
Speaker 0: And a brand new fourth edition.
Speaker 1: Fourth edition looked like shitty laser jet, like, crapo printing.
Speaker 0: No, the fourth edition had much greater saturation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was oversaturated.
Speaker 1: It looked like garbage.
Speaker 0: No, the revised one looked like someone had sandblasted the cards.
Speaker 1: Magic cards didn't look good again until Ice Age.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Ice Age looked the same as fourth edition.
Speaker 1: No, it didn't.
Speaker 1: It was like night and day.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so kids, fun fact.
Speaker 1: You can tell the difference between alpha, beta, unlimited, and revised based on primarily the borders.
Speaker 1: Alpha and beta have black borders.
Speaker 0: I think the kids know more about magic than we do.
Speaker 0: Considering we haven't played it in a hundred years.
Speaker 1: I don't think the kids know about old magic.
Speaker 0: Maybe not about old magic.
Speaker 0: But they know about magic in general more than we do.
Speaker 1: I don't think they know what a fucking Sol Ring is.
Speaker 0: They do.
Speaker 0: It costs one colorless mana.
Speaker 0: But when you tap it, it's an artifact.
Speaker 0: It gives you two colorless mana.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those are restricted cards.
Speaker 0: That card, I have one.
Speaker 0: It's basically mega illegal.
Speaker 0: One.
Speaker 1: I have a pile of them.
Speaker 0: I didn't have that many revised cards.
Speaker 0: I played when revised was there.
Speaker 0: My friend had a bunch of revised cards.
Speaker 0: And then I started playing and when I went to the store, revised was like expensive on its way out.
Speaker 0: It was like that moment.
Speaker 0: It was when I actually bought it myself.
Speaker 1: The thing is, fourth edition was just a gimped version of revised that took out all the good cards.
Speaker 0: That's correct.
Speaker 1: And unlimited was even better.
Speaker 1: I mean, back in the day, icy manipulator was basically the way you would interpret the rules.
Speaker 1: Tap this to tap or use it to tap any card, yours or an opponent's.
Speaker 1: And the implication was and activate that tap power.
Speaker 1: But they since continuously gimped the icy manipulator.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the ice age version of the icy manipulator has to a) tap itself.
Speaker 0: Making it so you couldn't just tap the other guy's whole loadout.
Speaker 0: Which you could do with the original one because it didn't tap itself.
Speaker 0: And b) the rules really specified that yeah.
Speaker 1: And everyone talks about the black lotuses like they were the biggest deal.
Speaker 1: No, the moxes were the big deal.
Speaker 0: You could still use an icy manipulator to like tap a dude's land and then he would have one less land that turn.
Speaker 1: Oh, so exciting.
Speaker 1: So much better than tapping his assassin to kill said assassin.
Speaker 0: Well, you could tap his really big creature so it couldn't attack that turn.
Speaker 1: Tap his really big creature to attack fucking him.
Speaker 0: Or you could tap something and then you could use some other card.
Speaker 0: that said do this to something that's tapped.
Speaker 0: And be like, oh, there we go.
Speaker 1: Alright, I'll make a reference.
Speaker 1: I'll use League of Leathers players.
Speaker 1: I don't know if any of you kids will even get this.
Speaker 1: Tap Tim to do damage to him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was the original interpretation.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So check out my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I didn't even say my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 1: So this is a Turing machine constructed with a 50 magic card combo where the cards beget other cards functions.
Speaker 1: This is some crazy shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: And again, I do not recognize a single card that is mentioned here.
Speaker 0: Not even one?
Speaker 1: Not even one.
Speaker 0: Not even the basic lands?
Speaker 1: Alright, let's see.
Speaker 1: Here's one of the cards.
Speaker 0: There has to be a basic land there.
Speaker 1: They're not listed.
Speaker 1: Teziah comma Orzeab Skyon.
Speaker 0: I think it's Sion.
Speaker 1: Human advisor.
Speaker 1: Sacrifice three white creatures.
Speaker 0: Why would you do that?
Speaker 1: Remove target creature from the game.
Speaker 0: This is not a card you would use in a real game.
Speaker 1: Whenever another black creature you control.
Speaker 1: Another black creature you control.
Speaker 1: Is put into the graveyard from play.
Speaker 1: Put a 1/1 white spirit creature token with flying into play.
Speaker 1: This is a 2/3 creature that costs one colorless, one white, and one black mana.
Speaker 1: And the symbol on it, I have no fucking idea what that is.
Speaker 1: It also has a black border.
Speaker 1: I don't know what that means anymore.
Speaker 0: It makes me wonder, like, is current magic, like, creatures are actually good?
Speaker 0: Because when I played magic, you basically, if you wanted to win- What, you revised?
Speaker 1: My green creature deck would kick the shit out of you.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, but I'm saying is like, in the day when I played, the way to win was to basically have no creatures.
Speaker 1: Whoa!
Speaker 1: Mindbend.
Speaker 1: Instant.
Speaker 1: Change the text target permanent by replacing all instances of one color word or one basic land type with another.
Speaker 0: That's a great card.
Speaker 1: For example, you may change non-black creatures to non-green creatures or forest walk to island walk.
Speaker 1: But then there's a sentence at the end.
Speaker 1: This effect doesn't end at the end of this turn.
Speaker 0: Right, it's permanent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's an instant.
Speaker 0: Right, so you play this and you would change your circle of protection red- As opposed to enchantment, which is the normal way to do that.
Speaker 0: To circle of protection blue.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So, I noticed that Conrad's Twitter avatar changed to what appeared to be a drawing of Miles Edgeworth with a daft punk helmet.
Speaker 1: I did also notice that.
Speaker 0: And I was like, man, that is the perfect Twitter avatar for someone of Conrad's nature.
Speaker 0: That is awesome.
Speaker 0: And then I saw a link like a few minutes later, and I played this link, and onto my screen came Phoenix Wright, and I said, "Huh, I wonder if this is a-".
Speaker 0: Yep, it's related.
Speaker 0: What this is, is somebody took a song, which is a, I guess the song is by the Mystery Skulls.
Speaker 0: It's called Money?
Speaker 0: Or it's the song called Mystery Skulls by a band called Money, I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: I think it's, the band is Mystery Skulls because the URL is MysterySkulls.bandcamp.com.
Speaker 0: And they made an animated video to this song on their own.
Speaker 0: It's not a real official work, it's by a fan.
Speaker 0: And basically, it starts with Phoenix Wright sort of slamming his hands on the table on the beats.
Speaker 0: And then it gets pretty crazy, and totally awesome, and the song's not half bad.
Speaker 0: So you should watch this for internet awesomeness.
Speaker 1: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: So because my thing of the day wasn't a video, I have one more thing of the day.
Speaker 1: You may remember in the old days, Dance Dance Revolution was the game.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And there was a dude.
Speaker 1: Dude's name was DJ 8-Ball.
Speaker 0: He's probably still alive.
Speaker 1: DJ 8-Ball was famous for faking a limp for an extended period, showing up at a Dance Dance Revolution style tournament.
Speaker 0: With a cane.
Speaker 1: Not a perfect attack, with a cane.
Speaker 1: And everyone's like, "Alright, he's gonna take the stage and do the best he
Speaker 1: can.".
Speaker 0: And the cane was incorporated into his routine, and his leg was just fine.
Speaker 1: The crowd went bullshit batshit.
Speaker 1: It was crazy.
Speaker 0: And the routine wasn't half bad.
Speaker 1: I'm not linking to that video, I'm linking to a video which is clearly made with a camcorder.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all the videos of DJ 8-Ball are so low quality.
Speaker 0: Some guy with a crappy old camcorder.
Speaker 1: This is from October 13th, 2001.
Speaker 0: You really didn't have high resolution digital video cameras in 2001.
Speaker 1: Somehow, in 2001, however, we saw this video.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: This is DJ 8-Ball performing
Speaker 1: "Cafe."
Speaker 1: Doubles.
Speaker 1: On a Dance Dance Revolution 4th Mix machine.
Speaker 1: 4th Mix Plus, I believe.
Speaker 1: The best machine.
Speaker 1: In a tournament where he won the shit out of it.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: So I just want to point out something I learned today.
Speaker 0: The current version of DDR, I think, is X3.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: I played that in Japan.
Speaker 1: DDR X3, I learned from-- I also have every song from it in StepMania.
Speaker 0: From Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Has a mode in it known as "Second Mix
Speaker 0: Mode."
Speaker 0: You basically can turn it into a second mix machine with all 30 second mix songs plus two extra songs.
Speaker 1: Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Speaker 0: It turns into a second mix machine.
Speaker 1: X2 or second mix?
Speaker 0: Second mix.
Speaker 0: As in the second DDR ever.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 0: Also, every single one of those second mix songs is available in the X3 mode.
Speaker 0: So you can just play the regular X3 and have access to the full second mix library.
Speaker 0: This makes me wonder.
Speaker 0: X2 did not contain a DDR first mix mode.
Speaker 1: But-- First mix sucked.
Speaker 0: Will-- they did.
Speaker 0: Will DDR X4 contain a third mix mode?
Speaker 1: If so, let's buy an X5 machine.
Speaker 0: Third mix has a lot of overlap with second mix.
Speaker 1: However, fourth mix is when everything changed.
Speaker 0: Will DDR X5, or whatever version that is, have a fourth mix mode?
Speaker 0: If so, how much money can we get together to finally buy a DDR machine?
Speaker 1: Last I checked, $14,000 is the going rate.
Speaker 0: I do not have that much money.
Speaker 1: I do, but I probably shouldn't spend it on a Dance Dance Revolution machine.
Speaker 0: Let's go quarter Z's.
Speaker 0: I pay one quarter, and you pay three quarter.
Speaker 1: How about I just continue to play in StepMania, but we buy some Cobalt Flux hardpads?
Speaker 0: Why don't we somehow emulate it in MAME, and then the real DDRX whatever in MAME by downloading it.
Speaker 1: Because I don't care about-- all I care about from the arcade, really, is that dance pad.
Speaker 0: I know, but it would be the true software arcade experience.
Speaker 1: We just did a lecture on this.
Speaker 1: You forget how amazing the dance pads are in DDR.
Speaker 0: I don't forget.
Speaker 0: They're perfect.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Let's buy an arcade just the dance pad part, and then-- What are you going to hook that up to?
Speaker 0: A computer running-- An Arduino, yes.
Speaker 0: A computer running MAME.
Speaker 1: With an Arduino.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Scott, have you seen how those connect to the machine?
Speaker 0: It's USB.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: It's not physically USB, but digitally it's USB.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe they changed it, because last time I checked when I was trying to make a pad, I did make, you guys, to make me feel really old a long time ago, a hard DDR pad out of metal and wood, with plexiglass and everything.
Speaker 1: And I looked up and tried to buy an arcade pad and use it, and the connector and the standard and everything for it was bullshit.
Speaker 0: It's got all kinds of crazy weird wires coming out of it, but you can definitely make it work, because you know what's inside the DDR machine?
Speaker 1: Now a computer.
Speaker 0: A PC.
Speaker 0: It's always been some sort of normal PC computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in the old days it was like a DVD or a laser disc.
Speaker 0: There were laser discs in there, but you know what was reading the laser discs?
Speaker 0: They were just laser disc readers, like LD-ROMs hooked up to a computer and a monitor.
Speaker 0: Actually, the new DDR machines are really nice in that they have a widescreen LCD instead of a CRT.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's pretty nice.
Speaker 1: But I can't do my Matrix walk anymore.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: I wonder if anyone knows what that is.
Speaker 1: Here's a hint.
Speaker 1: If you did that at an arcade, you would probably get beat the shit out of.
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably.
Speaker 1: So, metamoment.
Speaker 1: We're in and out of town.
Speaker 1: We recorded the show at some point in the distant past, actually, and it's up now because I'm in Mumbai right now.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is awesome.
Speaker 0: You should listen to us.
Speaker 0: Check out our forum.
Speaker 0: You should check out our places on the internet.
Speaker 0: that we have it, which is all the places.
Speaker 1: Check out our videos.
Speaker 1: Many of you found us from PAX.
Speaker 1: You realize a lot of our videos of panels and lectures from PAX are just on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Email newsletter, we have that.
Speaker 0: We have Twitter, Facebook, all those things.
Speaker 1: Book Club book is the man who was Thursday.
Speaker 1: We'll do the show on it real soon.
Speaker 1: The next Book Club book will be something at Scott's Pick.
Speaker 0: I think I know what it's going to be.
Speaker 1: And then I'm doing the Greg Gatsby right after that.
Speaker 0: I'm going with my strategy of book I own.
Speaker 0: I haven't read.
Speaker 0: That's how I have to save myself some money.
Speaker 1: The thing is, I'm going to read Richard Garfield's gaming book, so I got to squeeze that in.
Speaker 0: Well, don't make that the Book Club book because I don't really not that interested.
Speaker 1: You're really not that interested?
Speaker 1: Well, now it's the Book Club book.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 0: It's not the great Gatsby.
Speaker 0: I fooled you.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So PAX.
Speaker 0: It was another PAX, the same as all the other PAXs before it, only different.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there were a surprising number of... Well, it wasn't that there were a lot of changes to PAX in the fundamental spiritual sense.
Speaker 1: But there were a lot of logistical changes to PAX.
Speaker 0: There are many things we can discuss about this PAX.
Speaker 0: We will not discuss the things that are common to all PAXs.
Speaker 1: Yes, if you want to know about PAX in a general sense or anything we did not talk about, listen to any of the episodes I'll link to.
Speaker 0: We will only discuss things that are unique to this PAX or unique to our experience at this PAX.
Speaker 1: So, first off, we went to PAX devs.
Speaker 1: We were actually in Seattle from Tuesday onwards.
Speaker 0: PAX dev badge says do not talk about PAX dev or you'll be banned from PAX dev in all future PAXs.
Speaker 1: Well, it says do not talk about the specifics of any talk.
Speaker 1: So, I think we can review PAX dev in a general sense.
Speaker 0: If you are a dev, you should probably go to PAX dev.
Speaker 1: If you're interested in game design and you are serious about that.
Speaker 0: Because that makes it worth the cost of entry.
Speaker 1: If you're just a gamer or you're like, I'd like to make games, but you don't care.
Speaker 1: You don't know about it.
Speaker 1: If you haven't played some German board games, you've not played Doom 2, you're not a programmer, you're not an artist who's deep into gaming, don't go to PAX dev.
Speaker 1: It's not for you.
Speaker 0: It's not worth the amount of money you have to pay to get in.
Speaker 0: But, if you are serious, you're actually a game designer, you work in the industry, you should go to PAX dev just to hang out with all the other people.
Speaker 0: And we can't say anything else because we don't want to be banned from PAX dev and all future PAXs dev or otherwise.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Though, we did do our panel, academia versus reality, psychology, game theory and games.
Speaker 1: And it went very well.
Speaker 1: It did.
Speaker 1: I can't say anything else, but it went really well.
Speaker 1: I learned a lot that I can't talk about.
Speaker 0: We can say that it existed because it's on the public PAX dev schedule.
Speaker 1: I will say this, you know what sucked?
Speaker 1: We did our 20 minute lecture at PAX prime on the ethics of mind control.
Speaker 1: And we learned some things at PAX dev that I really would have liked to have been able to say in that panel that we couldn't.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so, regular PAX.
Speaker 1: Regular PAX.
Speaker 1: The keynote was okay.
Speaker 0: It was basically sort of like a corporate... It was the guy who made Spyro the Dragon and Ratchet and Clang.
Speaker 1: I'm going to say the harshest thing I can say, and dude, I'm sorry to sound so harsh.
Speaker 1: It was a wannabe Ted Talk.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But it's like he didn't really have anything that inspiring and it's like it sort of makes sense.
Speaker 0: he wouldn't have anything inspiring because this is going to be even harsher.
Speaker 0: All you do is you made like three franchises and a huge pile of sequels and most of the time, most of the innovative stuff you did that he even bragged about was all the creative weapons he came up with.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, that's, you know, the part of the game industry that I give no fucks about.
Speaker 1: My favorite keynotes are still McGonagall, the first one we went to and the second one we went to.
Speaker 0: The Warren Specter one I think was good.
Speaker 1: We already forgot we're old men.
Speaker 1: Name anyone who's done a keynote at PAX.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure Warren Specter did it.
Speaker 1: Alright, name anyone else.
Speaker 0: What's that guy's name?
Speaker 0: That guy?
Speaker 0: It's the guy from...
Speaker 1: Will Whedon did the one of the first PAX East.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's an East.
Speaker 0: That's too easy.
Speaker 1: I think if I had to rank him, it's the Ken Levine one in 2008, which is our first PAX.
Speaker 1: It's hard to compare any PAX because the first PAX I went to was in many ways the best one I went to, but it was mostly because I'd never experienced a fan convention that good before.
Speaker 1: I mean, I went into it before that PAX.
Speaker 0: There was something that I think the reason that PAX was so great in my memory, not just because it was my first giving it a personal significance to me of the novelty of the experience, but because at that PAX '08, PAX still was not at full capacity.
Speaker 0: So it was much more intimate in its size, like going to see a concert, literally, where there's less people at the concert.
Speaker 0: You get this more intimate setting than when you go to the stadium concert.
Speaker 0: And now, any PAX you go to, even if it's your first PAX, you get the novelty aspect, but it's stadium arena concert all the time, whereas PAX '08 was still small enough to be intimate, and the PAXes before that were even more intimate, and I'm very sorry I missed them.
Speaker 0: It was my regret for the rest of my days.
Speaker 1: But there's a little more to it than that, because one, before I went to that PAX, the benchmark of great convention, the best conventions I'd ever been to, were Otacon.
Speaker 1: So I was comparing everything at that PAX to the best convention I'd ever been to, and it was so far beyond it that I, it's telling that after, yeah, we pretty much stopped doing Otacon.
Speaker 0: So anyway, the current PAX, PAX 2012, PAX Prime, let's see what was interesting.
Speaker 0: Number one, let's talk about the League of Legends area.
Speaker 0: They had this thing up in the top, taking up a big-ass room, and the room was 100% League of Legends, but it wasn't play League of Legends, it was spectate the North American Championships of League of Legends.
Speaker 0: So let me tell you, this shit was fucking epic, yo.
Speaker 1: This was so professionally done, independent of what you like.
Speaker 0: I don't give a shit about MOBAs.
Speaker 1: I think MOBAs as a genre are stupid, but that's fine, I think baseball is stupid too.
Speaker 0: I don't think it is stupid, I think it is a genre of game that has many fun aspects that I personally enjoy and really want to play, but there are many stupid things that are in the genre.
Speaker 0: they won't remove that ruin it.
Speaker 1: But Scott, removing them makes it no longer the genre.
Speaker 0: League of Legends removes many of those things, but not enough of them.
Speaker 1: I put League of Legends on the same level as Major League Baseball, in my opinion, in terms of my like of it as a thing.
Speaker 1: But seriously, this area was off the hook.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: you're thinking about the wizard, right?
Speaker 0: You know, with the freaking Nintendo World Championships, this was way beyond that.
Speaker 0: This was like, whoa.
Speaker 1: They had professional commentators, and it was packed over capacity.
Speaker 0: The whole convention, people were packed in there watching, cheering, screaming.
Speaker 1: I was there at the end of I think the semi-finals or whatever, and suddenly one guy ganks jungle deep something, another boat sinking dude.
Speaker 1: I don't know, I'm an old man.
Speaker 1: And the crowd goes crazy, and then the announcer starts to explain what happened.
Speaker 1: And it was just, it was louder than the Omega-Thon finale.
Speaker 0: It was great.
Speaker 0: But I personally, and Rym's going to argue against this, right?
Speaker 0: It sort of, even though it was awesome and big, even though I personally don't care about it, it's not because I personally don't care about it.
Speaker 0: If let's say, let's say for example it had been the Counter-Strike arena, right?
Speaker 0: I still personally feel that it should not be using space, this large amount of space at PAX Prime, that is shared PAX space, should be dedicated to any one game.
Speaker 0: The square footage.
Speaker 1: You mean like the Omega-Thon finale, which is dedicated to one game?
Speaker 0: That's not, that is main events area.
Speaker 0: It is used for many things.
Speaker 0: We are talking about a section of square footage that is dedicated to one game and only one game disproportionately for the duration of PAX, right?
Speaker 1: So you say disproportionately, that space could not have easily been used for much else.
Speaker 0: It caused other things at PAX to be moved around.
Speaker 0: It could have just been bigger expo hall.
Speaker 0: It could have been more tabletop.
Speaker 0: It could have been PC area is bigger.
Speaker 0: It could have been console preplays bigger.
Speaker 1: Tabletop was pretty much never full.
Speaker 0: That's because they had this red lion, the red lion tabletop might have had not to had existed.
Speaker 0: They could have just forgot the red lion.
Speaker 1: No, because there was more space for tabletop in the red lion and better space than that space would have been.
Speaker 1: And there's no area of PAX I would extend in there and also...
Speaker 0: They could have not had that stuff in the Hyatt, saved a lot of money getting these extra hotels involved.
Speaker 1: They're going to need those extra hotels anyway if they want to increase capacity.
Speaker 0: They could have gotten those hotels and used this space and been like, well PAX is just even bigger and more awesome.
Speaker 1: It was bigger and more awesome.
Speaker 1: Think about that.
Speaker 0: But adding more to the generic things that everyone can enjoy and not to just any one game.
Speaker 1: But why is one game different from two games in a space?
Speaker 0: Even two games.
Speaker 0: Every other area of PAX is dedicated to gaming.
Speaker 1: It's not arbitrary.
Speaker 1: One, unlike the Halo area, which was stupid because hardly anyone went in there.
Speaker 0: Well okay, so what if everyone had been cramming into the Halo area?
Speaker 0: Then it's okay?
Speaker 1: Yeah, because PAX is for everyone and a lot of people at PAX really like that.
Speaker 1: A lot did.
Speaker 1: And that space, think about how crowded PAX was already this year.
Speaker 1: If all those people had been elsewhere in the convention...
Speaker 0: They would not have been elsewhere.
Speaker 0: They would have been in that area.
Speaker 0: It just would have been, you know, something else in that area.
Speaker 0: And not an area dedicated to a single game.
Speaker 1: That area was just tightly packed chairs and then standing room.
Speaker 1: There is nothing that could have put that many people in that space.
Speaker 0: You could put things in that space.
Speaker 1: That would occupy that many people.
Speaker 0: It could have been another theater.
Speaker 0: We could have had even more panel programming.
Speaker 1: One, that's a terrible place for a theater.
Speaker 1: It's out in the open.
Speaker 0: No, but there was the place that was... There were other places that could... For example, the console freeplay could have been there.
Speaker 0: And then the current console freeplay could have been there.
Speaker 1: No, I went into console freeplay a ton of times throughout PAX.
Speaker 1: There were several PAXes.
Speaker 1: Not that popular anymore.
Speaker 0: Didn't need more space.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying.
Speaker 1: And I point out that, for all that too, people loved the League of Legends thing.
Speaker 1: The only people who complained about it were the people who equally suggest that the expo hall should have its own badge.
Speaker 0: Well, those are people that are crazy and stupid.
Speaker 0: Those are the same people.
Speaker 0: No, but...
Speaker 1: You're in league with them.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not in league with them.
Speaker 0: In league.
Speaker 0: No, you're pulling the thing that's like, "Oh, well you think, you know, this is wrong.
Speaker 0: So therefore, you know, you like abortion, therefore you must take
Speaker 0: taxes.".
Speaker 0: They have nothing to do with each other.
Speaker 1: They highly correlate, however.
Speaker 0: No, expo hall badge has nothing to do with League of Legends.
Speaker 0: You know, I do not think that you should dedicate a large amount of square footage to a single game in that way.
Speaker 0: And I'll show you, the way to do it right is, you may not have known this, Rym.
Speaker 0: But the world championships of Dota 2 were also at PAX.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But they were not in PAX.
Speaker 0: They were at Benaroya Hall down the road.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Because Valve said, "Why should we take up all this space at PAX and dedicate it to just our game one
Speaker 0: game?".
Speaker 0: Well, you think Valve, would they have rather had it at PAX?
Speaker 0: Considering, if you look at pictures of the Benaroya Hall, not too many fannies in the seats compared to the League of Legends area.
Speaker 0: But are you saying Dota 2 is less popular by that much?
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: I think it's because they weren't at PAX.
Speaker 1: No, well one, League of Legends has a much tighter...
Speaker 0: It was less visible and people didn't know to go there.
Speaker 1: No, independently League of Legends has a much tighter professional gaming structure around it.
Speaker 0: I think if you would swap them and move League of Legends to Benaroya Hall and put Dota 2 in that space, that the crowds sizes would have remained the same per space.
Speaker 1: No, because from what I see, the professional gaming fandom is not nearly as big and professional around Dota 2 as it is around League of Legends right now.
Speaker 0: I think the Dota 2 is much bigger than the League of Legends.
Speaker 1: No, as a game, yes, but not the professional gamer media culture.
Speaker 0: No, but on the internet, coming into PAX, the hype around the Dota 2 championship was much larger than the hype around League of Legends.
Speaker 1: See, I saw the exact opposite, so it's just anecdotes.
Speaker 0: And the Dota 1 was also the world championship and not just the North American finals.
Speaker 0: So it was even a bigger deal.
Speaker 1: And yet people seem to care about it less.
Speaker 0: It was only because it was in the PAX space that made it more crowded.
Speaker 0: If you had put the Dota 1 in the PAX space, it would have been just as packed as League of Legends 1 was.
Speaker 0: And if you put the League of Legends 1 in the Benaroya Hall, it would have been as packed as the Dota 1 was at this pack.
Speaker 1: I actually don't think so, I disagree with you.
Speaker 0: You think you're saying all those people would have gone down to Benaroya Hall and packed it in for League of Legends when they didn't pack it in for League of Legends?
Speaker 1: The reason I say this is that if you look at pictures from the Dota thing versus the League of Legends thing, the sheer number of League of Legends cosplayers is ridiculous.
Speaker 0: There are plenty of Dota cosplayers.
Speaker 0: The other thing is how can you even tell the fucking difference?
Speaker 0: because most of the characters are the same goddamn thing.
Speaker 1: Anyway, if anything, Scott, I think your distinction is arbitrary and silly.
Speaker 1: If I was going to remove something from PAX, I'd get rid of BYOC.
Speaker 0: I would not get rid of BYOC.
Speaker 1: If you ever go to BYOC, while it's cool for the idea, it's usually about half full because the people are off doing other stuff.
Speaker 1: It's just like private area people buy a special badge for.
Speaker 1: And most of the people in there are just fucking playing World of Warcraft or Solitaire or dicking around single player.
Speaker 1: It's really boring and chill and I would use that space for something different.
Speaker 1: I think BYOC doesn't have a useful purpose at PAX anymore.
Speaker 0: See, this is the thing I think we're on.
Speaker 0: BYOC is a specific culture, it's just not your culture.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's League of Legends.
Speaker 0: No, League of Legends is a single game.
Speaker 0: The MOBA is a culture, right?
Speaker 0: If you made that the generic MOBA arena, I would have much less a problem with it.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: Why do you have a problem with a single game having a big space?
Speaker 0: Because this is PAX, it is for all gamers.
Speaker 0: And yes, players of League of Legends are gamers, yes.
Speaker 0: But the amount of space, it is disproportionate.
Speaker 0: You should provide equally for all the different kinds of gamers.
Speaker 0: Scott, League of Legends had way less space.
Speaker 1: In fact, MOBAs as a total had way less space than, say, TableTop.
Speaker 0: I think, but that's the thing that's fucked up.
Speaker 0: If you look at the proportions, yeah, they had less space in total.
Speaker 0: But think about this, a single TableTop game, how much space did Settlers have compared to League of Legends?
Speaker 0: League of Legends had way more space than Settlers, which is just one game.
Speaker 0: And you know what, Settlers?
Speaker 1: Not that popular.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying.
Speaker 0: Okay, Dominion.
Speaker 0: How much space did Dominion have compared to...
Speaker 1: Probably more than half of TableTop.
Speaker 0: Compared to League of Legends.
Speaker 1: And why do you care?
Speaker 1: Who says that the games have to be represented in any equal proportion?
Speaker 0: I think there should be an equal representation of all gamer cultures at the get-together of gamers.
Speaker 0: that is the best get-together.
Speaker 1: Alright, one, I think that's silly.
Speaker 1: Two, why don't we have a big poker area?
Speaker 0: Because you don't want to marginalize any one subset of the gamer culture.
Speaker 0: What if you had the miniatures stuff, which was in the red line and had plenty of space.
Speaker 0: What if it was just like, "Nope, we hate miniatures guys, we can eat one tiny
Speaker 0: table.".
Speaker 0: Or what if it was like, "We love miniatures guys, we're gonna have this giant room, Warhammer
Speaker 0: only.".
Speaker 1: You know what, that'd be pretty cool if one year they had a big Warhammer area.
Speaker 0: Nope, and you try to bring your war machine in there and like, "Nope, this is Warhammer
Speaker 0: only.".
Speaker 1: But Scott, this was a spectacle.
Speaker 1: This was basically a big panel room the whole time, showing this competition.
Speaker 0: I don't like that.
Speaker 0: it was one game disproportionately taking up space.
Speaker 1: There's a crotchety and old manny about it.
Speaker 1: And your argument is ludicrous.
Speaker 0: If it had been Counter-Strike, I would have had the same complaint.
Speaker 1: Yes, I think your argument is ludicrous in light of the fact that no other type of event could have used that space as effectively.
Speaker 0: It would have been space that could have been used.
Speaker 1: For what?
Speaker 0: The tabletop that wasn't full?
Speaker 1: The console preplay that wasn't full?
Speaker 0: There's plenty of stuff at PAX, you can always have all kinds of gaming going on.
Speaker 1: They never get a big arcade because they don't have space.
Speaker 0: They could have had a big arcade, they just refused to.
Speaker 1: Because they have no good space for it, and PAX would destroy arcade machines.
Speaker 0: They have arcade machines there!
Speaker 1: Yeah, a tiny number in a tiny room, that's on purpose.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they should get friggin' man up and get a big ass arcade.
Speaker 1: They can afford it.
Speaker 1: Scott, the only reason it works at MAGFest is because not that many people go to MAGFest.
Speaker 0: You could have a big arcade that's proportionate to the number of people.
Speaker 1: No, you really can't.
Speaker 1: MAGFest has pretty much the biggest arcade you could have at a convention reasonably.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: Why couldn't you have a large arcade with all kinds of crazy games?
Speaker 1: Power concerns, money concerns, logistics.
Speaker 0: Yeah, how much do you think that friggin' League of Legends thing costs?
Speaker 1: Probably... not that much, actually.
Speaker 1: In fact, the cost of League of Legends things in terms of running it was probably mostly the labor.
Speaker 0: They can do anything they want, they have mad monies, they could have a mega awesome super arcade.
Speaker 1: Uh, Scott, who paid for all the League of Legends stuff?
Speaker 0: The League of Legends guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if PAX does an arcade, who pays for that?
Speaker 0: Whoever's got the arcade.
Speaker 1: Uh, no, you mean PAX.
Speaker 1: Why would I pay to bring my arcade to PAX?
Speaker 0: Make people put quarters in.
Speaker 1: Uh, no, it's free.
Speaker 0: Why does it have to be free?
Speaker 1: Because if it's not free, almost no one's gonna go over to it.
Speaker 1: MAGFest is free because otherwise people wouldn't put quarters in.
Speaker 0: I think if you had a giant Uber arcade that had a fucking everything, and you had to put quarters in, people would put quarters in.
Speaker 0: That's silly.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I just think you have this weird fixation on League of Legends and moments.
Speaker 0: It has nothing to do with League of Legends, I said!
Speaker 0: If it was Counter-Strike, if the whole area was Dominion only, I would have said, "That's fucked up, you have this one giant room that's Dominion
Speaker 0: only.".
Speaker 1: This was not the League of Legends only area in essence.
Speaker 1: What it really was, was the professional gaming area.
Speaker 0: And it so happens that MOBAs- If it was the professional gaming area, it should have switched between different professional gaming competitions.
Speaker 1: Scott, in the US, MOBAs are the only professional gaming area worth anything.
Speaker 0: No, there is plenty- what are you talking about?
Speaker 0: There is huge RTS, fighting games, and other FPS gaming.
Speaker 1: And they don't get nearly the press that the MOBAs are getting lately.
Speaker 0: At least, at this moment, there is plenty of professional gaming of all kinds.
Speaker 0: The RTSs are huge.
Speaker 1: And I think the MOBAs have a lot more momentum right now.
Speaker 0: At this exact moment, but there is huge professional gaming in many, many genres.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I'm saying, I think MOBAs are overshadowing all of them, and give it six months, and you're gonna see MOBAs dominating American professional gaming.
Speaker 0: No, there is professional gaming of all kinds that is all huge, all over the place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Settlers, giant tournament, not that huge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay, whatever.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: Alright, so let's go to other things that are different at PAX besides this thing that Rym is wrong about.
Speaker 1: The thing that Scott has a ridiculous obsession with.
Speaker 0: That thing that Rym can't get over.
Speaker 1: I just don't understand why you have such a bug up your butt about one professional thing that was super popular at PAX.
Speaker 0: It happened because you dedicated a large area of PAX to one thing.
Speaker 0: What if there was a whole area of PAX that was just... I think we've said the same thing over and over again a hundred times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you haven't changed your argument.
Speaker 0: What if you went to Otacon, and there was one gigantic room, and that room was the Evangelion-only room.
Speaker 1: That'd be cool.
Speaker 1: What, are they just marathoning Evangelion?
Speaker 0: It's the only thing that's in there that's Evangelion, and it's taking up this gigantic room, and that's all it is.
Speaker 0: There's no other animes in there or anything.
Speaker 1: Alright, so is that room completely packed for the entire count of people lining up trying to get in?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Then yeah, that's awesome.
Speaker 0: So, you got no problem with that?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: See, I think that's fucked up, because it's supposed to be an anime con.
Speaker 0: It's sort of fucked up to have one thing overrepresented in that way.
Speaker 1: You mean have one thing that's ridiculously popular represented to a relative proportion of its popularity?
Speaker 0: Yes, I think a convention is better when it equally services all of its subcultures, right?
Speaker 0: Because the idea of PAX is...
Speaker 1: Alright, Scott, so then Kineticon had better equally service the furries.
Speaker 0: It does equally service the furries.
Speaker 1: We had one furry panel.
Speaker 1: I denied all the rest.
Speaker 0: That is panel-wise, there is plenty of furry service at Kineticon in proportion to the number of furries who were there.
Speaker 1: How so?
Speaker 1: There's a lot of them there, actually.
Speaker 1: Way more than the relative panel content.
Speaker 0: Just panel content you're looking at.
Speaker 0: There is plenty of things at Kineticon for furries to do.
Speaker 0: They are very happy there and they come often and they are welcome.
Speaker 1: But they're not dedicated to furries.
Speaker 0: There are many things at Kineticon that are dedicated to furries.
Speaker 1: Alright, fine.
Speaker 1: Otakon.
Speaker 1: Huge furry culture.
Speaker 1: Basically nothing for them.
Speaker 0: There are things at Kineticon for furries.
Speaker 0: Only unofficial cosplay photos.
Speaker 0: There are plenty of things in the dealer's room in the artist alley.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: What in the dealer's room?
Speaker 0: There's plenty of people selling furry shit in the dealer's room.
Speaker 1: Also, what's in the dealer's room?
Speaker 1: That content is not run by the convention.
Speaker 0: It's still content.
Speaker 0: It's still a proportion of the convention is dedicated to the things that they want.
Speaker 1: Alright, so why aren't you mad that Firefall is this gigantic area in the expo hall?
Speaker 0: That's the expo hall.
Speaker 0: And the expo hall was not the Firefall hall.
Speaker 0: It was the expo hall.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the Firefall had this gigantic edifice inside of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they bought it.
Speaker 0: That was part of the expo hall.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so League of Legends bought that bit.
Speaker 1: Consider that part of the expo hall.
Speaker 1: Scott, that's just the annex of the expo hall.
Speaker 0: No, it's not part of the expo hall.
Speaker 0: It was the League of Legends area.
Speaker 1: Would you have had a problem if that was just in the expo hall?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: It was the League of Legends area in the expo hall?
Speaker 0: No, that would have been okay.
Speaker 1: But they're the same thing for all intents and purposes.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: It's a specialized separate area.
Speaker 0: It was not integrated in the expo hall next to all the other expo hall things.
Speaker 1: What if they just called it the expo hall annex and it was the League of Legends thing the whole time?
Speaker 0: See, did they enlarge the expo hall by a whole room just to give it to them?
Speaker 0: Or was it, "Here is this giant expo hall.
Speaker 0: They happen to buy a large piece of
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: That's the difference.
Speaker 1: Who cares?
Speaker 1: That intent doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: What matters is that it was super popular.
Speaker 0: Why can't you just get off this?
Speaker 1: Because you bring it up constantly.
Speaker 0: I brought it up once and you wouldn't let it go.
Speaker 0: And then we spent the whole pack show talking about this one thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we got it long enough.
Speaker 1: This isn't the pack show.
Speaker 1: It's that show and we'll call it a night.
Speaker 0: Okay, fine.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.