Speaker 0: It's Thursday, January 12th, 2012.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm Riff.
Speaker 1: You're going slowly for no reason.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we talk about Magfest 2012.
Speaker 1: Uh... Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, you know what?
Speaker 1: On Monday, we do not have to go to work.
Speaker 1: Do you know why?
Speaker 0: Uh, MLK Day?
Speaker 1: That is correct.
Speaker 1: You know that on the list of federal holidays, at least incredibly major holidays, that most people get days off for, right?
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Only two of them are days for specific human beings.
Speaker 1: There is Martin Luther King Day.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Well, Martin Luther King Jr.
Speaker 1: Day.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: And Columbus Day.
Speaker 0: We used to have... Now we have President's Day.
Speaker 1: President's Day is not for a specific person.
Speaker 0: I know, but it was two different people.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: But anyway... Uh... Martin Luther King is awesome.
Speaker 1: Columbus is a dick.
Speaker 1: We have a day for a really good person and a day for a really shitty person.
Speaker 1: So I was trying to think, well...
Speaker 0: Why don't we have a day for a middle-of-the-road person?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Here's the real question that came up at work.
Speaker 0: Why isn't there Norman Borlaug Day?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Here's the real question.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Can you come up with an American better than Martin Luther King, or even as good as, to replace the Columbus Day?
Speaker 0: Wow, my brain went through a gigantic list of people who were all disqualified for not actually being American.
Speaker 0: That's correct.
Speaker 0: Is Norman Borlaug American?
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: I don't actually know, and I feel stupid now.
Speaker 0: We're on both Wikipedia-ing.
Speaker 1: It says he was.
Speaker 0: Ah, we got it.
Speaker 0: That was easy.
Speaker 1: Find a third person.
Speaker 0: I already got... I got one.
Speaker 0: Goalpost.
Speaker 0: Can't move 'em.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, there's not many.
Speaker 0: Well, we got one, so why don't we switch?
Speaker 1: Americans are mostly shitty.
Speaker 0: No, we've had some good people, like, uh... I don't know, a lot of the founding founders.
Speaker 0: FDR?
Speaker 1: That was one that I thought of.
Speaker 0: FDR's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Hell, Teddy Roosevelt.
Speaker 1: I don't think Teddy Roosevelt deserves a day.
Speaker 0: Does he deserve it more or less than Christopher Columbus?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean, I deserve one more than Christopher Columbus.
Speaker 0: Thing is, you know, I'm down with the hate on Columbus, but at the same time, a lot of the bad stuff that happened as a result of him was not intentional on his part.
Speaker 1: Then why don't we have, say, I don't know, Leif Erikson Day?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Why don't we?
Speaker 1: Or Eric the Red Day?
Speaker 0: Possibly because there are a lot of Italian communities that actually lobby pretty heavily to keep Columbus Day celebrated in places that tried to stop celebrating it.
Speaker 1: We'll tell those Italian communities we're gonna change it to Marco Polo Day.
Speaker 0: Marco!
Speaker 0: So CES is happening, and nah.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Nah.
Speaker 1: There is nothing.
Speaker 1: Eh.
Speaker 1: Except... Except... I was looking, you know, 'cause it's tons of CES news, you can't avoid it, but you mostly just breeze past most of it 'cause it's almost useless completely.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we just had a nice talk in the forum about how most of this stuff is companies manufacturing a product and then trying to manufacture a demand for said product.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, that's how you have to do it, right?
Speaker 1: 'Cause the demand doesn't exist before you make it.
Speaker 0: Well, there is demand for things, but no one makes them.
Speaker 0: And actually, I wonder why some things don't get made sometimes.
Speaker 1: It's because, and I've said this a lot recently, but it seems to me, this is just... I don't want to take this on a tangent, so let me say this without a reply.
Speaker 1: Do not reply to what I'm going to say, and then I will do my news, right?
Speaker 1: I'll.
Speaker 1: If you look around the world these days, right?
Speaker 1: We talk about the 1%.
Speaker 0: Look around the world these days.
Speaker 1: All the companies have all the money.
Speaker 0: All the companies have all the money.
Speaker 1: Stop it.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: All the money is in all the bank accounts of the companies, not even the 1% people, the companies, right?
Speaker 1: Normal people have no monies.
Speaker 1: It's companies that have all the monies.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, Apple has billions in the bank.
Speaker 1: Google, billions in the bank, right?
Speaker 0: So most of the business is business to business.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: If you are a business and you want to make money, you should have businesses as your customers, not people, because you can get one customer that's a business and get a zillion dollars, or you can spend a lot of money on marketing and on crazy expense to get enough real people customers who each give you five bucks.
Speaker 0: That's why day job I'm in that business, because the B2B has its own acronym for a reason.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Actually, that's technically an initialism.
Speaker 1: Which is why even products that are consumer products these days, such as, you know, electronics, do more to serve other corporations, which will say pay for advertising on those products or such and such, than they do to serve the people buying those products.
Speaker 0: So anyway, to keep the tensions away, there was one cool thing at CES.
Speaker 1: There was one semi-cool thing at CES, or at least worthy of discussing, and that is Boxy Live TV.
Speaker 1: So what this is, is if you have a Boxy box, you can buy this thing for 50 bucks.
Speaker 1: I don't know why they didn't come out with a new Boxy box that has this integrated.
Speaker 1: They will.
Speaker 1: Maybe they will.
Speaker 0: Or maybe the Boxy box hardware is not selling well enough to be worth it.
Speaker 1: And it's a USB on one side and a coax on the other.
Speaker 1: So it's small, but it's a lot like a video capture card, but it's actually doesn't do plain old video capture.
Speaker 1: What you need to do is plug into it either an antenna for the air or clear q-cam, which is what I have, which is unencrypted cable TV.
Speaker 1: So it's just a TV tuner card with a USB, but Boxy provides an interface, the new version for this particular thing.
Speaker 1: So even though you'll be using, you know, just over-the-air TV, you don't interact with it in the same way.
Speaker 1: you interact with over-the-air TV, which is changing channels and whatnot.
Speaker 0: So here's the big question.
Speaker 1: You got the.
Speaker 1: you're basically using the Boxy awesome interface to watch over-the-air live television in an awesome way.
Speaker 0: So here's the big question live television.
Speaker 0: All right, I can see that.
Speaker 0: I mean, I, you know, maybe I want to watch the game, but does Boxy now automatically do DVR type stuff, which is I don't think so, which is like why not?
Speaker 1: Myth TV has done that for DVR stuff over a decade.
Speaker 0: I think it's literally 99% of the reason why I would want to use this because if I have a Boxy box or a computer plugged into my TV already, and I'm going to plug the coax into the same TV, why even bother putting it through the Boxy box if all I'm going to do is watch the live thing anyway?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm still trying to understand this.
Speaker 1: like Myth TV, right, has been around since, let's see, when was Myth TV created?
Speaker 1: In '02, started in April '02.
Speaker 1: So for 10 years, Myth TV has been a free DVR that you can install on any computer to turn it into a DVR.
Speaker 1: How come?
Speaker 1: no other product is doing this?
Speaker 1: Every DVR is either like one that comes with your cable or it's like, you know, freaking TiVo, which you had to pay a monthly fee or some nonsense.
Speaker 0: Well, you had to pay a monthly fee at least at one point.
Speaker 0: Why doesn't someone just sell-- It's got for the network information, so it actually had a list of all the shows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but why doesn't someone just pay, you know, just sell computers that already have Myth TV on them?
Speaker 0: Why doesn't someone?
Speaker 0: I'll tell you why.
Speaker 0: One, you'd probably get sued by media companies again.
Speaker 1: All you're selling is computers, which is legal to sell computers, and it's legal to sell Myth TV.
Speaker 0: Ah, so here's the thing.
Speaker 0: If I were making a device like that-- And Linux.
Speaker 0: The primary feature I'd introduce is straight-up automatic commercial blocking coupled with straight-up, you know, in case a commercial wasn't blocked by accident, the 30-second, minute, whatever sketch.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna distribute Myth TV's latest stable release on a stable Linux that it works on with hardware that I know it works with.
Speaker 0: Also, Myth TV is really hard for normal people to use.
Speaker 1: And Ponzi also, and a remote.
Speaker 0: And I would argue that the majority of the market who is capable of dealing with a DVR that doesn't hold their hands the entire way, 100%, is also the kind of person who is just pirating everything from Pirate Bay anyway.
Speaker 0: See, this is why-- Why even bother with the stupid broadcast TV?
Speaker 1: That's why, you know, people are worried, right?
Speaker 1: You know, a really killed Myth TV is piracy.
Speaker 1: Why should I bother DVRing shit on this download?
Speaker 0: Yup, even though they have the same effect, because do you really think that people don't just skip the commercials when they DVR something?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so BoxyLiveTV, like, good idea.
Speaker 1: But, A, it only works with BoxyBox.
Speaker 1: You can't use it with a PC running Boxy, even with the new version.
Speaker 0: Now, speaking of which, independent of that-- Two, it doesn't, you know, you can't, say, use encrypted cable.
Speaker 1: Like, if you take a cable, put it into your cable box, and then take a cable out of that, it won't work.
Speaker 1: It has to be unencrypted cable.
Speaker 1: And three, well, yeah, it's 50 bucks.
Speaker 1: It should be, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so this is cool, but I think it's a terrible product.
Speaker 1: I do-- The one thing, though, is it does put a good user interface on live TV.
Speaker 0: Does it really?
Speaker 0: What is the user interface?
Speaker 1: It looks like a TV guide, only using the Boxy remote.
Speaker 0: So where does it get the data?
Speaker 1: I don't know where it gets the data.
Speaker 1: Because TiVo, you-- No one's been discussing that.
Speaker 0: Pay for that data.
Speaker 1: I know, no one has been discussing where that data comes from.
Speaker 0: Maybe Boxy made a deal, and that's why it costs 50 bucks, but even
Speaker 1: then-- But it looks like Boxy, it has little preview screenshots of every show, it says what time they start, it says whether they're HD, lets you share what you're watching on Twitter, you know, and it's got everything.
Speaker 1: All the descriptions of all the shows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but does it let me save it in a, you know, nice format that I can then use to make a PMV?
Speaker 1: Uh, no.
Speaker 0: Ah, so it doesn't do anything I care about.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: So right along these lines, I just want to point out that there's this article, because CES, a whole bunch of manufacturers are talking about making smart TVs.
Speaker 1: And when they say smart TV, what they basically mean-- A TV that sort of already has Boxy in it without a Boxy box, but worse than Boxy.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna translate exactly what this is.
Speaker 0: They want to make TVs with really shit, slow-ass interfaces that let you see a tiny subset of the censored content on the internet in a painful, slow, and tedious way.
Speaker 0: that will not be used by anyone who has the skills to use a real computer hooked up to their TV, nor will it be used by anyone who doesn't have those skills, because they won't be able to figure this out either.
Speaker 0: And you know what, the TV I have now, really nice, gigantic TV.
Speaker 0: It has, like, Yahoo bullshit in it, and if I plug an ethernet cable into it, it says it can play videos.
Speaker 0: Fuck if I could get it to work.
Speaker 0: And I'm a senior, I'm a fighting professional.
Speaker 1: Well, you're a glorified clock setter.
Speaker 1: I'm surprised your TV tells good times.
Speaker 0: So I got a web browser to start, right?
Speaker 0: After, like, five minutes, it loaded.
Speaker 0: It was just that slow.
Speaker 1: I don't understand why these things, cable boxes, are the worst.
Speaker 1: It's like you push down, down, down, down, down, and down.
Speaker 1: It's like Boxxy, at least, is immediately responsive.
Speaker 1: You push the button, it goes d-d-d-d-d-d-d-d-d-d-d-d-d.
Speaker 0: So I tried to get it to stream some video from my NAS.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not playing an MKV, or an MP4, or, you know what, any fucking format that I have.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it was just completely useless.
Speaker 0: Outerly, absolutely useless.
Speaker 0: And I don't know, like, I don't think there's any market for this at all, because literally, I think, everyone who's smart enough to use something like this,
Speaker 1: Who out there has a whole bunch of videos that they want to watch on the TV that are in the format that TV's gonna play?
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 1: That he's gonna use it.
Speaker 0: And there's no way anyone will get the licensing agreements to sell a TV that actually will just play the formats that people typically have.
Speaker 0: And even then, there might be lawsuits about piracy, enablement, or whatever.
Speaker 0: And the interface is just, like, they're guaranteed to be crappy, because without a keyboard, you're not gonna be able to search for stuff.
Speaker 1: And Apple TV has a good user interface, but it can only play, like, Apple things.
Speaker 0: And even worse, let's talk about Boxxy.
Speaker 0: Boxxy has these little apps, right, that let you see content.
Speaker 0: I pretty much had to give up on using Boxxy for anything but anime that I happen to already have downloaded.
Speaker 0: Because it does that really well.
Speaker 1: I use it for the Crunchyroll app also.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much the anime app here.
Speaker 0: Ah, but the Crunchyroll app.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about the apps.
Speaker 0: Crunchyroll app.
Speaker 0: This is not a problem for me or Scott, because I know how to use the mute button on my TV remote.
Speaker 0: But I want to point out that if you watch a show and an ad comes on, you can't skip it, obviously.
Speaker 0: And they disable your volume control until the ad stops.
Speaker 1: Well, the app does that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: The app does that.
Speaker 0: But that's still bullshit.
Speaker 0: That angers me.
Speaker 0: So as a result, why don't I just watch it on the Crunchyroll website?
Speaker 1: Because on the Crunchyroll website, it's the same thing.
Speaker 1: Ad.
Speaker 1: And you're not gonna tell me that pushing the mute button in the Crunchyroll video player is more convenient than pushing the mute button on your TV remote.
Speaker 1: You're gonna do the same thing and have the same problem.
Speaker 0: I have to go find my TV remote every time, because in Boxee, I got the Boxee remote out, not the TV remote.
Speaker 0: The point of the Boxee remote was that I didn't need to also use the TV fucking remote.
Speaker 1: Well, I have, like, a bunch of remotes, and I gotta use the, you know, the remote from my speaker system.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, I have three remotes, and I have a Bluetooth keyboard and a USB keyboard.
Speaker 1: See, the thing is, if your problem is too many remotes, right, Boxee remote doesn't solve that problem.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Boxee remote solves the problem of I want a keyboard without having to have a keyboard.
Speaker 0: But Boxee remote doesn't have any way to do the mouse, so unless you're in Boxee, it's still pretty useless.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Boxee remote doesn't solve that problem.
Speaker 1: If the problem you want to solve, which is the problem of I have too many remotes, you have to get the Logitech Harmony.
Speaker 1: The Logitech Harmony is amazing.
Speaker 1: People don't know about this thing.
Speaker 1: Basically, it's a lot of setup in the beginning, right?
Speaker 1: You have to set it all up, and it might be too hard for people who aren't techy, but it should be, if you know how to set up your home theater yourself, you can set up the Logitech Harmony.
Speaker 1: And what you do is you program it to be like, okay, listen, if I want to watch a DVD, you gotta turn on the DVD player, you gotta put the TV on video 3, and you gotta turn on the receiver and set the receiver to audio input 4.
Speaker 1: And then you program all that, and then you push the DVD, after you program it, you push the DVD button on the Logitech Harmony, and it will turn off everything that's not the DVD player, turn on the DVD player, and set all those inputs, and you'll do it with one button press, because you programmed it.
Speaker 1: And then you'll be like, okay, if I want to do the Wii, you gotta set the receiver to audio 5, and set the TV to video 1, and you program that in, and you have a Wii button, you push the Wii button, and your TV's in Wii mode, it turns the DVD player off, turns the Wii on, all
Speaker 0: that stuff.
Speaker 0: So anyway, all the apps, the CollegeHumor app doesn't have all the CollegeHumor videos, it only has their originals.
Speaker 1: That's CollegeHumor's fault.
Speaker 0: No, it's the app's fault, alright, alright, it's the app's fault, again, I'll give it that.
Speaker 1: CollegeHumor could have made their app include everything.
Speaker 0: Let's get to that.
Speaker 0: The YouTube app, one, I can't close those pop-up ads.
Speaker 1: It's slower than using real YouTube.
Speaker 0: It's slower, and the search results are different.
Speaker 1: Well, that's because you're not logged in.
Speaker 0: No, even if I, yeah, so how do I log in?
Speaker 1: You don't.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You're logged into Boxee, you're not logged into YouTube.
Speaker 0: Again, that's the app's fault.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Communism didn't work so well as implemented by Russia, or China, or anyone in the world.
Speaker 0: But I guess it's just those implementations' fault.
Speaker 0: The idea must be sound.
Speaker 1: That's not the same thing.
Speaker 0: Just like Boxee.
Speaker 0: I find that Boxee is utterly useless to me compared to a web browser on the TV, because I just can't do stuff.
Speaker 0: And the Xbox, you think, all right, there's a YouTube thing in the Xbox.
Speaker 1: That's even worse than Boxee.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I really want to put together an expose, because I've done a bunch of side-by-side searches, and a shit ton of YouTube content is just missing if you use the Xbox 360.
Speaker 0: And it seems to align with certain companies' ownership of the stuff in the videos.
Speaker 0: Like, it's not just logged in, not logged in.
Speaker 0: There's something else going on there.
Speaker 1: How about Bidoof?
Speaker 1: Can you watch Bidoof?
Speaker 0: Oh my god, Bidoof.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 1: He's so angry that he can't watch Bidoof on Xbox.
Speaker 1: He's as angry as Bidoof.
Speaker 1: He's got a gun.
Speaker 1: He's shooting Microsoft.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Oh, now he's up in the cloud with your save games.
Speaker 0: All right, so I guess we should get on with the main thing, but I do want to talk about this, because it's kind of funny, but also sad.
Speaker 0: You know what they're doing to Kim Jong Il's body?
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: They're Lenin-ing him.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: There's going to be a Lenin body.
Speaker 1: That's what they did with his dad, too.
Speaker 0: Apparently, his dad's body is interred there, but isn't visible, according to this one article.
Speaker 1: What I heard is that the dad's body, they had to get this Russian dude.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they have Russian guys doing this one, too.
Speaker 1: He's like the most expensive dude, but he can get the job done to make it look kind of okay.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So they put him in his jumpsuit, and they put him in this thing, and he's sitting there with his little toes sticking up under a red sheet.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: We've done a bunch of PMVs and AMVs for things of the day over the years, so I think it's time for a PPGMV.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: This is a Powerpuff Girls music video set to Him, the best character.
Speaker 1: Him is the best.
Speaker 0: Him, aka Akio in transvestite lobster form, is pretty much everything I like about Powerpuff Girls, as horrifying as that is.
Speaker 1: I don't know why Him isn't in every episode.
Speaker 0: There's just something about Him.
Speaker 1: There's so many Mojo Jojo episodes, and I was like, "Yeah, he's not that
Speaker 1: great.".
Speaker 1: And then, it's like, "Well, Him should be the guy who's on all the episodes all the
Speaker 1: time.".
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that's my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: This is pretty funny.
Speaker 1: See, here's an awesome Flash game.
Speaker 1: It's called "Let's Play" colon "Ancient Greek
Speaker 1: Punishment.".
Speaker 0: Oh my God, do I get to be Sisyphus?
Speaker 1: You can be Sisyphus, Tantalus, Prometheus, Dunaides, or Zeno.
Speaker 0: Do you want to reveal what the deal with this game is, or let people play it?
Speaker 1: Well, you play out the ancient Greek tortures of these various ancient Greeks.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: So, play these games and let us know when you win.
Speaker 1: I'm filling the bath to wash away my sins.
Speaker 0: Here I go.
Speaker 0: How's that going for you?
Speaker 1: I got the water.
Speaker 1: I'm dumping it in the bath.
Speaker 1: All right, the bath is 20% full.
Speaker 1: I'm going back to get more water.
Speaker 1: Oh, the bath is full of holes.
Speaker 0: Try to push that rock up the hill.
Speaker 0: I heard that one's easier.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll try that one.
Speaker 1: Actually, the one where you got to scare the birds away from pecking away your liver.
Speaker 0: I could win that one with a drinking bird.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I guess the drinking bird would eventually falter.
Speaker 0: Also, drinking birds don't work unless they're dipping their beaks in some liquid.
Speaker 0: So, no.
Speaker 0: But, anyway.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Pretty good.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, the book club book is two books, which we'll be doing soon.
Speaker 1: Real soon.
Speaker 0: Real soon.
Speaker 1: Next week, probably.
Speaker 0: They're your books.
Speaker 1: Yup, it is.
Speaker 1: The Little Prince.
Speaker 0: By.
Speaker 1: Antoine de Saint-Ejupéry.
Speaker 1: And also, Wind, Sand, and Stars.
Speaker 1: Il sait magnifique.
Speaker 1: By the same person.
Speaker 0: They're amazing books.
Speaker 0: Straight up.
Speaker 0: I just got to tell you.
Speaker 0: You should read them.
Speaker 1: And short.
Speaker 1: Ish.
Speaker 0: They're really short.
Speaker 0: The Little Prince, you can read in, like.
Speaker 0: A couple hours.
Speaker 0: A half hour.
Speaker 0: If you read it, like, quickly, ten minutes.
Speaker 1: I don't know, ten minutes.
Speaker 0: You could read that book in ten minutes.
Speaker 0: I don't know, ten minutes.
Speaker 0: You might not grock it.
Speaker 1: Maybe, like, a couple hours.
Speaker 0: You could read all the words in, like, ten or fifteen minutes.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We are going to be at the Penny Arcade Expo East, doing stuff like we always do.
Speaker 0: And if you didn't buy a badge, well, you fought because it sold out.
Speaker 0: You should have bought it a long time ago, like we said.
Speaker 1: You can go to Anime Boston instead.
Speaker 1: It's not sold out.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And I'm going to advertise.
Speaker 0: I'm looking for a system administrator.
Speaker 0: Linux and Windows in New York.
Speaker 0: Email me.
Speaker 1: You know, we're still not getting paid for this.
Speaker 1: This is not cool.
Speaker 0: I'll give you a job.
Speaker 0: You want to work for me?
Speaker 0: I'm a cool guy.
Speaker 1: It's not cool.
Speaker 1: We still haven't.
Speaker 1: We need to discuss this.
Speaker 0: Or girl.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, conventions are off in the distance.
Speaker 1: Nerd NYC recesses this weekend.
Speaker 0: Yes, Nerd NYC recesses this weekend.
Speaker 0: Scott will not be there because he's a little baby and has laundry to do and hair to wash.
Speaker 1: Hey, what hair to wash?
Speaker 0: I will be there.
Speaker 0: On Saturday only.
Speaker 0: I will be running one game in the evening slot, which I already ran at Burning Apocalypse Con to accolades.
Speaker 0: And if you want to be in that game, well, good luck because there's only four slots and a lot of people want to be in that game.
Speaker 0: But I will play in some other games.
Speaker 0: I'll be there.
Speaker 0: I'll hang out.
Speaker 0: I'll say hi.
Speaker 1: It'll be cool.
Speaker 1: One other game because that's all you get at recess is two games.
Speaker 0: I think there's three games on Saturday.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I haven't read any of the stuff.
Speaker 0: I'm just going to show up.
Speaker 0: But anyway.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: That was pretty bad.
Speaker 0: I'm still hurt from Magfest.
Speaker 0: My throat is still not 100% back.
Speaker 1: So we went to Magfest X.
Speaker 0: We have been to two Magfests.
Speaker 0: Magfest is the third best gaming con there is.
Speaker 0: If you count both PAXes as one and you count Kineticon's gaming as its own con.
Speaker 1: What about Essen?
Speaker 0: I've never been to Essen, so it doesn't exist.
Speaker 1: That we've been to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that we've been to.
Speaker 1: Magfest, if you don't know, it's a four day, 24/7 music and gaming fest.
Speaker 1: Not only is there gaming of all kinds, there is music of all kinds.
Speaker 1: This is a con.
Speaker 1: Well, of gaming kinds.
Speaker 0: Where you go to a con and you have two full days of conning and then you realize when you wake up the next day, it's only Saturday.
Speaker 0: And you have two more full days of conning.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: A lot of people show up Wednesday.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, we showed up Thursday like early afternoon and there were already a lot of people there.
Speaker 0: We'd already missed a lot of gaming.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's only a kind of a few thousand people, like five, six, seven thousand, something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I heard that it was like six-ish thousand, which was a lot.
Speaker 0: It was like 80% more than last year because they were limited by the venue last year, which was this tiny little crap hotel in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: Now, they're in a weird venue.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's the Gaylord, which you've known about for a long time, but haven't been to yet.
Speaker 0: KazuKan is there now.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It is enormous, but not in the way that the BCEC is enormous.
Speaker 0: The BCEC, where PAX East is, is like a hangar for spaceships.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Or perhaps a spaceship.
Speaker 0: It is three gigantic, like gargantuan rooms and then a whole bunch of other stuff.
Speaker 0: The BCC is like a long city filled with all different kinds of spaces.
Speaker 0: The Gaylord can only be described as something wrought from corruption on a civic level, coupled with grand visions of a 90s convention center.
Speaker 1: It's such a weird place because it's so fake.
Speaker 0: It has a fake town around it and a fake town in it.
Speaker 1: It's so strange.
Speaker 0: We could do a whole show on this place that we were in.
Speaker 1: But this place had to be created with mad corrupt moneys from somewhere.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: The best we can say.
Speaker 1: If you look at it on Google Street View, you see it while it was still in construction, which is really strange.
Speaker 0: Once I get the video up from this con, you'll see what we mean.
Speaker 0: I don't want to dwell on it, but it was an odd place.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like if you took Roosevelt Island in New York City and put all the tourist places from New York, not the tourist attractions, like the real things like the Statue of Liberty, but all the kind of like shit-tier tourism like the South Street Seaport Mall and all those kind of like the TGI Fridays and stuff in Times Square and put
Speaker 1: all that.
Speaker 1: And a really crappy part of Disney World, not rides, but like a character breakfast and a scenic walkthrough with animatronics.
Speaker 0: You built a town just for that, multiplied it by corruption, and then let some commuters live there.
Speaker 0: It's weird, and I don't know what my opinion is of it.
Speaker 0: I don't know what to say anymore.
Speaker 0: And I don't want to review it.
Speaker 0: I want to review MagFest.
Speaker 0: But suffice it to say, if you go to MagFest next year or you go to Katsu-Con, you'll see what we mean.
Speaker 0: It was really weird how many people came to this place on Saturday, not for MagFest, not for any other convention that was going on at the same time, but literally just to like go around the town and eat at the restaurants and like go to the character breakfast.
Speaker 0: This was like a resort destination for some people.
Speaker 0: Very strange.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was weird.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So the bad things we had to say about MagFest are the same bad things we probably said the last time.
Speaker 0: Yes, when we review cons, we try to get everything bad we have to say out first.
Speaker 0: Do we?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: In the past, we'd go look and listen.
Speaker 0: No, we try.
Speaker 0: We forget.
Speaker 1: I haven't listened to our previous MagFest show from the MagFest 9, but I'm pretty sure we said the same things.
Speaker 0: No, one's coming off the list, but we'll get to that.
Speaker 1: All right, anyway.
Speaker 1: Reg still sucks.
Speaker 0: It was not nearly as bad as last year.
Speaker 0: But still sucks.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: The Reg situation at MagFest is unacceptable.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: In fact, we got to wait in the very short, like special line.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: It still took a while, like a half hour.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you need that line to be way shorter.
Speaker 0: Mail the badges.
Speaker 0: Just mail them, guys.
Speaker 0: You can do it.
Speaker 0: Mail them also.
Speaker 0: I will help you do it.
Speaker 0: Email me.
Speaker 0: I will personally help you do it.
Speaker 1: You could also just have, if you just had twice as many people doing the badge things and you shorten the process to where it was like, "Bam, here's your badge.
Speaker 1: Bam, here's your
Speaker 1: badge.".
Speaker 1: Then you'd be better.
Speaker 1: The one thing they did improve, though, from last year is.
Speaker 1: last year, it was like specific badges were pre-numbered for all the people.
Speaker 1: That was a disaster.
Speaker 1: So they had to find your badge.
Speaker 1: This year, it was just like, "Here's your fucking badge.
Speaker 1: It's just the next one in the
Speaker 1: pile.".
Speaker 1: And that sped things up a bit.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: But it's still major problems.
Speaker 0: Also, if the con grows at all, they're going to hit the Otacon situation of, "All right, we got 30,000 people.
Speaker 0: We got to give badges
Speaker 0: to.".
Speaker 1: They're also still doing legally questionable things like making you sign a waiver and checking your ID and putting a wristband on you, which other conventions do not do.
Speaker 0: Actually, a lot of tiny, small shit conventions do some of that stuff.
Speaker 1: Big conventions don't.
Speaker 1: So I'm saying, I've heard rumors, I don't know how true this is, that someone on the MAGFest staff is sort of a lawyer and that they do this stuff.
Speaker 1: But it's like, "Listen, you need to get a real lawyer.
Speaker 1: You have 7,000 people going to a big fancy hotel.
Speaker 1: Get a real lawyer to tell you what to
Speaker 1: do.".
Speaker 1: Because I'm pretty sure, I'm the lawyer, obviously.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we are not lawyers.
Speaker 1: We are not giving you legal advice.
Speaker 1: But based on my convention experience from other conventions, I'm pretty sure that's not what you do.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The waiver, for one, in my non-lawyer opinion, means nothing.
Speaker 0: You might as well hand them a piece of paper that says nothing on it and asking them to sign it.
Speaker 0: Two, this bracelet thing we talk about, when you register, they take your ID.
Speaker 0: And when I say they, I mean just some con staffer.
Speaker 0: And they put on you either a different colored wristband you're supposed to wear the whole weekend, that designates whether or not you're 18 and/or 21.
Speaker 0: The goal is so that people who do room parties don't have to worry about IDs for drinking and that no statutory rape occurs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm pretty sure that by doing an ID check, that the con is now responsible if the wristbands get switched up, which is trivial for them to be.
Speaker 0: Also, the staffer, you know, I refuse to put on the wristband.
Speaker 1: I also refuse to put on the wristband.
Speaker 0: And the staffer gave me shit, but you know what?
Speaker 0: One, I'm not wearing a wristband for the whole con, especially if it has no function.
Speaker 1: Especially if it's mad uncomfortable.
Speaker 0: And it has no function in the con itself.
Speaker 0: And that is totally a lawsuit waiting to happen.
Speaker 0: MagFest, I love you.
Speaker 0: I don't want you to get sued.
Speaker 0: Do not offer this service.
Speaker 0: I agree, it's an awesome service.
Speaker 0: I love the fact that when people came to our room party we were hanging out in, one guy had a blue wristband, so we were like, yeah dude, sorry, not giving you any beer.
Speaker 0: But, uh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Legally.
Speaker 1: That dude could have easily swapped that wristband for a green one if he wanted.
Speaker 0: Yes, and we probably could have gone after you if we'd gotten in trouble for that.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: So, while it's all cool, and I applaud the idea as being an awesome idea in practice, fucking don't do it.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Secondly, they have a major problem with Securitad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they, this year, they had, now it's interesting because this is a complaint we have about most conventions we go to in that they really don't know how to handle the fact that people will try to steal their stuff from their arcades or whatever.
Speaker 1: It's really easy.
Speaker 1: Everything's bolted down.
Speaker 1: The end.
Speaker 1: That way no one can take it.
Speaker 0: So what MagFest did this year is if you went into the main hall, which was tabletop, vending, arcade, and consoles all in one area, so pretty much 90% of the con.
Speaker 1: The whole con, except for concerts.
Speaker 0: If you walked in with any bag, they demanded to search your bag.
Speaker 0: And if you had a laptop or anything like that?
Speaker 1: Well, it was weird.
Speaker 1: It's like if you walked in there with any sort of electronic thing, they wanted to check it into their system and put a barcode on your bag.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're not putting a sticker on my laptop, dude.
Speaker 1: Yeah, screw you.
Speaker 1: It's not happening.
Speaker 0: And then on the way out, they would search your bag and give you shit if you had a laptop.
Speaker 0: And it was just a disaster waiting to happen on so many fronts.
Speaker 1: I would purposely go down there without anything.
Speaker 1: I never brought my laptop in there or anything so I could avoid being searched.
Speaker 1: And half the time when I walked out of the room, they wanted to look at my stuff.
Speaker 1: And when they looked, they just glanced.
Speaker 1: They didn't really look.
Speaker 0: So it basically, it annoyed everyone.
Speaker 1: So it just annoyed me for no reason.
Speaker 1: And half the time, they didn't even ask to look.
Speaker 1: I just managed to sneak out without getting looked at.
Speaker 1: And then it was like, well, if you're going to let people sneak out, why even bother?
Speaker 0: It was a giant pain.
Speaker 1: Just don't do it.
Speaker 0: Two, well three, I guess the final thing, which is kind of part and parcel of this, is that they kind of made up rules inconsistently throughout the con.
Speaker 0: All con, I would go out and buy a Starbucks in the convention and then take it back into tabletop.
Speaker 0: And at one point on Saturday, I came back with a coffee I'd just bought.
Speaker 0: And they're like, you can't bring that in here.
Speaker 0: No open containers.
Speaker 0: Out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: And they made me throw it away before they let me in.
Speaker 1: We had been eating and drinking in there the whole con, by the way.
Speaker 0: And they claimed it was because they didn't want me to spill something on the consoles, even though I was going to tabletop.
Speaker 0: But two, while I was being, they demanded I throw away my coffee, a guy walked in with like three Subway sandwiches and three Subway drinks, and the same person let him go right through.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: So seriously, guys.
Speaker 1: Here's my suggestion to you, Magfest.
Speaker 1: The only thing you have to worry about, right, is your console stuff being stolen.
Speaker 1: No one's going to steal an arcade machine, right?
Speaker 1: The dealers can protect their own shit, as long as you have security walking around.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem.
Speaker 0: The dealer area is in the rest of the con shared space, so they can't just lock the room at the end of the night.
Speaker 0: They need to really put the dealers in a separate area.
Speaker 1: Well, that's definitely true.
Speaker 0: But that's just, they need to get bigger.
Speaker 0: They obviously couldn't get the space for them.
Speaker 0: They can grow organically.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the point is, it seemed like Magfest was worrying about attendees stealing other attendees' things, and it's like, Magfest, don't worry about that.
Speaker 1: Attendees are going to have their shit stolen if they're stupid, and that's their problem.
Speaker 1: It's not your problem.
Speaker 1: Just be like, well, tough shit, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you didn't protect your shit.
Speaker 0: But the moment you try to help, the moment you try to do the right thing, you think it's cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're going to protect everyone's stuff.
Speaker 0: Just like, yeah, we're going to try to make sure that underage kids don't drink.
Speaker 1: All you're doing is pissing off people like us with hassling us.
Speaker 0: Well, more importantly, again, one could argue that you are assuming liability if something does get stolen.
Speaker 1: But we're not lawyers.
Speaker 0: Even though you have this fake waiver that probably, in our non-lawyer opinion, doesn't mean anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all you got to do is protect your own console equipment by bolting it the fuck down, right?
Speaker 1: And if you got wireless shit, you need someone standing there taking care of it.
Speaker 0: They didn't protect any of the tabletop stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean, I walked in with like 15 games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they didn't even have a tabletop checkout.
Speaker 1: Heels was like, oh my god, this tabletop is just games on a table with no one protecting it on total honor system, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, I walked in and out with board games all night.
Speaker 0: One time.
Speaker 1: Nobody was checking to see if those board games I was walking out with belonged to the library or were mine.
Speaker 0: One time, someone stopped me and said, are those all yours?
Speaker 0: And I was like, yes.
Speaker 0: And I just kept walking.
Speaker 0: And I think he tried to stop me, but I just kept going.
Speaker 0: And they were all mine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like, yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay, so guys, here's the cool thing.
Speaker 0: That is literally every complaint I have about MagFest.
Speaker 1: Everything about MagFest on the net is the awesomest.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, MagFest was one of the best cons I've been to since PAX.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, playing games until five in the morning.
Speaker 1: Dude, guys.
Speaker 1: Then waking up to do a panel at 10 in the morning.
Speaker 1: On Thursday.
Speaker 1: A super art fight.
Speaker 0: On Thursday, a little after midnight, we sat down to learn and then play Eclipse.
Speaker 1: Well, some of us already knew how to play.
Speaker 0: I didn't know how to play.
Speaker 0: At 5am, we ended that game.
Speaker 0: I was victorious.
Speaker 0: And then, at 10.30am, we did a panel.
Speaker 1: Eclipse is fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: We talked about that on Tuesday.
Speaker 0: So here, let's talk about MagFest.
Speaker 0: We can obviously, if you want to know the vibe or what MagFest is like and all that, you can listen to our previous episode on MagFest.
Speaker 0: Because really, almost none of that changed.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: It's the same vibe, same culture, same people, same arcade.
Speaker 0: All that same stuff is just as awesome, if not more awesome, than it was last year.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about what's different.
Speaker 0: One.
Speaker 1: More space, which means that there was no B.O.
Speaker 1: smell.
Speaker 0: Yeah, last year, the B.O.
Speaker 0: problem was out of control.
Speaker 0: This year?
Speaker 1: I got a B.O.
Speaker 1: problem.
Speaker 1: This year.
Speaker 1: I got a B.O.
Speaker 1: problem here.
Speaker 0: There was effectively no B.O.
Speaker 0: other than the occasional fat guy walking by me.
Speaker 1: I don't think the problem was different people.
Speaker 1: I think there was still B.O.
Speaker 1: people.
Speaker 1: I think it was just simply that there was so much space and so much air and so much ventilation.
Speaker 1: Dude, the ceilings were like 30 feet high.
Speaker 0: The B.O.
Speaker 0: would go up there.
Speaker 1: There was no way you were going to smell the B.O Unless you were like, even at the DDR machine, you weren't going to smell it.
Speaker 0: That was crazy.
Speaker 0: There were a ton of DDR and Bemani machines.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: I wanted to play DDR and there were people playing DDR continuously all night.
Speaker 0: Even Thursday.
Speaker 0: All night.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 1: You can go 3
Speaker 1: a.m.,
Speaker 1: DDR.
Speaker 0: Even when the dude in the fursuit was doing 8 and 9 foot maniac songs on the machine, there was no B.O.
Speaker 0: smell anywhere.
Speaker 0: I was kind of amazed.
Speaker 0: Because I'd go to an arcade and there'd be B.O.
Speaker 0: at the DDR machine.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure there was B.O.
Speaker 1: smell in the fursuit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it didn't get out and it's all I care about.
Speaker 0: It's all I care about.
Speaker 1: They had some awesome games.
Speaker 1: They had Initial D3, which is the one I've played the most, which is good.
Speaker 1: 6 is better.
Speaker 0: 5 is better.
Speaker 0: 4 is better.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I sat down and played it.
Speaker 0: 3 is enough.
Speaker 0: That'll do, pig.
Speaker 1: 3 is still pretty fucking great.
Speaker 1: I can't imagine.
Speaker 1: I've played 4 a couple times.
Speaker 1: 5 and 6, I can't even imagine how awesome they are.
Speaker 0: They had 2 X-Men machines instead of 1 this year.
Speaker 0: One didn't work.
Speaker 0: They got it fixed at one point.
Speaker 0: Did they?
Speaker 0: I think it broke again.
Speaker 1: The pinballs they had were great, but there were people playing them the whole time.
Speaker 1: You'd wait in such line to get pinball going on.
Speaker 0: You had to wait to play DDR and Initial D the whole time, too.
Speaker 0: Except Thursday.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: I played all the Initial D I could on Thursday.
Speaker 1: They had 2 magical drops in Neo Geos, actually.
Speaker 0: They had 2 Dig Dugs side by side, 2 ice cold beers side by side.
Speaker 0: The arcade was the best.
Speaker 1: One of the ice cold beers didn't really work.
Speaker 1: But it only was missing Rampart.
Speaker 0: So last year...
Speaker 1: Only Rampart or Initial D 4, 5, 6 could have improved that arcade.
Speaker 0: Last year I mused...
Speaker 1: And more pinball.
Speaker 0: How come PAX has a crap arcade compared to Magfest?
Speaker 0: And this year I realized why.
Speaker 0: The machines failed and broke at a surprising... Not a surprising, but a pretty good rate relative to the number of people playing them at this con.
Speaker 0: And they had people fixing them constantly, but you could see...
Speaker 1: They got ahead of the game.
Speaker 1: Because the problem is they were basically still sort of setting them up when we got there on Thursday, right?
Speaker 1: They didn't have them completely set up and all repaired when the con started.
Speaker 1: So even though the con started, they're still getting some of them up to working that weren't working on arrival.
Speaker 0: So Magfest, let's say it had 6,000 people.
Speaker 1: It's like they didn't start out at 100% working.
Speaker 1: They started out at like 67% working and they had to build up as they were using them.
Speaker 0: Let's say Magfest had 6,000 uniques.
Speaker 0: Let's just say.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: A PAX has what?
Speaker 0: 15 to 20,000 uniques?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they would need like 4 Magfest arcades or else all the machines would fail.
Speaker 1: Here's the solution.
Speaker 1: You ready for my...
Speaker 0: Four arcades?
Speaker 1: I got a few solutions.
Speaker 0: Fill that third empty hangar with an arcade?
Speaker 1: Here's my solutions.
Speaker 1: Ready?
Speaker 1: Number one, you have so many games that even if everyone's using them like crazy...
Speaker 0: Pinkie Pie, that's a lot of games.
Speaker 1: That is.
Speaker 1: Solution number two, get a lot of guys.
Speaker 1: Because remember, if you're getting that many games, you're bringing in Videotopia and the ACAM and the Retro...
Speaker 0: That's what I say.
Speaker 0: You bring in multiple groups and set up...
Speaker 1: And they're basically, you're bringing in Pinball Joe.
Speaker 1: You're bringing in everyone and all they've got, they're bringing their whole crews.
Speaker 1: You have enough people who can fix the machines all at once.
Speaker 0: And PAX has the money to pay for that, I think.
Speaker 1: And some of the machines are really durable.
Speaker 1: Your Dig Dug's not going to go down.
Speaker 1: Only your ice cold beer and your pinballs are going to go down.
Speaker 1: Anyway, number three.
Speaker 1: Every machine, at least, will be free except the really popular ones.
Speaker 1: Set them on 25 cents mode and all the money goes.
Speaker 1: child's play.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: If it's a machine that's not really getting played, make it free.
Speaker 1: But the machines that are getting played like crazy, you don't need to make Dig Dug 25 cents.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's bullshit, right?
Speaker 1: But, DDR, 25 cents.
Speaker 1: Initial D, 25 cents.
Speaker 0: I'm used to paying a dollar for Initial D, gladly.
Speaker 1: Street Fighter 2, free.
Speaker 1: Super Street Fighter 4, whatever, Turbo, Hundreds, whatever, 25 cents.
Speaker 1: No more than 25 cents, obviously.
Speaker 1: But 25 cents.
Speaker 0: What about Fatal Fury?
Speaker 1: And then, those games, a guy will have to go around collecting the quarters, so he'll make sure the games are still working in good condition when he goes to get the quarters.
Speaker 0: I wonder if there might be legal stuff around that, but anyway.
Speaker 1: What, having an arcade that charges a quarter?
Speaker 1: Is it totally legal?
Speaker 0: No, because venue licenses, it gets complicated when you do that.
Speaker 0: The moment you go from providing it for free to paying for it, there are legal questions.
Speaker 1: Just an idea.
Speaker 1: You just need some of these.
Speaker 1: These are just some ideas to make sure it goes.
Speaker 0: But this isn't the Pac Show.
Speaker 0: It's the MagFest Show.
Speaker 1: Also, bring a bunch of replacement joysticks and buttons and all that other good stuff.
Speaker 0: So, another new thing.
Speaker 1: Also, set up the arcade a day in advance so it's 100% working.
Speaker 0: They don't have the resources for that.
Speaker 1: At the start of the convention.
Speaker 0: Anyway, different thing number two.
Speaker 0: They had actual panel rooms that actually had enough seats for everybody.
Speaker 1: And the convention center was very good about candy and water and all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: That was a separate thing.
Speaker 0: I was talking about just the panel rooms.
Speaker 0: It's part of panels.
Speaker 0: You need water.
Speaker 0: I was going to talk about the venue separately, because I talked a lot to the convention center staff.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: So, the panel rooms were good.
Speaker 0: Only one room had a jank as broken projector.
Speaker 0: Which was good, because it let us cut down on the demoing and get to the actual discussion.
Speaker 1: It seemed like their systems were good and working, but it didn't seem like they had enough microphones and they were moving them around a bit.
Speaker 0: Which was fine, because we're loud.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't even use microphones the whole panel time.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So we did Beyond D&D, which we rewrote for like the fourth time, and it went really, really well.
Speaker 0: It's a good Beyond D&D.
Speaker 0: It amazes me though, MagFest is weird.
Speaker 0: It's a con where it's a lot of hardcore gamers who, as far as I can tell, have never read the internet about gaming.
Speaker 0: Like, they have never heard of any of the stuff we talk about.
Speaker 0: And one of the gaming intellectuals panels we were on, a guy was like, "I'm going to demo this crazy
Speaker 0: game.".
Speaker 0: And we had someone play the game.
Speaker 0: It was VVVVVVV.
Speaker 0: The majority of the people in the room had never heard of it or seen it.
Speaker 0: So I was like,
Speaker 0: "What?".
Speaker 1: It's on Steam, guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was like, "Really?
Speaker 0: What?".
Speaker 0: I didn't really play it a lot, but I knew about it.
Speaker 0: At one point, I was like, "Yeah, so you've all played Binding of Isaac,
Speaker 0: right?".
Speaker 0: Like, nobody had.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Nobody.
Speaker 1: This is why you need to listen to Geek Nights, so that you will be taken into the future.
Speaker 1: Dude, you listen to Geek Nights?
Speaker 1: We're basically living in the future.
Speaker 0: And you go to MagFest, you will be a god.
Speaker 0: You'll walk around and be like, "Hey, you want to play this game called Burning
Speaker 0: Wheel?"
Speaker 0: And you will amaze people.
Speaker 0: Hell, you could be like, "Hey, you want to play Settlers of
Speaker 0: Catan?".
Speaker 0: And a lot of people will be like, "Oh my god,
Speaker 0: wow.".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: The tabletop library at MagFest is kind of sad.
Speaker 1: That's why you got to bring your own.
Speaker 0: It was okay.
Speaker 0: There were a lot of good games there.
Speaker 1: But people love to play games there.
Speaker 1: So if you bring your own games, it's totally awesome.
Speaker 0: They had a good mix of really weird old games.
Speaker 1: I guess what it is is they have pretty much one of each of the standbys.
Speaker 1: They had two power grids in Agricola, a bunch of Settlers, a Carcassonne.
Speaker 0: Three Puerto Ricos.
Speaker 1: Right, some Puerto Ricos.
Speaker 1: So it's pretty much like, "Well, we don't need
Speaker 1: any.".
Speaker 0: They had all the Dominions.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: They had one of every Dominion set.
Speaker 1: So it's like, it's not so exciting to us.
Speaker 0: But they had like old Candyland and like crazy weird... They had the old Battle Star Galactica and this weird Astro Boy game.
Speaker 0: It was more like a lot of people played Candyland.
Speaker 0: You know why?
Speaker 0: They'd probably never actually played Candyland before.
Speaker 0: And there's something fun about playing a weird, crappy game at a con drunk at 5 a.m.
Speaker 0: with four strangers.
Speaker 1: I saw people playing Monopoly.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But it was a pretty meager library.
Speaker 1: But they had, you know, the basics.
Speaker 1: The staples.
Speaker 0: It was pretty good though.
Speaker 1: It was okay.
Speaker 1: Bring your own tabletop games to MAGFest.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about panels a little bit.
Speaker 0: MAGFest has a weird panel culture.
Speaker 0: Partly because I think the con grew out of kind of its own culture.
Speaker 0: Kind of like how PEX grew out of Necro Womacon and its own culture.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, Katsucon, Otacon, Anime Boston, all these kind of like standby cons.
Speaker 0: Or like all the gaming cons or generic con and everything.
Speaker 0: They grew out of a sort of shared culture.
Speaker 0: so they kind of do things the standard way.
Speaker 0: The panels culture at MAGFest is really weird.
Speaker 0: People in the audience just like shout stuff and just say things.
Speaker 0: They'll be like, they want to just like interact.
Speaker 0: Like they want to just talk to you.
Speaker 0: And for the discussion panels it was fine because we have a moderator.
Speaker 0: And the audience like raised their hand and wanted to say something.
Speaker 0: But, you know, we did Beyond D&D, a straight up lecture.
Speaker 0: And half the audience kept like raising their hand.
Speaker 0: They didn't yell stuff out, they just raised their hand.
Speaker 0: And we ignored them because that's what we do.
Speaker 0: We don't engage with the audience.
Speaker 0: They kept their hands up the whole hour.
Speaker 0: One girl, I felt bad for, she raised her hand, raised her hand, raised her hand.
Speaker 0: Switched to the other hand, started holding it up with the other hand at the elbow.
Speaker 0: It's like, look, if it's not obvious...
Speaker 1: One guy even opened his mouth, he's like, can I say... I'm like, no.
Speaker 1: All I said was no and just kept going.
Speaker 0: But after that, you know what he did?
Speaker 0: Raised his hand.
Speaker 1: Well, this other guy raised his hand and it's like.
Speaker 1: he didn't realize that we weren't going to address anyone in the audience at any time for the entire panel.
Speaker 1: We didn't address a single person, but he thought somehow we were going to address him.
Speaker 0: But anyway, we got video of all the panels and lectures we were on.
Speaker 0: And we're going to get them on YouTube as soon as I can edit them together.
Speaker 0: And that's it.
Speaker 0: They were really fun.
Speaker 0: They were really interesting.
Speaker 0: I think my favorite one was.
Speaker 0: it was me, Scott, and Dr.
Speaker 0: Hazard just talking about like monetization models of games for an hour.
Speaker 1: And going off on tangents that were off topic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it was way fun because I really like talking to him.
Speaker 0: And we didn't get to see him and talk to him for more than like two minutes for the whole con.
Speaker 0: So the first time we see him to actually talk to him is on this panel.
Speaker 0: So it was just us and him talking to each other in front of an audience for an hour.
Speaker 0: It was great.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Ran into a lot of awesome people.
Speaker 0: John St.
Speaker 0: John was there.
Speaker 0: We didn't even get to say hi.
Speaker 0: But yeah, dude.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he did his thing.
Speaker 1: You know, I've been to two MAGFES so far.
Speaker 1: I still haven't seen James Rolfe, not even from far away.
Speaker 1: I saw a line to see him, but I didn't see him through that line.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The last time I talked to him was when I invited him to be on our failed late show attempt at PAX.
Speaker 0: And then the follow up email when he was like, "Yeah, I'm not going to be at
Speaker 0: PAX.".
Speaker 0: I was like, "Oh, that's fine.
Speaker 0: We just flew someone else in.
Speaker 0: We'll see
Speaker 0: him.".
Speaker 1: He was at the last PAX, I think.
Speaker 1: Because he made a video about it.
Speaker 0: For whatever reason, we didn't get a chance to talk to him.
Speaker 0: I think we had a panel at the same time.
Speaker 0: His panel?
Speaker 0: I forget.
Speaker 1: I don't even know anymore.
Speaker 0: Something came.
Speaker 0: There was a reason why we didn't go talk to him.
Speaker 1: Biggest fan of this guy, but we never see this guy.
Speaker 0: I know, and it's weird.
Speaker 0: We're in the same circles.
Speaker 0: He lives kind of near some people we know, and there's parties where people have been.
Speaker 1: He's at the same conventions we're at.
Speaker 0: Yep, we're both doing lectures and speaker stuff.
Speaker 0: But it's like, for all this overlap, we never talk.
Speaker 0: Kind of like how we know Dave Riley and Joel, but yet we never see them physically.
Speaker 0: We only talk to them on the inner tubes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, that's how it goes.
Speaker 0: Even though Dave's right there, like in Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: He didn't go to our New Year's party.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about the venue from a convention perspective.
Speaker 0: It's technically in Maryland, which is the same place that Otacon is at with the BCC.
Speaker 0: The convention center staff, not the con staff, the convention center and the hotel, was brilliant.
Speaker 0: They were so competent and cool and collected.
Speaker 0: I was amazed how professional they were.
Speaker 1: They're getting paid with mad crab monies.
Speaker 0: Compared to the disastrous staff at the BCC.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like Otacon.
Speaker 1: Well, there's nothing wrong with Maryland, right?
Speaker 1: It's Baltimore.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's a problem.
Speaker 0: But it's sad because, you know, half my complaints about Otacon are actually complaints with the BCC staff.
Speaker 0: And Baltimore.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: And the security people they get.
Speaker 0: There's nothing Otacon can do about that.
Speaker 0: I know the deal.
Speaker 1: I know the red shirts, the brown shirts, the green shirts, the yellow shirts.
Speaker 1: No, they can't.
Speaker 1: Yes, they can.
Speaker 0: No, because in the BCC, with the union rules and whatever, so they can choose from a number of vendors of security.
Speaker 0: And as far as I can tell, they're all actually the same.
Speaker 1: You can pay a whole lot more money to get out of that.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you can at the BCC.
Speaker 1: There is always a way to pay money to get a different term on your contract.
Speaker 1: Not always.
Speaker 1: Because basically what you'd have to do is you'd have to pay that union as much as you would if they worked, then not have them work and instead also pay, say, Blackwater to come and do the security.
Speaker 0: Okay, yes.
Speaker 0: There is a ludicrous and infeasible way.
Speaker 1: I said, I didn't say there was, I wasn't saying it was a feasible way.
Speaker 1: I said there was a way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, if you can't get a badge to PAX, you could just found your own convention just as good as PAX and run it just for you.
Speaker 1: That's feasible.
Speaker 1: Yes, you could.
Speaker 1: There is an amount of money you could actually pay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what, Scott?
Speaker 0: There is.
Speaker 0: It's called magfest.
Speaker 1: It's like, if I had enough money, I could just start a PAX and set the whole thing up and get the whole thing going and do all the work.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, I could, and Robert Coop, like, Hey, what are you doing?
Speaker 1: I'd be like, I'm paying you to show up at this.
Speaker 1: He's like, really?
Speaker 1: I'm like, yes.
Speaker 1: How much?
Speaker 1: A zillion.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: There's PAX three now, I guess.
Speaker 1: Cause Scott did it with a zillion dollars.
Speaker 1: It could happen if you had a zillion.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the convention center staff were scary, like in a good way.
Speaker 0: And I talked to a lot of them and they basically.
Speaker 1: I talked to a lot of people who were in the town and I was like, so what's up with this fake ass town?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the one girl I talked to was like, fuck if I know, I just work here.
Speaker 1: This place is weird.
Speaker 1: I was like, you live in this fake ass place?
Speaker 0: She's like, fuck now.
Speaker 1: I was like, no, I live outside.
Speaker 1: I don't live here.
Speaker 1: Cause there are weird apartments in there and stuff.
Speaker 0: And people live there.
Speaker 1: Frightening.
Speaker 0: But, uh, the, the venue is like enormous.
Speaker 0: Otacon could fit in there.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 0: The, the, what the trouble is, I didn't see all the space.
Speaker 0: Like I know every nook and cranny of the BCC.
Speaker 1: There was more space, but yeah, we weren't, there wasn't as nearly as many spaces.
Speaker 0: Granted, Scott, I went like into some of the service corridors and I got into some of the other space.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of different spaces in that convention center that were untapped.
Speaker 1: There were many untapped spaces, but not nearly as much as the BCC.
Speaker 0: Well, it's hard to say if it would be a suitable, like viable alternative and I have to figure that out, but to figure that out, I would have to actually like, you know, talk to the convention center and walk around it for real.
Speaker 0: But it's pretty big.
Speaker 0: MagFest has a lot of room to grow.
Speaker 0: They will run into problems other than filling the space long before they fill the space.
Speaker 1: Oh, I figured out where the corrupt monies came from.
Speaker 0: Oh, will we?
Speaker 1: The convention center hosted the 2011 Republican National Committee winter meeting at which the 2011 Republican National Committee chairmanship election took place.
Speaker 0: Duly noted.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: It opened in '08.
Speaker 1: Oh, so maybe the corruption came in in '08.
Speaker 1: It cost eight hundred and seventy million dollars to build.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 0: The one they want to build in New York is going to start at, what, a billion?
Speaker 1: So, yeah, that's so corrupt also.
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 1: I kind of don't care because it serves, even though it's not.
Speaker 0: If the biggest convention center in North America happens to be on the same subway line I live on, I am not going to complain.
Speaker 1: No matter how corrupt or evil or harmful it may be, for those five conventions a year I'll go to it for, probably, because you'll see all the conventions will move to it out of the Javits.
Speaker 1: I'll be going to New York Comic Con there, though probably someone will start another con there.
Speaker 1: That'll be awesome.
Speaker 1: Maybe the PAX will be there once it's out of Boston.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: But, yeah.
Speaker 0: So, what else can we say about MAGFest other than stuff that we said in the previous show about MAGFest?
Speaker 0: You should go to it.
Speaker 0: It's really fun?
Speaker 1: We still didn't go to the concerts just because you were gaming like crazy.
Speaker 0: But Nobu was there with Earthbound Poppas.
Speaker 1: And you can see it all on YouTube and he was awesome.
Speaker 0: The whole thing's on YouTube.
Speaker 0: He did the Colossus Roar.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Some other band, I think it was Bit Something, I forget their name, they had a guy play Mega Man 2 all the way through and they played the music during the whole thing.
Speaker 0: There was, and I do want to bring this up because you could not avoid it, a lot of My Little Pony at this con.
Speaker 1: There was indeed much pony even though BronyCon in New York was at the same weekend.
Speaker 1: There was Mad Pony at MAGFest.
Speaker 0: Like mad social currency and a girl dressed up in My Little Pony stuff totally groped my ass walking out of convention center after we talked about ponies.
Speaker 0: I think she was drunk.
Speaker 1: I had to tell on Rim.
Speaker 1: I had to tell Emily on him because he was groping all the ponied ladies.
Speaker 1: I was like,
Speaker 1: "Rim.".
Speaker 0: There was so much pony.
Speaker 1: You're not allowed to be groping ponies.
Speaker 0: The thing is, though, one girl, she made these cute rainbow- What's the word for somebody who gets it on with ponies?
Speaker 1: Equestrophilia?
Speaker 0: Equestrophile?
Speaker 0: Pona-phile?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But of all the stuff, there was this one hat that was kind of cute.
Speaker 0: It was like a Rainbow Dash hat, but actually when you wear it, it looks like you have Rainbow Dash's scalp.
Speaker 0: Like you've scalped her and put it on your head.
Speaker 0: It was kind of actually creepy seeing people wearing the hat.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Not a fan.
Speaker 0: Oh, the guy who does that canvas pixel art was there.
Speaker 0: I like that guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got to get him to make me something to go over my TV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I grabbed a lot of business cards.
Speaker 0: They're really cool people.
Speaker 0: The culture of the con is great.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Magfest in this venue had one thing going for it.
Speaker 0: The majority of the con was in one gigantic room, so you know how you do the wave in a stadium and it keeps going for a while?
Speaker 0: The Colossus Roar would start, and when people were feeling it, you know, like 3 a.m.
Speaker 1: on Saturday- Yeah, it definitely increased at night.
Speaker 1: There'd be a lot more roaring.
Speaker 0: But it would keep going for like five minutes, like looping around the room.
Speaker 0: Saturday, one time, it just wouldn't stop because I remember it just kept going and it started to die out.
Speaker 0: and then over by the machine, we hear it start up again.
Speaker 0: It just didn't stop.
Speaker 0: And then Wyatt looks at me.
Speaker 0: He's like, "Oh my God, I want to punch every motherfucker in the motherfucking
Speaker 0: face.".
Speaker 1: You know if you said that to me, you know what I would've said?
Speaker 0: You know what I said to Wyatt?
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: I love that aspect of Magfest so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's weird.
Speaker 1: It's like normally, right?
Speaker 1: That would be like, "Wait, scratch
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: But, scratch it.
Speaker 0: You know why?
Speaker 0: Because there's an unspoken rule.
Speaker 0: If you hear the Colossus roar, you respond in kind only if you are feeling it.
Speaker 0: So 6
Speaker 0: a.m.,
Speaker 0: I'm not feeling it anymore.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: No one else is too.
Speaker 1: So when one guy doesn't- But people are feeling it at 10 p.m.
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: Magfest is awesome.
Speaker 0: If you're a gamer of any stripe, you should go to Magfest.
Speaker 1: Or like listen to video game music.
Speaker 0: If you like our kind of shit at Magfest, tell them you liked it.
Speaker 0: If you went to our panel and you liked it, tell them so we will do more stuff at Magfest.
Speaker 0: Also, if you liked Super Art Fight at Magfest, tell them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we went to the Super Art Fight.
Speaker 1: It was awesome.
Speaker 1: I got photos of Magfest and also of the Super Art Fight in my Flickr because I have a camera now.
Speaker 0: Yes, we will have a whole bunch of content from Magfest up on the inner tubes in short orders.
Speaker 1: I have photos of things.
Speaker 1: Oh snap.
Speaker 0: And of course, kind of end this, if you want to see us at other cons, just tell the cons.
Speaker 0: Don't tell us because I don't care anymore.
Speaker 0: But if you tell a con and they come to us, that has a lot more weight.
Speaker 0: Magfest came to us.
Speaker 0: We were like, alright dogs, we're down.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: Magfest is added to the list of cons I would go to even if I were not a guest.
Speaker 0: I would show up and pay just to play games.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.