Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, October 10th, 2012.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Sky.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 0: Gravity Falls.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So a friend of ours, Judith, now she is a big fan of Shoujo Kakumei Utena.
Speaker 1: I'm very proud that I was the one who convinced her to watch it.
Speaker 1: But lately I think she's re-watching it because she keeps tweeting with the hashtag #IkuharaWorld and it is truths from a world that Kunihiko Ikuhara would create.
Speaker 1: And considering it's Wednesday, I'd recommend you check out this hashtag because if you're the kind of person who likes Utena or shows like that and you read this stream, you'll find this hilarious.
Speaker 1: But if you're not that kind of person, I'm not even going to kind of read any of these tweets because it will mean literally nothing to you.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: OK, so check this out.
Speaker 0: I'm checking.
Speaker 0: When I bought my I bought a new mattress when I moved up here.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And I bought that mattress at Sleepy's because, you know, they rip you off, whatever.
Speaker 0: It's just a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 1: I've been using the same mattress for like 12 years.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I expect this mattress to live me.
Speaker 0: it last me a fucking long time anyway.
Speaker 0: So but when I was at the Sleepy's, they had these pillows and it was so nice.
Speaker 0: So very nice pillow.
Speaker 0: But they were like 60 bucks.
Speaker 0: I was like, fuck you.
Speaker 1: It's how much a good pillow costs.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, I was so old.
Speaker 0: So I went to my.
Speaker 0: I bought regular pillows for like 15 bucks and they lasted me a long time.
Speaker 0: But now they're sort of sad.
Speaker 0: They have been squished by my head for many years and they're just sort of like food.
Speaker 1: So I have a collection of terrible pillows that I give to guests.
Speaker 0: I bought those two like one dollar pillows at Kmart.
Speaker 0: Those are in the storage in the couch for the couch bed.
Speaker 0: But anyway, but they're barely used.
Speaker 0: They're not too bad.
Speaker 0: So anyway, so I went to Bed Bath and Beyond to try to get some good pillows.
Speaker 0: So I traded all the pillows there and they were all sort of even expensive ones.
Speaker 0: I don't like those memory foam ones either.
Speaker 1: Well, Scott, you got to go to a boutique pillow store.
Speaker 0: I figure Bed Bath and Beyond.
Speaker 0: Bed is the first word.
Speaker 1: Gotta focus more on the beyond.
Speaker 0: I know, right?
Speaker 0: Uh, they had the whole store was disgusting anyway.
Speaker 0: So I try out all the pillows.
Speaker 0: They all suck memory foam.
Speaker 0: I don't like because when memory foam, I sleep on my side a lot, mostly.
Speaker 0: So when you sleep on your side, you crush your genitalia.
Speaker 1: How on earth do you do that?
Speaker 0: My genitalia is not in between the legs.
Speaker 0: It is out in front.
Speaker 1: So you like complex straight on your side or you don't like cross over a little bit.
Speaker 0: What do you mean crossover?
Speaker 1: Like is your waist completely straight or is your back like twisted?
Speaker 0: Well, my back is hunched forward in a fetal type position.
Speaker 1: Anyway, all I know of you from sleeping at conventions is that you're pretty much all elbows.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, pretty much the thing about sleeping on your side is you think about it.
Speaker 0: Your elbow is hitting the bed, which means if you allow your head, if you had no pillow, your head would sort of be like this.
Speaker 1: That's why you get one of those pillows that has like a hump.
Speaker 0: So, yes, you need enough pillows to cover the distance between the end of your shoulder and the side of your head so that your head points out straight.
Speaker 1: Well, you're a freak who claims to want to sleep on ridiculously hard mattresses and pillows anyway.
Speaker 0: So the pillows I have are very squishy.
Speaker 0: Now, obviously you don't want to sleep on an actual rock because then there's no give and it's sort of just like your head is on a rock.
Speaker 0: It's not comfortable.
Speaker 0: What you really want, the ideal pillow for me would be a rock so that it doesn't give but has some sort of jelly surface.
Speaker 0: so it is squishy and comfortable for your head to be on it.
Speaker 0: But it does not move away from your head.
Speaker 0: My head is still fully 100% supported.
Speaker 1: So why don't you get into the exact position you want on top of some device or some sort of moldable substance, make something in the shape of the correct side of your head with the air and everything, and then get someone to cast that in iron or something.
Speaker 0: That'd be sweet, but it'd be cold.
Speaker 1: And then cover it in felt, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that'd be good.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so I went on Amazon, I found the highest rated pillow is the Z-Zoned Talalay Latex Pillow.
Speaker 1: You touched my chalalay.
Speaker 0: Right, so it comes in four varieties, high loft firm, high loft plush, low loft firm, and low loft plush.
Speaker 0: So I got to assume high loft firm.
Speaker 0: That sounds exactly what I'm talking about here, right?
Speaker 0: You know, a big springy, you know, latex thing.
Speaker 0: Now here is the most important supposed feature of this pillow is it has a bunch of holes in it.
Speaker 0: Look, speed holes.
Speaker 0: Look all over the place.
Speaker 0: You know why it has those speed holes?
Speaker 1: Because it's an overpriced, ridiculous piece of crap the likes of which you would see in one of those Brookstone style stores in the mall.
Speaker 0: Maybe, but maybe it's because it supposedly will allow the pillow to always be cold.
Speaker 0: It will never be warm.
Speaker 1: I want my pillow to be warm.
Speaker 0: Why would I want my pillow to be cold?
Speaker 1: Everyone wants a cold pillow.
Speaker 1: Cold pillow is the best.
Speaker 1: I cover my body in blankets to keep it warm and to keep monsters away.
Speaker 0: No, the pillow is cold and you lay on it and then it warms up and you go and you move the pillow to go to the cold section and then that part heats up.
Speaker 0: So then you move the pillow again to go to different cold sections.
Speaker 1: No, I lay there until it gets warm.
Speaker 1: Then I go, ah.
Speaker 0: See, the listeners are going to comment on this and going to find out that you're the freak.
Speaker 1: I don't think anyone is going to comment on our pillow habits, but I order this pillow.
Speaker 0: It costs 50 bucks, but it says the list price is 120.
Speaker 0: If it doesn't work as advertised, I'm returning that fucker so fast.
Speaker 1: What do you mean work as advertised?
Speaker 0: Does it hold your head up if it's not comfortable and if it does not stay cold?
Speaker 0: I'm sending it back, but which Amazon doesn't care if you do.
Speaker 0: However, there is one thing about these latex pillows, apparently, is that they supposed to smell not good.
Speaker 0: So so what does Amazon say?
Speaker 1: What are the reviews?
Speaker 1: Some of them smell like a butt.
Speaker 0: Some of the reviews say, oh, my God, this thing smells so bad.
Speaker 0: I had to send it back.
Speaker 0: And some of them say smelled a little bit, but it went away in like a day.
Speaker 0: And some of them said, yeah, it smelled a little bit.
Speaker 0: When I put a pillowcase on it, I couldn't say it anymore.
Speaker 1: I guess I prefer we show on beds and pillows.
Speaker 0: I think we not done that.
Speaker 1: I don't think we have.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, then I'm not going to share my anecdote about what I prefer, because we might do a show on that.
Speaker 0: So this weekend, I just want to say, you know, I'm going to come back with a review of this pillow and I just don't want it to be a review out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: This weekend is the New York Comic Con 2012.
Speaker 1: We will not be there at all.
Speaker 1: I point out I've been to with a free badge every New York Comic Con and New York anime festival since 2007, except the first one.
Speaker 1: and this one, the first one I did not go to because it sold out and the fire marshal all but shut it down.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Every one after that I went to.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: I hate to say this, but every year there's been less of a reason to go to the next one.
Speaker 1: As of this year, I, I had a press badge for free.
Speaker 1: I can get it.
Speaker 1: I had, if I wanted it, a free badge.
Speaker 1: I live 20 minutes from the convention.
Speaker 0: Well, it's a Javits.
Speaker 0: You got to take a cab or walk.
Speaker 0: It's a, I live on the seven.
Speaker 1: I can take it most of the way there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I chose not to go and I re I declined the free badge because literally, well one, I looked through the schedule.
Speaker 1: There is nothing I care about at the New York Comic Con this year.
Speaker 0: Last year, Makoto Shinkai was there with a screening for the New York anime festival.
Speaker 0: That's actually no longer exists at all.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: Now you go to the New York Comic Con website and it just says New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Now there is some anime slash manga content there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there is like a, I think vertical.
Speaker 0: They brought like Miyoko Anno there, right?
Speaker 0: And some other people.
Speaker 0: So it is not completely devoid of anime, manga stuff.
Speaker 0: I'm sure that many dealers will still be selling things.
Speaker 0: There'll be that Gundam booth.
Speaker 0: That's awesome.
Speaker 1: The people cared about was the a silly kind of separate anime artist alley ghetto.
Speaker 0: I do not think that is going to be there too.
Speaker 0: There's one unified artist alley with all the same prices.
Speaker 1: and yeah, I looked at the schedule.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much nothing but a small number of like special screenings, like big ones, like hall H style stuff.
Speaker 0: Fuck that.
Speaker 1: Uh, normal screenings, autograph sessions, cost money panels that are clearly paid for by a publisher.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And maybe, maybe five or six other panels.
Speaker 1: There is nothing there.
Speaker 0: So the only reason to go to this is if a, you really, really, really want to go to a giant dealer's room to buy all sorts of comic related shit.
Speaker 1: That is not discounted in any way.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Or B, well, there might be a couple of the silver age, gold age, kind of like comic book bins are typical comic comic comic bins.
Speaker 0: There are going to be those booths though that have like the $5 trades if you want to stock up on unpopular Marvel titles of the nineties.
Speaker 1: But you're not going to find like the dominion tank police DVD box set for 10 bucks like you do at an anime.
Speaker 0: well, I mean sci-fi continuum will probably be there, but they had a pretty weak showing last year.
Speaker 0: They did.
Speaker 0: They're showing has been decreasing anyway.
Speaker 0: Uh, or two, you really, really, really, if you want to pay money to meet a famous person that is going to be there.
Speaker 1: If you want to see Ben Folds.
Speaker 1: five, they're doing a concert.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 0: Or three, the artist alley will be pretty good.
Speaker 0: It's going to be full of gold people, but it's not worth the price of admission.
Speaker 1: and what's funny.
Speaker 1: And you Scott pointed out a tweet on this from one of our friends, but, uh, I realized that no one I know who isn't exhibiting is going this year.
Speaker 1: And the people I know who are going, don't live in New York and are traveling for this shit.
Speaker 0: Well, because they're traveling because if you don't live in New York, right, you might not even have a comic shop.
Speaker 0: So of course, if you're going to make a trip to go to a comic shop, you're going to go to a super mega temporary ultra comic shop, which is basically what the comic con is true.
Speaker 0: And you're going to go to the one that's closer to you.
Speaker 0: So if you're on the East Coast, you're not going to go to San Diego, you're going to go to New York, a hero's con or something like that.
Speaker 0: If you live in New York City, you can go to Midtown Comics any day of the week.
Speaker 0: So why?
Speaker 0: And you can buy stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean, you can buy stuff online no matter where you live.
Speaker 0: But why go to New York?
Speaker 1: Well, I remember last year was really the last straw because I go, you know, we went every year and I always did some press coverage.
Speaker 1: We did one really big episode a long time ago and we used to lecture at the New York Anime Festival extensively on lots of stuff.
Speaker 1: We in fact, we ran, I found all these videos other people took of us running those crazy, like five hundred thousand person room match games like four years ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we did that once.
Speaker 1: No, we did that twice.
Speaker 1: We had Peter Fernandez as a guest on that one.
Speaker 0: That was the one time we did it.
Speaker 0: The New York Comic Con.
Speaker 1: I think we did it twice.
Speaker 0: I have two minutes.
Speaker 0: What was the second time we did it in New York Comic Con?
Speaker 1: I'll try to dig up my list of panels because I actually don't remember now.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure we only did it in New York Comic Con once.
Speaker 0: We did it at Coscom three times.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: But I'm saying New York Comic Con, we did it once and it was one giant room completely full.
Speaker 0: Actually, that wasn't even New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: That was New York Anime Festival when it was separate from New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: It's sad how the anime festival kind of just collapsed almost immediately into nothing because they couldn't make because they make all their money on that thing from the fucking exhibit space sales.
Speaker 0: What amaze me?
Speaker 0: There's no big anime companies to buy giant expensive booths.
Speaker 1: So three years ago, I said the New York Anime Festival is going to die.
Speaker 1: And I got a lot of shit hate mail from people who were like, no, you're wrong.
Speaker 1: You're just a hater.
Speaker 1: So I hate to be right.
Speaker 1: Hate to be right.
Speaker 1: In fact, some friends of mine, I was like, well, last year I was like, there's not going to be a separate New York Anime Festival Artist Alley next year.
Speaker 1: I guarantee you that no one believed me.
Speaker 1: And yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But what really is kind of sad is that you look at the New York Comic Con website and at the top, it was read pop and it was the Comic Con and some other comics thing and Star Wars Celebration and packs packs, packs, packs, dev.
Speaker 0: And then also isn't up there yet now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They have a UFC convention and they have some other stuff.
Speaker 0: No one cares.
Speaker 0: But
Speaker 1: the thing is it's like we complain about conventions like Otacon, like the completely fan run conventions because of all the drama and just
Speaker 0: unprofessionalism
Speaker 1: that we have to deal with, which is not readily apparent to the people who go, but to people who have to deal with them on a professional level, it's just a nightmare.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, the super corporate soulless conventions like the New York Comic Con have like the exact opposite problem of I don't want to deal with them because there's.
Speaker 1: it's so difficult to deal with them on a whole different level.
Speaker 1: It's like I don't even want to go somehow.
Speaker 1: Pax is the only con that balances the two perfectly.
Speaker 0: No, mostly perfectly.
Speaker 0: It's better than every other con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there is no question.
Speaker 0: But to be perfect, it would have to be like, you know, there is not a single even minor complaint that you can make because it is perfect.
Speaker 0: And that is not the case.
Speaker 1: I can't think of something I would complain about.
Speaker 1: that's actually the cons.
Speaker 1: Well, that's a separate thing.
Speaker 0: It could be anything.
Speaker 0: that's my.
Speaker 0: any minor complaint that you have counts makes it no longer perfect, even one, because perfect means one hundred percent.
Speaker 0: One minor complaint would make it ninety nine point nine percent.
Speaker 1: Would it count as a complaint if I saw something that was poorly managed, but it was something I personally did not care about and actually wish it wasn't there in the first place?
Speaker 0: Well, then your minor complaint would be that thing is there in the first place.
Speaker 1: Ah, but it was there and failed, which actually covered me pretty well.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But I mean, it covered you in that you were right that it should not be there, but it was still there.
Speaker 0: So they kind of made a mistake in having it there.
Speaker 1: How about perfection in the sense that as much as is practically possible, it is perfect.
Speaker 0: Ah, no, because perfect is, you know, the unattainable.
Speaker 0: That's why that's the point of perfect is that you can't be perfect.
Speaker 0: That's not perfect.
Speaker 0: Perfect.
Speaker 0: That's pragmatically perfect.
Speaker 0: You're just trying to bullshit so you can use the word perfect.
Speaker 0: Just let the semantics go perfectly.
Speaker 1: So not go to the New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: No, just hanging around, getting regular old shit done like cleaning the apartment.
Speaker 0: So check this out.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: There is in New York City, well, and a bunch of other cities.
Speaker 0: They're going in the United States.
Speaker 0: One, two, three, four, five.
Speaker 0: They're going to be showing screenings of, I think, the seven the current number seven on the Japanese movie box office, which is the Madoka Magica movie, one part one and two.
Speaker 1: I wanted to see that in the theater here.
Speaker 1: And in fact, I e-mailed Dave Riley.
Speaker 0: I checked the website.
Speaker 1: Dave, let's all go together and do a show on it.
Speaker 1: And then he was like, I think it's sold out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I checked the website a few times and it wasn't on sale yet.
Speaker 0: And then I checked it and it was on sale.
Speaker 0: But when I tried to actually buy the tickets, it didn't load.
Speaker 0: It's an error.
Speaker 0: I came back the next day and it wasn't there anymore.
Speaker 0: So I think it sold out and it was one screening in the city.
Speaker 0: And what other cities?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure they all sold out.
Speaker 0: Oh, they have a bunch in L.A.
Speaker 0: more than anywhere else.
Speaker 0: But Chicago, Houston, San Francisco were the other.
Speaker 1: thing is I feel like this is really only a movie for someone like me who's already seen the show and just wants to re experience the show.
Speaker 1: There's nothing different.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, I went.
Speaker 0: I looked up what the movie actually is from someone who saw it.
Speaker 0: And this is what the Madoka movie is.
Speaker 0: There's two of them.
Speaker 0: And basically each one is half the show.
Speaker 0: And they pretty much take the show end to end.
Speaker 0: And, you know, I think there's some sort of increase in resolution, you know, display video quality somewhere that there was no noticeable difference.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There's maybe like 30 seconds of added footage and they cut out a lot of stuff like that.
Speaker 1: I read the same review and actually take issue with the review.
Speaker 0: Well, how do you know you haven't seen the movie?
Speaker 1: Because what was pointed out as a strength was that it removes some of the repetitive like set building of the show, like how they keep bringing up what will you wish for and those sorts of things over and over again.
Speaker 1: I feel like that repetition is actually very important to what the show is doing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I mean, they said that the fact that that wasn't there was a like a something better about the movie compared to the show just seemed like a.
Speaker 0: well, I guess what it would be is that if you're watching one episode at a time with breaks in between, you know, there are more reminders usually necessary for, you know, purpose for purposes like that.
Speaker 0: And when you have a movie, you're watching on one shot.
Speaker 0: Well, you might not need as many reminders of certain things constantly and they would disturb the pacing.
Speaker 1: While you could say that, my rationale on paper said requires one to have seen the entire show or else I'll spoil it for everybody.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So anyway, is it to say, I think I am correct.
Speaker 0: that same review also said that the running time of like the first six at first half of the show is like 30 minutes longer than this movie.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: If you remove the openers and the closers in the right way, you remove the openers and the closers.
Speaker 1: That's like one of an anime screening.
Speaker 1: You got to watch every bad damn opener and closer.
Speaker 1: This is a so in English and then in Romangi and then in actual Japanese text and then.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: for convenience sake, if you don't want to sit there and watch 13 episodes of Madoka, you can watch the two movies and it's pretty much the same goddamn thing.
Speaker 0: 90 percent.
Speaker 0: So.
Speaker 0: But I mean, it'd just be cool to watch it in the theater.
Speaker 0: I would like to go.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It doesn't hurt to watch Madoka again or again, again or again, again, again.
Speaker 1: We've seen Madoka twice, four times, but I've seen the first eight episodes in about a fifth time for five times.
Speaker 0: Thinking about a fifth time.
Speaker 1: Thing is, I'm rewatching Cowboy Bebop right now and I just watched with Emily the last episode before the shit goes down.
Speaker 0: That's the if I remember correctly, the skyscraper episode.
Speaker 1: No, there's.
Speaker 1: I thought that too.
Speaker 1: There's one episode that happens after that.
Speaker 0: What episode is that?
Speaker 1: With the the ghost in the shelly kind of computer cult.
Speaker 0: Don't remember that one.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: I had to remember.
Speaker 1: Remember the scene where spikes walk in and he's in a room full of computer monitors and there's someone yelling at him from all the computer monitors and they is pass out and Ed dresses up like a girl.
Speaker 0: Vaguely, I'm going to go rewatch.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: Rewatching Cowboy Bebop again did one thing.
Speaker 1: Can't go wrong.
Speaker 0: It's again, again, again, again, again.
Speaker 1: It ruined my desire to watch 99 percent of the anime that's coming out.
Speaker 0: Anyway, whatever.
Speaker 0: Let us move forward onward into things of the day.
Speaker 1: So you all know that I am a incredible fan of hockey.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to talk about the fact that there's not going to be hockey this year because I might cry, but it's OK because the Russians are coming to play hockey in New York.
Speaker 0: Supposedly they still haven't.
Speaker 0: It's like this weird.
Speaker 0: you read these articles that are a few months old that say it's going to happen, but I can't find tickets or schedules or anything.
Speaker 1: So if that happens, I am going to see it no matter.
Speaker 1: It would have to cost like a thousand dollars for me to not go see this hockey game yet.
Speaker 0: But yet.
Speaker 0: So just so people know, the Continental Hockey League, which begins with K is the Russian Hockey League.
Speaker 0: It has Schley Valk.
Speaker 0: It has.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You don't even know what that means.
Speaker 0: Or if you're pronouncing it right.
Speaker 1: No idea.
Speaker 1: Bunch of drunk Russian men yelled it repeatedly during a hockey game when I was a little kid.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: So but that is supposedly the premier hockey league in the world now because there is the best NHL players have gone there.
Speaker 0: I think Evgeny Malkin's playing there with some other people.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah, there you go.
Speaker 1: So this is a video and an article about hockey.
Speaker 1: But this is not just modern hockey.
Speaker 1: This is hockey from nineteen sixty seven.
Speaker 1: Hockey is a lot, if I may.
Speaker 1: And the things that have changed are not what you would expect.
Speaker 0: Hockey or ice stick puck, if you will.
Speaker 1: Golly, that very nice.
Speaker 1: So hockey's changed a lot.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, it's changed in weird ways.
Speaker 1: It wasn't that long ago.
Speaker 1: Nobody wore helmets.
Speaker 1: I saw hockey games in my lifetime with people not wearing helmets.
Speaker 0: Well, there was a time in my life for the Institute to rule that was like every new player has to wear a helmet.
Speaker 0: But anyone who was in the league before the helmet rule was instantiated is allowed to continue to not wear a helmet.
Speaker 0: And now, of course, there's nobody still in the NHL old enough to be grandfathered in and allowed to be wearing no helmets.
Speaker 0: But in my lifetime, I have seen a handful of hockey players in live hockey games in my lifetime not wearing any helmet because they were grandfathered in for the helmet rule.
Speaker 1: That seems obvious.
Speaker 1: No one.
Speaker 1: Nineteen sixty seven.
Speaker 1: The goalies didn't have to wear face masks if they didn't want to or anything.
Speaker 1: So if you look at this article, you might notice notice that there's a goalie.
Speaker 1: He kind of looks like Frankenstein.
Speaker 0: So he is.
Speaker 1: he basically is Frankenstein.
Speaker 1: This goalie who played for the Red Wings a long time ago, Terry Sawchuk, he played for every team.
Speaker 0: Apparently is all six of them.
Speaker 1: He has an uncountable number of scars on his face for being a man.
Speaker 1: Count them one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, a lot in ten.
Speaker 0: Lots.
Speaker 0: I think he's three on the chin.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But what about this?
Speaker 1: How about to him in a hockey game that looks like it cut their shoulders and knees and toes?
Speaker 0: Knees and he is fucked the fuck up.
Speaker 1: So to make a long story short, this article talks about all the things that were different about hockey that back then and all the things that are the same.
Speaker 1: And it's actually really fascinating.
Speaker 1: A lot of people have this weird sort of idea that hockey was super different back then, just because most of the footage of it that you can see today is far away and blurry and seems just really kind of slow and stupid.
Speaker 0: That's the camera's fault.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So this is footage like from modern hockey, just of 1967 hockey.
Speaker 0: But did you see there was a controversy?
Speaker 0: This is a similar controversy.
Speaker 0: Robert Johnson is pretty much the inventor of blues music.
Speaker 0: You know, the guy who went down to the crossroads and such.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And there were serious discussions going on of, you know, there's the Robert Johnson tapes, which is pretty much like, you know, the foundation of all blues music.
Speaker 0: You listen to it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The only recordings of him.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And there's controversy of are those tapes sped up or maybe they're actually to like?
Speaker 0: are the one the songs that you hear?
Speaker 0: if you go type in Robert Johnson on Amazon or Spotify or Scott, those are those the wrong speed because of the way it was recorded.
Speaker 0: That's that is a serious matter of debate.
Speaker 1: Scott, you think that that is a new thing?
Speaker 0: I'm just saying it's similar to the hockey.
Speaker 1: No, no.
Speaker 1: So I'm going to tell you there's.
Speaker 1: there is a problem.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of different terms for this, but basically how we tune orchestras has changed over the years.
Speaker 1: And the classical music people argue as to what pitches should actually sound like is a 440 is a 444.
Speaker 1: Nobody knows.
Speaker 0: Ford hurts matters.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It matters.
Speaker 0: You can hear the difference.
Speaker 0: I mean, come on.
Speaker 0: You wouldn't know who you win a prize.
Speaker 0: Golden year.
Speaker 1: In fact, here's an entire article I'm showing you right now on pitch inflation.
Speaker 0: Maybe this is a whole topic of like, you know, lost history due to technological something something.
Speaker 1: Yes, it is.
Speaker 1: In 1834, the Stuttgart Conference recommended C to 64, also known as the A being four hundred and forty hertz as the standard pitch.
Speaker 0: So this is why it's good.
Speaker 0: Everything now is digital.
Speaker 0: It's zero or it's one.
Speaker 0: And there's no ambiguity.
Speaker 0: Analog assholes.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So I'm going to record my audio at one bid per second.
Speaker 0: Nice.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 1: This video is amazing, even if you don't like hockey.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day is actually comics related, right?
Speaker 0: There is apparently I did not know this because I haven't read newspaper comic strips in a long time.
Speaker 0: There is a newspaper comic strip called Close to Home by written by a person and drawn by a person named John McPherson.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: McPherson.
Speaker 0: And it is basically a really crappy sort of far side situation with the one panel with the text underneath and an illustration.
Speaker 0: Right now, this guy who has a blog here, his name is Tom Popolardo.
Speaker 0: He is a graphic designer, illustrator, animator, you know, typical cool person.
Speaker 0: And he is much, much smarter about graphic design and comic making than John McPherson.
Speaker 0: Now, what he did is he basically would keep reading this comic strip every day, not because he liked it, but because he hated it.
Speaker 0: It was so bad.
Speaker 0: It was awful.
Speaker 0: The composition especially was just horrendous.
Speaker 0: And the jokes were not funny.
Speaker 0: And it was like the word it pissed him off so much.
Speaker 0: He would collect the worst examples of this comic strip over time until eventually one.
Speaker 0: And he was like, one day I'll write a blog post about how awful this comic strip is with all these examples.
Speaker 0: And so one day one of them was so bad that he ended up writing the blog post.
Speaker 0: And here is that blog post with all these examples of these really, really bad comics.
Speaker 0: And he points out to you what's so bad about them and how the drawings are just awful and the jokes aren't funny.
Speaker 0: I think the line that he said, where is it?
Speaker 1: Was that the no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: OK, because it is so poorly executed, I usually spend more time trying to comprehend what I'm looking at than I do not laughing at the punch line.
Speaker 0: And I'm reading the comics.
Speaker 0: You completely agree with that sentence.
Speaker 0: And the worst thing is that he uses all these examples.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: This guy who writes a daily newspaper strip has reused the same jokes on different days.
Speaker 0: Like he'll write it.
Speaker 0: He'll write a thing.
Speaker 0: And then two years later, he'll do the same exact comic again.
Speaker 0: He'll just draw the same thing.
Speaker 1: Scott, I submit that there is, in fact, one comic that does that every day.
Speaker 1: that has had only one joke in his entire history.
Speaker 0: Garfield has three jokes as lasagna kicking off the table.
Speaker 0: And John's a loser.
Speaker 1: The Lockhorns has exactly one joke.
Speaker 0: I hit my wife.
Speaker 1: I hate my significant other.
Speaker 0: Well, and not enough, but not in at least Andy Capp has the say that joke and the I'm drunk joke.
Speaker 1: Also, I'm poor.
Speaker 1: He is poor and drunk and he hates his wife.
Speaker 0: Three jokes.
Speaker 0: Same as Garfield, the three joke standard.
Speaker 1: But the Lockhorns literally it is just.
Speaker 1: I hate my significant other, but not enough to divorce.
Speaker 0: Well, Marvin Duke also has one joke.
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 0: That dog is big.
Speaker 1: Or Kathy.
Speaker 1: I can't believe there are people who read this.
Speaker 0: But anyway, no, this comic you just made a whole fun of a whole bunch of crappy newspaper comics.
Speaker 0: You read this.
Speaker 0: You don't even need to read this blog post to know that these are the worst blog posts.
Speaker 0: Yes, you don't need to read this blog post to know that this comic is the worst.
Speaker 0: The comic stands out as the worst all on its own.
Speaker 0: But when you do, you need the blog post so that you can tolerate reading the comic strips because the comments in the blog, you know, along with the awful comic make it, you know, entertaining as opposed to making you want to hurt yourself.
Speaker 1: You know what that's analogous to?
Speaker 1: It's like watching an angry video game nerd about a bad guy.
Speaker 0: That is exactly what this is.
Speaker 0: This is the angry comic strip nerd.
Speaker 1: But with the Egoraptor tilt, because while, you know, the angry video game nerd, I love James Rolfe.
Speaker 1: But when he talked about how bad Castlevania two was, he he made fun of it, but didn't really analyze it.
Speaker 0: But then you're just going on that one because you are a Castlevania two fan.
Speaker 1: Now, I understand how Egoraptor also said it was a shitty game.
Speaker 1: He just made a much better argument as to why it's shitty.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, I realized that angry video game nerd, you know, he pays the bills with poop jokes.
Speaker 0: So he's not exactly going to go for eloquence to go along with this guy.
Speaker 1: That's because he, like all men who should be men, lives like a wind rammer as he fucks.
Speaker 0: And it's true.
Speaker 0: That should have been the thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Maybe it will be.
Speaker 1: It was the thing of the newsletter.
Speaker 1: So I guess that's a Segway for the meta moment.
Speaker 0: We have a newsletter.
Speaker 0: Apparently, it's much more popular than I thought.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Scott had an apology for all you for.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 1: For the one person in the world who actually has their email set to be text only.
Speaker 0: Well, OK, so here's how it is.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So the newsletter has like one hundred and twenty something subscribers.
Speaker 0: Just not bad.
Speaker 0: And and a lot of people seem to like it.
Speaker 1: And people are already like, hey, how can I get the back issues?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess our super hardcore crazy fans.
Speaker 0: And the way you get the back issues is find someone who got them to forward them to you.
Speaker 0: Number two, I suck at MailChimp and I'm still figuring it out.
Speaker 0: So here are two mistakes that I have made so far.
Speaker 0: Mistake number one, a very small mistake.
Speaker 0: The last newsletter was number five.
Speaker 0: And the one before that was also number five.
Speaker 0: I'm going to make the next one number seven just just to get it back.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute, Scott.
Speaker 1: You know, you know what's calling for you now?
Speaker 1: Ruda Khan.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: I don't think there's.
Speaker 1: there are many people left alive who I'm referring to.
Speaker 0: OK, so.
Speaker 0: and number two, a much more grievous error.
Speaker 0: When you subscribe to newsletter and MailChimp, you can choose text only or HTML emails, which is a choice you should be able to make.
Speaker 0: Right now, as an aside, especially if you want to read the newsletter in mutt, you don't want the HTML email.
Speaker 0: It's unreadable.
Speaker 1: There is no there's no reason to use mutt anymore.
Speaker 0: But it's good.
Speaker 1: OK, so dude, when I get a text email from someone from a corporation that still has their like corporate mandated signature at the bottom, but because it's not HTML, it's all just like text anyway.
Speaker 0: So I made a mistake in MailChimp.
Speaker 0: What I was doing to send out the newsletter is I would basically just copy the previous newsletter, go in and edit it and then send it and change the number from, you know,
Speaker 1: I feel a little bit vindicated that I'm not the only person who does that when I'm writing like an article or something.
Speaker 0: What else would I do?
Speaker 0: The thing is, in MailChimp, I was editing the HTML version.
Speaker 0: I assume that the text version would sort of inherit the changes because the very first newsletter I sent out, it generated the text version.
Speaker 1: Scott, you're a developer.
Speaker 1: You know better than to assume.
Speaker 0: But MailChimp is actually really well done and has a really good UI.
Speaker 0: I assumed that when you, you know, the first time I wrote a newsletter on there, the the text generate text version was automatically generated from the HTML version.
Speaker 0: So I was like, oh, I don't have to actually rewrite the text version.
Speaker 0: I just wrote the HTML one.
Speaker 0: I assumed that even looking to the text one would be updated.
Speaker 0: And I would even.
Speaker 0: every time I wrote a newsletter, I would send a test email to myself, go to Gmail and look at it and to verify it.
Speaker 0: And it was always correct because it was the HTML version.
Speaker 0: So the thing is, anyone who's subscribed to the text version, you actually got the same exact newsletter six times and it was never updated.
Speaker 0: It's just been newsletter number one every single time with no changes.
Speaker 0: So I apologize to all you.
Speaker 0: one persons who subscribe to the text version, doesn't have HTML email like a modern Gmail person.
Speaker 0: I will correct that for all future newsletter mailings, and that will never be a problem again.
Speaker 1: So a few minutes ago, I uploaded the third of our three mini lectures from PAX Prime 2012 on the ethics of mind control.
Speaker 1: I think that actually is the last of all the videos I have from PAX Prime so I can delete that like one hundred and eighty gigabyte project from my hard drive.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Another thing we have started in our efforts to expand and have geek nights in every possible Internet protocol that exists.
Speaker 0: We have added an IRC channel and I think, you know, in previous times people have tried to start many unofficial ones and they did not stick very well.
Speaker 0: So I was very unconfident in them.
Speaker 0: I also thought it may, you know, sort of be, I guess, redundant with having a forum, having an IRC.
Speaker 0: It's like, what's the point of having both?
Speaker 0: You know, what purpose does IRC serve that the forum does not serve?
Speaker 0: But whatever, if people want to be on IRC, why not put it there?
Speaker 0: It doesn't cost anything.
Speaker 0: So, Geek Nights IRC now exists.
Speaker 1: Someone said back.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Point your clients at IRC.funetic.net and connect to pound symbol Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Also, one of our listeners already made a bot that if you type Ubuntu, it just says Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: It's going to be the Geek Nights front row crew inside joke bot.
Speaker 0: There's also logs of.
Speaker 0: that was the real thing is I wanted to have if I was going to do an IRC, I don't like to lose anything.
Speaker 0: So I've been.
Speaker 0: I've logged the entire history of the channel and will continue to do so.
Speaker 0: You can go to the front row crew.com/irc/logs and read the logs.
Speaker 1: What's the logic of that?
Speaker 1: Like, when does it refresh?
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: Because if I go there, it usually only shows me like one like nothing.
Speaker 0: Go to front row crew.
Speaker 0: Now click on Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Oh, I have to click on that.
Speaker 0: Now click on it.
Speaker 0: Ah, I have to click on something.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: Oh, look at all these people talking to you.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: It's basically the way the bot works.
Speaker 0: is it's just there's a. it's a user in the IRC channel.
Speaker 1: And any time you say something, I have not idled on an IRC channel in almost 15 years.
Speaker 0: It writes down whatever you say into an HTML file that other people can read on the website.
Speaker 0: And every day it rotates to a new file.
Speaker 0: That's all there is to it.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of people.
Speaker 1: I guess I should in the tradition of how IRC is used, I should log in with Perch or Merc.
Speaker 0: You want to use IRSSI, everybody.
Speaker 1: Real men use Perch or Merc.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If the year is 1999.
Speaker 1: But I think the purpose of IRC is just to idle for as long as possible without saying anything.
Speaker 0: I'm using screen running on a line.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm always in there.
Speaker 0: It never leaves it.
Speaker 0: I'm just permanently in there.
Speaker 1: Watch out.
Speaker 1: You're going to accidentally hit control D instead or instead of control, whatever D.
Speaker 0: I did that the other day.
Speaker 0: It's fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I realize that most people cannot wrap their heads around screen.
Speaker 0: They should use TMUX then.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but screens what they got.
Speaker 0: Well, the TMUX is also free.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but screen is what's already installed on the Red Hat server.
Speaker 0: Control A, what else do you have to know?
Speaker 1: That's quite a leap for some people.
Speaker 0: Pressing control and A at the same time.
Speaker 0: And then after letting go, pressing something else.
Speaker 1: Oh, so we had a vague idea and I just want to run this out there.
Speaker 1: We'll end them at a moment.
Speaker 1: Get into a review.
Speaker 0: But before you do this, the book club book is The Name of the Wind by Patrick Rothfuss.
Speaker 0: It is a fantasy novel.
Speaker 0: It was New York Times bestseller.
Speaker 0: It is lauded and a lot of people love it.
Speaker 0: So you should read it if you're a nerd.
Speaker 1: So people have been bothering us for a long time because, you know, we used to do a lot more final thoughts episodes of like entire series of anime.
Speaker 1: I think Trigun was like the biggest one of those we ever did.
Speaker 1: And Big O too.
Speaker 1: We did a really good one for as well in like 2006.
Speaker 0: We haven't done one in a long time because we did Evangelion, didn't we?
Speaker 1: I think we did.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we haven't really finished watching.
Speaker 0: We did Monica.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the one that has been the most requested is Shoujo Kakamei Utena.
Speaker 1: Well, duh.
Speaker 1: I have seen like four times.
Speaker 0: The problem is the show is 50 something episodes.
Speaker 0: So it's not Scott.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: It's 52, I thought.
Speaker 0: Oh, 48.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: What what number is?
Speaker 1: a is a typical three partial season anime?
Speaker 1: This used to be one of our questions on Fanboy Feud in the anime club.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: Thirty nine.
Speaker 0: No, because there's either thirty nine.
Speaker 0: I feel I don't think it was thirteen, thirteen, thirteen.
Speaker 1: It was thirteen, thirteen.
Speaker 1: It was actually more like thirteen, thirteen, ten.
Speaker 1: The end.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's still.
Speaker 0: it's more episodes than the usual.
Speaker 1: And it's thirty nine episodes.
Speaker 0: And it also was never really released in a nice box.
Speaker 0: that wasn't fucked up in any way.
Speaker 1: The previous box that was fine.
Speaker 1: The only part that was fucked up was the first season.
Speaker 1: Thirteen episodes because it was put out on two also shiddily encoded DVDs.
Speaker 0: Also, when I started to rewatch it, the first DVD was in my Xbox.
Speaker 0: I got stolen.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So now I guess I had to rewatch it again again.
Speaker 1: And so what we're thinking about doing is we'd have to rewatch Utena anyway.
Speaker 1: Of course, to be able to do a final thought.
Speaker 0: I remember only the most basic of information.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: I can actually quote some things that people say.
Speaker 0: I can quote some things.
Speaker 1: I am a feminist.
Speaker 1: Choo choo.
Speaker 0: I can quote all of Choo choo's lines.
Speaker 0: Definitely.
Speaker 1: No, you can't.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh, oh.
Speaker 1: So we're thinking about doing is if we watch the show again to be able to do a deep, like detailed final thoughts.
Speaker 1: We're thinking about doing it episode by episode, making a separate show that'll just run for thirty nine episodes and then be done with it.
Speaker 1: So I'm asking you very rarely, will we talk about something we're going to do?
Speaker 0: And, you know, that feels like a really long trek up this really tall staircase.
Speaker 0: It does.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: What was it?
Speaker 0: Are you sure everything will get tired before the end?
Speaker 0: Let's just what was it?
Speaker 0: Let's take the elevator.
Speaker 0: It's been there the whole time.
Speaker 1: The gondola.
Speaker 1: So if do you guys if we made something like that, it's very rare.
Speaker 1: We tell you guys about stuff like this.
Speaker 1: Would you watch it?
Speaker 0: Because if not enough of you know, anyone who's listening will say yes to anything.
Speaker 0: Hey, if I put a camera in my butt and poop, will you watch it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they will.
Speaker 1: So your choices are the Scott butt poop cam or thirty nine episodes of us doing the RFE treatment.
Speaker 0: That's a false dichotomy.
Speaker 0: They can have both.
Speaker 1: That'll be the fortieth episode.
Speaker 0: Now, here's the real trick.
Speaker 0: Can they tell the difference?
Speaker 1: All I can picture now is James Rolfe trying to describe muck spreading and failing.
Speaker 0: I don't have a tail, sadly.
Speaker 1: If we made some sort of mechanical tail for you.
Speaker 0: But I wouldn't want to.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't want a fairy tale.
Speaker 0: You know, you could.
Speaker 0: you would want like, you know, some sort of lizard ish devil tale.
Speaker 1: You should use one of those little battery operated fans that tourists use in the summer.
Speaker 0: I don't think those can.
Speaker 0: They'll just think that could spread muck as soon as it hits the muck.
Speaker 0: It'll just sort of go and stop.
Speaker 0: The motor does not have the power to supercharge that shit.
Speaker 0: Then maybe it would work.
Speaker 1: Then the tool man Taylor knows what to do.
Speaker 1: What does it need?
Speaker 1: More power.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: OK, let's move on to the actual episode.
Speaker 1: We watched a show called Gravity Falls.
Speaker 0: So I got to give you some background on this.
Speaker 0: You might have heard of this show.
Speaker 0: Background number one.
Speaker 0: Rim said, hey, we should watch this Gravity Falls thing.
Speaker 0: It's popular with the pony people.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, oh, well, there's no ponies right now.
Speaker 0: So maybe I'll watch this show.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But, you know, one mention of a thing is not enough.
Speaker 0: In fact, even when I do want to watch something, for example, that show about the peasant in the Jester and the whatever.
Speaker 1: You haven't watched that at all yet, have you?
Speaker 0: No, it's great.
Speaker 0: People recommended it.
Speaker 0: I said to myself, this is the thing that I want to watch.
Speaker 1: It's called Medieval Lives.
Speaker 0: Keep forgetting to watch it.
Speaker 0: So but this Gravity Falls thing.
Speaker 0: So then since someone told me, I don't know who said this.
Speaker 0: It's the show with the vomiting rainbow.
Speaker 0: Now, that is a JPEG I've seen on the Internet.
Speaker 0: The gnome vomiting the rain.
Speaker 1: Now, it's worth noting at this point that when I went from my little pony to actually watching it was literally I saw an animated gif of Rainbow Dash doing something funny.
Speaker 1: And I was like, OK, right.
Speaker 0: So it's, you know, if someone made a JPEG of a show on the Internet that that maybe there's something to this show.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Internet people are into it.
Speaker 0: And then, of course, strike number three comes at my parents house this weekend.
Speaker 0: And my mom says, hey, is this show you should watch Gravity Falls?
Speaker 1: And I'm like, oh, Scott's mom actually has really good taste in like animation.
Speaker 0: Really, my mom and my sister are watching the show, but usually it's my sister watching shows like my sister watches like regular show.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, your sister's high five goes and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Gravity Falls is way up.
Speaker 0: But my mom was also watching this one.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, well, if my mom is independently telling me that she watches and I should watch this show, I guess I should watch this show.
Speaker 1: So Scott and I watched two episodes, two episodes just now.
Speaker 1: And Emily and I have watched some other episodes beyond that.
Speaker 1: So we've seen enough of the show to realize that it's actually pretty damn good.
Speaker 0: It's not pony level.
Speaker 1: It's not like.
Speaker 0: I'm not like voraciously going to go home and watch every remaining episode.
Speaker 1: But it was telling me finish one episode and Scott was like, yeah, put the second one on.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And when it was done, Scott was like, you want to watch the third one?
Speaker 1: I was like, yeah, let's do the show.
Speaker 1: I'm hungry.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The show does have many good aspects.
Speaker 0: And I will eventually watch as much of it until I get tired of it.
Speaker 1: So if we need to review the show, I'll just say this.
Speaker 1: It is in the same vein.
Speaker 1: If you like any of the following shows, there's a good chance you like this.
Speaker 1: My Little Pony, Phineas and Ferb, The Regular Show, any of those sort of modern cartoons that are popular among kids, but also popular among people who go to the New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's that kind of, you know, Homestuck.
Speaker 1: people seem to like this show.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's not so much Adventure Time, though.
Speaker 1: No, but the people who like Adventure Time like Gravity Falls a lot and vice versa.
Speaker 0: It's definitely in that modern cartoon style.
Speaker 0: I think we're entering, I don't want to say a golden or silver or bronze age, but it's definitely not a platinum age.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to call it a marble age because we got a lot of this material, you know, and now we're really good at chiseling.
Speaker 0: We've practiced a whole lot and some really adventurous sculptures and making some cool stuff.
Speaker 0: You want to hang up in your house.
Speaker 1: So the premise of the show is a pretty pedestrian premise.
Speaker 1: Two kids from not the middle of nowhere are forced to live in the middle of nowhere with their horrid Uncle Stan, who appears to be Moses Black.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, you can definitely see that these characters are all amalgamations of characters you already know, but amalgamated in sort of a good way, like Mabel.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Who is the main reason to watch the show, in my opinion, is basically Homer Simpson if he was an 11 year old.
Speaker 0: OK, well, sort of right.
Speaker 0: So Mabel is sort of like Didi from Dexter's Lab and that she's the sister.
Speaker 0: She is a prominent character.
Speaker 0: She is often doing, you know, silly nonsense sort of things and saying silly nonsense sort of things.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But she is also not stupid.
Speaker 0: And also is, you know, she is capable and can do awesome things.
Speaker 1: She reminds me of a season eight or nine Homer Simpson.
Speaker 0: I think, you know, I'm telling you, she's Didi from Dexter's Lab, but plus like extra competence and goodness and not torturing her brother when she is like grappling hook.
Speaker 1: That whole scene.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that could have been Homer Simpson.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, sort of that exact that entire scene, note for note, could have been.
Speaker 0: I think that I think the key factor is that she's sort of got that, you know, dumbness and silliness.
Speaker 0: But she is she doesn't like she is not she's not annoying.
Speaker 0: She's not bothering anyone.
Speaker 0: She's actually sort of helping out and doing good things.
Speaker 1: Well, I like how she does the Elaine of punching people to express most emotions.
Speaker 0: That sort of get out.
Speaker 0: the main character is really identifiable because he's totally a smart, normal dude.
Speaker 1: The second episode where they're going to go get a picture of a monster and he's like, all right, about 17 goddamn cameras.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Fucking this up.
Speaker 0: And in fact, the very beginning of the entire show.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: He's like, yeah, he's fucking evidence.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, you tell him.
Speaker 0: Basically, if they go to live in these woods with their great uncle and it's like how they call him Grunkle Stan.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of good characters otherwise living in the woods.
Speaker 0: But there's also supernatural kind of stuff going on in the woods, like, you know, well, there's a little bit naughty cryptozoology.
Speaker 1: Well, Scott pointed out there's there's an Evangelion kind of scene with the Illuminati logo.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, you know, the Evangelion opener shows you those rapid frames of animation to sort of that show you all this stuff.
Speaker 0: This said, the opener has one frame where it shows you sort of like the Illuminati pyramid with arms and legs, you know, really quickly at the end of the opener.
Speaker 1: Well, little things, too, like he finds this book that's like, oh, shit, there's bullshit in this town.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So that's the other thing about the show that makes me want to watch it.
Speaker 0: more is that clearly they're in strong.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't even say hints.
Speaker 0: that just there is a deeper subplot overarching of the hidden evilness of the woods.
Speaker 1: Now, be careful, because X-Files also pretended to have I was thinking the exact same fucking thing for that episode.
Speaker 0: when they find a UFO on the fucking beach.
Speaker 0: There is.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And then the piece of the UFO goes flying across the room and hits the Bible and points at a verse.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then next episode, I'm going to go chase this werewolf.
Speaker 1: So no UFO right there.
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: And they never went back to that.
Speaker 1: No, they went back to in the last episode.
Speaker 1: is bullshit all disappeared then.
Speaker 0: I don't happen to see that.
Speaker 1: I stopped watching the X-Files because of that.
Speaker 0: I didn't see that episode anyway.
Speaker 1: There's like a ghost aborigine.
Speaker 0: And it's like in the last episode, you clearly stopped watching X-Files after when that I tell you when that episode had the werewolf.
Speaker 0: That was last episode.
Speaker 1: I was I think it was actually a werewolf.
Speaker 1: I don't remember whatever it fucking was.
Speaker 0: That was the last episode.
Speaker 1: I was like to say why I like Gravity Falls.
Speaker 1: Aside from the overarching plot, then, like, for example, he has this book.
Speaker 1: There's a very obvious three on the book.
Speaker 1: And spoilers.
Speaker 1: One of the episodes Emily and I watched that you didn't see.
Speaker 1: Someone else has a book with a different number on it.
Speaker 0: Dun, dun, dun.
Speaker 1: And that guy has an artifact of power that he found the book.
Speaker 0: And, you know, the shady stuff in the woods anyway.
Speaker 0: But and you see this also they show you Grandpa Grunkle is he, you know, he goes down in some sort of secret passageway in his in his house there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's definitely up to something.
Speaker 0: And the book says don't trust anyone, which I guess includes Grunkle.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: That's how I identify with the main character even more.
Speaker 0: He's smart enough in that he only trusts the sister.
Speaker 0: He doesn't even trust the Grunkle.
Speaker 1: I think he trusts Zeus pretty good, too.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but he doesn't.
Speaker 0: but he doesn't actually trust him with the book or anything like that or knowledge of it.
Speaker 0: And he doesn't trust Grunkle either.
Speaker 1: The show also does a good job of skipping, like despite having a basically stereotypical plot from a very high level, it skips the kinds of things that shows like this usually do when they're made.
Speaker 1: Like when he finds the book and Mabel's like, what you looking at?
Speaker 1: And he tries to hide it.
Speaker 1: She's like, yeah, like you're actually not going to show it to me.
Speaker 1: And then they just skip that.
Speaker 1: And now she knows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that but then it also in the same episode, it's like you'd be worried, like, should we trust her?
Speaker 0: But that same episode is like, yes, you can trust her.
Speaker 0: Also, she's from out of town.
Speaker 0: Don't trust anyone from Gravity Falls.
Speaker 1: The foreshadowed and then switch up as to what the deal was with the zombie was also pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was very good.
Speaker 0: That caught me by surprise.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there were scenes in both episodes you watched where I did LOL for reals.
Speaker 0: So it is a funny show.
Speaker 1: In the second episode, I think the moment is when the crazy old man is running around and he just like, throws this guy's sandwich out of his hand.
Speaker 0: When he did that jig, that was a great jig.
Speaker 0: And also the reference, I'm betting money.
Speaker 0: that was a reference to O'Doyle rules.
Speaker 1: Oh, that totally was.
Speaker 0: There's that family, the red haired family of people on that boat are 100 percent.
Speaker 0: I go to him and I say, you know what that family is?
Speaker 0: And he's like, O'Doyle rules.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, that's what that is.
Speaker 0: O'Doyle rules.
Speaker 1: Like there's this one scene when they're there.
Speaker 0: If you're listening to this and you don't know what O'Doyle rules is, you suck.
Speaker 1: That is the second best Adam Sandler movie.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, no, no, it is the second best Adam Sandler movie because I really like Punch Drunk Love, but it's a different kind of movie anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the best one is Happy Gilmore.
Speaker 1: There's just.
Speaker 1: no, you can't even.
Speaker 1: That's one of the funniest movies.
Speaker 0: nobody's arguing about.
Speaker 1: That is our generation's Caddyshack.
Speaker 0: Is there anything else to say about?
Speaker 0: grab the name is kind of a funny pun, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Gravity Falls.
Speaker 1: Also, I got to say, I really like the opening sequence.
Speaker 0: And I think it's because I actually kind of think the opening sequence is boring, but it's I guess it's better than ponies.
Speaker 0: Ponies, actually, I don't like the opening sequence.
Speaker 1: I like the fact that the opening sequence is kind of it's cool and well animated.
Speaker 1: The only thing I like about it gets to the two points of Mabel.
Speaker 1: It's like, wow, I've never seen an opening to anything ever.
Speaker 1: In two, three second scenes encapsulate everything there is to know about one character.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess it does.
Speaker 0: It achieves that goal, but it's not like an opener.
Speaker 0: I want to watch.
Speaker 0: To me, a good opener is an opener where you're like, I want to watch the best opener to a show you've ever seen ever, ever because I'm trying to remember the best anime.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Let's talk just anime.
Speaker 1: I'm starting with My Heart, Sky Ties, My Baseline.
Speaker 1: So we got to name one better than that.
Speaker 0: That's a really good one.
Speaker 1: Before you forget.
Speaker 1: That alone does it.
Speaker 0: Oh, the Pat Labore first O.A.V Oh, that one's pretty good.
Speaker 1: Dominion Tank Police, but I can't count that because only the dub opener.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, Ava opener is not bad.
Speaker 0: Ava opener is not bad.
Speaker 1: But it's it doesn't do.
Speaker 1: it's not visually great, but it's great in that.
Speaker 1: Yes, that is a great thing way.
Speaker 0: Not great in the Gundam seed.
Speaker 0: Openers are great at giving away the show.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: They're really.
Speaker 1: they really pump you up to.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anything that pumps you up.
Speaker 0: Initial D openers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: It's got to pump me up for me to like it.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of opener I like, even video games.
Speaker 0: I like anything that pumps you up.
Speaker 1: Utena opener is pretty good, too.
Speaker 0: Oh, that.
Speaker 0: But you know, it's better than the antenna opener.
Speaker 1: But the horses.
Speaker 0: No, you know, it's better than Utena opener.
Speaker 1: Utena movie.
Speaker 0: Utena Closer.
Speaker 1: Oh, which one?
Speaker 1: Missin' Kissin' for that one.
Speaker 1: Not the actually.
Speaker 1: I like the second closing more because that song is crazy.
Speaker 0: Oh, OK.
Speaker 0: That's not bad.
Speaker 1: I really like that song.
Speaker 0: But they're all good.
Speaker 1: The thing is that is saying that because the closing in the second part of Utena is a little like, I don't know, it bothers me.
Speaker 1: Like there's something off about it on purpose.
Speaker 1: That's right when there's something bad going on in the show.
Speaker 0: All right, so.
Speaker 1: So gravity falls.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: Geek Nights Wednesdays animation.
Speaker 1: It's not just anime.
Speaker 0: You didn't think you had to defend that.
Speaker 1: So if you are in any way a fan of animation, you know what?
Speaker 1: We're entering this renaissance of animation.
Speaker 0: I guess maybe.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's just people seeing the success of ponies and trying to go for it.
Speaker 1: So you know what?
Speaker 1: Watch a couple episodes of Gravity Falls.
Speaker 1: The worst case scenario, you don't like it and move on.
Speaker 1: But it's no.
Speaker 1: it's come under our baleful gaze.
Speaker 1: And you know how hard it is for anything.
Speaker 0: One other thing to come under our animation quality is just as high as ponies.
Speaker 0: But the opener actually uses this sort of lighting effect on the 2D so like time lapse of the sun going across.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're actually using these lighting effects, at least in the opener.
Speaker 1: And I guess sometimes during the show, the use of color to the use the color in the show, especially around Mabel again and the rainbow.
Speaker 0: It's a little bit like a darker color set than ponies, but it's just as much just as much variety in the color.
Speaker 1: It's a darker and a lot of good lighting and shadows with occasionally like ridiculously juxtaposed color, like in the suddenly in the middle of what is otherwise a much darker palette.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And especially the lighting, like when they're running away from that monster and the glowing eyes, there was some really good lighting going on.
Speaker 0: That was really good.
Speaker 0: So that sort of puts it, I guess, you know, half a step above ponies, maybe in terms of animation quality.
Speaker 1: And it's worth noting that we both I mean, if nothing else, the only the best review I can give of any show like this is that we both laughed out loud more than once across multiple episodes.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: There are very few things in the world that are capable of making me laugh out loud like that.
Speaker 0: I think we're done.
Speaker 1: I think we're done.
Speaker 0: So we'll see you next week.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.