Speaker 1: It's Monday, October 22nd, 2012.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Sky.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, contributing to open source projects and why most people don't.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So in the course of a man's life, he learns many things by experience.
Speaker 1: You will occasionally experience a thing you have never experienced before.
Speaker 1: And good or ill, a man gets to understand what that experience entails.
Speaker 1: So today I had one of those experiences.
Speaker 0: Lost your virginity.
Speaker 1: So I was walking into the Fulton Street station to take the 4-5 train back uptown.
Speaker 1: And while I was walking down, the fire alarm in the subway station.
Speaker 1: Which until this point, I never even considered the possibility of a fire alarm in the subway station.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sometimes you hear the alarm on the emergency door.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you mean every time.
Speaker 0: Because people are opening the door and it sets off the emergency alarm.
Speaker 0: And I figured that that was, I guess, without even really thinking hard about it.
Speaker 0: I figured that is the fire alarm of the subway station.
Speaker 1: No, it is not.
Speaker 1: So I go to the Fulton Street station and there are people streaming out of it more so than usual.
Speaker 1: But usually when there's that many people streaming out, I assume there's some sort of fuck up with the subway.
Speaker 1: Like oh, the 4-5 is not running and all these people are trying to get to the 1-2-3, maybe the 9 if they're really old.
Speaker 1: So I go down anyway because I live like a wind rammer.
Speaker 1: And I get down there, the fire alarm is just fucking going off.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: Was it painful to listen to?
Speaker 1: No, it sounded like a normal fire alarm but it was drowned out by the generic noise of the subway station.
Speaker 1: But the strobes were going off too.
Speaker 0: What about the PA?
Speaker 0: Was there anyone talking in the PA?
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 1: Now I would not have noticed the fire alarm had the strobes not also been going off.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of them and I'd never noticed them there before.
Speaker 0: Me either.
Speaker 1: So, despite all the people who had streamed out, the vast majority of the people were ignoring it and waiting for a subway train.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 1: And a subway train came immediately.
Speaker 1: And as I've done in my entire life, I will continue to do now in the subway too, I've ignored every fire alarm I've ever heard.
Speaker 0: And you got on the subway?
Speaker 1: I got on the subway.
Speaker 0: And it took you to the next stop?
Speaker 1: Everything was normal.
Speaker 0: Perfect.
Speaker 1: I've never been in a building that had a legitimate fire alarm in my entire life.
Speaker 1: But I've experienced hundreds upon hundreds of either false alarms or fire drills.
Speaker 0: Well, I have experienced legitimate fires but they were not fires that would threaten me in any way.
Speaker 0: For example, a guy burning something in the microwave.
Speaker 0: There is a fire.
Speaker 1: You mean at RIT when Greg burned that egg and our entire building had been evacuated?
Speaker 0: You cannot say that it is not fire to some extent but it is not a fire that threatens my life in any way.
Speaker 0: You know what that fire threatened?
Speaker 0: It is not a fire worthy of evacuating.
Speaker 1: That fire, you know what it threatened?
Speaker 1: I remember that it fucking ruined my beef stroganoff because I was in the middle of cooking it and then the alarm went off and campus safety made me get out of the apartment.
Speaker 1: That was actually one of the maddest I've ever been in my life.
Speaker 1: That's like top 15 mad.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's Monday.
Speaker 1: Got any news?
Speaker 1: Any Monday?
Speaker 1: science technology news?
Speaker 0: I do have sort of a news.
Speaker 0: I don't really care about this that much but it's an internet explosion today of controversy and it has a couple interesting side topics.
Speaker 0: So there's some person from Northern Europe.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure if it is the Sweden, Norway or Finland.
Speaker 0: It's one of the three.
Speaker 1: I like how there's the only three you think of.
Speaker 0: I think it might be the Sweden because it's got the director with the O with the slash through it.
Speaker 0: But anyway, some person who travels a lot had a Kindle and they bought a lot of books and basically suddenly all their Kindle books were gone and they emailed Amazon a whole bunch and Amazon was all like, yes, your account was linked to an account that had problems.
Speaker 0: that, you know, violated terms or something along those lines is misbehaving.
Speaker 0: So we just you know, we just closed your account and now wait a minute.
Speaker 1: So my I mean, my account that does my like AWS and EC2 and whatever is also my account for like buying bullshit on the Internet.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so this person emailed back and they were like, is it correct?
Speaker 0: You cannot give me any information about one how my account is linked to the blocked account to the name ID of the related blocked account.
Speaker 0: Three, what policy was violated?
Speaker 0: I have no knowledge about any other account that could be related to mine.
Speaker 0: Cannot understand how it could have violated your policies in any way.
Speaker 0: Best regards.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So Amazon is pretty much like.
Speaker 0: we regret that we have not been able to address your concerns, your satisfaction.
Speaker 0: Unfortunately, we will not be able to offer any additional insight or action on these matters.
Speaker 0: We wish you luck in locating a retailer better able to meet your needs and will not be able to offer any additional insight or action on these matters.
Speaker 1: I would sue.
Speaker 0: I would also sue.
Speaker 0: But this person's in a foreign country making it very difficult to sue.
Speaker 0: But this is the perfect thing for small claims court.
Speaker 0: Like I would go to I'll be like, I want the full value of all the books I paid refunded and I want interest and I want, you know, the value of this Kindle is now useless.
Speaker 0: And I want all these things.
Speaker 0: But for a person in a foreign country dealing with an American company, I guess they were dealing with Amazon Co.
Speaker 0: I would sue the UK, it seems, because that's what the signature in the email says.
Speaker 0: You know, it might be difficult to sue a company in the UK or the US if you're in Finland, Norway, Sweden.
Speaker 0: But yet the things I want to address here is number one.
Speaker 1: That's bullshit.
Speaker 0: Do not buy it.
Speaker 0: Don't know if it's true.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: This could be a whole fake thing here.
Speaker 1: I would kind of lean toward it being true, I guess.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying there isn't a lot of evidence except for text, copy, paste of emails.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So I even though I have a Kindle, I have never bought a DRM book in my life.
Speaker 1: I've bought several because I'm a lazy ass.
Speaker 0: The only DRM things that I have bought in my life are number one, steam games and number two, I guess Netflix streaming is counts as DRM, maybe not because that's streaming.
Speaker 1: I know I don't own those things.
Speaker 1: I am paying for the service as opposed to the individual works.
Speaker 0: That's it, steam games.
Speaker 0: And I guess Adobe Cloud, does that count as DRM?
Speaker 1: I am paying for the service there too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's something they could turn off and then I wouldn't be able to download them anymore.
Speaker 0: But I'd also stop paying and I'm paying monthly, so whatever.
Speaker 1: So that's right.
Speaker 1: But this is I bought a book for ten dollars and now it's gone.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, yeah.
Speaker 0: Do not ever buy.
Speaker 0: I don't care if you're using a Nook or Apple iBooks or Amazon, even though I like Amazon.
Speaker 0: I have an Amazon credit card and buy all kinds of things on Amazon.
Speaker 0: Do not buy e-books on Amazon.
Speaker 0: Well, I only use my Kindle reading story.
Speaker 0: Of course, reading Project Gutenberg and other pirated books.
Speaker 1: Now, I think there is another way to take.
Speaker 1: Crack the DRM on every e-book you buy and save a backup of it, which I think I'm going to back up a little bit.
Speaker 1: There should be a law.
Speaker 0: And if even though it's not legal, you should definitely do, you know, civil disobedience.
Speaker 1: There should be a law or in fact, a constitutional amendment guaranteeing the rights to first sale and backups of things you have purchased that are digital and in general transferability of digital goods.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the other thing I really want to talk about here is the general concept that companies just not fucking talking to people.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like I can tell you why.
Speaker 0: Well, of course, we know a lot of reasons why.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You don't want to get sued.
Speaker 1: Anything you say.
Speaker 1: The other person probably can't sue you.
Speaker 1: But the more you say, the more ammo they have.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It costs money to provide support.
Speaker 1: So there's no reason to ever provide support because nobody makes the decision to buy a product based on the support.
Speaker 1: They just get pissed off after they already bought.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Google provides no support whatsoever.
Speaker 0: The only way to get support from Google is if you pay for Google apps and you are a company.
Speaker 1: Let alone Lenovo.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So Windows got corrupted on my my new laptop.
Speaker 1: It still works, but it has some problems.
Speaker 1: I got to reinstall from the media.
Speaker 1: The media I made just don't fucking work.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know, I you know, I've been trying for weeks to get a hold of anyone at Lenovo who knows fuck all.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They just send you a disk, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 1: They want to charge me like 50 bucks for a disk.
Speaker 0: Well, that went in to give them credit, though.
Speaker 0: You can get the disk in the checkout process and it costs money.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: So to buy the disk after the fact on the checkout process.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, I created the media per their instructions.
Speaker 1: And the media itself doesn't work.
Speaker 0: And is the laptop still under warranty?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Now, then, yeah, they should definitely do something.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, good luck getting them to do that.
Speaker 1: But it's like, you know, what about cell phones?
Speaker 1: What about cell phones?
Speaker 1: So Verizon has pretty crap service.
Speaker 1: What do I do?
Speaker 1: Go to Sprint?
Speaker 1: It's even worse there.
Speaker 1: AT&T.
Speaker 1: Good luck.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But for example, I signed up for that mentoring thing and the paperwork.
Speaker 0: There was one piece of paperwork I noted that said, you know, if we reject you, we you know, this is in English, right?
Speaker 0: It basically effectively said in legal speak, if we reject you, we don't have to ever tell you a reason why or anything.
Speaker 0: Now, it's interesting because we are under no obligation to tell you the reason why we reject you.
Speaker 0: We're just going to say, you know, you're rejected.
Speaker 0: Goodbye.
Speaker 1: So two things.
Speaker 1: One, say I like say geek nights, like we hired people for geek nights.
Speaker 1: If we ever fired anyone, we would never, ever give a reason because that just opens you up to liability in case that reason can in any way be construed to be discriminatory.
Speaker 1: But because you're not legally obligated to give a reason, it's kind of like how it's your best interest to never talk to the police, even if you're innocent.
Speaker 1: It's in your best interest to never give a reason for anything.
Speaker 0: But I actually even though I would open up myself to liability, right, I would tell someone the reason if I was firing them and they didn't want to be fired because that's what a non asshole does.
Speaker 0: Listen, Joe, you know, but we're running out of money and, you know, everyone else plays solitaire for two hours a day and you play solitaire for four hours a day.
Speaker 0: And, you know, so and so can do your work in the two hours of solitaire.
Speaker 0: And so and so else can do the other two hours of work if they stop playing solitaire.
Speaker 0: And we just someone has to go.
Speaker 1: Scott, there's a reason.
Speaker 0: there's no other ways you can save money.
Speaker 1: There's a reason why most companies have an H.R.
Speaker 1: person do that and not.
Speaker 0: That's how it's going to be.
Speaker 1: But the other thing, there is one realm where that is actually a specific protected thing, and that is credit.
Speaker 1: If I say apply for a mortgage and they deny me because of my credit report, they have to tell me and they have to tell me what part of my credit report they use to make that decision.
Speaker 1: Interesting.
Speaker 0: Interesting.
Speaker 1: You didn't know that?
Speaker 0: Did not know.
Speaker 1: I guess you've.
Speaker 1: you've never applied for a mortgage, have you?
Speaker 1: Well, no, but you ever applied for a line of credit that wasn't a credit card.
Speaker 1: because they also have to tell you.
Speaker 0: Well, I have done things that I've done a lot of things that aren't necessarily applying for credit, but require credit checks.
Speaker 0: For example, when you go to get a cell phone, they always run a credit check on you.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So they're also make you like make a deposit and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: I remember the first cell phone you tried to buy back in the early days of cell phones.
Speaker 1: They were like, yeah, you need to put down five hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: And you were like, why?
Speaker 1: I was like, no, I don't have five hundred bucks.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But, yeah, there's laws about that for credit.
Speaker 1: But yet this is another situation where we have a very complex, probably overly complex regulatory framework in a very narrow area.
Speaker 1: But yet because our law is so slow to update and everyone in our government is so old and incompetent and slow and corrupt and old and slow and old and corrupt that an old that we there's ten other things that are the same situation that have no regulation.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying it's bad that we have a system set up to incentivize not being nice and not explaining things to people.
Speaker 0: We should give some sort of protection to you.
Speaker 0: And the other thing is, you know, if you're thinking you're sitting there right and you have a company and you can decide, all right, we're going to screw this customer for a reason.
Speaker 0: We've decided to do that.
Speaker 0: We're not changing that decision.
Speaker 0: We can tell them the reason, but that might open us to legal liability or not.
Speaker 0: tell them the reason to protect ourselves or but maybe.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, they could still try to sue us either way.
Speaker 1: Wait, so how about this?
Speaker 1: How about a DMC?
Speaker 0: Maybe if we're nice to them, they won't even sue us.
Speaker 0: So maybe that's the better option.
Speaker 0: And they're not even figuring.
Speaker 1: There's another answer.
Speaker 1: Maybe just to save money by not having people even worry about this.
Speaker 1: You just don't know.
Speaker 1: your support basically just has an autoresponder that gives a form letter and no human ever even sees it.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: That's one way to go.
Speaker 0: And the other thing is think about what small percentage of the customers are actually going to get mad at the form letter rejection.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So the few that say I do.
Speaker 0: But yeah, but the few the very few who actually fight and want reasons, I think it might actually be worth your time to give the reasons and talk to them and be nice to them because, number one, you guarantee that this blog post will never happen.
Speaker 1: Now, that means at least one human involved.
Speaker 0: It does.
Speaker 0: It will cost you money, but better.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe if those people have good experiences and blog those, you could just take that out of the market.
Speaker 1: Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Speaker 1: Let me put on my.
Speaker 0: Consider that to be marketing.
Speaker 1: Scott, let me put on my.
Speaker 0: Look at how much.
Speaker 0: Think about this.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Imagine if PayPal had done that.
Speaker 0: How many people hate PayPal and refuse to use it because of all the bullshit of locking accounts, taking people's money.
Speaker 1: You want to know how many?
Speaker 1: Like four.
Speaker 1: Nobody gives a shit about that except us.
Speaker 0: And you use it anyway.
Speaker 0: I don't because I don't care.
Speaker 0: But there are thousands of people.
Speaker 0: No, there's so few people who complain about PayPal all the time.
Speaker 0: If PayPal had just.
Speaker 0: No, Scott, you're out with people, Scott, who had their accounts locked.
Speaker 1: No, the people who care.
Speaker 0: And people love PayPal.
Speaker 1: No, because the people most people use PayPal anyway.
Speaker 1: The tiny minority who care is kind of like how Best Buy and clothing stores will basically just ban customers who return stuff or assholes are annoying.
Speaker 0: Well, those are assholes are annoying.
Speaker 0: This is someone who has a legitimate problem.
Speaker 0: How about all those people who had charities who got too much money and they just locked their account for no reason?
Speaker 1: Fuck them.
Speaker 1: Enough people use PayPal anyway.
Speaker 0: What is that?
Speaker 1: Why did you even lock that person to to prevent any sort of.
Speaker 0: And also, if you're if you're right.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: There's a new person in charge of PayPal now and they're doing what I said.
Speaker 0: They're working to fix this problem of people getting their accounts locked.
Speaker 1: Maybe or maybe they're saying they're doing that now.
Speaker 0: At the very least, they're being nicer, which is I am in favor of.
Speaker 1: So let me put on a cynical rimhead.
Speaker 1: So all right.
Speaker 1: Why bother having anyone be proactive about this?
Speaker 1: Because then there's a human who has to worry about it.
Speaker 0: No, you don't be proactive.
Speaker 0: You just be reactive.
Speaker 0: When the asshole when this kind of article happens.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You talk to the person, but you know, why even talk to the person?
Speaker 1: Why not just ignore it completely because of the Barbra Streisand effect?
Speaker 1: If you actually ignore something on the Internet, it has to be so big to go.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like when the president that this is not.
Speaker 0: this is not the Streisand effect.
Speaker 1: No, Scott, it's similar, though.
Speaker 1: Hear me out.
Speaker 1: Now, if if you just ignore something on the Internet, that's the equivalent of the president vetoing something from Congress.
Speaker 1: You had so much bullshit has to happen for the Internet to continue to care about anything for more than a week.
Speaker 0: That's not the Streisand effect at all.
Speaker 0: The Streisand effect is when there is something that nobody notices.
Speaker 1: Yes, Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm well aware.
Speaker 0: Point it out and say stop.
Speaker 0: Yes, Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm well aware.
Speaker 0: This is not.
Speaker 0: even this is not.
Speaker 1: it already exploded on the Internet.
Speaker 1: Scott, did you realize it only exploded among super nerds?
Speaker 1: No one else gives a no.
Speaker 0: This was all over the all Internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Internet.
Speaker 1: What about the rest of the country?
Speaker 0: It was not just on the nerd Internet.
Speaker 0: It was on the full Internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And, you know, I saw it on Google News.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: If Amazon literally completely ignores it, I guarantee within two weeks no one will be talking about.
Speaker 0: It's not exactly the biggest news story in the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm saying this.
Speaker 1: The thing it's better from cynical rooms perspective to literally ignore anything like that.
Speaker 0: If it would be better for it not to have happened in the first place, which you could have done just by saying I would argue that no effect on Amazon.
Speaker 1: No, no.
Speaker 1: Literally, I'm serious.
Speaker 1: I don't think that this will have any effect at all on any portion of Amazon.
Speaker 1: In any way whatsoever.
Speaker 0: I think there will be.
Speaker 1: there will be zero backlash.
Speaker 0: Hundreds of people.
Speaker 1: Everyone who has the capacity to pirate e-books already pirates e-books and justifies it with some other people I see who have the capacity but have some sort of weird, stupid moral whatever.
Speaker 0: They believe that they actually believe piracy is whatever.
Speaker 0: And they buy things.
Speaker 1: Seriously, this has no impact on Amazon.
Speaker 1: They have no incentive to even say anything about this.
Speaker 1: And if they say anything, it'll have the same effect as in the proper Streisand effect where Barbra Streisand says stop talking about it.
Speaker 1: Stop talking about it.
Speaker 0: They should have said something before this happened.
Speaker 1: No, they're better off saying nothing.
Speaker 0: Better off saying something.
Speaker 0: Being nice.
Speaker 0: Making people love you.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 1: See, you're thinking about this from a human perspective.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking about it from an answer.
Speaker 0: I have the thesis that if a company friggin acted like a human being and wasn't an asshole, that company would be so beloved that it would be able to dominate all the other companies.
Speaker 0: And the only reason companies don't do that is because no one else is doing it so they don't have to.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you think that.
Speaker 1: Think back to PAX East.
Speaker 1: Remember when the hotel fucked us on the charges for those flyers?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So we still stayed at that hotel the next year.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I'm not staying at it this year.
Speaker 1: We tried to stay at it this year.
Speaker 1: We failed because it was too popular.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So what incentive does the hotel have to even talk to us?
Speaker 0: We stopped shipping things there.
Speaker 0: If we needed something shipped, we would ship it to a different place.
Speaker 1: You know why hotels charge so much for that?
Speaker 1: Because they don't want to have to deal with it at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but how come other hotels just let it be free and we're awesome?
Speaker 1: Actually, most hotels don't.
Speaker 1: It's just that one Renaissance hotel was like the only one that doesn't charge.
Speaker 0: Man, I just watch all these old movies where the hotels provide so many awesome services.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: The hotels I stay in for business?
Speaker 0: Still provide those services.
Speaker 1: Yes, and you know what?
Speaker 1: They cost twice as much.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: If I'm traveling, I'm not staying in those fucking hotels.
Speaker 1: The $100 a night hotel is just as good for me.
Speaker 0: Unless you need one of those services.
Speaker 1: I never need those services.
Speaker 0: Except that time you just used the services and they fucked you.
Speaker 1: I used it because I was lazy and also because I printed the things like three days before the con.
Speaker 0: Alright, let's move on to the next news.
Speaker 1: So, in Italy.
Speaker 0: It's me, Mario.
Speaker 0: Let's be racist and punch out a stereotype.
Speaker 1: So, six days ago on a Tuesday, this is October 16th.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, not Tuesday.
Speaker 1: So, this is back in June.
Speaker 1: So, in June, there's an article about some scientists in 2009 in Italy who were geologists and they analyzed data about geological things.
Speaker 1: And they concluded in their sort of internal little like study that there wasn't much threat of an earthquake at some particular time.
Speaker 1: And there happened to be an earthquake that killed 300 people.
Speaker 1: So, in June of 2010, about a year later, the government talked about charging them with gross negligent manslaughter for not predicting the quake.
Speaker 0: Well, the question is, right, is did they not predict it?
Speaker 0: or did they predict not?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: See, that's the difference, right?
Speaker 1: Scott, there is no difference because it's all statistics and percent.
Speaker 1: Basically, any prediction that a real scientist ever makes is just a sort of percentage coupled with a percentage that the percentage was right.
Speaker 1: And that is the only recommendation that can possibly be made.
Speaker 0: And did they do their science proper like?
Speaker 1: Doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Here's the other thing.
Speaker 0: Was it good science or was they fucked the fuck up?
Speaker 1: Here's the reality.
Speaker 1: It's basically impossible to predict earthquakes.
Speaker 0: So.
Speaker 0: You don't say.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that wasn't news that, you know, the government was talking about and stuff like that happens all the time.
Speaker 1: As of today, they were found guilty of manslaughter.
Speaker 0: Way to go, Italy.
Speaker 1: So I learned some things.
Speaker 1: Apparently, Italy is one of the least productive academic countries in the entire industrialized world.
Speaker 1: The number of papers coming out of Italy from academia is lower than I believe almost any other industrialized nation.
Speaker 1: They're like all.
Speaker 1: they're all the output.
Speaker 1: I found all these articles about this is apparently academic circles talk about this a lot.
Speaker 1: And scientists who were good have been fleeing Italy for many years.
Speaker 1: So there's a very anti science culture in the Italian government.
Speaker 0: Does this have to do anything to do with religion in Italy?
Speaker 1: Doesn't appear to.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: Now, obviously, this is bullshit.
Speaker 0: They do have lots of engineers in Italy at the Ferrari factory.
Speaker 1: I mean, Scott, should I sue you because you didn't predict that you were about to fart?
Speaker 0: No, that is obvious bullshit.
Speaker 0: So obvious I didn't even think we needed to discuss that.
Speaker 1: So it turns out Italy does not have a monopoly on bullshit prosecution of scientists.
Speaker 1: So in America, North Carolina law was passed.
Speaker 1: This was a while ago.
Speaker 0: North Carolina is also anti intellectual.
Speaker 1: North Carolina is not nearly as intellectual as South Carolina.
Speaker 0: It's still not great.
Speaker 1: So June 5th, 2012.
Speaker 1: Here's an article that I remember being pissed off about this back then.
Speaker 1: North Carolina passed a law saying that government institutions, insurance companies, all basically anyone who they could cover by laws was not allowed to use scientific analysis or extrapolation of global warming data to make predictions of any kind.
Speaker 1: Because if they did that, the insurance companies and it would probably raise insurance rates on the places that are very likely to be hit by hurricanes.
Speaker 0: She in a hurricane state.
Speaker 1: And the government might, you know, you might be able to assess tax values differently or they might predict that certain areas might be underwater in 10 years and that might cause property values to decline.
Speaker 1: So North Carolina basically passed a law that said, nah la la la, I can't hear you.
Speaker 0: So, you know, what I would do is if I was in North Carolina is I would sell, sell, sell.
Speaker 0: And it's basically a fake prop.
Speaker 1: I don't know if the law actually passed.
Speaker 1: It was proposed.
Speaker 1: It was very popular.
Speaker 0: But if they did it, there would basically be this fake propped up market where people were being forced to have these hot inflated prices.
Speaker 0: I would sell like crazy.
Speaker 0: And then when those places were literally underwater, I would be like, woo, cashing in big time.
Speaker 1: So apparently the defense in Italy, their argument was you can't predict earthquakes.
Speaker 0: Uh huh.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty good argument, I think.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: This is a jury trial, how to trial other courts.
Speaker 1: I have no idea how Italy works.
Speaker 0: Right, because in Japan it's all fucked up where like they make you confess.
Speaker 1: Now here's the part that bothers me.
Speaker 1: So let's say the same data had come out, you know, the same like analysis happened and they said there was going to be an earthquake and there had been a panic fleeing from the city and people died.
Speaker 1: Would they then have been found guilty of manslaughter?
Speaker 0: If somebody made a big to do saying there's definitely an earthquake run for your lives and there wasn't, that could be a yelling fire in a crowded theater situation.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: Depending on the exact circumstances of the warnings and such.
Speaker 1: What if they make the prediction with the right amount of due diligence and everything and the populace who does not understand statistics panics unduly and causes deaths?
Speaker 0: That would not be any fault of theirs.
Speaker 1: So what if they made a prediction that there was going to be an earthquake and there wasn't?
Speaker 1: Would they then be sued for lost tax dollars from tourism?
Speaker 0: It depends on how, if they had the yelling fire in a crowded theater situation I think is the only situation where you could get in trouble.
Speaker 1: I think the real answer is that scientists should not be able to be prosecuted for doing their science and the government needs to look at what scientists do, make decisions and deal with the consequences of those decisions.
Speaker 1: If you're a scientist and you're in Italy.
Speaker 0: Well, they're smart.
Speaker 0: They're already fleeing.
Speaker 0: They don't need us to tell them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, apparently they've been fleeing for many years.
Speaker 1: So I found some article that basically said nail plus coffin.
Speaker 1: So yeah.
Speaker 0: This is so sad.
Speaker 1: So anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: Time for the thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I feel no bad.
Speaker 0: I'm going to make fun of the elite because they are so stupid and hurting the scientists.
Speaker 1: I am a big fan of anger, also a fan of Son of Destroy, just like you.
Speaker 1: I don't even want to talk about this beyond what I just said, but basically there is a blogspot site called fighthardyat.blogspot.com.
Speaker 0: Fight hard, yeah.
Speaker 1: And fighthardyat, the proprietor of this fine internet establishment, sent a comment to the angry video game nerd, James Rolfe.
Speaker 1: And this is a video of him simply reading this comment out loud and he is unable to not lose his shit.
Speaker 0: Shit all lost.
Speaker 0: Fucks all given.
Speaker 1: He in fact lives like a Windrammer as he fucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would tell you talk all about this fighthardyat person and tell you everything there is to know about them.
Speaker 0: But you can learn everything that I know and more by reading the blog and the Twitter if you wish to find out.
Speaker 1: So here are the top two YouTube comments on this video.
Speaker 1: One, 119 people don't see their futures in balls.
Speaker 1: That's the number of dislikes.
Speaker 1: Other comment, the next time James fucks it's going to be real awkward when he starts laughing his ass off uncontrollably.
Speaker 1: Just watch this.
Speaker 1: There's something about watching someone else trying not to laugh and laughing anyway.
Speaker 1: And also, live like a Windrammer as you fuck is one of the greatest compliments or pieces of advice you can ever give to a human being.
Speaker 0: Okay, so there's this high school, right?
Speaker 0: It's called Whitney Young.
Speaker 0: I guess you can learn about it according to the YouTube comments.
Speaker 0: It's a magnet school and whatever.
Speaker 1: I've heard of that school.
Speaker 1: It's talked about on Fark kind of often.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: It seems to be a pretty cool place based on this vertical video.
Speaker 0: But this vertical video in the content of the video, while the framing and quality is low, the content is very, very high.
Speaker 1: So it's kind of a random piece of advice.
Speaker 1: If you ever think you should take video vertically.
Speaker 0: I don't even know why the phones fucking let you.
Speaker 0: The phones should just always make the video sideways and then you hold it up and you'll realize.
Speaker 1: Aspect ratio of the sensor, that's why.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: If I turn the camera, the sensor is probably in a 16 by 9 configuration.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So if I turn my HD camera sideways, it's getting video like that regardless of how it displays it.
Speaker 0: No, what it should do is it should just always.
Speaker 1: Shock you?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: It should just have an electric shock.
Speaker 0: It should always like this video, right?
Speaker 0: This one is a vertical video.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If somebody, if you try to unload this from your phone, it should come out 1990 degrees rotated to the left.
Speaker 0: So everyone's lying on their side because you fucked up taking the video.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Anyway, in this video, what happens is some student started with this sort of cool, funky prank.
Speaker 0: A totally harmless prank, the kind that everyone enjoys.
Speaker 0: They would play music by like, you know, with improvised percussion elements like banging chairs on the floor or slapping tables.
Speaker 0: And this kid would go find people, usually teachers or other people who weren't in on it, and sort of do a little funky dance, right?
Speaker 0: Get up right in front of their face, do a funky dance.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: And it's like you do that to someone and then walk away.
Speaker 0: And he'd be like, oh, that's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: That's pretty great.
Speaker 0: I like that.
Speaker 0: He went up to.
Speaker 0: so he goes up and people are starting to get more excited about this as he keeps doing it more and more.
Speaker 0: Turns into like a little mini party, right?
Speaker 0: Goes up in front of this one dude teacher.
Speaker 0: He looks like a teacher standing there.
Speaker 0: Does his funky dance.
Speaker 0: Does it so hard he loses a shoe.
Speaker 0: Then gets out the way because he finished doing it on that guy.
Speaker 1: So there's either two ways this could go.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Either the teacher beats the shit out of it or the teacher dances the shit out of it.
Speaker 0: You got to see the dance.
Speaker 0: this teacher lays out.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to tell you which dance it is.
Speaker 0: And I'm not going to.
Speaker 1: Is it Gagnam style?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: But he I'm going to tell you which dance it not is.
Speaker 0: It not is Gagnam style.
Speaker 0: The teacher busts out a dance and of course the students are like super awesome reaction.
Speaker 0: that makes the video worth watching.
Speaker 1: Do they all start dancing?
Speaker 0: It gets crazy going on.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment this weekend is the burning con.
Speaker 0: Too late to sign up.
Speaker 0: If you're going you're awesome not going pussy.
Speaker 1: As a as a meta thing.
Speaker 1: Luke Crane posted a list of advice which while it is advice specifically for burning con.
Speaker 1: If you ever run a role playing game at any convention ever a one off.
Speaker 1: and you don't follow all of this advice.
Speaker 1: You are terrible.
Speaker 0: Read the advice.
Speaker 1: I'm going to read it because it's really quick.
Speaker 1: Here's a list of basic things you need.
Speaker 1: One an idea of the scenario or situation.
Speaker 0: You don't even need to know the whole fucking thing.
Speaker 0: You just need to have an idea.
Speaker 1: Two characters provide that shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah you don't have time to burn that shit up or roll characters.
Speaker 0: Provide all game materials.
Speaker 1: Have dice, cards, anything you need.
Speaker 0: Yeah some people don't have dice I guess.
Speaker 1: Have notes, sketches, obstacles written down already.
Speaker 0: Oh good idea.
Speaker 1: Have, here's the big one, have at least one twist.
Speaker 1: Something new that changes the starting dynamic but not more than three.
Speaker 1: You find a magic sword.
Speaker 1: You must decide who gets it.
Speaker 1: And then you have to find your way out of the dungeon.
Speaker 0: Yeah because what happens is a lot of times people make a scenario that has like an obstacle.
Speaker 0: Like beat the monster, we beat it.
Speaker 0: The end.
Speaker 0: You got to have something else to fill in your four hour session.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 1: So.
Speaker 1: Now you could just have a really long session but then the dynamic stays the same.
Speaker 1: It gets stale.
Speaker 1: Peter's out.
Speaker 1: People look at their cell phones.
Speaker 0: Yeah people are going to play and then whatever they're playing goes.
Speaker 0: you need to do something to sort of restart the game as it winds down.
Speaker 1: So more importantly.
Speaker 0: I need to keep restarting it and putting the sparks on over and over until you get to the end of the time.
Speaker 1: Until that spark hinders the burning wheel.
Speaker 0: And then les denommons.
Speaker 1: Here are the things not to do.
Speaker 1: Don't sit back and expect the players to do all the work.
Speaker 0: Duh.
Speaker 1: Yeah say that to 99% of the people who have ever run games for me at any convention ever.
Speaker 1: Don't over prepare.
Speaker 1: Don't plan such a detailed scenario.
Speaker 1: You'll never hope to finish it.
Speaker 0: I almost did that by accident but then I corrected myself.
Speaker 1: Do not setting dump.
Speaker 1: If I catch you saying more than one minute of world or setting info I will be very angry.
Speaker 0: I almost did that as well and I corrected that mistake.
Speaker 1: And do not explain the rules.
Speaker 1: Demonstrate the rules.
Speaker 0: That is also correct.
Speaker 1: BurningCon is going to be great.
Speaker 1: My game is in the first slot on Saturday.
Speaker 1: It is called the Ark of Obscenities.
Speaker 1: So if you want to play in my game it is in the first session and you should try to get into my game.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll play in your game and crash it.
Speaker 1: You should try.
Speaker 1: I was told by one of the people who was in my game at the last BurningCon that it was the best game they played in at the entire BurningCon.
Speaker 1: I was very proud of that.
Speaker 0: We'll have to compete and see whose game is better because I think mine is in the last slot on Sunday which means hardly anyone is going to be there.
Speaker 1: I should play in your game.
Speaker 0: It's going to be a quieter game.
Speaker 1: So, Magfest is coming up in a ways.
Speaker 1: In January.
Speaker 1: Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: Even later than that.
Speaker 1: PAX Australia is officially officially announced.
Speaker 1: We'll probably be there.
Speaker 1: PAX East.
Speaker 1: Yeah, three day badges sold out.
Speaker 1: We told you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we told you.
Speaker 1: Single day badges are not sold out.
Speaker 1: However, the reason they are not sold out is because all the hotels are sold out.
Speaker 1: There are no hotels within two miles of the convention.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now that New York Comic Con is over, there really aren't any cons until Magfest.
Speaker 0: So, there's probably going to be more geek nights.
Speaker 0: There's going to be some American holidays and Universal holidays and things like that.
Speaker 0: There's going to be fucking snow.
Speaker 1: And then I'm going to go skiing every weekend.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's going to be a lot of book reading and comic reading and video game and playing.
Speaker 1: The Book Club book right now is The Name of the Wind.
Speaker 1: Scott Joseph.
Speaker 0: By Patrick Rothfuss.
Speaker 0: Rothfuss.
Speaker 0: I've already finished reading it.
Speaker 1: I am 21% through.
Speaker 0: Nice.
Speaker 1: I'll probably blow through it this weekend.
Speaker 0: And you should read that shit and you should go on...
Speaker 1: I got to the point where shit got fucked up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you should go on the internets and read all about us on the internets.
Speaker 1: It has a good tendency to do something that a lot of books don't do.
Speaker 1: Where it'll overstep itself and kind of tell you the aftermath of something.
Speaker 1: And it takes you a while to realize, "Oh wait, something bad
Speaker 1: happened.".
Speaker 1: And then it backs up and tells you what bad happened.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, "Yeah, that was before the Great
Speaker 0: Cataclysm.".
Speaker 0: And then there'll be a story years before the Great Cataclysm.
Speaker 0: And they'll be like, "Yeah, five years before the Great
Speaker 0: Cataclysm.".
Speaker 0: And they start telling the story about five years before the Great Cataclysm.
Speaker 0: And you're like, "What the fuck is a Great
Speaker 0: Cataclysm?".
Speaker 0: And then eventually the story gets to the point where the Great Cataclysm happens.
Speaker 0: And you're like, "Oh, the Great
Speaker 0: Cataclysm.".
Speaker 1: Or there's a point where things are pretty happy.
Speaker 1: and then a character says something like, "Out of nowhere, in the middle of this happy story,".
Speaker 1: the character's like, "And I really hope that those people spent those last few hours
Speaker 1: well.".
Speaker 1: And you're like, "Wait a minute, what do you mean last few
Speaker 1: hours?".
Speaker 1: Then the next chapter is basically the fucking.
Speaker 0: It's like if the title of the book was "The Guy Named Scott Who Died in Chapter
Speaker 0: Two.".
Speaker 0: And then you read the book and there's a guy named Scott who dies in chapter two.
Speaker 0: All right, so yeah, go to frontrecruit.com and click on all the things.
Speaker 1: Oh, and there's probably a new Radio Free Equestria up to celebrate the fact that the real season three is going to start in, what, 19 days?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I'm going to send out the next newsletter real soon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I will tell you all that because there is enough interest, we will attempt to do an episode of Radio Free Equestria after every episode of Ponies for as long as we can in season three.
Speaker 1: We have streamlined our video production process over the last year to a degree that I'm actually pretty comfortable saying that.
Speaker 1: We got other video coming in the works, stay tuned.
Speaker 0: All right, so submitting to Open Source Projects.
Speaker 0: So here's the deal, we actually went into the thread on our forum that said "Show ideas and reminders" and found this idea because we're really low on Monday ideas the most compared to the other days.
Speaker 0: And it's a good idea, I got a lot to say.
Speaker 0: So here's the deal, is Open Source Projects out there, right?
Speaker 0: And the idea of Open Source, if you don't know, you've been living under 10 rocks, is you have some sort of software project and people all around the world work on this project.
Speaker 0: You can just walk in, you know, do some, you know, improve the project, you know, modify it in some way and share your improvement with the other people who use and work on that project.
Speaker 0: And, you know, then maybe it will be incorporated into the, you know, it'll be, you know, shared by everyone because it's such a good improvement.
Speaker 0: And more people do that, the project just keeps on improving and improving and getting better all the time.
Speaker 0: So if you encounter an Open Source Project and you have something you want to do to it or you come up with an idea or there's a bug and you want to fix it or something, how do you actually, you know, get to work on that shit?
Speaker 0: This is something a lot of people have a problem with.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 1: It's kind of an aside, but we'll get back to this, but there's a much more fundamental problem in that a lot of people who have skills that many Open Source Projects really need, the one thing that those people are not is programmers.
Speaker 1: So a guy who actually, like, fully designs a specification or makes, like, a whole new awesome icon set usually has no idea how they could possibly contribute that and they need someone else to basically help them and contribute it for them to most projects because most Open Source Projects are really, really unfriendly and unresponsive to non-programmers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the other thing is that, you know, if you're running an Open Source Project, you know, you made something, you make it Open Source, how do you handle people submitting to you, right?
Speaker 0: So basically what it comes down to is every project is different and this is why this sucks because there is no one right answer.
Speaker 0: Every single Open Source Project in the world decides for itself what bureaucratic system to set up around who and when and which submissions and modifications are going to make it into the official build and which ones are not.
Speaker 0: And so you have to figure out whatever project you want to work on, you have to get involved with the community surrounding the project if there is one and read their documentation and talk to the people who run it and figure out how to get your stuff in there.
Speaker 0: Now, it could be a very small project, like one guy just put his thing on GitHub, in which case maybe you can just fork him on GitHub, you know, make a modification, push it to your thing, click on the GitHub pull request and you're done.
Speaker 0: And maybe the guy will like it and he'll let it in and that's the simplest it could possibly be.
Speaker 0: But maybe you want to submit to the Linux kernel, in which case you have to get on the kernel mailing list and you have to, you know, make sure that you write your, you know, you have to git clone the kernel and you got to make your modification in just the right way and you have to, you know, write your commit message in just the right way.
Speaker 0: You can't talk to Linus Torvalds usually, you have to talk to some lieutenant who deals with the part of the kernel that you work on and you have to email him your patch the proper way and get whoever that is lieutenant to like your commit and integrate it and make sure it works with everything else that's going on and you submit it at the right time and then if it gets incorporated, maybe it'll get in there.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 1: Now, meanwhile, if you're, say, you know, trying to help some open source project with a horrible UI, have a new UI, you've got to find some programmer to wire up or write the UI.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, the people who write the UI usually know shit about design.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So as a result, we have this dichotomy of there are people who cannot commit anything to open source projects because you can really only submit code.
Speaker 1: Very few projects have any way for you to submit anything other than just code.
Speaker 0: Well, there are things you can do to help open source projects besides code.
Speaker 0: For example, you can file bugs, which I do often.
Speaker 0: True.
Speaker 0: And all you have to do for that is usually find whatever bug tracking system they're using, which could be GitHub, it could be Bugzilla.
Speaker 1: You know why I stopped doing that?
Speaker 0: It could be Track.
Speaker 1: Almost every bug I ever submitted to any open source project ever was responded to with a won't fix and very little communication, and then I just didn't give a shit anymore.
Speaker 0: I've had that a couple times, but usually the bugs I submit are mega bugs but they aren't important enough to actually get anyone to fix them, but they get a lot of comments and they hang around for years.
Speaker 0: I had this Ubuntu bug since like '07, and I've got a Chrome bug that's sitting around.
Speaker 1: I'll put it this way, I manage the entire QA department.
Speaker 0: And every once in a while, I get emails from these bugs that I'm still tracking because someone comments on them.
Speaker 1: I manage the entire QA department.
Speaker 1: The one thing I've learned is that most developers fucking hate it when you give them a bug and don't want to fix it.
Speaker 0: I don't really care if someone sends me a bug, you know, I fix it.
Speaker 1: Well, because usually the bug, it's easy to find these sort of like easy to fix bugs, but I have a knack for finding bugs that are almost impossible to fix or even replicate.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: See, I have a knack for finding bugs where it's hard to figure out who's responsible for them.
Speaker 0: So there'll be arguments like, "You fix
Speaker 0: it."
Speaker 0: "No, your code's
Speaker 0: broken."
Speaker 0: "No, no, no, your code's
Speaker 0: broken.".
Speaker 0: You don't even know which project needs to be fixed, right?
Speaker 1: That's when you've got like, like in Python, you've got a Python SOAP library, but it's connecting to like some other SOAP server.
Speaker 1: And the Python library does something one way in the SOAP request, and the server is set up to where it can't handle that.
Speaker 1: It needs a slightly different format.
Speaker 0: Well, let's say you have a problem in Ubuntu, right?
Speaker 0: For example.
Speaker 0: Ubuntu is a combination of thousands of different open source projects all put together in one.
Speaker 0: If there's a bug in something, that bug could be in actually 20 different open source projects.
Speaker 0: There's no way to know which one really is the one that's wrong.
Speaker 0: And if, you know, all of them individually will say, "There's nothing wrong with me.
Speaker 0: I'm doing
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: So the bug is actually only in that particular combination.
Speaker 1: Now that is what I was getting at.
Speaker 1: One of the most important things, you know, software engineering as opposed to computer science, is managing like the project as a whole.
Speaker 1: And the arbiter of this is this responsibility or that responsibility.
Speaker 1: This class has to deal with that.
Speaker 1: This application, this service, whatever.
Speaker 0: If that person changes their piece to get that combination to work, it'll break a different legal combination.
Speaker 1: So in my experience, most people who run small to like the lower end of middling open source projects manage the whole thing themselves and they won't accept any assistance from someone who would help them manage it on that level but simultaneously desperately need someone to do that because they won't do it.
Speaker 1: They just won't make the decision.
Speaker 1: And then the thing languishes and the community fights over it forever.
Speaker 0: The other thing I see a lot that bothers me is some projects, usually larger, more established ones, will have very high barriers to entry for submitting things, right?
Speaker 0: Like the thing you see a lot is they won't accept something from someone they don't know.
Speaker 0: So even if you do some great work, you're just a user.
Speaker 0: You're not involved in their community.
Speaker 0: You don't know them.
Speaker 0: And you're just a user, but you also have skills and you get the code for the project and you work on it and you do something kind of awesome maybe.
Speaker 0: Or maybe you just fixed a small bug.
Speaker 0: Who knows what you did?
Speaker 0: And you just send it in and say, "Hey guys, I did this
Speaker 0: thing.".
Speaker 0: They'll just reject it because they don't know you.
Speaker 0: Like, "Who is this?
Speaker 0: This wasn't
Speaker 0: discussed.".
Speaker 0: It's like in order to really get something submitted, especially to a larger project, they forced you to be involved in their community.
Speaker 0: Now seriously, I have no time for that crap.
Speaker 0: If I was involved in the communities of all the things that I use, I couldn't do anything else in my whole life.
Speaker 0: I couldn't do any geek nights.
Speaker 0: I couldn't do video games.
Speaker 0: I couldn't do anything, right?
Speaker 0: There'd be so many fucking communities, right?
Speaker 0: I just don't have time to be involved in them.
Speaker 0: If I can submit something to an open source project, it really has to be, "Here's my code.
Speaker 0: You guys who really care about this project way more than I do.
Speaker 0: This is the extent of the effort I'm willing to exert for you.
Speaker 0: If you like this, you have to do the rest of the
Speaker 0: work.".
Speaker 0: But none of them care about the code that I wrote, so that code just sits there and doesn't get in.
Speaker 1: The worst thing is you can't even just pay lip service usually.
Speaker 1: You have to go to their forum or their mailing list.
Speaker 0: Usually it's mailing lists and IRCs.
Speaker 1: And you usually have to have unrelated conversations about generic crap because you have to be friends with them and all this.
Speaker 1: So you get to the situation where you've got this balkanized, "Let's have the same conversation about politics across 11
Speaker 1: forums.".
Speaker 0: Now something else you can do, right?
Speaker 0: If there's a modification that they won't accept and merge or whatever into the official build, you can just, every time they put out a new release, get their updated code, merge your code in and use your own personal modified version because that's what open source is all about.
Speaker 0: But that's just a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: Also, the other thing you can do is fork.
Speaker 0: Your own personal fork.
Speaker 0: That is, your own personal fork.
Speaker 1: No, but fork it publicly and shame them.
Speaker 0: But if you make a public fork, now you're managing an open source project and now you've got to build a community.
Speaker 0: Because that's the thing, every open source project, to be successful, needs to have a community.
Speaker 0: You can't just put code out there, not have anyone managing it or having anything like that and expect it to just magically work.
Speaker 0: An open source project needs a community to succeed.
Speaker 0: So if you put code out there, if you don't start the community and no one else starts the community supporting that code, it's just going to sit there unused and unnoticed and your fork will fail.
Speaker 0: And communities also decide, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, think about X11, you know, X80, that original one, right?
Speaker 0: Why did it fail?
Speaker 0: Because the community moved to Xorg, right?
Speaker 0: LibreOffice, the community moved to LibreOffice.
Speaker 0: That's what really makes the decisions.
Speaker 0: The decisions aren't really made by the person in charge of the project.
Speaker 0: The decisions are made by which project the community endorses in the cases of forking.
Speaker 1: And then beyond all that, there is the final barrier.
Speaker 0: There are more barriers.
Speaker 0: I think your barrier might not be the final one.
Speaker 1: When I say the final, I mean the one that usually ends anyone's interest is the drama barrier.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, that has to do with the community again.
Speaker 0: But the other barrier, the true final one, if you can't think of any others, right, is the projects that have high technical requirements for submitting, right?
Speaker 0: They might be willing to accept a patch from a stranger coming out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: And they might be, your patch might be totally awesome and totally work, but they'll demand like it must fit our coding style or it must, you must write tests in our testing format and your tests had to be complete enough and have enough coverage and you have to document what you did and modify the documentation also.
Speaker 0: It's like, look, dude, I just wanted to write this code and change this icon.
Speaker 0: Well, I think that's actually- I don't have time to write documentation and tests.
Speaker 0: You take care of that shit.
Speaker 1: That is a subset of the more fundamental problem of without a sort of like software engineer or manager who is vested, there's a lot of pieces.
Speaker 1: All the glue of software is the part that nobody actually wants to do.
Speaker 1: And that's the part where most open source software really starts to fall down.
Speaker 1: Like even if someone, like Scott said, you write the patch and it'll work just fine.
Speaker 1: But that last 5% of the work to make it conform and test and integrate really well takes more effort than the first 95%.
Speaker 1: And it's boring effort.
Speaker 1: So it's almost like to have a really successful open source project that isn't big enough to where people are willing to do that.
Speaker 1: just for the street cred is.
Speaker 1: you almost would want to have a way where the project generates money either by donations or something and hire one developer to manage all the stuff that no one else will do.
Speaker 0: Well, usually you look at Linux, right?
Speaker 0: Most of the big submissions to Linux actually come from people who work at Red Hat, NVIDIA, IBM, places like that.
Speaker 0: Which is a huge problem because- Those companies hire people to write things, to work on the Linux kernel, but they're full paid employees of Red Hat and they submit patches to the kernel that Red Hat needs.
Speaker 0: The same way that I would submit patches to the kernel that I needed if I needed a patch to the kernel.
Speaker 1: Now the trouble is, so all right, we see that a large chunk of the patches submitted to Linux are from these basically funded developers because other people need stuff.
Speaker 1: Companies like Red Hat and all these sort of enterprise-y Linuxes, I don't think have much of a future.
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 1: I don't think the revenue streams will exist in the long run.
Speaker 1: I mean, as a senior IT guy, a production engineer and all this stuff for all these years, there is literally no reason to use Red Hat over CentOS, ever.
Speaker 1: But yet, how long will people pay for Red Hat?
Speaker 1: And if people stop paying for Red Hat, then who's going to commit the code to make CentOS keep working?
Speaker 1: And as an aside, CentOS and Red Hat both.
Speaker 1: I installed an Ubuntu recently just to get a server going for some things I wanted to test in VirtualBox.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, I forgot how much I hate Red Hat and CentOS and any of that branch of Linux.
Speaker 1: Kind of an aside though, but what do we do if it turns out that some of the major open source code is actually coming out of these sort of subsidized developers, how do we get that code written if the companies that subsidize it disappear?
Speaker 0: It's mostly just Linux has this problem.
Speaker 0: No other open source project really has this.
Speaker 1: Well that's because Linux is languishing because the desktop side of it has completely fallen behind the rest of the world.
Speaker 1: Desktop Linux is unusable unless you don't use your computer.
Speaker 0: Well, it's surprising.
Speaker 0: In some ways, desktop Linux kicks all the ass and in some ways it fails all the fail.
Speaker 0: But those aspects of it really don't have anything to do with the kernel.
Speaker 0: That has to do with other things.
Speaker 1: Well here's two differences.
Speaker 1: If my laptop were Linux and some stuff in my file system got corrupt, I could fix it with Yum.
Speaker 1: Or Avget in this case.
Speaker 1: But I can't do that with Windows.
Speaker 0: So this might sound really discouraging to anyone who wants to submit to an open source project.
Speaker 0: Talking about all these barriers to entry and stuff.
Speaker 0: But the fact is, most of the projects out there aren't big scary ones.
Speaker 0: Most of them actually are the completely deserted ones.
Speaker 0: Some guy wrote some code, he posted it on his GitHub and he doesn't pay attention to it.
Speaker 0: And if you fork it or something, nobody's going to notice if you send him a pull request because he's not even paying attention to that.
Speaker 0: So your best option is that you can take that code, look at what license it is.
Speaker 0: Always worry about licenses.
Speaker 0: We did an episode about licenses.
Speaker 0: You might want to go listen to it.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure we did.
Speaker 0: I think we did.
Speaker 0: Or go online and go to the OSI website and read about the licenses.
Speaker 0: It explains all the differences between them in plain English.
Speaker 0: And check what license each project uses before you do anything.
Speaker 0: So you understand what you're getting into.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if you see an abandoned project and no one's paying attention to it, really the way to submit to it is to take it and make it your project and become the guy who runs it.
Speaker 0: Because if you try to send the patches to the guy who originally wrote it, he doesn't give a shit anymore about it.
Speaker 1: Now, while that's all well and good, I think we still have to come up with the solution to the problem of.
Speaker 1: there are non-code resources that a lot of open source projects need.
Speaker 1: The people best suited to doing that work are basically completely discouraged from even interacting with the community or ever submitting anything.
Speaker 0: There's no way that they just can't unless they have somebody to tag team them to help them to do the rest of the work for them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so should open source projects that need UIs find graphic designers and try to work with them?
Speaker 1: Because no one seems to do that.
Speaker 0: Ubuntu has an art team.
Speaker 0: I know, Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: If you're not, it's open source, right?
Speaker 0: You can't force anyone to do anything.
Speaker 0: So if someone submits a patch with no documentation and no tests and it's your policy not to accept that documentation and tests and nobody wants to write documentation and tests, you can't force them.
Speaker 0: If someone sends in an icon set to make your icons look nicer and nobody wants to wire it up or cut it and forget everything in the right place, you can't make anyone do it.
Speaker 0: There's a ticket there and it's up to someone else to of their own volition, go and make it happen or the volition of the artist who sent it to learn how to do it or join the community and see if anyone in the community will willingly help them figure it out and get the skills to do it.
Speaker 0: That's all there.
Speaker 0: You know, if you can't force someone to do it, maybe you can pay someone with donations.
Speaker 0: Even then, they might not do it, even though you paid the money.
Speaker 1: It's tricky, too, because a lot of people...
Speaker 0: That's what open source is.
Speaker 0: If you don't want that, make a company and hire someone to do it.
Speaker 1: It's tricky, too, because I remember when there was a big movement to make a sort of distributed DNS system a while ago after some peer-to-peer news.
Speaker 1: This was some years ago.
Speaker 1: So a bunch of people got together and set up this open source project to make this distributed DNS and I jumped on board to try to help these people out and work with them.
Speaker 1: After about a week, I realized that every single person involved had no idea what they were doing and there was literally no one who was going to take over and manage the thing.
Speaker 1: Then I just backed away and I watched the whole thing collapse.
Speaker 0: I would have not even looked.
Speaker 1: I looked because I feel like something like that would be useful, but everyone who was involved was either someone who didn't know anything but cared about piracy or people who appeared to be developers who could probably write good code
Speaker 0: who didn't
Speaker 1: know anything about the project and were unwilling to let someone else dictate the architecture.
Speaker 1: So egos seem to get in the way more than anything in my own experience, but I don't submit code.
Speaker 1: I submit other things.
Speaker 1: Actually, I don't submit anything anymore, but there definitely is a particular ego problem of.
Speaker 1: I feel like a lot of people who write software and commit to open source projects are a little resentful of people who don't write code, but have other things they could contribute getting into their playground.
Speaker 0: Well, they're also, think about it, these are people who are actually doing work for nothing.
Speaker 0: So if their work that they did for nothing ends up being thrown away, it's like I spent two weeks on that to make this thing awesome and you guys rejected it.
Speaker 0: It's not going to get in there.
Speaker 0: No one's going to use that code I worked so hard on.
Speaker 0: Fuck you guys.
Speaker 0: Even a non drama person, a chill person, you could see how with certain situations that are just necessary in the management of an open source project will cause, you know, not bad people really to, you know, do dramatic things.
Speaker 1: That happens in closed source communities.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So an open source community of a significant size when you get more than a few people becomes one of the most difficult kinds of online community to manage effectively.
Speaker 0: Jono Bacon is a guy.
Speaker 0: He's in a metal band.
Speaker 0: He's from the UK and his job title is, I believe it still is community manager at Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: So he's the top community guy at Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: He wrote a book that you can get for free Creative Commons ish.
Speaker 0: You can also pay for it, I think, called The Art of Community.
Speaker 0: And it pretty much has the instructions on how to manage an open source community or an online community in general down to the like ditty details of like.
Speaker 0: you should ban a person from a forum if this and manage your IRC like that and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: We did a lecture like that, but it was more about like communities around games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was more.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you should check out that book if there's something really appeals to you.
Speaker 0: But if you're an open source person or if you want to get involved in open source and this whole thing has scared you a fuck ton.
Speaker 0: Here's just do what I tell you.
Speaker 0: Find the project on GitHub that people are actually working on.
Speaker 0: And the way you can tell is if it's had commits recently.
Speaker 1: Now, it has to also be a project that you care about somehow.
Speaker 0: And there's something that you want to change on it that you're capable of changing.
Speaker 0: Just click the fork button, clone the code, you know, make your change in your fix, push it back to GitHub and use the pull request button and just stick to working on projects that use GitHub pull requests, at least for the near future.
Speaker 0: to when this podcast was made before, you know, GitHub dies.
Speaker 0: Something replaces.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Learn how to use Git properly and just commit to projects that are that scale that work that way.
Speaker 0: And if you really want to submit to some other project that has its own thing, you just had to get involved in the community for that project.
Speaker 0: There's no way around it.
Speaker 0: The same way you should get involved in like the community because you don't have to submit anything.
Speaker 0: There's less drama.
Speaker 0: No drama.
Speaker 1: Oh, I just I've read the XKC for today.
Speaker 1: It's about drama.
Speaker 0: Oh, how about?
Speaker 1: the graphics didn't correct, though?
Speaker 0: Nice.
Speaker 1: It says that the rate at which people create drama is proportional to often they declare the hate drama and always avoid it.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, because I hate drama and always avoid it.
Speaker 0: How much drama do I create?
Speaker 0: Unless how much drama do you think I got?
Speaker 1: So what I'm saying is there's a possibility that you and I are, in fact, like revenants in the.
Speaker 0: well, you know, that could be.
Speaker 0: that could be one looking at the.
Speaker 1: because here's the here's the revenues work, right?
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 1: In an interview with a vampire.
Speaker 1: So if I if I'm a vampire, so they were vampires, I bite someone and I have them drink my blood.
Speaker 1: They become a vampire, too.
Speaker 0: Wait, you have them drink your blood?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You got to do a thing.
Speaker 1: If I just bite someone, leave them.
Speaker 1: They turn into this mindless vampire that goes around killing people and you leave them behind.
Speaker 1: So you leave behind this trail of bullshit.
Speaker 1: It is possible that we do, in fact, cause a lot of drama, but only in the people we leave behind or pass by.
Speaker 0: See, I'm thinking you look at remember Otacon.
Speaker 0: Look at this graph.
Speaker 0: This is clearly, you know, not a straight plot.
Speaker 0: This is one of those ones where you scatter plot and then you draw the line.
Speaker 1: You're saying we're down here.
Speaker 0: This is where we're one of those dots.
Speaker 0: that's way outlying.
Speaker 0: But we're just.
Speaker 0: you know, the dots aren't on this rendering of the graph.
Speaker 1: because remember, we were in the Otacon staff.
Speaker 1: We quit basically because of all the drama around us.
Speaker 0: And we don't have zero.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to say we have zero drama, but I'm saying we left behind a hornet's nest of drama.
Speaker 1: But none of it actually involved us.
Speaker 1: We just left it there.
Speaker 0: That hornet's nest was already hornet's nest.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess us walking in disturbed it and then we left and it's still disturbed.
Speaker 0: We didn't disturb it that much.
Speaker 0: It's always been disturbed.
Speaker 1: I think it's more disturbed.
Speaker 0: Like two or three wasps got a little bit more pissed off.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I learned recently that apparently a bunch of people within that still specifically hold a grudge and in fact talk about it whenever even unprompted.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: I learned about this a few days ago.
Speaker 0: How do you know this is true?
Speaker 1: I trust the person who told me.
Speaker 0: It's such evidence that it's so strong.
Speaker 1: I trust the person.
Speaker 1: I mean, if someone lies to me about this, that is also drama.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: So either one.
Speaker 0: But that's the exact kind of thing a drama person would say.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So there is drama regardless of whether or not they lie, therefore there is drama.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.