Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, July 18th, 2012.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And we're Geek Nites back from Kineticon.
Speaker 1: Tonight, the in-call, the epic journey sent to us by Teemo.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: We're back, we're back.
Speaker 1: Kineticon was last weekend.
Speaker 1: My voice is mostly recovered.
Speaker 0: My voice never faded.
Speaker 1: Mine got a little faded by Sunday, but then again, I was running around and putting out, well, actually, you know what?
Speaker 1: Compared to previous Kineticons and previous conventions we've been to, there were relatively few troubles to deal with.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know.
Speaker 0: There wasn't really any big trouble that was involving us.
Speaker 0: I mean, no conventions perfect, but there wasn't anything.
Speaker 0: devastatingly, "Oh no, everything's screwed
Speaker 0: up.".
Speaker 1: The con went awesomely.
Speaker 1: The attendance was the most it'd ever been.
Speaker 1: We had more panels than we'd ever had.
Speaker 1: I think we had over 230 panels, workshops, and lectures across 12 rooms for three days.
Speaker 1: I feel particularly accomplished that we were able to pull that off.
Speaker 1: And Scott and I single-handedly ran each one of them.
Speaker 1: No, but we were the heads of panels and workshops.
Speaker 1: So if you were at Kineticon, I hope you had a good time.
Speaker 1: If you're one of those random dudes who complained that there were no good panels, I suggest that you have no idea what you're talking about.
Speaker 0: I suggest you submit some or don't just judge them and decide they're no good based on the title.
Speaker 0: You can't be telling me a panel wasn't good if you didn't go to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The thing is the guy who, there's one guy and I saw him all over the internet.
Speaker 1: Like I think it's the same guy.
Speaker 1: He's the only guy I see who was actually complaining as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: And basically his complaint was there were no good panels.
Speaker 1: All I wanted to see was that guy with the glasses and I couldn't get into his thing.
Speaker 0: I think the thing is a lot of, uh, with Kineticon, right?
Speaker 0: It's, we have so many panels covering so many different areas that if you're only interested in one area, we don't really have that much for you.
Speaker 0: Like if you're just into manga, it's like how many manga specific panels are there?
Speaker 1: Actually for us, there were almost no manga panels and relatively few anime panels because we got fewer anime panel submissions than we've ever gotten.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know, if there's one, if you're only into one nerdery, you've only got a few panels to go to and then you should, if you're, you should either a get into some more geekeries or B spend the rest of the con doing something else or maybe engaging in that geekery.
Speaker 1: I feel like that's not actually a concern because the fact is almost every panel was very well attended.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We have notes on everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Kineticon went awesomely.
Speaker 0: Too much Kineticon discussion.
Speaker 0: Let's move on.
Speaker 1: It was a big part of the last six months of my life and I don't have to worry about it for at least a couple months.
Speaker 1: But it was awesome.
Speaker 1: I want to really, uh, give special thanks to Charles Dunbar for coming and doing his thing and a more specifically to Dave Riley and his crew for actually showing up at something.
Speaker 0: I even almost on time.
Speaker 1: he showed up, he started his panel on time.
Speaker 0: Almost on time.
Speaker 1: What was great is there's a big audience and he gets there and he's like, oh my God, are all these people here to see me?
Speaker 1: And I was like, what have I been saying for the past, I don't know, three years that you should do stuff at cons.
Speaker 1: So hopefully there will be more Dave Riley stuff at conventions.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, it was awesome.
Speaker 1: We'll review it on some other day in the far flung future.
Speaker 1: And if you want to run a panel workshop or lecture at Kineticon, we're going to open up submissions for 2013 in a month or two, probably whenever we can.
Speaker 0: Uh, anything else going on?
Speaker 1: But you're the one who wanted to stop talking about Kineticon.
Speaker 0: All right, let's talk about something else.
Speaker 1: I guess you had something to say.
Speaker 0: So check this out.
Speaker 0: I'm checking.
Speaker 0: Usually, you know, big time manga creators, you know, they're not the easiest people to, to meet and greet.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like comic creators in the US.
Speaker 0: You can see the artist Ali and such, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And you know, anime creators, you can see some of them at conventions even in the US, but a manga creator, pretty rare.
Speaker 0: I guess some of them go to manga next.
Speaker 0: Does that still exist?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I've never actually been to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, it's, it's much rarer to find one of them, especially the big name ones.
Speaker 0: But here's the thing that's actually happened in Japan though, but still rare.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the conference of the manga guest of honor of Japan expo Naoki Urasawa took place yesterday, not, not actually yesterday because this article is from July 8th, so July 7th and had great moments in store for the audience of the main stage.
Speaker 0: There's all these pictures here.
Speaker 0: I've been drawing on a gigantic whiteboard and he's actually playing like rocking out and playing music for everybody.
Speaker 0: And why don't someone get him to come to the US and do the same thing?
Speaker 1: Well, I remember way back when I was at an amazement, Akira Kamiya was there and not only did he do like the most awesome panels and be the most awesome, like hanging out dude, but one of his panels was a voice acting workshop workshop of how to be a good voice actor.
Speaker 1: And he did a bit of, you want to sound like Ken Shiro and it was pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: So someone, why hasn't he come to the US yet?
Speaker 0: Someone get him to come here and do a panel.
Speaker 0: Jesus Christ.
Speaker 1: You mean come to an anime con in America so five people can see him and be the guest of honor.
Speaker 0: I think more people will see him, right?
Speaker 0: I saw the girl at Kinetic Con this weekend.
Speaker 0: She went to the Namakopia booth and bought the full stack, all 18 volumes of monster.
Speaker 0: She told him, I was like, oh man.
Speaker 0: And she, and she was like, I spent all my money's on this.
Speaker 1: I said that.
Speaker 1: I'm going to make a supposition here.
Speaker 1: If we got him to come to Kinetic Con, I think more people would go to his panel than if he were at Otacon.
Speaker 0: I think it would feel like less people at Otacon because the room would be bigger.
Speaker 1: Well, let's assume we put them both in main events.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: Then it would, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I, it's hard to say.
Speaker 1: I don't, I think they'd be close, but if we did, if you do it on a per capita basis.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, mr didn't know what per capita meant.
Speaker 0: I know what per capita meant.
Speaker 0: Did you?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Does it involve land areas?
Speaker 1: No, I said per capita.
Speaker 0: I know that.
Speaker 0: But the thing is, is that a lot of times people will say per capita, but really they don't know what it means.
Speaker 0: I've seen that happen very often where people will say per capita when they really just mean according to some ratio and they don't really know what the ratio is and they'll just use that word.
Speaker 0: So you can't trust when someone says per capita that they mean per capita.
Speaker 1: I said that you spell potato with an E because I couldn't trust that you didn't know that.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Don't do Donnie.
Speaker 1: Don't anyway.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So, uh, Sailor Moon, you know what amazes me.
Speaker 1: at Connecticut, we ran some anime panels.
Speaker 1: because there's so few people submitted anime panels.
Speaker 1: We ran a good chunk of them.
Speaker 1: Charles ran another big chunk of him and that was most of them.
Speaker 1: So uh, I mentioned offhandedly during the anime openers from around the world panel, which scarily was identical to the one I ran.
Speaker 1: I don't know every time I've ever run that because it's a backup panel to put on early in the morning.
Speaker 0: But did you actually do beyond candy lane?
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, I did the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Cause I was like, oh, that happened.
Speaker 0: I missed it.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: Where'd it go?
Speaker 1: I videoed it too.
Speaker 1: There's proof.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: All I got to say, those slides, I had not looked at them since the last time we ran that.
Speaker 1: We didn't know what the fuck we were doing back then.
Speaker 1: That is an awful panel.
Speaker 1: We're going to rewrite it and redo it.
Speaker 0: I didn't even go to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Room was almost full.
Speaker 1: So anime openers from around the world, right?
Speaker 1: I haven't updated it.
Speaker 1: I only scheduled it because I wanted something to be in the schedule at nine 30 in the morning.
Speaker 1: So the other things at nine 30 in the morning didn't feel all lonesome.
Speaker 1: Like the room almost filled.
Speaker 1: half the people there saw it the previous year and when I told them it's the exact same panel, they cheered.
Speaker 1: So that's how it goes.
Speaker 1: So my tool, you could pretty much run the same dubs.
Speaker 1: The time forgot for the next 10 years.
Speaker 1: No one would notice.
Speaker 0: Do not do.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: The fact that Mike does all original content every time.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's all original every time.
Speaker 1: He said it is all or almost all original content for the dubs of the time.
Speaker 1: Forgot.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Not for, you know, I know he's played the same video.
Speaker 1: I've seen Ivan, all right, at least more than once.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: But I digress.
Speaker 1: So offhandedly I showed some Sailor Moon openers and I said something like, now the new Sailor Moon is probably going to have a different opener.
Speaker 1: And the audience was like, what?
Speaker 1: What do you mean new Sailor Moon?
Speaker 0: And the whole thing, not read the internet.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I was like, all right, how many of you are anime fans?
Speaker 1: And most of the room raised their hands.
Speaker 1: I was like, how many of you read the anime news network?
Speaker 1: Like one person raised their hand.
Speaker 1: Well, no, no.
Speaker 1: A bunch of them raised their hands.
Speaker 1: And I was like, for anything other than just reading anime news, Nina, and like one person still had their hand up.
Speaker 0: They just read anime news Nina and that's it?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Sounds like me.
Speaker 1: I was like, guys, they actually have all the anime news there is.
Speaker 0: So you should probably read it once a week or so.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So yeah.
Speaker 1: New Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: So that's my news there right around the 20 year anniversary of the Sailor Moon manga.
Speaker 1: There was announced that there is going to be a Sailor Moon anime series.
Speaker 0: It's not giving me that scary live action thing.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: It is not film.
Speaker 1: It is definitely animated.
Speaker 1: You can tell how animated news network when this news broke was like, oh shit.
Speaker 1: Because there is the news, which is two paragraphs update, update two, update three, update four, update five.
Speaker 0: The anime news network always does that.
Speaker 0: Their style is to update things like crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Cause they had to jump on.
Speaker 1: this new Sailor Moon is a big deal because as Mike tool pointed out, which is the only reason I was thinking of him right now, there are probably more sales of bootleg Sailor Moon DVDs than any other anime in the U S could be because Sailor Moon is ridiculously popular and has a huge nostalgia fan
Speaker 0: base.
Speaker 1: And it's a great show for young kids.
Speaker 1: And it was on TV in America after school.
Speaker 0: Well, it's one of those things where it was on TV in America after school syndicated.
Speaker 0: So it's just as popular as Voltron, GI Joe, et cetera, perhaps even more popular.
Speaker 0: And those things are all worthwhile apparently financially to bring back transformers even.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But this one, because it was an anime, right.
Speaker 0: Where as opposed to sort of a half anime like transformers, a Thundercats or any of the other things, um, because it was anime after it was on TV and then marketed and then it disappeared.
Speaker 0: And I think they're currently publishing manga of it in the US.
Speaker 0: And I think that also some company has t-shirts with this.
Speaker 0: We love fine of the t-shirts.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Someone has the merchandise license and makes a few t-shirts, but that's pretty much the extent of Sailor Moon being used for money making purposes legally in the United States, despite the fact that it is at the present time recording of this podcast.
Speaker 0: and compare that to say Voltron and Voltron is way more being used by all kinds, DVDs, books, comics, you know, it's all very interesting.
Speaker 0: Sailor Moon is a very underutilized, underexploited license in the United States of America.
Speaker 1: Basically just highlights the absolute dysfunction of the anime industry here that this Sailor Moon is pretty much if I was if I was going to bet on the most guaranteed anime moneymaker there is, I think it's that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It like guaranteed money.
Speaker 1: And yet somehow the show is awful.
Speaker 1: No, no.
Speaker 1: The original the old Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Just taking that old license, just selling DVDs, putting it back on TV, selling.
Speaker 1: I think I would make a load of money, but I digress.
Speaker 0: Well, relative to anime.
Speaker 1: So there's new Sailor Moon and it appears that it is going to be a redo, like a retelling.
Speaker 1: It's going to follow the manga.
Speaker 1: There were rumors that it's going to follow the manga more closely in style, which would be really interesting because if you think the show is trippy, especially like Sailor Stars to the end, you've never seen the Sailor Moon manga.
Speaker 1: It is good.
Speaker 0: Maybe it'll be like the Hakama Kitarou Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: I would watch that.
Speaker 1: I would watch the shit out of that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because Sailor Moon is not what you think it is.
Speaker 1: If you it's all it's basically Green Lantern space bullshit.
Speaker 1: But anime Sailor Moon magical girls style it.
Speaker 1: That is what Sailor Moon is at its core.
Speaker 1: Also lesbians.
Speaker 1: Lots of lesbians.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But we don't know many more details than this.
Speaker 1: And the rumor about that.
Speaker 0: What's in those five updates?
Speaker 0: Any details?
Speaker 1: Oh, so you want to, here's all the details we know as of when we recorded the show reading from the anime news and idol group more.
Speaker 1: Moro Clover Z. Never heard of him is singing the new song and they covered moonlight.
Speaker 1: It might be a new song, but they covered moonlight Densetsu from France where they were guests of Japan expo.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: And we over just around the world.
Speaker 1: I think I know why people keep coming back to it.
Speaker 1: People were growing crazy for German Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: They don't know how to use YouTube to listen to it whenever they want.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: At the end of the panel I was like, guys, you can just go to YouTube and find all this stuff and more.
Speaker 1: I could do this panel for four hours.
Speaker 1: So anyway, update two, uh, the original voice actors of, uh, Usagi and, uh, Mamoru were at this event, but no one knows if they're actually going to be the voice actors for the new show or not.
Speaker 0: I'm sure someone can sound just like them.
Speaker 1: Probably.
Speaker 0: This has never really been a problem.
Speaker 1: Uh, konacha editor Osano confirmed that it's an anime.
Speaker 1: I like how that was.
Speaker 1: update two.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I update three.
Speaker 1: He also emphasized that no details have been set for when it hypothetically will be broadcast, but it will be released to the world simultaneously.
Speaker 0: Hooray.
Speaker 0: Smart person.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: A winner is you.
Speaker 1: Uh, so one of the voice actors, the one, the girl who played the Usagi originally mused publicly if she will be in the anime or not and her blog, she said she'd be eager to play a role in it and there was no other update there.
Speaker 1: And the final update, she said in her blog that the enemy is not the dark kingdom and people lost their shit about that.
Speaker 1: But then there was a clarification that she was speaking metaphorically and that her, the figurative enemy of her would be her when she originally played sailor moon.
Speaker 1: because quote, that was an audacious performance compared to her acting now.
Speaker 1: That is all we know.
Speaker 1: But the fact that there is a new sailor moon, if anything could be used to catapult anime fandom back to, I don't think it'll make anime fandom.
Speaker 0: It'll just make sailor moon fan.
Speaker 1: All right, fine.
Speaker 1: I'll, I'll, I'll qualify this further.
Speaker 1: If anything could be used to take anime and use it to make money in the us from a mainstream market, it is this right now.
Speaker 1: This is like a big chance for that industry to ignore the history of terribly licensed, terribly managed companies and properties and just make money, which is what companies are designed.
Speaker 0: I think I just sort of, you know, realize just now it's like, you know, we're looking at anime like anime fandom, but it's really, no, it's people are, you know, you could be a Voltron fan, but no one says, oh, you're an American cartoon fan.
Speaker 0: It's like what?
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: And that it's like people are just fans of individual properties.
Speaker 0: They're not really fans of a whole, you know, category of media or whatever.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Some people are, but some people are not.
Speaker 0: This is what's killing.
Speaker 1: anime cons, not to name any names, but many people I know who work on the panels departments for anime cons have said they're getting fewer and fewer submissions for anime related content and less and less interest in anime content, even though the cons are all growing crazily in attendance, because it'd be like, if you had a sci-fi TV convention, all the doctor who fans show up and all the Sherlock fans show up and all the firefly fans show up, but they're not all self-identified sci-fi TV fans.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of sci-fi TV.
Speaker 0: They don't give a shit about it.
Speaker 0: And if you have, you need doctor who panels to get them to go.
Speaker 1: I mean, look, Connecticut last year, we had almost almost, I think we actually had fewer than half the anime rated related submissions.
Speaker 1: this year is the previous year.
Speaker 1: Anime fandom as a discreet fandom is basically collapsing anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's all asides because it's time for things of the day.
Speaker 1: So your fans got, this is kind of up your alley.
Speaker 1: You haven't actually watched it yet.
Speaker 1: We showed you the beginning, but a Terry Jones, you know, and you're a fan of, uh, medieval guys and tapestries and things like that.
Speaker 1: So Terry Jones has a show on the BBC called medieval lives, and it's a pretty well researched and, uh, believable.
Speaker 1: I'm credulous toward its information.
Speaker 1: Look at what different sorts of lifestyles were actually like in the middle ages.
Speaker 1: It's delightful and all of it's on youtube.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: I have to watch this at some point.
Speaker 1: It's pretty great.
Speaker 1: I've watched every episode.
Speaker 0: So here's a video on youtube that is almost over 5 million views, right?
Speaker 0: We all know that snakes are not good.
Speaker 0: You don't want to get bit by a snake.
Speaker 1: Don't you dare say anything bad about that?
Speaker 1: hot Lamia.
Speaker 0: You don't want to get bit by a poison snake.
Speaker 1: No, you don't know.
Speaker 1: So, uh, right.
Speaker 0: But you know, snake venom, how does it work?
Speaker 0: Like magnets, like magnets.
Speaker 1: Now there are different kinds of snakes, venoms, of course.
Speaker 0: So what they do in this video to illustrate the danger of snake venom and how crazy, you know, you don't want to get bit by it.
Speaker 0: They take a snake.
Speaker 0: that's way dangerous and they get some venom out of it, like a few drops, like less than like a milliliter in a tiny in a syringe.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Then they get like a little cup full of blood from a person.
Speaker 0: Not too much.
Speaker 0: And they put one drop of the snake venom into the cup of blood and swoosh it around.
Speaker 0: And it's like, whoa, whoa.
Speaker 0: That is why you do not want the snake venom in your blood.
Speaker 0: You will be dead in like two seconds.
Speaker 0: You got to see what happens to this blood when the snake venom gets in it.
Speaker 1: So that is, I believe, an opisthologic glyphus color Britic poison.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: As opposed to a protero glyphus snake.
Speaker 1: So I went to Wikipedia to figure out which kind of snake venom that was.
Speaker 1: And I know I read the wrong ones.
Speaker 1: Actually, it is the protero glyphus.
Speaker 1: No, it's viper venom.
Speaker 1: That was a viper.
Speaker 1: It says, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: Bringing about coagulation of the blood and clotting of the pulmonary arteries.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Any herpetologists out there?
Speaker 1: I'm sorry for the manner in which I said the words I just said.
Speaker 1: I apologize to you.
Speaker 0: Are you sure it's not a glyphus?
Speaker 1: Uh, well, okay.
Speaker 1: I'm going to read to you what happens if it watch this video and you could watch it while you're listening to the following.
Speaker 1: This is a quote from Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: The bite is immediately followed by local pain of a burning character.
Speaker 1: The limb soon swells and becomes discolored and within one to three hours, great prostration accompanied by vomiting and often diarrhea sets in cold, clammy perspiration.
Speaker 1: As usual, the pulse becomes extremely feeble.
Speaker 1: A slight this Nania and restlessness may be seen in severe cases.
Speaker 1: The pulse may become imperceptible.
Speaker 0: I'm going to have just listen to this.
Speaker 1: Uh, I'm going to read one sentence.
Speaker 1: The sentence horrifies me.
Speaker 1: The limb becomes flag, menace and occasionally separates.
Speaker 0: I'm good because that words don't mean anything to me.
Speaker 0: That didn't bother me because I don't know what the words mean.
Speaker 0: I'm glad I'm not going to become flag.
Speaker 1: Menace leads to death.
Speaker 0: Yeah, duh.
Speaker 0: G. How about this poison?
Speaker 0: Oh, it's nonlethal poison.
Speaker 0: There's not poison, is it?
Speaker 1: All right, so nonlethal bullets, meta moments.
Speaker 1: The book club book was one Q eight four by Herkey Murakami.
Speaker 1: We read it a while ago.
Speaker 1: We just haven't done the show yet.
Speaker 1: We'll try to do the show soon before I forget what the book was about.
Speaker 0: I should have taken notes.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I didn't take notes.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 0: I should have taken notes.
Speaker 1: I started taking notes halfway through and I have three notes, one of which is little people with a question mark.
Speaker 1: And then later I circled that.
Speaker 0: I'm taking notes from now on for all future book clubs to improve the episode.
Speaker 1: The next book club book will be the man who was Thursday.
Speaker 0: How could you be Thursday?
Speaker 0: It's a day of the week.
Speaker 1: That's like, maybe you should read the book.
Speaker 0: The man who was car.
Speaker 1: Have you met my good man Friday?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's cause the guy's name is Friday.
Speaker 1: How do you know this guy's name isn't Thursday?
Speaker 1: The man who was rim.
Speaker 0: Well, if he was Thursday though, that means he's no longer Thursday.
Speaker 0: Maybe he changed his name.
Speaker 1: Well if he was Thursday, then the question is, has he been since Thursday?
Speaker 1: I don't think anyone's going to get that reference.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Has he been?
Speaker 1: After breakfast.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So we will be at the penny arcade expo.
Speaker 1: We actually, I can announce our panel.
Speaker 1: It is called short subjects in gaming.
Speaker 1: Remember that triple threat?
Speaker 1: It's that again, but with three new topics.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's too bad.
Speaker 0: We need to come up with a way to title it.
Speaker 0: That'll get better attendance next year.
Speaker 1: I should see last year.
Speaker 1: It almost filled the room and was PAX East, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, two years ago at PAX East.
Speaker 1: That, that was a very popular panel and I think the difference is this year.
Speaker 1: Uh, what I noticed was that we always write very succinct descriptions because most conventions don't only give you a little bit of space in the program book, like 80 words, 90 words.
Speaker 1: So last year I find like, I usually don't really read the packs program guide.
Speaker 1: So I was like reading it and I realized everyone else who speaks at packs writes like a quarter page description.
Speaker 1: So I emailed them and I was like, so can I just, is, is there a limit?
Speaker 1: And they were like, not really.
Speaker 1: So I wrote a gigantic description of showing all the different parts of this panel and what we're going to talk about and we'll see what that does.
Speaker 0: But we were doing, I not too many people look at the description.
Speaker 1: I named these sub panels.
Speaker 1: So we're doing a competitive test of skill.
Speaker 1: That's one of them.
Speaker 1: When the game plays the player, uh, that's about rhythm games.
Speaker 1: I think that's a good way to call that.
Speaker 1: And on the ethics of mind control.
Speaker 1: Uh, well, we'll, we'll talk about more as that's coming up, but it is on Friday in the Wolfman theater in the afternoon.
Speaker 1: We are also, we can announce now going to be at packs dev for the first time ever, even though we are not devs.
Speaker 1: Well, uh, I have half written a shitty game in unity where a cube scrolls back and forth sideways shooting cubes at another cube.
Speaker 0: I wrote hang man in C for the Apple LC two.
Speaker 1: Oh, and remember that I bet that ad you had about a Puerto Rico style war game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: I designed it on the way home.
Speaker 1: I have this really good idea.
Speaker 1: I it was in my pocket, but it got wet.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure the game's already been done in some fashion.
Speaker 0: I mean, eclipse is sort of it.
Speaker 1: No, you'll see what I, anyway, I digress, but uh, we're going to be there.
Speaker 1: We've got a Lou Crane on our panel, Jared Sorenson, uh, Alex Avery of PopCap games.
Speaker 1: Uh, we've got a couple other people that I shouldn't announce yet because they may or may not actually be able to be on the panel, depending entirely on whether or not they either get permission to be on the panel or are going to be in Seattle.
Speaker 1: bail now, because they didn't, they never, whoa, they didn't actually bail because they didn't a hundred percent confirm yet.
Speaker 1: So it was, it was possible they would bail and I knew they was possible.
Speaker 1: So it's not actually a bail, but anyway, it is academia versus reality, psychology, game theory and games.
Speaker 1: So we talk a big shit game about, you know, how games should be designed.
Speaker 1: Like here's the game theory, Colonel Blotto game, all this analysis, psychology, and we're going to talk to game designers and see how much of that academia is actually used in games and game design.
Speaker 0: Almost none.
Speaker 0: Dr.
Speaker 1: Hazard might be the only person who actually uses it.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 1: And I think it's going to be an interesting discussion commercially for, you know, consumer video games and such.
Speaker 1: Uh, anyway, uh, otherwise we'll be in mag fast doing our thing.
Speaker 1: and that's as far out as I want to project other meta moments.
Speaker 0: You should go to our website for a crew.com because that's our website.
Speaker 0: You should go to the website of things that if you're, I mean, if you're listening to the podcast, how could you not go to the website of the podcast?
Speaker 0: Also, if you're an old fuddy duddy, we have an email newsletter.
Speaker 0: It's kind of crazy.
Speaker 0: I actually sent it out on time.
Speaker 0: The second, you know, that's the second one I've sent.
Speaker 0: I'll probably send them, continue to send them cause it's on my calendar and have a reminder for it.
Speaker 0: So if you go to the website, there's a little email subscriber link somewhere.
Speaker 0: I think it might be in the footer somewhere.
Speaker 0: Um, you can subscribe to this email newsletter.
Speaker 0: If you think it's stupid, you can unsubscribe and it'll actually unsubscribe.
Speaker 0: You see, we're not going to spam you and it will remind you occasionally of the things are up to.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's uh, if you don't like to be reminded by email, you can also be reminded by Twitter, Facebook, Google plus.
Speaker 1: I will tell you though, if you don't subscribe to Scott's, there's, you know, the information in the newsletter we talk about in the meta moment, everything, but there is also a newsletter thing of the day that is not ever going to be on regular geek nights.
Speaker 1: We, uh, you will be missing content.
Speaker 0: If you do not subscribe, there is a small amount of exclusive content in the newsletter part.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Very important.
Speaker 0: You could real also just, I mean, it's an email guys.
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 1: Also, you know, we have a video section, so go to our youtube channel, spread our videos around.
Speaker 1: If any one of our packs lectures gets up to 10,000 views before packs, I will find out based on the refers who caused that to be, and I will buy you one or more beverages at packs that may or may not be alcoholic.
Speaker 1: Notice how I'm giving.
Speaker 1: very difficult to acquire from me, but easy to provide if someone does actually put forth the effort of acquiring them.
Speaker 1: prizes.
Speaker 1: I've learned my lesson from the contest of yield and days met a moment.
Speaker 0: We did things of the day we did.
Speaker 0: All right, let's do the show.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So this is a very special, very important review.
Speaker 0: You see several years in the making.
Speaker 1: Several years ago, our good friend Timo who lives very far away and as a particle physicist who had one point one very important time at packs, he came to packs to hang out with prime.
Speaker 1: Yes, it was awesome.
Speaker 0: But you also get in the Mogo.
Speaker 1: one year whenever a physicist is at a bar with you having dinner and he says, here, let me show you something about physics and he pulls off his belt.
Speaker 1: You know, you're in for a wild ride.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have pulled that belt trick and so many people, even though I barely understand it, I'm taking his belt off and on bars around the world anyway.
Speaker 1: So Timo, you know, he sent us a care package, a box of a number of comics from his native land that he would like.
Speaker 0: So long ago we still lived in beacon.
Speaker 0: So I guess it had to be oh eight or nine or earlier that, you know, to read.
Speaker 1: and some of them he let us keep, but some of them are rare or you know, they're dear to him.
Speaker 1: and he wanted us to send them back.
Speaker 1: And we said, yes, we will review them, read them all, enjoy them and send them back.
Speaker 1: We're assholes.
Speaker 1: And I've still got the, I'm sitting here with the books right now.
Speaker 1: We finally read them.
Speaker 0: We didn't lose them or ruin them or forget them.
Speaker 1: But in return, the care package, when we send them back, I am sending him two of the rarest and most dear, hard to get comic series that we have.
Speaker 1: And he can basically hold them hostage as long as he would like.
Speaker 0: What are you sending him?
Speaker 1: I think I want to send him sanctuary and Eagle.
Speaker 1: I think he has scans of sanctuary, but it's something else to read the actual original like printing of it.
Speaker 0: Make sure he wants them before you send them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, we'll follow up on that, but we've, we're, we've read many of these comics.
Speaker 1: I think we reviewed one of them because it was short a long time ago, but we read the in call all the way through.
Speaker 1: We're here to review this.
Speaker 1: So Timo, this is for you.
Speaker 0: I know that the in call, I, I've heard of this and I knew it was a famous thing.
Speaker 0: And also I know who Mobius is extra famous and had does the awesomest arts of all time.
Speaker 0: And he also passed away recently, which is sad.
Speaker 0: I don't know who the writer is.
Speaker 0: I never heard of him before.
Speaker 0: Alejandro Jodorowsky.
Speaker 1: I'd heard of the Jodover's, but I didn't know what that was.
Speaker 0: I'd never heard of that either.
Speaker 1: Kind of like how way back in the day I'd heard a bone.
Speaker 1: Like I'd be like, Oh, there's that bone.
Speaker 1: But I didn't know what it was like.
Speaker 1: I didn't know.
Speaker 1: it was just a fancy adventure with a guy who was from Bonville.
Speaker 0: But anyway, uh, but I knew there was a comic called the in call.
Speaker 0: I didn't know anything else about it.
Speaker 0: I just read it and there are two volumes and that's the whole thing.
Speaker 1: So in the fashion of old comics, we had two trades here and there is absolutely no indication which one to read first.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And if you start reading either one from page one, it is not any clearer which one to read first.
Speaker 0: You have to read the back to where it says like epic conclusion or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You have to read the text on the back to figure it out.
Speaker 0: But yeah, that's an annoying thing.
Speaker 0: Just the way they publish comics in the U S until the manga boom sort of where they sort of realized you're supposed to put volume numbers on things and people know what order to read stuff.
Speaker 0: Now even the ages sort of made trades.
Speaker 0: They didn't really give a shit.
Speaker 1: Even dark horse of guilty is guilty of this bullshit.
Speaker 1: The, uh, the, uh, well, oh my God is, oh my God is back in the day.
Speaker 1: There were no numbers on it.
Speaker 1: You had no idea which one was the most recent one, which one to read.
Speaker 0: That's still going by the way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 1: But there's numbers on it now as far as I remember.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I think there, there's a newer edition of it.
Speaker 1: that is, I really liked that comic, but it eventually went nowhere and I couldn't read it anymore.
Speaker 0: It's still going even in Japan.
Speaker 0: So it's still going nowhere.
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: anyway, the in Kyle gets a lot of points for the fact that it starts and ends effectively in media res, but in a way that feels like you're starting with like issue 108 of the uncanny X men and you just, you should know who all these people are, but yet, no, it's the beginning.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's sort of the, you know, it does that thing that we always say we like a lot of things to do where there's a universe and there's a lot of things in that universe, but they, they're just sort of there and carrot people, you know, it's not like where people will, you know, explicitly go out of their way to explain something because in the meta, the author knows that you don't know what that is.
Speaker 0: It's more like Prince of nothing where people just start using proper nouns and they don't explain them and there's no glossary.
Speaker 0: So you have to sort of figure out in context what all those proper nouns mean and what those things are.
Speaker 0: And it's like, oh, okay.
Speaker 0: The police are robots in this world without any character having to say, yes, in this world, you know, the police are all robotic things and they work this way.
Speaker 0: It's just, you just see them and that's how it, you just accept it.
Speaker 1: But the, the difference is that this really makes you feel like you should know like the Prince of nothing.
Speaker 1: Like, I don't know what I'm trying to figure it out.
Speaker 1: This, I feel like, ah, how come I don't know who that guy is, but not in a bad way, but more like the book is admonishing me to make me feel confused and disoriented and, and force me to kind of just get past that and just go with it.
Speaker 1: And I kind of liked that because I remember when I was a kid and I read my first X-Men comic Eve ever, I just picked up a random X-Men comic and I started reading it and comics in that era were like the cool kids would read them.
Speaker 1: And I was into other things.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh, I'm going to read these comics.
Speaker 1: And I read, I read some X-Men and I felt like, oh, that, that'd be, I should know who these people are.
Speaker 1: Like I should know.
Speaker 1: It's a failing of me that I do not know who these characters are.
Speaker 1: The end call evoke that same feeling.
Speaker 0: I did not have that feeling.
Speaker 1: Oh, maybe it's just me.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, I have had that feeling in the past, but not with this particular book, but I could see how one could have that feeling.
Speaker 1: So interestingly, you know, where a lot of people might've heard about these is that the director, the fifth element, there was a lawsuit claiming that elements in the fifth element were borrowed from the income.
Speaker 0: I could see how somebody might think that looking at the two things, how they might have some sort of connection, but no, not really.
Speaker 0: They're pretty far apart, even though they have similarities.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's any enough similarity to, uh, to claim that there's any sort of, uh, wrongdoings.
Speaker 0: What, what happened with the lawsuit?
Speaker 1: Uh, they lost.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They lost handling.
Speaker 0: So in other words, I'm right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I saw Lulu cosplay kinetic on this weekend.
Speaker 0: I said multi-pass and she pulled out a multi-pass of course.
Speaker 1: If you're cosplaying as her and you don't have a multi-pass on you, I'm just saying, Oh, uh, random aside, the best cosplay kinetic con was the running man cosplay.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I was so amazed that that was there.
Speaker 1: And I think they were equally amazed that we immediately knew what they knew.
Speaker 1: We were like, Oh my God, I almost wanted to run over and rip off their name tag, but I was worried.
Speaker 1: It wasn't actually Velcro and I was going to ruin their costume, but no, that was super cool.
Speaker 0: But anyway, back off the tangent.
Speaker 1: One other interesting thing about the in-call is that the, the additions that Timo sent us, it was printed multiple times.
Speaker 0: Well, in different countries, it was pretty well in English, at least it was printed by Marvel.
Speaker 0: Well, in English also the word with the UK versions and printed by DC and Australian versions, but it was printed by both Marvel and DC.
Speaker 0: That happens a lot actually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 1: So Marvel printed it through their Epic comics label and DC printed it through their humanoids label, which was just interesting.
Speaker 1: I learned that from Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 1: I wish I've got open right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So anyway, the in-call is the story of a man, John DeFool.
Speaker 0: I mean, come on then.
Speaker 0: I was talking about the name, John DeFool, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, come on, you could get a little better with the creative name, but obviously he is DeFool literally and figuratively all at the same time.
Speaker 0: But I mean, come on that you so blatant.
Speaker 0: So it's, it's, it's almost lazy, but also at the same time hero protagonist.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's the same deal.
Speaker 1: I have no problem with that.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying it's the same thing because the names in this are great.
Speaker 0: The other names are only the John DeFool.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: I wonder the thing is he's called meta Baron, which is sort of a bad-ass name, but it's like, he is not a Baron nor is he meta.
Speaker 1: He is a bad-ass though.
Speaker 0: He is a bad-ass.
Speaker 0: But yeah, DeFool is the only one with a lazy name.
Speaker 0: Everyone else has a pretty good name.
Speaker 1: Anima and Tanata.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That doesn't bother you?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Not really.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So John DeFool is a PI, cool dude, I guess.
Speaker 1: Kind of a loser, kind of smart, kind of shaggy from Scooby-Doo.
Speaker 0: A little better than Shaggy from Scooby-Doo.
Speaker 1: His character is all over the place.
Speaker 1: He reminds me almost even of Ataru.
Speaker 1: Like he's just, he's lecherous.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like.
Speaker 0: on the one hand, it's like, it seems like he's really competent at being a PI, but on the next moment, he's just like getting into all sorts of trouble being stupid.
Speaker 0: And then he's being like, you know, all smart, like, no, I'm not going to go along with this bullshit.
Speaker 0: I'm just going to go back to my normal life.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: There's so many times in these comics where fuck all this insanity.
Speaker 0: I'm just going home.
Speaker 1: All the other characters are like, but we're going to save the world.
Speaker 1: He's like, this is bullshit.
Speaker 1: I'm going home.
Speaker 0: And then he gives in and it's like, what?
Speaker 0: He's just so all over, you know, clearly he is DeFool.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But the way it starts is basically like, not even the way it starts.
Speaker 1: The one I like about the in call the most is that the characters are nothing.
Speaker 1: They're there, but they, they're almost like set pieces.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: As opposed to characters, right?
Speaker 0: I'd say this, I really need better words for this.
Speaker 0: Cause I say it about almost everything, right?
Speaker 0: When we talk about ponies, I'm like, Oh, look at the characters and ponies.
Speaker 0: They're so such full characters.
Speaker 0: They have personalities.
Speaker 0: They have all these things going on.
Speaker 0: You could imagine a scenario and say, what would X character do?
Speaker 0: And you would know what that character would do and be able to act like them or make funny jokes relating to their personality.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But with in call, it's like each of the characters has sort of, you know, a backstory and a plot and things like that, but they don't really have a strong personality.
Speaker 0: It's like, what would the meta Baron say in this situation?
Speaker 0: You know, if someone said this to him and it's like, um, you couldn't really make a joke, like meta Barons do this and John, the fools do that.
Speaker 0: You couldn't make that joke, but you could easily make the Twilight sparkle does this.
Speaker 0: Rainbow dash does that joke.
Speaker 0: Cause the characters are just so empty, but it's sort of like a lot of superhero comics have that same issue, you know, where there's just so many characters, maybe they focus on a few that aren't empty, but most of them are just shells with costumes on.
Speaker 0: that serves some sort of.
Speaker 0: the thing is, even though they don't have these personalities and character, they have roles in the plot.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like each character is almost like a talking McGuffin of sorts.
Speaker 1: But while everyone is like that, they're not bland.
Speaker 1: They're just not characters, right?
Speaker 1: But what they are is great.
Speaker 1: The income from start to finish is just like set piece after set piece of just crazy crap, crazy weirdos, sci-fi world.
Speaker 0: The things that are happening make sense in order, right?
Speaker 0: Actually, there are some characters that do have character like the president at the beginning.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Um, but not much.
Speaker 0: And the character sort of disappears.
Speaker 0: Mostly not entirely.
Speaker 1: Depot is pretty good.
Speaker 1: The, uh, the stone, the bird thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Not bad.
Speaker 1: Cause he's, often the voice of reason.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But it's mostly just, you know, follow this crazy plot that does make sense in a crazy world.
Speaker 0: And these characters, you know, do their thing along the way and stuff happens.
Speaker 1: It builds to a sort of existential, this kind of thing can only go in an existential direction.
Speaker 0: You know, I love, that's my kind of action.
Speaker 0: I love it whenever, you know, an anime gets crazy weird at the end, like in a Monica, Evangelion way.
Speaker 0: And in call definitely goes in that sort of fashion.
Speaker 0: If you like those sort of sci-fi anime plots or everything gets trippy to, as you get closer to the end, in call does that times 10.
Speaker 0: And plus the Mobius art totally fits with that.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, handing glove giant space, baby gods and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: But the reason I'm not talking a lot about the plot is that it goes like, it's hard to describe because it's so trippy.
Speaker 1: Like in the beginning, remember the super pretty androgynous God, people who rule above the crappy city and like the guy, a guy tries to commit suicide.
Speaker 1: And whenever someone does that bunch of other people usually just also jump.
Speaker 1: And then people who live in the city for fun, I'll just try to shoot them out of the sky as they fall.
Speaker 0: There's this whole big, it's like, it's like, think about that.
Speaker 0: Even though these characters are nobody, that setting right there, that place, you could imagine all kinds of cool things that could happen in a place like that in a world like that, you know?
Speaker 0: So, you know, even though you don't care about the people, any specific people, you feel immediately you're in this place where this crazy cool stuff, you know, a lot like many other cyberpunk spacey things, you know, like, you know, Logan's run, you feel like, oh man, it's an underground place where you die when you're 30.
Speaker 0: You know, it's all about the place.
Speaker 0: Really cool.
Speaker 1: But then not that much later, like about halfway through from that point, which is almost right at the beginning, you get to places where there's crazy bird people who worship a fertility thing and all the, all the guys are actually sperm and you've got to run toward this disintegration chamber and have sex with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Cause like I don't want to be a disintegrated.
Speaker 0: It pretty much follows a pattern of introduce a weird alien thing.
Speaker 0: Learn how to deal with it, deal with it, move on to next weird alien thing, you know, and beach and you get your, and in the process of dealing with the alien thing, you are transformed in an alien way.
Speaker 0: And then when you go to approach the next alien thing, it's their characters are transformed again and rinse and repeat until all the alien things have been dealt.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot else I can say other than that, if you are a fan of comics, you should read this just to see.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to say this is like so great, super amazing, but if you are a fan of cyberpunk things that get existential at the end, uh, crazy, awesome artwork, uh, it is worth reading, especially since only two volumes.
Speaker 0: If you can get your hands on them, it shouldn't be that hard.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine.
Speaker 0: Uh, but it's not like.
Speaker 0: this is must read comic of the universe or anything like that.
Speaker 1: This is must read comic for someone who claims to be a comic book fan.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: This it's one of those things where you you'll either, you're going to love this or you're not going to get it, but it'll be memorable.
Speaker 0: It is something I will remember.
Speaker 0: I didn't really need to take notes on it.
Speaker 1: Like I am loathe to describe plot points though, because they're, you just got to experience it.
Speaker 0: Well, it's mainly, it's about this, some device called the Inca, which you don't really learn too much about, but it's always there and it can sort of go in people and it's also powerful, but there's also you suddenly, you learn a little bit later on, there's like a dark one and a light one.
Speaker 0: and you have that typical dark light symbolism, you know, balance and all that jazz going on.
Speaker 0: And there are some, you know, some people want the Inca, some people have the Inca, some people want to use it for bad, some people want to use it for good.
Speaker 1: Now this all plays out in this sort of like space opera drama of empires and mutants.
Speaker 1: And there's a sort of, you know, and there's, there's a metropolis style uprising early on.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it's, you know, one alien race is actually using another alien race to, you know, work for them.
Speaker 0: So you sort of have that, you know, beat the guys.
Speaker 0: Oh wait, there was another higher level guy who was actually behind things.
Speaker 0: move on up the chain to more craziness situations going on.
Speaker 0: And then, you know, of course things get so crazy up near the top, you know, the universe might be destroyed or whatever.
Speaker 0: So everyone's got to, you know, figure out what to do to prevent that and crazy things happen along the way.
Speaker 1: And the way language is used, it was originally in French, but like the, the emperor, the, the leaders, remember the, the guys with the, the guy and the girl with the head stuck together, sitting before that, like galactic, show
Speaker 0: me the picture,
Speaker 1: the mega holiness,
Speaker 0: the, the emperor, the emperor risks,
Speaker 1: but the fact that they call him and her together, the mega holiness, like your mega holiness.
Speaker 1: And that's the word they use.
Speaker 1: stuff like that is everywhere.
Speaker 1: The meta Baron, the mega holiness, stuff like that.
Speaker 1: in this kind of setting, it would be really silly and derpy anywhere else, but the way this is presented, it is dead serious.
Speaker 0: It's kind of crazy how they can get away with that.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Of having such crazy weird names, but also you're not just like laughing at it.
Speaker 0: Like it's a joke, but in many ways it actually is sort of like almost humorous.
Speaker 0: It's like, if you took, you know, all it's like, if you took a snow crash and put in a little bit of hitchhiker's guide, you know, just to sort of make it wow off to the side a little bit.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I can't explain it any better than that.
Speaker 0: You just have to see it for yourself.
Speaker 0: Like the matrix.
Speaker 1: A lot of naked people too.
Speaker 0: There's nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 0: It's French.
Speaker 1: I was going to point out there's a, there's a lot of naked people.
Speaker 0: You know that the first time you see anima and she's all naked way hot.
Speaker 0: Those are like the nicest boobies I've ever seen drawn by hand of human being.
Speaker 1: She's very matter of fact though.
Speaker 0: I just said the boobies really nice.
Speaker 0: I didn't say anything about anything.
Speaker 1: I like when he's in the disintegration chamber to have sex with the thing and it takes whatever form will be most pleasing to him, which is her and the whole time because she's with like their ground control, basically spying on him.
Speaker 1: She sees that and it's the way she's kind of nonchalantly reacting to.
Speaker 1: that is actually pretty funny.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If you want to learn how to draw boobies really nicely, you should learn from Mobius.
Speaker 1: I like how.
Speaker 1: of all the things in this comic, that's what you're really remembering.
Speaker 0: I remember a lot of other things.
Speaker 0: That's just what I mentioned because you brought that up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But no, the in-call is, like I said, if you're a comic fan, you got to read this at least so you can talk about it in the context of comics because there's not a lot else out there that's like this.
Speaker 1: that is also self-contained.
Speaker 1: There are things.
Speaker 1: That is also self-contained.
Speaker 0: There are.
Speaker 0: You just don't know about them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like what?
Speaker 0: Weird sci-fi things like that.
Speaker 0: I guess Nexus is sort of like that.
Speaker 1: But the fact you're struggling a little bit.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I see things like that.
Speaker 1: There's DC Green Lantern crap, but that's a different kind of crazy and it's not self-contained.
Speaker 0: There is some Jim Starlin stuff, but that's a little weird.
Speaker 1: I'm saying there are not a lot of comics like this.
Speaker 1: And the fact that you can read this.
Speaker 0: I guess Fear Agent maybe.
Speaker 1: The fact that you can read this whole thing in two trades means that if you're going to read something crazy like this, you should just read this.
Speaker 0: Invincible also has some similar aspects in a way.
Speaker 1: Granted.
Speaker 0: Invincible has the superhero aspect.
Speaker 1: The conclusion to the whole thing?
Speaker 1: I wish the whole comic was drawn like that.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: I always hate that when there's an artwork.
Speaker 0: That's the thing about Mobius, right?
Speaker 0: You look at most Mobius artwork and it's like, "Oh man, that's so
Speaker 0: awesome."
Speaker 0: Especially things he's painted and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: But then you look in the actual printed comic and the interior pages, they're great, but they're not as great.
Speaker 0: And it's like, I wonder what it looked like before it was colored.
Speaker 0: It would probably be stunning if it wasn't colored.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Serious.
Speaker 1: If you get to the end of this, like the last page, that style is great.
Speaker 1: And if the whole comic had been like that, or if they animated this and it looked like that, I don't even know what I'd do.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's all right.
Speaker 0: We're going to read some comics that are awesome the whole way through for awesomeness.
Speaker 0: I'm going to make it happen because we need some Wednesday episode.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.