Speaker 1: It's Monday June 18th 2012.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm sky, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: laptops.
Speaker 0: Alright, rawr Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Are you want to hear some good stuff?
Speaker 1: possibly alright?
Speaker 0: This is the kind of material that people love.
Speaker 0: so I'm gonna dish it out, so it's poop and food.
Speaker 0: it is poop.
Speaker 1: So If we're gonna poop anecdotes, I got an anecdote myself, but go on Alright, so I feel like every human being.
Speaker 0: on Saturday I'm biking and I decided to bike to the beach because it was all nice out and I say Rockaway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, I succeeded in doing so and I went over the Adobo bridge which I will now call the Obobo bridge.
Speaker 1: Ah so you went over.
Speaker 1: I didn't.
Speaker 1: last time I went out there I didn't go over that bridge.
Speaker 1: It was already like five o'clock when I got out there.
Speaker 0: Well, I left at 1030.
Speaker 0: I got to the above bridge like less than noon even right.
Speaker 0: It's like it's a short ride if you push it.
Speaker 0: well I went.
Speaker 0: I went you know extra a ways right.
Speaker 0: so I went to Queens and then I went to these two other parks.
Speaker 0: There's one that's the south part of the Corona Park, and then there's.
Speaker 0: oh So you went out and then down went out and down and then is the forest park Which I didn't know about till recently.
Speaker 0: so when the forest park, and then I went to the Bobo bridge, so You go over the Obobo bridge And there's like this little landing there and on the left side you can see JFK and on the east side you can see Manhattan from real far away.
Speaker 0: And there's like this little like landing area with like a little building and a parking lot And it's like tiny little show or outcropping.
Speaker 0: you can even go under the bridge.
Speaker 0: There's real fishing good times.
Speaker 0: And then you go over the thing the Veterans Memorial Bridge And then you're on the beach, and it's weird because it's like it's Wildwood.
Speaker 0: But if you turn around you can sort of see Manhattan way over there over yonder.
Speaker 0: So now I kind of want to get a little house over there.
Speaker 0: He got a weekend house, and then on Friday after work.
Speaker 0: We can bike over there, and then on Sunday We all right tell you what you pay for half of it.
Speaker 0: all right.
Speaker 0: They had co-ops there.
Speaker 0: There's a building full of co-ops.
Speaker 0: They're trying to sell.
Speaker 0: Anyway right on the beach anyway, so you know I go out there.
Speaker 0: I'm biking down the boardwalk right to go west to take the Gil Hodges bridge which goes to Brooklyn which goes back to New York.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so going west down the boardwalk And my stomach hurts, and I'm like huh, it's probably this bumpy ass boardwalk.
Speaker 1: Usually that is not the cause of stomach hurt.
Speaker 1: that was simply you trying to postpone the inevitable The.
Speaker 0: the Rockaway was quite longer than I expected right, and I'm you know I get down to like this other I think it's called Reese Park, and then you know to get to this bridge I was like wow it's kind of you know.
Speaker 0: on the map the map was basically lying to me.
Speaker 0: I thought it would be like.
Speaker 1: so you're on that gigantic bike path that just goes like forever.
Speaker 0: I took the boardwalk, and then I had to like do some tricks to like get over the highway to the other North part of Rockaway, so I got.
Speaker 0: actually get on the bridge and basically you know like when I was up in the other area You know in Queens there were plenty of like porta potties everywhere and everything.
Speaker 0: it was all good You know.
Speaker 0: but in this area not so much Crowded beach people everywhere even on like side paths like this dude fishing this you know not exactly a wooded area All right, so I go over the this bridge And I sort of get to this area where it's like crazy highway, and you're sort of getting back into Brooklyn.
Speaker 0: But and it's.
Speaker 0: but it's very tricky to figure out like exactly how to get.
Speaker 1: I know where you were yeah But it's like this kind of mall nearby.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 0: No if you look on the map It's where I originally wanted to go.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like this is airfield there, and you can theoretically bike on the airfield on the runways, but it's not JFK It's a small plate right yeah, but I didn't go in there cuz I had to go elsewhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, so Apparently like right after the bridge like you know most of everyone was going straight And I saw this little you know path went into the woods, and I'm like hot diggity dog going to the woods.
Speaker 0: So I go right into the woods And I go deep into the woods is get a little maze like in there, and I'm like well This is good right, but this pads this pads in the woods, but it's sort of maze ish, and I'm looking around And I'm listening and it's not like I could go physically into the woods.
Speaker 0: all I can really do is go like near the pass.
Speaker 1: you're trying to get just far enough away from people to Yeah, yeah, yeah, so anyway.
Speaker 0: I laid down two logs and then Use some leaves.
Speaker 0: there was some good leaves there that I knew were not well.
Speaker 1: What do you lay down?
Speaker 1: two logs?
Speaker 1: Just pop a squat.
Speaker 0: That's what I did lay down two logs.
Speaker 1: Okay, this for some reason.
Speaker 1: I had this image of you Taking two logs and laying them next to each other than sitting on that and then laying down to know There's.
Speaker 0: no there were no logs of that nature.
Speaker 1: You know the one time I ever had to poop in the woods unprepared.
Speaker 1: I've been camping where you dig a hole.
Speaker 1: But the one time there's in high school I was out biking same thing with a bunch of people and I had to poop like all day.
Speaker 1: But I just didn't.
Speaker 1: I was busy like all day, and then we're out biking.
Speaker 1: I'm like all right I'm gonna go home and poop and I was getting to be crisis situation, so I figured hey Let's go through the woods as a park.
Speaker 1: here I got to use the bathroom and bike through the woods.
Speaker 1: we get to the park bathrooms locked cuz it's like midnight.
Speaker 1: So I'm not gonna make it.
Speaker 1: so I basically just bike off into the woods in the dark like down this trail.
Speaker 0: This is broad daylight.
Speaker 0: There was no darkness whatsoever.
Speaker 1: the problem with the darkness Is that there's no way to tell if the delivery was clean or any sort of follow-up there, so basically I rocketed one out.
Speaker 1: It was one and it was a rocket.
Speaker 0: so the thing is right is I laid him out there I wiped with some leaves that were pretty good and worked pretty well.
Speaker 1: No poison ivy.
Speaker 0: No it was.
Speaker 0: no No, it was like a real tree, so it's just like normal poison sumac like a maple tree or something.
Speaker 0: You know it's real normal leaves there.
Speaker 0: They're nice and big they worked anyway.
Speaker 0: but then I got sort of fascinated because Okay go on because even though like you know it was a clear day It didn't you know there was really nothing you know in the air.
Speaker 0: But like within seconds like tons of flies came out of nowhere All over that poop Scott mmM.
Speaker 1: So a flies dude.
Speaker 0: I know but it's like they.
Speaker 0: there were no flies Scott.
Speaker 1: it'd be like then suddenly tons of like we're in Wildwood You know or an arcade anywhere, and you hear that fourth mix off in the distance like hot shit come.
Speaker 1: Except imagine if what is.
Speaker 1: fourth mix to you is poop to that fly.
Speaker 1: I know right now we're at RIT and when you heard a rumor there might be and a DDR machine somewhere in the vicinity of campus anyway.
Speaker 1: So the final bit of the story right okay, so the story was you pooped in the woods and no one saw you right?
Speaker 0: So while I'm examining the flies right and by extension the poop right I Hear two people coming down from the opposite direction, and I made a getaway, and I think they saw me make a getaway.
Speaker 1: You should have been like oh my God someone pooped here.
Speaker 0: No But they didn't like.
Speaker 0: you know I just thought like they saw a guy.
Speaker 0: Look at them quickly as they were maybe like 50 feet away.
Speaker 0: Get on a bike and go the opposite.
Speaker 1: by doing that you cemented in their heads the idea that whoever that was that's cool Because they were walking.
Speaker 0: they didn't have bikes.
Speaker 0: There's no way they ever caught up with me or saw me or knew me.
Speaker 1: You know I'm gonna laugh so hard if we get an email.
Speaker 1: It was like I was in the woods the other day, and I some guy pooped and ran off.
Speaker 0: I'm sure someone will try to say that maybe just because you said that.
Speaker 0: but yeah Then I biked home.
Speaker 0: It's Monday, but I didn't get to go.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go back is now I want to go to the airfield that it's Monday It's science day, but first you reminded me.
Speaker 1: I might make this an extra thing today sure enough.
Speaker 1: Poop report is still going nice.
Speaker 1: Oh my that's a blast from 2000 and poo.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So you got a news all right.
Speaker 0: so check this out.
Speaker 0: This is I guess this counts as news, right?
Speaker 0: So you know Apple came out with them new MacBooks.
Speaker 0: They did and you know the.
Speaker 0: they have the quote retina display on the MacBook Pro 15-inch And they canceled the 17-inch completely which is that was a good move cuz yeah who what the fuck wants that thing?
Speaker 1: I don't know anyone who has that seriously right.
Speaker 1: well the thing is there are.
Speaker 1: there are cases.
Speaker 1: You know if we're talking about laptops There's like.
Speaker 1: there's the case of the ultra portable like super tiny laptop.
Speaker 1: That's to go.
Speaker 1: and then there's the giant laptop you put in your check bag.
Speaker 0: That's 15 inches.
Speaker 0: the giant laptop 17 should not exist.
Speaker 1: I could see you might as well.
Speaker 0: Just bring a monitor and a desktop with you 17 inches still way smaller.
Speaker 1: So wait monitors are actually a giant pain in the ass to transport.
Speaker 1: Anyway though the x230 has an option for the external second monitor.
Speaker 0: see Apple loves external adapters so much Right you know what.
Speaker 0: I don't understand Why they don't do this which is make an adapter you can buy for 50 bucks that has all sorts of video inputs.
Speaker 0: well in Their case it would have one video input which would be the Thunderbolt whatever right or each mini HDMI Whatever the hell they use yeah.
Speaker 0: And then the other end goes into the iPad.
Speaker 0: so you can basically use an iPad as a monitor with this $50 Thingy attached to it.
Speaker 1: That would be a great idea.
Speaker 0: I got by iPads just uses monitors, but anyway.
Speaker 0: So the thing is the.
Speaker 0: you know the resolution of this new MacBook is incredible.
Speaker 0: It's 2880 by 1800. yeah.
Speaker 1: meanwhile the laptop.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking about buying has I think 1330 by.
Speaker 0: yeah my 24 inch monitor at work doesn't have 2880 by 1800 it's 19 something by 1200 right and this is only 15 inches.
Speaker 0: So this is 220 ppi.
Speaker 0: that is pretty great.
Speaker 1: There is no you know discussion in that factor other than you'll have some trouble playing games at that resolution.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, well you're gonna have trouble playing games on the Mac anyway And it's you know it's 15 inch laptop.
Speaker 0: who wants that?
Speaker 0: but Whatever, so the thing is it's 220 pixels per inch.
Speaker 0: and the thing is when they originally came out with retina Right it was on the iPhone 4 which I have which is like 300 something pixels per inch.
Speaker 0: Oh, here's a little chart.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: It has to do with the distance from your eyeball right.
Speaker 0: well That's the bullshit line that they gave you which is you know well since you hold the iPad a little further away from yourself we can still call it retina if You you know if it is less ppi because you're not holding it as close to your face as a phone.
Speaker 0: It's like Well you keep a laptop even farther away right.
Speaker 1: so by that logic right my that that 800 by 600 non-native CRT that I had Was retina if I stand across the room exactly, but they you know they're basically making to just shoot.
Speaker 0: They're arbitrarily choosing how many inches they think you know is normal to be away from it to make this thing correct.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem and this great article explains the whole thing.
Speaker 0: their assumption of retina, right?
Speaker 0: is based on 2020 vision.
Speaker 0: and apparently 2020 vision is not what you think it is.
Speaker 0: 2020 vision means you can read that you're like the average person reading the eye chart from 20 feet away.
Speaker 0: Yeah Apparently like you know if most people have better than 2020 2020 is the standard of this or better is considered effectively perfect vision.
Speaker 0: because Measuring better doesn't matter no But the point is 2020 isn't even close to perfect vision.
Speaker 0: people who don't have eye problems can mostly see way better than Even people with eye problems With classes.
Speaker 1: corrective lenses can make give you better than normal human vision already.
Speaker 0: so like you know I could say I have 2020 vision But the point is I could read the eye chart from farther than 20 feet away.
Speaker 1: Right you want to have an eye chart contest and be in my cyborg glasses versus you and your Biological.
Speaker 0: I will play the eye chart game with anyone any time I think I would.
Speaker 1: we need an Neutral to make an eye chart that neither one of us has ever seen before but at least according to this article right he says.
Speaker 0: But while 2020 vision might traditionally refer to standard vision most research suggests that normal vision is actually much better than 2020.
Speaker 0: In fact people with normal vision usually won't see their eyesight degrade to 2020 until they are 60 or 70 years of age.
Speaker 0: So when I'm maybe 70 then I'll have 20/20 vision, right?
Speaker 0: So the thing is he calculates based on a who knows what kind of math that I don't understand What it really takes to get a real retina display.
Speaker 0: So it's like at first I thought Apple was bullshitting.
Speaker 0: I thought that the iPhone 4 was retina and the other ones weren't.
Speaker 0: now In fact, none of them are retina right.
Speaker 0: in order for the iPhone at three and a half inches to be retina the resolution would need to be 2772 by 1848 which is 952 PPI.
Speaker 0: Right, and this is even giving, you know Apple their inch distance calculation, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, iPad would need to be 59 68 by 44 86 which is 769 PPI.
Speaker 0: It's and he gives a whole chart here.
Speaker 0: He also shows is the cool part You know the ultra high-resolution image of Earth that NASA lets you download.
Speaker 0: Yeah he shows you how much of it you'll be able to see at once in full resolution on a theoretically true retina device and None of them can see the whole thing.
Speaker 0: But the 27-inch iMac at true retina.
Speaker 0: by his calculations you can see almost the whole thing at once because it's sort of widescreen and there's a lot of black area on the sides.
Speaker 0: and He's you know.
Speaker 0: on the one hand.
Speaker 0: it's annoying because it means right now our monitors aren't as good as we.
Speaker 0: you know That's as they're saying they are.
Speaker 0: but he's very happy about this actually because it means hey Shit's only gonna get better.
Speaker 0: even though he doesn't bring in any sort of monitor technology knowledge into this Showing that it's possible.
Speaker 0: He just sort of makes the assumption that we're just gonna keep making higher resolution monitors forever until we get them to be so high resolution that it's true retina.
Speaker 0: and Then he's excited about that because it means you'd be able to look at your monitor and not even be able to tell That it's like, you know a camera or you know Like.
Speaker 0: you'll look at it and you won't even be able to tell that it's rim versus a picture of rim Right looking at the at the thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well the true the trouble we'll run into is display technology is one thing but also the processing power.
Speaker 1: Exactly make images like that.
Speaker 0: He sort of makes his assumption that we're just gonna keep advancing with pixels per inch the same way that say hard drive space or CPU Cycles, you know keep increasing and he doesn't bring any knowledge of actual how LCDs work or LCD technology or even cam.
Speaker 1: I don't think it'll.
Speaker 0: cameras have to get better and you know cameras have to get better.
Speaker 0: Processes have to get better.
Speaker 0: all these things have to get exponentially better.
Speaker 0: be able to push these pixels I think it's a longer ways out than he thinks it may even be something that we see later in our lives.
Speaker 0: to get true You know that many pixels per inch?
Speaker 1: Well at the same time It's hard to say because technology is moving moving both slower than I'd ever hoped and faster than I could ever have imagined.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's always weird.
Speaker 0: You know, what areas move right?
Speaker 0: I mean you see things for example, like, you know We've seen flexible display prototypes like e-paper for years all these flexible monitors on like a little plastic card.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen them for at least 10 years and no one's ever brought one to market for reals, right?
Speaker 0: But yet there are things that you've never seen a prototype of anywhere.
Speaker 0: and then suddenly boom here it is in stores by tomorrow.
Speaker 0: It's like whoa.
Speaker 0: So, yeah All right.
Speaker 1: So this is a little bit of kind of cool sci-fi.
Speaker 1: MIT has created a special kind of fuel cell.
Speaker 1: Okay, this fuel cell runs on glucose.
Speaker 1: You wanna know why it runs on glucose?
Speaker 0: It's full of some biological organism.
Speaker 1: Nope, so you can put it in a brain.
Speaker 0: Oh, I read this and it can power itself.
Speaker 0: and well, how does your brain know to send enough glucose to it?
Speaker 1: The thing is it doesn't need to.
Speaker 1: okay now obviously this is you know early.
Speaker 1: I don't want to do what everyone on slashdot does which is oh, here's the technology article.
Speaker 1: Clearly these scientists have not thought of all the basic simple arguments that I thought of just now.
Speaker 0: No, I know that they have.
Speaker 0: I'm just wondering what the answers are.
Speaker 0: because they clearly the scientists have thought of these things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know if I can think of it they can think of it.
Speaker 0: and and because they've published something They probably already have the answer.
Speaker 0: and I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying I'm smarter than the scientists I have found the problem in your thingy.
Speaker 0: I'm saying what solution did they come up with these obvious problems that even I could see?
Speaker 1: Glucose gets through the blood-brain barrier and that's what the brain uses to power itself.
Speaker 1: It doesn't so it's just in the blood.
Speaker 1: So if you have a thing like a probe in the brain that also is connected to the blood supply this thing can just strip electrons off of glucose molecules and Use that to make enough power to run a very small device.
Speaker 1: Now obviously the questions are more.
Speaker 1: things like it's more kind of like deus ex We're alright, I can need a power bar to power up my cybernetics.
Speaker 1: but it also means What if the technology starts eating too much power?
Speaker 1: you didn't eat enough that could get dangerous in a hurry.
Speaker 1: diabetes, uh More like well like more like the opposite of diabetes.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, I mean you can have diabetes both ways.
Speaker 0: right if you're a diabetic you got sugar pills and insulin Whether or not you're hyper or hypoglycemia, but the point right.
Speaker 0: the point is this good, you know It could be bad in those ways.
Speaker 1: The thing is I'm getting hopeful because there's a lot of Different, you know, we're just talking about like the retina display this one guy looked at it from this one perspective.
Speaker 1: And there's so many other factors that make it so hard to guess when it'll be a reality Cybernetic brain implants and like real cybernetics that are somehow integrated with our nervous system and augmented reality and all those things together.
Speaker 1: I've seen a lot of articles in the last few years of all these kind of side Angles of that technology all starting to converge and I think I think that stuff is moving a lot faster than most people realize.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I'm gonna get Google Glass Pretty much day one even if it's even if it sucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's gonna suck my whole life.
Speaker 0: I've been waiting since as soon as I mean there are computers They're people who have stuff like it or you know They've had it for a long time like MIT had the thing you can wear around your neck Yeah, and what's-his-name had glasses he made.
Speaker 0: what's the guys in there?
Speaker 1: I forget anyway, but that's you know on the curve of like people adopting things.
Speaker 1: That's not even early adopter.
Speaker 1: That's innovator.
Speaker 1: That's like one dude.
Speaker 1: I don't have time for that.
Speaker 1: I don't have time to be the first augmented reality, dude.
Speaker 1: I have enough time to be the second wave Meaning I can buy it in a store and it just works mostly, right?
Speaker 1: But I'm getting increasingly excited about this stuff Even if our generation doesn't get it.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of doubtful that'll happen in time for my brains old and decrepit, but I kinda There's a tiny chance.
Speaker 1: I'll be able to upload myself into a computer before my body dies.
Speaker 1: Tiny chance.
Speaker 1: the fact that we're one of the first generations for that chance is not zero.
Speaker 1: But is some zero zero zero zero one is a big deal to me.
Speaker 1: That's all.
Speaker 1: I think everyone should read this article because it's kind of neat stuff.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day, so I don't mind dubstep and I don't hate it.
Speaker 1: I don't love it.
Speaker 1: It's a sub-genre.
Speaker 0: It depends on the song particularly cuz.
Speaker 0: some dubstep songs are just like And the whole time some of them right they got some other stuff mixed in there And that I think those are.
Speaker 0: you know, I could like those I like, you know I guess it just.
Speaker 1: it doesn't differentiate itself enough from a lot of other similar sub-genres for me But nonetheless, no problems with it.
Speaker 1: Someone made a great YouTube video.
Speaker 1: It's really just an audio file.
Speaker 1: This is what dubstep sounds like to old people.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: I defy you to not at least almost crack up while you're listening to this especially right toward the end.
Speaker 1: That's all nice and simple.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So here's this great article I read.
Speaker 0: It's actually a two-parter or maybe even a multi-parter.
Speaker 0: I read all the parts that are here so far and what it's about is really fascinating.
Speaker 0: and it's because we already know Right that the language you speak has an effect on how you think about the world, right?
Speaker 0: You know language can you know controls thinking and vice versa, but this specifically focuses on the area of color.
Speaker 0: Right and how for example, he starts off talking about the Japanese language how there was the word Oh Right, which is the blue green stuff right which is blue and they didn't even have a word for green, right?
Speaker 1: Until like the word midori came around like very recently Right, and then as a result a lot of Japanese people don't differentiate that much between blue and green, right?
Speaker 0: and it's like basically someone linked to this from an anime discussion of like, huh?
Speaker 0: Here's why sometimes you're watching an anime and The light the streetlight is blue even though in Japan if you go and look at streetlights, they're green Right, but it's like how come in the anime the streetlight was blue instead of right?
Speaker 0: It's because it's the same name.
Speaker 0: So you pick up the Crayola crayon and you know people don't you know it affects?
Speaker 0: How people can see?
Speaker 0: and the thing the really interesting part right was.
Speaker 0: they drew this little color grid.
Speaker 0: Look at the color grid, right.
Speaker 0: and they did this study where they had people look at this grid and then for example They would say all right highlight all the ones that you consider to be yellow.
Speaker 0: now highlight all the ones you consider to be green.
Speaker 0: Now highlight the section you consider to be of the blue chartreuse, right?
Speaker 0: And it's sort of like that It's you know even uses the XKCD comic as an example, right and pretty much it comes down to yeah everyone has different words for different colors and Depending on your language in your words, well like you captain read in advance Wars.
Speaker 1: It was clearly orange.
Speaker 1: I can prove it from screenshot.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's orange.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: It's the same kind of thing.
Speaker 0: So Even you know, so this it gets pretty fascinating here when he talks about how like yeah You know these people only had so many words for colors.
Speaker 0: so therefore they didn't differentiate between these two.
Speaker 0: and It's.
Speaker 0: it's pretty cool stuff and it's not just colorblindness, right?
Speaker 0: It's it's the fact that you have different words, so we don't have a word that's for different green and blue.
Speaker 0: So we consider them to be the same color.
Speaker 1: Yeah But at the same time and I'm looking at a screen right now and I see there's some blue and some green and the difference Is like palpable.
Speaker 0: Yep, but there are other people.
Speaker 0: they'd like they had a different word for green and yellow green.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like there were.
Speaker 0: there are distinct colors in this one particular language.
Speaker 0: So these people like they can just tell right away Oh, yeah, that's the yellow green color and that's green green.
Speaker 1: So well People grow.
Speaker 1: I mean did we grow up in the era of hex codes for writing HTML something like that?
Speaker 1: is that?
Speaker 1: yeah I mean to this day?
Speaker 1: I remember 23 80 23 was the color I picked to use as the font in the first blog I ever made.
Speaker 0: He even talks about Darwin was upset that he tried to teach his kids to colors and they had a really hard time for quite A few years.
Speaker 0: like there's something about kids learning to differentiate colors.
Speaker 0: It doesn't you know, it takes a while.
Speaker 1: I remember when I was really really young I hated the color orange because It had a whole bunch of letters in it compared to most of the other colors.
Speaker 0: Well the reason right.
Speaker 0: so the reason and nothing around with it.
Speaker 0: So the reason the children have a large time hard time learning the colors, right?
Speaker 0: and this is the point of the whole thing right is that Before you learn the language of the colors what their names are The right side of your brain is doing the color figuring work.
Speaker 0: But then once you learn the name of the color it switches over and the left side of the brain.
Speaker 0: does that work?
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: you got to read this.
Speaker 0: it's good All right.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment the book club book is still Qteen eight four.
Speaker 1: I gotcha.
Speaker 0: No, I'm mixing it up.
Speaker 1: one q8 for yeah By Haruki Murakami, it's I'm pretty much done with it.
Speaker 1: I'm getting near the end.
Speaker 1: There's a character.
Speaker 1: I like more now than I thought I would have liked.
Speaker 0: There's a reason that everyone on the subway is reading this book like every day.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty good but most commonly seen subway book of the past months, so you should read that shit.
Speaker 0: We got any other meta stuff.
Speaker 0: you should go to our website.
Speaker 0: you should go to Kinetic on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Kinetic ons coming up in Hartford, Connecticut at the Connecticut Convention Center.
Speaker 0: the heart Hartford Convention Center is the only one there, Connecticut steak.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it's called.
Speaker 0: It's the only big convention center in Hartford.
Speaker 0: There's nothing near it.
Speaker 0: It's just a convention center.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty good con because it's not an anime con not a gaming con though It has more good board gaming of the tabletop variety than any con I've ever been to including packs and Maggie.
Speaker 0: let's type up the board gaming right.
Speaker 0: so not only is their board game library Astounding pretty much including all the big euro games as well as a lot of like rare older games that are hard to find.
Speaker 0: but There's plenty of tables and that's it's not super crowded like Pax's.
Speaker 0: you can get a table very easily.
Speaker 0: You walk up you take out a game you give them your con badge or your driver's license or whatever.
Speaker 0: you get a game you Play it for playing games you get tickets and those tickets can be used to cash in to get stuff sort of like the arcade Where you play skee-ball and then you get a plastic frog, right?
Speaker 0: Only the payout ratios are not ripoffs like the arcade.
Speaker 0: like for 10 tickets You can get a $40 board game, which is like unbelievable.
Speaker 0: You just got paid with a real board game an expensive one for playing board games And the only money you had to pay was the money you paid to get into the convention.
Speaker 0: if you walk out with one board game which you can easily get more than one in like a day of gaming and Assuming you don't do anything else at the con You just got a free badge because basically you bought a board game and like for buying a board game We will let you in the con for free That.
Speaker 0: so if you get two games by playing games for say you could play games say all day Friday all day Sunday and enjoy The rest of the con on Saturday or something like that, you know, see bar fight.
Speaker 0: You wouldn't want to miss that And you'd basically get two free board games.
Speaker 0: So it's like you get a you buy a board game you get one free and you get a con badge free.
Speaker 0: That's a great deal.
Speaker 0: How can you not go to Connecticut?
Speaker 1: Yep, July 13 14 15 will be there.
Speaker 1: Yeah so laptops.
Speaker 1: I got one again about laptop season.
Speaker 0: We did a show about this once long long time ago and then we ran out of show ideas in June actually decided 2008.
Speaker 1: but You know at the most recent anime Boston packs, my laptop can't really play modern HD video anymore.
Speaker 1: It's an old Centrino.
Speaker 0: I don't understand this right cuz I had that core solo.
Speaker 0: that core solo can play pretty much any video just got.
Speaker 1: this is Probably slower than that.
Speaker 1: It's a centrino.
Speaker 0: the one you have was the model after mine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's got a centrino and it's still.
Speaker 1: it can play most HD video, but it can't play Certain high-res HD video like if you take a I don't know like a video I export from premiered up to upload to YouTube.
Speaker 1: Those that can't play at all because those have a 50 megabit per second, right?
Speaker 1: In fact, even like fairly powerful computers have trouble playing those smoothly.
Speaker 1: I only uploaded that way to YouTube because YouTube transcodes them to all the different YouTube standards.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and Furthermore certain like anime fan subs are usually fine, but like a blu-ray rip of a movie not gonna play I'm going but mostly based on anime fan subs that I That I would download.
Speaker 0: cuz I never really.
Speaker 0: and that's not like I'm watching blu-ray rips on that thing You know, but anyway.
Speaker 0: So yeah, so if you're the one who's buying a laptop my laptop is all good.
Speaker 1: So it's getting about time to buy a laptop again, but we did this old show on how to buy a laptop.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean it seems to be a popular thing, right?
Speaker 0: It seems back in our day.
Speaker 0: Everyone had the desktop computer.
Speaker 0: That was the thing and laptops were like if you had mad moneys you had when I was in high school.
Speaker 1: There's one kid who had a laptop.
Speaker 1: It was a 486 laptop and he'd run nesticle on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually, I think it was a penny him.
Speaker 1: It was something I forget it was this was Eighth grade.
Speaker 0: but then there were people.
Speaker 0: it started to happen that laptops are just the primary computer and people didn't have desktops.
Speaker 0: And I think a lot of people go that way today.
Speaker 1: Yep So when we did that show way back, I mean laptop.
Speaker 1: advice is pretty straightforward.
Speaker 1: if you can afford, you know.
Speaker 1: basically you choose between size and power and you just pick what's which one of those is more important and When in doubt you might as well go for the extreme of one or the other.
Speaker 1: Yeah but I mean is if it's portable you're gonna use it on a plane.
Speaker 1: get a tiny one.
Speaker 1: if It's something you put in your checked bags and bring to a place like college Like it's mostly just sitting on your desk, but then you bring it home get a big one.
Speaker 1: There weren't tablets really back then not like we have now.
Speaker 1: there weren't even Smartphones to the degree that we have them now.
Speaker 1: there weren't even really netbooks to the degree that we have them now and The landscape has changed so much that the advice is kind of different now.
Speaker 1: I think most people don't need laptops.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends right?
Speaker 0: I mean if you are Not doing it typing intensive applications, right?
Speaker 0: If you just want to like browse the web and look at some files while you're on the go You could probably just get an iPad.
Speaker 0: I Mean what do you need?
Speaker 0: You know, you only need a laptop.
Speaker 0: if you need to be able to compute Right, even going to do some sort of work like if you're coding on the go you need a laptop now.
Speaker 1: What I think is interesting is that because of this I think It's weird because the MacBook Air came out and then many ultra portable seem to go down that road and try to be Like the MacBook Air like be stupidly thin but yet bigger in every other dimension Thus not any easier to carry around.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't understand this view but That after that happened then the pads really took off and the tablets and I think there's been a shift from.
Speaker 1: there was a time when Netbooks were super popular because everyone wanted to have a tiny little computer that they could use it like Starbucks or on the go.
Speaker 1: you know at a convention have some internet display some stuff and Tablets have mostly destroyed that market.
Speaker 0: because I think well here's what happened.
Speaker 1: right the majority of the people who got netbooks Really just wanted the stuff that a tablet does and netbook was just the cheapest way to do that.
Speaker 0: But the reason the netbook was crazy popular.
Speaker 0: there were some people who were like man I can have my normal desktop computer and then I can just have a really tiny computer That does almost nothing.
Speaker 0: that's super portable, right?
Speaker 0: But most of the people I think who bought netbooks bought them because oh my god It's a computer for like $200 holy shit.
Speaker 0: and then they would get them and they would buy a ton of them or you know or one for everyone in Family or who knows right.
Speaker 0: and they'd be like, oh these are really crummy and they break and they don't work.
Speaker 0: So then they didn't get repeat customers and they didn't last very long at all before they were useless You know, they would physically break or become so slow that they were used, you know, and then Nobody bought them anymore.
Speaker 0: And that was the end of the netbook.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't know if it's completely dead if you still want one.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you can get one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I guess that Bunch of factors combined and we're at the point where that market of the ultra portable Ultra little ultra cheap ultra crappy laptop really doesn't have a market.
Speaker 0: I think the other thing is right is that most of these people, you know, you buy a powerful computer, right?
Speaker 0: And you're a stupid computer user.
Speaker 0: I'm not even gonna beat around the bush and you fill it up with malware and other crap because you're dumb and you accidentally Potentially fill it up with junk even if you don't not intentional.
Speaker 1: I mean on my laptop my Fujitsu, you know ultra portable.
Speaker 1: I spent a lot of money on in 2008. ish It's actually.
Speaker 1: no I reinstalled windows because cruft had built up windows.
Speaker 1: Let's cross build.
Speaker 0: I don't have cruft building.
Speaker 1: Oh, I had cruft build up though.
Speaker 1: Most of it was actually Fujitsu updates that now that I reinstalled I'd got rid of all that stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got rid of all the stuff from the get-go.
Speaker 0: but anyway if you're the dumb person lets cruft build up.
Speaker 0: your stuff gets slower and the computer gets less and less useful and then you can Reinstall to get back to where you were.
Speaker 1: most people don't realize that that's what you do though.
Speaker 0: Well, that's true.
Speaker 0: But the thing is you have a netbook that things slow to begin with.
Speaker 0: It's gonna take like a month before you get so slow.
Speaker 0: You can't even use it.
Speaker 0: Yep, because you know the powerful computer It's like you can fill it up with more crap before it's useless.
Speaker 1: But I mean at this point I like I thought about it.
Speaker 1: Do I really need a laptop much like a long time ago?
Speaker 1: I bought a Mac to use as my primary PC because you know PC gaming was dead at the time.
Speaker 1: I wasn't really I didn't need a desktop, you know computer in the like I had in the old sense and It was a failure.
Speaker 1: It was a mistake.
Speaker 1: I went back to using a Linux PC within about a week, but me all that aside I'd really tried to think like do I really need a new laptop or Can I just get by with this old one and or not even need one?
Speaker 1: and it turns out I do.
Speaker 1: I actually need a laptop for a lot of things.
Speaker 1: I travel a lot and When I'm using a computer somewhere remote, I'm not surfing the net with it.
Speaker 1: I have a smartphone for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like if I'm in the shore, I don't even need to bring a laptop.
Speaker 1: I got a smartphone.
Speaker 1: What I mean to the shore look at Twitter and then go to the beach, right?
Speaker 1: And I have a data plan on the phone.
Speaker 1: I don't need a data plan on my computer anymore because I don't need the data drop that often.
Speaker 1: What I need the laptop for is type and shit because I type a lot of stuff.
Speaker 1: I Need a laptop.
Speaker 0: you could even get an iPad that you can attach a computer a keyboard to that Yeah, but that's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: then also I Do video editing and it turns out if I get a new laptop They're actually like the new x230 if I get it with the i7 comparable in power Not counting video card to my desktop PC.
Speaker 0: That's the thing.
Speaker 0: is a video card right?
Speaker 0: if you did PC gaming did not exist.
Speaker 0: I would not even I would not need a desktop computer I would but only for HD video editing.
Speaker 1: that is literally the only thing I would need it for right?
Speaker 0: I would just not have a desktop computer and I would just get an even.
Speaker 0: you know Maybe I would even get the stupid Mac, but who knows what I would get right?
Speaker 0: But I would just have a laptop only maybe the Lenovo T with a bigger one.
Speaker 0: Yep You know, there's a lot of hardware the normal the normal size one, right?
Speaker 0: and then I could everything I do I could do on there except gaming because you can't get a real video card in a Reasonable laptop.
Speaker 0: and if I am getting a big gaming computer I don't want one of those mega Right freaking gaming laptops because the reason you gaming laptop is no good Is that number one.
Speaker 0: it costs more money for less power.
Speaker 0: Even if you go all out than a desktop and two you can't detach the monitor from the keyboard So you can't position yourself for gaming properly.
Speaker 0: It's no good.
Speaker 0: And if I'm plugging a keyboard into it, why didn't I just get desktop?
Speaker 0: This is you know, it's the.
Speaker 0: the whole purpose is stupid and it's also you can't upgrade it like you can a desktop so you got to replace it more often.
Speaker 0: gaming laptop is no good, but Regardless if I didn't play games, I would not need a desktop at all.
Speaker 0: I would just have a laptop.
Speaker 0: But this is the problem We're sort of running into here is you've got this range of devices that are all Computers and all sort of do the same thing in different places.
Speaker 0: You got a smartphone.
Speaker 0: You got a tablet you got a laptop.
Speaker 0: you got you know, a netbook a laptop a desktop an HDPC right all these devices.
Speaker 0: But if you have all of them, right then it's like you hardly use any Individual one of them because it's like okay if I'm on the subway Do I use the tablet or the phone if I'm in bed?
Speaker 1: Do I use the tablet?
Speaker 1: That's something I've run into in general that my living in the city has.
Speaker 1: you know, there's a whole bunch of tangents.
Speaker 1: I go off and I want to go on those tangents But living in New York using a subway and or a bicycle to get around all the time Has basically completely changed my computing landscape Like night and day like if I didn't live in a major city.
Speaker 1: a smartphone actually is not that useful to me But a laptop with a data connection will be much more useful because in those, you know, if I live outside of the city I Drive to places.
Speaker 1: I don't need to plan meeting up with people ad hoc like I do now.
Speaker 1: I mean now we always have the texting and messaging and Google latitude of hey, we're all gonna meet somewhere for dinner.
Speaker 1: Where do we eat?
Speaker 1: I don't know and we'd literally don't plan at all.
Speaker 1: we just wander out of the city and I'll meet up and do stuff like it's not and - I spend a lot of time in the city like Standing outside of a place waiting for other people to show up laptop is useless for that.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna open up a laptop for seven minutes of amusing myself.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna go into a Starbucks and by the time I sat down to open the laptop you guys show up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the phone is perfect for that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's a question of okay, you know in these different situations I would use these different devices.
Speaker 0: Is there should I have all of them or can I not for example?
Speaker 0: I don't have a tablet, you know if I had one I might use it a lion on the couch.
Speaker 0: But I have an HTPC there and I could use my laptop on the couch or my phone on the couch.
Speaker 1: Yep, so another.
Speaker 1: I'm buying a new laptop.
Speaker 1: I have an old laptop.
Speaker 1: that for lying on the couch Just fine.
Speaker 0: So why?
Speaker 0: so why spend money on a tablet if I have like three other devices that are already sort of going in Area?
Speaker 0: if I'm in bed a tablet is probably more comfortable than the phone or the laptop.
Speaker 0: I'm using in bed right now, but why?
Speaker 0: Should buy buy a third device just to be slightly more comfortable in one situation?
Speaker 1: Well personally the decision I have made because I you know I could try to do a thing like we did before and like well if you're this kind of person whatever.
Speaker 1: but now look at me Businessy dude also, you know podcasting nerd dude goes to a lot of conventions My needs are I need a device.
Speaker 1: I mean if you list out all the needs then you can slice it up to figure out how many purpose-built devices you need.
Speaker 1: For example, what do we need?
Speaker 1: people like us?
Speaker 1: We need something that can play HD video and audio to pretty much any projector in the world at a convention.
Speaker 0: That's gotta be a laptop.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: No, I mean you can maybe find a tablet that does that but it's everyone I've seen trying to do something like that has failed right?
Speaker 0: It's gonna be finicky.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be you.
Speaker 0: we need something that's super reliable and we need it multiple times a year.
Speaker 1: It has to be a laptop too because it has to be powerful and versatile.
Speaker 1: I mean we did that one packs panel.
Speaker 1: We were playing games live emulated in like maim.
Speaker 0: I mean you can't do it with Xbox controllers connected to right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know good luck getting that to go on some tablet That's running Android or iOS.
Speaker 0: Maybe you've got a Windows tablet, but then why don't you just have freaking left?
Speaker 1: I need a device.
Speaker 1: I need my connectivity device which is a classic device that didn't exist for me in 2008 But it's my smartphone now.
Speaker 1: It's I'm always connected.
Speaker 1: anyone who messages me emails me calls me tweets me text me anything I had I always have it.
Speaker 1: I literally leave this in the bathroom when I'm showering.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, there's also the.
Speaker 0: the smartphone is just um, you can't have not have a smart.
Speaker 0: It's also the iPod music player.
Speaker 0: It's also a catcher, you know, my calendar.
Speaker 0: It's it's everything.
Speaker 1: It's even my wallet for something.
Speaker 0: Yeah And it's so small you can just take it anywhere Even places that you know.
Speaker 0: a small like 8-inch tablet would be prohibited.
Speaker 1: I read a great article talking about how rapidly humans evolved sort of socially or not.
Speaker 1: not evolved in the evolution sense But in a more direct sense.
Speaker 1: People who lose a sense like sight or smell or hearing.
Speaker 1: there's a specific sort of withdrawal.
Speaker 1: They go through where the brain is like grasping for that sensory input that's not there anymore before it adapts around it.
Speaker 1: There's an article showing that if someone has been using a smartphone the way we do for more than some amount of time It's not that long a time.
Speaker 1: It was like six months or so That if the smartphone is unavailable You your brain literally reacts in a way that is indistinguishable to someone who has lost their sight or hearing.
Speaker 1: The brain treats it like you have lost a primary sense if your smartphone is not available.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know, it's sort of like when you pick up a hammer to hammer things your brain basically makes that hammer Not like, you know, it's not thinking about your hand.
Speaker 0: It's like the hammer is now a part of your body.
Speaker 1: or driving a car, right?
Speaker 1: You know this.
Speaker 1: when you're driving like you're actually driving not that we drive that much anymore But your butt kind of gets replaced by your two rear wheels.
Speaker 1: like you feel like the car is an extension of you.
Speaker 1: It's not this separate thing.
Speaker 1: You're piloting right?
Speaker 0: That's how your brain works.
Speaker 0: So, you know if you had a hammer in your hand all the time 24/7
Speaker 1: I'm showering pooping laying in bed the last thing I do every
Speaker 0: night It's basically your brain has replaced your hand with the hammer And if you lose the hammer your brain is gonna like whoa.
Speaker 1: That's why the one thing I worry about if I get Google Glass, even if it's shitty having it It'll be trouble when I take it off Like big trouble.
Speaker 1: I mean look the what's the first thing I do in the morning.
Speaker 1: I hear the Uniqlo thing make its noise Because I've been waking up too early.
Speaker 1: I Hear it, but the volume was like messed up.
Speaker 1: It was really quiet.
Speaker 1: So I'm laying there and I'm like I hear music.
Speaker 1: Who's playing music?
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: You know when you're in that Twilight where your brain doesn't fully turned on yet?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you can't figure stuff out.
Speaker 1: Like if a phone rings you expect the alarm to be there.
Speaker 1: You're like what the fuck is that?
Speaker 1: I've never heard us.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the first thing I do in the morning is pick up my smartphone Don't even put my glasses on yet and I hold it up to my face and I look at what time it is.
Speaker 1: I unlock it and I see if I got any email and I look at Twitter.
Speaker 1: Yep, and I read Google News.
Speaker 1: The last thing I do before I go to bed is look at my smartphone to make sure the alarm is set Same thing.
Speaker 1: and then I plug it into a USB thing and I fall asleep same thing.
Speaker 1: That's why the Jane McGonigal game.
Speaker 1: I I'm a proponent of it, but at the same time it it's I Feel a lack.
Speaker 1: So yeah smartphone.
Speaker 1: I don't think of it as what do I need?
Speaker 1: What does the smartphone do instead?
Speaker 1: I think smartphone is given.
Speaker 1: What does it already do?
Speaker 1: that?
Speaker 1: I don't have to do with another device.
Speaker 0: So really it's like if you're PC gaming you need a desktop.
Speaker 0: Yes No We're on it if you don't have some sort of ultra powerful application that you're working on at home.
Speaker 0: If you don't already have a desktop, you probably don't need one though I would recommend you should be a PC gamer and get a desktop because seriously or in the very least you need home Infrastructure.
Speaker 1: if you're going all laptop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're going all laptop, you need to say you need an answer saying in your house You don't have a sand in your house.
Speaker 1: You could we're getting there.
Speaker 0: Where are you gonna put it?
Speaker 1: actually You get a NAS in your thinking about that because I got a lot of HD video I was doing.
Speaker 0: I was doing pricing and you've got a media center.
Speaker 0: You should get an HD V C. Yeah, but you know if you go all laptop you got a laptop and you have a smartphone.
Speaker 0: do you need the tablet?
Speaker 0: Well, I think what it comes down to is, you know, maybe you're like grandma.
Speaker 0: grandma probably just needs tablet and nothing else.
Speaker 0: tablet it's only and only because Tablet would be easier for grandma to use because you just touched the things to make them go.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll say this here's where tablet could fit into my existing workflows of life.
Speaker 0: I could just.
Speaker 0: I would use it on couch bed and other places where it'd be more.
Speaker 1: If I didn't have a Kindle, I would also use a tablet as an e-reader.
Speaker 1: yeah, because one of my primary use cases now is standing on subway platform or train Crowded because it's the four or five and it's rush hour Can't even hold a book with two hands, but I can hold a device in one hand.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's either a phone or a tablet or a Kindle.
Speaker 0: I pads too big for one hand.
Speaker 1: Uh, I've seen people do in the one hand you what they had they I. so I've seen multiple people with this.
Speaker 1: It's one of those flip cases that like holds the iPad got a gripper.
Speaker 1: when you open it The inside has a gripper.
Speaker 1: you stick your hand into like a reverse.
Speaker 0: I'm anti anything like that because it's dorky.
Speaker 1: Uh Since when do you care about aesthetics?
Speaker 1: Because I have the 100%.
Speaker 1: all my devices are naked at all times.
Speaker 1: Otherwise the fuck's the point.
Speaker 0: That's right
Speaker 1: because Well, no, I should qualify that I am only of the luxury of that because I am wealthy enough to where if I break my Smartphone and it's my fault Not that I've ever done that but if I did I can afford to just buy a new one.
Speaker 1: if I was like when I was RIT and I didn't have any money like I couldn't even afford food if I had a smartphone I would have had some sort of protective case.
Speaker 0: I'm going.
Speaker 0: I'm going further than that, right?
Speaker 0: I see a lot of people with shattered phones even people I know.
Speaker 0: What the fuck did you do?
Speaker 1: I've dropped my iPhone 3G and for many times but you dropped your iPod mini to demonstrate to me how Invincible it was.
Speaker 1: you and wait, but I did one foot no and poked it with your toe.
Speaker 1: No, the screen is not correct.
Speaker 1: That is what happened.
Speaker 1: No, that is not what I was like.
Speaker 1: Scott it don't bring that bike.
Speaker 0: Hey, you're like no fine This is what happened and in fact, I will tell you okay I was trying to demonstrate the invincibility of the iPod mini.
Speaker 0: you demonstrated.
Speaker 0: it was in a case.
Speaker 0: I Dropped it on the floor and then I stomped on it with my heel and the screen broke by stomping.
Speaker 0: I was stomping on the screen with my heel of my foot and it broke.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile, I had iPhone 3G and iPhone 4. at first I protected the 3G But that was only for like a few months.
Speaker 1: I had my Motorola Razr the good one.
Speaker 1: Not the shitty Crazer.
Speaker 1: I I was drunk and showered with it on me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was fine.
Speaker 1: I hit the next day.
Speaker 0: I called people with it But anyway, I had 3G and a 4. it fell off.
Speaker 0: my 4 has never been protected.
Speaker 0: I've had it for two years.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: The 3G was only protected for a few months.
Speaker 0: It was otherwise naked.
Speaker 0: I dropped them both many times.
Speaker 0: They have never shattered or broken or had battery problems or anything.
Speaker 0: So anyone who has them either it is more confirmation of my magic technology protecting powers or a confirmation bias or These people who have broken it are doing something for example getting drunk and showering with their devices.
Speaker 1: I Dropped that same one in the toilet like four times over the course of the time.
Speaker 0: I had protectors are dumb.
Speaker 0: You only need a protector if you need to protect it from yourself if you need to protect it from yourself.
Speaker 1: Well, actually I am thinking about getting a protector, but I won't use this protector all the time.
Speaker 1: This is this protector is waterproof protect.
Speaker 1: Yes or yon beach for yon beach and rock climbing slash mountain climbing.
Speaker 0: because well No for that you want a device a thing that lets you tether it to yourself.
Speaker 0: So if you drop it off a mountain, it's just sort of hanging on.
Speaker 0: what I want is because when I went in the Adirondacks It doesn't go tick tick All the way down the mountain tick.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I did draw my phone skiing once and it's this phone with this convex landed like this and started just sled it down Like I was chasing it.
Speaker 1: It was going faster than me.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: You should make a ski That's shaped like the bottom of that phone.
Speaker 1: You know skis are kind of shaped like the bottom of this phone actually.
Speaker 0: No, man.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 1: Yeah But where was I going with this right?
Speaker 1: so we went up mountain climbing right Through torrential pouring rain like I was walking down a waterfall at one point.
Speaker 1: Everyone but me brought their fucking smartphones with them in like multiple ziplock bags.
Speaker 1: Every one of those smartphones was fucked really because the ziplock bags filled up with water ziplock But they didn't fill up but enough moisture got in.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah a little secret guys one ziplock bag not enough.
Speaker 1: No kidding two ziplock bags barely enough.
Speaker 1: But I'm thinking about getting a like hard case that also is a like arm straps.
Speaker 1: I can strap the smartphone to my.
Speaker 0: I mean That's a special purpose thing, right?
Speaker 0: There's nothing wrong with say having the thing that lets you tie your iPhone to your arm for running or the one to mount it To the bike like that on shoes.
Speaker 1: We're like, it's one thing to have a hundred pair of slight crook slightly.
Speaker 0: So fashion shoes, yeah, I have the same.
Speaker 0: I have ten Nike sneakers in ten different colors.
Speaker 1: But now I got.
Speaker 1: let's see skis.
Speaker 1: Well ski boots are rollerblades running shoes Exactly shoes climbing shoes.
Speaker 0: It's a snow boots.
Speaker 0: The default phone protector is naked.
Speaker 0: The default protector is always naked.
Speaker 1: The thing is what really gets me is the Kindle like?
Speaker 1: the Kindle is the main reason I don't get a pad.
Speaker 1: because I love Irritators I like after a month of using that thing Fuck paper books.
Speaker 1: I'd like now when I have to open a paper book.
Speaker 0: I'm like, ah my god I still like a paper book.
Speaker 0: But the Kindle is the first e-reader that I can actually kind of use.
Speaker 1: The only thing is I won't use the the Kindle on the beach.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I got to bring a physical book to the beach.
Speaker 0: So I think my bad luck with that, too.
Speaker 0: I've had books get so wet on the beach.
Speaker 1: I only bring books I bought at the beach.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the beach.
Speaker 0: and then I got.
Speaker 0: I remember one time I bought a book at the beach and then I left it out.
Speaker 1: Oh, you left it outside overnight.
Speaker 0: I left it outside overnight.
Speaker 0: But dude The thing is I the worst part about it was I saw the book out there on the stoop and I knew that it was Out in the stoop and you were like, I will be fine.
Speaker 0: No, I thought it was someone else's book.
Speaker 0: Right, and I was like, oh someone else leaving their book outside whatever.
Speaker 0: it doesn't bother me and I'm God if there was ever Karma in the world And I still haven't finished reading.
Speaker 0: it was kidnapped by Stevenson.
Speaker 0: I haven't finished reading that.
Speaker 1: but basically look I need I need a device that I can read books on and I have a Specific.
Speaker 1: it's a device that only does that.
Speaker 1: I got the non touchscreen Kindle.
Speaker 1: The cool thing about it is it fits in my pocket like for real naked.
Speaker 1: But if it was in a case it wouldn't fits in a big pocket.
Speaker 1: it fits in all my blazer pockets But you can't like.
Speaker 0: that's a big buck.
Speaker 0: You can't sit on it though.
Speaker 0: It doesn't bend.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, but it'll fit.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, it's like you can get it in the pocket and you can walk around But it's like it's a little big in there and then you can't sit with it.
Speaker 1: But if you're wearing a jacket like a blazer or a suit, it just fits in the pocket.
Speaker 0: I mean a Giant gun will fit in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sort of the point.
Speaker 1: so that covers e-reading my phone covers.
Speaker 1: pretty much all Want to connect to things when I'm not home.
Speaker 1: So the only things I need a laptop for are showing video and audio conventions Editing HD video while I'm at said conventions, so I don't forget about it.
Speaker 1: and you know put up a video from packs Just in time for the next packs And recording audio from a firewire thing live at an event.
Speaker 1: So I need a super powerful laptop.
Speaker 0: the things I need my laptop for our conventions, of course, right?
Speaker 0: Yep, doing computing for real like in the bedroom just cuz I don't want to get up and head on Saturday morning But maybe I could do some work.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you need to do something that involves multiple computers, especially developing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I got to get more computers going on in the house just to you know Network stuff or who knows what.
Speaker 1: yeah, I never have to.
Speaker 0: sometimes I had to bring a computer.
Speaker 0: that like moves, right?
Speaker 0: For example, I want to plug a real computer into say my Apple to GS.
Speaker 0: Well, I can't bring my desktop over there and the Apple to GS is big and heavy And maybe I don't want to bring that over near the desk, you know stuff like that.
Speaker 0: And also when you go to events in the city like hacker events, you got to bring a laptop, right?
Speaker 0: I can't bring my desktop there to do right.
Speaker 0: so I need a portable thing that can also do coding work.
Speaker 1: Laptop is the only thing I'm looking at this one because it's powerful enough.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's no video card.
Speaker 1: it'll it won't play games effectively, but It'll do some of that stuff well enough like I'll be able to play Civ 5 on it if I want.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if I didn't need to do this work on the go, I could probably just have the iPad instead or something like that I don't know.
Speaker 1: So I have all these use cases.
Speaker 1: So I need a very portable very high-powered laptop.
Speaker 1: So again, I need an ultra book.
Speaker 1: There aren't that?
Speaker 1: I mean there's still a lot of ultra books.
Speaker 0: I'm surprised but I think there's more than there used to be.
Speaker 0: but they're different than they used to be because now they used to Be right more like the Lenovo X that I have which is we'll make a laptop We're gonna just make it a smaller screen size like 12 13 inches But at the same time we're gonna pack a lot of horsepower into there.
Speaker 0: lots of RAM lots of CPU lots of everything Everything but video card and an SSD makes you third is gonna have 8 gigs of RAM and an i7.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right and an SSD.
Speaker 1: It's actually almost better than my desktop except for the video card.
Speaker 0: But what's happened now is the MacBook Air right is sort of like ultra book, but it's sort of netbook, right?
Speaker 0: I view it as like extra small netbook But it's slightly more like reliable and it's not just gonna like die on you like a netbook.
Speaker 0: It's actually gonna last and it does normal computing work, you know, I could almost use it if it ran windows With the air's and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: a laptop that is big in Horizontal, you know in two dimensions and super thin and the third one is not useful to me.
Speaker 1: I need something I can carry in a tiny bag Exactly.
Speaker 0: That's why I mean the MacBook Air isn't.
Speaker 0: that bit is very very small in all the dimensions It is but it's like they.
Speaker 0: you know, the thinness is impressive, you know, but at the same time It's like how much does that thinness really affect me, right?
Speaker 0: I'm you know, it affects me more having having to carry a whole another weight.
Speaker 0: The air is also way less.
Speaker 0: is that I need it for the air?
Speaker 0: You need like a zillion adapters on it to get all these connectors and thingies that you need to do work whereas the Lenovo X just has freaking as USBs all over the place and a VGA and Ethernet even as a dial-up modem daddy
Speaker 1: to USB 3 and one always powered USB 2.
Speaker 0: Right, it's got headphone hole microphone hole.
Speaker 0: I got all these holes removable batteries all these things that allow me to get work done Right.
Speaker 0: and and for you know, the price of that is an extra centimeter or two of thickness But it's really not any bigger than there any other dimensions.
Speaker 1: so much And as a real chicken keyboard, you know, I was kind of sold on the x230 because the x220 was so great.
Speaker 1: But you know, I got to my due diligence.
Speaker 1: I did a whole bunch of research.
Speaker 1: all the other similar ultra portable ultra book kind of things I found were a thousand dollars more Slightly smaller not any more powerful.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they kept the altar.
Speaker 0: Everyone's trying to copy the MacBook.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna be another thousand dollars to save like two millimeters in one dimension.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone's just copying the air.
Speaker 1: because they also seriously, you know I love my Fujitsu life book.
Speaker 1: like that Fujitsu makes really great like boutique ultra books but Fujitsu support really fucking sucks like Really hard to get any sort of drivers or help and like they'd had the shock sensor thing that you know Protects the hard drive.
Speaker 0: You don't need that if you have an SSD I know.
Speaker 1: but yeah that stopped working as soon as I installed service pack one of Vista And I went to Fujitsu, but I can't wait to support that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it just like Those sort of like non Big name in America laptops seem to be cooked slightly So in weird ways that just cause problems.
Speaker 0: that is one thing that's very annoying right when you build a desktop, right?
Speaker 1: I get like art, you know a bit.
Speaker 0: or aces Chipset though you build it on your own which means you install clean windows or clean Linux on it.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're going that road, right?
Speaker 0: If you no one buys a desktop that's already put together.
Speaker 1: People do.
Speaker 0: but if you buy a laptop, you can't really buy a blank one.
Speaker 0: I mean you can.
Speaker 0: there are companies that sell like awesome Linux laptops and stuff like that But their hardware is so bad.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it.
Speaker 1: Now the only way to do it.
Speaker 1: you can't get a clean install disk either.
Speaker 1: They either give you a restore partition or like a DVD that reinstalls all the bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah If you buy it see buy a laptop that's already put together that has a bunch of bullshit on it at least Lenovo at least the one I had.
Speaker 0: you could go on and uninstall all their bullshit through the you know Uninstalled programs menu and it would work.
Speaker 0: You just had to uninstall all their stuff and then it would be clean windows.
Speaker 0: Tada But otherwise you got to get a Windows disk from somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but without you know with you get the key and everything, but they're not gonna give you the disk and legally technically contract Whatever, you'd have to buy a new life.
Speaker 0: Somebody was saying that if you buy a Dell, I don't know how true this is.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna tell laughter.
Speaker 0: I have somebody said if you buy a Dell or maybe certain Dell I don't know and you click the right thing when you're checking out They'll send you the disk and the disk is a real Windows disk.
Speaker 0: That's blank.
Speaker 0: Someone said that I don't know if it's true or not.
Speaker 1: I would pay like 20 bucks more just for you to not give me your Norton bullshit.
Speaker 1: I don't want it.
Speaker 0: I don't know why they give this bullshit.
Speaker 1: Why do they?
Speaker 1: I guess Norton and all those people pay them?
Speaker 0: It's well, I mean I can understand Norton right paying them to do something, right?
Speaker 0: But take this for example.
Speaker 0: you buy Lenovo and in that in the taskbar, there's another.
Speaker 0: this is Intel Wi-Fi manager, right?
Speaker 0: Intel or Lenovo, what do they gain by having that there?
Speaker 0: Windows already has a Wi-Fi man.
Speaker 0: It works fine.
Speaker 0: Why do they have this other Wi-Fi manager in there?
Speaker 0: that's ugly I could see and is worse.
Speaker 0: if it let you use some special features of the hardware that weren't standard Why don't you just make a normal Windows driver that exposes those so that the Windows Wi-Fi thing can take advantage of that?
Speaker 1: Nope, but well, I was gonna make it even more rude.
Speaker 0: quite a standard Windows.
Speaker 1: No one uses those things anyway Like in the x230 you can get.
Speaker 1: now it's free to get the regular Intel Chipset for the Wi-Fi instead of when you get it.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be this bullshit.
Speaker 1: Hardware wise you can get the Lenovo one or the Intel one.
Speaker 1: you can pick for free which one yeah or you can pay like 50 bucks to get the Intel like special one.
Speaker 1: as far as I can tell it doesn't that?
Speaker 0: no I thought that has 3g if you buy that.
Speaker 1: no No, the 3g stuff is completely separate from that.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay There's a lot of like special hardware and software for Wi-Fi.
Speaker 1: As far as I can tell it's not used by any actual environment anywhere in the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you see all these things like hey, it's double Wi-Fi like you know It's not next twice and you get double bandwidth because it's like you're connecting with two.
Speaker 1: I defy you to get your router to support.
Speaker 0: Nothing will do that unless you buy like a set of hardware and then it'll work once and never work again.
Speaker 0: It's bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I did all my research.
Speaker 0: that's a great way to kill an episode.
Speaker 1: I think right now the you know, I need new laptop my Fujitsu from 2008 2008 to get near its end though.
Speaker 1: I'm turning into the kitchen PC.
Speaker 1: Okay, I don't have to print out recipes anymore.
Speaker 0: See tablets actually really good for a kitchen PC.
Speaker 0: Nah Maybe right because then you if it was mounted if it was mounted on the wall like I'd not because the even if you cry cuz it's a tablet you can just wipe it off.
Speaker 0: if you get the Keyboard going on in there stuff can get in there in the kitchen.
Speaker 1: Well, what I would do is all get dirty.
Speaker 0: you touch some eggs and then you touch the keyboard.
Speaker 0: I would actually mount the tablet on the wall, right, but you touch some eggs you touch a tablet.
Speaker 0: Well, you can just wipe that off spray with some whatever.
Speaker 0: All right, it'll be all clean again.
Speaker 0: Spray with some rubbing alcohol water mixture.
Speaker 0: be all good and won't be all nasty with who knows what kind of Line of buying any hardware is.
Speaker 1: does it fill a need I have and is that need a legitimate need?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and is it worth the money?
Speaker 1: It's not worth the price of iPad for Slightly less chance of ruining a really old barely functional laptop.
Speaker 0: No I mean I you know what price of iPad slightly more comfortable computing in bed when I wake up and go to bed and Slightly more comfortable computing on the couch.
Speaker 1: Yep, not worth $500 cuz I'm not gonna carry it to Starbucks.
Speaker 1: I got not carrying it anywhere.
Speaker 0: I already carry and all the things I need.
Speaker 0: I still.
Speaker 1: Whenever I see someone holding up a gigantic iPad or MacBook to take a picture with the built-in camera I should just I want to just reach up and smack the left smack the tab.
Speaker 1: The act is its own punishment as it is.
Speaker 0: No, you know because they don't realize it.
Speaker 0: It's the same thing.
Speaker 0: I see people with iPhones or all kinds of smartphones and They don't hold the next to their head like a regular phone.
Speaker 0: when they're talking on the phone They like hold it like a taco or they'll just put the bottom near their mouth like pointing forward.
Speaker 0: Or people are holding this phones and all these weird ways.
Speaker 0: It's like dude.
Speaker 0: It's a phone.
Speaker 0: You hold it like a phone this part near the ear this part near the mouth Right.
Speaker 0: or people have those little headphones that have the microphone on the wire and then they'll like grab the microphone part and push it Close to their face.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: no just like.
Speaker 1: no you have to do that mine.
Speaker 1: You do not mine the way it works.
Speaker 1: It's just a microphone.
Speaker 1: if you leave it hanging by the neck.
Speaker 1: No one can hear shit.
Speaker 0: No, that's bullshit.
Speaker 0: I have the etymotics and also I've done this with the official Apple ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right There's a microphone on the string.
Speaker 0: You just let it hang where it hangs.
Speaker 1: Yes I tried that.
Speaker 1: I'm on the street in New York and I do that.
Speaker 1: I've done it.
Speaker 1: I've done it too.
Speaker 0: We're just fine.
Speaker 1: I recalled myself and recorded it.
Speaker 1: the voice.
Speaker 1: you basically hear the traffic and me in the distance.
Speaker 0: I've used it works just fine.
Speaker 0: You just push the button and you just start talking.
Speaker 0: you don't touch anything.
Speaker 0: You just leave the phone in your pocket.
Speaker 0: You leave the wire where it is.
Speaker 0: Just talk.
Speaker 0: Alright, if you have a smartphone you hold it like a phone next to your head.
Speaker 1: if you do not do those thing Microphone near my mouth because otherwise it doesn't work Then yours is shitty.
Speaker 0: mine doesn't have this problem.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I buy a new laptop I think the best ultra book from all everything I can all the research I can do the Lenovo x230 wins Which is still sad because it has problems like it has a chick-lit keyboard.
Speaker 1: well, it is a chick-lit keyboard and a Relatively low resolution screen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it's not perfect and it's like how come a perfect thing doesn't exist.
Speaker 1: It does it's a thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not perfect.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can get slightly better for another thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: What can you get for those no slightly higher resolution screen slightly thinner from like Panasonic?
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando Okay for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.