Speaker 1: It's a Monday April 2 3. they say oh, I'm Scott I'm rim Geek nice time and the show is on.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the fuck.
Speaker 1: the title this show?
Speaker 0: Principled idealism versus pragmatic reality.
Speaker 0: sleepy time the show.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Usually you're the one yelling at me saying hey the openers way too long.
Speaker 1: It would have been it would have been the right length if you didn't make the title so long As opposed to nothing.
Speaker 1: that's nothing would have been very short.
Speaker 1: the shortest in fact none shorter.
Speaker 0: So I did you know kind of a more short.
Speaker 0: now We've already done the book club show and I don't really want to do a separate review of the movie.
Speaker 0: But I did see the Hunger Games movie, and it was a solid beef lick.
Speaker 0: Pretty good.
Speaker 1: re-watched the Lord of the Rings Which I probably hadn't seen in its entirety since the theater.
Speaker 1: wait so all three leave it or not?
Speaker 1: 12 hours Yeah, believe it or not was in 2003 was the last one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's some good shit.
Speaker 1: Yo Like the best Pretty good it comes to you at the turn of the tide.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 1: That was like all right this.
Speaker 0: yeah, you know to this day My whole life.
Speaker 0: I have said any time something comes anywhere.
Speaker 0: I usually say at the town of the tide Even before those movies.
Speaker 1: It's just on the dawn of the fifth day.
Speaker 1: look to the east.
Speaker 1: What's taters?
Speaker 1: yeah, no okay, no.
Speaker 0: no I think I say that about as often as I say.
Speaker 0: turn of the tide.
Speaker 0: No, I did not say it until the movies.
Speaker 0: fair.
Speaker 0: Anyway anyway Got a news.
Speaker 1: all right, let's just jump to news captain.
Speaker 1: So Intel came out with the new chips the potato variety.
Speaker 0: yep, not the very salty not the potato variety also, not the Crazy, I don't know the rumor sites up until the announcement.
Speaker 0: We're doing the usual.
Speaker 0: This is gonna be like nothing.
Speaker 0: People were talking about crazy.
Speaker 1: All the non crazy sites were saying the same thing and then in the reviews now that they actually have it They're pretty much saying the same thing.
Speaker 1: and this is what went down right.
Speaker 1: so they had Sandy Bridge and now the new one is Ivy Bridge, so do not buy Sandy Bridge otherwise right now.
Speaker 0: Otherwise you are dumb yep, and as of this morning when I looked at Newegg they cost about the same.
Speaker 1: well Yeah, that's pretty much how it goes.
Speaker 1: so Basically here's the deal.
Speaker 1: It's Smaller and way more energy efficient.
Speaker 1: So if you got like a laptop or a netbook or something hot shit that batteries gonna be lasting way longer.
Speaker 0: I'm going away fast pretty much waiting on buying a new laptop until there's a new Lenovo that uses these things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the same time.
Speaker 1: It's like how much faster is it than the Sandy Bridge?
Speaker 1: not that much faster I mean, it's quad-core.
Speaker 1: It's a thing is like 15% Faster, but it's not so much faster like if you've got a sandy bridge.
Speaker 1: You should not upgrade.
Speaker 1: You're just blowing Scott.
Speaker 0: I got a core i7 920 from before they'd renumbered it yep, and it is yet to be the bottleneck on anything I've ever done including HD video editing my hard drives Benchmarks that were comparing like you know video encoding and game playing.
Speaker 1: upgrading my video card has more effect than anything Yeah, and it showed like graphs like comparing the benchmark of the previous and the current i7 and the difference.
Speaker 1: It's like it's faster, but it's like a tiny bit faster.
Speaker 1: It's like it's not gonna change your life.
Speaker 1: It's not worth $300.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my i7 920.
Speaker 0: I think is gonna last me another two years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my I got a core to do.
Speaker 1: Oh, I expect it to last me another year or two.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right That might not suffice if you actually want to record the entirety of that stupid bike race in 1080p and then edit it It'll be fun.
Speaker 0: You will see.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but the big job the other big thing about this is they up.
Speaker 1: the integrated Intel GPU that's in there is Significantly better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I heard it was marginally better.
Speaker 1: Okay, it's still.
Speaker 1: here's the thing.
Speaker 1: It's still shit.
Speaker 1: It's an Intel integrated GPU.
Speaker 1: It's still shit, but it is Significantly better than the 3000. so it's like before.
Speaker 1: you had sort of like this sort of runny almost diarrhea And now you've got like a consistent normal healthy piece of poop.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is I need that how it is still because I you know for laptops like I ran into a problem that our conventions I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna do a Linux like straight-up install on my old laptop now because that laptops near an end-of-life anyway.
Speaker 1: But the new Ubuntu is apparently really good.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Conrad I saw his tweet about it.
Speaker 0: So that's what I'm gonna put on there.
Speaker 0: just to see.
Speaker 0: It can serve really good most HD videos.
Speaker 0: But if I encode an HD video that has a high maximum bitrate and a two pass VBR PCs play it fine that laptop cannot play it.
Speaker 1: Maybe it has to do with like the size of the something like this.
Speaker 1: You know if the bit rate is high then at a point in the video if the bit rate is variable where there are lots Of bits maybe it's greater than like a certain spot and the memory can't hold all the bits.
Speaker 0: So I did a little bit of performance profiling.
Speaker 1: Maybe the memory isn't fast enough and it can't push Straight up.
Speaker 0: when I play an HD video Like a modern one like get an MKV from like a current blu-ray release of something on the Pirate Bay It maxes out the CPU and it stutters every now and then.
Speaker 0: so I think it's just the fact that it's like a Centrino because I bought that laptop when I still learned in the hospital.
Speaker 1: I three played, you know, my i3 HD PC played.
Speaker 1: Lord of the Rings Scott Ray rips just fine.
Speaker 0: I think I bought that laptop in 2005.
Speaker 1: All right, that's not too bad.
Speaker 0: might have been 2006 maybe seven at the latest.
Speaker 1: I know I drove to that FedEx after driving home stupid goddamn play Anyway from beacon, but yeah, basically apparently according to all these articles Intel has like a tick-tock strategy, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like tick is like, you know, though for one generation of CPUs They'll be like little update like tick and then the next generation talk like big update.
Speaker 1: They're calling this generation tick plus.
Speaker 1: So it's like yeah, it's it's a small update.
Speaker 1: But wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute Intel.
Speaker 0: So you're doing so.
Speaker 0: here's the thing I don't like about the technology industry that they seem to change the numbering of various products Semi arbitrarily to make it as impossible as possibly possible to understand Whether or not something is better than something else.
Speaker 1: If there was just clear numbering of what if you could just be like this Intel is better and right cuz Lex more.
Speaker 1: Let's pretend I had was a CPU company right and the first CPU I ever made was the one And the next one I made was the two.
Speaker 1: and then the next one I made was actually two times better than the two.
Speaker 1: So instead of calling it a three I called it the four Right, and actually the numbering was pretty equivalent to how much better it was fine.
Speaker 1: So something was a hundred times as powerful as the one I'd call it the hundred right and I num.
Speaker 1: I'd called all my products this, you know, the Scott 100 the Scott 200.
Speaker 1: You would look at the prices and you would look at the numbers and with math that even dumb people could do you could be That is the one to buy and that is the only one that would.
Speaker 0: so instead I'll release a GTS 2700 X and a GT 2750 and they cost about the same.
Speaker 1: and how do you know which one to buy?
Speaker 0: Well, you go to Tom's Hardware and look at benchmarks and guess right but the thing is it comes down to like your chip factory.
Speaker 1: Not all the chips come out as good.
Speaker 1: I know Oh, I made this chip and I you know, I got to get my yields But I have no problem with binning.
Speaker 0: that is a natural part of right.
Speaker 1: So here's the thing.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I manufacture all these chips.
Speaker 1: Let's just say for you know The sake of whatever half of them come out perfect and half of them.
Speaker 1: there's one part that's busted but they still work.
Speaker 1: They're just a feature that won't work.
Speaker 1: So now I've got to sell all of these chips to make maximum money.
Speaker 1: I'm not just gonna throw half of them away.
Speaker 1: That would be stupid.
Speaker 1: So now how do I sell that other half?
Speaker 1: and I so I could just say okay How much is that feature worth in money and performance wise and give it a different number accordingly?
Speaker 1: So it's sort of honest.
Speaker 1: or I Could sort of jigger the numbering so you're not quite sure.
Speaker 1: and then all these sites are arguing over the need for that feature.
Speaker 0: That's disabled on those GT Yeah, and then benchmarks don't even help you.
Speaker 0: right you have to have a custom benchmark for that exactly.
Speaker 1: and then Suddenly, I'm selling both of these at the same price even when I should always go.
Speaker 0: I should have clarified Non-profiteering evil bullshit reason to do this.
Speaker 0: But this annoys me in general.
Speaker 0: but Intel had a simple like tick tock tick plus.
Speaker 0: next you're gonna have tick GX.
Speaker 1: Well, it's gonna be clock with double plus.
Speaker 0: We're gonna have tock 5,000 and then tick 5050.
Speaker 1: right, but basically that's their strategy is one of one generation is gonna be a small update.
Speaker 1: The next one is a big update small update big update.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I got a core to duo.
Speaker 1: It still works really well.
Speaker 1: Nothing.
Speaker 1: I have no problems whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Mike.
Speaker 0: I got a core i7 920 it.
Speaker 0: I've never maxed it out doing anything
Speaker 1: right, but you know what when that talk hits in about a year or two Probably gonna get you know I'll just replace the motherboard the CPU the memory and the video card and I'll get like, you know the maximum talk with like.
Speaker 0: probably You're gonna get the second best time.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, yeah, I'm not gonna buy the stupid thousand dollar extreme.
Speaker 0: That doesn't get three hundred and fifty dollars.
Speaker 1: you believe they even sell those like you.
Speaker 1: go on Newegg.
Speaker 1: There are people who buy those the thousand dollar CPU.
Speaker 0: That's like a one one percent faster faster than and will be.
Speaker 0: It'll be commodity.
Speaker 0: in like.
Speaker 1: the $300 one's the best one.
Speaker 1: That's the one you should get.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm gonna wait.
Speaker 0: I think I'm gonna skip this tick.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna skip the next talk Following talk.
Speaker 1: That's what you should get because my 920 is going strong.
Speaker 1: by that time I'll probably be getting like 16 gigs of RAM and a who-knows-what video card.
Speaker 0: I've got 12 gigs now.
Speaker 0: I've got 12 gigs of RAM now.
Speaker 0: I got four.
Speaker 0: Wow But see laptop.
Speaker 0: wise, you know, remember I bought my laptop.
Speaker 0: I spent like three grand on that thing because that was before there were netbooks and I bought an ultra portable.
Speaker 0: That was you know back in that day.
Speaker 0: ultra portable meant it Performs as well as a gigantic laptop and is tiny.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now you don't have to know they call that ultra book now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah, I paid a premium for that thing and it lasted a long time, but it is that end-of-life.
Speaker 0: I have to buy a laptop.
Speaker 0: It cannot work anymore Which I'm sad.
Speaker 0: I wanted to hold out longer, but at the same time this laptop lasted forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, relative to what I paid I mean, I bought mine a little bit before yours and I upgraded it a little bit before you did.
Speaker 1: Laptops lasted about the same time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I bought literally the next generation of the same laptop.
Speaker 1: Well, the next generation of the laptop I have now is already available So you're gonna get two generations ahead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you wait for like the X, who knows what the X 220 at work It's pretty great.
Speaker 0: Ah, yeah, I'm gonna get the next x 220.
Speaker 0: Whatever is next.
Speaker 1: Well, it'll probably be x 221 or x. The thing is they already had x 300 right.
Speaker 1: x 300 is the bigger one.
Speaker 1: So it's like they had to make like the x 230 or the x 221 or who knows what I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'll do my research when the time comes.
Speaker 1: it'll probably be x 221 which would probably be exactly the same as x 220 just with The newer Intel chips, I think early fall Which would be a great fucking computer.
Speaker 0: early fall is the longest I can wait because I can't.
Speaker 0: Right now if we show videos at cons, we're relying on your laptop until I get a new one.
Speaker 0: That's fine, which is fine, but it reduces our redundancy.
Speaker 1: It does.
Speaker 1: Anyway, do you have any news?
Speaker 0: I do so.
Speaker 0: Not a lot of people have been talking about this compared to how many people I thought would be talking about it, but basically, the story here is that Larry Page and James Cameron Titanic guy the movie director.
Speaker 0: Yes, Ross perot's son the Ross perot's son Okay guy who is the Mars mission manager for NASA?
Speaker 0: Okay, and the guy who does the X Prize and some other people have all got.
Speaker 0: so basically that's a wild bunch basically a bunch of Billionaires rich white guys and multi-million.
Speaker 1: are any of them not men?
Speaker 1: No, are any of them not white?
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: Okay, who's got?
Speaker 0: I've got That last part.
Speaker 0: who've gotten together and said you know what?
Speaker 0: We are gonna fund a robotic mission to capture and mine a fucking asteroid in space.
Speaker 1: That's pretty badass.
Speaker 0: now why?
Speaker 1: so what kind of men?
Speaker 1: things that they think are on the end, okay Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: I was talking about this at work actually a lot because the space shuttle flyover today got cancelled.
Speaker 0: So we're talking about space and there's some former NASA at my company.
Speaker 0: So there's a lot of.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's got you realize pretty much Most of the successful people in the financial world now were engineers for either the military or NASA.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, there's no money in doing that.
Speaker 1: Look at the NASA budget.
Speaker 1: Yep, but basically, you know where the money is working for the bank.
Speaker 0: I will make an argument that skips all the specifics of this one tax dollars aren't funding it.
Speaker 0: So who cares?
Speaker 1: I care.
Speaker 1: why cuz some guys stupid wasting his money So - he could be doing something better with it Even if this is not like giving it to me.
Speaker 0: if they capture these asteroids and they mine them and they do stuff with them And they don't get a return on their multi-billion dollar investment a direct one I think it's still fine because the in my opinion.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll discover a lot of things in the process.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: space travel space exploration all these things right now are not theoretical problems.
Speaker 0: The theoretical problems in space travel are so far beyond what we're looking at right now.
Speaker 0: I mean theoretical questions are things like speed of light and wormholes.
Speaker 0: space is an engineering problem and History has shown that the only way to advance engineering in a field like this?
Speaker 0: Do it is to try something crazy and go for it?
Speaker 0: Yep That is the only reason I want this to happen because see I gotta say something people haven't said right?
Speaker 1: Yes, people have been concentrating on the fact that like oh my god It cost two bajillion dollars to go get an asteroid and it's only got like half a million dollars worth of rock.
Speaker 0: Well, here's one big point.
Speaker 0: people forget that even if before I want to head you off if you're doing stuff in space with it That is so much cheaper than launching that much stuff into orbit - that is true.
Speaker 1: But here is another thing, right?
Speaker 1: now Those rocks ain't worth shit But you wait for the day when there's no rocks left on earth.
Speaker 1: Those space rocks are gonna be worth a fortune.
Speaker 1: So you'll be like in the year 3000. it'll be like, okay It cost only because we developed this technology a long time ago.
Speaker 1: It only costs a million dollars to get a space rock.
Speaker 1: But because there's no rocks left on earth the space rock is worth a trillion dollars.
Speaker 0: Now one way to look at this.
Speaker 1: or like you're playing Starcraft and there's no mod There's no little blue rocks left on the sky.
Speaker 1: Say how much would you pay for more blue rocks?
Speaker 0: Yes Here's me say we're making a moon base, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah How many how much how many?
Speaker 0: Resources would it cost us as humans on earth to send enough stuff into space to maintain that thing forever and build it?
Speaker 0: five coffee and a tobacco versus capturing asteroids putting them in an orbit of the moon and Manufacturing it all in space.
Speaker 1: That's six doubloons.
Speaker 0: second And this is the cool part Material science is I think the next big sort of like fundamental other than it's already pretty big.
Speaker 0: No, no, I mean other than augmented reality.
Speaker 0: I think the other thing that's already sort of done already - what do you mean done already?
Speaker 1: You don't even know what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: We got that shit barely, what I'm saying is that augmented reality as it becomes mainstream and as the sort of Like as this accelerated rate of advancement reaches this point where it is, you know, it starts, you know It's sort of like combinatorial complexity.
Speaker 0: when we get to that point with augmented reality I think it's gonna change society in crazy fundamental ways.
Speaker 1: I think material society of our people who have access to it The society of all the other people is still gonna be fall even farther behind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a greater cultural Divergence and such.
Speaker 0: that's a separate problem.
Speaker 1: I wasn't worrying about it The number one problem we have that we encounter in our everyday lives.
Speaker 0: the second part though is I think Advances in like fundamental material science research are going to revolutionize society just as much they already have and will continue to do So.
Speaker 0: I think that the they they already have of the last decade will have nothing on like the few years After we start manufacturing things in space.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you think we'll do stuff even better than like carbon fiber and aerogel.
Speaker 0: I think carbon fiber and aerogel will be has bends within a decade.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 1: What could it possible be pot and how quickly possibly make better than like carbon fiber?
Speaker 0: What could science possibly do?
Speaker 0: tubes better than the automatic horse carriage?
Speaker 0: What could science possibly do for me?
Speaker 1: Well, can you can't even imagine?
Speaker 0: So imagine this.
Speaker 0: imagine a skyscraper that we just grow organically and is held up by like one.
Speaker 0: We've already imagined.
Speaker 1: we already imagined that.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, we haven't built it yet.
Speaker 1: I have since the 2000 about the whole screen Nothing but you can see nothing but that.
Speaker 0: so my point on all this is that if you manufacture stuff in space because there isn't the pesky influence of gravity and Atmosphere.
Speaker 0: you can do things that we can't do here.
Speaker 0: You could start to manufacture fundamentally new kinds of materials in really interesting ways.
Speaker 1: Yes, and no right cuz like I don't take for example.
Speaker 1: Let's say you want to Forge some items, right?
Speaker 1: Well on the one hand you don't have gravity so it's really easy to lift a heavy thing to smash down on it Right, but on the other hand is no gravity to pull it down and do the smashing Scott.
Speaker 0: That's not the part I'm talking.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you need to make no no Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about things like certain crystalline structures only form in zero-gravity environments Certain kinds of my growing.
Speaker 0: imagine growing just diamonds in space Also coating things right.
Speaker 0: if you're like spraying stuff you can spray it real even like Wow, I can't really express to you, but I'm sure the listeners might get it how far I am Overshooting your ideas in terms of what is possible.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I'm like we'll build space diamond colonies And you're like we'll put that spray paint on a real fucking good.
Speaker 1: You can get like a centrifuge to spin.
Speaker 1: so perfect spinning.
Speaker 0: anyway summarize my point.
Speaker 0: We did a show on this before men.
Speaker 0: space research is not useful right now.
Speaker 0: stuff like this is awesome And I fully support this endeavor even if it is a complete failure and someone else's money.
Speaker 1: But hey, I'd rather have them give me the money.
Speaker 0: So what are you gonna do with it?
Speaker 0: Sit on a tropical island.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd rather have space mining.
Speaker 1: I might have rockets on my tropical island.
Speaker 1: Oh, will you?
Speaker 1: they might land off the coast of my tropical island.
Speaker 1: I can go swim out and get them.
Speaker 1: That'd be fun.
Speaker 1: Imagine like you're watching a shuttle launch from your Florida Key Island And then the booster lands off the little shore.
Speaker 1: you row in your rowboat.
Speaker 1: go grab a piece.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna do with that?
Speaker 1: put in my little museum my tropical island?
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day I present to you a memoriam of one sea roach.
Speaker 1: I Love I just love roaches in the bug or roach as in smoking some weed or roaches in a dude named roach.
Speaker 0: So this is this is in the same vein as the sort of infamous free cat meme but much more tasteful.
Speaker 0: and Also, I love this sort of thing.
Speaker 0: I just think it's clever and funny and I hope the people who walked by I got a little bit of a laugh.
Speaker 0: I think the moment that really makes it for me is when the guy pours out the coke like you would pour out like when The guy throws the flower a tiny flower.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so what do you got for me?
Speaker 1: So, you know one thing we always complain about is people one thing at panels not knowing how to ask a question.
Speaker 0: In fact, I believe we talked about how you should never let people ask questions at length.
Speaker 1: So here is a Chronicle calm which is the Chronicle of higher education.
Speaker 1: This guy wrote this article entitled how to ask a question by Peter wood.
Speaker 1: He posted it in March 30th 2012 So it's pretty recent.
Speaker 1: allow me to read to you Paragraph number one.
Speaker 1: last Wednesday.
Speaker 1: I attended a debate at st Francis College in Brooklyn at which three men engaged in a lively literate and deeply informed exchange.
Speaker 1: After they finished and the moderator opened the floor for questions the usual thing happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the questioners by and large had no questions.
Speaker 1: instead They offered up prolix piles of words that led nowhere in particular.
Speaker 1: Some sought to show off what they mistook as their own superior knowledge.
Speaker 1: others scolded.
Speaker 1: a few got lost in their own Labyrinths.
Speaker 1: the closest we came to a question was the jacuzzi Rhetorical jab more or less in the form.
Speaker 1: Don't you agree that you're an ignorant buffoon?
Speaker 0: This guy's speaking my language.
Speaker 1: Yes, and he said basically says why has asking become so hard?
Speaker 1: and he wrote this great article That's pretty long ish.
Speaker 1: It's about regular length actually about how people don't know how to fucking ask a question at a panel Lecture, it's debate.
Speaker 0: It's a ye out there Whoever impinge upon us for telling you you should not accept questions.
Speaker 1: Behold well, this guy isn't.
Speaker 1: he's doing.
Speaker 1: he's not doing that.
Speaker 1: He's basically telling people how to ask a question properly.
Speaker 1: He's saying no, he's talking to the question askers not to the question takers.
Speaker 0: But I would I would posit that that will not have any effect for the people who tend to ask those questions Will not read no, but yeah.
Speaker 1: But basically he completely agrees with us and he is the right ideas Pretty much straight down the line about how to ask a good question, etc.
Speaker 0: It said you get one punctuation mark and it can't be a semi-colon.
Speaker 1: Yep And he also one is.
Speaker 1: one of the great things he points out is here.
Speaker 1: I'll read it if you are tempted to speak as the representative of some category Resist as a native of Pittsburgh.
Speaker 1: I find your categorization of the open-hearth Bessemer steel process historically uninformed and offensive Accomplishes nothing.
Speaker 1: were there any viable alternatives to the Bessemer steel process of the 1860s would suffice.
Speaker 1: Declarations that begin as a woman as an African American as a Christian all carry the same instant discount in the audience.
Speaker 1: They claim a privileged form of knowledge that no one need grant you.
Speaker 1: other people in the same category May have quite different views.
Speaker 1: who appointed me to speak for Pittsburgh or you to speak for all women?
Speaker 0: What if?
Speaker 0: what if the lecture were about me?
Speaker 0: And I said as me the person you were just speaking about is the one exception.
Speaker 1: But The whole article is basically full of paragraphs much like that one.
Speaker 0: so I'm tempted to to recall a moment long ago when we used to go to Otacon and We were at the con feedback and like eight people in a row stood up and said I've been coming to Otacon for eight years.
Speaker 0: I've been coming to Otacon for 12 years and everyone applaud each time.
Speaker 0: And our friend Pete was in line to ask a question and when he got up he said my name is Pete.
Speaker 0: I've been coming to Otacon for 400 years.
Speaker 0: Few people in the audience laughed and most everyone else actually looked pretty pissed off.
Speaker 0: It was a proud moment.
Speaker 1: who's good times.
Speaker 0: But speaking of conventions in the meta moment the mocha fest the museum of comic and cartoon air Which we've neglected to mention if you do not know has a fest Except for every year.
Speaker 1: when we mentioned it we attended every year.
Speaker 0: It is one of my favorite things.
Speaker 0: every year Saturday or Sunday Saturday, I think what time I don't know all day all day.
Speaker 1: But you thing is I always go as soon as it opens and then you don't get there into like one.
Speaker 0: That's cuz.
Speaker 0: I'm always laden back with a bunch of people and plans and I eat and I'm not gonna go to one.
Speaker 0: Okay, I'll get there opening.
Speaker 0: Thing is this year I'm gonna a lot of video and do a nice montage video of the whole thing.
Speaker 1: Tell me when you're actually gonna be there.
Speaker 1: cuz.
Speaker 1: then that way like if you go with the opening then I get there at one.
Speaker 1: You'll be like at lunch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if I go there at the opening and you don't get there till later I'm gonna want to go anyway.
Speaker 0: You just showed up if you were anywhere near New York City and you like comics and/or cartoons.
Speaker 0: This is your jam.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, this is great.
Speaker 1: It's there's great stuff here And you only have to go for like you.
Speaker 1: only you don't to go for like the whole weekend three hours.
Speaker 1: You can walk around the whole place just show up walk around to every table and then leave.
Speaker 0: it's like $15.
Speaker 1: there's some really good panels if you really want to go to them, but they have tiny rooms.
Speaker 0: It's not worth.
Speaker 0: I've never gone to one but there's pretty awesome people to give it him.
Speaker 0: Yes, but it is this weekend.
Speaker 0: Oh shit, Saturday, April 28th and Sunday, April 29th.
Speaker 0: So not too long after that July 13th through 15th is Connecticut that convention in Hartford that has everything from steampunk to anime to vidya games.
Speaker 0: soon Yep, we were on the panels department.
Speaker 1: What day is it again?
Speaker 0: Oh, July 30, July.
Speaker 1: Okay, it's more time than I thought.
Speaker 1: I think he's at June.
Speaker 0: So I have started scheduling panels workshops and lectures.
Speaker 0: So if you want to submit an event Go to the website and submit it soon.
Speaker 0: the longer you wait the shittier time slot You are likely to get and the web form is real shitty.
Speaker 1: We're sorry.
Speaker 0: It'll get better next year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's last year.
Speaker 0: It did get well it got worse, but that's cuz.
Speaker 0: we went to a new system Between last year and the year before.
Speaker 0: it got better and between the year before.
Speaker 0: in the year before that it got a hundred thousand Infinity percent better.
Speaker 1: I guess I just start working on the kid.
Speaker 0: I guess you should captain head of all operations and logistics for panels workshops and lectures and guests.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the main I mean if I can get the tripods and I can guarantee that table is gonna be there.
Speaker 1: pretty much everything else I can just do myself.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much all I got to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Connecticut is fun.
Speaker 0: If you're friends with Dave Riley of fast karate fame We've invited him to submit a panel.
Speaker 0: He said he might uh Tell him to submit it.
Speaker 0: I guarantee he will fill rooms.
Speaker 0: all of you fans of him tell him to come and I will hook him up.
Speaker 0: But he has to give me a submission.
Speaker 0: I'm not just gonna pay for him to come for nothing.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: What else I can zenka can?
Speaker 1: when is it is soon?
Speaker 0: You hear that delay there.
Speaker 0: that's me.
Speaker 0: I have to look at my man.
Speaker 1: 11th and 12th Which I think is a Friday and a Saturday, but not a Sunday.
Speaker 1: That's us Greater Philadelphia Expo Center Oaks, Pennsylvania.
Speaker 0: I think that's in or near King of Prussia.
Speaker 0: I forget Zenkai Khan is an anime con that is run by people we know.
Speaker 0: and Actually, the other Scott is the head of panels and workshops at that conventions got Johnson.
Speaker 0: Yes, the other Scott the one who likes politics not me.
Speaker 0: Yes There is a third Scott Johnson and a fourth and a fifth.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of Scott.
Speaker 0: Yes We will be a Zenkai Khan doing a po a pony a panel about both my little pony and dude bro in the same panel.
Speaker 0: Okay, and I forget what else we're doing but we're doing a bunch of stuff and if you were there when we're not presenting we're either going to be eating ridiculous food or Playing German board games in the gaming area both.
Speaker 0: We actually ran into a lot of fans there last year.
Speaker 0: So feel free to bother us and say hi if you see us at the con It's one of the few cons where we're actually kind of just chilling with downtime.
Speaker 0: We're not like in a hurry to run off and do crazy programming.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Are we actually gonna go on the Friday though?
Speaker 1: I think we'll just go.
Speaker 0: just I think we'll just be there all day Saturday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like, you know the dead thing is a day after is Mother's Day.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well the day after it I got a fly to Istanbul.
Speaker 1: so my mom was like, hey, we're barbecue something I'm like coming in from Pennsylvania.
Speaker 0: You could fly to Connecticut.
Speaker 1: Yeah, where am I gonna fly to?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's got to be an airport somewhere near Bridgeport.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, how about near New Haven?
Speaker 0: Nope, I'm pretty sure there's an airport near New Haven.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It's a tiny kind of Airport where you know They get a little tiny Cessna.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you can get a shitty little tiny Cessna from Philly.
Speaker 1: That's just what I want to do.
Speaker 1: It's worth it.
Speaker 1: No, why not?
Speaker 1: No Renting a car is a better idea.
Speaker 0: Anyway, and I guess after all that is Otakon We did submit panels as we do every year.
Speaker 0: if they accept our panels They accepted our panels every time.
Speaker 0: every panel we'd ever submitted every year since 2002 were accepted until they decided they hated us And kicked us off the staff.
Speaker 0: So we'll see.
Speaker 1: if they accept the panels we'll go.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure if they kicked us off the staff because we resigned and they didn't respond and then like Months later, they cut off my access to the staff site.
Speaker 0: So I don't know.
Speaker 0: No one ever like emailed us.
Speaker 0: They didn't.
Speaker 1: they did not communicate very well, which is the problem.
Speaker 0: So I guess I don't know but we submitted yet again.
Speaker 0: So I'll just say that if you want us to attend Otakon we did submit a bunch of panels.
Speaker 0: You should tell Otakon you want us to be there.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll be there.
Speaker 0: if they give us panels we'll show up and Pax dev slash.
Speaker 0: Pax prime is also coming.
Speaker 1: We will be at pax day weekend for sure same weekend as dragon con which we won't be going to.
Speaker 0: sorry dragon con If you move we'd go.
Speaker 0: that's right.
Speaker 1: It's like Dragon con is sort of like swords And I'm pretty.
Speaker 0: I think I'm gonna go to Pax dev.
Speaker 0: so if any of you were going to Pax dev let me know.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: well, I think I'm gonna go anyway.
Speaker 0: Maybe do a lecture.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: That's all up in the air still.
Speaker 0: So I guess Scott can introduce this since it was his idea for a show.
Speaker 1: I actually should probably bring it up.
Speaker 1: Is the story right?
Speaker 1: so Twitter bootstrap?
Speaker 1: if you don't know Twitter bootstrap, this is pretty awesome JavaScript framework library sort of thing.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: and basically what it does is if you see a website mate once you go to the Twitter bootstrap website and if you go to Twitter the actual Twitter website and You see what they look like.
Speaker 1: you'll know if you when a website is made with Twitter bootstrap It's like you can just tell that's a bootstrap website just by looking at it, right?
Speaker 1: And it basically allows people who don't have a lot of front-end web developments HTML CSS skills But in jazz skills but still have enough skills To make a pretty good looking website with good fonts and colors and buttons and all the and pop-ups and menus and navigation Without.
Speaker 1: you know that don't look like complete shit without a lot of skills, so it's a good thing and There's a lot of JavaScript in it.
Speaker 1: So there was an issue right?
Speaker 1: Let me explain the issue in detail.
Speaker 1: So in JavaScript semi-colons are optional.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: the JavaScript, you know Parsers and compilers that are in the browsers can sort of figure out where the end of a statement is.
Speaker 1: So if you have a semicolon, they know that a statement is ended.
Speaker 1: But if you don't have one they can sort of tell and it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: you can.
Speaker 0: you know It's optional kind of like in bash.
Speaker 0: You don't have to stick them in the ends of your statements But I should.
Speaker 1: well you can if you want to put multiple statements in the same line But you probably shouldn't same thing in JavaScript, right?
Speaker 1: You can use a semicolon to put in the same line, but whatever.
Speaker 1: so The bootstrap people they sort of don't like the semicolon like they're anti semicolon.
Speaker 1: They're like, hey We let's just do it one way consistently through the whole probe through the whole, you know file all our code.
Speaker 1: No semicolons.
Speaker 1: So there was a particular line in one of their you know code things that did not have a semicolon Because they didn't have a semicolon.
Speaker 1: right their code did work.
Speaker 1: But if you minified the JavaScript using JS min a very popular JavaScript minifier.
Speaker 1: Now JavaScript minification if you don't know is when you squish the JavaScript real small like so that it takes up less space So it downloads faster so your web page loads faster, but which actually can add up it can it's.
Speaker 1: it's very important.
Speaker 1: It's something you should definitely do.
Speaker 1: So for example, I write some JavaScript I have real variable names like, you know, you know size of button But then it would be get changed to like s you know in that way.
Speaker 0: It's shorter when the code Yeah, it makes it as small as it can be and still do the same thing, right?
Speaker 1: So when you JS min when it minified this code Right because there was no semicolon the code actually broke when it was minified.
Speaker 1: So a huge internet debate broke out on github because somebody submitted a thing that said Issue need semicolon and the guy was like here you want it.
Speaker 0: I'll read it.
Speaker 0: Fat the guy who would close the issue.
Speaker 1: That's the bootstrap guy.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: That's a bug in JS min.
Speaker 0: You probably should let Douglas Crockford know about it though.
Speaker 0: Thanks.
Speaker 1: Douglas Crockford is the JS min guy and fat is the bootstrap guy.
Speaker 0: Yep, so he basically said he basically said the developer equivalent of yeah, fuck you.
Speaker 1: So Douglas Crockford the JS min guy said that is insanely stupid code.
Speaker 1: I am NOT going to dumb down JS min for this case.
Speaker 1: And he also said TC 39 is considering the use of bang which is exclamation point as an infix operator.
Speaker 1: The code will break in the future.
Speaker 1: fix it now.
Speaker 1: learn to use semicolons properly.
Speaker 1: Bang is not to be intended to be a statement separator.
Speaker 1: semicolon is.
Speaker 1: so basically what happened here is The code broke when it was JS minned.
Speaker 1: the other guy said that's JS min's fault.
Speaker 1: My code is valid code.
Speaker 1: JS min shouldn't break the code when it means it.
Speaker 1: the jazz min guy said your code is valid code.
Speaker 1: But jazz men, you know, you write stupid code without semicolons, you know, Jay I'm not gonna put a thing in JS min to handle your stupid code when all you could do is type one character the semicolon and it would work.
Speaker 1: and Also in the next version right in TC 39. right your code won't even work anymore Right.
Speaker 1: It's only only now your code works.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna work in the future.
Speaker 1: It's not forwards, you know compatible.
Speaker 1: So and you know jazz min is forwards compatible.
Speaker 0: screw you now 240 something comments later.
Speaker 0: a lot of comments is this gets huge internet war.
Speaker 0: I think every kind of IT and CS guy made at least one comment from you.
Speaker 0: guys are stupid.
Speaker 0: picture of a lolcat to.
Speaker 0: You know every possible, you know, the new type people were posting in here.
Speaker 0: Scott posted something.
Speaker 0: Did you find my post?
Speaker 0: I found your post.
Speaker 1: Oh here.
Speaker 1: Let me read my post.
Speaker 1: Reason to use semicolons.
Speaker 1: code will work properly and people will be able to get work done.
Speaker 1: reason not to use semicolons.
Speaker 1: Aesthetics and ego.
Speaker 1: are you adults or children?
Speaker 0: question mark don't be a JavaScript hipster.
Speaker 0: use semicolons That's right, or I think my favorite one.
Speaker 0: Oh for fuck's sake people.
Speaker 0: if using ugly semicolons and a few actual parentheses will guarantee current and future compatibility Then what is the problem?
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: So this is an age-old argument that anyone who's dealt with software developers or open source projects or GNU Linux people There's two camps on every is not something that is new.
Speaker 1: this is an age-old thing that has many incarnations.
Speaker 0: This is just a simple example of.
Speaker 0: is it just one example that is recent and big camp number one Technically correct and or right and I say right in quotes because they have some sort of Ideological reason to be right.
Speaker 1: Yes Someone has some sort of principle that they you know stand by like.
Speaker 1: this is my coding principle and I will follow it Even though if it isn't, you know, technically necessary to follow like for example, ah Someone might say you should never use ternary operators.
Speaker 0: I will never use them in my code and my code era.
Speaker 0: I have a thing even though they work.
Speaker 1: Yep, and they're a thing.
Speaker 0: I will never support them.
Speaker 0: my thing whatever it is compiling code Maybe I wrote a custom compiler will break if you use them.
Speaker 0: So fuck you, right?
Speaker 1: But yet there is they.
Speaker 1: someone finds an example.
Speaker 1: Hey, if you use a ternary operator here, you know obviously this example would never be true, but If you think it's really actually answer yet No, there's a there's a you know, there's a performance bonus to using the ternary operator here instead of a. you know An if statement which is never gonna be true because the compiler is smart enough to tell the same difference.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe the thing that guy wrote is a shitty compiler.
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like come on dude, right?
Speaker 0: But then the other camp is do stuff that works for the most people in the simplest way possible.
Speaker 0: Yeah You know what.
Speaker 0: the people on the back on the right side the second half they're pretty much right.
Speaker 0: that wins in the end.
Speaker 1: I mean the thing is this is open source, right?
Speaker 1: So you could just fork this and put your semicolons in which people did but that's that's the stack.
Speaker 1: But that's annoying because shit fracture.
Speaker 1: because now I can't just you know Keep installing the latest version of bootstrap.
Speaker 1: now every time I install or upgrade bootstrap I have to remember to go put the semicolon back and then minify it and it just creates all this work.
Speaker 1: or I have to Follow this other version of bootstrap.
Speaker 1: but what if that guy doesn't update quickly enough and you just make a whole bunch of work for a whole bunch of people just Because you won't push one button on your keyboard to type a semicolon.
Speaker 0: Yep principles in technology real technology You know stuff that you actually want people to use and actually do use Has to work before it's good as opposed to being good before it works.
Speaker 1: That's right You know, I mean I'm not saying principles are not completely worthless, right?
Speaker 1: You know, there are many principles where it's like, you know, you should you should do this.
Speaker 1: It's a should versus a must.
Speaker 1: the only must is your shit must always work Right, if it doesn't work if there is an instance no matter what instance where there is brokenness Then you need to fix that.
Speaker 1: Here's an if that fixing goes against some principle.
Speaker 0: if you do something that is technically a hundred percent correct with say some version of HTML and it turns out that most browsers do it wrong and There is a technically incorrect way that every browser supports you should be using the technically incorrect way, that's right.
Speaker 0: I'm at you know, my job is basically to manage software now and actually I've run into this.
Speaker 1: I have built this engine in this car according to these principles.
Speaker 1: The car doesn't start of course not because of this bullshit, but I've done it the right way and I won't change it.
Speaker 1: Well, your car is never gonna go anywhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at least my car is right.
Speaker 1: All your driving cars are wrong.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna make it to contentious point that a lot of open source Equivalence of things and open source projects go nowhere because of this sort of bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yes, because if I'd like a lot of libraries for like Python have this problem, like I'll find some Python library I'm like, oh I'll use this.
Speaker 0: it looks great and it has some like stupid principled bullshit where I have to do all this Wrapper code around it to make it work because it doesn't play nice with anything else.
Speaker 0: I just give up I don't even bother.
Speaker 1: and it's not just.
Speaker 1: you know Computers you see this problem.
Speaker 1: You see this in all sorts of professions, you know various engineering things, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like no the plumber insists on using this particular thing, you know, every time things not available For a month.
Speaker 1: Yeah using some particular method of screwing or piping or who knows what because that's a much, you know Superior method to whatever it is these engineering.
Speaker 1: so he follows that method but it doesn't actually work as well.
Speaker 0: now No, we're talking about principles as an abstract sense.
Speaker 0: if you take a principled stand on a functional issue For example, if you build the building that way it'll fall down if there's an earthquake.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's not what I mean by a principle.
Speaker 0: that's a functional stand as well as a principled stand.
Speaker 1: a principle is like You know just some sort of like ideal thing that you follow.
Speaker 1: that is like, you know your way for example Let me try to think of some sort of principle.
Speaker 1: Well, you know.
Speaker 0: just a code example right?
Speaker 1: no exactly, you know, no semi-colons for something else.
Speaker 1: Well, you know.
Speaker 1: Here's an example.
Speaker 1: Someone has a particular way.
Speaker 1: They like to hold the joystick in Street Fighter, right?
Speaker 1: You got to put your hands just like this and they you know, that's the right way to do it.
Speaker 1: Some guy comes around he's holds the joystick in a different way, you know.
Speaker 1: Maybe he's got his hand backwards or who knows what the hell.
Speaker 1: maybe he's holding it from the top instead of from the side Or whatever.
Speaker 1: the other guys like you're holding the joystick the wrong way But meanwhile the dude kicks your ass perfect two out of three rounds.
Speaker 1: You don't even get to punch him once.
Speaker 1: Does guess what?
Speaker 1: winning matters more than how he holds a joystick, right?
Speaker 1: You have your you know, you you think that that's the proper technique for holding a joystick.
Speaker 1: Well, the other guy beat you so Tough shit.
Speaker 1: Yep, you know in golf.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of debates over like using the belly putter which you know is a Legal thing to use even though they might change that rule, but right now it is a legal thing Even though other people, you know, like Tiger Woods like says odds bullshit.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't be able to do that, but they can.
Speaker 1: It's like Tiger Woods is a principal.
Speaker 1: belly putters are bullshit.
Speaker 1: guy with the belly butter beat you.
Speaker 1: it's legal tough shit.
Speaker 1: Snaking
Speaker 0: you're making
Speaker 1: exactly right same thing, but
Speaker 0: especially here You it seems like ideals in the in the open source technology world specifically get in the way of progress more so than they need to And it's always the exact same kind of crap like this discussion happens Everywhere every day every big product.
Speaker 0: It's all over the place.
Speaker 0: It's endemic and It happens.
Speaker 1: You know what happens.
Speaker 1: a lot happens a lot in like open source gooey design, right?
Speaker 1: Where you know the like the gnome three people are like.
Speaker 1: these are the principles by which we will you know?
Speaker 1: Design our new gooey for gnome three, but then you know a designer like me.
Speaker 0: They follow they if you put a button here, even though that's not your button standard.
Speaker 0: It's way more intuitive.
Speaker 0: They'll be like nope can't do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like.
Speaker 1: these are the rules that we put down and we're gonna follow those rules to the T in every Single window and every dialogue and everything.
Speaker 1: There's only everyone's like gnome three sucks.
Speaker 1: We want gnome two bag.
Speaker 0: I you know I designed a. I'm really big on Semantic consistency like this.
Speaker 0: the semantics of an interface or of a software design have to be consistent Like the same language is used every.
Speaker 0: you can't call something an alert in one place and an event somewhere else If they're actually the same thing, that's right.
Speaker 0: You can't switch your verbs, you know that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And at the same time a. some of the software I manage has legacy code.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna hold up a production release because some legacy code doesn't fit the new semantics.
Speaker 0: if it's functional That's right.
Speaker 0: I'll open a ticket to fix it later.
Speaker 0: But I'm not gonna hold it up for my bullshit principles because the users never gonna see that.
Speaker 0: that's like I'm wanting people to change Class names.
Speaker 0: Yep it's the same thing and I don't know what else we can say on this really other than the People.
Speaker 0: whenever you see an argument like this Figure out who's taking the principal non-functional stand and make fun of them.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm That's really all you can do.
Speaker 1: and or beat them.
Speaker 1: And also if you you know, you catch yourself right being the guy who's making the stupid stand like, you know It's broken.
Speaker 1: and if you're the guy who says don't fix it then you're wrong because the answer is always fix it All right, we don't care, right?
Speaker 1: Just fix it make it work.
Speaker 1: working is the most important thing Even if it you know The ugly working is better than the pretty broken because pretty broken may as well not even exist because it's broken.
Speaker 1: Look I made the most beautiful screwdriver in the world.
Speaker 1: Does it screw screws?
Speaker 1: No, but doesn't it look great?
Speaker 1: Oh, what's that?
Speaker 1: You got there?
Speaker 1: It looks like a rusty stick.
Speaker 1: it is but watch it screw.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.