Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, May 1st, 2012.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 2: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we talk to Luke Crane about his game, Mouseguard.
Speaker 0: You may have heard of it.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 2: So it's warm today.
Speaker 0: It is pretty warm today.
Speaker 2: But more importantly, today is the first of May.
Speaker 0: Very important day.
Speaker 0: It's the first of May.
Speaker 0: We're already outside of my office for whatever may happen.
Speaker 2: I was referring to the musical...
Speaker 0: I'm also referring to the musical representation of what happens on the first day of the month of May.
Speaker 2: If you have not heard the first of May and what you should do today, that's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: Well, you better get on that.
Speaker 0: So we've got an interview with Luke Crane, the designer of the Mouseguard game based on the comics.
Speaker 0: Based on the comics with the comics.
Speaker 0: So we're going to get right to that.
Speaker 0: We're going to skip news and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: But first, I guess it's time for Things of the Day.
Speaker 2: No, it's the first of May.
Speaker 2: It's time for something completely different.
Speaker 0: So I'm a big fan of videos.
Speaker 0: And the way I always describe this is it's a video that is a compilation of something from either a movie that keeps happening or a thing from a whole bunch of different media.
Speaker 0: that's all the same words.
Speaker 2: So you've used Things of the Day a lot of times, like all the glass breaking in Total Recall.
Speaker 0: Or my favorite version of Pulp Fiction that's just people saying the word fuck.
Speaker 2: Or every time Hank's peeing.
Speaker 0: You know, I can't help but see Tom Hanks and think about peeing now.
Speaker 0: If I ever meet him, I'm going to be like, "So what's up with you peeing in
Speaker 0: movies?".
Speaker 0: It's like part of your contract.
Speaker 2: These are called supercuts now.
Speaker 2: That's the word people have decided on.
Speaker 0: Well, people.
Speaker 0: So basically, someone made a site.
Speaker 0: And the idea is to collect all of these things that are defined as the noun supercut.
Speaker 0: A fast-paced montage of short video clips that obsessively isolate a single element from its source.
Speaker 0: Usually a word, phrase, or cliche from film or TV.
Speaker 0: So I love that.
Speaker 0: I live in a world where I can have a like, a desire, a hobby so specific as this.
Speaker 0: And there is a site now dedicated to it.
Speaker 2: So according to Urban Dictionary, a supercut is a fast-paced montage of short video clips that obsessively isolates a single element from its source.
Speaker 2: Usually a word, phrase, or cliche from film and TV.
Speaker 0: Look at that.
Speaker 0: We got two sources.
Speaker 2: I'm willing to bet the same guy.
Speaker 2: Oh, you know who typed this in?
Speaker 2: WaxPancake.
Speaker 2: That's Andy Baio, I think, is that guy.
Speaker 0: Well, this is a waxy.org project.
Speaker 2: Oh.
Speaker 2: So he definitely is the one who typed it into whatever.
Speaker 0: Writer and tech entrepreneur in Portland, Oregon.
Speaker 0: He works on Expert Labs.
Speaker 2: He used to be the CTO of Kickstarter.
Speaker 0: Found it upcoming.
Speaker 0: Made an album and other stuff.
Speaker 0: I'm reading his webpage.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's an important guy.
Speaker 2: You should know that guy.
Speaker 0: Alright, so that's what I got.
Speaker 2: Alright.
Speaker 2: So check this out.
Speaker 2: Some guy in Paris, there's a fountain.
Speaker 2: It's like a big pool.
Speaker 2: But it's not a still reflecting pool like in DC.
Speaker 2: It's a pool with fountains, right?
Speaker 2: And apparently, there's tables and chairs all around it.
Speaker 2: It's in a park, a public park.
Speaker 2: And people, you know, some guy sat near the fountain next to the side of the pool.
Speaker 2: And when the fountain went off, he took a picture from such an angle, or his friend did, that it looked like he was peeing the fountain because the fountain was on the other side of him.
Speaker 2: And it looked like he was having an enormous pee while sitting in the chair.
Speaker 0: Ho ho, a standard and classic picture.
Speaker 2: So he posted this picture to the internet and said,
Speaker 2: "Lols."
Speaker 2: It's a good picture.
Speaker 2: Good picture.
Speaker 2: Someone replied and was like, "I took same picture, same
Speaker 2: fountain.".
Speaker 2: And people just started posting all the same picture with the same fountain with different people in it.
Speaker 0: Well, you got what I want to see is a picture from a long time ago, like on that like '70s sort of...
Speaker 2: So of course, some guy created a Tumblr.
Speaker 2: "Look, I'm original dot Tumblr dot com," which is... The title is "The Best Picture I Took in Paris.
Speaker 2: Holding up the Leaning Tower of Pisa is so
Speaker 2: 2005.".
Speaker 2: And it's just every picture of people at this fountain and similar fountains doing the same thing.
Speaker 0: This is the revolution that Tumblr did.
Speaker 0: In the old days, you'd say, "Oh, that's the name of my cover
Speaker 0: band.".
Speaker 0: Or, "That'd be a great name for a metal
Speaker 0: Or, "Rock band," I guess, before there was metal.
Speaker 0: But now, you say, "That's my new
Speaker 0: Tumblr.".
Speaker 0: Well, in a way... But the difference is that if you say that's your new Tumblr, most likely you're going to end up making that Tumblr because it doesn't take much effort.
Speaker 2: This is what I'm saying is that these Tumblr's are super cuts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of the internet.
Speaker 2: It's a super cut of photos or a super cut of... Is that right?
Speaker 0: But super cut is a subset of those sorts of super cuts dedicated solely to that in the visual medium of movies and TV.
Speaker 2: Well, I want to know why they made supercuts.org instead of just a Tumblr, supercuts.tumblr, which would have been super cut of super cuts.
Speaker 0: Better branding.
Speaker 0: I mean, I would make a Radio Free Equestria site if I wasn't just lazy.
Speaker 2: But anyway, you get the idea.
Speaker 0: So very briefly, in the meta moment, we're going to be at Kineticon.
Speaker 0: If you wanted to submit a panel to run at Kineticon or a lecture or a workshop, the deadline's passed, so do it soon because I'm currently scheduling stuff.
Speaker 0: We will be at, not this weekend, but next weekend, ZenkaiCon, where we will be presenting a couple of lectures.
Speaker 0: PEX Prime is coming up in some months.
Speaker 0: We'll be there.
Speaker 0: And a bunch of other cons.
Speaker 0: If you want to see us at Otacon, we'll tell them.
Speaker 0: We submitted events like we always do.
Speaker 0: So Luke, we had you on the show some time ago with Jared.
Speaker 2: Some billion times.
Speaker 0: Talking about just games and stuff, but we've never actually really talked deeply about Mouseguard.
Speaker 1: I think it's been a while since we've talked about a game and just haven't shot the shit.
Speaker 2: Yeah, we pretty much always just talk about things in general or conceptual things and whatnot.
Speaker 0: Or the old days, we'd go to cons and hang out.
Speaker 2: And we're doing it now again.
Speaker 0: But now I think the problem is we're actually all busy at PAX.
Speaker 0: Like, actually busy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, for reals busy.
Speaker 2: And sick.
Speaker 0: Only you got sick.
Speaker 1: Well, Jared got half-sick.
Speaker 2: Yeah, Jared was also sick.
Speaker 2: The podcasting condition, that was for sure.
Speaker 0: There was an Otacon years ago where we could not talk for like three days after the con.
Speaker 0: I was coughing up blood.
Speaker 0: It was not a sight to see.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's been a long time since I've lost my voice at a con, actually.
Speaker 1: I've learned to speak in a smooth con voice.
Speaker 0: And the trick is to not say stuff when you don't need to say stuff.
Speaker 1: True.
Speaker 1: There's a double trick for it for me, and that was hiring people to demo my games.
Speaker 2: Very good move.
Speaker 0: I feel like you can't hold it in when you're doing a demo.
Speaker 0: Like, once someone starts burning something.
Speaker 0: Sometimes metaphorically, sometimes not.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm a man for funny voices, so I can't resist shouting my bad dwarven brogue.
Speaker 0: But yeah, Mouseguard.
Speaker 0: We've played Mouseguard a little bit, and I think I played with some of you guys once.
Speaker 0: I played a weird remake of Mouseguard, some fan made that was all steampunk at a con.
Speaker 0: Thor was in the same game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was at 11.11.
Speaker 0: It was at 11.11.
Speaker 1: That was my friend Mike Miller, who made a Gaslight version.
Speaker 0: It was actually neat, but it was the last game of Mouseguard I've played, because I've been so busy I haven't even played anything lately.
Speaker 2: We tried to play it once on our own, but I ran it and I wasn't so good.
Speaker 2: It was pretty sad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it takes a bit of a mental shift to get into the Mouseguard mindset.
Speaker 1: Burning Wheel players have a hard time with it, because it tweaks a lot of the Burning Wheel rules and kind of throws a lot of them out, too.
Speaker 1: And people who play traditional roleplaying games have a hard time with it, too, because it introduces some paradigms that you don't see in traditional roleplaying games.
Speaker 0: So what's the biggest paradigm shift?
Speaker 0: D&D three and a half guy never went to four because he thinks it's not old school enough, but yet he's not old school enough to have played advanced dungeons.
Speaker 2: You mean the guy who's playing Pathfinder?
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Or three and a half Pathfinder, like that guy.
Speaker 0: What's the biggest paradigm shift?
Speaker 0: What makes Mouseguard so different?
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's kind of a two-lane paradigm shift.
Speaker 1: On one hand, on the GM side, is the turn structure.
Speaker 1: We feel like we just kind of teased out how people really play roleplaying games, but we're arrogant pricks.
Speaker 1: We just made a game, and the game has a turn structure.
Speaker 1: And we gave it a turn structure because we wanted people who don't play roleplaying games to be able to come to it and say, "Oh, look, a game.
Speaker 1: A game has turns.
Speaker 1: This game has turns.
Speaker 1: In the turns, I say funny things, and I roll some
Speaker 1: dice.".
Speaker 1: Like, okay.
Speaker 1: It's not a big leap for people who don't play roleplaying games.
Speaker 1: People who do play roleplaying games, a turn structure such as it is is problematic.
Speaker 1: But get over it, people.
Speaker 1: And then on the player side of things, it's the idea that you're not power leveling.
Speaker 1: You're not power leveling.
Speaker 1: There's power gaming in Mouseguard, but it's just not in the same extent.
Speaker 1: It's very easy to power game in Mouseguard because we don't really care.
Speaker 1: And there's a lot of player-driven action.
Speaker 1: Your character and what your character wants is basically going to be the story.
Speaker 2: So the turns in Mouseguard, right?
Speaker 2: It's the player turn and the GM turn, right?
Speaker 2: Correct.
Speaker 2: It's not like a board game where your turn is very well-defined.
Speaker 2: Like, you do these actions and your turn is over, right?
Speaker 2: It's sort of like there's a long GM turn and then a little player turn.
Speaker 2: At least that's the way I felt.
Speaker 1: The turns are about equal length, actually.
Speaker 1: It's deceptive.
Speaker 1: It seems like one is shorter than the other.
Speaker 1: Some people think the player's turn is longer than the GM's turn.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: And some people think the GM's turn is longer than the player's turn.
Speaker 0: Scott, maybe it's because you never earn any checks.
Speaker 2: I don't earn checks for shit.
Speaker 2: I suck.
Speaker 1: Well, that's a trick to playing the game.
Speaker 1: And it's one of the trickiest parts of playing the game.
Speaker 1: Because the GM has to give you a reason to earn checks, and then the player has to sit up and go, "Oh, it's time for you to earn
Speaker 1: checks.".
Speaker 1: But we're getting ahead of ourselves.
Speaker 1: People in TV land, podcast land, have no idea what the fuck we're talking about.
Speaker 0: So we're talking about the role-playing game Mouseguard, which was designed by the eminent Luke Crane here.
Speaker 1: I am not eminent.
Speaker 1: I am right here.
Speaker 0: I have to use a different incorrect adjective every time you're on the show.
Speaker 2: Based on the comic book by David Peterson, who's also not here.
Speaker 2: So he is eminent?
Speaker 1: If he's en route.
Speaker 0: And I believe when we talked about this before with you and Jared a while ago, you collaborated pretty closely on canon and things with him, at least in terms of how the game should feel and how it should work.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: The comic book author and I worked very closely together.
Speaker 1: I mean, I asked him all sorts of difficult questions like, "How do you get into the
Speaker 1: Mouseguard?".
Speaker 1: And he gave me all sorts of difficult answers at 3 a.m But anyway, so the game, as we were talking about, has a turn structure to it.
Speaker 1: And the turn structure is, right, it's not I go, you go, I go, you go, per se.
Speaker 1: There's one turn in which basically the GM goes, and the GM gets to push two or more problems in your path.
Speaker 1: And basically it's two or more die rolls or series of die rolls.
Speaker 1: And it's supposed to be two in the game, but if things go wrong, it can spin out to more die rolls.
Speaker 1: And then in the player's turn, every player is guaranteed to get one die roll, basically one scene or action or something.
Speaker 1: And then there's ways for you to earn more screen time depending on how you play.
Speaker 0: So like on my turn, if I'm a player, then if I want to do something, I have to get one of these.
Speaker 1: Right, so you're, right, you don't, well, by default, you don't have to do anything.
Speaker 1: You're guaranteed to get to do one thing on your own of your choice, as you like it, per game.
Speaker 1: Which is new, like lots of games don't have that.
Speaker 1: Lots of games, you might sit there for the whole session, lots of role-playing games, and you just, you maybe roll the die once or whatever, and you may not fail and do anything.
Speaker 1: But in Mouse Card, you're guaranteed to be able to do something.
Speaker 1: But you can increase your resources in the player's turn by characterizing yourself in the GM's turn, but you have to characterize yourself by putting yourself in danger.
Speaker 1: You have to show your character as vulnerable, flawed, or otherwise in trouble.
Speaker 1: And that gets you resources to use in the player's turn.
Speaker 0: You look like you're about to say something.
Speaker 2: No, not yet.
Speaker 0: So what kind of things do I want to do in my turn?
Speaker 0: We haven't talked a lot about mechanics or anything, but what are some things I would do?
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a role-playing game, so I could say I go meet with the Mistress Eleanor and talk about fancy pastries.
Speaker 1: You could, and if you have Mistress Eleanor as a relationship, or you've met Mistress Eleanor in the game, you could do that, probably even without even having to spend one of your resources.
Speaker 0: So what do I get if I spend it?
Speaker 0: What's the point of spending it?
Speaker 1: Well, if there is no Mistress Eleanor, let's say your character's a cook, and you want to learn about making pastries, and you can do this in Mouseguard.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't be the strangest thing that's been done.
Speaker 1: You could actually bring Mistress Eleanor into the game, and that would cause you to spend one of these resources called a check, and that would allow you to test an ability in the game called circles, and circles is who your character knows.
Speaker 1: If you're successful in the test, then absolutely, you know a pastry chef named Mistress Eleanor.
Speaker 1: Bring her in, and then she can instruct you in pastry cooking.
Speaker 1: More often, players will use these checks to recover from their hurts, or to build gear for future missions.
Speaker 1: Occasionally, a savvy GM will beat the players up really nice and hard in the GM's turn, but won't quite take them to the conclusion of their mission.
Speaker 1: So that's the GM's turn, and then in the player's turn, the players have to make a decision about what's more important to them.
Speaker 1: Recovering their own hurts, accomplishing their own agendas, or accomplishing the mission.
Speaker 1: And that is where the magic really happens in Mouseguard.
Speaker 1: That's where you get players making these great decisions, and they sacrifice themselves for the greater good of all Mousekind.
Speaker 2: So they would, on their own turn, try to complete the mission, but they didn't heal themselves, so they're totally screwed.
Speaker 0: Or they go help their brother, but now they didn't heal themselves, and now the mission's in jeopardy.
Speaker 1: Right, exactly, and all of those things have happened in games that I've played, and where that really shines, in a one-session game of Mouseguard, it's cool, you're like, "Oh, wow, I did this thing," right?
Speaker 1: But when you play the second session and you're still sick, your character's still sick because he was out in the cold and wet and rain, but you accomplish the mission anyway, that's when it really bites.
Speaker 1: That's when you're like, "Oh, now I need to work harder.
Speaker 1: I need to put myself in more jeopardy now, both because I'm sick and because now I need more resources to recover on my
Speaker 1: turn.".
Speaker 2: Oh, see, if you earn more checks, then you could have gotten rid of your sickness and worked on the mission.
Speaker 0: Right, but then you would have hurt yourself in the previous, then things might have gone differently.
Speaker 0: Correct.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're basically giving the GM more ammunition.
Speaker 1: The more you put yourself in jeopardy, the more potential ammunition you're giving the GM to introduce twists and to further screw you over.
Speaker 2: So I've got the flu, so now I need two checks, because I want to complete the mission and get rid of the flu.
Speaker 2: So in order to get a check, I put myself in danger and I break my leg.
Speaker 2: So now, even though I've got my extra check, I've got another problem.
Speaker 1: You're sick and you're injured, but there is a major but there.
Speaker 1: So if the GM decides that when you fail a test, he thinks it's right that your character would break his leg here, in that case, you succeed.
Speaker 1: If that's the mission-accomplishing test, you accomplish your mission.
Speaker 1: So the GM can't just punish you, punish you, punish you, punish you.
Speaker 1: Either you're going to get a twist introduced by the GM and your character is going to stay whole, confronting that twist, or you're going to get a condition in the form of hunger or fatigue or injury and you're going to succeed at what you were after.
Speaker 2: So when you get hurt, you still got what you wanted in exchange for getting hurt.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's kind of the part of the mouse guard ethos.
Speaker 1: You sacrifice yourself a little bit to accomplish the mission.
Speaker 0: To me, that's actually the biggest paradigm shift from, say, traditional D&D, because there, you've got hit points.
Speaker 0: Sacrificing 99% of your hit points doesn't have any game effect and you get all your hit points back pretty easily.
Speaker 2: Or even in Burning Wheel, I lost my foot.
Speaker 2: What did I get?
Speaker 2: Nothing.
Speaker 0: Well, that was your fault.
Speaker 2: I just lost my foot.
Speaker 0: You could have gotten something.
Speaker 1: Your game master clearly didn't read the adventure burner.
Speaker 2: Well, we got back to the village alive.
Speaker 2: I guess that counts as something.
Speaker 0: Scott, we march off into the Siberian wilderness to die with, like, one person with a B2 orientation.
Speaker 2: We didn't get lost and dead.
Speaker 0: Remember when Alex said, "Are you sure you want to trample off into the snowy
Speaker 0: woods?".
Speaker 2: Well, instead, "Okay, so stay still and
Speaker 2: die.".
Speaker 0: Sure just fought that zombie.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we digress.
Speaker 0: But there weren't really mechanical consequences in D&D other than taking away gear or injuring someone, but injury was so temporary it never meant anything.
Speaker 0: Now it seems like you have to give up something, but there's a mechanical reward.
Speaker 0: I got hurt and I got what I wanted, as opposed to the soft game master makes something up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean, you know, it kind of always comes out that the game master makes something up, but in this case, we give the game master very strict rules to follow.
Speaker 1: Right, and I guess you're right.
Speaker 1: When you talk about failure in this game, it's very different than most role-playing games.
Speaker 1: And, right, in D&D, failure can often be a full stop.
Speaker 1: It's not always a full stop.
Speaker 1: It is often a full stop, but in Mouseguard, it's either a new plot point is introduced, a twist, we call it, or you continue with the mission.
Speaker 1: You succeed, but you're at a cost.
Speaker 0: So I guess my point is, you put this in the rules of Mouseguard, where D&D doesn't really say what to do if you fail a diplomacy check other than you don't get what you wanted, and now what?
Speaker 0: The game master has to do something.
Speaker 1: I think in the Dungeon Master's Guide, too, there's advice on what to do when characters fail and how to keep things moving.
Speaker 2: If you buy all the extra books, then we'll tell you the real secrets.
Speaker 1: Right, but what this does in Mouseguard, though, is it keeps the pace of the game moving very quickly, and I feel like in a lot of role-playing games, if you have a story, it's an accident.
Speaker 1: In Mouseguard, it's an eventuality.
Speaker 1: The way the mechanics interact with the way people play, it's going to create a narrative of some sort.
Speaker 1: I hope it's not the story that you expected.
Speaker 1: It's not what you planned out, but something is going to happen.
Speaker 1: There's going to be some kind of conflict and resolution.
Speaker 2: Did the idea for this system come from the Mouseguard comics?
Speaker 2: If you read those, that's pretty much how they go, is the mice want to do something, and they usually succeed to some extent with great, horrible sacrifice happening to them along the way.
Speaker 2: They don't ever succeed and not have any problems in pretty much any part of it.
Speaker 2: You don't just fight the crab and win.
Speaker 1: Right, you fight the crab and one of you dies, and the other one runs away.
Speaker 1: Well, if you look at my other big game, Burning Wheel, you can see that I didn't simply just take Burning Wheel and bolt Mouseguard on top of it.
Speaker 1: I took Burning Wheel, stripped away everything but some core mechanics to it, and then said, "Okay, what do we need here to really make this game represent
Speaker 1: Mouseguard?".
Speaker 1: I didn't want to make it a comic book game.
Speaker 1: I didn't want there to be paneling and gutters and inking and coloring or any kind of comic book-y terms, but at the same time, I wanted there to be a rhythm to the game that reflected the stories of the Mouseguard comics.
Speaker 0: Now we're getting into mechanism design.
Speaker 0: The rules of the game push people to create the exact kind of story you wanted them to create, even if they don't know where that actual story will go within that rubric.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is a mechanism, and it is willfully designed.
Speaker 2: Does it bother you?
Speaker 2: Some people are always like, "Oh, Mouseguard is like Baby Burning Wheel or Easy Burning
Speaker 2: Wheel.".
Speaker 2: Does it bother you when people say that?
Speaker 1: It used to really get under my skin.
Speaker 1: I don't really care anymore, but it's really not.
Speaker 1: It's its own game.
Speaker 1: Again, one of our design philosophies for Mouseguard was to strip Burning Wheel down to its core essentials and see what kind of game that was.
Speaker 1: It's fun, but it's cool when you do that to a game, and you do this to any game.
Speaker 1: When you strip a game down to what you think are its core essentials, you're making a value judgment.
Speaker 1: You're deciding what the core essentials of the game are.
Speaker 1: Then when you start bolting other things on top of it, you're also making a value judgment as a designer.
Speaker 1: What's important to you about gameplay here?
Speaker 1: Ultimately, you're coming out with a different game, no matter what you say.
Speaker 1: Mouseguard, it's a cousin to Burning Wheel, but it's certainly not Burning Wheel's little brother.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely.
Speaker 0: My experience, I played Burning Wheel, and I sat down with Mouseguard, flipped through the book, like, "Oh, it's like Burning Wheel.
Speaker 0: I get
Speaker 0: this.".
Speaker 0: Then we actually sat down to play, and I realized I really should have read that whole book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a couple things that catch players.
Speaker 1: Also, as you know from my games, you basically should read the rules and try to play it by the rules at least once.
Speaker 2: It's hard.
Speaker 2: There's a lot of rules.
Speaker 0: I always run into the side problem of a lot of role-playing.
Speaker 0: people will read the rules of a game, have never played it, and immediately modify it extensively before they play it.
Speaker 0: I don't know what to do about that.
Speaker 1: I spend a lot of time playtesting, designing and playtesting these games.
Speaker 1: I put a lot of effort, way more effort than I should into these games.
Speaker 0: I can imagine I played in a playtest of another game you were working on, and it was obviously rough around the edges, but obviously the crazy cool ideas were added and removed all the time, and you were taking notes on what players did.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it really bugs me when somebody thinks that they can simply read one of my games, understand it completely, and then begin to modify it.
Speaker 0: Well, the metaphor I've used more and more when I argue with people like this is that if you go to a five-star French restaurant, there's one thing on the menu.
Speaker 0: If you ask the chef to make an alteration to that, he'll probably kick you out.
Speaker 0: Even if he changes it, you paid for a five-star meal from the guy who knows what he's doing.
Speaker 2: You don't put ketchup on it.
Speaker 2: There isn't even ketchup on the table.
Speaker 2: If you ask for ketchup, they'll just look at you funny.
Speaker 2: There is a chance it could be a fancy restaurant where the chef is no good.
Speaker 2: It exists, but it's not going to have a five-star on the door.
Speaker 2: Mouseguard won all kinds of awards.
Speaker 2: It basically is a five-star RPG.
Speaker 1: I guess it's a five-star RPG.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm not qualified to say that.
Speaker 1: I don't even fancy French restaurants.
Speaker 0: We're semi-objective reviewers.
Speaker 0: I'll put it up there.
Speaker 0: Five stars.
Speaker 0: We didn't say out of how many.
Speaker 2: It definitely gets five stars for nothing else.
Speaker 2: If you don't want to give it five stars for the game, the physicalness of it is... I can't even think of another game that says...
Speaker 0: Tell us a little bit about that, because the game was first published.
Speaker 0: It was a book, and then there were some rumors, and then a box came out with little mouse figures just like were in the comic.
Speaker 0: The thing that, when I read the book, the first thing I said was, "I want to play Mouseguard with those things in the comic,".
Speaker 0: and then the box appeared.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: That was my idea.
Speaker 1: It was actually my idea from the get-go, was to make Mouseguard, in addition to a game, a product so that one might make money from it, though that is a myth.
Speaker 1: That one makes money from good products.
Speaker 1: One does not make money from there.
Speaker 1: One makes money by fleecing one's customers.
Speaker 2: That is true.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the box set was something that David Pearson and I worked on, along with the publisher, Arcaya.
Speaker 1: I wasn't sold.
Speaker 1: It's funny.
Speaker 1: It was my idea.
Speaker 1: The publisher got on board.
Speaker 1: They started pushing me, and I was like, "Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: This sucks.
Speaker 1: I don't want to do this.
Speaker 1: This is
Speaker 1: crappy.".
Speaker 1: I went through with it, and it came out pretty good.
Speaker 0: When I bring out the book, people are like, "Ooh and ah," but when I show them the box, they're like, "What's that?
Speaker 0: I want to play
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's been definitely gaining momentum.
Speaker 1: People at PAX seem to really like it.
Speaker 1: It has a little toy factor to it, like you said, with the mouse pieces and the map and whatnot, which are meant to mimic the comics.
Speaker 1: Peterson did the sculpts for the dice and the mouse figures.
Speaker 2: Oh, I didn't know that.
Speaker 2: His sculpture is crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's a little craftsman.
Speaker 1: We had to send a little model of the mouse figure to the factory.
Speaker 1: We did want the colors on the pieces to be a little more muted, a little more natural, but it's hard.
Speaker 1: The manufacturing process was very difficult, and without doing extensive sampling on the plastics, we took what we could get.
Speaker 0: Yeah, having seen some recent experience from similar projects to doing similar kinds of manufacturing.
Speaker 0: At the scale we all do manufacturing, it is not easy to get what you want without paying a lot of money.
Speaker 2: Or going to China.
Speaker 0: No, even if you go to China, you'll get 10 proofs back that are interesting.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, unless you physically go to the factory in China.
Speaker 2: That's what I'm saying, yeah.
Speaker 1: So yeah, Mousecart, it comes with cards and custom dice, character sheets and a GM sheet, my friend, that includes on the back, includes a cheat sheet for all the rules.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 0: Very important.
Speaker 1: Very important.
Speaker 1: And a GM screen, which I use pretty extensively myself.
Speaker 0: I need one of those for Burning Wheel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 1: It's hard, though.
Speaker 0: What are you going to put on it?
Speaker 0: I had this DVD one that was three fold-out panels that were separate, and each one had nine sides.
Speaker 0: It was duh.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: I've made a Burning Wheel screen before.
Speaker 1: I digress on this one, but my only problem with a Burning Wheel screen, and maybe the listeners out there in TV land can give me some advice, I just don't want to scream between me and my players when I play Burning Wheel.
Speaker 1: It's inappropriate.
Speaker 0: True, because you don't have the hidden dice like you do in every other game.
Speaker 0: The game master's not rolling secretly and being like, "He hits
Speaker 0: you.".
Speaker 2: But you can just do a mat, right?
Speaker 2: It goes out, right?
Speaker 2: Because you don't have miniatures walking around a board, so you can just put it in the middle of the table flat, and it has all the charts on it, and you can-- Hey,
Speaker 0: if it's on the table, then we're going to say the thing, "You
Speaker 1: know what you should
Speaker 1: do?".
Speaker 1: All right, Jerry.
Speaker 2: What should I do?
Speaker 2: It's your favorite.
Speaker 0: No, but there's cool stuff if you do something like that.
Speaker 1: I asked.
Speaker 1: The problem with a mat, and we did a rules reference sheet for Burning Wheel Revised, and the problem with that and the mat is that they get buried.
Speaker 0: On their Cheetos and Mountain Dew and everyone's books.
Speaker 1: Dice and books, yeah.
Speaker 0: Though with the mouse guard, the thing that really helped was that I realized, once I opened the box, that whenever we played, everyone had their books open to those maps on the insides of the covers, because they needed to refer to them all the time.
Speaker 0: So everyone bent the covers of their books just to have them open like that.
Speaker 0: So the box set with the mat in it, that saved my books.
Speaker 1: You know that the dust cover came with a map on the back, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, dust cover was lost right away.
Speaker 2: I got to say, I don't know much about publishing, but I know dust covers is some of the most expensive things in publishing.
Speaker 2: They cost a lot of monies, and I really don't like dust covers.
Speaker 2: I wish they never existed.
Speaker 2: I just want to get rid of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was against the dust cover for mouse guard.
Speaker 1: I advocated against it.
Speaker 2: And even the cover has the same art on it too, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if we were going to do a dust cover, then I wanted to do a separate, more of a graphic cover of the actual book.
Speaker 1: But I went with David and Mark on their judgment on that one, and it's fine.
Speaker 1: The dust cover actually has some utility to it.
Speaker 1: It has a funny picture of me on it.
Speaker 1: It's cool.
Speaker 2: I forgot about that.
Speaker 1: It has a picture of me eating pizza on it.
Speaker 0: So what's going to kill a mouse?
Speaker 0: How much death is there in mouse guard?
Speaker 1: Do you want to hear a horrible mouse guard death story?
Speaker 2: Tell us your role-playing game stories.
Speaker 1: So my character was walking in the woods.
Speaker 1: I was in Canada a couple years ago in Montreal for a small gaming event.
Speaker 1: I was there with Vincent and Joshua and Rob Bull.
Speaker 1: I was playing mouse guard with a group of people, and one of the people with whom I was playing was a young girl.
Speaker 1: I think she was about nine.
Speaker 1: If I'm not mistaken, her father was an avid gamer.
Speaker 1: Sorry, her father came up, handed her off to me.
Speaker 1: So this is her first gaming session.
Speaker 1: Maybe she had read the comics or something, but her dad was a gamer.
Speaker 2: Does her dad know who you were, or she just looked at the schedule?
Speaker 0: Found some stranger to come?
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: He knew who I was.
Speaker 1: She wanted to play mouse guard, if I'm not mistaken.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so we get into it.
Speaker 1: She's a little shy at first, as some people are, but eventually she's in there, and it comes down to it.
Speaker 1: In the final scenario, there were mice in jeopardy.
Speaker 1: There was probably a mouse caravan that was stopped.
Speaker 1: Mice in jeopardy.
Speaker 1: I think even the mouse guard themselves were kind of pinned down by a killer shrike.
Speaker 1: As you saw, by a shrike.
Speaker 1: She went toe-to-toe with it.
Speaker 1: While the other mouse guard were getting everyone to safety, she went toe-to-toe with the shrike, duking it out, battling, carried off into the air, swinging away, lost her sword, and lost the conflict.
Speaker 1: I didn't think I had a chance in hell.
Speaker 1: I think she even had help from her friends, because I think that was part of the conflict.
Speaker 2: Throwing some rocks.
Speaker 1: They were trying to escape, and I was trying to kill her.
Speaker 1: They were shooting bows and throwing rocks and screaming and whatnot.
Speaker 1: So yeah, the shrike.
Speaker 1: We all knew exactly what had happened when the dice hit the table, and this silence, a silent explosion.
Speaker 1: Everyone stopped and looked.
Speaker 1: I looked at her.
Speaker 1: She turned bright pink.
Speaker 1: Because I'm a bad man, I described the shrike impaling her on a thorn, as shrikes do.
Speaker 1: That's how they kill their prey.
Speaker 1: They impale them and then save them for later.
Speaker 1: She turned pink and then got sad.
Speaker 1: The other players were really cool.
Speaker 1: They had a little funeral for her character.
Speaker 0: That's a great story.
Speaker 0: That's not horrible.
Speaker 1: She really liked the funeral.
Speaker 1: They even all made something for her funeral.
Speaker 1: They crafted something.
Speaker 1: All your characters have crafty skills in Mouseguard.
Speaker 1: You could tell that by the end of it, when I took her back to her dad, I was like, "We ended a little
Speaker 1: early."
Speaker 1: Because she died.
Speaker 1: And by "died," I mean I killed her in a horrible way.
Speaker 1: She was a little crestfallen, but she definitely seemed proud of herself, that she had sacrificed herself for the guard.
Speaker 0: But Mouseguard is a game that can be dark and super serious for people who want it to be.
Speaker 1: I personally, and no one agrees with me on this, I think Mouseguard is the darkest fantasy game out there.
Speaker 1: If you really get down there on the ground with the mice, you're in the most horrific fantasy world ever.
Speaker 1: There's no magic.
Speaker 1: There's no salvation.
Speaker 1: Everything wants to either eat you or eat the things you eat.
Speaker 1: There's nothing beneath you on the food chain.
Speaker 2: Even your non-magical powers are pretty weak, right?
Speaker 2: No one's really super strong or super fast or super anything.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: As a player in the Mouseguard, you can build up some pretty killer resources and you can muster a lot of dice.
Speaker 1: And you can put a herd on a wolf.
Speaker 1: You can't kill a wolf outright, but you can definitely drive it off.
Speaker 1: But it takes a lot of gamesmanship to get there.
Speaker 1: But just the world in and of itself, right?
Speaker 1: Your mice, everything else is bigger than you.
Speaker 1: Everything wants to eat you.
Speaker 1: You can't kill them.
Speaker 1: Not without some serious mouse science or mouse military action going on.
Speaker 1: I just think it's really bleak and dark, but nobody agrees with me.
Speaker 2: I never really thought about it that way.
Speaker 2: You think about games that have a dark theme, like Apocalypse World or something.
Speaker 0: But then I'm a badass with eight guns.
Speaker 2: Exactly.
Speaker 2: It's a scary, dark, horrible place.
Speaker 2: Or maybe vampire games.
Speaker 2: Everything's black.
Speaker 2: The cover of the book is black.
Speaker 2: All the text is black.
Speaker 2: And it's supposed to be dark.
Speaker 2: But actually, you're a superhero.
Speaker 2: You're somehow a badass in some sort of way to escape some sort of danger.
Speaker 1: I temper the darkness in Mouseguard with recognizing that the comics are a heroic journey.
Speaker 1: And that the world is against the heroes in this, but that's how they prove themselves heroes.
Speaker 1: And you prove yourself a hero in the game both by how you live and by how you die.
Speaker 0: Well, it feels very medieval, which kind of fits the sort of bleak "we are at the bottom and everything's out to kill
Speaker 0: us.".
Speaker 0: I guess that's how a peasant would feel in the Middle Ages.
Speaker 1: Yeah, depending on... Maybe 100 Years War France.
Speaker 0: I'm talking early Middle Ages, before things started to solidify.
Speaker 1: It wasn't always Monty Python.
Speaker 0: I'm talking the year 850.
Speaker 1: People had nice lives in the year 850.
Speaker 0: Some mice have nice lives.
Speaker 2: The ones that stay in town and never leave.
Speaker 0: The ones who don't join the Guard.
Speaker 2: Yeah, the big town.
Speaker 1: The other thing that's out to get you is the weather, too.
Speaker 1: There are rules where everything is out to get you.
Speaker 1: The weather, the environment, the animals, everything.
Speaker 1: Even your other mice.
Speaker 0: That was when it really sunk in, when I was looking at the Game Master section on my turn.
Speaker 0: It was like, "What can I do to
Speaker 0: them?".
Speaker 0: And it's like, "Have it
Speaker 0: rain.".
Speaker 0: And I kind of thought about, "Wait a minute, yeah.
Speaker 0: Rain is kind of a big deal for a
Speaker 0: mouse.".
Speaker 2: Yeah, they go inside and they don't come out, and they got to make sure that the inside isn't a flooding inside.
Speaker 1: Right, right.
Speaker 1: And I love that about the comics.
Speaker 1: That's, I think, maybe my favorite thing about the comics.
Speaker 1: Like when it snows?
Speaker 1: Well, no, it's the matter of perspective.
Speaker 1: And if you really get down there, it's a really imaginative universe.
Speaker 1: When you're looking at it from the forest floor, you're looking at what a leaf, what a twig, what a tiny rivulet of rain is to us, what it means to them.
Speaker 1: I like that.
Speaker 1: I like that perspective, and I feel like it gives a lot of role-playing opportunities in that it creates the necessary disassociation so that you can really imagine.
Speaker 1: You can really get in there and you can, as people, we can identify with these problems.
Speaker 1: Because that's the weird thing about Avatar Association.
Speaker 1: If it's too close, it's hard for us to identify.
Speaker 1: But we create just the right amount of space, and you can get in there and kind of fill up that space with your imagination.
Speaker 2: It's like in Arrietty, right?
Speaker 2: And in Arrietty, they really concentrate on all the small things as tiny people.
Speaker 2: But it's in contrast to the real, full-size people living in the house, so there's always this sort of connection going on, right?
Speaker 2: Where as opposed to if it's just mice, you're just getting the small world and you're not thinking about the big world at all.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: - Right, yeah.
Speaker 1: David was very explicit when we designed the game.
Speaker 1: No humans, no cats, no rats.
Speaker 1: So basically all the kind of products of humanity.
Speaker 1: I imagine no dogs either, now that I think about it.
Speaker 0: - Makes sense.
Speaker 0: So we've got the big, great elder Cthulhu Moose who will come by occasionally.
Speaker 1: - Yes, oh yes.
Speaker 1: Moose God.
Speaker 1: He'll journey through the territories once in a while.
Speaker 1: That was a really fun mission.
Speaker 1: I ran once.
Speaker 1: I had a springtime mission, a herd of moose coming.
Speaker 1: - A herd?
Speaker 1: - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: A big family of them or whatever were coming.
Speaker 1: And Gwendolyn's like, divert them.
Speaker 1: - Yeah.
Speaker 2: - How about I just hide and wait for them to pass?
Speaker 0: - Well what if they're headed straight for your town?
Speaker 1: - Well no, no, no.
Speaker 1: Because with the spring moose comes calves and with calves come wolves.
Speaker 1: And wolves eat mice.
Speaker 1: Especially hungry wolves.
Speaker 1: So yeah, that was.
Speaker 1: the mission was to get out there and divert them.
Speaker 2: - How is a mouse gonna divert a moose?
Speaker 1: - They did it.
Speaker 1: I think they actually used the wolves that were chasing the mooses to divert them.
Speaker 1: To chase them off.
Speaker 0: - That's a pretty dangerous ally.
Speaker 1: - It was a really intense mission.
Speaker 1: - That's big time.
Speaker 1: - That was deep into our mouse guard run.
Speaker 1: It was deep into the campaign.
Speaker 2: - How often, if I was gonna do a full mouse guard campaign, how many sessions do you usually go?
Speaker 1: - I would recommend playing no less than four.
Speaker 1: If you're gonna sit down, if you're gonna buy the book and you're gonna get your friends together, play four sessions of mouse guard.
Speaker 1: And if you like it, if you're into it and your characters are starting to develop, I would go eight to 12.
Speaker 1: Most of my games are built for eight to 12 sessions to really sing.
Speaker 2: - That's usually the length, that's as long as we can get a campaign to go.
Speaker 2: -
Speaker 0: Well that's the biggest problem I've had with so-called indie RPGs or non-indie in general is that most people only have the convention experience of the one-off or the one-off, they play the game for their friends to get them into it, but they never get, like Free Market, a lot of people never get the next session when you kind of realize how you're advancing and how you're changing.
Speaker 2: - Yeah, it's something I've noticed is that when I run the Free Market and they sort of realize it's just one session, they burn everything.
Speaker 0: - Burning Wheel, all that earth is gone at the end of that one-off.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, I know, I know.
Speaker 1: It's a problem, my games are built for long-term play.
Speaker 2: - Right, and it's like I like that, but it's so hard, it's hard for most people to get one-off play, let alone long-term play.
Speaker 1: - I know, I know, but I'm a fanatic about the medium, so.
Speaker 1: - Yeah.
Speaker 2: - I mean, it's like I want it too, but it's just, it's hard to get people to show up.
Speaker 1: - I know, I agree.
Speaker 0: - I think everyone will show up tomorrow.
Speaker 1: - But it's easy to get everyone to sit around and talk into their Xbox Live headsets.
Speaker 1: Weird.
Speaker 2: - Yeah, right?
Speaker 2: - You need to make an RPG for the Xbox Live.
Speaker 0: - We could argue all that, the physicality of at least this kind of role-playing game, I think, is a big part of it, and it'd be hard to replicate that.
Speaker 1: - Oh, I agree.
Speaker 0: - Short of like some sort of future sense where you have a table where it kind of like projects images of everyone around it.
Speaker 0: And there's a shared space that you have.
Speaker 1: - I mean, even rolling dice, right?
Speaker 2: It's like you can roll dice on the computer, but rolling, you know, having the dice in your hand, you know, the person gives you the helping dice, the whole thing, you can't, you know, everyone looking in the dice pit as they turn over.
Speaker 0: You make a big deal in multiple games about if you're helping, you physically hand them the die, like it has to be, 'cause then you can even see, like if you roll, if that die helped or not.
Speaker 1: - Right, also, I think one of the core components of my designs is that I recognize that there are people sitting around a table playing these games, and I want the people to be interacting.
Speaker 1: When I demoed the game for Mike of Penny Arcade at PAX, and I demonstrated the helping rules to them, and at first, they were like, you know, at first, they'd never seen anything like that, so at first, of course, oh, that's weird.
Speaker 1: One or two rolls with the helping, they were like, oh, I get it, that's cool.
Speaker 1: And then we didn't even have the multicolored dice, I just had one set of dice, and they were just passing.
Speaker 1: Just because, I mean, we're physical creatures, and so when you get that experience of, you know, I am telling you what I'm doing, I'm saying I'm helping, but then I'm handing you something, you get the experience that you're, it's the illusion of the experience that you're actually helping.
Speaker 1: It really works.
Speaker 0: - I think everyone in their head when they hand it is thinking, with my ax.
Speaker 1: - Well, maybe, I hope not.
Speaker 1: Gimli, not my favorite part of those movies.
Speaker 2: - I just watched them like yesterday.
Speaker 1: (laughing) - Whatever, anyway.
Speaker 2: - So if there's someone out there, right, you know, regardless of RPG level experience, and they wanna play some mouse guard, right, what should they do besides obviously buy it?
Speaker 2: Like, what should, like, their first thing that they should do?
Speaker 0: - Other than read it, I guess.
Speaker 2: - Yeah, reading, buying, okay.
Speaker 1: - Well, you can read the rules, I mean, I recommend the box set, I think the box set is actually easier to learn than the book.
Speaker 2: - Is the box set still able to be gotten?
Speaker 1: - It is, it is still in print.
Speaker 1: - That's good, cool.
Speaker 1: - It is still out there.
Speaker 1: So I recommend the box set because the cards make everything visual, the dice really make everything very clear, and the character sheet for the square character sheet and then the square GM sheet have all the rules of the game on them between the two of them.
Speaker 2: - Yeah, I like how they're the same size as the mouse guard comics.
Speaker 2: - Yeah.
Speaker 2: - It's really cool.
Speaker 1: - If you're gonna do it, you gotta do it.
Speaker 1: - Right.
Speaker 1: - Anyway, honestly, I recommend sitting down with a friend and doing a one on one mission.
Speaker 1: I am much, I'm more and more a fan of this.
Speaker 1: The more I play and the more I do them myself, I love one on one missions.
Speaker 1: I'm in the middle of doing a burning wheel one on one with one of my friends right now and I love it.
Speaker 1: And mouse guard, you're not gonna get the full synergy of all the helping rules and conflicts and stuff are gonna be hard, so start easy, don't go crazy, and just do a very simple mouse guard mission as kind of a trainer and then you two go and advocate the game to the rest of your group.
Speaker 1: Much easier to advocate, we have learned, when you have a wingman.
Speaker 1: And when it's just the crazy GM being like, "I got a new
Speaker 1: game."
Speaker 1: Nobody ever is like, "Yeah, whatever, just come on, "where's the
Speaker 1: D&D?".
Speaker 1: But when it's people on both sides of the screen going, "Come on, we should try
Speaker 1: this."
Speaker 1: Things go much easier.
Speaker 2: - Oh, that's a--.
Speaker 0: - I never thought of the solo, 'cause the mere thought of a solo D&D game just like gives me goosebumps of dread.
Speaker 2: - I mean, it's like you.
Speaker 2: think about any one on one RPG and it always seems like an awkward thing to do.
Speaker 2: Like it's technically you can do it, but it always seems like a weird thing, right?
Speaker 1: - What's weird about it?
Speaker 2: - I don't know, it just seems like, imagine like me and Rim were sitting here, it's like, okay, Rim, you're the GM and it's me.
Speaker 0: It's like, uh-- - All right, the dragon's about to eat your mom, what you doing?
Speaker 2: - Ah, shit, oh.
Speaker 2: I guess, how powerful am I?
Speaker 2: Am I gonna fight this dragon or am I gonna run the hell away?
Speaker 0: - I guess for me, what would make it awkward is that when there's at least one other player there, there's always that ability to retreat from the baleful gaze of the game master.
Speaker 0: Like the story is looking at you, you can always like kinda look away and then the other player might say something.
Speaker 0: But when it's just you and me, then you say you present a situation and there is nobody to speak but me.
Speaker 1: - Well, yes, and that's I think a feature of solo play is that there's no downtime, so it's very intense.
Speaker 1: You play a lot faster, but at the same time, the GM hopefully will learn rather quickly not to be a fucking dick.
Speaker 0: - Ah.
Speaker 1: - Because I'm a very, very generous GM as a solo GM.
Speaker 1: I like to talk, I like to bandy ideas back and forth.
Speaker 2: - When it's not solo, watch out.
Speaker 1: (laughing) - I don't play another character or anything like that.
Speaker 1: I'm not like, I'm not GMing myself.
Speaker 1: - Right.
Speaker 1: - But no, no, no, but right.
Speaker 1: But no, I see what you're saying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yes, but when I have five people at the table, you're like, what are you, meh, meh, meh, meh, meh, meh.
Speaker 1: And I'm just like, shut the fuck up, shut the fuck up.
Speaker 1: What did you wanna do?
Speaker 1: What did you say?
Speaker 1: Okay, now it's your turn.
Speaker 1: Right, just 'cause you get people, human beings only have so much ego shielding.
Speaker 1: We can only kind of be patient for so long before we start telling people to shut the fuck up.
Speaker 2: - Maybe we should try that, Ryan.
Speaker 0: - You wanna try it?
Speaker 2: - I don't know, just pick some game and do, what?
Speaker 1: - Well, the thing that I believe where my games are very strong in this is that they can be very personal and you can do a really cool personal story and it's not just about basically getting lucky, rolling some numbers, defeating a monster or whatever, but you're playing out, accomplishing a goal or a belief or something like that.
Speaker 1: So it feels natural that you're always on 'cause suddenly you're the protagonist in the story.
Speaker 1: It's about you, it's about this thing now.
Speaker 1: So yeah, try it, you guys.
Speaker 2: - I think we should, yeah.
Speaker 1: - So yeah, so all right, so thanks for having me on the show, guys.
Speaker 0: - It's always a pleasure, we gotta hang out more.
Speaker 0: - Like right down the street.
Speaker 1: - Man, I forgot to bring your DVD that I borrowed a year ago.
Speaker 2: - Oh, they were 11?
Speaker 2: Did you watch that?
Speaker 2: - I did.
Speaker 2: - Did you like it?
Speaker 1: - I did, I liked it a lot.
Speaker 1: I still haven't figured out how to make a game out of it.
Speaker 1: - I
Speaker 0: know, we've
Speaker 2: tried forever.
Speaker 2: - Well, I know at least we need a big red button in the middle of the table.
Speaker 2: Any other part of the game, I don't know.
Speaker 1: - I know, I'm trying to go with that constraint and I don't know.
Speaker 2: - But do you see how you want it to be a game?
Speaker 2: Like you wanna be in that situation.
Speaker 1: - Well, part of me is like, well, let's just make it like a deep form LARP or something and we'll--.
Speaker 2: - That's not a bad idea.
Speaker 1: - And just, 'cause you could make it so you could only play once, but then you could also make it Battlestar Galactica E and make it, you know.
Speaker 0: - I'm really down on those Battlestar Galactica E games 'cause they all have, like Shadows Ever Camelot and all of them have this horrible mechanic of.
Speaker 0: you can kind of say what you've got in your hand, but you can't explicitly say it and the rules are just so mushy that I can't, like I rage when I read those like that.
Speaker 2: - Yeah, they're unenforceable BS rules, you know.
Speaker 0: - It should either be silent or you can say anything.
Speaker 1: - Interesting.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I'll bring that DVD back soon.
Speaker 2: - Yeah, sure.
Speaker 1: - The, anyway.
Speaker 1: - Blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: - Well, at least I didn't fumble during the interview.
Speaker 1: - Whatever.
Speaker 1: - Anyway, I will be with you guys at Kineticon.
Speaker 2: - Oh, nice.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, Kineticon, we'll schedule him wherever he wants to be, so if you guys wanna see Luke Crane doing stuff.
Speaker 1: - I am really excited to run the panels.
Speaker 1: I ran at PAX East at Kineticon.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna run my Intro to Burning Wheel panel.
Speaker 1: - Oh, that's good.
Speaker 1: - Complete with gorgeous illustrations and slideshow.
Speaker 1: - Ooh.
Speaker 1: - And I am going to run the D&D You Never Knew panel, which is about the 1981 edition of D&D.
Speaker 0: - I really wanted to go to that, actually.
Speaker 2: - So wait, I'm always confused about the different colors, right?
Speaker 2: So I have the one, we got it at a Goodwill store in Rochester.
Speaker 2: It's three boxes, red, green, blue.
Speaker 2: Is that the one you're talking about, or are you talking about a different one?
Speaker 2: - You have three red-- - You have three boxes, one's red, and that's box one, then there's green is box two, and blue is box three.
Speaker 1: - It's actually red is one, blue is two, green is three.
Speaker 2: - The green and the blue might be backwards.
Speaker 2: Red is definitely box number one.
Speaker 1: - That's probably the 1983 edition.
Speaker 2: - So it's not the one you're talking about?
Speaker 1: - It is not.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about the one before that.
Speaker 2: - So is that the little tiny box?
Speaker 1: - No, no, it was a box set.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it was, yeah, it was a box set, and it was the red box and blue box, but there was a red box and blue box before.
Speaker 1: there was a red box and blue box.
Speaker 2: - Okay, all right.
Speaker 1: - So it's not the pink box or the white box?
Speaker 1: - You're gonna have to come to the lecture.
Speaker 1: I explained it all.
Speaker 1: I have slides, I have a little timeline.
Speaker 2: - We should put this on YouTube.
Speaker 1: - If you want to record it, that's fine.
Speaker 0: - We'll video it.
Speaker 1: - Anyway, so I'm excited to see you guys at Kineticon, and then I'll see you again at PAX Prime.
Speaker 1: - Oh yeah, PAX Prime.
Speaker 1: - Just booked my booth today.
Speaker 0: - Very nice.
Speaker 0: We're putting together, what we're gonna lecture on there.
Speaker 2: - Are you working on any games that you're free to talk about?
Speaker 2: I mean, you must be working on something, right?
Speaker 1: - We are working on a bunch of stuff at Burning Wheel headquarters, and we are neck deep in play testing.
Speaker 1: We've made some really, really cool discoveries rules-wise.
Speaker 2: - Ooh, discoveries.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, and I'm glad that we haven't gone forward with any of these.
Speaker 1: I'm glad we haven't released any of them in any capacity because especially over the winter, the developments were sweet, but--.
Speaker 2: - So if you would have released too soon, you wouldn't have had these nice discoveries in the game.
Speaker 2: - Right.
Speaker 2: - It's good to take your time.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, yeah, so we're working hard on them.
Speaker 1: It's a slow process, but we're confident that when these come out, you guys are gonna like them.
Speaker 1: - Yeah.
Speaker 2: - All right.
Speaker 0: - This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 2: - Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: - Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 2: - Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 2: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 2: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.