Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, February 7th, 2012.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights Tonight, elevator source.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: You know, I think ticker tape parades are one of those things that I will never get sick of only because they are so rare that their occasion warrants some manner of celebration.
Speaker 1: Well, if you would, you said you would never get sick of them, but what if they were happened every day?
Speaker 0: Well, one, if they happen every day, good God.
Speaker 1: Then you would get sick of them.
Speaker 0: But I won't because they will never happen that often.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: One, they're a thing that really in the modern world can only exist in New York.
Speaker 0: I mean, ticker tape implies stock market, even though we no longer use ticker tape for anything.
Speaker 1: But we should buy rolls of ticker tape on eBay just to use it in the parade.
Speaker 0: I almost bought.
Speaker 0: I was thinking about buying it for the office when I was at my old company.
Speaker 0: Because remember, we were a broker dealer for Wall Street.
Speaker 0: There was an old New York Stock Exchange ticker machine like the thing with the glass dome that printed out quotes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And I wanted to hook it up to an Arduino.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And I didn't do it because it only cost one hundred bucks and like a thousand dollars of freight shipping.
Speaker 0: But now I'm wealthier and I'm poking around again to see if I can find one and maybe I'll buy someone else's money to buy it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll put it on the corporate card, put it in the office and hook it up.
Speaker 0: I think that'd be really cool.
Speaker 0: And I think I think my company is hip enough to where they'd be OK with me doing that.
Speaker 0: OK, I want to go for it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the Johnson wins the Super Bowl.
Speaker 1: Oh, that every other state you saw.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But you guys, our state is clearly superior to the Empire State.
Speaker 0: We've got not one, not two, but three football teams.
Speaker 0: And one of them won the Super Bowl.
Speaker 1: The other two suck balls.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It was actually a pretty good game, too.
Speaker 0: Like I was impressed.
Speaker 0: And also, it's worth noting this Super Bowl was just free to watch online.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because NBC is not as dumb as the other TV network.
Speaker 0: I would wager I wonder I'd love to.
Speaker 0: I can't wait to see all the statistics for like how many people watched it online.
Speaker 1: Oh, we already know that.
Speaker 1: for a fact it was the most watched TV program in the history of the world.
Speaker 0: I think that was due almost entirely to the fact that it was on the Internet for free.
Speaker 1: Possibly.
Speaker 0: Now, I do know what was interesting is that the commercials, you know, the so-called famous Super Bowl commercials are not as crazy as they were not on the Internet stream.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: And I bet I don't know.
Speaker 0: I didn't research this for all I know.
Speaker 0: There's some news article explaining why.
Speaker 0: And I'm just stupid because I didn't research because they sell those ads for different prices.
Speaker 0: I'm also betting that the networks refuse to allow it under any conditions because every network knows.
Speaker 1: That's not true, because, number one, a lot of those advertisers just put their commercials on their website.
Speaker 0: Oh, they do.
Speaker 0: But before the Super Bowl, even until normal people, I think, don't realize this and watch them at the Super Bowl.
Speaker 1: But that's going to disappear, you know, within a few more years to you can go to NFL dot com such videos and watch all the ads.
Speaker 1: True.
Speaker 0: But they specifically were not in the stream.
Speaker 0: Instead, they showed one ad every time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, well, two ads.
Speaker 1: that if you watch because it's NBC.
Speaker 1: So NBC usually does Sunday Night Football, which is one game a week.
Speaker 1: And that's how I was watching football when we were in Beacon.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And they've been doing that for years and they've always just shown like one or two ads over and over again during the regular commercial breaks on that system.
Speaker 1: Now, what I really think system the users Sunday Night Football.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They can't just suddenly change it to show real commercials.
Speaker 1: The system can only handle a handful of commercials can't handle.
Speaker 0: Or I wonder what the actual pricing structure is in the back end.
Speaker 0: It's definitely different pricing, because I think that the the one supposition I have is that the advertisers didn't want to pay shit to be on the Internet because who cares on the Internet anyway?
Speaker 0: And the network was like, got to make money somehow.
Speaker 0: So they sold different ads for the Internet demographic, which meant two ads.
Speaker 1: I think they were just doing the same.
Speaker 1: You know, it's big businesses did just have systems and routines.
Speaker 1: They don't change them.
Speaker 1: And here's what's interesting.
Speaker 0: The system was did not work.
Speaker 0: So every time it cut to the ads, one, most of the time it would like freak out.
Speaker 0: And I could still see one of those camera angles, like all the extra camera angles we had pointed at the field, just kind of showing what was going on while the ad was happening.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And to the ad wouldn't play would like get stuck or the the thing would hang for like 30.
Speaker 1: so using silver light or they change it to flash yet.
Speaker 0: I don't actually know.
Speaker 0: I didn't pay attention.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because it used to use silver light and then it was flash.
Speaker 1: I think I'm pretty sure it's flash because the last time I watched it, they had all these Adobe ads.
Speaker 0: It was a 50/50 shot.
Speaker 0: Every ad cycle of the ad even played.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And but the street, the football stream was perfect, like 100 percent.
Speaker 1: Well, you had files, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 0: I thought we were streaming the Super Bowl and the Puppy Bowl simultaneously.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And in a third window, we were watching YouTube videos whenever ads came on.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you don't have files, though, they can eat.
Speaker 1: The quality could get pretty awful.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I have files.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: If you don't have files, that's that's just really sad.
Speaker 0: Unless you're at university, they think this is really happy.
Speaker 1: Even files is shit compared to the real Internet that other people have, like in the Netherlands or people have gigabits.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except for the fact that all the content is overseas.
Speaker 0: So they still have high latency.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: It's so fast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's trouble, though.
Speaker 0: I'd love to see you Netherlandsians play Counter-Strike.
Speaker 1: They do on European servers, which there are plenty of.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Play with me on my server.
Speaker 1: They don't want to play on your server.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they do.
Speaker 1: No, they don't.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the Super Bowl was good.
Speaker 0: And once again, you know, not to harp on this point.
Speaker 0: You nerds who, you know, go out of your way to say, I don't care about sports.
Speaker 0: The Super Bowl, you're the same as the people who are like, I don't care about Battlestar Galactica.
Speaker 0: Why is everyone tweeting about it?
Speaker 0: Why do you nerds care so much about Battlestar Galactica?
Speaker 1: I mean, it's like no one's making you like it, even though I can make an argument as to why you should care about it.
Speaker 1: And it's not dumb.
Speaker 1: But I saw so many tweets.
Speaker 1: It was pretty much mostly Twitter.
Speaker 1: People explicitly.
Speaker 0: What's the demographic of Twitter?
Speaker 1: And people I follow on Twitter were explicitly going out of their way to make a tweet to express their dislike, ignorance, distaste or whatever.
Speaker 1: They were like tweets that ranged from all you morons shut up about football.
Speaker 1: And I'm paraphrasing, obviously, to her.
Speaker 1: There's some superb owl going on, you know, stuff like that.
Speaker 1: And it's like, listen, no one says no one makes tweets that are like, heard there's some pony shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they do.
Speaker 0: Listen, you nerds.
Speaker 0: It's the same thing every time you rage because someone tweets like, I don't like that game.
Speaker 0: My little pony B.S.
Speaker 0: Nerd, furry, whatever.
Speaker 0: That's exactly what you're doing.
Speaker 1: It's haters gonna hate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, that's all it is.
Speaker 1: So stop.
Speaker 1: You know, football is a better game, but it seems it's weird.
Speaker 0: Most video games and board games.
Speaker 1: The thing, the reason this is different, though, is because when nerds hate on other nerd things, right?
Speaker 1: Some guy who likes the Skyrim's hate is like, why is there this pony mod gay pony guys?
Speaker 1: And then, you know, someone who likes Call of Duty is like, man, Counter-Strike, right?
Speaker 1: It's nerds hating nerds on nerdy things.
Speaker 1: So they're all, whenever that happens, nerds recognize that and they go, haters gonna hate.
Speaker 1: But when nerds are all collectively like hating on the sport, like no one's being like haters gonna hate.
Speaker 1: They're just being like, yeah, that's OK.
Speaker 1: We all hate that.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, no, football's a nerdery, too.
Speaker 1: Those people just aren't talking to you at all.
Speaker 0: Sound body and sound mind are very important.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: So, you know, football's the same.
Speaker 0: Don't be hating kids.
Speaker 0: It's all cool.
Speaker 0: Except for furries, I guess.
Speaker 1: Furries?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: So I got a bit of a geek bite here.
Speaker 1: A geek bite?
Speaker 0: Well, I got a geek bite.
Speaker 0: Because, you know, while Scott hates on most games and won't play him.
Speaker 1: Haters gonna hate.
Speaker 0: I actually did buy Deus Ex when it was like $14.99.
Speaker 1: Well, I bought Deus Ex when it was like $2.
Speaker 0: Well, the new Deus Ex.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I didn't like the first one.
Speaker 1: Why would I spend $15 on a sequel that became so many years later?
Speaker 0: What didn't you like about the first one?
Speaker 1: It's unplayable.
Speaker 0: In what regard?
Speaker 0: I'm curious.
Speaker 1: I couldn't even beat level one.
Speaker 1: Even though I tried to beat level one every different possible way.
Speaker 0: So, Scott, I'm going to say this.
Speaker 0: There is no reason, unless someone is one of those hardcore people, kind of like how you don't need to go back and play the old Fallouts.
Speaker 0: You just need to know they were there.
Speaker 0: You don't need to go back and play the old Deus Ex.
Speaker 0: You just need to know it was there.
Speaker 1: But the point is, people rave about that game.
Speaker 1: And they're always like, "Oh, man, playing Deus Ex again is so
Speaker 1: awesome.".
Speaker 0: Scott, you know what?
Speaker 1: They're full of shit.
Speaker 0: I'm going to play the hater game.
Speaker 0: I rave about Mega TF.
Speaker 0: Mega Team Fortress.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Compared to modern games, that game sucks.
Speaker 1: No, we should fucking play that game.
Speaker 1: It's awesome.
Speaker 1: It is not unplayable by any means.
Speaker 0: Except to people like us.
Speaker 0: Scott, do you remember how to write a fucking script?
Speaker 1: I was about to say, before you interrupted, do you know how to write a script?
Speaker 1: The only thing the game is lacking is an appropriate control configuration interface.
Speaker 1: If it had that, it would be all set.
Speaker 0: I think you forget how poor the graphics are in the Quake 1 engine.
Speaker 1: They don't need to be that good.
Speaker 0: They're kind of like how I played Doom.
Speaker 1: Can I tell what class the other guy is?
Speaker 1: Can I fly across the two form without touching the bridge?
Speaker 1: Can I rocket a guy in the face?
Speaker 0: Scott, could you ever actually wall run in Team Fortress?
Speaker 0: Mega TF.
Speaker 1: I could do in Doom 2.
Speaker 1: Do they still have the new grenade thingy?
Speaker 0: An Otis?
Speaker 0: Anyway, Deus Ex Human Revolution.
Speaker 0: Don't forget about Deus Ex.
Speaker 0: Just play that game, because it was super fun.
Speaker 0: I got about 27 hours of, well, no.
Speaker 0: I got 26 hours and 55 minutes of enjoyment out of that game.
Speaker 0: It's super fun.
Speaker 0: It's stealth that works really well.
Speaker 0: I kind of played the game, I think I talked about this in another episode, as though it was Ghost in the Shell and I was the Major.
Speaker 0: So I only ever put upgrades into things that made me better at hacking, sneaking, and butt.
Speaker 0: But in every situation I thought, what would the Major do?
Speaker 0: And that made for a really enjoyable experience.
Speaker 0: The stealth stuff works, like guys kind of walk around intelligently and there's always a vent.
Speaker 0: And if there is an event, there's always some clever thing you can do.
Speaker 0: And it's pretty intuitive.
Speaker 0: I had almost no difficulty.
Speaker 0: Like one boss fight took me like 10 attempts before I figured out the deal.
Speaker 0: I only have one complaint with the game.
Speaker 0: The ending is fucking bullshit.
Speaker 0: I was pissed off.
Speaker 1: Are you sure maybe you didn't get the good ending?
Speaker 0: No, I got all the endings.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: The end of the game was so fun.
Speaker 0: You know, games can have crappy endings.
Speaker 0: I've lived through that in my life.
Speaker 0: But the ending to Deus Ex Human Revolution was so cheap and so lazy, so hackneyed, so forced, so abrupt.
Speaker 0: I was disappointed to the point of a little bit of actual anger.
Speaker 0: I would have rather the game just like crashed and not let me finish than have actually gone through the final end of the game.
Speaker 1: Was it the actual play ending or just like the video at the end?
Speaker 0: So, the final sequence at the end when you're on this like Arctic base is pretty- Spoilers.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: You want some other spoilers?
Speaker 0: There's vents.
Speaker 0: You sneak through them and you jump down behind guys and you punch them in the face.
Speaker 0: So, there's this awesome end sequence.
Speaker 0: One, I heard Dave Riley and a bunch of people talk about how the end of Deus Ex was four buttons.
Speaker 0: Kind of like how Fallout 3 had the "Do you save everybody or are you a jerk" ending.
Speaker 0: So, people kept saying, "Yeah, it's a four button
Speaker 0: ending.".
Speaker 0: Like, kick a puppy, save a puppy, eat a puppy, leave the puppy to fend for himself like a little brother.
Speaker 0: I did not expect that they were not making a metaphor that it was literally four buttons.
Speaker 0: That literally, after you beat the final boss, the game walks you into a room and you're standing there and there's an FMV.
Speaker 0: And a character says, "Well, you've won, blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Now what do you
Speaker 0: do?".
Speaker 1: They actually say, "Well, you've
Speaker 1: won.".
Speaker 1: Basically.
Speaker 0: She says something like, "If you want to tell the world what happened here, knowing full well that they'll probably abandon science and technology forever, press this
Speaker 0: button.".
Speaker 0: And then a little button door opens up and there's a button.
Speaker 0: "If you think you should just fucking burn this place down, kill yourself and everyone in the facility to let mankind choose on their own, press this other
Speaker 0: button.".
Speaker 0: And then another button opens up.
Speaker 0: And those are the only options you get unless you do some bullshit and find some people in the last stage.
Speaker 0: Then you get two other options.
Speaker 0: But one, the options don't make any goddamn sense.
Speaker 0: I did not like any of them and I could think of a thousand better options that the character could have actually done in the real story.
Speaker 0: So the end made no sense.
Speaker 0: Two, there's no difference between any of the endings.
Speaker 0: There's no epilogue.
Speaker 0: There's a million open threads.
Speaker 0: You get nothing.
Speaker 0: No matter which button you click, you get a four minute or so kind of video of the real world.
Speaker 0: And depending on what ending you click, which button you click, you get a different order of the scenes in the video and a different voiceover.
Speaker 0: But the voiceovers all boil down to the same thing.
Speaker 0: "What is humanity?
Speaker 0: What does it mean to be a human?
Speaker 0: Are we really capable of harnessing this sort of technology?
Speaker 0: What if people abuse it?
Speaker 0: Have people ever abused
Speaker 0: technology?".
Speaker 0: With these cliche images of Nazis and atomic bombs.
Speaker 1: "Me and play
Speaker 1: gods!".
Speaker 0: And then, that's it!
Speaker 0: You don't even get to see the results of your decision.
Speaker 0: You get the same vague bullshit, half-assed bullshit.
Speaker 1: "You and play
Speaker 1: gods."
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: This is why I don't care about story in fucking games.
Speaker 1: I just care about the actual game.
Speaker 0: The story was good.
Speaker 0: Other than, there's one, I'm gonna get another spoiler.
Speaker 1: If the story's so good, I'll just watch it on YouTube.
Speaker 1: I only want to play a game if the game is worth playing.
Speaker 0: Yes, the game is worth playing.
Speaker 0: Same story.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, the story was revealed in interesting ways throughout the game.
Speaker 0: Mostly in the course of actual contextual play.
Speaker 0: Much like Half-Life 2.
Speaker 1: But apparently not at the end.
Speaker 0: Everything except the end, yeah.
Speaker 0: The end was just... And the thing is, all they would have had to do to do a 180 on that bullshit was to just, instead of doing that kind of existential, half-assed, no-answer BS where all the endings are the same, if they'd just given me a denouement, if the ending for each of the buttons had been just a 10 years later video, like, "What the world is like 10 years later after you did X," that would have been fine.
Speaker 0: That would have been awesome, in fact.
Speaker 0: But no.
Speaker 0: You get nothing.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, the game is stupid.
Speaker 0: fine.
Speaker 1: If you want to play a good stealth game...
Speaker 0: Play Deus Ex Human Revolution?
Speaker 1: You can go to GOG.com and they have...
Speaker 0: Or play Metal Gear.
Speaker 1: They have Thief Gold and Thief 2, the only real stealth games I've ever played in my life.
Speaker 1: They are both now available at GOG.com with no DRMs.
Speaker 0: We've never done a show on Thief, have we?
Speaker 1: I got Thief Gold.
Speaker 1: I didn't get Thief 2 yet.
Speaker 0: I have a copy of Thief 3 that came with my video card a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Thief 3 was okay.
Speaker 1: And I started playing Thief Gold, and you know what?
Speaker 1: Still fucking a real stealth game where actually stealthiness works and it's awesome and it's a good game.
Speaker 0: Scott, you should play Human Revolution because the stealth works and is awesome.
Speaker 1: Maybe if it's a dollar.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But seriously, the stealth really works well.
Speaker 0: Simple stuff matters.
Speaker 0: Doors being open or closed and distance and all the sounds you make actually...
Speaker 1: You mean the same as Thief 1?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a lot like Thief 1.
Speaker 1: Even though Thief 1 got it right 100 years ago.
Speaker 1: So another game also got it right.
Speaker 1: So it did the exact same thing.
Speaker 1: If it's a new game, it needs to be much more advanced.
Speaker 1: It's like, "Yeah, I got it right.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: You did the same thing that they did in the 90s.
Speaker 1: Good for you.
Speaker 1: You made no advancement or improvement
Speaker 1: whatsoever.".
Speaker 0: I think you're being a little too black and white and dismissive here.
Speaker 0: Fuck Scott and haters, Deus Ex.
Speaker 0: Human Revolution is super fun.
Speaker 0: However, at the end, once you beat the last boss, just turn the game off.
Speaker 0: Don't even click.
Speaker 0: Don't even give the game the pleasure of picking any of its BS endings.
Speaker 0: Just watch them on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Also, I'm disappointed, spoilers, that four-fifths of the way through the game, one of the bosses is like, "Oh man, I'm just a pawn in a greater game.
Speaker 0: It's actually the
Speaker 0: Illuminati.".
Speaker 0: And the main character is like, "Illuminati?
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: It's actually the
Speaker 0: Illuminati.".
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was not pleased with that either.
Speaker 1: Spoilers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: Who cares?
Speaker 0: Spoilers, this is Robocop Ghost in the Shell the game.
Speaker 0: Who cares?
Speaker 1: So here's a real game news, right?
Speaker 1: This is a geekery that I'm sort of not in and I never will be in, but I know it exists and I respect it.
Speaker 1: And that is the flight simulation geekery.
Speaker 1: And there are many levels.
Speaker 1: There are people who just go wee with a flight stick and they fly around.
Speaker 1: And then there's people who are like pretending to be air traffic controllers using Skype and whatever it is.
Speaker 1: they got to actually control people who are simulating flying.
Speaker 1: And there'll be people copiloting.
Speaker 1: I think there might even be people simulating being stewardesses.
Speaker 1: Handing out drinks, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know what these people are doing.
Speaker 1: But they love flight simulating.
Speaker 1: And they got a lot of softwares they use.
Speaker 1: Isn't X-Plane the free open source one or something?
Speaker 1: And there's another one that's the expensive one.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I remember back in the day it was all about Microsoft Flight Simulator on MS-DOS.
Speaker 0: Because it came with your computer, you just had it.
Speaker 1: And that was something that Microsoft kept going.
Speaker 1: You know, they had other things in that line like Microsoft Golf, which is a golf simulator but that didn't, you know, that died.
Speaker 1: But they kept going with Flight Simulator.
Speaker 1: I think they actually had Flight Simulator X. I think they had like a ton of versions of it.
Speaker 1: But then it sort of died.
Speaker 1: But now they're coming out with Microsoft Flight.
Speaker 1: Not Flight Simulator, just Microsoft Flight.
Speaker 1: And it's going to come out on February 29th at the end of the month, the leap day.
Speaker 1: And it's going to be free.
Speaker 1: Not free like, you know, the free to play, but you can't actually play, you know, it's really free.
Speaker 1: And the only thing they're charging money for is like, add a plane.
Speaker 1: Add the rest of Hawaii.
Speaker 1: Add, you know, stuff like that.
Speaker 1: And it's like if you just want to, you know, the free area gives you a bunch of planes and a bunch of places to fly.
Speaker 1: And if you don't really- The important thing is- If you don't want to fly a particular edition of a particular airplane on the extra Hawaiian Islands- The Beegee better be in there.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: You don't- The Beegee's a pretty good plane.
Speaker 1: You don't need to pay any extra money.
Speaker 1: And you know what, if you're really crazy about it, it's actually not crazy expensive.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, you can get the Hawaiian Adventure Pack for 20 bucks.
Speaker 1: And it's like, oh, okay.
Speaker 0: I was really into flight simulators.
Speaker 1: It's a lot more going to be like that train thing that's on Steam.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Which again, if I could get that and all its DLC for like a dollar, I'd buy it.
Speaker 1: But I mean, for free, for a game that you just play locally, really, I'm definitely going to at least try it.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to get a stick or anything, but I'll use my mouse and keyboard and fly around and see what happens.
Speaker 0: I would need a stick because I was really into flight simulators back when I was a kid, and I was seriously courting the idea of getting a pilot's license.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to do it for series, but I'll try it for free for a few minutes.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: I'll let you in on a secret.
Speaker 0: Flying planes is actually- Boring.
Speaker 0: Really easy and boring for the most part.
Speaker 0: Unless you're in an ultralight or something.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it exists.
Speaker 1: And it's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: It's a thing.
Speaker 0: So one other piece of gaming news.
Speaker 0: There were rumors this was going along for a while, but I didn't- I ignored it because Gamefly, who cares, and Direct-to-Drive, who cares?
Speaker 0: And then I was cleaning out my inbox and I found an email I never noticed where Direct-to-Drive was like, "Yeah, we got bought by Gamefly, and you can't download your games anymore.
Speaker 0: Now you have a Gamefly
Speaker 0: account.".
Speaker 0: So I was like, "Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Why would they email-".
Speaker 0: Oh no!
Speaker 0: I bought a Direct-to-Drive game, like, forever ago.
Speaker 0: I bought Bionic Commando Rearmed.
Speaker 0: And sure enough, I cannot download it from Direct-to-Drive.
Speaker 0: They're gone.
Speaker 0: I also can't download it from Gamefly, because they haven't migrated their whole catalog yet and they've refused to give an ETA and when they will.
Speaker 0: Two, I don't think they're actually going to migrate Bionic Commando Rearmed, because it doesn't even show up in their normal catalog.
Speaker 0: And this just reiterates, one, fuck you, Gamefly.
Speaker 0: I only have an account because I'm trying to get my one game that I legally own downloaded from your bullshit.
Speaker 0: So far I can't.
Speaker 0: Your customer service has been worthless.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how many stories do we need of, "Fucked by DRM, pirates get better service than people who pay money, blah blah
Speaker 1: blah.".
Speaker 1: I mean, it's the same story over and over again.
Speaker 0: Why repeat it?
Speaker 0: But now I got fucked by it, so really- Why repeat the story?
Speaker 0: This is why I never buy any game that isn't on Steam.
Speaker 1: Steam has the same problem, though.
Speaker 1: They're DRM'd and closed, but we can trust them not to fuck up.
Speaker 0: No, there's two reasons.
Speaker 0: One, I trust them to do the right thing if they have to, or they're forced into a weird situation.
Speaker 0: Two, so many people rely on Steam, I am confident that if Steam went away or turned evil, that shit would be cracked right away.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But, uh, yeah, who even uses Gamefly?
Speaker 1: There are people who use it actually for the game renting service, where they mail you discs.
Speaker 0: Oh, I used to use Red Octane for that, which was actually send me a PS1 disc that I copied and immediately mailed back that day.
Speaker 1: Right, but here's the thing, what's gonna happen?
Speaker 1: uh, there's rumors going around about the Xbox 720 and how it won't let you use used games.
Speaker 1: Oh, we've known this for a long time, the entire media industry- But it's like, well, first of all, Steam already doesn't let you use used games.
Speaker 1: Two, I don't have any Xbox games that are on a disc except Rock Pan 3 and the ones that came with it.
Speaker 1: Oh, and Street Fighter.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: Uh, it's like I'm probably not gonna buy any more disc games ever.
Speaker 0: I'm not even renewing Xbox Live Gold, 'cause I don't fuckin' use it.
Speaker 1: Me either.
Speaker 1: Right, it's like I'm not buying a disc game, pretty much ever.
Speaker 1: All the best games are download games that I can't sell used anyway, but even more interesting there was some court case I read about on Slashdot, where there was some company where what they were doing, I think it's called Re-Digi, and it's like you sell your used iTunes music to other people, and they have some clever way where it removes the song from your iTunes account and deletes it so you can never have the song again, and it gives it to the other person.
Speaker 1: And so you can, it's like, I don't know what kind of crack they're doing, but they have a thing where you can sell your used, legally purchased iTunes music to other people with your writer for a sale.
Speaker 1: And, uh, it's gonna be, and the court was like, yeah, okay, and it seemed there was a slight, tiny bit of momentum going in the direction of the, uh, the people who were, you know, doing this, so.
Speaker 0: That'll be interesting.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be interesting to see what goes on here.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day!
Speaker 0: What do you got for me?
Speaker 1: So, I actually, I'm gonna do my own thing.
Speaker 1: That's right, I did-- Master Batari!
Speaker 1: I did something that is so awesome, that it is a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: And I'm gonna pick it, 'cause I did something and I think that I'm awesome enough to be a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Uh, you know what, I agree.
Speaker 0: I think it's a great idea.
Speaker 1: So I made a Tumblr, and I'm not replacing my blog with a Tumblr or anything like that, right?
Speaker 1: I just made this Tumblr for one specific purpose, and that is a Tumblr consisting only of video game meat.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: Meats from video games.
Speaker 1: It's pixelmeat.tumblr.com and, uh, I got, every day, I got a JPEG or something of a meat from a video game.
Speaker 1: Like, we're gonna have mostly Castlevania going on here, but for now, we got some variety.
Speaker 1: Uh, if you know of any video game meats that I have not yet covered, please send them in, 'cause I don't wanna run out.
Speaker 0: Well's drying up fast, surprisingly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's, you know, it's not really drying up.
Speaker 0: The Dungeons and Dragons game and/or Golden Axe.
Speaker 1: I thought of those already.
Speaker 1: They're already, I have a list, but I've already thought of the Dungeons and Dragons arcade games and the Golden Axe.
Speaker 0: I already got Gauntlet on there.
Speaker 1: I'm sure, the thing is, there are multiple Gauntlet meats I can go for, but here's the one I've already got, is the one with the plate and the beer next to it.
Speaker 0: That's my favorite one.
Speaker 1: That's a good one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you love to shoot it.
Speaker 1: Um, but yeah, if you know any video game meats, please send them in.
Speaker 1: There's a submit button on the side that says submit meat.
Speaker 1: Uh, submit your meat.
Speaker 0: So, thanks to My Little Pony, I discovered a genre of music that I guess I could've extrapolated, but I never thought about it, 'cause I'm a big fan of swing, and I'm a big fan of big band and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: I'm really a big, like, the Squirrel Nut Zippers were actually one of my favorite bands, like when I was younger.
Speaker 0: And, I never thought to combine that with techno, because half the genres of music out there are... Yeah, take genre X, turn it into techno.
Speaker 0: I never thought to do a swing, and apparently there's a huge genre of music called electro swing, and someone made a PMV to a song by a band called Caravan Paradise called Clash, and the PMV was awesome.
Speaker 0: The song was awesome.
Speaker 0: So, I searched for them, and I find their normal video, well, I guess the link to the actual full-length song, and it's all pony comments there.
Speaker 0: The band, this Parisian band, was catapulted to American fame due to My Little Pony, and they're fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: This is a great song.
Speaker 0: It's been stuck in my head.
Speaker 0: I've been playing it, like, every ten minutes for the last two days.
Speaker 0: We'll see how long it takes me to get sick of it.
Speaker 0: I found them on Spotify.
Speaker 0: I found all those other bands.
Speaker 0: I am totally pumped about this.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, PAX East is coming up.
Speaker 0: If you didn't get a ticket, well, we told you.
Speaker 0: You can buy three stupid one-day badges, but if it's not too late, you can take up the black and/or the blue.
Speaker 1: They shouldn't even sell the stupid one-day badges anymore.
Speaker 1: They shouldn't.
Speaker 1: Three-day only.
Speaker 0: You could try to be an enforcer, but otherwise, you're not going.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: If you don't have hotel room, good luck staying by the Hines.
Speaker 1: Yeah, where Anime Boston is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we will be at PAX.
Speaker 0: We will also, very likely, as long as we can work out the scheduling between the two, be at Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: For at least a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Probably around dinner times, we're trying to work out a deal.
Speaker 0: Well, we kind of did work out a deal where, if we're going to be at Anime Boston, it's going to be around dinner time, so we can get away from the horde of PAX and eat on Newbury Street.
Speaker 1: Yeah, where the good food is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I love PAX, and the BCEC has some good restaurants, but not enough of them.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, right, Anime Boston usually, you know, tries to give us money that we don't need.
Speaker 1: Instead, if they pay for cabs, it'll be about less money than that.
Speaker 0: I don't want any of that, as long as I can, I have an excuse.
Speaker 1: But I'm worried about speed because I want to get back to PAX after Anime Boston and dinner, so that we can then play games.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I'm super pumped.
Speaker 0: KineticCon, coming along, look for the website soon-ish for panels and missions and all that.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Check out our YouTube.
Speaker 0: Check out all our stuff.
Speaker 0: We got stuff.
Speaker 0: We played with our friend Chase and some other people.
Speaker 0: A game that brought us up to 28 randomized floors to stop on.
Speaker 0: A thrilling co-op experience.
Speaker 0: Realistic elevator physics.
Speaker 0: Cunning, state of the art AI that really goes into the elevator and waits.
Speaker 0: And real moral choices.
Speaker 0: What floor do you get off?
Speaker 0: Do you ever get off?
Speaker 0: We played a mod for Half-Life 2 called Elevator Source.
Speaker 0: We actually played it.
Speaker 1: It was a recent thing of the day.
Speaker 1: We played it once through.
Speaker 1: It was pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we'll talk about it.
Speaker 1: It's worth doing once.
Speaker 0: Here's the key.
Speaker 0: Don't do it by yourself.
Speaker 0: What you gotta do is get a bunch of friends, like at least three.
Speaker 1: Who've never done it before.
Speaker 0: Yeah, who have no idea what this is.
Speaker 0: Get them to install... You gotta have Gary's mod.
Speaker 0: You gotta have Half-Life and the episodes.
Speaker 0: Half-Life 2, obviously.
Speaker 0: And the episodes.
Speaker 0: And install this mod.
Speaker 0: Pretty straightforward to install.
Speaker 0: Start a server.
Speaker 0: Everyone joins it.
Speaker 0: Set all talk to true so you can all chat with each other because the key is to be able to talk with voices while you're playing.
Speaker 0: And the game is just.
Speaker 0: you're in an elevator.
Speaker 0: Shit happens.
Speaker 1: I mean you don't really do anything, right?
Speaker 1: It's like basically the way it works.
Speaker 1: you join the server and you all start in this lobby, right?
Speaker 1: And you know if you're standing there and if you get in the elevator the game will start.
Speaker 1: So pretty much no one gets in the elevator until everyone's there.
Speaker 1: Then you all get in the elevator together.
Speaker 1: Then the elevator just goes on its own and it stops at floors.
Speaker 1: And on each floor something happens.
Speaker 1: And you react to it because it's totally unexpected.
Speaker 1: And some of them are really creative.
Speaker 1: Things happen.
Speaker 0: Some of them were really creepy actually.
Speaker 1: Some of them were creepy.
Speaker 1: A lot of different things going on there.
Speaker 1: Some people get in the elevator.
Speaker 1: Some people leave the elevator.
Speaker 1: A lot of stuff goes on and it's just about reacting to this crazy shit that happens with your group of people.
Speaker 0: Now what's funny is this is we always talk about games.
Speaker 1: The definition is you can't even leave the elevator or do anything.
Speaker 1: There's nothing to play.
Speaker 1: There's nothing to shoot.
Speaker 0: We use a series of meaningful and/or interesting decisions.
Speaker 0: Or we use a competitive fair test of one or more skills among more than one player.
Speaker 0: Or maybe even one player.
Speaker 0: Depending.
Speaker 0: But there's that third definition of an enjoyable pastime.
Speaker 0: Because this game is in that third group.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: there's no skill.
Speaker 0: There's no real decisions to be made.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much an experience.
Speaker 0: A shared experience that is minimally interactive.
Speaker 0: But it's an exploratory one.
Speaker 0: Like the first thing you do is you start hitting all your buttons.
Speaker 0: And like you hit a certain button, your guy coughs.
Speaker 0: Like I'm on an elevator and I coughed.
Speaker 0: Hit another button and you check your watch and there's little details.
Speaker 0: Like the watch is accurate to the current real time.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: At least in your time zone.
Speaker 1: But yeah it's almost like a role playing game where you're being railroaded and you can't get off the tracks.
Speaker 0: So you start to follow these characters and I bet you'll find, we're not going to spoil too much, but we'll spoil a few things.
Speaker 0: just to give you an idea of what this is like.
Speaker 0: Like at one floor it stops.
Speaker 0: There's this guy just kind of walks on to the elevator and starts waiting with us.
Speaker 1: Every time he plays it's going to be different too because I think it chooses the next floor randomly.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And so you never know.
Speaker 0: This guy had a name.
Speaker 0: You look at him and he's got a name.
Speaker 0: He's just standing there.
Speaker 0: So of course everyone walks over to him coughs on him.
Speaker 0: And then again he walks around him in a circle for a while.
Speaker 0: I love the guy who got on later with the shotgun and just kind of kept looking at us warily the whole time.
Speaker 1: Never shot anything.
Speaker 0: I was waiting for him to just fucking shoot us.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like I really don't want to spoil because there's not that much to this game but I will say this.
Speaker 1: We didn't even see all the floors.
Speaker 1: There's plenty of floors we didn't see.
Speaker 0: But it's exploratory in that at some point you eventually do get to get off the elevator.
Speaker 0: And what's interesting is that this is where you see this kind of exploratory gameplay really shining even though it doesn't fit the usual definitions of game that we use when we're talking about games we like or are good.
Speaker 0: You'll hear things like as soon as you can get off the elevator everyone fucking runs and is just like running around like oh my god look at this.
Speaker 0: Oh my god look at this.
Speaker 1: Because you've been stuck in this elevator and you couldn't do anything.
Speaker 1: Suddenly you're in a place where you might be able to do something and look around.
Speaker 1: so you're just like oh.
Speaker 0: finally oh my god.
Speaker 0: Like I hear Chase in one corner is like oh my god check out this skull.
Speaker 0: Oh wait I can pick it up.
Speaker 0: And meanwhile I'm in another room.
Speaker 0: I'm like there's a slot machine.
Speaker 0: Guys it works.
Speaker 0: Oh my god I'm playing.
Speaker 0: And there's a pool table and a blender.
Speaker 0: I went to the fridge and got like an orange out and blended it and lots of fun stuff was going on.
Speaker 1: Even though that stuff is you know if you think about it okay.
Speaker 0: It's really lame.
Speaker 1: Blending an orange is pretty lame but.
Speaker 0: It feels like one of those like old Quake 2 mods or something like a machinima almost.
Speaker 0: There's not much going on but sharing that experience with other people it shows that you know Scott and I are pretty fucking jaded.
Speaker 0: Where you know this game didn't do anything new.
Speaker 0: but it proves that a well executed simple concept even if it's just a retread of existing known ideas can still instill in someone that childlike wonder of oh my god I got the pool table to do something.
Speaker 0: this is so awesome.
Speaker 1: I pushed a button and a thing happened.
Speaker 1: You know it's like the oldest you know amusements in the world.
Speaker 1: Or walk up to a thing push a button and a thing happens.
Speaker 0: And part of it too is that you're so constrained that you know you're on the elevator for a while between floors and you pretty much explore and start to like examine every tiny god damn detail in this entire game.
Speaker 0: Like you will start examining like the buttons.
Speaker 0: You'll be hitting every button on your keyboard you'll like duck and look at every object from every possible angle.
Speaker 0: And you've got to have a bunch of people and you've got to play it together.
Speaker 0: You've got to have the shared experience.
Speaker 0: You've got to have voice chat.
Speaker 0: You've all got to be engaged.
Speaker 0: And I think everyone should play it.
Speaker 0: The only problem is you've got to own Garry's Mod which if you don't it's like 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: I don't know if this experience is worth 10 bucks.
Speaker 1: No but if you use Garry's Mod for other shit it might be worth 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But actually I was thinking you know it's really similar to those things where you know you get in one of those like those amusement park rides where you sit and it drives you around.
Speaker 0: And you shoot at like the pirate and he goes wah wah wah.
Speaker 1: Yeah it's like you just see stuff but if you shoot a thing then it doesn't you know then it does something.
Speaker 1: So it's like there'll be a barrel and you shoot the barrel and a pirate comes out and goes argh.
Speaker 0: It's basically that.
Speaker 1: It's basically that.
Speaker 1: And maybe we should make one of those in Garry's Mod.
Speaker 1: you know where you get in a car and you get in a tram because Half Life loves trams and you sit in it and everyone has a gun and all you can do is shoot at things outside the tram and if you hit a thing you know it does something.
Speaker 0: This game also falls into that category much like Passage or Covetous.
Speaker 0: These games that are like they bridge the line between an interactive game and an interactive art installation.
Speaker 0: Like this is more installation than a game but yet it kind of proves that the line is not nearly as well defined as a lot of people would like to lead you to believe.
Speaker 0: And it is really telling how much we enjoyed it despite the fact that it pretty much does.
Speaker 0: everything that we say is shitty about games.
Speaker 1: Well you know it's not.
Speaker 1: I wasn't going into it expecting a competitive battle for who can win the elevator because if that had happened if there was some sort of win the elevator I would have ripped all your motherfucking throats out.
Speaker 0: Oh my god this game could have done more and Ben it would have gone from a really interesting experience to transcendence.
Speaker 1: See that's what I would have done.
Speaker 1: to add more I would have had like you know the same sort of weird build up and then some sort of thing like maybe you're split up and it's like I don't see you guys I still see you guys you know some confusion you know.
Speaker 1: and then maybe like some sort of actual competition like someone sees a note on their screen or you know things like that get the people to do something and then like someone wins and gets to see stuff the other people didn't see and they try to take screenshots of it to prove it.
Speaker 1: and you know shit like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah I thought something weird happened.
Speaker 0: I was taking screenshots because I got separated from everyone but it was just a. I got teleported back to the beginning of the game.
Speaker 0: it wasn't anything special but for a second I was like guys oh my god I'm somewhere weird.
Speaker 0: let me get some screenshots.
Speaker 1: oh wait oh fuck yeah because you can just ride the elevator again.
Speaker 1: Um yeah also uh it's got some cool stuff in there like.
Speaker 1: there's a part where like you can there's a TV and you can put YouTube videos in the TV but it didn't really work.
Speaker 1: And there was also the part where like there was all these cats outside the elevator but you couldn't see them.
Speaker 1: only we could.
Speaker 0: I know like I think that was.
Speaker 0: I don't know what was wrong with my installation.
Speaker 1: You suck.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: this is a fun experience I recommend.
Speaker 0: it's kind of like how uh you know not so much Four Swords but Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles the original.
Speaker 0: If you play it by yourself it's a pretty mediocre game.
Speaker 0: But if you play it with four people who get into it it's one of the greatest gaming experiences you could ever have.
Speaker 0: And this is the same way in that if you play it with a bunch of people who all come into it ready to experience it with an open mind and some optimism it was enjoyable enough for us to actually talk about it here and say you should do it.
Speaker 0: Have we ever steered you wrong?
Speaker 1: Well yeah we didn't have anything else to do a show on either.
Speaker 1: I mean there's a bunch of Half-Life mods that are all sort of in the same category like the Stanley Parable and they're basically but this one made the rounds.
Speaker 1: So did that one.
Speaker 1: There's basically this whole genre of Half-Life mods which is I created a map with some scripted events and stuff like that and you go through it and it's.
Speaker 1: it's the kind of experience that you know you can't really make in a physical museum because it would just take up so much space and for one person to do it at a time wouldn't be economical you know.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: you know it's like even better than amusement park rides.
Speaker 1: You can do things amusement park rides can't do because it's all fake.
Speaker 1: So it's it's pretty crazy.
Speaker 1: and you know if you like amusement park rides well you'll love the hell out of these things.
Speaker 1: right and there's a bunch of them so try them all out.
Speaker 0: They added support for custom floors.
Speaker 0: so I think we could use Gary's mod and some documentation to make our own floors.
Speaker 0: I wonder if we could just give it to them or make our own DLC.
Speaker 1: Yeah the thing with Gary's mod it's basically like like Stanley Parable is a mod mod.
Speaker 1: you can just you don't need Gary's mod for it.
Speaker 1: but you know this needs Gary's mod because basically Gary's mod is like the meta mod.
Speaker 1: it lets you make mods with it and it does other crazy stuff.
Speaker 1: so a lot of people who are can't really program a mod which is not easy can use Gary's mod to make a mod but then anyone who wants to play that mod needs Gary's mod.
Speaker 1: you know the whole thing anyway.
Speaker 0: This was super fun.
Speaker 0: you should do it.
Speaker 0: unless you don't have Gary's mod you don't plan to use it.
Speaker 0: You don't have friends and ten dollars is a lot of money but you should have friends on Steam.
Speaker 1: I mean come on guys.
Speaker 0: You've got you've got to be able to get a posse like five people to hide inside the bones.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember Geek Nights is not one but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.