Speaker 0: It's Monday, May 7th, 2012.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm sky and this is geek nights tonight to the web vulnerabilities.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I just stopped to get some lettuce for the the bunnies on the way home And I go to Grand Central fancy market and there's a new place there that I hadn't noticed before.
Speaker 0: Okay inside and they sell like baked goods and fancy cookies, but they're not sorrows fuck sorrows.
Speaker 0: They're like the worst blandest anyway, so I go over there and I'm like, alright, I'm kind of hungry.
Speaker 0: So I get like a cookie and I get a little like a little small package of cookies and two things of fancy-looking crackers.
Speaker 0: I go to the front to pay and I don't really you know when I buy small things.
Speaker 0: I don't like look at what they cost because I assume they're reasonable.
Speaker 0: So I get up there and she's like that'll be thirty four ninety eight and I'm like for what?
Speaker 1: What were you buying?
Speaker 0: so, like I said, so 2020. and then I realized that that won't be enough because of the amount of money she said Which doesn't jive with the amount of goods and services that I'm acquired the amount of goods.
Speaker 0: So I stopped and I say excuse me thirty bucks for that for what that was one Ginger cookie like a normal like, you know big ginger cookie not as big as the panko to the end.
Speaker 0: No, not like.
Speaker 0: I would order the size which is three dollars and change Two but small boxes of fancy but very small crackers and one small carton of about 14 cookies.
Speaker 0: so I'm like How can this be 34 whatever dollars?
Speaker 0: This is ludicrous and she gets really huffy like.
Speaker 0: Well, this cost this and the crackers everything were reasonable.
Speaker 0: that little pack of cookies was like $16 and I'm like, are they really that good?
Speaker 0: and she's like, yeah, and I'm like, oh, I don't want him.
Speaker 0: It was this tiny pack that would have been more than a dollar a cookie for these tiny little cookies I think can't be that good.
Speaker 0: But I just I was dumbstruck by that.
Speaker 0: Like I didn't know what to do.
Speaker 1: What was it in them?
Speaker 1: truffles?
Speaker 1: and gold?
Speaker 0: I Don't even know.
Speaker 0: I picked I picked him up semi randomly foie gras truffle cookies.
Speaker 0: Even then $15 to be fair.
Speaker 0: The carton was really heavy, but it was clear I could see inside.
Speaker 0: there were not that many cookies led And we also did the five borough bike tour over the weekend.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my I was a little disappointed that I was doing fine.
Speaker 0: Like I was in the right heat I made it all the way up to like the middle front of the blue pack and then Half a little over half way through the race.
Speaker 0: My right knee looked at me and said, you know what rim?
Speaker 0: Fuck this.
Speaker 0: and I basically had to do the whole rest of the race primarily using my left leg.
Speaker 0: So now my right knee hurts and my left leg hurts.
Speaker 0: Okay, but I did do a little bit of research and talk to a doctor and I think I know how to handle this.
Speaker 1: He surgery.
Speaker 1: Nope Yeah, hitting your knee with a book It's Gideon's knee.
Speaker 0: So apparently this particular kind of knee pain is caused when you're pushing too hard with too low of a cadence.
Speaker 0: So the best strategy is to go here lower gear and if you're going on a long-distance bike race The doctor and a bunch of websites I found said that you should be pedaling above 80 rpm.
Speaker 0: Otherwise you're prone to that over long distances and sprinting and all these things are different, but I thought that was interesting.
Speaker 0: Thought you should know.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And by you I mean all of you out there.
Speaker 1: So use lower gear pedal harder.
Speaker 0: Basic pedal faster.
Speaker 0: Yeah harder, right, but I mean it was fun.
Speaker 0: I got a time-lapse.
Speaker 1: if I'm pedaling over 80 rpm and it's just spinning cuz I'm going too fast Then you need a differently geared bike.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 0: My only complaint well not a complaint because this was not a race.
Speaker 0: It was not like a hardcore like there was no prize for coming in first.
Speaker 0: nor Could you come in first because there is no further than hat?
Speaker 0: Well, there is a first person.
Speaker 0: The problem is more than half the people in the event are People who have to walk their bike up all the hills or little kids.
Speaker 1: Yeah I actually didn't see half the people walking up the hills.
Speaker 1: I saw like one in 20 people walking up the hills.
Speaker 1: I think like whenever I got to a hill there would be one or two people Talking and everyone else.
Speaker 0: but I think the reason I saw more is that I was in the second heat So I passed the entire trailing edge of your heat.
Speaker 0: So I passed all the slowest people in the front heat and they were walking up every step.
Speaker 1: I was in the front heat and I went basically You know that the first people to leave.
Speaker 1: I got to Astoria and for the first time ever in my life during a strenuous Athletic activity.
Speaker 1: usually what happens if I try to like run a mile or something is my lungs go out don't breathe no more Except not a heart attack.
Speaker 1: I said Right, and then I go.
Speaker 1: oh man, my leg still feels good.
Speaker 1: I could keep going.
Speaker 1: My heart lungs like nope You're not going anywhere this time.
Speaker 1: I was going on the FDR and I was like, oh man the FDR I can never bike on this because it's I would die.
Speaker 1: and also you're not allowed to and I'm going.
Speaker 1: I'm going.
Speaker 1: I'm just going A little hill on the FDR and I'm like, huh?
Speaker 1: My legs are getting tired.
Speaker 0: Well Scott, you know what happened.
Speaker 0: You uh used to be pretty sedentary.
Speaker 1: now You move your ass and then I went to the Queensborough Bridge and I'm like, ah Queensborough Bridge I go over you every day.
Speaker 1: Oh upper level This is no problem.
Speaker 1: And then it's like guess what?
Speaker 1: You're not going on a pedestrian path today, son You're going to upper level.
Speaker 1: It's way higher and I'm like, oh my legs.
Speaker 0: The thing I got to say is this was granny gear help me This wasn't like other than going over the Verrazano at the end like that extra few miles.
Speaker 0: This was not more than like what I do in a typical weekend, but I got to ride places.
Speaker 0: I normally don't get to ride Yeah, so All concrete.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think my favorite part was riding over the crazy entrance and exit ramps on the Queensborough Bridge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, so then I get to my house and I'm like my house.
Speaker 1: It's literally right next to the friggin bike tour, so I'm like, I'm just gonna go to my house.
Speaker 1: I'm like, there's no way that everyone will pass me in like 10 minutes.
Speaker 1: So I go inside my house and I realize whoa, I am way hungry literally shoved a sandwich and a banana and like two glasses of apple juice and I refilled my water and drank the water and refilled the water and peed and did all this stuff and stretched.
Speaker 1: and then I go back outside and I was in the blue group and I'm looking at you know Figuring red people are going by by now because I basically stood still for ten minutes still blue people.
Speaker 1: And then I biked for five minutes and I brought a banana with me.
Speaker 1: by the way You hit that mandatory rest stop.
Speaker 1: I biked for five minutes to the park not even five minutes and there's a mandatory rest stop.
Speaker 1: And then so I'm at the mandatory rest up.
Speaker 1: I grabbed my banana to eat it.
Speaker 1: You know the second banana my sweet my sweet.
Speaker 1: I dropped the banana and a dude immediately steps on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then I look at the rest stop this infinite free bananas.
Speaker 1: I'm like fuck.
Speaker 0: they were I what bunny?
Speaker 0: they were a different brand.
Speaker 1: It didn't matter what brand they were.
Speaker 1: I could have and I thought about seriously considered Grabbing a whole bunch of those bananas going back to my apartment just bike away with a whole crate of them Like it I'd be like.
Speaker 1: well No one caught.
Speaker 1: no one in the red group caught up with me in ten minutes.
Speaker 1: That would take about 15 minutes to go get a bunch of free banana.
Speaker 0: one trouble with this notice how I got a picture of It.
Speaker 0: those bananas were all Perfectly ripe.
Speaker 1: They were exactly good.
Speaker 0: They would not have been good like ten minutes later.
Speaker 1: No, they were just fine.
Speaker 1: but I ate like two of them.
Speaker 1: and then I had Lara bars which were free and all.
Speaker 1: my guy never had those before.
Speaker 1: those are really good and Whatever.
Speaker 1: awesome free rest stop.
Speaker 1: and then I biked the rest of the way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was super fun But then I did stop again in the Brooklyn Bridge.
Speaker 1: rest stop not cuz I actually needed stopping But because there was a great view of from there just in general and there are free bananas.
Speaker 0: I've been to that park area before like that.
Speaker 1: It's not much of a park Yeah, but I got to try all the other Lara bar flavors.
Speaker 1: Let's get the coconut flavoring Another banana.
Speaker 0: and now my stomach hurts because you realize your banana plan is reminiscent of an anecdote.
Speaker 0: Remember the soap.
Speaker 1: Oh My god, that's the same plan.
Speaker 1: It is the same plan except soap doesn't go bad Yeah, and we use that shit for years and that was shitty soap.
Speaker 0: and these are perfectly Blasted like two showers.
Speaker 1: The bananas are perfectly okay.
Speaker 0: We had more than 60 pounds of it.
Speaker 1: You should join the Fireboro bike tour for one reason free bananas.
Speaker 1: Little kids can do it.
Speaker 1: You can do it too.
Speaker 1: Just free bananas.
Speaker 0: Also biking through the freeway is actually surprisingly Neat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just wish that was the first part.
Speaker 1: So you wouldn't be tired on that.
Speaker 0: I kind of cheated and did a pace line through all that bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was really no one.
Speaker 0: Granted I cheated in the pace line.
Speaker 0: So all these super fast guys like blow by me.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, oh shit son.
Speaker 0: So I catch up to him and get in the back of their pace line and every time they shift positions Like someone's gonna take the point.
Speaker 0: I just backed up and the guy kind of got in.
Speaker 0: then I got right up behind him.
Speaker 0: So I didn't have to ever take the point and after a while take the point.
Speaker 0: Yeah after a while they noticed and they all just like sped up way faster than I could possibly go and that was the end Of me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think next year.
Speaker 1: I'll get a faster bike.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well your because I test rode the $5,000 bike on Saturday.
Speaker 1: It is clearly superior.
Speaker 1: The more expensive bike is just better.
Speaker 1: The one thing I didn't realize right so I knew well If you got a faster bike, it's lighter, right?
Speaker 1: It has better gears.
Speaker 1: It has better everything more aerodynamic in the lower position.
Speaker 1: I knew all these things but I still also knew physics.
Speaker 1: right and if you get a faster car It has a bigger engine.
Speaker 1: no matter what bike you get the engine is your legs.
Speaker 1: So there isn't a bigger engine even on the fast even on the better bike.
Speaker 1: How so even if you go to the highest gear on the better bike?
Speaker 1: You still need to be able to turn it and it's just as hard to turn it as it is on the shitty bike.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, they've got a picture on the website of that crazy like fireball machine they had at the start.
Speaker 1: Apparently I was completely wrong on the fancy $5,000 bike.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because it's lighter or because it's better or because of something.
Speaker 1: Yeah with these same legs you can crank the highest gear with less effort.
Speaker 1: Like I cried was in the highest gear and I was like this doesn't have a higher one and I was going really fast.
Speaker 1: But it didn't feel like I was going fast and the bike was perfectly stable and it wasn't hard to pedal as it was As it is to pedal the highest gear on my current bike.
Speaker 0: The only trouble there is that the $5,000 bike is definitely superior.
Speaker 0: I'm not paying Bike but it's only like 5% better.
Speaker 1: I currently have these sub thousand dollar bikes.
Speaker 1: So next year, I'll probably get maybe the one or two thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: You should use a test ride my bike because that's pretty much the top of what you can get Without going to like a crazy road bike.
Speaker 1: I think I have to get the road bike.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think is most of the riding I do.
Speaker 0: I'd rather have a hybrid so I got the best hybrid and if I ever Any time I do like a super long ride, I'm just gonna rent like the $10,000 bike I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't feel comfortable riding a rented bike.
Speaker 1: Why bikes got to be exactly right to you.
Speaker 1: that counts for a lot.
Speaker 0: You rent a bike from a nice place that cost that much money you go in and you like you get it set by a guy Who knows more than you do about bikes?
Speaker 0: Anyway, so we got to talk about this because I didn't think the jury would actually rule today and It's kind of bad news bad news.
Speaker 0: So this is kind of your news.
Speaker 0: You want to take it?
Speaker 1: Yeah So if you don't know there's been a trial going on a sort of civil suit between Oracle and Google and it's because Oracle bought Sun.
Speaker 1: Sun owned Java.
Speaker 1: so now Oracle owns Java.
Speaker 1: kind of right.
Speaker 1: and if you don't know Google uses Java.
Speaker 1: a lot right.
Speaker 1: Google's Google itself is written already.
Speaker 0: You know, this is how it'll be very confusing for people.
Speaker 0: Google uses Java.
Speaker 0: Java could refer to the Java programming language the Java runtime The JDK the development any number of specific Java runtime Java SC enterprise, whatever Java, right?
Speaker 1: So Java the language is like this open source language.
Speaker 1: Mostly right.
Speaker 1: and you know, you can put this all kinds of different JREs and it's not like there's one one.
Speaker 1: That's the one right?
Speaker 1: It's sort of like You know, there's no the C right.
Speaker 1: there is a C standard That's like and if you write in C code in the C standard then any C compiler can compile that C right and There is sort of a Java standard and many things, you know sort of follow it, but it's not set in stone, right?
Speaker 1: You know Android the Java is a little different on Android.
Speaker 1: It's not exactly the same as the other Java's.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now there's also multiple.
Speaker 0: I mean if you install Linux pretty much anywhere you realize the J that Sun Java JRE Java runtime environment is not.
Speaker 1: you mean the Oracle?
Speaker 0: Is not Redistributable.
Speaker 0: So if you buy install like Ubuntu Java's there and it just works That's some ghetto ass like open source like reimplementation of the JRE.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's not the Sun Oracle job.
Speaker 0: And you know what a lot of shit doesn't work on that thing.
Speaker 1: This is confusing even for us, right?
Speaker 0: I only know as much as I do because My company all of our software is written in Java.
Speaker 1: I know as much as I do because even though Java is not my job I did learn it in school and this is something everyone sort of Because it came up in a thread just now in the forum.
Speaker 0: I think I should say this right now unless you have a specific reason to use Java Don't install it on your Windows PC.
Speaker 0: It's just or any PC.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it'll come with words, you know, it's gonna be there already if you install like Ubuntu I guess.
Speaker 0: but if you install a Windows PC don't bother with Java unless you have a specific need.
Speaker 0: it's just a security hole That's right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, because it means that anyone and you visit someone's web page They can now run Java code on your computer, which is usually safe because there are security restrictions on that.
Speaker 1: But there are often security holes.
Speaker 1: they get announced constantly and that's why Java keeps updating constantly to fix them.
Speaker 1: And if you don't update it fast enough and you visit the wrong website now, you're fucked.
Speaker 0: Java also like JIT one six has been the standard for pretty much ever lately and It's end of life.
Speaker 0: where they won't support it anymore is real soon like November soon.
Speaker 0: But most stuff doesn't work on one seven because one seven is not compatible with one six in a lot of ways.
Speaker 0: But anyway, you can see Java is the thorny mess, right?
Speaker 1: So so Oracle had this fight with Google in court.
Speaker 1: They wanted to sue Google for like infringing upon Java copyrights and patents.
Speaker 1: Because you know Google made their own sort of Java for Android and such much like the people who made a Jerry for you know Linux.
Speaker 1: maybe the people who bought Android made that Java and Google bought them but you know Does a lot of their own Java stuff.
Speaker 1: so there's a lot of room there for this to possibly have happened.
Speaker 1: So they went in court and it was funny because early on in the case There were these awesome things where they would show like Google, you know They would.
Speaker 1: they would ask, you know, Larry Ellison was on the stand But the head of guy of Oracle and they were you may remember being hated by most nerds from the 90s onward.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Google would like at.
Speaker 1: the lawyers would ask him questions and then in their presentation They showed videos of him being asked the exact same questions and giving a different answer.
Speaker 1: It was totally a Jon Stewart move in the courtroom, right?
Speaker 1: Where it's like is you know it okay to do this?
Speaker 1: and he'd be like, I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: and then they'd show a video.
Speaker 1: Is it okay to do this?
Speaker 1: and he in the video he you know for of a previous time and date?
Speaker 1: it was the exact same guy saying yes, that is perfectly okay to do that and it's like Okay, so that was pretty much like boom Google's bringing the hammer down in the court and we were feeling pretty good about that.
Speaker 0: So how'd that case turn out?
Speaker 1: Well, it's not a hundred percent done yet, but it's not.
Speaker 1: the look is all good Mario's not happy.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Now it was complicated because the jury last week, you know, you can read all the details We're not.
Speaker 1: we don't know much about the lawyering.
Speaker 1: We're repeating what we have read elsewhere, but basically the jury came up.
Speaker 0: We may send a note to the judge But apparently the jury wasn't even sure among itself whether or not they should send a note to the judge saying look We agree on these things we can't agree on these things.
Speaker 0: What do we do?
Speaker 0: And one thing led to another and they were like, alright, let it go until Monday which is today and then try to make a decision.
Speaker 0: and They mostly made a decision.
Speaker 0: and now Google's move for a mistrial.
Speaker 0: the decisions incomplete all sorts of shenanigans But the trial has been partially decided in favor of Oracle.
Speaker 1: Well, how can which is pretty bad news because someone gets John's stewarded like that, how can you decide in their favor?
Speaker 0: Well the way I see there's one way I can evaluate any case between two big tech companies.
Speaker 0: It's very easy.
Speaker 0: I put them both on a scale, you know one in each hand and I look at them and say which of these companies Do I hate more Oracle?
Speaker 0: Well, then Oracle should lose.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: And if I hate them both equally I want them both to lose in some sort of like pyrrhic victory King Solomon situation.
Speaker 0: Like I want the situation where yes, you win the fight.
Speaker 0: TOS are not enforceable.
Speaker 0: I mean if TOS are or are not enforceable in any absolute sense we win.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: But Yeah, I didn't want Oracle to get anything here because Oracle has been pretty bad for nerds for a long time.
Speaker 1: So yeah, if you are nerd This is actually really important and even if you're not a programmer or technology person Even though you should be because otherwise you can be left behind in this futuristic world of high-tech stuff This will come down and affect you especially you millions of Android phone users.
Speaker 1: You know things could happen there.
Speaker 1: that could be very bad.
Speaker 0: So what it seems to come down to and it's a technicality, but it's one that has far-reaching implications Whether or not APIs are copyrightable.
Speaker 0: now I'm gonna say this right now if the answer from this case ends up being yes, we're fucked.
Speaker 0: that is like a huge epic fucking Upon the large majority of programming in America if not the world.
Speaker 0: Yep Independent of that The the case is also being decided.
Speaker 0: they basically Agreed that Google violated copyright.
Speaker 0: So now Google's trying to argue that they had fair use which was put the part that was undecided.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, here's a the official Google statement from Jim Prosser.
Speaker 1: We appreciate you the Google chief legal guy, right?
Speaker 0: We appreciate I think We appreciate the jury's efforts and we know that fair use and infringement are two sides of the same coin.
Speaker 0: The core issue is whether the API's here are copyrightable and that's for the court to decide.
Speaker 0: We expect to prevail on this issue and Oracle's other claims.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm This is I don't have anything else to say.
Speaker 0: you can read all these details and I'm not a lawyer.
Speaker 0: So the more I say I edge toward our lawyer friends calling me and being like no, it's not how it works Mm-hmm It's bad news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the this is far worse in the long run than all that Piracy CISPA CBD tPA kind of stuff you guys complain about.
Speaker 1: Any news from you?
Speaker 0: I have some news.
Speaker 0: I got a bunch of little stuff.
Speaker 0: I want to talk about great.
Speaker 0: So Verizon's gonna start allowing people on their networks in that over the next year to send a text to 911.
Speaker 1: Hooray.
Speaker 0: most of the news coverage I've seen on this are people flipping out and making jokes about texting or saying that Texting is something stupid.
Speaker 0: kids do we shouldn't dumb down, you know, basically everyone's arguing that this somehow Trivializes 9-1-1.
Speaker 1: if I have a heart attack and I can't really talk and I need to but I can sort of move my hand.
Speaker 0: What if I'm deaf?
Speaker 0: What if I'm witnessing a robbery and if I call?
Speaker 1: no, this is a deaf.
Speaker 1: There's a TTY 9-1-1, but still what?
Speaker 0: What if I'm witnessing a robbery and if I pick up my phone and go yo dog someone's getting robbed the robber might notice me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can just text really quickly and discreetly without being noticed.
Speaker 1: texting 9-1-1 is awesome.
Speaker 1: I don't know why we don't have it already.
Speaker 1: I know we should have had it a long time ago like Ten plus years ago.
Speaker 1: I'm sure other countries probably have it where everyone texts.
Speaker 0: We should have an email I think - we should have an everything.
Speaker 1: you should be able to use any form of communication available To call 9-1-1 except maybe yelling.
Speaker 1: that's a little unreasonable to expect to expect yelling to work.
Speaker 0: Well Scott if we let Big Brother have cameras and microphones everywhere
Speaker 1: There it we could set up a system where you know if I'm fine if it's on you know Public property where you know somehow you can yell and not help help and 9-1-1 will actually work and figure out Hey someone's.
Speaker 1: yeah That might be a stretch Some listening device where you can yell a certain thing and then it will know that someone is yelling that certain thing at this Intersection and then people will be deployed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is mocking Jays will happen.
Speaker 0: I know yeah, I don't think we need it.
Speaker 0: But all I can say is I think this is great.
Speaker 0: I think this should have been a standard decade ago plus and Anyone who trivializes this or tries to argue against it is a moron.
Speaker 0: You know what is one argument anything if you don't so I got it can be made against this.
Speaker 1: if you don't want 9-1-1 texting to be a thing then if anyone texts 9-1-1 and they show up and you're one of those people you don't get help They'll just turn around.
Speaker 1: go home.
Speaker 0: well There is one argument that can be made against this.
Speaker 0: I think it's a fairly poor argument, but it can be made.
Speaker 0: I just want to get this out here.
Speaker 0: so if you think you're against this the only argument you can make is that SMS is by definition unreliable and it's not guaranteed your Message will get anywhere in a timely fashion.
Speaker 0: better than my counter argument is one what Scott just said and two if We implement a text to 9-1-1 feature.
Speaker 0: We can implement QoS to where if you text 9-1-1 it gets precedence in the network.
Speaker 1: We can do that too.
Speaker 1: problem solved, you know 9-1-1 texts are a lot like UDP jokes.
Speaker 1: I don't care if you get them or not.
Speaker 0: You should have just not said anything and continued.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I got.
Speaker 0: well, I got one really controversial thing.
Speaker 0: I want to talk about and then Controversy don't do this time on cross geek.
Speaker 0: So there was an article on semantics like internet security threat report and a bunch of people have been commenting on it.
Speaker 0: the gist of this is that religious and Technological websites have far more security threats per year than Pornographic sites pretty much across the board.
Speaker 0: That is not unexpected I know but a lot of people are again mostly non tech people freaking out about this and it harken back to a conversation I had with Emily and some people not that long ago.
Speaker 0: I was explaining to a whole bunch of people that The most dangerous websites you can visit in terms of malware are not the scary porn sites.
Speaker 0: It's MIDI files song lyrics and cursors.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah.
Speaker 1: So basically what it comes down to is obviously whoever did this research if it was real research even and not just a made-up thing Right, but semantics.
Speaker 0: so I give it a 50/50 shot, right?
Speaker 1: Is that they only looked at these two categories?
Speaker 1: But in fact, these are just subsets of larger categories.
Speaker 1: The fact is this websites run by technology professionals have fewer vulnerabilities than websites set up by some schmo Right.
Speaker 1: What do you think sets up the local churches website some?
Speaker 1: Outsores local guy who sets up crappy restaurant.
Speaker 0: Well, I know the security vulnerabilities.
Speaker 1: This is actively on some crappy managed hosting running some old ass who knows what.
Speaker 0: but this is Actively bad software attacking people who visit the sites injected usually via ads, right?
Speaker 1: It's somebody who set up the website set it up real shitty like and then somebody else came and it put Evil things in that site that were you know, not the person who said at the site up the church people didn't put it There.
Speaker 1: someone else put it there because the site was so shitty that someone else right.
Speaker 1: meanwhile porn sites are run by You know, at least the big ones especially well a friend of ours have to be capable of delivering lots and lots of videos.
Speaker 0: God, you may recall and a certain friend of ours ran a porn site at our IT.
Speaker 0: He was technologically fisticated.
Speaker 1: but most porn sites are run by highly technologically sophisticated people Even if they don't look like they are well porn sites As a business and have a vested interest in not fucking their customers, that's right.
Speaker 1: So they definitely want to pop up all kinds of ads on you and shit like that and some of them want to infect You know purposefully infest you with viruses and such.
Speaker 1: but our people who look at porn know which sites are good And which ones aren't good.
Speaker 1: and if their site gets all virus there, you know browser gets all virus coming to your site.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna come there again.
Speaker 0: So I give to you right now a very easy way to tell if a site is likely to be dangerous if it has Universal or very mass appeal to a demographic of people over the age of 45.
Speaker 0: Yep, and is something generic and probably non-copyrightable.
Speaker 0: If an example a website that has cursors for your computer puppy wallpapers Yep, that puppy wallpapers is probably the worst possible site you could ever visit.
Speaker 1: iPhone wallpapers free.
Speaker 1: iPhone free.
Speaker 0: iPad free anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much, you know any song lyrics.
Speaker 0: because song lyrics are not you can't just legally put them up because of copyright BS Which I don't want to get into that argument.
Speaker 0: so one the only people who post song lyrics in any sort of database or archive are usually overseas and dodgy anyway, and two Song lyrics are super searched for by teeny boppers and older people pretty much any non-technologically savvy people.
Speaker 1: pretty much any website that was set up, you know e greeting cards anything that was set up either Intentionally by some you know, you're gonna have the intentional virus, you know Put there by the website creator and the kind of site rim is talking about but also the websites that are run by people who?
Speaker 1: Are not technology experts are likely to have the virus put there by someone else who didn't create the website Attacking the website and installing a virus in it that then hits all the visitors.
Speaker 1: So you got to watch out for both kinds.
Speaker 0: So things of the day.
Speaker 0: a long time ago we had a thing of the day that was a very apt succinct and wonderful explanation of how a Differential gear works like a differential in a car.
Speaker 1: That's a great thing of the day.
Speaker 0: so in that spirit, I found a very similar video for something a little more complex and I'm not gonna do many more of these but I'm trying to put together a compilation of the best of these and maybe make a tumbler.
Speaker 0: So this is a similar explanation made by the military for the military in the u.s.
Speaker 0: On how fluid couplings work.
Speaker 0: now, you might think Ram.
Speaker 0: Why do I care about a fluid coupling?
Speaker 0: Well, that's how automatic transmissions work sort of.
Speaker 1: I didn't even really know so much about fluid couplings But now I feel like I know everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you ever wonder why you can just have your car idling, you know, I know I don't know everything.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty cool video and actually it does a similar job in terms of Demonstrating the principle and then like ramping it up and ramping it up then getting to the real application.
Speaker 0: I want to make modern like technological Demonstration explanation videos about complex computer concepts in this style with this narration.
Speaker 1: The thing is you can't it's really hard.
Speaker 0: Move the glow to the menu item on the left.
Speaker 1: Sure click on the glow All right, so here's another is the thing of the day this thing of the day.
Speaker 1: sure this is one of those What's it called super cuts because well, they're easy to grab and this one's pretty great.
Speaker 1: This is every Emotional breakdown in all Phoenix Wright games.
Speaker 0: Oh, man
Speaker 1: every time one of those characters goes doo doo doo doo doo doo doo and they're going oh my god and tearing their hair out or Exploding or pounding their hair against the wall or you know Punching themselves or making crazy faces or their radios that are exploding or whatever.
Speaker 1: It's all of those in a big string.
Speaker 1: It's pretty epic.
Speaker 1: It also spoils all the Phoenix rights, but whatever it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: It's awesome, and I kind of want to play some Phoenix, right?
Speaker 1: but there hasn't been a new one and I heard the next one's gonna be 3ds only.
Speaker 0: so Thing is there's no Phoenix right right now and there's no advance Wars.
Speaker 0: So Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: hey you can relive the olden days.
Speaker 1: maybe remember what Phoenix Wright was all about if you play this shit Let me watch this video.
Speaker 0: So in the meta moment this weekend Saturday only though the con is Friday and Saturday.
Speaker 0: We will be at Zenkai con.
Speaker 0: We will be there doing two presentations.
Speaker 0: we'll be doing how ponies and dude bro can take over the internet at 3 o'clock and then at 530 we'll be doing motivational anime.
Speaker 1: ponies haven't already taken over the internet.
Speaker 0: When I put this in and suggested it they hadn't completely taken over the internet yet.
Speaker 0: Okay now they pretty much have.
Speaker 0: And outside of those things we will pretty much be hanging out at the con Playing board games talking to people.
Speaker 0: if you want to say hi This is pretty much your best con to actually come up to us and say hi Ask Scott for an autograph.
Speaker 0: He loves that shit.
Speaker 1: No sure.
Speaker 1: I don't know why you'd want it.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 1: So that the book club book is 1 q 8 4 by Haruki Murakami.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure if is.
Speaker 1: Is it supposed to be 1 q 8 4 1 q 84 or?
Speaker 0: Why don't you tell me you teen 84 or?
Speaker 1: 1,000 q hundred and eighty four Right, but whatever You should read it because the book club book also Recent book club books have been relatively small and short.
Speaker 1: This is a long manly book or womanly book.
Speaker 1: It is for adults.
Speaker 1: It is like 900 something pages hard babies.
Speaker 1: That's right, baby.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Read a book not a sports page or a magazine or young adult novel or you should read I want my hat back But don't make that the only thing you read.
Speaker 1: That's actually sort of less than a sports page also in July better than a sports page in July.
Speaker 0: Connecticut.
Speaker 0: in Hartford, Connecticut We run the panels workshops.
Speaker 0: department submissions are pretty much closed and full.
Speaker 0: But if you have a really good idea for a panel workshop or a lecture Go ahead and submit it on the website.
Speaker 0: If it's good enough.
Speaker 0: I might bite bump something.
Speaker 0: I've already tentatively scheduled.
Speaker 0: However, every hour that you wait means it's less likely I will accept your submission.
Speaker 0: All right, and if you submit it After May well, you're not getting in pretty much no matter what happens.
Speaker 1: Also, I've mentioned in a while, you know, we are on the internet.
Speaker 1: The internet is the thing.
Speaker 1: We are very internet people.
Speaker 1: we're on there.
Speaker 1: So if you have Facebook or Google+ or Twitter or just website RSS or iTunes or any other thing you can imagine We are on that thing.
Speaker 1: There's even some fan even made like a Windows 7 app, right?
Speaker 1: So if you like geek nights, you should get whatever thing geek nights is follow like whatever it is.
Speaker 1: Do that if you want to.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna make you and I just want to make kind of a super meta note.
Speaker 0: we recorded a little bit ahead because I'm going to Turkey for a while and In the upcoming Tuesday episode we say something to the effect of you should have bought a packs badge And if you didn't well, haha.
Speaker 0: But we may recorded that episode before the badges went back online and sold out within like an hour.
Speaker 0: So it sounds a little mean they were not sold out as of the time when we did that show.
Speaker 1: just saying but our advice Still stands.
Speaker 1: if you wanted a packs badge You should have listened to our advice and bought one immediately and I don't know why people don't listen to our advice.
Speaker 0: Apparently this time the problem is people did listen to our advice and as a result packed sold out immediately.
Speaker 1: But there were still other people who did not listen to our advice and then complain.
Speaker 0: Scott If it sells out immediately then enough people have heeded the advice.
Speaker 0: to where that's it?
Speaker 1: You have to heed the advice of being just like us and being attached to the internet all the time so that you are the First guy no matter what.
Speaker 0: Ah, that doesn't always work.
Speaker 0: I point out that Otacon and kinetic ons artist allies, even if you are sitting there Manually running was watching a w get scrubbed constantly refreshing.
Speaker 0: You might not get one once it goes live because the sheer number of people trying to get one and limited quantity.
Speaker 1: I guess we have a lot of practice registering for classes at RIT so I would try to bring SAS or whatever.
Speaker 0: It was called down.
Speaker 0: Here's what I should do.
Speaker 0: I said I tried to sin flood it one year so I could crash it hoping that by the time it rebooted I'd be the only one still trying.
Speaker 1: So what you should do is you should practice doing something like buying concert tickets on Ticketmaster or some shit like that And you can actually make.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of people do that as their job, right?
Speaker 0: We should do this on a Tuesday show but I'll put it bluntly or easily if you want to get badges or artist alley tables Or anything like this find out what the maxes you can get and have a bunch of friends who are watching.
Speaker 0: if Any one of you gets in first have an agreement that you will buy the max for your friends.
Speaker 0: Hmm now if and as soon as you do this immediately, you know tweet and call your friends milk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got him.
Speaker 0: Did you get him?
Speaker 0: and on the off chance that you get some extras and because it's so hard to get them It's unlikely that all of you will get a full loadout of extras.
Speaker 1: Even if you do you can easily sell them.
Speaker 0: Yep, you should probably sell them at list price or you're slightly douchey Depends it's got.
Speaker 0: it's okay to scalp.
Speaker 0: However in a technical sense However, you're being a dick when you do it for an event like packs.
Speaker 1: I think that's just because the past community pushes down on you.
Speaker 1: I actually don't have any moral problem with it.
Speaker 1: You purchase a good that is in high demand and low supply and you own that good.
Speaker 1: and is your transfer right to transfer that Good, you should get the maximum money you can get for that good, but Scott I have the alternate argument that packs is deeply artificially discounted for a lot of specific reasons.
Speaker 1: It's not my problem.
Speaker 0: So you didn't.
Speaker 0: I said it's perfectly morally okay to do it.
Speaker 1: However, you're kind of a dick if you do it Stupid if you don't because you just gave away a bunch of free money.
Speaker 1: I was if I had an extra pegs badge I just give it away to someone who really needed it might give it away in a contest or Something, you know, but I definitely wouldn't just sell it at list price.
Speaker 1: That'd be bleh lame.
Speaker 0: Well, I would sell it to someone I knew at list price.
Speaker 0: Maybe give it away to someone I knew a little better maybe But anyway, so this was your show your idea, right?
Speaker 1: So I feel like we've discussed this on the show as do
Speaker 0: I in
Speaker 1: the past but despite great amounts of searching I could not find a show on this specific topic on its own even though I think we've discussed parts of subsets of it You know, which we will rediscuss today.
Speaker 1: Also, if we even if we did the show, I don't think it was very well listened to or remembered It's an interesting topic and we have no other Monday ideas.
Speaker 1: So Let us discuss security vulnerabilities, but specifically security vulnerabilities in websites and to people who visit websites since that is most of what would people do with computers these days and the vast majority Of security problems in the world these days are these kinds now?
Speaker 0: We're not gonna talk about stuff that is related to that but not kind of germane like for example Trojans.
Speaker 0: if you download if you download an executable file and run it with elevated privileges.
Speaker 0: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: You're already too far gone It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: That's it Alright, so let's let's just get right into it, right?
Speaker 1: so the first thing which I definitely know we've discussed on the show in the past is Injection attacks SQL injection, right?
Speaker 0: Usually SQL injection, but could there could be other injections, you know, Johnny Single per single quote drop tables.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: So let's say, you know, you've got this website and there's a search on the website.
Speaker 1: So if you type in I want to search for geek nights, right?
Speaker 1: What does the server do?
Speaker 1: it says?
Speaker 1: Select from the table where the disc title contains the word geek nights Quote semicolon.
Speaker 1: Well, what if instead of typing in geek nights you type in?
Speaker 1: geek nights quote semicolon Select drop drop tables drop Right all kinds of other evil things.
Speaker 1: Well now what happens is the web server takes that and instead of you know Normally put the word geek nights it now puts the word geek nights and also a whole bunch of other evil stuff And it actually does all the evil stuff because it's a stupidly written web application.
Speaker 0: so how do we get around this?
Speaker 1: because this is a Surprisingly large number of websites are still affected by this In fact, most of those shitty ones run by churches and such.
Speaker 0: it's for certain kinds of input.
Speaker 0: It's very easy to sanitize your input But a lot of the obvious ways to sanitize or clean up input are Relying upon things like JavaScript.
Speaker 0: like in the browser It'll see you type like commas and things and remove them or encapsulate.
Speaker 1: Yeah That doesn't work because I don't have to run that JavaScript Exiled to say yeah disable the JavaScript or I'll just won't even visit your website in my browser.
Speaker 1: I'll just use curl and send stuff to your server.
Speaker 1: Yep All your security.
Speaker 1: you need super security on the back and the front.
Speaker 1: You can't rely on the front to protect the back or the back to protect what.
Speaker 0: there's a particular one for XML.
Speaker 0: It's called like the million lulls or the billion lulls Where if you're if someone's sending you XML you can define XML such that it'll basically expand and take up all your RAM while you try to parse it Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And how do you validate against that if it's a relatively small set of XML in terms of number of characters?
Speaker 0: That and you're expecting XML.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: See when you write a website, you've got these two parts the JavaScript part in the browser in the HTML and the CSS and the server and these are actually You.
Speaker 1: you have to consider these things to be two programs that talk to each other Right and they where it is.
Speaker 0: It's called the billion laughs.
Speaker 0: It has a whole Wikipedia page dedicated to it.
Speaker 1: Both of these applications have to be secure.
Speaker 1: and what's?
Speaker 1: to make it even more complicated?
Speaker 1: that front end that HTML JavaScript CSS Application is written is partially rewritten by the server and then so the server actually Generates a program Even though some of it isn't generated.
Speaker 1: but it generates a program sends that program to your browser Your browser runs that program that program then talks to the server which then generates more programs and sends them to your browser to be Executed.
Speaker 1: it's crazy.
Speaker 1: And that's why it's hard to get exactly right.
Speaker 1: but if you use a modern web framework instead of just writing your website from scratch or if you actually have technologically intelligent people writing your website This is Injection is so easy to not have because what just happens is every single quote that's coming over the line Gets back slashes in front of it the correct number of them and then the back slashes are removed at the appropriate times and added At the appropriate times.
Speaker 1: It's a solved problem.
Speaker 1: And if you do that Then if someone tries to search for geek nights blah blah blah drop tables Then what will happen is they'll find every article that has the words geek nights drop tables blah blah blah in it.
Speaker 1: They won't find any articles and nothing bad will happen.
Speaker 0: I guess the point is to simplify it.
Speaker 0: if you're trying to catch all these things on your own by thinking about them You're gonna miss something.
Speaker 1: you're doing it wrong.
Speaker 0: You've got to use a framework like there are XML Validation engines whose sole job is to validate XML based on other schema you define to figure out.
Speaker 1: All of these problems have been solved and if you try to solve them again on your own You will fail in some aspect.
Speaker 1: most of the time these Vulnerabilities are cosmic people using old software or their own software instead of the tried-and-true software.
Speaker 1: Right and not updating it or something.
Speaker 0: Scott this billion laughs.
Speaker 0: XML bomb is actually pretty funny now that I'm looking at it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, entity lol has a test string of lol.
Speaker 0: Entity lol.
Speaker 0: one is a set of ten instances of lol.
Speaker 0: lol.
Speaker 0: two is ten instances of lol one Etc till you've got like nine of these and then it's just lol nine in lol's tags.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Whatever you do and you're making a website make sure you use things that our people have written.
Speaker 1: use open SSH use open SSL.
Speaker 1: use some framework like Ruby on Rails or Django or you know symphony or any of those web frameworks that already has a bunch of code written.
Speaker 0: so Scott a buzzword that is out there a lot and We once a long time got a forum that was actually vulnerable to this sort of thing is cross scripting attacks Cross-site scripting attacks.
Speaker 0: Well, you can have interest site scripting attacks.
Speaker 0: Like we had two forums.
Speaker 1: Oh you could.
Speaker 1: yeah, we had two forums.
Speaker 0: They're both vanilla a long long time ago.
Speaker 0: You guys probably wouldn't even know that other forum that we ran.
Speaker 0: But and it's not the one that had the old geek nights on it It's a third other old forum, but I digress they were on the same site But they were both vanilla and it was pretty trivial Taking a cookie from one to get access to stuff.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't have gotten on the other one by making user.
Speaker 1: Well, that's actually slightly different.
Speaker 1: That is a subset of a cross-site scripting attack known as the cross-site request forgery.
Speaker 1: It is but I'll get to that.
Speaker 1: Let us talk about cross-site scripting attack, right?
Speaker 1: So every web browser every major web browser at least and you would be stupid not to use a major web browser Has this thing called.
Speaker 1: I think it's that only the exact word for it, but basically it's the same domain.
Speaker 1: Guarantee, right?
Speaker 1: I think there's an actual term for it.
Speaker 1: But basically what it does is Firefox.
Speaker 1: let's say you have Firefox right and you go to a website and that website includes some JavaScripts from some other website.
Speaker 1: Those JavaScripts on the other website aren't going to be allowed to really do anything because they're from some other website.
Speaker 1: They're gonna be severely limited if not completely disabled.
Speaker 1: Right because it only trusts things from the website that you're on.
Speaker 1: So if you're on google.com and there's some shady JavaScripts trying to load from front-recruiter.com Your browser is just not even gonna do those JavaScripts.
Speaker 1: They're just not gonna happen because obviously that's a no-no, right?
Speaker 1: And even if let's say the JavaScript that Google gives you tries to do something to front-recruiter.com, right?
Speaker 1: So the Google JavaScript tries to grab the front page of front-recruiter.com and load it up That's probably not gonna work.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 0: So it's got.
Speaker 0: why do we block this sort of thing?
Speaker 0: Like why do browsers block it?
Speaker 1: Because then it would be it would be trivially easy to do all sorts of evil goodies.
Speaker 0: For example, well here I visit my Facebook and I got a cookie.
Speaker 0: I'm authenticated and then I visit a bad website and it runs JavaScript that figures that I'm logged into Facebook and at least my profile.
Speaker 1: Yep, that can happen.
Speaker 1: BAM.
Speaker 1: So how does one of these things actually get through?
Speaker 1: Well, there are ways to do this on purpose that work like such as JSONP and I'm not gonna go into the details of that.
Speaker 1: But basically it's let's say I have two domains.
Speaker 1: They both belong to me.
Speaker 1: I own them.
Speaker 1: I want one of them to hit the other one.
Speaker 1: So let's say I own Twitter and I own front-recruiter.com and I want you when you visit front-recruiter.com To have like this little Twitter thing happening in the middle of the page.
Speaker 1: I need to be able to have the JavaScript talk to twitter.com.
Speaker 1: I can make it happen if I jump through the right hoops legit-like and that's okay.
Speaker 1: But those same hoops can be sometimes forced Unlegit, and that's not okay.
Speaker 1: So usually the way this happens is let's say you got a forum right and someone makes a post in the forum And they post some JavaScript in their forum post.
Speaker 1: Usually the forum should be removing the JavaScript from the forum post But sometimes an old stupid PHP VV from 100 years ago isn't gonna do that.
Speaker 0: yep, like it'll have a blacklist of things you can't use and Blacklists don't work for security.
Speaker 0: No kidding.
Speaker 1: So what happens is now everyone else who reads that forum thread This JavaScript that they're getting is actually coming from the same domain as the forum Which mean that JavaScript can do what it wants.
Speaker 1: and now that JavaScript is a no-good JavaScript that I put there Not the person who made the forum.
Speaker 1: JavaScript doesn't care That's right, so now suddenly it's doing all sorts of nasty shit.
Speaker 1: So everyone who visits this website is executing this bad bad JavaScript Vulnerabilities like that happened in the earlier days of Facebook.
Speaker 0: They've happened in a lot of mediocre forums.
Speaker 0: There were things.
Speaker 1: yeah Even the biggest websites are vulnerable to this shit and you have to be extra super careful Right not to have it now If you don't know better.
Speaker 0: again aside from using you know standard platforms and protocols and using like real frameworks Generally don't let people use anything other than basic HTML on anything public.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is why you'll see on a lot of websites like Wikipedia makes you write things in wiki language.
Speaker 0: And well, that's also because wiki language is kind of standard and it's not what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: It's that you've got other websites.
Speaker 1: they you know, they don't let you comment in HTML.
Speaker 1: they make you use pH, you know the BB code or some other kind of language or markdown or something like that.
Speaker 1: because You know the parsers for those languages will remove all sorts of evilness and you won't be able to type any JavaScripts or HTMLs in those through those parsers and actually get it made to the other end.
Speaker 1: You're just limited to the things that a user should be limited to like bold make a link Make it put an image there and that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: You can't do anything else.
Speaker 1: if you're allowed to freely post HTML and JavaScript you could put all sorts of evilness in there.
Speaker 0: So what about?
Speaker 0: because a common?
Speaker 0: Problem or a common place people get malware is not websites themselves, but the ads hosted on those websites bought from shady people.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm You can't.
Speaker 0: protecting against those is pretty much the same as protecting against, you know actual problems on the right side itself.
Speaker 1: This is number one reason right if you're a web user Even if you are one of those people who really believes that you should look at ads because it makes money for the person You should use adblock to protect yourself from evil.
Speaker 1: And here's why right a lot of people run a website and they run ads, but they don't.
Speaker 1: actually some people You know manually sell their ads like go arcade like penny arcade.
Speaker 1: penny arcade says send us a JPEG and we will make an ad For you, but other people just say, you know they might use an ad network and that and then people will bid on that ad network and put ads on this person's website and That person doesn't even know what those ads are.
Speaker 1: They just put a spot on their website They sell that spot to someone and then ads just appear there.
Speaker 1: They don't don't even know what ads are gonna be there.
Speaker 1: They come from somewhere.
Speaker 0: if you are running a website do not do that.
Speaker 0: No this is trivial to get around.
Speaker 0: only get ads from like Google Adsense or something reasonably safe and even then Google Adsense could be Compromised.
Speaker 0: it could be but at least if you go with a legitimate ad provider You're probably a lot less likely to get caught.
Speaker 0: and if you get caught you're in the same boat as a thousand other people Right, but if you get some shady porn guy or some shady religious website guy or online gambling.
Speaker 1: Yep What's gonna happen is basically a web advertisement spot like that, right?
Speaker 1: A lot of them have JavaScript and flash and all these things.
Speaker 1: they need to work Right or tracking so that they know how many users visited the ad.
Speaker 1: so the ads that are on your site get all these privileges That normally they would not get because they need those things for the ads to function because they have.
Speaker 1: you know They're very, you know functionality wise they're very interactive and all this kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: So some guy puts an ad on your website in that spot that you open to the world that anyone could buy.
Speaker 1: He buys it with money legitimately and in that spot He puts some nasty JavaScripts and flashes and those flashes do all sorts of evil things to everyone who visits your site and loads that ad.
Speaker 1: and now You look like a bad guy.
Speaker 1: But really you're just dumb.
Speaker 1: and you sold your ads.
Speaker 1: you sold part of your website to someone and they put bad news there.
Speaker 1: That's like saying hey, I got a banana stand.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you what, dude I'll only make 75% of the bananas the rest of the 25% of the banana.
Speaker 1: You can fill that in with whatever you want.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm gonna fill it with cyanide.
Speaker 1: Hahahaha.
Speaker 1: That's what happens.
Speaker 1: So yeah before I was mentioning the cross site request forgery Which is sort of a subset of the cross site scripting attack, right?
Speaker 1: it's sometimes pronounced CSRF because that is or XSRF or CSRF or People call it all kinds of things.
Speaker 1: I tend to say the whole thing and basically here's how it works.
Speaker 1: Right when you visit a website you get this session, right?
Speaker 1: And that's how you sort of stay logged in.
Speaker 0: remember the OSI model.
Speaker 0: We talked about years ago.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's in that You can guess where based on the names.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's right.
Speaker 1: So what happens is is that you go to one website and you sort of have a session there, right?
Speaker 1: And you you know make a request to that website get and your browser will only you know Allow it to see cookies that that website's allowed to see including your session cookie and such like that.
Speaker 1: All right So you go to some other website, right?
Speaker 1: And this website, you know will be able to trick You or your browser into thinking that you're actually visiting Website 2 and then do things as if you're visiting website 2 and as if you were logged into website 2, right?
Speaker 1: So this my website like my browser has a Facebook session cookie and Facebook It only allows facebook.com to see that session cookie, right?
Speaker 1: So this means that if it wants to do something as me on Facebook this other website can't do that because it can't see that cookie.
Speaker 1: It's not allowed to see that cookie, right?
Speaker 1: No permissions.
Speaker 1: but What happens is someone did this vulnerability a while back.
Speaker 1: It was very clever.
Speaker 1: They load a little iframe and in that iframe is Facebook.
Speaker 1: So then that iframe is basically a whole nother web page, right?
Speaker 1: Okay So that little tiny iframe is a lot.
Speaker 1: as gets my Facebook session ID.
Speaker 1: This still doesn't really help them though because Facebook's in the iframe They can't really get anything in there or get anything out of there.
Speaker 1: so much, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like, okay It's no different than really if I loaded Facebook in another tab and their website in another tab.
Speaker 1: They can't really do anything on my behalf on Facebook, right?
Speaker 1: Well, actually they can sort of use JavaScript to force you to click in that little area or They can do a JavaScript like hey if he clicks here move his mouse and then click and do stuff like that.
Speaker 0: So now the old horrible windows days of things that would have a window that popped up.
Speaker 0: You could never get the close button.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: So they could do that to you.
Speaker 1: and now suddenly You've clicked on this like button that you didn't even know was there.
Speaker 1: that was in an iframe and suddenly you'd like something different That you didn't know you liked.
Speaker 1: you think you clicked this like button, but you actually clicked that like button.
Speaker 1: Oh No Right, there's other things that you can do.
Speaker 1: For example, like you could send someone an email Alright, and then in the email would be something evil, but they read that email with webmail Alright, and now so you're on gmail.com.
Speaker 1: There's an email there.
Speaker 1: Gmail is very smart about removing this kind of evil stuff.
Speaker 1: But let's say you're using a bad another one like, you know squirrel mail or something, you know, you go there and You know, there's something evil in the email that's now running on the domain of the your web email provider.
Speaker 1: bad news bad news Right.
Speaker 1: You've also got to worry about things such as you know images right like you're allowed to hotlink images.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Google image search is actually kind of Dangerous in some ways though.
Speaker 0: It's gotten better because a lot of if you search for generic things It'll one take you to websites full of crazy malware And to the images themselves.
Speaker 0: if you click on the link could have bad stuff around them.
Speaker 1: But here's the real trick right?
Speaker 1: So the way browsers work is if there's an image tag, right?
Speaker 1: It doesn't care if it's from a different domain.
Speaker 1: it loads that.
Speaker 1: if I do IMG SRC equals google.com.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna see anything on the web page where that image is supposed to be But the browser is still gonna load google.com even though I visited frontrecruit.com.
Speaker 0: Now the simplest exploit there is really simple.
Speaker 0: you can you.
Speaker 0: for example You could find out if someone visited a page By making a or find out their IP address or find out all sorts of things by having an image Somewhere that they will load and then you see the IP it was loaded from.
Speaker 0: you know was loaded.
Speaker 1: So for example, I can go into your forum right and I can do IMG SRC equals Facebook.com slash a whole bunch of stuff like frontrecruit.com slash.
Speaker 1: so now anyone who visits that page who is logged into Facebook Upon loading that image in quotes, right?
Speaker 1: They will actually be liking me.
Speaker 1: Everyone who visit that page likes me.
Speaker 0: now browsers aren't that stupid.
Speaker 1: They're not that stupid as it used to be but it's still.
Speaker 1: It could happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you have to be more clever about it.
Speaker 0: You can't just be like IMG.
Speaker 0: SRC equals link to my like button and it'll work.
Speaker 1: It won't work Yep, but basically it's you're trying to trick the browser into somehow Using or telling you about cookies from other domains that don't belong to you so that you know.
Speaker 1: frontrecruit.com tricks your browser into telling it your Facebook session ID Now or getting your browser to use that session ID on its behalf and what happens is now Frontrecruit.com can basically do anything you could do when you were logged into Facebook and pretend to be you on Facebook post tweet Whatever it's gonna do and it's bad news
Speaker 0: now in terms of visiting websites and then I guess we can wrap this up.
Speaker 0: We've gone on a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was you know, the brouhaha some time ago about fire sheep but basically it came down to the fact that in the old days you had a hub or a big like shared land where you Could see other people's traffic and sniffing other people's traffic.
Speaker 0: if it's not encrypted It's trivial to get their credentials and authenticate and do whatever you want Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So we moved to mostly switch networks and then that ceased to be a problem.
Speaker 0: But then we started having public Wi-Fi everywhere.
Speaker 0: Public Wi-Fi is like one of those big public lands.
Speaker 0: You can see what people are sending and if they encrypt their stuff.
Speaker 0: In most implementations you can also see that stuff because you're using similar cryptography to connect to the same.
Speaker 1: Well if they encrypt it, right?
Speaker 1: So there's different encryptions are talking about here.
Speaker 0: So if they're using wire like encryption at the access point then Y can see it.
Speaker 1: We're all connected to the same Wi-Fi and we're all using WPA.
Speaker 1: that is encryption.
Speaker 1: Right and you need that passphrase to get connected to the router to encrypt things properly.
Speaker 0: But if I go one step further and I'm using SSL, I'm safe because I have my own layer of encryption, right?
Speaker 1: So it's actually encrypted twice.
Speaker 1: It's encrypted with SSL and then it's encrypted with WPA.
Speaker 1: So if you decrypt the WPA, which you can do because you're on the same Wi-Fi You know how to decrypt that you end up with a whole bunch of ink stuff That's encrypted by SSL that you can't decrypt and you go fuck me.
Speaker 0: So the reason I bring this up is very simple if you're on any sort of public wireless or untrusted network don't visit websites that have authentication that don't use SSL and if you get a warning about a certificate from a major site like Amazon or Google I doubt their actual certificate is bad You're probably being attacked.
Speaker 1: In fact, if you get a warning about a bad certificate ever You should not visit that website period.
Speaker 1: Well, what about if it's a site that you're logged into?
Speaker 0: What about a self-signed certificate from a?
Speaker 1: you are the person who did it and you know it.
Speaker 1: then you can do it.
Speaker 1: or if It's like your friend and you know, they did it.
Speaker 0: What if it's a dodgy site that you know is dodgy?
Speaker 0: if it's done.
Speaker 1: Why are you going there?
Speaker 0: It's well say it's a dodgy site or it's a site that doesn't.
Speaker 1: don't go there.
Speaker 0: It's dodgy Yeah, but you don't care if you get to it.
Speaker 0: You just want to access it.
Speaker 1: virtual machine.
Speaker 0: Accepting that self-signed certificate in most cases will not hurt you unless the site you accepted it from tries to fuck you Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I think the last thing is that you know, I just tried this thing out.
Speaker 1: It's the Pirate Bay offers it.
Speaker 1: It's called I predator.
Speaker 1: It costs $22 or three months.
Speaker 1: It's a different price in Europe, but whatever and the way it works is this it's a VPN.
Speaker 1: So you get a username and a password and you connect to the VPN.
Speaker 1: you can connect from your phone You can connect from your computer you can connect whatever and this will encrypt all of your internet traffic Period all of it and it will basically make a connection between your computer All the way to the Pirate Bay's computer the I predator computer and it'll be encrypted the entire way and then the I predator computer.
Speaker 1: The rest of the connection will be from there to wherever it's going.
Speaker 1: So if you don't use SSL, right, for example, if I just visit frontrecruit.com, which is not SSL protected It would be in my traffic would be encrypted from me all the way up to the Pirate Bay computer.
Speaker 1: Then it would be as normal From that computer to frontrecruit.com and then as normal back to the and then can crypt it all the way back to me.
Speaker 0: Now I point out there is one potential vulnerability here.
Speaker 0: You have to trust the Pirate Bay.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: I think I trust them.
Speaker 1: I trust him pretty well Right, but basically if you don't trust them even my SSL stuff.
Speaker 1: Okay, so use SSL.
Speaker 1: It's encrypted triply going to the Pirate Bay then it's still encrypted doubly going to where it's supposed to go From this tunnel I then connect to Tor.
Speaker 1: Right, you know you can do all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: The thing with this is it's $20 to three months.
Speaker 1: It's a bargain.
Speaker 1: It protects you from the fire sheep completely.
Speaker 1: if using open Wi-Fi You can only use it on one device at a time.
Speaker 1: So if I'm using it on my laptop I can't use it on my phone simultaneously.
Speaker 1: I have to.
Speaker 1: I have to turn it off on my laptop then turn it on on my phone or I can pay for it twice or three Times or I can get it to work on a router.
Speaker 1: But then it doesn't protect you under the router.
Speaker 1: it only protects you above the router and such and such.
Speaker 1: But what I've you I've been using it for a little while now and they don't charge you based on usage.
Speaker 1: There's no reason not to always use it.
Speaker 1: So I always use it also.
Speaker 1: Well, there is one reason not to always use it which is bandwidth right.
Speaker 1: the bandwidth on it as far as I can tell is Fine.
Speaker 1: I've.
Speaker 1: when I'm using it I experience no slowdown in general internet using whatsoever.
Speaker 1: It's I don't even know it's on.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling I would.
Speaker 1: Because files yeah, maybe but when I go to play a game online The ping is way higher because there is latency even though there is significant bandwidth.
Speaker 1: So if you're playing a real-time game, like if you're playing chess, it doesn't matter, but if you're playing counter-strike You got to turn that shit off.
Speaker 1: Otherwise your games gonna be ruined.
Speaker 1: your pings are all gonna be like a bajillion because your traffic is going far away And then going to the server.
Speaker 1: It's not good news But I highly recommend it for anyone who can afford $22 for three months.
Speaker 1: It can't hurt right?
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's only a good thing and Especially it's especially useful if you're using a shared Wi-Fi and Starbucks unless the Pirate Bay is actually a long play by the intelligence Organizations of the world.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, it's possible it is.
Speaker 0: then they'll find out that you secretly pirated Firefly and love it But won't tell anyone sure This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.