Speaker 1: It's geek nights.
Speaker 1: I'm Greg.
Speaker 0: I'm Jennifer and tonight.
Speaker 1: We'll be talking about all the I works.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So yeah, we don't know when rim is going to release this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we we answered his call for people to do podcasts to fill in.
Speaker 0: So here we are a little bit more about us during the meta moment but We're here and we're recording at some point.
Speaker 0: actually, it's It's Independence Day the real one the real American Independence Day in other words September 3rd September 3rd.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's when the Treaty of Paris which ended the Revolutionary War and recognized America as a sovereign nation was signed.
Speaker 0: So citizens of the United States of America if you are celebrating your independence on July 4th You are doing it wrong.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That was just a bunch of old white dudes signing a piece of paper.
Speaker 0: Well, you know in all fairness the Treaty of Paris was also a bunch of old white dudes signing a piece of paper.
Speaker 0: It was just more important much more Enforceable.
Speaker 0: it was paper.
Speaker 1: It was a piece of paper Forged by the deaths of thousands exactly as opposed to.
Speaker 0: hey This is our opinion about what our Declaration of Independence is all about.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it also happens to be Labor Day Mmm Today.
Speaker 0: yes, because it doesn't always match up exactly because in the United States Labor Day is the first Monday of September As opposed to much of the rest of the world which celebrates International Workers Day on May 1st.
Speaker 1: Is there historical significance behind that?
Speaker 0: oh You know, I'll bet there is and I do not know the association.
Speaker 1: Generally, you can assume that if it if it is on a specific day It has a historical significance.
Speaker 0: Usually although I'm suspicious of the fact that it's May 1st That it's like the first of the month.
Speaker 0: That's Well, whatever.
Speaker 1: Well, it could be it could be something that was scheduled.
Speaker 1: true cuz I mean like, okay Maybe it was a protest.
Speaker 1: Maybe it was some big protest in the streets that brought about radical change in Policy.
Speaker 0: Well, what do you say?
Speaker 0: I google that while we start into gigabytes?
Speaker 0: So, all right Go do a gigabyte first.
Speaker 1: you've decided not to do news because by the time you hear this the news will be old and stale Like to the point where you're like really that was news at some point Or to the point where you actually didn't know that it happened because it was so old.
Speaker 1: But instead we're doing gigabytes and my gigabyte is kind of weird.
Speaker 1: I watched all this in World War two.
Speaker 1: Ah Which is a movie that only barely exists.
Speaker 1: it was made in 76 and is the story of World War two as told by news.
Speaker 1: footage movies and The Beatles Cover songs, yes covers covers of Beatles best Beatles covers you've ever heard ever ever ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's interesting the story behind that.
Speaker 1: because Fox was spending no money on this because they already had the rights.
Speaker 1: Well, not absolutely no money But pretty much no money because they already had the rights to all the footage and they didn't need to shoot anything.
Speaker 1: So They just had to pay for editing.
Speaker 1: So they decided to license people to Cover the Beatles so that they could sell the soundtrack Which ended up being the only thing that made money because it was the 70s and People did not want to go see a war movie.
Speaker 0: Well, and the movie was marketed all wrong.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, the movie was just marketed all wrong.
Speaker 1: I think that's just the 70s.
Speaker 0: I Think that's some of it.
Speaker 1: Movies in the 70s just kind of were advertised like that.
Speaker 0: Also.
Speaker 0: This was an art film.
Speaker 0: This was not Potential blockbuster and it was marketed like a blockbuster, but it was released with.
Speaker 1: it was given a major release.
Speaker 1: Oh absolutely, and it was in the theaters for two weeks and Then it left theaters never to be heard from again except for rare showings at Film festivals and and TV.
Speaker 1: It's never gonna get a DVD release because they would have.
Speaker 1: At the time there wasn't a home video market so They didn't get the home video rights to any of the covers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the home video rights are extraordinarily complex.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just because of the number of sources of intellectual property involved They would have to they would have to go into licensing with Rod Stewart Tina Turner the moon estate the gibb estate.
Speaker 1: Mmm Oh my god, it.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's pretty much.
Speaker 1: and the amount of money they would demand versus the amount of money that The movie would actually make yeah.
Speaker 0: However, you can't find this on the internet either for download if you so choose or there I bootleg.
Speaker 0: you can buy a bootleg which might be convenient for you depending on the state of your home network.
Speaker 1: if you don't have if you don't have a HDMI port on your TV like ours mmm and Don't have like a ps3 or xbox.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then you're gonna want to get the bootleg Or if you just want to Support a relatively small business that does vintage films.
Speaker 0: I Can't remember the name of company that distributes the bootleg, but you know, I can't really get behind.
Speaker 0: not hard to find a business That sells.
Speaker 0: Okay, fair enough.
Speaker 0: All right, so I've got the history now at International Workers Day And this is shameful that we did not know this.
Speaker 0: This is absolutely shameful at least As long as Wikipedia is telling me the truth.
Speaker 1: It's the roses strike, isn't it?
Speaker 0: Nope International Workers Day according to Wikipedia is the commemoration of the 1886 Haymarket affair in Chicago.
Speaker 0: The police were trying to disperse a public assembly during a general strike for the eight-hour workday When an unidentified person threw a bomb at them.
Speaker 0: Then it goes on from there.
Speaker 0: So it's kind of police or the workers I believe at the police because the police reacted by firing on the workers Killing dozens of demonstrators and several of their own officers.
Speaker 1: I wonder what the NWA has to say about this NWA.
Speaker 0: NWA And with attitude Yes, well, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Oh in terms of frack the police.
Speaker 0: Yes, which I should get because I'm old But at any rate it's.
Speaker 0: it's kind of interesting that we celebrate this so little in the United States given that we are in the country where the event happened to everyone listening if you want to feel old Straight out of Compton came out in 1989.
Speaker 1: hmm, that was 23 years ago.
Speaker 1: I Wasn't alive.
Speaker 0: Yeah more about our relative ages at the metamoment.
Speaker 0: so anyway for my geek bite I Must put in a plug for humanity has declined which is an anime Which is currently airing in Japan and it's simulcasting on crunchyroll and I'm sure there's other places.
Speaker 0: You can find it as well.
Speaker 0: I am enjoying it.
Speaker 0: It is an odd show.
Speaker 0: It's hard to even know what to say about it when when I first heard about it It was everybody talking about the fact that a piece of bread essentially commits Suicide in order to provide food for some people.
Speaker 0: and we're talking Blood everywhere as the bread is killing itself.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's an odd little show in a lot of ways, but the basic Concept of it is that the last generation of human beings has been born.
Speaker 0: It's like the room of golf is an empty from from Ava or something.
Speaker 0: So no more human beings are being born and The new dominant species on the planet is the species of fairies and they're like maybe five or seven inches tall and It's not entirely clear to me even ten episodes in exactly where they're going with this thing.
Speaker 0: But that's kind of what I like about it so much.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of stuff about the fairy and human interactions.
Speaker 0: there's A lot of things about food.
Speaker 0: food is clearly playing a very important part in this show And it's just kind of got an interesting style.
Speaker 0: It's very bitter and it's very cute and That is appealing to me, but I can also see where for some people that would make it Unappealing.
Speaker 0: But yeah, so I would say check it out on crunchyroll or wherever else you may find your anime the things of the day.
Speaker 0: So since I did my first I'm gonna let you go first for the things of the day, okay Well, the thing of my day has been the thing of many of my days now actually But I do not believe it has ever been mentioned on geek nights.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna put in a plug for a webcomic called in his likeness.
Speaker 0: It's grown in complexity over the years, but the basic concept is simple.
Speaker 0: All of the characters are represented by dots and It's about God and it's about the devil and it's about Neptune.
Speaker 0: Eventually, it's about the devil lets.
Speaker 0: sooner or later Cthulhu gets involved, but it's a very simple visual style and it's a kind of Chatty silly punny in in some corners Kind of webcomic strip the first like two or three hundred Strips are really great.
Speaker 1: I Haven't read anything in the last hundred.
Speaker 1: that was about God So I can't.
Speaker 1: I don't really like it as much.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: He's using like Cthulhu and cats and I'm not.
Speaker 1: It feels kind of woo game ish.
Speaker 0: There's some God stuff that's still going on more recently but at any rate in his likeness check it out.
Speaker 1: and my thing of the day is an old classic that I was sure had been on geek nights and Discovered was not.
Speaker 1: So I'm going to cop out and use it anyway But it is the old Negro space program.
Speaker 1: Oh a not Ken Burns documentary.
Speaker 1: indeed All I'm going to say is that space is cold Almost froze my mother a freaking nuts off.
Speaker 1: All right, so metamoment already then.
Speaker 0: yes metamoment.
Speaker 0: So some of you know us from the front row crew forums.
Speaker 0: I am JTVH on the forums and Greg is Greg.
Speaker 0: You might know us from some of the panels that we do at Anime conventions and similar conventions like Kineticon.
Speaker 0: You might know us as two-thirds of the family that geeks together.
Speaker 1: by the time this goes up for all we know will have been Panelists.
Speaker 0: who knows who knows?
Speaker 0: well hopefully we'll see.
Speaker 0: we'll see if Otakon wants any of our stuff next year.
Speaker 0: But at any rate we also have another project that you may not be aware of Which is I am one of the co-hosts and co-producers of a podcast called those darn cats.
Speaker 0: my co-host is my best friend Lisa and we talk about all things Disney and we touch on things from Their reviews of different Disney Cruise Line ships to a feminist analysis of Minnie's country home in Toontown in Magic Kingdom to an unfortunate lack of theming event at the Tomorrowland Noodle Terrace Which is inexplicably our most downloaded show.
Speaker 0: We did a show one time on gay days at Disney parks Which is a more inflammatory topic than one might imagine.
Speaker 0: we had different people come on as guests for that.
Speaker 0: So at any rate if you're interested in Disney stuff at all Check it out at those darn cats dotnet.
Speaker 1: All right, so into the main bit.
Speaker 1: absolutely All right, so of I works.
Speaker 1: is The man that Disney doesn't want you to know about?
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's the man that they want on you to think.
Speaker 1: Walt was?
Speaker 1: he designed Mickey Mouse?
Speaker 1: he was an amazing.
Speaker 1: Single-handedly.
Speaker 1: It was an amazing an amazing engineer.
Speaker 1: he Went off and did his own stuff trained Chuck Jones Who is known as the director of all your favorite Warner Brothers cartoons?
Speaker 1: Where should we start?
Speaker 0: Where should we start?
Speaker 0: Well, first of all, let me just say he's the man that Disney Kinda doesn't want you to know because he is listed as a Disney legend legends series not for any of the reasons that they don't want you to know about.
Speaker 1: the weird part is They published the book the hand behind the mouse, which is kind of what exposed is all this.
Speaker 1: They made it into a documentary.
Speaker 1: You can buy this documentary on the Disney Treasuries DVD which It's the Oswald collection Oswald the lucky rabbit.
Speaker 1: Yep, so They like you know about him, but it's a pain in the ass to find any of these.
Speaker 1: I Could not find any Disney Treasuries when looking for them on the Disney site.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, that's interesting because they're not hard to find at Best Buy or at least they weren't when that first came out.
Speaker 1: Yeah yeah, but like just the interface did not let me find them.
Speaker 1: I gave up and went to Google and And Googled for the product I was looking for.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm so they're they're willing to admit that he did this but they they're not willing to publicize him as The god he was which is a shame because he was a lot more amazing than they even let.
Speaker 1: He was a more amazing person than Walt the legend was.
Speaker 1: for example Disney in 1936 Spent seven million dollars on a multi-plane camera.
Speaker 1: The multi-plane camera is something that allows multiple cells to be used in One frame of animation which sounds like a waste of cellulite but hurt celluloid celluloid.
Speaker 0: a Waste of cellulite is a whole different topic.
Speaker 1: Seems like waste of celluloid But what allows you to do is it allows you to move things at different rates so that Don Quixote is Moving faster than the forest is moving faster than the castle.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm That's just one example.
Speaker 1: three years before Disney developed it of.
Speaker 1: I works at his own student as independent studio at MGM which had been founded in 1930. the studio not MGM bought a used car for under a thousand dollars and Made one out of that.
Speaker 0: Well and that it just interestingly enough that is the multi-plane camera that they talk about in the attraction.
Speaker 0: one Man's dream about Walt Disney.
Speaker 1: if you ever go to Disney World Go to one man's tree.
Speaker 1: well first read the book the hand behind the mouse because it's great book.
Speaker 1: then go to one man's dream and Look at just how much stuff was actually done by up the multi-plane camera when he was still at in art school He invented or not quite invented, but he made a self cranking camera because in the time animation required two people one person to crank his camera and the other to feed the cells in and So he made a device that would crank the camera itself.
Speaker 1: He made huge innovations For on the mat process did special effects for the birds.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Hitchcock's he developed a machine based off of xerox that got rid of in-between urs.
Speaker 1: In-between urs are animators who draw all the frames between the key animators drawing.
Speaker 0: So basically you put a lot of people out of work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it was incredibly efficient.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Yeah, he put a lot of people out of work, but it's also ten times more beautiful.
Speaker 1: Mmm, absolutely Like watch Sleeping Beauty.
Speaker 1: that's not a good movie, but it is a beautiful movie and so I like it anyway Mmm, and I've also did a bunch of work on Disney Parks attractions, too.
Speaker 0: That was later on in his career mind you that must have been in the 60s.
Speaker 0: Yep in the 60s he got involved with Disney theme park Imagineering and Played a part in developing.
Speaker 0: It's a small world.
Speaker 0: great moments with mr.
Speaker 0: Lincoln and the Hall of Presidents and The first and last of those.
Speaker 0: it's a small world and Hall of Presidents.
Speaker 0: They may be annoying and/or boring attractions But especially in Hall of Presidents the animatronics involved were pretty impressive for the time and they're still in use.
Speaker 1: Small world not so impressive animatronics.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, not so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah more or less just puppets on sticks Yeah, but what I find most notable about of is his early animation When he began his career fresh out of high school or not high school art school with Walt They began the Laugh O'Grams company, which this is fun.
Speaker 1: theaters would commission them to make music videos for regional hits which is interesting because that was something that was frequently done in like the 20s and to a lesser extent in the early 30s.
Speaker 1: But then music videos more or less disappeared until the 70s Yeah, which is kind of fascinating.
Speaker 0: Yeah with the exception of the Beatles.
Speaker 0: the Beatles actually were doing music videos at a time that nobody was doing music videos.
Speaker 1: Well, they were making movies that let them make music videos.
Speaker 1: true true fair enough I are see the monkeys were doing the same thing.
Speaker 1: Mmm So it's not like it was just the Beatles.
Speaker 0: True but they I think the monkeys started doing it after the Beatles but back to up.
Speaker 1: but yeah, so they making music videos and advertisements at Laugh O'Grams made the Alice comedies which were a series about a little girl played by Virginia Davis being transported into this cartoon world which Had varying quality.
Speaker 1: Mmm first one was really good everything afterwards was kind of yeah, but then they made Oswald lucky rabbit Which was licensed and distributed by mints mints industries or Corp or whatever who would later be bought by Universal Mm-hmm, and the Oswald's are really good.
Speaker 1: It's the first instance of conservation of mass.
Speaker 1: Felix the cat his legs would extend so that he could get taller and look at something But they wouldn't get thinner right exactly his.
Speaker 0: his amount of mass would change.
Speaker 1: It's also one of the earlier appearances of elasticity of all objects Mmm-hmm before like in the Alice comedies.
Speaker 1: if something stretched it would then just sort of go back like a telescope Right, whereas in Oswald it snaps back it like Snap and then go forward really fast.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And it also features a robot cow.
Speaker 0: And what's not to like about a robot cow really?
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I think the best is trolley troubles which is simply fantastic it is.
Speaker 1: indeed it also has inexplicable telescope vision.
Speaker 0: So, oh, yeah, this was.
Speaker 1: this was sort of a trope of the time both in animation and live-action and I don't know why but Frequently the frame will become circular with just like black around the edges.
Speaker 1: I don't know why it does this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's very interesting.
Speaker 0: I don't know why either.
Speaker 1: if someone who knows more about silent film Could tell us yeah drop a fantastic podcast at those don't cats net.
Speaker 1: but yeah, and it's at this point that Charles Mintz fires Walt and Contracts out all the animators.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, except for of course up because of is awesome knows that he can succeed without Pretty much anyone which was tested later.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but true.
Speaker 1: We'll get to that in a minute.
Speaker 1: So Of in Kansas City knows that Mintz has done this and is working on a solution while Walt is still in California being caught up and It's at this point.
Speaker 1: Cuz remember this is back when there weren't airplanes.
Speaker 1: I mean technically their work is Wright brothers were I'm gonna say but they were not in common usage.
Speaker 1: Yeah stretch of the imagination yeah, so people were still taking trains and trains take a long time.
Speaker 1: Walt was in California for just a few days, but it took him Like a week and a half two weeks in order to do his business.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And so it's in these two weeks that of designs Mickey Mouse and draws the first cartoon playing crazy Which is about date.
Speaker 0: rape in the air.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: Yeah Which?
Speaker 1: No, no, I feel kind of bad saying this but it's also my favorite Mickey Mouse.
Speaker 0: well, it's back when I say.
Speaker 0: it's back when as if like At any rate, it was not a time when it was 1927 28 it's a different time.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's at a time when Mickey was still the mischievous character because that's how he started out.
Speaker 0: he started out very mischievous and It was only when he became the corporate mascot that he had to get more wholesome And less troublemaker.
Speaker 0: II.
Speaker 1: his wholesomeness Begins as soon as Walt intervenes.
Speaker 1: of didn't really believe in likable protagonists.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm He believed in a protagonist that would keep the viewers attention.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm He probably would have done very well on South Park.
Speaker 1: Yes, whereas Walt wanted the viewer to like The the character he was seeing he wanted them to connect with Mickey Mouse Which is why as soon as he returned to Kansas City, he had had of and Two other animators make a cartoon where Mickey abuses animals for seven.
Speaker 0: We are speaking, of course of the Steamboat Willie.
Speaker 1: Yes, which was released before playing crazy because they wanted to have a gimmick To draw people's attention to their new character, which was a smart business move.
Speaker 0: quite frankly Yes, nobody had done synchronized sound for a cartoon before.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It's perhaps the Smartest and certainly the most important decision that Walt made in his entire career.
Speaker 0: Well, certainly in terms of animation stuff.
Speaker 1: Yes, and so they're released.
Speaker 1: Steamboat Willie, which is about Swinging cats around in the air and pulling on the teats of poor little piggies Yeah, and beating on the cows teeth.
Speaker 0: Yes Yeah, it's a really really sadistic little Mickey Mouse.
Speaker 1: you got there and then like Pete throws him in the in the brig to peel potatoes and we're supposed to Dislike him for this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I still don't understand why.
Speaker 1: oh and also that crane is a total perv.
Speaker 0: True true true.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everybody's just got to go watch Steamboat Willie.
Speaker 0: So they have any clue what we're talking about?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they also should watch plain crazy which features the earliest I've seen.
Speaker 0: Example of uses of wiener dogs Technology, I would like someone to write a book about the history of wiener dog technology in cartoons.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I would read that book like three times and I don't read that fast.
Speaker 1: but Anyway, he made those and he makes the galloping Goncho or Gaucho Gaucho the galloping Groucho.
Speaker 1: That would have been good Steamboat Willie and galloping Gaucho actually are both parodies of contemporary movies.
Speaker 1: Steamboat Bill was a Big hit of the time and I don't remember what the galloping Gaucho was a parody of but I do remember it was double Douglas Fairbanks movie.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Okay, Mickey was very Heavily inspired by Douglas Fairbanks.
Speaker 1: that didn't stick around.
Speaker 1: but at the beginning Mm-hmm, really?
Speaker 1: And the galloping Gaucho.
Speaker 1: I don't really have any good jokes about.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen this many times.
Speaker 1: so It's this point that Walt launches the Silly symphonies.
Speaker 0: I was going to say initiative But he begins that line of cartoons.
Speaker 1: Yes But you know, what's just the Silly symphonies series which is where of makes my favorite cartoons From Disney save for World War two.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm because that That's stuff like Nazi Donald and oh Hemisphere exactly the grain that changed the hemisphere though.
Speaker 0: They um a Packet.
Speaker 0: what's it called on the front lines?
Speaker 1: I think it's called on the front lines also from the Disney Treasuries Collection.
Speaker 1: the moral of the podcast is buy everything from the Disney Treasuries collection.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's really more interesting.
Speaker 0: Then one might imagine there's a lot of interesting early Disney stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if it's from before 1950 just buy it Mmm, don't even ask questions or look on YouTube because a lot of this stuff is on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Yes, search YouTube for Der Führer's face.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Donald in Nazi Land.
Speaker 1: Yep They didn't change the name because it was offensive.
Speaker 1: They changed the name because Der Führer's face was a contemporary radio hit.
Speaker 1: Mmm, yeah, and so as a result anyone who's any buddy Says calls it Donald in Nazi Land.
Speaker 1: So uh begins work on.
Speaker 1: Probably the most famous is the skeleton dance.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm with music by Carl Stalling who have to give a lot of credit to absolutely who is the best composer to work in the field of cartoons?
Speaker 1: and Sung by Thoreau Ravenscroft an amazing voice actor.
Speaker 1: Yes, amazing voice who I think our our listeners will certainly recognize him as the guy who sung Grinch Absolutely, and somehow over the course of 40 years his voice didn't change that much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, amazingly consistent over the years.
Speaker 1: yeah, and so up writes that and he also or not writes of creates that and he also Drew a less well-remembered Cartoon that I like more, but I'm not sure why which is Hell's Bells.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Which the best way to describe it is Satan the musical.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty good way to describe it.
Speaker 1: It's about demons and The inferno and all this stuff and they're all smiling and why shouldn't they be?
Speaker 1: and they're all doing that thing that they did In the 30s car in the cartoons in the 30s where they're bouncing up and down.
Speaker 0: I love that.
Speaker 1: There's actually a reason for it Because they used it as a metronome basically.
Speaker 1: So the characters bounced to the beat so they could sync them up easily, but it's also really silly Exactly, and so Hell's Bells is kind of silly, but I like it.
Speaker 1: I've worked on two more cartoons with Disney the spring and summer Silly symphonies which were part of a series about seasons, but he was getting disgruntled with Walt Because Walt was me was very much streamlining the process of animation.
Speaker 1: He was he was trying to do to animation what Henry Ford did to the car and Of didn't like that.
Speaker 1: So he was given an offer by MGM to form his own studio which he gladly accepted and He brought with him a lot of the highest talent at Disney Bob Clampett Carl Stalling and also people from other studios.
Speaker 1: Tex Avery was from I don't remember if it was Van Buren or God, I'm blanking on their name the guys who did Betty Boop.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: I can't remember what studio that was.
Speaker 0: I was never a Betty Boop fan Fleischer Brothers.
Speaker 1: But yeah Tex Avery from Fleischer Brothers all these Amazing people came because they heard of I works is starting his own studio.
Speaker 1: Mmm, that's the biggest thing that can happen.
Speaker 1: Yep, they go to work for him and He makes cartoons.
Speaker 1: they are Interesting.
Speaker 0: balloon land is my favorite.
Speaker 1: You can watch them yourselves.
Speaker 1: Actually, they are on Netflix streaming Mm-hmm cartoons.
Speaker 1: the time forgot of I works collection.
Speaker 1: they also have the Van Buren collection on there, which I have not watched yet, but I have seen the up ones and they are Interesting.
Speaker 1: the first one or no, not the first one but first comic color was a little piece called fiddlesticks Wearing a very early flip.
Speaker 1: the frog which would become the mascot for them does dances with a Mickey Mouse ripoff Which I have mixed feelings about because he kind of made him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's kind of ripping off himself.
Speaker 0: But at the same time it's Walt's intellectual property like Well, but actually it's questionable.
Speaker 0: There are some intellectual property questions about some of the early Disney.
Speaker 0: It may have fallen into the public domain now, but no one really wants to be the test case.
Speaker 0: So you were saying about flip?
Speaker 1: Yeah the flip he made series is flip the frog and Willy Whopper or The consistency.
Speaker 1: he also made a series of fairy tale adaptations which were kind of the beta testing for fractured fairy tales Mmm, the Rocky and Bullwinkle segment.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but you got things like Humpty Dumpty Which is really silly and I really love it.
Speaker 1: and it has this silly song at the end about spooning in a spoon.
Speaker 0: Oh, I love the um Humpty Dumpty.
Speaker 1: Yes Yeah, and some of the characters get hard-boiled.
Speaker 0: yeah, one of the eggs basically turns into Mae West Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Oh and the Don Quixote adaptation.
Speaker 1: I simply love.
Speaker 1: but anyway, these didn't really stick around because they they didn't have.
Speaker 1: It was the of I works philosophy of don't make a protagonist that that people root for make a protagonist that people like or no don't make a protagonist that people like make a protagonist that people pay attention to.
Speaker 1: and Because the characters didn't stick with people the same same way that Walt's Mickey did It didn't grab people as well.
Speaker 1: on Top of that.
Speaker 1: It was the Great Depression Mmm, the studio was founded in 1930 and was bought by Schlesinger Studios in Which would then be brought by the Warner Brothers and be turned into Warner Brothers animation.
Speaker 1: and on top of that Ubs cartoons were very risque.
Speaker 1: It was not odd for a pair of breasts to be featured in one of his cartoons.
Speaker 1: they weren't designed for children.
Speaker 1: they were designed for a businessman who was traveling through town and had five minutes to Spare and enjoy himself.
Speaker 1: And so when the Hays code came into effect the Hays code banned Disrespect of religion races all religions authority and quote anything else.
Speaker 1: so Ubs very politically incorrect before politically incorrect was a thing Studio ran into a lot of trouble which is unfortunate because I really love flips design and So they ended up running pretty much out of money.
Speaker 1: So Schlesinger was able to buy them cheap.
Speaker 1: after Working for a few years at Schlesinger You can find Ubs name on one or two Warner Brothers is he returned to Disney but not as an animator.
Speaker 1: He decided that he had beat animation.
Speaker 1: He instead returned as a engineer Mm-hmm, which is where he developed the mad technology the Xerox derivative All that stuff.
Speaker 1: It was heavily involved in Mary Poppins.
Speaker 1: Yes special effects for that which seemed kind of rudimentary to us But there hadn't been live-action animation crossover in a long time.
Speaker 0: Well, and that little that little anim audio animatronic bird and Mary Poppins was actually Pretty good for its day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so since Greg you're more the I works expert of the two of us.
Speaker 0: It seems to me that if someone's going to If they want to learn about a buy works.
Speaker 0: Some of the best things they could do would be watch the hand behind the mouse or read the book the hand behind the mouse.
Speaker 1: The book was better.
Speaker 0: if someone was gonna just go look at one of I works Property, what would you tell them to go watch?
Speaker 1: Do you mean anything he's worked on?
Speaker 1: or do you mean anything from his studio anything?
Speaker 0: He's worked on Oswald lucky rabbit Mmm, and some of those are available on YouTube.
Speaker 1: I do believe yes Oswald is finally back at the Disney Company after doing nothing at Universal for a little bit under a century.
Speaker 0: Yes, and some people may remember it wasn't too long ago that Disney Traded al Michaels the sports reporter from ESPN in order to get Oswald back into the fold and the thing that they've done with Oswald subsequently that people might be familiar with is The epic Mickey series of games
Speaker 1: which are not good, but we like them anyway, because they have Oswald.
Speaker 0: Well, and I like the fact that they've actually done something to bring Oswald's back into the corporate fold and to be actually Hey, hey, they did two things They made epic Mickey and they made a plushie.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: And I bought both these things And a few pins in the parks.
Speaker 0: They've got a few pins of the parks here and there.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think my Favorite of I works property because I'm assuming that people have seen at least some of the vintage Disney which may or may not be correct pretty much.
Speaker 1: I think everyone's seen either played in crazy or steamboat Willie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you haven't you really if you're a fan of animation at all You owe it to yourself to go see that.
Speaker 0: also watch Gertie the dinosaur, but my personal favorite of I works Would have to be the Humpty Dumpty.
Speaker 0: Oh which I believe may well be on YouTube and if not, it's certainly in the.
Speaker 1: I think it's in the Film archive thing the one that's on streaming Netflix.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know what's on streaming Netflix.
Speaker 0: Okay, so if you got Netflix It's in the cartoons the time forgot and I think that that's all.
Speaker 1: fortunately Netflix kind of screwed up Cartoons.
Speaker 1: the time forgot is treated as a movie, right?
Speaker 1: So that's like four hours of cartoons and No scene select or anything.
Speaker 1: You can get the discs also from Netflix, but on streaming There's no scene select.
Speaker 0: Yeah But it's worth it to deal with the fast forwarding if you want to because or you just don't fast forward and just watch Shotgun them all in an afternoon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz that's what I do.
Speaker 0: Cuz why not?
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz yeah, I love the Humpty Dumpty and I love balloon land.
Speaker 0: Balloon land is a very very strange cartoon indeed.
Speaker 1: balloon land is definitely at the end of something.
Speaker 0: Yes Not sure at the end of what but it is certainly at the end of something and I guess I should mention that up one More Academy Awards than I can even mention.
Speaker 0: Oh Absolutely.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one of them being for the birds the office cock property.
Speaker 1: Yes, he won one for the toy soldier cartoon that he did MGM and A million and a half for special effects.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you could argue that he won one for the lifetime achievement Given to Mickey Mouse.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that really should have.
Speaker 0: His name should have been on that thing.
Speaker 1: That's debatable Cuz.
Speaker 1: I've never took credit for it true?
Speaker 1: Oh very much believed that the reason that Mickey succeeded was because Walt took it away from him Mmm, and if he had continued working on it would not have been a success.
Speaker 0: Well, and you know in all honesty, he could be right about that because in my opinion Of was not quite as skilled as Walt at sort of long-term character development.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could not have made a movie.
Speaker 0: Yes, I would have to agree.
Speaker 1: of was great at Comedy, but not character not nothing longer than like 12 minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he really was not into developing the characters at all.
Speaker 0: So yeah, they which is what made them such a good team mind you given how flat Snow white was maybe he could have.
Speaker 2: maybe This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 2: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 2: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 2: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 2: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays Night's is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 2: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 2: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 2: It's actually recorded at night.