Speaker 1: It's Monday, March 26th, 2012.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, it's a tech news round-up.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Cuz we didn't have much else to do the show on in a hurry.
Speaker 0: Well, I figure I figure it's okay Cuz we haven't done in a long time.
Speaker 0: You know, if we did tech news round-up every week Then we would be Twit and not Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Ah, but if we were Twit Do you think I'm not saying whether or not?
Speaker 1: I believe it is true that we could give better or worse commentary than them?
Speaker 0: It's hard.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean the thing is it but you have to put a definition of better or worse, right?
Speaker 0: Because you know, they're more.
Speaker 0: they're more professional than we are.
Speaker 0: You know higher profile and such and I'm sure most people in our geek community, you know, at least not our listeners.
Speaker 0: but obviously, you know twit listeners would probably say that twit is more entertaining than we are but We are clearly vastly more technologically knowledgeable than they are.
Speaker 0: there is no question about this.
Speaker 0: if you're looking for technological accuracy Definitely want to go with us.
Speaker 0: nerdy guys you don't give a shit and we're willing to lay down, you know, all kinds of big words and Not you know the people going for the more mass appeal even though we haven't really done that lately.
Speaker 0: Not so much.
Speaker 0: It's like when we're talking about a tech news though, you know We don't you know, it's like, you know, even if we're talking about tech news on a low level We don't bring in you know something that's contradictory to technological fact and we often do bring in the Technological fact as like supporting like it can't be done because blah blah blah You know other people always seem to fail at that and they'll be like, oh, well, what if there's something something?
Speaker 0: I'm like that something something is not possible.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah, it's a tech news roundup meaning it'd be kind of stupid to do some news now.
Speaker 1: Oh Cue of that music there little thing of the day music and how about that?
Speaker 1: It's time for things of the day.
Speaker 1: What do you got for me?
Speaker 0: So check this out, you know Brian Kern Ahan of Kern Ahan and Richie the guys who wrote the book on C Literally, he wrote a book much more recently.
Speaker 0: You can buy the Kindle Edition for 10 books or the paper edition for 15 or you can just read it.
Speaker 0: Uh, oh, I think you can only read the table of contents.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I Thought it was free whatever But this book is still worthy of being a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Basically, you know, this is very important and smart technological person wrote a book called D is for digital.
Speaker 0: What a well-informed person ought to know about computers and communications.
Speaker 0: This book explains how today's computing and communications world operates from hardware through software to the internet and the web.
Speaker 0: It includes enough detail that you can understand how these systems work no matter what your technical background.
Speaker 0: The social political and legal issues that new technology creates are discussed as well.
Speaker 0: So you can understand the difficult issues we face and appreciate the trade-offs that have to be made to resolve them.
Speaker 0: So from the looks of it, obviously, I haven't read it because I thought But anyway, I think this book is probably you know, at least from what I've seen so far the best book to give to a person who doesn't know about internets or anything like that and Get them to be educated.
Speaker 0: Obviously, it won't teach you programming.
Speaker 0: It won't teach you how to use a computer It won't teach you anything like that But it'll sort of help you understand, you know the new Laws of society in a technological world and how things work, you know, basically I mean, let me read the table of contents preface introduction.
Speaker 0: part 1 hardware.
Speaker 0: What's in a computer?
Speaker 0: bits bytes representation of information inside the CPU.
Speaker 0: part 2 software algorithms programming and program languages software systems learning to program.
Speaker 0: part 3 communications networking the internet the World Wide Web data information and privacy, so that pretty much covers Everything, huh?
Speaker 1: You know, I wonder if we could do the same concept.
Speaker 1: remember those old the way things work books.
Speaker 1: They had the mammoths in him Nuclear power and like how records work and everything and excruciating detail for little kids.
Speaker 0: Maybe I had different books than you.
Speaker 1: Maybe you did.
Speaker 1: Those are really good books.
Speaker 1: I will make those the next book club book, perhaps As good as I want my hat back.
Speaker 1: Nothing is as good as I want my head back.
Speaker 0: I think something is All right, here's a question for you right ready rim Tomorrow on Amazon.
Speaker 0: There's two books.
Speaker 0: They have the same release day, right the sequel to.
Speaker 0: I want my hat back.
Speaker 1: I want my other hat back.
Speaker 0: That's right, or I want my shoe back or something like that.
Speaker 0: and New Prince of nothing book, which one do you read first?
Speaker 1: That's not fair because I could.
Speaker 0: what is not fair?
Speaker 0: I'm just saying if it happens just saying what do you read?
Speaker 1: That's like saying all right There's two pieces of entertainment that may be equally compelling One of which takes 30 seconds to consume and one of which takes about four days to consume Which what there has to be one that you are you can't be absolutely 100% equally excited.
Speaker 0: Ah, but even if I were you have to be slightly more leaning towards one of them than the other.
Speaker 1: fact, even if you know All right, here's is okay I'll check cuz I gotta bust out the game theory analysis because here's the trouble if one of them is very quick to consume Even if okay half as good as the long book by consuming it first.
Speaker 1: my net enjoyment Over a period of time obviously, okay.
Speaker 0: I made a mistake and asking you which one you would go after first.
Speaker 1: What if I only get one?
Speaker 0: What if you only had one and the other one you could never see or experience in your life?
Speaker 0: But the other one you could read in full as many times as you please.
Speaker 1: Prince of nothing cuz it's equal Couldn't live up to what happened in the first hat.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, Prince of nothing.
Speaker 1: I gotta know what the fuck happened.
Speaker 0: That's right That's right.
Speaker 1: I really got to know.
Speaker 1: actually now I'm thinking about that again.
Speaker 1: next book come out.
Speaker 1: god damn it.
Speaker 0: Let's check Amazon.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Not talking about ponies, but it's tangentially related.
Speaker 1: I got to make that known.
Speaker 1: Lauren Faust who basically made my little pony what it is today the internet phenomenon also was doing another little show.
Speaker 1: as you may know she had a hand in such great classics as the Powerpuff Girls and You know, she made my little pony what it was and she moved on.
Speaker 1: and now she's doing a little thing for DC the super best friends forever and It'll be interesting.
Speaker 1: I saw you know, there's a clip.
Speaker 1: I'm linking to the sort of like teaser clip.
Speaker 1: She does good stuff and I look forward to seeing more of her work in non pony realms in the future Even though I kind of wish you just go back to ponies.
Speaker 0: I wish you'd make a comic book.
Speaker 0: right because you look at this really reminds me of like tiny Titans the comic book Only a little less tiny but it's that same sort of thing.
Speaker 0: We're like you.
Speaker 0: take the superhero characters you sort of, you know Boil their characters down to like this caricature of themselves and you sort of you know Make it, you know, really expressive and cute and you tell fun stories.
Speaker 1: That is what her biggest strength is.
Speaker 1: look at all the words that we like it's.
Speaker 1: she has characters like.
Speaker 1: she's a Independent of who writes a good story because you know, they have different writers for a lot of these things.
Speaker 1: She takes good characters and she does good character direction and like overall like world direct all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: But anyway, you know there have been lots of these sorts of things in comic book form But relatively few in TV animation for me and even these are shorts, right?
Speaker 0: No, it's a whole show like this except ponies And I really wish someone would make a whole show like this to start with a comic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I think you know.
Speaker 0: Maybe what she should do is she should make a comic book because she definitely do it all in her own and it would be Epically awesome.
Speaker 0: She could do a pony comic book.
Speaker 0: I mean, I Want to know why there's a strawberry shortcake piece of shit.
Speaker 0: boycott all-american greetings still because of the penny arcade Back in the day Hasbro being a relative but Hasbro does plenty of comics as Transformers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they do.
Speaker 1: however, they Not the best I can tell.
Speaker 1: remember they appointed not to make this the pony show They hired or are trying to hire a product manager just for my little pony.
Speaker 1: They realize they have to you know Exploit it the right way and they appear to be very carefully not wanting to fuck it up.
Speaker 1: So they don't want to make the comic until they make the comic right though There are pony comics in a ton of other languages.
Speaker 0: Well, those are more like kids coloring books not comic books.
Speaker 1: you buy the comic book, but they still have comics in them.
Speaker 0: They should just get bongo or IDW to do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's not the pony show.
Speaker 1: That's that's coming.
Speaker 1: That's right later.
Speaker 1: So it's a tech news roundup, but first the meta moment.
Speaker 0: you do the day.
Speaker 0: All right, of course, I did not.
Speaker 1: this coming weekend, but next motherfucking weekend We're gonna be in Boston for anime Boston and the penny arcade Expo East.
Speaker 0: Oh 2012 fuck your mother.
Speaker 1: we are doing.
Speaker 1: let's play money-making game.
Speaker 1: We are doing the geek nights tabletop workshop.
Speaker 1: That one is a class.
Speaker 1: We're teaching you how to play and win Carcassonne and Agricola and a secret game to be announced.
Speaker 0: how much time is left?
Speaker 1: Yep, we are also going to be there with a bunch of our friends like I don't know Luke crane and Jared Sorensen who are doing a whole bunch of things some parsley events a The D&D a panel on old D&D and why it's actually awesome.
Speaker 0: Play old D&D by the book, but no one wants to play with me.
Speaker 0: I'll play it and we need more.
Speaker 0: people who are dedicating will actually show up every time and prepare and Some of those nerd NYC people probably would invest in it for reals.
Speaker 1: Maybe those guys love that kind of role-play.
Speaker 0: Maybe let's run it at recess.
Speaker 0: Ah Old D&D by the book.
Speaker 1: How old though because while the original one that I have that I got a goodwill in Rochester I would not mind reading the red green blue dungeons and dragons as in from the Dungeons & Dragons Cyclopedia.
Speaker 0: the thing is I have to read it again But yeah the red green blue that I got at the Goodwill store levels go up to I think 36 I don't know.
Speaker 1: I look in the Cyclopedia in Dungeons & Dragons that was existing at the same time as advanced dungeons and dragons.
Speaker 1: Anyway Anyway, so yeah, we'll be packs be an anime Boston shits going down.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: Book Club book is the Hunger Games.
Speaker 1: Just the first one.
Speaker 1: I know the movie came out.
Speaker 1: read the book.
Speaker 0: This one should be easy enough because most of you fucking read it.
Speaker 1: Alright, read the book Movie doesn't count.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't gotta read.
Speaker 0: It's the book club.
Speaker 0: Not the movie.
Speaker 1: Not a sports page.
Speaker 1: Not a magazine But a book.
Speaker 1: that's right.
Speaker 1: So yeah tech news roundup.
Speaker 1: I have most of the news is here.
Speaker 1: So I will start.
Speaker 0: I've been reading a lot less internet lately.
Speaker 0: So I have a lot less news is.
Speaker 1: so let's start.
Speaker 0: I have my ability to discuss the news is has not dwindled.
Speaker 1: Let's start with the National Highway Transportation Safety Administration.
Speaker 1: Because they were in the news twice.
Speaker 0: How could they be in the news twice?
Speaker 0: did somebody like who works there quit and like post a bunch of stuff on the internet?
Speaker 0: That was scandalous.
Speaker 0: So first there must be some reason.
Speaker 1: this is kind of an aside in technology.
Speaker 0: But I have a big press conference or they announced it's interesting that they had two things.
Speaker 1: The first one is that they proposed some rules to how GPS navigation systems work in cars.
Speaker 1: Specifically they wanted to make it such that the screens cannot display your position Relative to the car you're in Like, you know, you can't angle the map down and show like the arrow that shows like see the turns coming up ahead.
Speaker 1: This is how it'll look like to you.
Speaker 1: So no GTA mode only over-the-top mode Yep, and two they can't update in real time.
Speaker 1: They have to show you a static map Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Their argument is that this will reduce distractions and make people safer drivers that people rely too much on GPS.
Speaker 1: and I didn't read their study fully, but I read.
Speaker 1: I read some of the commentary.
Speaker 1: I found some counter studies that I didn't read just as much.
Speaker 1: I Think this is ridiculous.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you know now one of those things that sounds like common sense, right?
Speaker 0: Do you think oh, yeah if it updates less often then that means you look at it less or whatever.
Speaker 0: But you know, there's an argument to be made the other way and I'm pretty much whatever the science.
Speaker 1: Well, there is an argument to be made for as you can look at.
Speaker 1: remember when we were looking to buy that house and beacon Remember a realtor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she would drive look at just literally just staring at the GPS.
Speaker 1: She wouldn't even look at the road and apparently she'd been in like 10 car accidents in the previous few months Yep, and we're riding in her car like oh god.
Speaker 0: So I think it pretty much just comes down to the evidence right if you can demonstrate.
Speaker 0: You know within reasonable doubt or whatever some level of confidence that these rules will decrease.
Speaker 0: You know damage and death on the road.
Speaker 0: So I know you should put them in.
Speaker 1: but I have a counter argument to even that.
Speaker 0: you do not have the evidence Then do not do that.
Speaker 1: I have a counter argument to even that.
Speaker 1: Okay, what if it turns out that only shitty drivers are more likely to get into accidents because they stare at the GPS Mm-hmm and good drivers?
Speaker 1: Because the orientation and real-time updates of the map are so accurate and from the perspective of the user?
Speaker 1: You could argue that someone who glances at it quickly and then resumes looking at the road is much more likely to be able to Information and then resume looking at the road if it's contextual and in real time if it's just a static map.
Speaker 1: How many times you've been driving but again right in the days before any of this?
Speaker 1: You know any sort of navigation device and you had a map like print it out.
Speaker 1: You're trying to like hold it in front of you while you're driving.
Speaker 1: that shit is dangerous, right?
Speaker 0: But I mean again, this is just your common sense as opposed to someone else's common sense.
Speaker 0: You know if you can provide evidence to suggest that that is true within some high level of confidence.
Speaker 0: Then what we need obviously is some sort of rule that says Oh, well, if you're this kind of driver, then you can do use this But if you're not you can use that.
Speaker 1: so, you know, ah, but how do you legislate that?
Speaker 1: and more importantly?
Speaker 1: this is all crazy anyway, because Phones have the real-time GPS and will never be regulated in that regard.
Speaker 1: So anyone who wants to use GPS navigation if a law were passed to Basically ruin in-car GPS, they would just mount their phone on their dashboard.
Speaker 0: But then they'll just say, you know any GPS software that they would there's no way that would fly.
Speaker 1: I mean does that count?
Speaker 1: All right GPS software on my laptop computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: What about my boat navigation?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That's Bring your boat navigate.
Speaker 0: your boat navigation isn't gonna have the road data, you know, so you can't bring it in your car.
Speaker 0: It won't help you Yeah.
Speaker 1: But what if I just overlay him out?
Speaker 1: the thing is that there's no way a law could be passed that would ban GPS navigation systems updated in real time.
Speaker 1: because what constitutes a GPS navigation system?
Speaker 0: I think I think the fundamental thing here right is that remember this is a regulation of software.
Speaker 0: It's impossible to regulate software.
Speaker 0: You cannot make a law that says software that does X may not exist or may not be sold or may not be used.
Speaker 0: So they can always.
Speaker 0: someone can always make software that does X and distribute it and there's no way you can stop it Which
Speaker 1: so the way they would do that in this case is they would regulate that the ones that are Built to be mounted in cars like the in-car like the ones that come with cars would be subject to this.
Speaker 1: and Unless you're an uber hacker who knows how to you know, root it and fuck with it You couldn't load software on it because it's a walled garden.
Speaker 1: Not even a walled garden.
Speaker 1: You're walled out of the garden.
Speaker 0: The question is right.
Speaker 0: if you know, basically car GPS is like that, you know Like those specific car devices were gimped in this way.
Speaker 0: Would that hurt their sales?
Speaker 1: Oh, I think it would destroy their sales meaning they're gonna lobby against this new, right?
Speaker 0: So basically they're gonna make a law that basically puts those companies out of business.
Speaker 0: if it's hell if it's enforced and Just everyone gets smartphones or you know In fact that can actually beneficial because then a lot of people who don't have smartphones.
Speaker 0: and Now, you know can't you get a GPS that does?
Speaker 0: that will end up having to get a crappier GP.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We don't know.
Speaker 1: Yep to quote every current Navigation system uses the car as a fixed point and shows the map moving around it.
Speaker 1: The NH TSA wants that change was to keep the map fixed.
Speaker 0: Well, there have to be some.
Speaker 0: they'll be.
Speaker 0: might some be like some black market for old bootleg?
Speaker 0: You know some old GPS devices that still do it this way.
Speaker 1: I Think there would be.
Speaker 1: now I would argue obviously like I agree with you that we would have to do some real studies.
Speaker 1: But I would argue that my guess is to where this legislation is coming from.
Speaker 1: is that people are You know, they want to do something about distracted driving.
Speaker 1: We know it's a real problem and they can't easily legislate against things like eating an apple.
Speaker 1: I mean look how much trouble they had even trying to make the phone talking stuff Despite the fact that the evidence shows that talking on any phone hands free or not has equal damage to your ability to navigate safely, but Most of the most of the commentary I see on this people saying yeah, you shouldn't even use a GPS.
Speaker 1: Just read a map, but I have seen studies saying that the safest way to navigate in unfamiliar terrain road signs Actually is GPS.
Speaker 1: Mmm, but that's assuming you have situational awareness of the road signs and such.
Speaker 1: But for example, imagine if you have to take a detour and you know, you memorized your route.
Speaker 1: You printed some map quest you looked at maps along the way, but you didn't memorize like, you know bumblefuck town next to the highway Halfway along your route.
Speaker 1: You can't memorize every map in the world.
Speaker 1: So what's safer?
Speaker 0: trying to look at a map while you're driving trying to hit your phone and tell it to reroute or the GPS That automatically reroute exactly.
Speaker 1: So I think this whole thing's silly and driven probably I'm gonna stereotype here By old people who are mad about GPS is who knows.
Speaker 1: but uh The NH TSA was in the news again Because they miss have something interesting.
Speaker 1: They said that every driver's ed in America teaches bullshit way to drive.
Speaker 0: That might be true.
Speaker 1: the specific one They say is that putting your hands at 10 and 2 which is what everyone says you should do Which actually I was taught in real driving school specifically not to do.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm is a terrible way to drive.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really matter.
Speaker 0: Yes, it does matter that much.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It does your hands Scott.
Speaker 1: Have you ever heard of push-pull?
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of different like sort of techniques to turning.
Speaker 1: push-pull is when you put your hands lower And when you want to turn right instead of like kind of pulling with your left hand like over the top.
Speaker 1: Your hand is lower and you push up with the right hand and you have a lot more maneuvering and movement of the wheel before the other hand has to take over, you know, I never really thought about how I and Think about it.
Speaker 1: you often you probably hand overhand it when you're turning quickly.
Speaker 0: I don't know how.
Speaker 0: I'm just trying to imagine doing it, but I can't because it's like Imagining it versus you know, it's not you know, and because I'm consciously thinking about it I'm not sure how I do it when it's just a motor reflex and I'm not doing it.
Speaker 1: so I guess the driving instruction I got because I learned a little bit from some police and from other some other people that were Interesting as opposed to just driver's ed.
Speaker 1: They talked a lot about like when to do hand over hand and where to put your hands and how would you put your hands?
Speaker 1: all that stuff.
Speaker 1: and Basically, the the reason they're bringing this up isn't the control factor though I've seen many studies talking about how it's better to put your hands different positions Yeah But it's that airbags will break your arms if you're attending to
Speaker 0: that is true
Speaker 1: or that your hands will be knocked off of the wheel And you won't be able to control the car as easily.
Speaker 0: That's also true.
Speaker 0: didn't think about that, but it's absolutely true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't think about that at all.
Speaker 1: I saw the article and I was thinking all about like technique one thing I was driving And they were like airbags.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh one thing I always wondered right is like you look and it's like every car has a circle steering wheel, right?
Speaker 0: But you look at like f1 cars and they sort of this rectangular steering with handles on the side.
Speaker 1: Also, that's think about the wheel play of how how far you do they have to hand overhand that thing?
Speaker 0: No This is the thing that I'm getting to right an f1 car if you turn it like basically like, you know 90 degrees to the left that's all the way left and 90 degrees to the right.
Speaker 0: That's all the way, right?
Speaker 0: It doesn't?
Speaker 0: you don't turn it around more than one, you know, so Scott the reason why are the dry?
Speaker 0: Why are the steering wheels in cars?
Speaker 0: So Unsensitive that you have to turn them so much because we could easily change that.
Speaker 1: No, we can't.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of one.
Speaker 1: the faster you're going the more effect the slight angle of the wheel has on your.
Speaker 1: you know Vector mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So and f1 car is going so fast that you need the ultra sensitive one because the tiniest little will to put the car crazily in a different direction.
Speaker 1: So and also they're driving in a very different kind of environment.
Speaker 1: The wheels are different.
Speaker 1: almost everything about those cars is different.
Speaker 1: Normal cars have to drive at both five to ten miles an hour.
Speaker 1: You know parking parking lots maneuvering around and eighty ninety miles an hour on the freeway.
Speaker 1: You need a wheel Ratio that fits all of those situations and don't say dynamic because there's no safe and Cost-effective way to do that in current cars.
Speaker 0: Your steering is power controlled.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's drive by wire.
Speaker 0: You're not right.
Speaker 0: who's right?
Speaker 0: unless you your power steering fails and you have to use like crack and pain.
Speaker 1: I'll use a simpler argument rather than trying to get into the details of it.
Speaker 1: Would you trust the average person on the road if they had an extremely sensitive steering wheel?
Speaker 0: They're already not trustworthy on the road.
Speaker 0: So what difference does it make?
Speaker 1: I would argue would probably make them work.
Speaker 0: At least it should be customizable.
Speaker 1: also a Power steering can fail.
Speaker 1: it does and having the your car has failed in your ass and having the early Means you can still leverage the wheel and bring yourself to all stop.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: there are a lot of reasons why we use the circle.
Speaker 0: I mean some people say would you but then again even if you have the ultra sensitive steering wheel if it fails it could unlock And then you could spin it around a whole bunch of times.
Speaker 1: Yes You really want normal people driving cars to have a wheel sensitivity that changes on them all of a sudden.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, it's you know, it's if it feels natural.
Speaker 0: You won't even realize it, right?
Speaker 0: Just sort of you know.
Speaker 0: No, like you won't.
Speaker 0: even people won't even realize their wheel sensitive is changing even though it is if it's done properly Unless it changes in an emergency situation like that and they never run into emergency situations.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you know if the power steering is out the card be like holy fuck.
Speaker 0: your steering is broken.
Speaker 1: now It's all moot.
Speaker 1: You know why we don't need to change?
Speaker 1: because robot cars will be here before We could train people to use something other than the current wheel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I hope so Doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: I just thought it was interesting that the NHTSA came in on two things and I agree with one and disagree with one and I don't know the bunch of times.
Speaker 1: It's synchronicity.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so here's pretty much the biggest tech ish story that there is period going around the Internet's these days.
Speaker 0: That's the Facebook password deal, right?
Speaker 1: Not the mega upload thing, which is still pretty big news.
Speaker 0: That's a little older story, but it's you know, it's still going.
Speaker 0: This is this is the big one right now.
Speaker 0: At least it's definitely the higher headline in Google News.
Speaker 1: This has been going on Stories about this for like the last four Right.
Speaker 0: Well the deal is that for months and for quite a while right companies and schools and all kinds of various people right have been sort of asking and or forcing and or Coercing potential employees current employees students whoever someone in subservient positions, you know Or disadvantaged bargaining positions to give up You know Facebook passwords email passwords or to log into accounts and let people, you know teachers, you know administrators Yeah Bosses potential bosses.
Speaker 0: Now, look, we're not at their private information We're not talking about.
Speaker 1: tell me what your Facebook account ID is.
Speaker 1: I have things to say about that too, but that's not this problem, right?
Speaker 0: And then you know look at those things before deciding to hire.
Speaker 0: Suspend.
Speaker 0: all kinds of things right schools jobs all kinds of places not just school.
Speaker 0: Those are the only ones I can think of right now.
Speaker 0: And the reason this is news because it's been ongoing Is that Facebook came out and they're gonna try to fight this shit, which is like fuck.
Speaker 0: Yeah Facebook you go for it.
Speaker 0: Yep, right because it's really like no matter how much we tell people right and I can't reiterate this enough.
Speaker 0: under no circumstances None whatsoever Should you ever tell any other human being on the planet Earth past present future living or dead?
Speaker 0: Your password to anything not even your spouse not even your own mother.
Speaker 1: I'm going to qualify that with some exceptions not even anything.
Speaker 1: It's not exception one old systems where there isn't the concept of users.
Speaker 1: There is a password.
Speaker 0: Well, okay that isn't your password then is it?
Speaker 1: ah Okay, so you as long as it cuz and secondly upgrade that shit fast.
Speaker 0: That should be priority.
Speaker 0: You know there are.
Speaker 1: there are things like a shared account for specific purposes that can make sense though There are usually better ways to go about it.
Speaker 1: Not every system allows right but if it's your personal thing that is like basically email Facebook like your slash dot account anything like that Never ever ever ever right.
Speaker 0: and you might be thinking well, wait a minute There is.
Speaker 0: you might be thinking wait, there must be a crazy situation where you have to for example rim I die.
Speaker 0: I'm the only one with the passwords like the geek nights web server.
Speaker 0: I need to fix that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so your password should be in escrow with the lawyer.
Speaker 0: That's not even necessary because I'm dead.
Speaker 0: you and the lawyers can go to line ode and You can get the account reset and transfer it over to you because when you inherit the things that belong to me you inherit Belong.
Speaker 1: what if for example, I use Windows encryption So my account is encrypted and unless you actually know the password there is no way to get the data?
Speaker 0: This is why you have some sort of thing in a safe deposit box.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Someone can inherit.
Speaker 0: it's called escrow But that's not telling it to anyone.
Speaker 0: That's putting it in a safe deposit box or the key and then someone can inherit that key when you are dead?
Speaker 1: Yep at best the the same as the keys to your house Even if you tell it to someone.
Speaker 1: that would be a situation where you give it in confidence to for example an escrow company And there's a reason why you can't encrypt.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to tell it to a person though.
Speaker 0: You could just put it on a piece of paper in a safe box that no one looks at but you anyway.
Speaker 1: The the sheer idea that anyone would ask you for something so blatant, you know Even you know edge cases aside for your Facebook.
Speaker 1: And
Speaker 0: the thing is even someone who is smart enough to know this rule because you know that you should never tell it to anyone Ever even a smart person who knows that and I'm sure most of the listeners already are smart enough to know that There are situations where you could be disadvantaged, you know and sort of you know be coerced or forced into giving it up.
Speaker 0: if I'm desperate for a job and I can't Even eat and some guy says hey if you want this job, it's the only job you can get fucker Let me look at your Facebook to make sure that you know, you're kosher Even though you know, it's bad.
Speaker 0: You might be willing to do it Yep, and that the thing is.
Speaker 1: that's why we need someone like Facebook to not.
Speaker 0: you didn't even get socially engineered Right.
Speaker 0: You just got socially owned which is not fair Yep.
Speaker 1: So we need someone big a juggernaut with money to take this to court and fight it cuz they'll win.
Speaker 1: they'll win so hard for reasons I don't really want to bother getting into but yeah, but One thing I could say is that I have asked that question before occasionally when I've interviewed people Because if they if they agree they stop easily.
Speaker 0: no and you never hire them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would.
Speaker 1: that's basically a deal-breaker.
Speaker 1: Anyone who would give me their password?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I see no not safe.
Speaker 0: I see no problem with the actual asking.
Speaker 1: right if you want to ask someone for their path Because actually the laws will probably say that you cannot even ask because you can't even ask for example What someone's gender identity is you can't ask them how old they are.
Speaker 0: That's different.
Speaker 0: that's only in a job situation, but that's the job situation.
Speaker 0: But I mean, I'm just saying, you know, I don't think there's anything wrong with asking someone.
Speaker 0: Here's one a rim.
Speaker 0: Do you want to tell me your password?
Speaker 1: So Scott if I am interviewing you for a job and I ask you that it could be a problem.
Speaker 1: You want to know why your Facebook account may well have information about you that I'm not allowed to ask about like religion race Of course Sexual orientation, but I'm saying it's if you actually were to look at the Facebook account with that pass.
Speaker 1: Oh Most of the laws are geared around asking the question Mmm or asking for access, but that's.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about morality.
Speaker 0: I'm not I don't care about.
Speaker 0: you know, the laws are crazy Whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't not a lawyer, but I'm saying I don't think you know.
Speaker 0: personally I don't feel there's anything wrong with asking the question.
Speaker 0: I feel if you answer it truthfully you're dumb and - you shouldn't look and you should just say yeah, I'm not hiring you because obviously you're a security threat to this company.
Speaker 1: Well, the important thing is that Facebook is fighting this because non technologists Especially people who are also in a desperate economic situation are pretty much fucked and would have to you know Give up whatever the person asks.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So we need someone to fight for them and I guess Facebook's the only one who's yeah Well Facebook says there it could take legal action, but it has no immediate plans to sue any specific employers.
Speaker 0: So I think basically this is the ultimatum which is like hey stop doing it or we're coming we're gonna.
Speaker 0: you know We could come after you and you'll see.
Speaker 0: if any I'm sure if the someone who was like a huge Continuous flagrant violator will be targeted by the lawyers to bring the smackdown to set an example if this wasn't enough.
Speaker 1: so Japan They don't really have free speech in Japan, but Japan did the thing that everyone drives As free as it is here.
Speaker 1: well, yeah most places aren't yeah But they did the thing that a lot of people try to do and I'm not I don't want to talk about the details of This I want to talk about it kind of a more fundamental problem here.
Speaker 1: So the Japanese court ordered ordered Google to disable auto complete for its search engine.
Speaker 0: So just for everybody period yep, or at least all the autocompute or at least everyone in Japan.
Speaker 0: So just turn off all autocompletes everywhere.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And now it's not like.
Speaker 1: this was a you know a pending.
Speaker 1: This was the court straight-up ordered it.
Speaker 1: Google said fuck you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course But basically the reason is that someone in Japan filed suit saying that if you type his name into autocomplete.
Speaker 1: Most of the suggestions are associated with criminal behavior because apparently there's someone with the same name as him who was a criminal.
Speaker 0: Alright, there's a lot of.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of people named Scott Reuben.
Speaker 0: if you type in Scott Reuben and it starts to autocomplete Let's see what happens.
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: so The that's an old news, you know, Google says producer filmography Willow Creek Facebook, so, you know, oh I'm not a Producer, right?
Speaker 0: This is bullshit.
Speaker 0: This is false advertising Right.
Speaker 1: I'm see what I want to talk about the fact that Google said no and that Japan tried this crap.
Speaker 1: and the people don't understand Technology, it's old news the new.
Speaker 1: the interesting part here Is that the common theme in a lot of these problems isn't even people trying to hide information about themselves though that may be the case here, but How can we live in a world where any human being?
Speaker 1: Would do a Google search for someone maybe because they're hiring them or whatever?
Speaker 1: look at the first hit they see and Blindly assume that is in fact John Smith the serial rapist As opposed to John Smith the guy who applied for a job like.
Speaker 1: in what world is that?
Speaker 1: Actually a problem and apparently this one.
Speaker 0: Yeah There was a great.
Speaker 0: Oh, what was it?
Speaker 0: Hold on.
Speaker 0: I got a fine.
Speaker 0: Hope it's still there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, here it is.
Speaker 0: The top link on reddit as we speak says The title of it is Samuel Clemens dropping the knowledge and as you know, that's Mark Twain, right?
Speaker 0: So It says right here.
Speaker 0: This is the quote Censorship is telling a man.
Speaker 0: He can't have a steak just because a baby can't chew it and that is so appropriate to this.
Speaker 1: That's one of my favorite.
Speaker 1: Okay, so if I type rim I get of Bedford, how about the underwear brand?
Speaker 0: is it still around?
Speaker 1: Oh, well it is but the if I the autocomplete is rim of Bedford, okay, uh, which is in Brooklyn.
Speaker 0: Yeah bed stay.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's also rim incorporated.
Speaker 1: That's the underwear I think.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: What do they make trying to figure this out?
Speaker 0: so just because a baby can't tell the difference between rim the podcaster and the clock setter and Rim the underwear company Doesn't mean that we should.
Speaker 0: smart people should not be able to have our stake of Google autocomplete.
Speaker 0: Just cuz babies can't chew it.
Speaker 0: and that is censorship which is all over in Japan.
Speaker 0: Japan censors the porn.
Speaker 0: They put the mosaics over it.
Speaker 0: They censor political speeches actually rules about like, you know, how many flyers you can send out during elections and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now that's a complicated issue because obviously I'm not saying it's good or bad I'm just saying it is censorship and they have it in many areas.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: They were their recent talks about those laws censoring various mangas or animes in Tokyo that were threatening and so they have all kinds of stuff that is censoring over there and in Most countries in the world right?
Speaker 0: Japan is not alone You know, they're just a little more sensory than us and a little less sensory than China.
Speaker 0: It's you know, it's just how it goes.
Speaker 1: So you have another news.
Speaker 1: you want me to keep going?
Speaker 0: I Pretty much don't have news, but I can look for one.
Speaker 1: All right, so an MIT professor This is an interesting article Basically made a very lofty statement a y+50 which we know.
Speaker 1: y+30 is impossible.
Speaker 1: So I can't imagine.
Speaker 1: y+50 argues that it is possible that within 50 years.
Speaker 1: We as humans can literally end Disability in any practical sense.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I believe that.
Speaker 0: I mean I see where he's going right because we have managed to counter even today a lot of disabilities, right?
Speaker 0: Some blind people depending on the cause of blindness can be made to see again with things like eye donations or you know Implanting like cameras into your body that are wired into your nerves or brain, you know We can.
Speaker 0: people can see like that with low resolution.
Speaker 0: We've got all sorts of you know ear implants to fix some forms of hearing loss now already in with cochlear implants are where you see the first.
Speaker 1: it's more I think social problems are going to be a much bigger drain on this being reality than Technological problem because the reason he made there are people who've lost limbs.
Speaker 0: obviously now
Speaker 1: The reason he believes this is actually kind of sad but also hopeful that the two wars America started recently brought back a huge number of severely disabled people and This is
Speaker 0: called only certain kinds of disabilities though
Speaker 1: but this has caused a huge explosion in the prosthetics industry and prosthetics research and Actually, it's been kind of quietly advancing for the past decade to a degree that is almost ludicrous.
Speaker 1: and he has all these examples of Basically most of the prosthetics that are advanced today that we're seeing like on TV like the runners and the climbers and everything Didn't exist until very recently and are progressing very rapidly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I mean if you're only talking about that kind of disability, you know the missing limb sort of disability.
Speaker 0: Then I actually probably agree with him that in 50 years if you have that kind of disability and you can afford it That you will be able to basically not only you know that you know Have some sort of replacement part that is basically equivalent to the lost part or perhaps even better
Speaker 1: Although while
Speaker 0: it may risk, you know be equivalent motor function, you know, you can walk you can pick things up You can do all those things.
Speaker 0: I don't know if we'll actually be able to restore full feeling.
Speaker 0: You know, maybe in 50 years they'll definitely will be some amount of feeling restoration, but that's a very narrow Category of disability true, but what if you have?
Speaker 0: what if we expand this a little bit?
Speaker 1: I mean, we're already at the point where there are a lot of severe genetic disorders or Congenital disorders that can be detected in the womb.
Speaker 0: So what if I Are you talking about not having those babies?
Speaker 1: Of genetic testing and abortion and You know things like that and also treatments, you know genetic treatments We're able to eliminate maybe not a hundred percent of disability.
Speaker 1: But what if we get to the point to where we look at back at a wheelchair and that's this kind of archaic You know old barbaric way people had to get around because yeah Because we're rich people living in the fancy country, right?
Speaker 0: It's not gonna be true for the whole world Not at first 50 years that for sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah first so, you know Definitely among a class of people who you know hat is does that and is willing to do that and wants to do that Right, and you know does, you know test and not have babies that disabilities.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be a lot less of that particular kind of disability.
Speaker 0: But there are still even then even then there are still lots of disabilities that come about that you there.
Speaker 0: We still don't see them coming and there's not much we can do about it.
Speaker 0: like we're making Hawking, right?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna fix Stephen Hawking in 50 years.
Speaker 0: I don't think.
Speaker 1: maybe actually we're like to see we're making surprising strides in a lot of Neurodegenerative order disorders and things like that.
Speaker 1: if I don't see 50 years, right 50 years in current science is a law.
Speaker 0: But I don't see I do a hundred percent fit.
Speaker 0: He's talking a hundred percent fixing.
Speaker 0: No disability.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, I You know, that's the stretch Scott.
Speaker 1: I think he's being a little bit.
Speaker 1: I Think he's being a little exaggerated on purpose.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no kidding.
Speaker 1: But also I think for people who can afford them and at least, you know for the West for the like the industrialized world I think within 50 years there will be a great decrease in the occurrences of any sort of Visible disability.
Speaker 0: and people I would say that you know plus, you know, I guess also I just want to toss this aside in there.
Speaker 0: Right, there are things that technically legally count as disability but aren't disability.
Speaker 0: Like if you're pregnant as this, you know, you can get disability payment, whatever and we won't have babies in 50 years.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: But I think that is definitely true Right that there is has been and continues to be a huge increase in our you know technological ability to Assist or mitigate disabilities of a wide array and that the trend is clearly Going upwards and will not cease.
Speaker 0: and with such a long runway There will be a ginormous amount of progress in that area.
Speaker 1: Now what I do wonder is that look at the huge Controversy in the deaf community over cochlear implants even though it's more and more youth Don't see a controversy at all and think the whole thing's ridiculous.
Speaker 1: But I wonder if we'll see the same thing with the wheelchair.
Speaker 1: I Wonder if there will be people who will argue that we should keep the wheelchair even if we have a in every way better solution.
Speaker 0: Well, what are you doing?
Speaker 0: Is it right?
Speaker 0: this brings in all sorts of other questions, right?
Speaker 0: Like okay, we can repair legs and make them awesome right just like we have the perfect leg replacements robot leg.
Speaker 0: Yep Okay, so who uses wheelchairs?
Speaker 0: because they can't walk?
Speaker 0: a lot of people some people Because they lost a leg.
Speaker 0: Okay, obviously you lose a leg you get a robot leg.
Speaker 0: No one's really gonna argue with that right?
Speaker 0: What if I never had a leg?
Speaker 0: Okay, well maybe robot leg not.
Speaker 0: maybe no one's really gonna complain about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I see what if I'm an old lady or an old dude and my leg is just all weak Should I go get her and I'm using a wheelchair?
Speaker 0: cuz I've you know I just have we got legs of 90 years old that I go get robot leg.
Speaker 0: That
Speaker 1: is a personal choice and I think once again that independent of all other factors The biggest thing that will hold this back in the next 50 years will just be people's hesitance to give up their humanity Mm-hmm and or people's hesitance to Experience invasive surgery and also, you know, there will be physical things
Speaker 0: whether there's nothing wrong with my leg.
Speaker 0: I just want to win the running race And I go and you know, but then there's some law that says oh you can only get robot leg if you lost your leg.
Speaker 1: You know quote legitimate, but then there will be a rise in oops.
Speaker 1: I got run over by a car.
Speaker 1: Oops, just on my leg.
Speaker 0: I fucked around with the Mafia on purpose.
Speaker 1: Somehow I don't think the Mafia would leave you in a position to get a robot leg.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying unless you were assuming the break in the nose thing is they don't know.
Speaker 0: is that I'm still with the Mafia?
Speaker 0: They're gonna bet on me and they're in the robot leg race.
Speaker 0: Right, we're gonna.
Speaker 0: they run over my legs then I got robot leg.
Speaker 0: then they Spend a lot of money to get the even better robot leg.
Speaker 0: We're getting into the robot race and the mafia is betting on me in the robot race.
Speaker 1: I think in 50 years, we're gonna see.
Speaker 0: maybe if I'll say this within a hundred years I'm like the boxer who throws all the fights.
Speaker 1: I think we're gonna have a surprising an Analog to the ghost in the shell world where the ultra-rich who need it actually have completely aesthetic bodies and pretty much any good Sci-fi, you're gonna find some analog in the real world.
Speaker 0: That's just how it works.
Speaker 0: Oh, gee, we're living in the brave new world world.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Oh, we're living in the 1984.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think goes in the shell is more Predictive of our current social trends than a lot of other science fiction.
Speaker 0: Well, obviously if you just take all the science fiction there ever was sure.
Speaker 0: but I'm talking about the good stuff the stuff that's relevant The people that people know and keep bringing up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know why.
Speaker 0: the people know it and keep bringing it up because it partially came true and is coming more true.
Speaker 1: Make a second to suggest it's the other way around.
Speaker 1: those people are still in college.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: But it's you know, this is what you don't realize.
Speaker 0: It's the other way around.
Speaker 0: why you know, it's like oh the good stuff comes true It's like.
Speaker 0: no It's not.
Speaker 0: it's you know It is the good stuff because it already is or has or is coming true or it's an idea That's so either disturbing or pervasive or appealing that people are kind of in the last questions coming.
Speaker 1: Society is guided toward it.
Speaker 1: I mean how much of our scientific advancement has Mirrored science fiction partly because people are inspired by science fiction.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at what point is our society a feedback loop?
Speaker 0: even they're made of meat.
Speaker 0: It's coming true.
Speaker 1: Is it?
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, we are made of meat.
Speaker 1: I know we haven't True.
Speaker 1: in fact, it's becoming less true.
Speaker 1: We're replacing our meat with non-meat.
Speaker 0: The opposite is happening I know but that's the whole story.
Speaker 0: You don't get it.
Speaker 0: Where are the visiting guys?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I forgot that we used to be made of meat.
Speaker 1: Not yet.
Speaker 1: There's no one to visit.
Speaker 0: It's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Maybe there will be.
Speaker 0: it's coming.
Speaker 1: That's coming But for example 1984 only came to pass it like in North Korea.
Speaker 0: Hey, it just is it for someone.
Speaker 0: That's the most relevant book there.
Speaker 1: Well, anyway, you got a news or I gotta keep going.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I pretty much didn't find any tech news.
Speaker 0: cuz like I said, I'm not reading that much internet.
Speaker 0: How did you want to give and go here?
Speaker 1: Let's do one more.
Speaker 1: I don't want to.
Speaker 1: I'll skip the Interpol thing.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about mega upload because I got a lot to say about that.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: No, not not the court case Not piracy.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna have any of the arguments that anyone else has had.
Speaker 1: There's a problem.
Speaker 0: the same argument we've been having for 15 years did not anticipate.
Speaker 1: so mega upload paid for hosting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, someone hosted all that data.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well, they hosted in quite a few places mega upload.
Speaker 1: Uh Can't make any more money because of court injunctions and the fact that their The sites down.
Speaker 1: yeah law enforcement wants access to that data.
Speaker 1: So do all of the legitimate customers of the company The people who are hosting the data Don't want to host it for free and shouldn't have to?
Speaker 1: if mega upload weren't under any sort of legal injunction and they just you Know stop paying that ISP would probably just delete their goddamn data.
Speaker 1: But now we're in a situation where whose Obligation is it to pay the hosting company to continue to host mega uploads data?
Speaker 1: Until the court case is sorted out because there are legitimate customers who have a legitimate claim to that data.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the answer is other than that.
Speaker 1: I feel like the prosecution which in this case may or may not be involving the government.
Speaker 1: or Maybe the government or the courts should pay it for the time being and then whoever loses the case may or may not have to Pay it in the end.
Speaker 0: Well, I just wonder what normally happens in these situations, right?
Speaker 0: like what if you know the government, you know comes and You know, I have a small business and the government, you know shuts me down, but I'm innocent till proven guilty, right?
Speaker 0: But there's a court injunction that shuts me down, right?
Speaker 0: So what normally happens?
Speaker 0: How do I pay my electric bill and that who pays my electric bill in that situation, right?
Speaker 0: Do I have to pay it for my savings, you know, obviously if I win the case do I get the money back?
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: and then what?
Speaker 0: if the elect, you know, I don't that was all my money and I get my electricity shut off You know, do I just have to?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty much just fucked until you know the.
Speaker 0: you know Get proven innocent and then get you know, some sort of compensation, you know there are a lot of.
Speaker 0: I just read a story about a guy who was wrongfully in jail for a long fucking time and Just because he was in Washington State He didn't get shit that he just got set free.
Speaker 0: and that was it where if he was in another state He would have gotten hundreds of thousands of dollars.
Speaker 1: I feel like so in cases like this.
Speaker 1: it's one of those situations where there is no good answer and Whenever there's no good answer.
Speaker 1: There's a government answer, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like I think the government should front this money out of tax dollars because there's no better option.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: And it's like you can't?
Speaker 0: you know?
Speaker 0: Just and your thing is you're not just punishing the dude right, you know innocence of proven guilty, whatever.
Speaker 0: He has customers that you're punishing.
Speaker 0: What if I was a dry cleaner?
Speaker 0: and how these clothes in there?
Speaker 0: and but you shut my ass down now What about all these people who own those fucking clothes?
Speaker 1: I wasn't laundering money through the dry cleaner.
Speaker 0: I dropped off an $800 suit to be dry clean and now you can't get it Right because you can't.
Speaker 0: and it's like cuz they you know The.
Speaker 0: I didn't pay rent and the building is closed and the landlord refuses to open it.
Speaker 0: Now you got to sue the landlord which means does we had to sue the hosting company to get the files off?
Speaker 0: mega upload You know, but if the government's forcing them to do it, it's like, ah, it's a really really bad situation.
Speaker 1: No, I feel like.
Speaker 1: I don't know if this would come to pass But if the government in this case just this particular case We're forced to guarantee the bill for as long as the data had to be held there.
Speaker 1: the government would have a sudden big incentive to sort this shit out quickly and Nothing is sorted out quickly.
Speaker 0: court shit takes multiple years I know so.
Speaker 1: but maybe we could make an incentive structure where the government in the very least Wants to make the data available for some grace period to let everybody download whatever they've got up there that they need and then Shut it down.
Speaker 0: This is one of those situations.
Speaker 0: We just I think you just need a judge to come in quickly and fix this thing.
Speaker 0: You know that is clearly holding everything up, right?
Speaker 0: You know, there's this huge limbo.
Speaker 0: you need some smart judge to be like, all right This is what we gonna do, right?
Speaker 0: We're gonna put all these servers online and download only mode for you know This period of time or we're gonna make some sort of thing.
Speaker 0: We go through all the legitimate accounts and we mail everyone, you know a disk with their files on it And so, you know or whatever and then that's it.
Speaker 0: You just need something.
Speaker 0: but the thing is this evidence in there, right?
Speaker 0: So but you don't lose the evidence.
Speaker 0: who's supposed to pay for the taking of the care of the evidence?
Speaker 1: But in this case in the very least you don't lose the evidence if you let everyone download their stuff and that at least Reduces the total harm Servers around the company.
Speaker 1: Yes, the hosting company is getting fucked here But if you let everyone download their stuff It reduces the total harm.
Speaker 1: as the result of the court It does all the legitimate customers can get their data and they're no longer involved.
Speaker 1: It reduces the problem because now if they do decide to delete the data or the police have to pay for it or whatever They don't have to consider the feelings of all the people who were fucked by, you know The externalities of the situation because they got their data.
Speaker 1: They're fine.
Speaker 0: I think that's something else right?
Speaker 0: The problem is this hosting company, right and it's like well this stuff is evidence and that's why they're supposed to keep it.
Speaker 0: But where does evidence usually go?
Speaker 0: Usually it's confiscated.
Speaker 1: Ah, but Scott brought it to an evidence place What is say there was a murder in our apartment like a hobo broke in and then another hobo broke in.
Speaker 1: there's a murder.
Speaker 1: So the government, you know the police block off my apartment and they investigate it for like a month that I can't come in.
Speaker 1: Do I get compensated?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: what does ask a lawyer what I don't know.
Speaker 0: I have no idea what happens.
Speaker 1: So but the problem is at least those cases are you know what?
Speaker 0: you know?
Speaker 0: who covers that your insurance?
Speaker 1: Yep Here's the problem.
Speaker 1: Here's why this is an interesting story with these mass.
Speaker 0: I wonder if there's any insurance companies involved in this.
Speaker 1: with these massive technology Situations, you know a massive court action that shuts down a server used by millions of people.
Speaker 1: It's as though a murder happens in an apartment building and we block off the entire city block.
Speaker 1: The scale is so great that we can't just treat this the same way.
Speaker 1: we treat similar situations because far too many people are affected.
Speaker 1: I mean already if there's a you know a death on the freeway We shut the freeway down for like an hour or so and cause huge problems for everyone else while we sort it out.
Speaker 1: Imagine if we shut the freeway down for a month.
Speaker 1: Are we shot all the freeways down in an entire state because there was one deadly accident?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know usually this stuff it does, you know doesn't get?
Speaker 0: you know It caused a huge ruckus because oh no, we blocked off one dude's apartment.
Speaker 0: Well sucks for that one, dude That guy has insurance.
Speaker 1: Maybe the you know, the judge is sympathetic and right makes an agreement.
Speaker 0: my dry cleaner example one, dude This is thousands upon thousands of people, you know getting held up and the hosting company getting held up big time.
Speaker 0: So this is like a you know Isn't something?
Speaker 1: that's why the hosting company is the one that filed an emergency motion.
Speaker 1: They're the ones that said look It's an emergency motion.
Speaker 0: How can the judge?
Speaker 0: it doesn't seem too much of emergency.
Speaker 0: The judge doesn't done shit.
Speaker 1: We.
Speaker 0: it's an emergency To go.
Speaker 0: take care of it.
Speaker 1: You want us to keep this data for your evidence and we want to do the right thing and not delete You know all these customers data.
Speaker 1: We just want to guarantee that someone's gonna pay for this.
Speaker 0: Yeah $9,000 a day I heard That's actually not that much money.
Speaker 0: in that in the scale of hosting that we're talking I can't think of any reels, you know straight up any.
Speaker 0: all the straight-up answers seem wrong.
Speaker 0: Like should mega upload have to pay?
Speaker 0: no not unless you let them restart their business.
Speaker 0: Should the hosting company have to pay?
Speaker 0: No, she's the one doesn't pay their bill because the company shuts them There.
Speaker 1: should the individual users have to do some sort of class action.
Speaker 1: No, that's BS.
Speaker 0: That's also Bureaucracy of the government have to pay.
Speaker 0: Well, no, why should the government pay?
Speaker 1: There is an argument that the government should pay because some but it's all.
Speaker 1: at the other hand no Yeah But one one function of government is that it deals with the things that private enterprise the free market individual people and society as a whole Cannot deal with.
Speaker 0: but that's a huge cost for society to bear especially if it turns out that there actually are guilty and that in the end they do shut down the servers because it's like Oh, we had to pay to keep these fucking servers up.
Speaker 1: That's why I think we need two situations.
Speaker 1: one the government should pay But to.
Speaker 1: the government should have a huge incentive to reduce the stakeholder You know the breadth of stakeholders in the situation as much as possible.
Speaker 1: the government should pay for the hosting they should.
Speaker 1: the judge should mandate that the company and mega upload allow read-only access to all The files to all their users, even if people download infringing things.
Speaker 1: who cares For?
Speaker 0: like judge?
Speaker 1: He shouldn't because the infringing stuff is already the court case.
Speaker 1: If another five people download an mp3 that damage is far less than the millions of people with legit files.
Speaker 0: And then but then right now the RA MPs will sue the judge and the court.
Speaker 1: now I think that this is a case where the judge to have the authority to tell them to go fuck themselves.
Speaker 1: They've already got a pretty solid case.
Speaker 0: They're gonna win the case anyway, they're gonna win it actually.
Speaker 0: Think it's like 7525 right?
Speaker 0: just It's like normally.
Speaker 0: I would say 50/50 just based on you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: Well, I have a complicated opinion.
Speaker 1: my my personal goal, but corruption goes into there.
Speaker 1: My personal goal is that even though yeah mega upload was pretty much just like the worst pirates.
Speaker 0: But if you look at his case, he's actually working pretty easy.
Speaker 0: He's fighting it like the true fight Up on his side.
Speaker 1: I hate the RIAA More than I hate most organizations in the world and it's to the point to where I really just want to see him go down Even though I don't want it to be just a straight-up copyright free-for-all.
Speaker 1: I still want there to be music industry.
Speaker 1: I want all these things to happen.
Speaker 1: I want a reasonable answer.
Speaker 1: The RIAA has excluded all reasonable answers and I really I'll let a lot of things burn down if they get burned down with it.
Speaker 1: And I think we're done.
Speaker 1: tech news roundup great.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Speaker 1: music can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.