Speaker 2: Are we good?
Speaker 2: Is it working?
Speaker 1: That's working fine.
Speaker 1: Is everyone working?
Speaker 1: Yes, everyone's working fine.
Speaker 2: Okay, you ready?
Speaker 0: One time I saw a goose.
Speaker 1: So we're here, we're here with Conrad Kraling.
Speaker 1: Many of you may know him from the internet.
Speaker 2: Yeah, our fans, it seems it's weird.
Speaker 2: It's like people are, I guess they listen to our show and they say they're our fans, even though I tell them not to listen to our show, but all they want to hear on our show is people who aren't us.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 2: People who are on the show only once, like, you know, a separate weird situation.
Speaker 1: If I had a listener not that long ago at an event, say, wait a minute, you know, Conrad, the guy from Johnny Wander?
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: People will be like, oh man, the best episodes of Geek Nights.
Speaker 2: How about, you know, fast karate for the Geek Nights, the one they always say is the food episodes.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: We should do a show on food.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 2: But anyway, so by popular demand, we have brought back.
Speaker 1: So Conrad, the corn bed, we've heard that you've seen a ghost.
Speaker 0: Well, one time I did in fact see a ghost.
Speaker 0: What was it like?
Speaker 0: Well, okay.
Speaker 0: You see, I was, I was trapped in a dungeon after an entire year of imprisonment.
Speaker 0: I spent it with a dragon.
Speaker 0: Finally, I escaped on a rowboat and after about a year of drifting on the sea, I finally regained feeling in my legs.
Speaker 2: Okay.
Speaker 1: So I think Emily didn't realize until recently that every time you said that you were referencing this, this thing that we're all, she knew the thing that you were referencing, but she didn't realize that the seeing a ghost was a reference to that thing.
Speaker 0: Oh no, it's, it's perfect.
Speaker 1: It is because when you reminded me of the dragon was when you put it in the bio, you gave me for our PAX dev panel.
Speaker 2: It was dead.
Speaker 2: That was on.
Speaker 1: And you emailed me too.
Speaker 1: You were like, is it okay?
Speaker 1: And I was like, yeah, sure.
Speaker 1: And I went for it.
Speaker 1: I put it up and it's in the book.
Speaker 2: You could, anyone can get the PAX dev 2012 program and see it says right there, Conrad.
Speaker 1: It's like wearing an Ogloff shirt.
Speaker 1: People who know, know, and nobody else is the wiser.
Speaker 0: I should note that I also use that exact same bio for the mobile gaming summit bio I had to submit.
Speaker 0: And that is an industry professional like situation.
Speaker 0: I had never been happier because they printed it.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: They printed it.
Speaker 0: I tweeted it.
Speaker 0: I was like, this is the happiest day of my entire life.
Speaker 2: I'm so happy that I got a reference to, do we know who the guy is who actually made the song?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Can we like, uh, get him on the show?
Speaker 0: Probably.
Speaker 0: I would love to shake his hand with gloves on.
Speaker 1: We should say something much more important that our friend Kate usually yells at us for stupid shit on the internet.
Speaker 1: She is the one who showed us the dragon.
Speaker 2: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So it is her fault.
Speaker 2: But yet she'd probably complain if you brought it up.
Speaker 1: No, she would probably say probably.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So you might remember years ago we were doing a profiles and geek and then we kind of forgot to keep doing those,
Speaker 2: but now we're going to keep doing them
Speaker 1: because Conrad's here and we didn't want to talk about cell phones again, even
Speaker 2: though everyone wants to hear about cell phones, it's just the same shit over and over again.
Speaker 1: It's easy.
Speaker 1: Buy an iPhone.
Speaker 1: If you don't want an iPhone, buy the old nexus S.
Speaker 0: well, you can buy the nexus as the nexus.
Speaker 0: This is a pilot.
Speaker 2: You can get the next song nexus.
Speaker 0: Yes, the Samsung nexus.
Speaker 2: It's disgusting for, but it's gigantic in other ways.
Speaker 2: It's good, but it's sold out.
Speaker 2: But I point out that the majority, look, I'm limiting the cell phone discussion to three minutes.
Speaker 1: Look at my monitor here.
Speaker 1: This is Dell ultra sharp with a proper color gamut.
Speaker 1: The majority of people in the world don't know or care and they'll buy a monitor that costs a quarter as much and say it looks better.
Speaker 1: Do you think any of those people need a better screen than this screen on my nexus?
Speaker 0: I refuse to give money to any company that ships pentile matrix.
Speaker 2: It's a question of whether it's, you know, but you know, if it's better for you, but do you know it's better for you?
Speaker 1: So when I tweeted about that, I tweeted something.
Speaker 1: I was like, nobody really understands color gamut and they showed blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: And there's a Twitter account dedicated to color gamuts and they retweeted me and they emailed me and they were like, you are one of the few people in the world who understands what we care about.
Speaker 0: I will, I will go on record as saying that a non tech just did the write up of the nexus for, and the nexus for is this beautiful panel that has not been calibrated at all.
Speaker 0: They did not calibrate it in the factory and they sold out like crazy though.
Speaker 0: And a non tech was like, they didn't even, it's not even touched like the nexus for is just, it's gigantic.
Speaker 0: Huge.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: If it was this size or a smaller, I'd probably consider it my Palm pre a little while ago.
Speaker 2: Cause I have a small, it's the best size.
Speaker 1: It's thick though.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 2: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: It has a physical keyboard, which while I still kind of miss physical keyboards, I'm done with physical keyboards.
Speaker 2: Yeah, probably.
Speaker 2: It's nobody.
Speaker 1: There's very few people still type faster on my pre than I can.
Speaker 2: You guys have one minute left on this.
Speaker 0: I'm done.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So what about Google glasses?
Speaker 2: They're not coming out yet.
Speaker 1: They will someday.
Speaker 1: Did you see that new game ingress?
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: If you have an Android phone, get it.
Speaker 1: But no, it's a closed beta.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Well, if you'd got to get in the beta.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I tried.
Speaker 1: I even tried to pull rank and be like, do you know who I am?
Speaker 1: Google doesn't.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Google.
Speaker 2: Do you know who I am?
Speaker 2: Some guy who uses our fucking thing and doesn't even give a bunch of people at Google.
Speaker 1: And that has worked before it's got, I got us into some, some of our early con.
Speaker 2: I got the fucking CR 38 Chromebook thing and I don't even use it.
Speaker 1: I got some of our earliest con gigs by pulling the, do you know who I am?
Speaker 2: Sure.
Speaker 2: Anyway, let us move on.
Speaker 1: That was when I wasn't even anyone.
Speaker 2: Are we going to do news and things a day or are we going to do those later?
Speaker 2: That.
Speaker 2: Okay.
Speaker 1: So let us.
Speaker 1: Thursday.
Speaker 1: It's the lounge.
Speaker 2: So let us profile the Conrad.
Speaker 2: So the Conrad, we met you in the college.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 2: We know very vague details of your pre-college.
Speaker 0: Oh wow.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Um, our listeners don't even know about our pre-college.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 0: My family moved all around New York state.
Speaker 0: So I used to, I was born in Buffalo, but my family immediately moved as far North and as far East in New York state as you can go to base in Canada.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: On the Canada, Vermont, New York border on the New York side.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: It was in this tiny town called Rouse's point.
Speaker 0: And, um, some of my fondest memories, uh, as a child, we're going into with my father into Canada for beer, Vermont for gas, and then back home where he would make me pancakes every Saturday.
Speaker 0: And this was like a really like formative memory I had.
Speaker 0: It was, it was awesome.
Speaker 2: And I could definitely identify with that.
Speaker 2: That's good.
Speaker 0: And so.
Speaker 0: when I was nine though, we moved to Lancaster, New York, a suburb of Buffalo.
Speaker 0: Um, which is, I think now why I could never imagine living in the suburbs ever again, like suburban wasteland sort of doesn't even begin to describe it.
Speaker 0: Like we had to take the bus 45 minutes to get to the mall, which was the most exciting thing available to us.
Speaker 1: You know, it's interesting because suburbs in the Midwest, especially like Southeast Michigan, North, like Northern Ohio are not like that.
Speaker 1: There's sub.
Speaker 1: they're suburbs, right?
Speaker 1: The same kind of thing you were living in, but they're so dense.
Speaker 1: There's a grocery store, like every mile.
Speaker 1: I live near the grocery store.
Speaker 1: It's like five minutes in any direction from my house, my house.
Speaker 2: I grew up in which my parents still live in.
Speaker 2: You could walk to the mall or the grocery store, but you know, now having lived in the city, I cannot tolerate being not in a city.
Speaker 1: I can't tolerate very long.
Speaker 1: I was talking to some of your friends, Conrad, at the party last night.
Speaker 1: And we were talking about like, imagine going to a restaurant in a car.
Speaker 0: Imagine if you needed milk, you have to get into the car.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: What now to me, a car?
Speaker 1: actually, now that I don't need a car anymore, getting into a car is like this mystery time.
Speaker 1: Like, Oh my God, we're going somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I feel like a dog, right?
Speaker 0: I'm sure.
Speaker 0: I'm so excited.
Speaker 0: It's embarrassing.
Speaker 2: So being someone who lived in the stakes, how did you become all nerdy and technology?
Speaker 1: How'd you get your nerd on?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So I mentioned that I lived up in this very small town called Rouse's Point.
Speaker 0: Despite it being a very small town, my father was very in line with the tech community there.
Speaker 0: So one of his best friends, John Rigby, actually ran a bulletin board system.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 0: I was on, I was on BBSs when I was like four and five and it was a big, I didn't realize.
Speaker 2: What kind of computer did you have then?
Speaker 0: I believe it was a 386 at that time.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: My first computer was a 486 SX.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, we, I missed the 486 line.
Speaker 0: We had that 386.
Speaker 2: The first computer that was in my house that wasn't a video game console was a 486, a hundred megahertz.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it was a, and you know, I used to like dial in with all those mysterious pro modem protocols.
Speaker 0: It had those funny names.
Speaker 0: We only had the one phone line.
Speaker 0: So despite the fact that I had, cause back in the day, BBSs, you would have metered a lot of time that you could be on to dial in.
Speaker 1: I went to, I used to go to this pirate BBS where you could download, download basically pirated versions of games.
Speaker 0: Oh, every BBS.
Speaker 1: But I had to, you had to donate money to them, like by mailing them a check.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: And then you would get oxygen.
Speaker 1: And it was, it was, it was at this underwater.
Speaker 1: Were they running space trade around there?
Speaker 1: It was the underwater theme.
Speaker 1: And if you ran out of oxygen, you couldn't download any more stuff.
Speaker 1: And the analogy really didn't work.
Speaker 1: that well.
Speaker 2: No.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I had unlimited time on it and it had red dragon, of course, like every BBS.
Speaker 0: And I spent a lot of time on that.
Speaker 2: So that's the year you spent with the dragon.
Speaker 0: That was my year with the dragon.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Bringing it back around.
Speaker 0: So, so that was, uh, those, uh, that was sort of my nerdy history.
Speaker 0: Otherwise my father always had computers around the house.
Speaker 0: I was doing basic when I was, you know, in kindergarten and, uh, I sort of just stuck with it.
Speaker 0: because I mean, why not looking back on it?
Speaker 0: Like it's really easy to look at that period of time and be, you know, like, wow, how did I, I was just using windows 95 all those years.
Speaker 0: Like it's sort of a miracle thinking back on it.
Speaker 0: Hey, that we moved forward as a race.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 2: It's like, I use like windows seven today and it doesn't, you know, and it's like one part of my brain is like, this isn't any different than windows 95.
Speaker 2: But then I look at windows 95 and I'm like, what?
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Remember when plug and play, what didn't even always work?
Speaker 0: Well, we, we referred to it as plug and pray at the time, sort of jokingly, but you know, yeah, like it's really easy to look back on those times in my opinion and, and sort of marvel at how anti-competitive everything was and how very, it was like, well, if you need a computer, you have one choice, you go to the store and you buy a compact.
Speaker 1: I remember I tried to go to gateway and I really wanted windows NT and they wouldn't sell it to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And there was like that, that Ray of sunlight that windows 2000 was, it was like, Oh, this is what a real multi-user operating system is like.
Speaker 2: But like, you know, obviously I didn't get that until I got to fucking RIT.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I had windows 2000 before I went to RIT.
Speaker 2: I used 98 SE for a long time.
Speaker 1: Because I cashed in all the bonds my grandparents gave me.
Speaker 1: And I bought that AMD K7 800 with windows 2000.
Speaker 0: I bought a via chip.
Speaker 2: Oh, you and, you and Greg Hartman.
Speaker 0: I bought, I bought it with money that I made from my paper route.
Speaker 0: And, uh, I saved up for months to get this, this via chip.
Speaker 0: And I was so excited about having enough money to buy the via chip that I actually didn't have enough money to buy a motherboard, but it didn't matter.
Speaker 0: I was just excited.
Speaker 2: I saved up a thousand dollars working at the dry cleaners in high school and I bought a Pentium three 450 with a TNT two.
Speaker 2: I bought the TNT two the day it came out.
Speaker 0: Did you remember when a CPU slotted in?
Speaker 2: Yeah, it was a slot.
Speaker 1: Well, they were sockets.
Speaker 1: Then they went to slots and then back to sockets.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 2: I never understood what the point of the slot was.
Speaker 1: The point of the slot was that because you had more space on that board, you could put a shit ton of like L3 cash on there.
Speaker 0: And it was actually thinking about the layout of a board.
Speaker 2: You could probably, and it would still be, it would still be standard, I guess.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Basically.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You'd have more space on the, on the board.
Speaker 1: You'd have more space.
Speaker 1: You could put a bunch of memory in there, like caches and stuff, more L2 L3, which before then only existed on motherboards.
Speaker 2: I think it was a lot easier to put a computer together because you didn't have to deal with the fricking janky ass.
Speaker 2: lock it where you're going to destroy everything.
Speaker 1: I read.
Speaker 1: The only reason that we went back to sockets was that the chip, by only having this edge connection, it just, there was a limited number of pins and a limited amount of bandwidth and the physical distance started to matter.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Well now the new thing they come up with is the pins are on the motherboard and the contacts on the chip.
Speaker 2: And apparently that like reduces some heat or so it's like apparently way better.
Speaker 0: I mean, if you think about it, it makes the chips like more physically reliable if nothing else.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: We've all, we've all been to pin on a, an Athlon.
Speaker 0: Let's be fair to anybody who has done that.
Speaker 0: So, so I think the move back makes a lot of sense.
Speaker 0: I think it's smart.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: Um, I'm very excited about building my, my next computer.
Speaker 0: Um, I have it all specked out, but I, I'm like really sort of nervous because Ivy bridge is very good, but everything I read about has, well, it's like land of milk and honey.
Speaker 2: Because it's tick tock, right?
Speaker 2: So Ivy bridge was tick and the next one's going to be boom, big move.
Speaker 1: Every time I've ever researched a computer, I'll immediately see like, Oh, or there's a, you know, X millimeter process coming next.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, you know, there's always something next.
Speaker 0: Well, like let's take Nvidia cards, for example, Nvidia cards right now.
Speaker 0: The six 60 TI is this phenomenal piece of technology that I would have.
Speaker 0: no, I would throw it down for that today.
Speaker 0: I'll do it right now.
Speaker 2: I got a six 80.
Speaker 0: it's crazy high roller, but I mean price performance, like that's, it's such a compelling value and it's so, you know, that's what Emily got.
Speaker 1: She's actually these computers.
Speaker 1: Emily's computer, my computer are identical, except she has a new video card and I still have my GTX two 60, two six.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: Does it fucking matter?
Speaker 1: Cause my computer is a fucking supercomputer.
Speaker 1: I can play counter-strike full FPS, NS two full FPS.
Speaker 2: Yeah, but I can play NS two full FPS, vertical sync at full resolution with fraps running.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got vertical sync off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm going to upgrade.
Speaker 1: The reason I haven't upgraded is that settings.
Speaker 1: I want the mercury playback engine to work in.
Speaker 1: premiere premiere supports a list like 12.
Speaker 2: I enabled, even though I'm not on the list and it works, uh, it's probably not actually working.
Speaker 1: How did you enable it with the checkbox?
Speaker 1: That's not doing anything.
Speaker 1: If you're basically the premiere looks at a string to see if the string for your video card is in a list.
Speaker 1: Otherwise it does not enable GPU offloading of a automatic, like live rendering.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I'll send you a link.
Speaker 1: Basically you can add the string of your video card to the list and pretty much any video card after like a 300 series.
Speaker 2: I'm pretty sure mine will do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, well, but they, for some reason they won't certify it or whatever, but that is why it's supposed to be a Conrad.
Speaker 0: Well, I, Hey, I'm more than happy to talk about.
Speaker 0: I love this shit out of video cards because I do 3d graphics programming.
Speaker 0: Now I spend a lot of time limiting the video card conversation.
Speaker 0: I will say that Nvidia and AMD need to get their shit together.
Speaker 0: Whoever's writing their drivers needs to fucking step into high gear.
Speaker 1: All of our video drivers for a long time.
Speaker 1: They were awesome compared to any other.
Speaker 2: lately they're getting flaky because the competition has also always been flaky.
Speaker 0: An unnamed source of mine that used to work at Microsoft reported at one point that 50% of windows, blue screen, automatic file bug reports are caused by Nvidia drive.
Speaker 0: that I've been getting blue screens lately, you know, some of our user, our user, we get so many support emails that are like your game, blue screen, my computer, and it's too blue screen.
Speaker 2: And you know what?
Speaker 2: It happened when an onus was stomping, but it was, it was clearly because the video guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, but I mean, to a degree, like it's, it's kind of, um, for us, it's really frustrating because we're a small company.
Speaker 0: We want to treat our customers really well.
Speaker 0: And we're just constantly getting reports.
Speaker 0: It's like, well, I play every other game just fine.
Speaker 0: What is your game?
Speaker 0: Blue screen.
Speaker 2: That is a good question.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: The answer is, well, you probably don't actually play every other game just fine.
Speaker 2: You're probably made that one open GL call that no one else is making.
Speaker 0: Well, and it's unity too.
Speaker 0: The problem is since we do everything in unity, three D we're so limited in how much access we have to a lot of this stuff.
Speaker 0: And so we're sort of at their mercy.
Speaker 0: I think it's the way I want to have.
Speaker 2: other unity games would crash as much, you know, well, then there would have to be one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but hey, the new Nintendo Wii U, you can ride unity games for it.
Speaker 0: Oh, great.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 2: Nintendo will let you sell those on the store.
Speaker 1: The Wii U came out this weekend and I did not know that someone posted on the forum tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, someone on the forum is recording.
Speaker 2: So you've already got it out.
Speaker 1: I won't have it.
Speaker 2: I mean, anyone listening, it's already out.
Speaker 1: It's like Nintendo.
Speaker 1: Way to, way to be the one thing in my entire life that was constant and trusted without reservation.
Speaker 1: And to blow that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they blew it hard to like generations of bad decisions for me to actually move from sight unseen to going to wait and see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this one, this one was particularly bad.
Speaker 0: I mean, when you're, when you're up at E3 showing footage of call of duty that you recorded on a PC talking about your next generation graphics, man, you really kind of have to consider where you are at and then ship what is basically an Xbox three 60 repackaged into Nintendo hardware.
Speaker 0: Man, they've got to be, they've got to be desperate is the only thing I could think.
Speaker 1: And yet they've got the controller.
Speaker 1: So they're doing what they, they're doing what they should have done seven years ago.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 2: Oh, well.
Speaker 1: So do you play any video games?
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Well, what games are you playing right now?
Speaker 0: Well, okay.
Speaker 0: So I'm playing Mass Effect three multiplayer with everybody.
Speaker 2: How does that work?
Speaker 0: It is board mode in call of duty.
Speaker 0: So you survive waves of enemies.
Speaker 0: You complete mission objectives on every third wave.
Speaker 0: And I play it with, uh, Ananth and my, uh, my girlfriend, Rochelle, and we have a good time.
Speaker 0: Um, and I also was playing fallout, new Vegas for quite some time, which it was the best of times.
Speaker 0: And it was the worst of times.
Speaker 2: I played it a little bit and then I stopped.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I was impressed obviously with the world as ever, but towards the end of it, I felt like I was tiptoeing around the crash bugs or tiptoeing around the bugs that would delete my inventory.
Speaker 2: I am glad I didn't get that far.
Speaker 2: I had problems early on.
Speaker 2: where it's like, I think in the first town, there's like a robot, but I never talked to the robot.
Speaker 2: And then when I went to the second town, the robot was there and he acted like he knew me already.
Speaker 2: And I was like, I was like, I know you were in the first town because people talked about you, but I never found you.
Speaker 2: And why are you here now acting like, you know, me, shouldn't we introduce first?
Speaker 2: And it is stuff like that.
Speaker 2: Whereas in the original fallout three didn't have issues like that.
Speaker 2: You know, everything sort of more was, I think they spent more time on making sure each person and character behaved appropriately and was in the right place.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, like when I remember the guy who wants to blow up Megaton.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: When I met him the first time I was like, you fucker.
Speaker 1: And I just punched him to death right there.
Speaker 1: And that plot just disappeared.
Speaker 1: Never came up again.
Speaker 1: And I took his clothes and the whole rest of the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I also, I feel like all out three proper spoken, a more coherent voice throughout the game.
Speaker 0: I really do feel like new Vegas, although at times it was significantly stronger overall.
Speaker 0: I don't think it was as cohesive.
Speaker 0: It was still really good.
Speaker 0: Like, don't even get me wrong.
Speaker 0: I, I want that setting.
Speaker 1: I love those games, but it was because the primary joy I got from it was exploring the world and kind of seeing cool things like the ruin houses and everything.
Speaker 1: But the fact that it was actually so sparse and so generic other than very tiny areas of content that I kind of lost interest almost immediately.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: That's another thing.
Speaker 2: Cause fallout three is like you come out of the vault and then what?
Speaker 1: And I'm like, Oh my God, look at that freeway.
Speaker 2: Not only is it technologically open world, it's the plot is open.
Speaker 2: It's like Megaton is right there obviously, but it's like, you don't have to fucking go there first.
Speaker 2: It's like, you don't, you know, just, you can see it there.
Speaker 2: So it's sort of a design choice, but you can just go out there and you can see it there.
Speaker 2: Whereas in fallout new Vegas, it's definitely more of a linear, like, go here next, dude.
Speaker 2: They're telling you where to go.
Speaker 2: You know, like, Hey, you should really go that way.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 1: More sort of a deus exe of, yeah, the plot's over there whenever you're ready, dude.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I really do feel like that was a very intentional choice made on feedback from the first game.
Speaker 0: Like in fallout three, I'd be willing to bet that they got a lot of feedback that was like, well, I just didn't know where to go.
Speaker 0: And so they probably, they probably doubled down on being easy and in doing so probably punch that particular aspect of it.
Speaker 0: To the game in the face.
Speaker 1: Did you play the new deus exe human revolution?
Speaker 1: I guess it's not new anymore.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 0: I played human revolution.
Speaker 0: Did you like it?
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 0: Uh, I thought it was, I thought it was very good.
Speaker 0: Um, of course there, this is, this is another one of those cases where you're talking about design concessions from the first one.
Speaker 0: Uh, I think that the first one was more interesting in some ways.
Speaker 0: Uh, and also the newest deus exe brought to light for me exactly how bad every modern stealth game is.
Speaker 0: I think every stealth game is bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, cause I like, I tried playing it except for thief.
Speaker 2: thief and nothing else.
Speaker 1: Mark of the ninjas 2d thief gold.
Speaker 1: That was a good job.
Speaker 2: He've gold is also gay.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Three came for free with my creative graphics blaster extreme, I think, or some other video card I bought and using the old school glide drivers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, dude.
Speaker 1: I remember when my friend Ken came over when he's like, I have open GL.
Speaker 1: We're going to play GL quake.
Speaker 0: Do love glide.
Speaker 0: That's like, it's like technological API or sex tool.
Speaker 0: We can make a fun game out of this.
Speaker 0: Actually.
Speaker 2: We should make a new, a new standard to compete with them.
Speaker 2: K y you feel like everyone does your video cards for k y it better.
Speaker 2: It's really hard to install it in the case.
Speaker 2: It just keeps slipping.
Speaker 0: It was supposed to make inserting these cards easier.
Speaker 0: No, just inserting the cables is easier, but uh, but yeah, so day deus X, but I really liked, again, I really liked the environment.
Speaker 0: I liked the world.
Speaker 0: I thought that they did a lot of things.
Speaker 1: worried about it in deus X was much deeper feeling and more fleshed out and all the interesting side bits were interesting as opposed to follow three, which actually, well, I know it's a barren post-apocalyptic wasteland, but I was kind of taken aback.
Speaker 0: At how barren it was, even like inside of town, new Vegas in particular, it's supposed to feel very sparse, obviously, I think due to its, uh, desert location.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: It's, it's in a desert.
Speaker 0: And so you're supposed to feel this, this, the gravity of this massive world.
Speaker 2: And if there wasn't apocalypse pretty much anywhere is going to be sparse.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But, and, and even in DC and in fallout three, there were buildings and there were things, but it was extremely empty.
Speaker 0: And of course that was part of the feel.
Speaker 0: And so you remove the buildings from the emptiness and it's literal, just like sort of how, you know, a universe and gravity.
Speaker 2: It takes over after all the other forces of neutral that entropy always wins.
Speaker 0: But, but yeah, so, uh, otherwise I can't think of what I've really been.
Speaker 0: Well, I've been playing a lot of my own game.
Speaker 0: guns of Icarus as you can probably
Speaker 2: talk about that for a
Speaker 1: bit is to give you the most honest feedback.
Speaker 1: I can give actually fun.
Speaker 1: The fact that I play it at all in my, in my rotation, my 10 year rotation of counter-strike sleep and natural selection.
Speaker 1: The fact that I'm playing guns of Icarus as a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And, and I am a very harsh self critic.
Speaker 0: I will, I will critique, critique myself very strongly, but I'm actually willing to say that I'm very proud of the work that we've done on guns of Icarus.
Speaker 0: And I think it's fun and I like playing it.
Speaker 0: So it's a, just for, for those of you who might be listening and somehow, uh, haven't heard me talk about this on another channel, it is a steampunk airship combat game, and it's all small team-based.
Speaker 0: So you and three other dudes get onto this airship and shoot down other dudes full of four people.
Speaker 0: And, uh, you obviously you're all on teams and, uh, you have to work together on the ship to perform various tasks like manning the guns, which are affixed to hard points or repairing, uh, the hard points and the weapons and your engines and hull.
Speaker 0: And then there's of course the captain who is ostensibly in charge and hollering at you to do things that if my play experience is any indicator, you will ignore and just camp, camp the balloon while our hull gets blown up.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, it's, it's actually fun.
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 0: I can recommend it in good conscience and say, this is a fun game that I worked on the most fun.
Speaker 1: Like once I was playing during the beta with Adam and he's like in storm going to do and he's, he's Clanny and old school.
Speaker 1: Like I kind of am.
Speaker 1: So once the two of us were on a ship together, that shit was motherfucking invincible.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 2: You guys probably, cause he'd just be like rubber guns, broadside coming three, two, cause every other, cause everyone and every other ship was camping the balloon or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Then we're all just hammering away.
Speaker 2: If you have two people working together, well forget it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We see, we see ships now in game with, with like really experienced players and they, they are really into it.
Speaker 0: They're talking about meta strategy.
Speaker 0: They, we, we added this item.
Speaker 0: It was like a harpoon gun and you can harpoon ships and like drag them into you and like nobody used it.
Speaker 0: Everybody was like, what is this even for?
Speaker 0: Well, okay.
Speaker 2: What I will harpoon and then they can't get, you can see really easy to shoot them now.
Speaker 0: This was, this was our thought.
Speaker 0: Initially we were like, well you just harpoon them and you drag them in for the flame thrower.
Speaker 0: We almost like you, you could very easily see how you would use it on the ships with two guns on the same side.
Speaker 0: We're like, this will be great.
Speaker 0: What we didn't expect was there's a ship with two guns on the very front and the new strategy is to put two harpoons up there and harpoon somebody at you and drag them into you at such speed that you careen right through them and destroy them with your ship.
Speaker 1: That is really, you like, it's amazing.
Speaker 2: So you had, you, you put in ramming damage, which is a factor of speed and the size of your ship.
Speaker 2: And it just so happened that the speed of the harpoon pole added with the, it just, it just worked out that way.
Speaker 2: You didn't put it in there on purpose.
Speaker 0: The ship is the pyramidion, which is a very fast ship to begin with.
Speaker 0: And so you, you increase the speed at which you're traveling by like pulling the other ship into you.
Speaker 0: You effectively double your collision damage and in doing so you just barrel right through them.
Speaker 0: So you start on broadsides to weaken like their components and then you just careen into them with these harpoons.
Speaker 2: I mean, you don't, I don't think even want to check to make sure whether those physics are accurate, right?
Speaker 0: I will say actually our, our guy, Jezary Bankston, who did all of the flight and collision models, they're incredibly well modeled.
Speaker 0: The, the flight model is, is extremely physics based.
Speaker 0: So the distance that your engines are away from the center of the ship, for example, determines your rotation speed.
Speaker 0: It determines how fast you can turn because he's applying torque in that way.
Speaker 0: It's, it's really cool.
Speaker 0: He actually wrote a biplane flight model too.
Speaker 2: That's super accurate.
Speaker 1: So who's writing the boarding engine?
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm glad you should ask about that because it's time for me to kill you.
Speaker 2: We've made this joke before.
Speaker 1: I think it's, it's that you, I think part of your success in my opinion is that you guys, because I seem to know a lot of people at this company somehow are doing the opposite of what the tribes two team did.
Speaker 1: You have a forum, you look at what your people, like the people playing your game say, but then you make your own decisions based on that feedback instead of doing what they ask.
Speaker 0: This is, this is the only way to make a game.
Speaker 0: And, and I said this in another place and I was actually pretty happy with this analogy is that if you have a room full of smoke, your players will ask you to put in a fan to blow away the smoke.
Speaker 0: What you actually want to do is put out the fire.
Speaker 0: And so when, when people ask us for things, we like to put them through a filter of like, well, what problem are they attempting to solve with this and how can we affect that more positively or at a more fundamental level?
Speaker 0: And I'm, I'm really happy with the work that we've done in that regard.
Speaker 0: We, a lot of people are very right about a lot of things.
Speaker 0: So for example, the ability to form a crew before you enter into matchmaking or before you enter into a match, that is important.
Speaker 2: You can't, you can't, you get in the game, it starts, no one's joined the server yet because they're still loading the map and the game starts and no one wants to get in the comm chair.
Speaker 1: Counter-Strike even has that problem in puppy games.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So we're, we're actively looking at that.
Speaker 0: We, we just implemented and by the time this airs, it will be out.
Speaker 0: But, um, Monday coming up, we have a big patch that will do automatic rematch.
Speaker 0: So when you're done with a game, it'll put you into a new game on a new map with the same people.
Speaker 0: And that's not done yet.
Speaker 0: Uh, and so, you know, it'll be in on Monday.
Speaker 0: I'm really excited about it.
Speaker 0: And, uh, of course we're going to be making fixes to spectator mode and the like to better support, uh, tournament casting and we're going to get clan support in, in the near future as well.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We're, we're really excited about, you know, we're going to try to make this game more competitive, I think, and then cater to that community.
Speaker 0: It should be really cool.
Speaker 1: That's a good community.
Speaker 1: That community is on the upswing.
Speaker 1: lately has been rocking it.
Speaker 1: I mean, you saw the legal legends thing at pass.
Speaker 1: That was, that was like more professional than that fake tournament in the wizard.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: I think it's definitely, it's, it's becoming a crowded space.
Speaker 2: There's a lot of people going for it, but I think everyone's going for it because you know, the pie is getting bigger, right?
Speaker 2: So, you know, you might feel like, well, how are we, anyone going to care about my game being competitive when everyone's playing, you know, all these mobas and FPSs and such?
Speaker 2: Well, there's, you know, there's a whole lot of people looking for games to watch, you know, there's no hockey, no hockey.
Speaker 0: watch guns instead.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: No, I mean, and it's twitch TV is huge.
Speaker 0: No, absolutely.
Speaker 0: And we're, you know, we, we have an official channel on twitch and we're, we're trying to court some casters on twitch.
Speaker 0: I'm really excited about getting more into this space.
Speaker 0: and on the topic of mobas, how do you guys feel about stupid?
Speaker 2: I'll be honest.
Speaker 2: Okay.
Speaker 2: I think the fundamental game of a MOBA, right?
Speaker 2: The, you know, five on five sort of, you know, thing, it has something going on there.
Speaker 2: It's fun.
Speaker 2: I kind of want to play kind of like a versus tower defense, but the reality of what every implementation is.
Speaker 2: Some are better than others.
Speaker 2: Like legal legends is better than Dota because it doesn't have the nonsense, denying bullshit is the bottom, right?
Speaker 2: But they're all, you know, it's like they get the details wrong.
Speaker 2: And I feel like if I made a MOBA, I could keep the same fundamental thing, you know, game idea of, you know, five on five control one guy on this map, but it would, but it would be good because there wouldn't be any bullshit.
Speaker 1: Well, this gets into the same thing.
Speaker 1: I mean, in my opinion, MOBAs steer wrong and that the original game had a lot of emergent properties that people who can, you know, had a really strong community around it.
Speaker 1: So people would do these emergent things like the last hitting, because that was just the limitation of this mod.
Speaker 1: But then when they like canonized those emergent behaviors into legit game mechanics, instead of addressing them in a different way, that is where these games fall flat.
Speaker 2: So, you know, judging by the way you even asked that question, I get the feeling you are also anti MOBA.
Speaker 0: Let me let me preface this by saying that it is my hope to someday compose a rap song so that I can use the line last hits like MOBAs.
Speaker 2: There is the Dotas, you know, the...
Speaker 0: MOBAs represent a really interesting case study for me because it's exactly what you said.
Speaker 0: It's the emergent properties and how they've translated into codified formalized rule sets.
Speaker 0: And I think you're dead on with the last hits.
Speaker 0: I think the concept of last hit and you, man, you see this in other games, too.
Speaker 0: So I mentioned I was playing Mass Effect 3 multiplayer.
Speaker 0: The points you get from killing enemies is weighted extremely heavily in your favor if you get the last hit.
Speaker 0: Even if you didn't contribute most of the damage, you get that last hit.
Speaker 0: You get an insane amount of like experience points.
Speaker 0: I consider that a weak design, I think.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's a symptom of a greater problem.
Speaker 1: Those mechanics are there, in my opinion.
Speaker 1: I can use a better lexicon now because I've read that Characteristics of Games book that we learned about at PAX Dev.
Speaker 1: But these games, they have these skill components that require you to master all of these sort of individual fiddly bits.
Speaker 1: Because that's the only way to give these games enough strategic and tactical and execution depth to make them appeal to competitive players.
Speaker 1: Because there's an extremely high return on investment for learning those skills.
Speaker 1: But the problem for me is that those skills that these games make you learn are not analogous to what the game is about at all.
Speaker 1: The game appears to be about one thing, but really it's about the worst parts of StarCraft.
Speaker 2: Last hitting, right?
Speaker 2: It's like, well, why is last hitting a thing?
Speaker 2: Last hitting a thing has always been in video games.
Speaker 2: If you kill the guy, you get the frag.
Speaker 2: In Quake, if you're the one who kills the guy with your Rocky, even if the other guy did 99 of the damage, you are the one who gets the frag on your score.
Speaker 1: Dude, Crystal Warriors on the game gear.
Speaker 2: And the reason for this, right?
Speaker 2: Why is the reason that every game does this?
Speaker 2: This is the reason.
Speaker 2: Because we need to add the code that says frag plus one has to be somewhere.
Speaker 2: Where do we put it?
Speaker 2: We put it in the onDeath function.
Speaker 2: Right?
Speaker 2: So, when someone dies, that's when someone gets a frag.
Speaker 2: So, in the onDeath function, right?
Speaker 2: How do we, oh, we have to also have access to the person to give this frag to.
Speaker 2: Well, we don't, you know, we're going to do at that moment when someone dies, have a running tally of all the damage that's been done to them and figure out, you know.
Speaker 2: No one was going to do that, especially not way back in like a mud.
Speaker 2: Well, certainly.
Speaker 2: This is carried over till the present day and towards become sort of just gaming common sense in a way, even though it's not common sense, but to where no one would think to do it differently.
Speaker 0: Mass Effect 3 does accumulate damage counters though for everybody and experience is divvied up, but the waiting function is my objection in this case, I think.
Speaker 0: And I'll also preface this by saying that I'm more in line with Dave Serlin, for example, who's doing a lot of work for Capcom right now on balancing the old school fighting.
Speaker 0: He used to be an active member in the fighting game community, but he and I suffer from the same problem in that we're both hands.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: Actually, neither of us are particularly good at execution and we don't necessarily consider that to be the core component of the game.
Speaker 1: So you can play Yomi.
Speaker 1: Well, if you remove those components, then you get to the situation where all games break down pretty rapidly and return on investment of skill has to eventually have an end game that is within the reach of players.
Speaker 1: MOBAs have these shitty fiddly mechanics because that's the only way to keep a perfect end game out of the grasp of a player who's dedicated to solving the game.
Speaker 0: I think to a degree, I would actually rather make a good game every two years.
Speaker 0: If that's the alternative, I would rather make a good game every two years.
Speaker 1: Ah, that is why I put so much stock in German board games because we solve every game we play eventually.
Speaker 1: I mean, Settlers isn't done.
Speaker 1: I'm done with Settlers, but you know what?
Speaker 2: Every time.
Speaker 1: It was way fun while I was playing it and when I was done with it, I played a different game.
Speaker 2: And you look at board games and constantly there are new ones coming out that are all awesome and in some way, you know, it's like Settlers is no good anymore.
Speaker 2: Where did this eclipse thing come from?
Speaker 2: Suddenly this huge hit game selling all selling out multiple editions.
Speaker 1: Though I do still play Counter-Strike and I like it for all the meta reasons that these kids like MOBAs.
Speaker 1: So I can't pretend that I'm immune to the desire to see a great return on investment.
Speaker 2: But at least that the you know, that stuff in Counter-Strike, you know, makes sense, right?
Speaker 1: The actions are analogous.
Speaker 2: Right.
Speaker 2: The actions are analogous to what you're trying to do.
Speaker 2: I mean, in Street Fighter, they make mostly sense, but not as much sense as Counter-Strike.
Speaker 2: And in Dota, they make even less sense.
Speaker 2: Shoot your own guys to win.
Speaker 1: I think Soul Calibur has a better analogy.
Speaker 2: Soul Calibur has the best analogy of any real time fighting game that I have played ever.
Speaker 1: Well, Bushido Blade.
Speaker 2: No.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: Taking it back.
Speaker 0: I haven't even heard the words Bushido Blade.
Speaker 1: I was not good at Bushido Blade, but I was better than all my friends.
Speaker 0: It was an SNK game.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking of the right game.
Speaker 0: That was an SNK game.
Speaker 2: It was the realistic 3D PlayStation game where when you hit someone, they were dead.
Speaker 0: Long game.
Speaker 0: OK, cool.
Speaker 2: Never mind.
Speaker 2: No, you're thinking of the game where I showed up.
Speaker 1: I was like, I've got a sword and you've got a hammer.
Speaker 1: If I hit you with the sword, maybe you're dead or you're almost dead.
Speaker 2: Or you're wounded at best.
Speaker 1: And you start looping around the ring.
Speaker 1: Like, ready?
Speaker 1: Go.
Speaker 1: Someone's dead.
Speaker 1: It was awesome.
Speaker 2: Anyway.
Speaker 1: I love those games.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Now I'm just looking forward to my Strike Suit Zero Kickstarter coming through.
Speaker 0: I really like just sometimes, man, like especially working in games now and having to actually make game design decisions.
Speaker 0: Some days I just like to come home and shoot other spaceships in a spaceship.
Speaker 0: That's just the thing I like to do.
Speaker 0: And Strike Suit Zero looks like it's going to be a blast.
Speaker 0: And even, you know, even if it's just like to a degree, what I what I've always wanted was sort of like a free space kind of game with like Newtonian physics where you could.
Speaker 2: Nobody's made a free space game in so long.
Speaker 1: No, I would I would I would if there was.
Speaker 1: if somehow if Disney made a new TIE Fighter game happen, that was a free space shooter.
Speaker 2: Oh, Disney.
Speaker 1: I would tie fighter.
Speaker 1: I would probably back the highest level of whatever.
Speaker 2: I don't think Disney needs to kickstart anything.
Speaker 2: They got money.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess a principle.
Speaker 0: I absolutely appreciate it.
Speaker 0: But like, you know, I really remember that Sophie game that came out for the Xbox 360 that was made by Square Enix.
Speaker 2: I didn't play it, but I know it was silly.
Speaker 0: It was silly as shit.
Speaker 0: It was like anime spaceships.
Speaker 0: And yeah, it was.
Speaker 0: it was just really dumb and flashy.
Speaker 0: And like, I loved it.
Speaker 0: I love the shit out of it.
Speaker 0: I must have played it for like 60 hours.
Speaker 2: It was just like to this day, there's someone listening right now who's like, yeah, they're like, oh, my God, someone else played seriously.
Speaker 2: And he's like, yeah, the voice acting was awful.
Speaker 2: And now he's listening to this and saying, oh, my God, it's me.
Speaker 2: They're talking about me.
Speaker 0: Interestingly, when we used to do game jams at work where like every Friday at the last Friday of the month, we would all sit down and a programmer would pair off with an artist and you would come up with your idea for a game.
Speaker 0: And then we would vet these ideas and see if anything good came out.
Speaker 0: And I am not a creative person by any means.
Speaker 0: I'm just I'm just not.
Speaker 0: And so I got paired with John Lynn and John was like, you know, what games do you like?
Speaker 0: And I was like, well, you remember Sophie from the PC and like nineteen eighty three.
Speaker 0: I like that.
Speaker 0: I also kind of like to rez.
Speaker 0: And so I made this like a rez, like Sophie game that used the music on your hard drive to to create like waveforms and enemy enemy patterns and stuff.
Speaker 2: So that was that was the extent of pretty sure that I'm pretty sure the original Sophie wasn't that like for more systems and like any game ever.
Speaker 2: Well, yeah, it was like there was a Web page I went to once I had like samples from like every sound card ever.
Speaker 2: And like the only game that they could find that they could actually test and all these different sound cards through the generations was like the original.
Speaker 2: So I'm pretty sure it was the original Sophie.
Speaker 2: I have to check that out.
Speaker 0: It would make sense.
Speaker 2: It was like Commodore, you know, Atari.
Speaker 0: I was like, what might have made it all the way up to the Sound Blaster era.
Speaker 1: I remember when I got my dad, he wouldn't buy me more RAM, but he bought me a Sound Blaster AWE 32 advanced wave effects.
Speaker 1: The only benefit was MIDI was a little bit better set in your blaster environment variables.
Speaker 1: You realize that thing needed two IRQs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was serious business back then, man.
Speaker 0: Not to be trifled with.
Speaker 0: Yeah, high level ones that you had to reboot DOS in a real mode.
Speaker 1: Oh, shit.
Speaker 1: I made boot disk because SimCity 2000 would not play on my computer.
Speaker 2: I only needed boot disk for the mech warrior, too.
Speaker 2: And I only freaking had to do that until I got 16 megs of RAM.
Speaker 1: Until I upgraded my RAM, I could not play Doom.
Speaker 1: if I booted the computer legit.
Speaker 2: I had 8 megs of RAM, so I could always play Doom.
Speaker 1: I'd hold an F5 to boot to like raw DOS and then I would type mouse to load my mouse driver.
Speaker 1: Hi Mem Mem Maker, all that stuff.
Speaker 1: And then I would start Doom.
Speaker 2: Not only that, but I, because I had 8 megs of RAM and a quad speed CD-ROM, I could install Doom and Doom 2 in under a minute.
Speaker 2: So I could just keep, whenever I needed more space, whenever I needed more space, I could delete it.
Speaker 1: Doom came on a fucking disk.
Speaker 2: I had a CD-ROM that had Doom 2 and Doom Ultimate.
Speaker 0: Maybe at the time he had to put into a plastic caddy to load into his CD drive.
Speaker 2: You don't know, it's possible.
Speaker 2: No, the CD drive was quad speed, bitches.
Speaker 0: So by that time, yeah, you're right.
Speaker 2: That's why I said Doom installed, like boom, it's installed.
Speaker 1: Scott, I bought the Doom 2 shareware like when Doom 2 came out.
Speaker 1: And then I'd use like wadded and de-hacked to make my own Mavs.
Speaker 2: Good job.
Speaker 1: I'm very proud of myself.
Speaker 0: Those were the days.
Speaker 2: They were.
Speaker 2: So what are you into besides technology and games that you were known for?
Speaker 2: Uh, well, I live with a lot of- I know you were a nerd of many colors.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I live with several illustrators and many of whom do comics.
Speaker 0: And so I end up reading a lot of comics or as to say, comics end up piling up next to my desk.
Speaker 2: That sounds like me.
Speaker 0: I should read them.
Speaker 0: I think that's the way I want to put it.
Speaker 2: What's piled up next to your desk right now?
Speaker 0: Oh, God.
Speaker 0: The worst part is Ananth will periodically come into my room and just be like, "Hey, we got these in the mail.
Speaker 0: You should read one of
Speaker 0: these.".
Speaker 2: And so I will say- You didn't know if Ananth is going to do this, it's going to be good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you put it on the pile of everything else, that's good.
Speaker 1: Particularly- I mean, I just got my Daisy Cutter Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: I haven't even like read it at all.
Speaker 0: That looks so good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it does look good.
Speaker 0: I will say that I just finished up King City by Brandon Graham.
Speaker 0: King City was originally a Tokyo pop property.
Speaker 0: They published the first book.
Speaker 0: It didn't take off.
Speaker 0: And then so they canned it.
Speaker 2: Oh, right, right.
Speaker 2: A lot of those people have found other places to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it sat in purgatory for like several years.
Speaker 0: But recently the Omnibus got published.
Speaker 0: So it's this amazing, large, hardcover compilation of all the King City comics.
Speaker 0: And it is just the most incredible, off-the-wall, urban decay.
Speaker 0: I highly recommend it.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to do it justice summarizing it because this is sadly not my forte.
Speaker 0: But I do recommend everybody grab at least the first King City volume, if not the whole hardcover, and just give it a read because it's a blast.
Speaker 0: I love it.
Speaker 2: How about in terms of, you know, movies, musics, and that sort of thing?
Speaker 1: Did you see Wreck-It Ralph?
Speaker 0: I did see Wreck-It Ralph.
Speaker 1: Did you like it?
Speaker 1: Because I liked it because Roger Rabbit did in that all the plot was like new characters and the old characters were just cameos.
Speaker 1: They weren't actually- Absolutely.
Speaker 1: Like Bowser was not the villain.
Speaker 0: No, it nails what a video game movie sort of needs to be, right?
Speaker 0: Especially because you're absolutely right in your analogy of Roger Rabbit.
Speaker 1: So did you notice that Sandy Fox did one of the fucking voices and AKB48 did the theme to Sugar Rush?
Speaker 1: Well, I did notice AKB48.
Speaker 0: I didn't notice Sandy Fox or something?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Sandy Fox.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what voice he did.
Speaker 1: She was credited.
Speaker 1: I was like, "Sandy
Speaker 1: Fox?".
Speaker 1: I still haven't looked up what she did.
Speaker 0: Yeah, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize that.
Speaker 2: It's Rim's favorite.
Speaker 2: The only thing that can make Rim go crazier is if it was like a two-mix opener.
Speaker 1: I was just watching old anime openers from the '90s.
Speaker 0: Getting some Nagumi Hayashibara into your diet.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, two-mix, man.
Speaker 0: Did they do rhythm and motion?
Speaker 0: Was that two-mix?
Speaker 1: The White Revolution was that music video that everyone thought was an anime, but it was just a music video.
Speaker 2: I didn't know what I was watching that first day of anime club.
Speaker 1: I watched that.
Speaker 1: No, two-mix?
Speaker 1: In high school, me and Ken found it.
Speaker 1: We had this MPEG file, but that shit was hard to play back in the day.
Speaker 2: So when you were at that first anime club meeting in 1/2000, you knew you had already seen that.
Speaker 1: Scott, when I came to that anime club meeting, I already knew who two-mix was.
Speaker 1: I knew White Reflection, and I had seen easily half the anime I've seen in my entire life already.
Speaker 0: High school, man.
Speaker 0: That's just how it was.
Speaker 1: Scott, I had already seen most of Slayerz, like Eska Flonay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Eva's the only thing I hadn't actually watched.
Speaker 0: So, okay, no lie.
Speaker 0: I have this problem, whereas generally when we discuss the media that I've consumed, generally there are two different categories, and it's like a Venn diagram in which the circles don't touch.
Speaker 0: It's like good media and shit that I've accidentally seen.
Speaker 0: And this absolutely applied to me in anime in high school as well.
Speaker 0: So I ended up with these fan subs of Tenshi ni Naruman, which is this weird, bubbly, sort of just awkward story about this angel that falls to earth and then falls in love with a dude who's all tsundere about it.
Speaker 2: I've never heard of this.
Speaker 2: It's got a anime news network.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Tenshi ni Naruman is the name of it.
Speaker 0: It's patently bad.
Speaker 1: I asked because Luke liked it.
Speaker 1: I ended up seeing some of Rhizal Mine.
Speaker 2: What?
Speaker 2: I completely forgot.
Speaker 2: there was a show called that.
Speaker 2: I have no idea what it's about.
Speaker 1: It has that Hajime Te Shimimasho whatever opening song.
Speaker 1: If you hear that song, you'll be like, "Oh, great
Speaker 1: show.".
Speaker 1: I probably will.
Speaker 2: How about Alien 9?
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 0: Wow, taking it better.
Speaker 0: That was the one with the creepy hats, right?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: The creepy hats.
Speaker 2: And the whole plot was in the closer the last episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we all went to eat dinner and Gabi was in the other room watching.
Speaker 1: We watched the end of the show.
Speaker 1: And Gabi was watching the closing credits.
Speaker 0: She's like, "Oh, my
Speaker 0: God.".
Speaker 2: They just kill everyone in the closing credits of the last episode.
Speaker 1: All right, she's credited in Wreck-It Ralph with "additional
Speaker 1: voices."
Speaker 1: We got burned.
Speaker 0: Ouch.
Speaker 1: No information.
Speaker 2: Background characters.
Speaker 0: No record.
Speaker 2: Needs some money.
Speaker 0: Wreck-It Ralph was definitely one of the best things to happen this year.
Speaker 0: And we got Looper this year.
Speaker 0: And Looper, man, I take a lot of shit for Looper as much as I did.
Speaker 2: I haven't seen either one.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: My thing about Looper is even if it wasn't perfect, I think it represents something important.
Speaker 0: It's like we can have these high-concept movies come into Hollywood and do very well.
Speaker 0: Just as a template, that's a positive thing that I want to see more of, right?
Speaker 0: Even if Prometheus wasn't perfect, I want to see more Prometheus.
Speaker 0: I want to see more Looper.
Speaker 0: These are things that I like.
Speaker 0: I like that.
Speaker 0: I can go to the movies and see good sci-fi again.
Speaker 1: I heard, though, that the new Bond movie is really good and makes up for the second to most recent Bond movie.
Speaker 2: I haven't seen either one.
Speaker 2: I only saw Casino Royale.
Speaker 1: I've seen a lot of people who actually like Bond, like they know Bond, and they call this their second or third favorite Bond ever.
Speaker 2: Well, I've seen every Bond movie up to Casino Royale.
Speaker 2: I just haven't seen the two newest ones.
Speaker 1: It was okay.
Speaker 1: The only problem with Casino Royale, in my opinion, is that Casino Royale is the derpiest Bond plot.
Speaker 1: Like it's too close to the original book and all of its derpiness.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: It was all right.
Speaker 0: Are you talking about the old Casino Royale?
Speaker 1: Oh, with Woody Allen or whatever?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: There was a new one.
Speaker 0: Oh, I see.
Speaker 0: This is what I mean about this Venn diagram, man.
Speaker 0: It's real.
Speaker 0: My Venn diagram of media is real.
Speaker 1: Wait, so what was the last James Bond movie you've seen?
Speaker 0: It was that one where it's like the software mogul tries to shoot down North America with a space laser.
Speaker 0: So what, Pierce Brosnan?
Speaker 0: Yeah, Pierce Brosnan one.
Speaker 0: It wasn't GoldenEye.
Speaker 0: No?
Speaker 0: No, it was a Pierce Brosnan one.
Speaker 1: I hated Pierce Brosnan's Bond movies.
Speaker 1: He was an okay Bond, but his movies were, I just didn't like him.
Speaker 2: Wasn't Pierce Brosnan in GoldenEye?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That was the only good Bond movie he was in.
Speaker 1: He was in a bunch more.
Speaker 2: Pretty sure GoldenEye.
Speaker 0: Maybe it was GoldenEye.
Speaker 2: Pretty sure GoldenEye is about a space laser on a satellite.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'm thinking about Dr.
Speaker 0: No, actually.
Speaker 2: Dr.
Speaker 0: No is about a rocket.
Speaker 0: No, I like Dr.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Dr.
Speaker 0: No is about a rocket.
Speaker 0: But this was definitely a Pierce Brosnan one.
Speaker 2: Yeah, Dr.
Speaker 2: No is.
Speaker 2: Sean Connery is the first Bond movie ever.
Speaker 2: It's about a rocket.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: That was awesome.
Speaker 0: Dr.
Speaker 2: No.
Speaker 1: From Russia with Love, Goldfinger, Thunderball.
Speaker 1: Which I really like.
Speaker 2: Thunderball is the best.
Speaker 1: You only live twice on our majesty's Secret Service.
Speaker 1: Diamonds are forever.
Speaker 1: Live and let die.
Speaker 1: The man with the golden gun.
Speaker 2: You don't have to go over the whole list here.
Speaker 1: Moonraker.
Speaker 2: Moonraker is the corniest, but I like it anyway.
Speaker 1: Well, because it gave us the Moonraker laser.
Speaker 2: Of course.
Speaker 0: It was The World Is Not Enough.
Speaker 0: That was the one.
Speaker 0: That was the last one that I'd seen was The World Is Not Enough.
Speaker 1: Oh, that was like at the peak of everything I hated about Bond.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: And that was the last one.
Speaker 0: So like after that, I was like, well, we're done.
Speaker 0: We're done with Bond for a while.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: All right.
Speaker 2: What else?
Speaker 0: So now now I have to see Skyfall, though, I hear it's very good.
Speaker 1: Well, you should probably see Casino Royale first.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It has one of the better opening credits I've ever seen in a movie theater.
Speaker 1: If that's worth anything.
Speaker 2: How long have we gone?
Speaker 1: We can keep going.
Speaker 1: We've gone on for forty six minutes.
Speaker 2: Not bad.
Speaker 0: I mean, ask.
Speaker 0: Ask me anything.
Speaker 0: I am a Conrad.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: If you had to give an over/under, how many times have you ejaculated in your entire life?
Speaker 2: It's going to be a big number.
Speaker 0: 365 days in a year.
Speaker 1: Now you have to think back to the day when that started happening.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, you're right.
Speaker 1: But there's a graph.
Speaker 1: It's got to be weighted.
Speaker 1: There's probably way more in the days of discovery.
Speaker 0: Well, it was weird because I started masturbating before I could ejaculate.
Speaker 0: So like now this is a weird question.
Speaker 0: That does happen.
Speaker 1: I saw I saw a video of a baby in the womb.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 0: Oh, yikes.
Speaker 0: I mean, it makes sense.
Speaker 0: All the wiring is there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, man.
Speaker 1: OK, so let's say this is called the kids at home with science.
Speaker 1: This is called a Fermi calculation.
Speaker 1: You're attempting to make a broad, generalized guess based on extremely like estimated numbers.
Speaker 0: Let's say 15.
Speaker 0: I'm 27.
Speaker 0: So 12 years, 365 days in a year.
Speaker 0: Let's say that there's an average of one time a day.
Speaker 0: Somebody can do the math with a calculator because I'm not very good at multiple large number multiplication.
Speaker 0: But it basically comes down to 12 times 365.
Speaker 1: It's not too bad.
Speaker 2: No, not bad at all.
Speaker 0: I try really hard.
Speaker 0: You working that bone.
Speaker 0: OK, OK.
Speaker 0: Speaking of shitty anime, have you guys ever seen Green Green?
Speaker 2: I never even heard of Green Green.
Speaker 0: It's awful.
Speaker 1: It was the shit anime.
Speaker 2: Why did jerking off every day remind you of Green Green?
Speaker 0: Because in the opening scene of the first episode, there is a man who introduces himself in this really dramatic way by proclaiming that he's he's masturbated at over 100 strokes a minute and shows his blistered hands.
Speaker 0: That's the image of me you should have right now.
Speaker 1: This is like 2002.
Speaker 0: I watched this in college.
Speaker 2: We didn't know about it.
Speaker 0: My freshman year of college, I watched it.
Speaker 1: We were there.
Speaker 1: No, I know.
Speaker 1: A whole bunch of girls without shirts on.
Speaker 1: One's holding a cactus.
Speaker 1: They're all drinking milk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, this is Green Green.
Speaker 0: OK, so in college, my freshman year of college, we used to every every night we would get Gracie's takeout food.
Speaker 0: And we would watch the worst anime we could find.
Speaker 1: Remember, you remember, Scott, you could fill that you could fill that tray.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 2: The white styrofoam tray.
Speaker 1: But you had to be able to close it or they wouldn't let you walk out with it.
Speaker 0: Which what I always end up like half of the time we did this, I would always end up taking an entire styrofoam tray full of waffle crisps.
Speaker 2: Why didn't you hide a bunch of styrofoam trays in the safety barrel?
Speaker 2: You probably could have gone.
Speaker 0: Oh, God.
Speaker 0: Safety barrel.
Speaker 1: Well, I remember when I moved out of RIT and I looked in my dorm and I realized I had like 40 Gracie's glasses and like a bucket full of styrofoam.
Speaker 0: All of that silverware.
Speaker 0: We still probably have.
Speaker 1: I have several Gracie's forks and knives.
Speaker 2: OK, like I'm not one to be turned on by like, you know, hentai and such, right?
Speaker 2: Animated people.
Speaker 2: Wait, Scott, anytime someone ever says I'm not X, but but if that situation were to occur in real life, that would be pretty amazing.
Speaker 1: Scott, maybe not because she one of these naked girls has a cactus.
Speaker 1: She looks prepared to use it.
Speaker 0: But I really like they all have milk.
Speaker 0: They're all pretty cute.
Speaker 0: I really like milk.
Speaker 2: They're all smiling.
Speaker 2: They're all having a good time.
Speaker 2: They're not upset or anything.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: You know, where's Darryl?
Speaker 1: So I was like, how come they're always crying?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 2: These ones are just like, hey, how's it going?
Speaker 2: It's almost like they're going to play volleyball in nudist colony or something, which is totally hot.
Speaker 1: But Scott, the cactus really worries me.
Speaker 2: Hey, you don't know what the cactus could be for.
Speaker 2: It could be for anything.
Speaker 1: I wonder if that show is worse than Photon.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We did a show recently.
Speaker 1: We started talking about Tenchi Muyo.
Speaker 1: And I remember that I really, really have fond memories.
Speaker 2: You know what my memory of Photon is?
Speaker 1: A small amount of Tenchi Muyo.
Speaker 2: Let me tell you my memory of Photon going into media play.
Speaker 2: And every time the Photon DVD was always there in the same spot and it never moved.
Speaker 2: And I kept seeing it every time I went in there to look through DVDs.
Speaker 2: And that's what I remember of Photon.
Speaker 0: I remember about Blockbuster, actually.
Speaker 0: You'd always go into Blockbuster and every time Ninja Scroll would be in the same place.
Speaker 1: Right next to Doom Megalopolis and Armageddon and Wind of Amnesia.
Speaker 0: Fucking Wind of Amnesia.
Speaker 1: I remember watching that.
Speaker 1: I thought it was the deepest thing ever.
Speaker 1: I was like, "This is amazing.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: This is society.
Speaker 1: This is
Speaker 1: deep.".
Speaker 1: And then at the end, it's like, "Oh, they're having sex
Speaker 1: now.".
Speaker 1: Then my mom walks in and I'm like, "I swear it wasn't like this until just
Speaker 1: And then there's this moment burning my brain where just as my mom is like,
Speaker 1: "Really?"
Speaker 1: He is nibbling on her nipple.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: It gets really into it.
Speaker 2: Well, she didn't bring a cactus.
Speaker 2: Of course, he's going to nibble if you don't have any cactus protection.
Speaker 0: And she's wearing gloves too, man.
Speaker 0: She's ready.
Speaker 1: She's got gloves on both hands.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know.
Speaker 0: She's serious about that cactus, man.
Speaker 1: She is the cutest of these four girls too.
Speaker 0: Oh, I know.
Speaker 1: That hair.
Speaker 0: Yes, that's right.
Speaker 0: We watched this.
Speaker 0: We watched Midori no Hibi.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I watched one episode of that and I was like, "That is
Speaker 1: enough.".
Speaker 2: Is that the one with the puppet hand?
Speaker 2: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It was the shit anime tour, man.
Speaker 0: We watched all the worst stuff.
Speaker 0: We watched Fullmetal Panic, which was good.
Speaker 0: And then we watched Fullmetal Panic Fumofu.
Speaker 2: And that was not.
Speaker 1: That was a travesty, man.
Speaker 0: That was the bait and switch of the moratorium.
Speaker 2: I watched one episode of Fumofu.
Speaker 0: We watched two, which was tough.
Speaker 1: It was like, "Hey, remember this thing that was pretty good that you kind of
Speaker 1: liked?".
Speaker 1: It was okay.
Speaker 1: We're going to shit all over.
Speaker 2: Regular Fullmetal Panic was pretty much a straightforward anime, you know, a little school humor and a little robot fighting.
Speaker 1: And then... Decent plot.
Speaker 2: Fumofu was just, "Where'd the robot fighting
Speaker 2: go?".
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I've asked you guys what you all think about Haruhi.
Speaker 2: I think it's awesome.
Speaker 2: I have only seen a few episodes.
Speaker 1: The original Haruhi?
Speaker 1: Like the first...
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: The very first incarnation.
Speaker 2: I'm not sure what order to watch them.
Speaker 2: Whatever episodes I saw were all right.
Speaker 2: I would watch more.
Speaker 0: I watched them in broadcast order.
Speaker 1: That's how I watched them.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I think it was a brilliant show.
Speaker 1: I thought it was really heartwarming.
Speaker 1: I really, really, really liked it.
Speaker 0: Dude, I actually did too.
Speaker 0: And I get mixed reactions when I ask people about it, which is why I was curious as to what you all thought about it.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to...
Speaker 1: I don't want to speak about it too much because Scott hasn't seen it.
Speaker 0: I don't really want...
Speaker 1: What it is actually about is what makes that show Haruhi.
Speaker 2: Pretty sure I know what it's already about.
Speaker 1: What do you think it's about?
Speaker 1: This is interesting because Scott recently enlightened the fact that he's never read or seen Macbeth.
Speaker 1: So I asked him to explain to me what he thinks Macbeth is about.
Speaker 2: So Scott, what's Haruhi about?
Speaker 1: What is Haruhi about?
Speaker 0: You just changed my entire perspective.
Speaker 2: There's some aliens.
Speaker 2: I know that.
Speaker 2: And they're real.
Speaker 2: And this girl really wants to find the aliens and everyone around her is actually the aliens.
Speaker 2: But she doesn't know that.
Speaker 1: There is a meta...
Speaker 2: And it's also time traveling.
Speaker 1: You're correct, except that there is a meta... You've got what the Prince of Nothing is about, but not what it's about.
Speaker 2: So I don't see the consult.
Speaker 2: is what you're saying?
Speaker 1: No, there's a consult.
Speaker 1: I'll put it like that.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: There's a meta.
Speaker 1: The show is one step deeper than that.
Speaker 2: That's good.
Speaker 2: That means there's a reason to watch.
Speaker 1: That is why the show is good and worth watching.
Speaker 1: Unlike Scrap Princess, which was really fun, but...
Speaker 2: So sad truth.
Speaker 2: I know more about Haruhi, which I've only watched a couple episodes, than I know about Macbeth.
Speaker 0: This is like the affliction that we all have, like 80s anime watchers.
Speaker 0: This is what we take home at the end of the day.
Speaker 1: Well, look at what just happened in our group, just now, this discussion.
Speaker 1: The culture of connected people in the world, at least in the Western industrialized world, is that any conversation, no media is sacred.
Speaker 1: In any group of people, there's going to be the same reaction to... If anyone says any name of a movie, no matter how famous, someone in the room will not have seen it, and everyone else goes,
Speaker 1: "What?".
Speaker 2: Think about it.
Speaker 2: You've never seen the West Indies?
Speaker 2: Think about this, right?
Speaker 2: I say this a lot, I might have said it on the show 10 or 12 times already.
Speaker 2: A kid was just born, just now, somewhere in the world, right?
Speaker 2: Hasn't seen Star Wars, hasn't seen anything ever, hasn't played any video game, hasn't played any... And meanwhile, we're making things faster than that kid can possibly even play one game or whatever, right?
Speaker 2: So yeah, starting now, and starting actually a long time ago, no one's ever going to see or hear or play all the things.
Speaker 2: No matter who you find, it's going to be like, "You don't know the
Speaker 2: whatever?".
Speaker 2: Of course not.
Speaker 2: This isn't possible.
Speaker 0: We've been discussing this a lot, particularly as we've been watching Adventure Time at my house.
Speaker 1: I'm really digging Adventure Time.
Speaker 2: I'm going to start watching Adventure Time pretty soon.
Speaker 1: Scott, it's like Venture Brothers.
Speaker 2: I know what it's about.
Speaker 1: No, I'm saying first season is super fun, but then once you start to get it and kind of get these characters...
Speaker 2: It's all about the secret apocalypse of the past.
Speaker 1: It's also just like, it really grows on you in a way that you wouldn't expect.
Speaker 0: It does, but what really interests me is that the inspiration and the template work that these guys are building off of is very, very clear in a lot of cases, and yet they bring their own really unique and distinct voice to this.
Speaker 0: So you can say, "Well, there's a kid out there who has never seen Star Wars or who maybe will never see Sailor Moon,".
Speaker 0: and to a degree, they have received at least a part of that because they're part of this conversation, I think, that is ongoing.
Speaker 0: I'm not doing a good job of encapsulating in some kind of rambling.
Speaker 0: I apologize.
Speaker 0: But it's very cool to see how all of that stuff that we consider really sacred will appear to the next generation of people.
Speaker 0: I think that's very, very cool.
Speaker 0: And I'm really happy that we have people like Frederator working on stuff like this because they're doing it in absolutely all the right ways, and I think Wreck-It Ralph is another good example of how to kind of respect the past while creating something for the future.
Speaker 2: Did you see that episode that the Adventure Time people put onto this other show on YouTube?
Speaker 2: It was like...
Speaker 0: Oh, with Cartoon Hangover.
Speaker 0: I believe it was called like Awesomenauts or something similar?
Speaker 2: No, it wasn't Awesomenauts, but it was basically like these, you know, what the hell was the name of it?
Speaker 1: Not Superjail.
Speaker 2: No.
Speaker 0: Oh, that was something else.
Speaker 1: Oh, give me... I don't even know what that is.
Speaker 1: I just keep... YouTube, until recently, has recommended to me nothing but that He-Man, yeah, yeah, yeah Because you've watched that a thousand times.
Speaker 1: And My Little Pony.
Speaker 1: And lately, it's been recommending to me Superjail.
Speaker 0: I wasn't impressed with Superjail.
Speaker 0: I just don't think it was my kind of show.
Speaker 0: I don't think it was my kind of humor.
Speaker 0: And I'm not even attempting to make a value judgment.
Speaker 0: It wasn't for me.
Speaker 1: It wasn't for me.
Speaker 1: We have similar tastes lately.
Speaker 1: I mean, Gravity Falls is rockin' it.
Speaker 0: Gravity Falls is phenomenal.
Speaker 1: It's got some flaws, but we didn't show it.
Speaker 0: It does.
Speaker 0: And in the context that nothing is perfect, I think that Gravity Falls is very good, you know?
Speaker 0: And I think it's just good to see all this really good creative work coming to light.
Speaker 0: that's also just very popular and making a lot of money.
Speaker 0: This is what I've always said.
Speaker 0: I've always said that making a good product is very difficult, but once, you know, you've put in the time and you've managed to create something good, pretty much success follows naturally.
Speaker 0: And so part of what I do at Muse is, you know, we all try to focus on that point.
Speaker 0: We try to make a good game above all else.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: This is our one objective.
Speaker 0: And the last game I made, Crevers, wasn't perfect, but I can very easily now isolate the flaws with, you know, the way I ran the project, the flaws with the way I coded the project and the flaws with the way that we created the project.
Speaker 0: And I think that it was like a really necessary speed bump to a degree on the way to Guns of Icarus.
Speaker 0: And, you know, I'm just.
Speaker 0: it's making a good product is the most important part.
Speaker 0: And I really do think people lose sight of that fact.
Speaker 2: The name of that new show is Bravest Warriors.
Speaker 2: That's the way this Warriors.
Speaker 0: Thank you.
Speaker 2: I watched the little thing.
Speaker 2: It was cute.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was cute.
Speaker 2: And I mean, one guy looks like Mega Man.
Speaker 0: I think cartoon, Cartoon Hangover is doing this thing now where you can pitch them anything.
Speaker 2: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 2: And I'll pitch you something.
Speaker 0: They will.
Speaker 0: They will like, man.
Speaker 1: So get this.
Speaker 1: I'm kidnapped and put in a dungeon and there's this dragon.
Speaker 2: There's also a ghost.
Speaker 0: No, the dragon isn't the ghost.
Speaker 0: You see the ghost incidental to the dragon.
Speaker 0: The dragon has the juiciest B hole in town.
Speaker 0: However, slimy, scaly stick around.
Speaker 2: He does.
Speaker 0: You should actually let me close this out with a rap segment.
Speaker 2: Mark, if you're going to close out with a rap segment, you should preempt by pimping yourself, promoting the things that you would like people to.
Speaker 0: I'm actually not going to do a rap segment.
Speaker 0: The only rap lyrics I know are both fake rap lyrics and insanely offensive and feature either any other kind.
Speaker 1: Nothing could be worse than when Tycho did that rap about the prostate at Pax prostate rather barely.
Speaker 2: I remember he did it.
Speaker 1: I don't remember the way I have it in my like mashup of Pax Prime one year.
Speaker 1: I'm going to isolate that and make a separate video of it and link to it.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 1: It's an insidious cluster.
Speaker 1: But anyway, dick ballista.
Speaker 2: Promote your shamelessly self promote your things, which you've already done.
Speaker 2: some of my name.
Speaker 0: My name is Conrad Kraling.
Speaker 0: Right now I'm working at Muse games.
Speaker 0: I was one of the senior engineers on guns of Icarus.
Speaker 0: I was project lead on our last game, Crevers.
Speaker 0: I did the Johnny wander website.
Speaker 0: I am on Johnny wander, Johnny wander.com.
Speaker 0: You'll probably see a lot more of me in the near future.
Speaker 0: I have some cool stuff coming up.
Speaker 0: I'm very excited to share that with you guys.
Speaker 1: You should all cosplay as Conrad at conventions.
Speaker 0: Yes, that's that's right.
Speaker 0: It's really hard.
Speaker 0: You just have to not get a haircut and wear a T-shirt that you stole from somebody two years ago.
Speaker 2: If you need if you need a reference picture, just buy a bottle of what's that stuff?
Speaker 1: Oh, that's soju.
Speaker 1: Soju.
Speaker 0: Just buy a bottle.
Speaker 0: Buy a bottle of Chamey Sewell Original and take a look at the guy holding it.
Speaker 0: That's me.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Chamey Sewell Original, by the way, is the only soju you should drink the end.
Speaker 0: The only.
Speaker 0: That's the one.
Speaker 2: Well, you endorse it.
Speaker 2: You're on it.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, obviously they pay me the right.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: I feel like if William Williams told you to drink St.
Speaker 2: Paint, it's not going to happen.
Speaker 1: It is no worse.
Speaker 0: Nobody is surprised.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 2: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 2: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 2: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 2: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: As long as I wear this, I'm able to cast three spells simultaneously.
Speaker 1: Remember, this is dangerous, kids, so don't try it at home.