Speaker 1: It's Wednesday April 24th 2013.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight the anime we're not watching.
Speaker 1: let's do this all right.
Speaker 0: so I think it's just about Oh near the end of April so it's time to curse the Mets because they're not doing the worst.
Speaker 1: you know every.
Speaker 0: make sure they do the worst.
Speaker 1: every year season starts.
Speaker 1: either someone links it to me or whatever.
Speaker 1: it's in a forum somewhere.
Speaker 1: it's on Farc.
Speaker 1: there's just that video of Stewie Griffin and family guys sitting down for a baseball game and at the announcer's like and it's opening season and the Mets have lost and then he's like throws his head down and walks away.
Speaker 0: yep that's how it is so.
Speaker 0: but anyway we have a pitcher on our team.
Speaker 0: his name's Matt Harvey right and he's apparently like the best.
Speaker 0: he's pretty much the best pitcher there is.
Speaker 0: he just showed up out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: it doesn't mean much though because I mean there was a point where the Tigers had a great pitcher didn't really win.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 0: so I thought of talking about this as an opening bit because I saw a guy on the subway just now wearing a Matt Harvey jersey and the.
Speaker 0: he didn't go to the.
Speaker 0: he thought he was gonna get on the seven and go to the game but he didn't.
Speaker 0: okay well you got off at Queensborough Plaza and he went somewhere.
Speaker 1: you know you thought he was.
Speaker 0: I thought you said he thought like I got he was going to the game.
Speaker 1: and I'm like what you said that I thought he thought he was going to the game and then didn't.
Speaker 1: and I was like how could you even know?
Speaker 0: no it's like you see someone going on the seven train platform wearing a lot of Mets.
Speaker 0: shit you think they're gonna get on the seven train especially when the game is gonna start at like 710. right he could easily made it to that game on time.
Speaker 0: he was on the train.
Speaker 0: that was the perfect way to get to the game.
Speaker 1: I would posit that that's only the case if he's also loud and or belligerent on the train.
Speaker 0: no that's on the way home after but anyway.
Speaker 0: so you know the thing is right.
Speaker 0: my dad's name is Harvey.
Speaker 0: so we usually have a no Jersey buying policy because if you buy if you know if I buy a Matt Harvey Jersey guess it's gonna happen he's gonna break his arm.
Speaker 0: right it's guaranteed.
Speaker 0: it's basically saying hey sporting goods store I will pay you I don't know.
Speaker 0: what do they cost like 75 to 100 bucks.
Speaker 0: I'll give you a hundred bucks if you can make sure the Matt Harvey breaks his arm like in the next week.
Speaker 0: so thank you.
Speaker 0: here have a free Jersey as a token.
Speaker 1: see hockey has such the opposite culture.
Speaker 1: like you buy the Jersey of the guy that you are sure is going to live forever and he will.
Speaker 1: I mean I still have a Fedorov Jersey and I was good Jersey.
Speaker 1: I think even have a Vernon Jersey laying around.
Speaker 0: you should have bought a jogger Jersey.
Speaker 0: he's we can live forever.
Speaker 1: anyway my brother has a thing in Constantine off.
Speaker 0: my dad can buy a Matt Harvey Jersey because at least for him it'll be good.
Speaker 0: even if Matt Harvey like gets hit by a bus he'll still be like because it says Harvey.
Speaker 1: huh so it's Harvey.
Speaker 1: we're in the Harvey Jersey drinking a Harvey wall banger.
Speaker 1: sure though I you know it's kind of a random aside but I was uh you know I have this like I don't know whitewater rafting Jersey that I just have that I wear when I go skiing like over my under armor but
Speaker 0: a white one yeah
Speaker 1: but under my ski jacket.
Speaker 1: so when I'm like in the lodge I have something on other than just my undershirt basically and it's for warmth and whatever.
Speaker 1: no one ever commented on it.
Speaker 1: it's totally utilitarian kind of old and stained and worn out.
Speaker 1: the last few times I went skiing I started wearing my Fedorov red wings Jersey instead and apparently red wings jerseys are girl magnets.
Speaker 1: okay because once I was wearing that instead of my white Jersey girls would hit on me at the bar after I was skiing before I got on the bus home reliably.
Speaker 0: it is a ski lodge.
Speaker 0: yeah what do you think they do there?
Speaker 0: they're not skiing.
Speaker 0: they're always like the only one who's going there to ski.
Speaker 1: or they're from upstate New York or they're from there like local.
Speaker 0: you are the only one who is at the ski lodge for skiing except for that old guy with the crazy not matching clothes and the young kid on the bunny slope right.
Speaker 0: so and the ski patrol?
Speaker 1: I've talked about this a lot.
Speaker 1: well not a lot but I brought it up often.
Speaker 1: but now that I've gotten past the middle point of the show I want to give a kind of for real review of from the new world or Shinsekai Ori because I've seen enough now to know that it is a good show.
Speaker 1: in the very least the worst-case scenario this is a b-plus anime like beaten-out scrap princess.
Speaker 0: is this the one that had a porny manga or was it the pointy at it?
Speaker 1: okay there is a it's complicated I'll put it this way what this show is about and I believe it's based on some light novels.
Speaker 1: there may be a manga in other words porn.
Speaker 1: no no so here's the deal.
Speaker 1: people say that but it's actually a plot point.
Speaker 1: that's kind of zebra storyteller ition.
Speaker 1: interesting the plot of this show is that sounds like a true bra excuse.
Speaker 1: okay so hear me out.
Speaker 1: in the in the nearing future some sort of modern society like today suddenly out of nowhere people start manifesting psychic powers like x-men style.
Speaker 1: but imagine if everyone had Jean Grey's powers great automatically the end of the world.
Speaker 0: so.
Speaker 1: and the opening montage is horrifying.
Speaker 1: like a kid just suddenly everyone around him explodes in piles of blood and yeah ours are just flying everywhere.
Speaker 1: society basically falls apart.
Speaker 0: so it's a lot like what's it called.
Speaker 0: that's the cute town that's actually murderville with the labor unions or whatever it was.
Speaker 0: what are you talking about that anime where?
Speaker 1: oh oh the one with Colonel Sanders when they cry yeah yeah as a million sequels.
Speaker 1: I kind of liked that show and I show one episode.
Speaker 1: I was about to say that shows relevant to our topic today's indeed.
Speaker 1: so you made me lose my train of thought there.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: so since I got yours so this happens.
Speaker 1: you just get like this sort of montage of this happening and then the show just starts with a bunch of kids in elementary school into what looks like old Japan but with a few anachronistic modern technologies laying about.
Speaker 1: so it's a prequel to Adventure Time and it's weird and you're not really sure what's going on.
Speaker 1: and basically the plot is that society Futurama style.
Speaker 1: remember when you see that that montage where he's frozen and like society gets destroyed by aliens castles aliens destroy the castles.
Speaker 1: the same thing happens.
Speaker 1: society kind of rebuilds over time and eventually the society that works is based on this amalgam of old cultures and hypnotism and eugenics and societal structures set up in place to allow humans who had basically have Jean Grey's powers to coexist with each other and not accidentally murder everybody.
Speaker 1: okay and it works really well.
Speaker 1: and but at the same time the eugenics is to such a degree because the danger is.
Speaker 0: so let's see this baby up.
Speaker 0: this is dangerous baby kill it.
Speaker 1: yeah there's a point where you find out.
Speaker 1: you find out from I guess the Ethics Committee that they changed the Constitution or the rules of the society so that the dates before which is legal to abort someone is moved from like a week or two after birth to the age of 17.
Speaker 0: and in case they discover somebody's gonna destroy the world by accident they say you know the way I would describe this show.
Speaker 1: really is it's a post apocalyptic psychic 1984. all right and it's really good.
Speaker 1: and the reason it's really good.
Speaker 1: I want to compare it to another show we tried to watch and didn't watch called number six because number six started out in kind of the same way in the sense that all right there's some awesome stuff here there's some kind of mystery of space there's all the stuff that I care about.
Speaker 1: and then that show just went nowhere.
Speaker 1: it had like the worst pacing like it got to a point of all right.
Speaker 1: now it's time to move on to the next thing.
Speaker 1: and then it stayed on a thing for so long that I stopped watching.
Speaker 0: I noticed this theme a lot in anime.
Speaker 0: number six ergo proxy Raza fon of the.
Speaker 0: you know there is a an evil 1984 society in a dome and something else going on outside the dome.
Speaker 0: big oh big oh has the same thing but it some shows like number six.
Speaker 1: as soon as they get outside of the dome the plot just goes nowhere and the end is stupid.
Speaker 1: Emily spoiled it for me.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I didn't watch number six.
Speaker 1: fuck that show.
Speaker 1: so the reason this show is good one is pretty good music - it escalates rapidly and it time skips several times.
Speaker 0: and where's all this porn come in?
Speaker 1: okay so one of the aspects of the show is that basically the plot like you don't know what's going on.
Speaker 1: they just keep showing you vignettes from different eras of history like at one point it cuts to some point that looks older than the current time in the show but much newer than the apocalypse and it looks like a traditional Japanese like this is the new Emperor.
Speaker 1: and then the Emperor uses psychic power to float over the crowd and very happily announces that they're that in celebration of the inauguration of his eternal reign the first hundred people to stop clapping will be executed.
Speaker 1: and then later you see a flashback of later than that someone assassinating him.
Speaker 1: and it keeps going back and forth current day and these weird sort of flashbacks to things that happened in this society and then eventually the kids who are kind of the focus of the show.
Speaker 1: they're like the main characters go on a school trip and they go kind of outside where they're supposed to.
Speaker 1: they find a library and they get zebra storyteller because the library is like yeah your society is designed eugenics eugenics eugenics.
Speaker 1: babies get murdered and they're like what.
Speaker 1: and they learn things like.
Speaker 1: here's an example I get.
Speaker 1: the show kind of goes really in-depth.
Speaker 1: there's a point at which they skipped over all the porn part.
Speaker 1: I'm getting to the porn part.
Speaker 1: so they learn that humans have this sort of.
Speaker 0: just tell everyone the whole show.
Speaker 0: you've been going on for like 10 minutes.
Speaker 1: yeah cuz this is not the spoiler stuff.
Speaker 1: you sort of learned that like.
Speaker 1: one of the ways the society works is that humans cannot harm things that look like humans.
Speaker 0: mm-hmm that's like embedded deep into the psyche of all except for that kid who just made out everyone explode around.
Speaker 1: that was way before.
Speaker 1: that was before this new society existed.
Speaker 1: okay that was like modern times.
Speaker 1: it's like today kid in the street get psychic powers.
Speaker 1: one of those things is that what is implanted into humans is very sort of specific sexual needs and progression such that they won't get pregnant.
Speaker 1: or have you know the urges that might cause them to lash out until they're ready and then they'll sort of immediately pair off and have babies.
Speaker 1: and in stressful situations they took genes and brain things from bonobos.
Speaker 1: so people will respond to stressful situations with pleasure or sex rather than violence.
Speaker 0: so in other words they created that plot point just to put lots of porn.
Speaker 1: no they actually don't really show that at all.
Speaker 0: then why are all these pictures of the show really sort of perverted looking like all the other anime?
Speaker 1: I really don't know because I've seen 14 episodes of the show and that's not there at all.
Speaker 1: there is literally nothing like that in the show.
Speaker 1: okay there is one point where one of the girls is in a relationship with another one of the girls because that's how the society set up.
Speaker 1: they don't want to have babies yet so they're all kind of automatically homosexual.
Speaker 1: but the show that's just part of the.
Speaker 1: you know what's going on.
Speaker 1: suddenly the girls like because she knows about the bonobo thing she wants to kiss the other girls.
Speaker 1: she's like wait a minute wait a minute.
Speaker 1: this is just the society.
Speaker 1: psychic bullshit 1984. and these kids are all sort of zebra storytellers and the ethics committees and everything are watching them and it's just like 1984 but they have psychic powers.
Speaker 1: yeah everyone has psychic powers.
Speaker 0: yes it's like a battle time.
Speaker 1: they can't battle each other.
Speaker 1: because of that thing where you can't hurt other humans physically prevented from doing so you basically die.
Speaker 1: if you try to do it the show is really really good.
Speaker 0: I'll just knock this building down.
Speaker 0: I was hurting the building.
Speaker 1: that's also very difficult to do that.
Speaker 1: I mean I'm trying to skip stuff because you wanted me to not talk about the show too much.
Speaker 1: anyway I'll put it this way the show is really well done.
Speaker 0: no reason to watch the show now.
Speaker 1: really well animated escalates very rapidly every time.
Speaker 1: I think alright now the show is gonna get boring.
Speaker 1: it immediately skips to the next plot point burning wheel style and every time you think well why don't the characters just do act?
Speaker 1: yeah they do pretty much immediately.
Speaker 1: they're smarter than you or at least as smart as you and I really like this show.
Speaker 1: I think it's the best anime I'm watching currently or know about.
Speaker 1: that is on recently that I haven't seen yet man.
Speaker 1: so I'll probably finish it soon and whenever Scott watches it will do a kind of full review.
Speaker 0: but it's super good on your porn if you need any anime to watch right now.
Speaker 1: watch since that guy you're.
Speaker 1: it's all on crunchyroll alright.
Speaker 0: so we've been talking about this for a thousand years.
Speaker 0: the Monaco is out today.
Speaker 0: yes I've been playing it for about a two keys already one in the newsletter that you subscribe to and one on Google Plus on our Google Plus page which you should you know look at.
Speaker 0: so you know hey benefits for following us in all the places.
Speaker 0: yep Monaco is the best.
Speaker 1: Monaco is pretty fun.
Speaker 0: if you play video games and you have a computer you should be playing this video game seriously.
Speaker 0: how often do we say this video game is the game to play doesn't even begin with N?
Speaker 1: the way I would sell it to you is it's a stealth cooperative competitive game but unlike most stealth games like mark of the ninja where oh I got seen start over.
Speaker 1: fuck this.
Speaker 1: when you get seen it's oh shit.
Speaker 1: and that's when you start bombing everything and running away.
Speaker 1: and it's.
Speaker 1: it's just like a heist movie.
Speaker 0: it's a party game.
Speaker 1: it's a party game.
Speaker 0: heist movie with it might be it might be the ultimate party game.
Speaker 0: that's actually not just something like Tetris.
Speaker 1: well the ultimate party game is still a wario where on the game I'm just saying this is there's no better might be like the skill based party game.
Speaker 0: it's pretty great just never really existed before.
Speaker 1: I'm digging it.
Speaker 1: and our review of early be on Tuesday.
Speaker 0: yep yep all right all right.
Speaker 1: so things of the day.
Speaker 1: if you guys haven't noticed I'm a pretty big fan of adventure time and had the same progression that ponies had that.
Speaker 1: a lot of things I've seen recently had even venture brothers where I watch the first like couple episodes of something I'm like oh this is okay.
Speaker 1: I know why.
Speaker 1: I understand why people like it now but I'm not that into it.
Speaker 1: and then a few more episodes later just one of my favorite things ever adventure time pretty much followed that exact same progression.
Speaker 1: I watch every episode like the day it comes out on some ultra like bootleg cam cap bullshit.
Speaker 1: okay it's great.
Speaker 1: my thing of the day is just a pretty good.
Speaker 1: what time is it?
Speaker 1: musical mashup from adventure time.
Speaker 1: that reminds me very much of this cool guy who did similar mashups of for example the old Alice in Wonderland cartoon pogo.
Speaker 0: yeah yeah the guy who can't come in the US because he fucked up his visa pogo is pretty cool.
Speaker 1: this is reminiscent of his style and it's also if you haven't seen adventure time it gives you a nice sampling of what the deal is with adventure time.
Speaker 0: alright.
Speaker 0: so my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: this guy works at Publix which is a pretty good grocery store not as good as Wegmans but it's down in Florida.
Speaker 0: Publix has a secret if you've never been to one.
Speaker 0: if you live down south where they have these stores you can actually go to the deli counter where they have the meats and the cheeses and get peanut butter that they make in the store from peanuts.
Speaker 0: fresh is the best peanut butter.
Speaker 1: like the grocery store right here has that too.
Speaker 1: which grocery store the food cellar like right there?
Speaker 0: that's a fancy grocery store.
Speaker 0: yeah this would be like if stop and shop had that shit.
Speaker 0: this is like you know if you went to you know fine fair and they had some Trader Joe's shit up.
Speaker 0: it's like whoa.
Speaker 0: what is this doing here?
Speaker 0: cuz Publix is like a normal grocery store.
Speaker 0: it's like a stop and shop but it's like they got some pretty good stuff there that you wouldn't expect to be you know.
Speaker 0: so anyway this guy works in a Publix.
Speaker 0: he looks like maybe a high school kid or whatever I can't even tell and he's cutting up a watermelon cuz you know what they do is they have an ugly watermelon.
Speaker 0: it's not gonna sell you know.
Speaker 0: so they cut it up and they will sell slices in a plastic package or they'll sell.
Speaker 0: they'll put up a bunch of chunks into like a little plastic cup and sell that.
Speaker 0: you know grocery stores do.
Speaker 0: she's cutting up a watermelon.
Speaker 0: this dude can cut the whole watermelon in 30 seconds or less.
Speaker 0: it is crazy.
Speaker 0: his watermelon cutting skills.
Speaker 0: you got to invite him to your you know 4th of July party.
Speaker 1: it goes to show if your job if you have a job that makes you do one thing that's boring and mechanical repeatedly you will get good at it.
Speaker 0: I always have a lot of respect for people with those menial jobs where they get.
Speaker 0: you know incredible dexterity and you know reflex skills got to this day.
Speaker 1: you should see me or Alex make a fucking submarine sandwich after working.
Speaker 0: right but it's like see how many videos are things of the day.
Speaker 0: we're like guy really good at ironing or guy really good at making pancake or guy really good at doing his little ice cream trick where he gives you ice cream and then takes it back.
Speaker 0: you know all that kind of stuff I kind of actually you know think one day maybe I'm an old man or when computers program themselves I'll get a job like that and master some meaningless skill for awesomeness.
Speaker 0: you know I kind of want to do that.
Speaker 1: book club.
Speaker 1: book is player of games by you know banks.
Speaker 1: we'll do it soon.
Speaker 1: it's biking seasons.
Speaker 0: only next month.
Speaker 1: I don't read as much as I do in normally in biking season because I primarily read on the subway.
Speaker 1: we got internet stuff.
Speaker 1: we're gonna be an anime Boston.
Speaker 1: we're gonna be at PAX Australia.
Speaker 1: we're gonna be a pecs prime.
Speaker 1: we might be a pecs dev.
Speaker 1: yeah we're gonna be at all those things.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: check out our youtubes.
Speaker 1: and rave master was a pretty shitty show I don't know.
Speaker 1: I know you watch way more of it than I did.
Speaker 0: I watch like five six seven episodes something like that.
Speaker 0: I thought it was long ago.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: we were trying to think about a show vaguely around the idea of anime we won't watch or didn't watch.
Speaker 0: but I started watching and didn't finish watch because I thought way back.
Speaker 1: someone put together a pretty good list.
Speaker 1: it was like the hundred best anime of all time and I remember looking at the list realizing I had watched like 97 of them most and I knew what the other three were.
Speaker 0: I knew I knew what every single thing on the list was and I had seen the overwhelming plurality of them and I realized I've seen a lot of goddamn anime.
Speaker 1: but yet there is a large list of anime that I have specifically despite knowing it exists chosen not to watch it and I'm talking about stuff that I barely know exists like I don't know crappy new moe show that is obviously just incest.
Speaker 0: yeah like I know there's a show called Canon but do I really need to tell you why I haven't watched it?
Speaker 1: yeah I watched one episode of that Tokimeki anime and it was awful.
Speaker 0: there's the Tokimeki anime.
Speaker 1: I got it because the kill the guy who did those Sailor Moon subs and the end of Eva subs.
Speaker 1: back in the day that I got he also randomly subbed that.
Speaker 0: yeah let's start by talking about anime that we started watching but didn't finish and then we'll move on from there rave master.
Speaker 0: so rave master I watched five six episodes.
Speaker 1: I watched two episodes and I remember thinking it was just dumb and I actually stopped watching current anime after that because that was the popular show everyone was watching.
Speaker 1: I was you know it wasn't that popular in the anime club at the time.
Speaker 1: it was yeah was?
Speaker 1: we showed in the anime club but then people were all talking about it and watching it like.
Speaker 1: I don't remember that was the show all the normal people in the club would talk about before club for like.
Speaker 0: well I don't remember that.
Speaker 0: I watched just a few episodes because it was the new show.
Speaker 0: it had bright colors the.
Speaker 0: it was a basically an adventure show where the guy had a big sword and a pet and the pet was really cute and there was some sort of mysterious fantasy adventure that I want to know the secret of.
Speaker 0: but what ended up happening was after five six episodes I realized wait a minute and I rewinded and I looked.
Speaker 0: they spent like four or five episodes in a row like a whole bunch of them.
Speaker 0: they were in one room.
Speaker 0: all the characters are in that room not leaving the room.
Speaker 0: it was like some throne room or something or something right and just this one battle that was even slower than Naruto battle and I was like wow nothing has happened in these past few episodes.
Speaker 0: it is still the same battle not watching anymore.
Speaker 0: yep the same thing happened to me with Naruto.
Speaker 1: oh my god we've.
Speaker 1: I remember Naruto like the people who are.
Speaker 1: why cuz you know we were running the anime club so we didn't have as much time to watch anime.
Speaker 1: a few of the harder core people in the club watched Naruto before us and we're raving about.
Speaker 0: everyone is raving about Naruto and it was this was Naruto was brand new the newest.
Speaker 1: so we were like all right it's funny ninja school.
Speaker 1: let's show it to the club.
Speaker 0: I had never I had never seen it and but everyone was talking it up.
Speaker 0: so I said I'll get to it someday.
Speaker 0: so we showed it at clubs and I watched those four episodes and I said that is hysterical that ninja school with the sexy nojitsu this is.
Speaker 0: everyone was totally right.
Speaker 0: the show is awesome.
Speaker 1: that show was awesome.
Speaker 0: and then I recall so I went home and I kept watching Naruto.
Speaker 0: yeah but I recall it was so awesome.
Speaker 1: where actually two moments ruin the show from.
Speaker 0: I got episode 13.
Speaker 1: the moment that ruined it for me was there was this whole build-up in this big fight that I didn't notice yet was just a Dragon Ball fight and sudden fine the whole thing was how did Naruto do that like how did he win?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: everyone's trying to figure out how he won and then it was just some proper noun bullshit.
Speaker 1: he just used a special technique and I was like wait a minute.
Speaker 1: how long did that fight?
Speaker 1: wait a minute.
Speaker 1: this is Dragon Ball.
Speaker 0: I got to episode 13. they were basically in this fight against like magic crystal mirror girl and big sword guy and it was you know Naruto and the girl and Sasuke I remember the girl's name anymore right and they're fighting against magic mirror crystal girl and big sword guy.
Speaker 0: it's like the first big fight of the show.
Speaker 0: and first of all I'm already upset because funny ninja school is gone right yep and the best character the teacher guy is not there and I'm like what the fuck where is the awesome teacher?
Speaker 0: I want him in every episode.
Speaker 0: he should be the main character and that fight finally ends like episode 13 and I said wait a minute rave master.
Speaker 0: this fight has been going on since like episode 7 now watching any more Naruto's.
Speaker 1: I don't think we need to belabor the point on fighting shows but suffice it to say there's a problem.
Speaker 1: we had in those days where we were mostly watching really old anime from the library and the current popular show and every time it was a shonen fighting show.
Speaker 1: the first couple episodes of those shows are usually awesome because they usually have really cool iconic characters.
Speaker 0: yeah bleach yeah bleach bleach is the worst of them all.
Speaker 0: cuz after episode one I knew and I was done with it.
Speaker 0: yeah I was like episode one.
Speaker 0: all right this is a little bit like Yu Yu Hakusho kind of.
Speaker 1: yeah Yu Yu Hakusho episode.
Speaker 1: one same thing.
Speaker 1: I thought it was great.
Speaker 0: then episode two.
Speaker 0: wait a minute I'm catching on now you're not fooling me till episode 13 again.
Speaker 1: so I think the worst of all of those it's because it's so bad it warrants a special mention.
Speaker 1: because this show we I watched four episodes of yeah partly because we showed it in club and I was the one who had to stick around to lock the door.
Speaker 1: Final Fantasy unlimited.
Speaker 0: I did not watch that.
Speaker 1: that might be the worst show.
Speaker 1: I say show because there's special things like gray the digital target that I had ever seen up to that scene.
Speaker 1: okay it was unbearable and had nothing to do with Final Fantasy except it happened to have a chocobo and this is before a lot of the final thing wasn't there.
Speaker 0: that other Final Fantasy anime?
Speaker 0: yes it is older it is worse worse Christiana whatever?
Speaker 1: yeah yeah that's worse and I chose not to watch it.
Speaker 0: never see.
Speaker 0: I remember that tape was always in the library and that would be one of the tape was always in blows.
Speaker 0: one of the tape see but always point you and go.
Speaker 1: wow the worst that was a show.
Speaker 0: I didn't watch that either.
Speaker 1: I'd go I'd look at blockbuster and I'd see that and I'd see like Armageddon and I'd be like I'm gonna watch Armageddon anyway.
Speaker 0: so another just to finish off the fighting show list.
Speaker 0: right one piece.
Speaker 0: I will actually watch the one piece anime for episodes and I liked all of them and I wanted to keep watching.
Speaker 0: but I switched over to the manga and I got to fighting the swordfish man and that lasted multiple volumes of manga.
Speaker 0: so I stopped buying new volumes.
Speaker 0: but then it the final volume showed up because I pre-ordered and that volume they beat the fish man and the plot moved crazy fast and I was like oh my god this is why one piece is awesome.
Speaker 0: why can't every volume be like this?
Speaker 0: but then I still held fast and did not order any more volumes.
Speaker 1: yep these are just showing.
Speaker 0: that is a good thing.
Speaker 0: otherwise I would need the whole bookshelf just through the one piece.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I will ever be at a point in my life where I can deal with the shonen fighting formula of fights go on forever and the show also goes on forever no matter how good the character.
Speaker 0: watched all of Hokuto no Ken and now I feel as if I'm done.
Speaker 0: I feel like and if I need that again I'll watch Hokuto no Ken again for whatever reason.
Speaker 1: well like we've talked about this before Hokuto no Ken despite having many of the same issues feel because it invented the issue exactly.
Speaker 1: but it also feels faster like if I watched ten episodes.
Speaker 0: yeah because when he punches someone in the head they die immediately.
Speaker 0: none of this ten episode per fight it's just a different fight every fucking episode.
Speaker 1: there might be several episodes of.
Speaker 1: I'm going to do this thing.
Speaker 0: even the climactic fights like against row and shit are like two episodes the same as the initial D. a race doesn't last more than two episodes in initial D but one piece I just couldn't deal with.
Speaker 1: yeah I think it might have be the one.
Speaker 1: how long the show is like initial D. even when I was watching it I recognized the formula that was going on but I knew it was 26 episodes.
Speaker 0: but it's not.
Speaker 1: it was at the time one piece I knew from the beginning was gonna be even longer than freakin anything all right.
Speaker 0: so other anime started watching did not finish.
Speaker 1: interesting though I watched all of Sailor Moon that's 200 episodes so whatever.
Speaker 1: so let's get into something different not a fighting show.
Speaker 1: ergo proxy was the show that I liked.
Speaker 0: I kind of liked it was good.
Speaker 0: it wasn't the best.
Speaker 0: it was a show that when I was wondering what the terrible secret of space was started out kind of boring and then really quickly got really good.
Speaker 0: I actually thought the first episode is more exciting because all the cool sci-fi stuff in the city.
Speaker 1: I thought the first episode was less exciting because it seemed so like it was trying so hard to be dark and gritty and it wasn't the best cool sci-fi city cyberpunk.
Speaker 0: but it was okay.
Speaker 0: but basically outside the city.
Speaker 0: it was like oh I don't care about these people outside the city I just want to see you try to get back in.
Speaker 1: well the show.
Speaker 1: I was like.
Speaker 1: I liked it.
Speaker 1: and then just when I started to get bored they were like we're getting out of the city with the girl in the rabbit costume.
Speaker 1: then I was like oh this is awesome and then it got boring again and it just started to pick up and then we were just busy and kind of stopped watching it.
Speaker 1: cuz I think we were Netflix net at the time and I didn't like it so much that I like fought to go back and see it again so that eventually we kind of like it was a show that we liked but we kind of forgot we were watching.
Speaker 1: yeah because there was a gap.
Speaker 1: like if there hadn't been that gap I think it was like we went to two conventions or something.
Speaker 1: we didn't have time.
Speaker 1: we probably would have finished the show but as soon as we forgot we were watching it we've never stopped.
Speaker 1: we never watched any more of it.
Speaker 0: Kazu no Yojimbo is similar right.
Speaker 0: it's like we watched a little bit of anime club back in the day or something I
Speaker 1: tried to watch a
Speaker 0: watching it for Netflix and it's like it wasn't the best show but it wasn't bad and I was kind of curious what the D of mystery was in the town.
Speaker 1: yeah it also had really good moments like where the guy'd go out.
Speaker 1: then there's the gunshot.
Speaker 1: he's like who fired that.
Speaker 1: what's going on?
Speaker 0: yep so it's just we just kept watching it sort of you know rolling with it just seeing what's up and then something interrupted them because it wasn't so good that we were desperate and wanted to seek again.
Speaker 0: we wasn't good enough for us to put an effort to see more.
Speaker 0: so any interruption in the habit of watching it basically ended watching it.
Speaker 1: so years later when I was commuting every day on the train to Yonkers from Beacon I had a little DVD thing and I was like you know what I'm gonna start why I need some anime I can watch going to and from work on the train.
Speaker 1: so I got I was like oh yeah Kazu no Yojimbo I remember kind of liking that.
Speaker 1: so I started watching it and I got to about the point.
Speaker 1: Scott and I had watched it before and I suddenly realized it was a chore like.
Speaker 1: I liked it.
Speaker 1: okay but an episode would end and I'd be like well guess I should watch the next one like I got.
Speaker 0: if I gotta get it's not like that time when I put Evangelion on my phone and was like can't stop oh my god.
Speaker 1: there was one time one of our friends was on my phone one of the FRC you know Scott and I moved back into our apartment at RIT mm-hmm like we're.
Speaker 1: I forget if we move back in or if we just been there and then someone returned.
Speaker 1: cuz I figure we hear the turn cowboy bebop on.
Speaker 1: yeah we just like marathoning it to an unnamed member of the FRC.
Speaker 1: we were like what you've never seen cowboy bebop what the fuck.
Speaker 1: well here we'll show you a couple episodes and then whatever and then the three of us marathon the entire show.
Speaker 1: at that moment I watched episode one.
Speaker 1: I was like oh right the show is the best.
Speaker 1: so I was watching cos the new yojimbo kind of forcing my way through it.
Speaker 1: it was okay.
Speaker 1: but then I watched one episode of eska flown and I was like oh my god that's what it feels like to really want to watch the next episode of a show.
Speaker 1: that's right.
Speaker 1: and then I decided right then and there I will never again watch another episode of any show that I don't feel.
Speaker 1: hmm as soon as I detect that it is they chore a slog.
Speaker 1: perhaps I'm bailing and going home and I'm watching Ava or eska cowboy bebop Gundam seed yeah ghost in the shell all right.
Speaker 0: are there any other shows you started watching and did not well pleat watching we so Scott and Emily both had never really seen slayers a while ago.
Speaker 1: so we started watching it bit by bit because I've seen most of slayers.
Speaker 1: yeah this is before revolution or any of this stuff.
Speaker 1: so we you know I got a dvds a bard and we started watching regular slayers again and super fun.
Speaker 1: and we watch next and we just haven't started.
Speaker 1: try yet.
Speaker 0: well that's not sweet haven't started it.
Speaker 0: so it doesn't really fit the start of it.
Speaker 1: you've never seen it.
Speaker 1: you could watch it at any time.
Speaker 1: it's sitting right there I will.
Speaker 0: I want to.
Speaker 0: yeah it's good.
Speaker 0: I did watch the first episode of slayers revolution.
Speaker 0: that doesn't really go.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of.
Speaker 0: have the animes that I've watched one episode of but I don't think those count.
Speaker 0: I think it's more animes.
Speaker 0: you watched a few episodes of right for example.
Speaker 1: I think the killer is the show that you watch most of and that like if you got more than halfway through and then you stop.
Speaker 0: yeah so check this out right over the winner.
Speaker 0: I got my bike in place thing.
Speaker 0: I was watching space runaway eating on while biking in place right I remember that shows name.
Speaker 0: originally I had watched like five episodes and stopped and then I got this time while biking in place in my apartment I watched seventy to eighty percent of that show before stopping.
Speaker 0: wow and it's not that it really changed.
Speaker 0: it got bad or was a slog.
Speaker 0: it was you know it was just sort of.
Speaker 0: so nothing in is a terrible secret I want to learn to.
Speaker 0: but the thing is most of the episodes it's pretty much every episode has a space battle no matter what right even though it's a different space battle each episode.
Speaker 0: so it's sort of like I really just want to fast forward through that battle.
Speaker 0: see who wins it.
Speaker 0: it's just like okay you're flying around and shooting each other in spaceships again and the robot okay and yep and that takes up a lot of time.
Speaker 0: some of the episodes it'll take up like half the episode.
Speaker 1: you know Wolf's Rain which is people have talking about again.
Speaker 0: another one.
Speaker 1: I started I got more than halfway through it.
Speaker 1: I got ten episodes maybe and then I got bored with it.
Speaker 1: I never saw the end.
Speaker 0: I got it when I got it when the party was together and running through the snowy place.
Speaker 1: yep but there's a part.
Speaker 1: I literally I was just like I didn't care anymore like I couldn't see where the show was going.
Speaker 1: yep but I got more than halfway through at least with a speedgrapher four episodes in I was like fuck this yeah as soon as he got weird.
Speaker 1: no I like weird.
Speaker 1: it just it was weird that I didn't care about.
Speaker 1: yep I mean and it was slow but not in a good way like gassaraki is slow but I like that kind of slow.
Speaker 1: yep I like that kind of slow a lot way more than a lot of other people do.
Speaker 0: but you don't like the galaxy train kind of slow night on the galactic railroad.
Speaker 1: yeah no I don't enjoy that movie don't enjoy it at all.
Speaker 1: but slow space other kinds of shows that do like.
Speaker 1: yeah but speedgrapher was just like.
Speaker 1: it's the kind of show where I if I can't project any good direction like any angle for the show like Ava watching it I projected immediately there's all these angles that could have like.
Speaker 1: maybe it's gonna be about gods maybe it's gonna be about transhumanism.
Speaker 1: but I can project or predict angles that are gonna be awesome but like Wolf's reign I couldn't come up with any possible way for it to have a satisfying ending.
Speaker 1: hmm and the same thing with speedgrapher.
Speaker 1: I was like there is nothing the show could be about that would actually satisfy me at the end and explain this bullshit that I just watched.
Speaker 0: right I got two other shows that I can think of on the top of my head that fit this category.
Speaker 0: all right one is the or on high school host club.
Speaker 1: I really like that show.
Speaker 0: actually watch like four episodes and it was funny and it was good.
Speaker 0: but by the fourth episode it was sort of like it's the same joke all this sort of same.
Speaker 0: you know jokes that you had in the other episode.
Speaker 0: you know these sort of gendery jokes and things like that and you know what.
Speaker 0: I've heard those jokes before and I don't really feel a strong desire to see the next episode because I'm not laughing at these jokes that hard.
Speaker 0: so I actually did want to keep watching.
Speaker 1: I watched two episodes of that and I marathon the whole thing with Emily.
Speaker 0: I want to know the terrible secret but I did terrible see.
Speaker 1: that show is great.
Speaker 0: I know most of the terrible secrets.
Speaker 0: actually at least I'm pretty close.
Speaker 1: yeah I know you don't and then I'll put it this way who do you think is the terrible secret like?
Speaker 1: what do you think it revolves around?
Speaker 0: well is it?
Speaker 0: isn't the idea that Hari is looking for aliens?
Speaker 0: she believes all this crazy shit.
Speaker 0: yeah and so.
Speaker 0: and then she's with all these people think she's crazy but they're all in the same club but actually all of them are the aliens all the time except maybe the guy.
Speaker 0: okay and then I don't know.
Speaker 1: okay there is a significant something about time travel.
Speaker 0: that's why the episodes are all mixed up.
Speaker 1: you have not even conceived of what the show is actually about.
Speaker 1: yet.
Speaker 1: okay show is gonna do a thing.
Speaker 0: you're gonna be like oh all right all right at a point anyway but yeah that's you know.
Speaker 0: sometimes that just happens.
Speaker 1: so there's some shows that are big popular well-known or at least in their time we're super well-known that despite being the biggest goddamn anime fans not only did we never watch them or at least I never watched them.
Speaker 1: but in that era in the 2000s if I was an anime con and I was like I've never seen the - Co people be like what the fuck rim what the fuck actually I did watch a few episodes in - Co and not finish.
Speaker 1: I didn't watch any.
Speaker 1: I I never cared about a - Co.
Speaker 1: everyone who ever tried to tell me to watch it told me it was about something different never told me it was about something good and the fact that it is basically completely forgotten except by people
Speaker 0: who were big
Speaker 1: into anime and watched it in the two in the 2000s.
Speaker 1: I think I made the right choice and never watching it.
Speaker 0: yeah I didn't finish it and I'm good.
Speaker 1: yeah but sir I don't think you guys can understand.
Speaker 1: that was people would say in the - Co.
Speaker 0: it was a pretty big show at the list of the five or ten shows that they assume everyone in the club has seen all of and when the anime club had like giveaways there would be like a - Co wall scroll and people knew what it was.
Speaker 1: it was like right next to the Ava wall scroll.
Speaker 1: that's right that level.
Speaker 1: yep and completely forgotten.
Speaker 1: Ava people still argue about it.
Speaker 0: well I don't even remember the last time I heard someone mentioned a - Co before.
Speaker 1: right now yeah it came up recently because someone one of our friends was like you've still not seen the - Co.
Speaker 1: which is why I was thinking about this and I was like I don't actually ever plan to.
Speaker 1: yeah no one has ever told me it was good.
Speaker 0: don't we have the full set right here?
Speaker 1: yes I bought the box set.
Speaker 1: it was like five dollars.
Speaker 1: I've never even opened it.
Speaker 1: yeah there was another show that was stupidly popular among a good chunk of the anime club.
Speaker 0: I remember Weiss Cruz White Cross mmm that's what I was a cute boys show.
Speaker 1: I think I don't know what it's about.
Speaker 0: I never learned it.
Speaker 0: st.
Speaker 0: say huh or am I just way off?
Speaker 1: I think it's about flowers people who run a flower shop but are also terrorists.
Speaker 0: isn't that gravitation which I also didn't see?
Speaker 1: I watched some of it.
Speaker 1: I have beef with gravitation but not in this sense.
Speaker 0: I think I connect them because they're both cute boys shows.
Speaker 1: right White Cross?
Speaker 1: the reason I did not watch it was that a ton of people I remember we're going crazy about this show and then I learned that most of them had not ever actually seen a single episode of it.
Speaker 1: really so when I learned that I decided that show is probably stupid and in retrospect I was 100%.
Speaker 0: another show no one talks about anymore.
Speaker 1: that show is forgotten mm-hmm I remember.
Speaker 1: so the tenchi or what gal gaga?
Speaker 1: I've never watched.
Speaker 1: I have no plans to.
Speaker 0: I don't watch that.
Speaker 0: simply I think I actually might like gal gaga but everyone says well it doesn't get good until this late episode and it's way too many episodes to sit through that are bad unlike say hoke don't know can which is good every episode.
Speaker 1: thus gal gaga for me is in that same category.
Speaker 1: that not worth the effort of the galactic heroes is.
Speaker 1: is that it is worth the effort when I don't have anything else to do?
Speaker 0: when I'm an old man and we're tired I'll watch gaga shows like that.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna watch when I'm 90 in a retirement home and all my friends are dead.
Speaker 0: yep well I'll be the one alive when I'll be the one alive.
Speaker 0: okay on this I will watch gaga gaga and be like this.
Speaker 0: one's for you rim but and I'll pour out some digital bits.
Speaker 1: so there was a whole special class of shows that I stopped watching.
Speaker 1: that were basically the shitty TV knockoff of what was a good Oh AV reader die TV.
Speaker 1: so actually that's the one I watched all the way through that for last.
Speaker 1: so El Hazzard is a great show.
Speaker 1: the Wanderers is just a slow-paced poorly done shitty watered-down TV show.
Speaker 0: redo yep I knew better and didn't even try to watch the Wanderers.
Speaker 1: I was like five episodes.
Speaker 1: I was like what?
Speaker 1: the same with lotus war lotus war oh yeah same thing tenchi muyo.
Speaker 1: same thing the original av love or hate that kind of harem show.
Speaker 1: it was an important show in its time.
Speaker 1: I enjoyed that show a lot.
Speaker 1: the TV series is is is is that came afterward where each and every one of them increasingly mediocre?
Speaker 1: you can tell how mediocre attention episode of anything is by how much later it came out after the first OAV ended.
Speaker 0: that reminds me of similar things.
Speaker 0: for example I watched all of the first season of full metal panic but did not watch any other full metal panics because I sort of regretted finishing watching the first one.
Speaker 1: I didn't finish the first one because I knew better.
Speaker 1: I watched that show and I was like all right.
Speaker 1: it's got an average to like be level robot plot and a mildly funny school plot and they mash them up and the.
Speaker 1: the good part of the show is that they mashed them up and that's like.
Speaker 1: that's the cool part.
Speaker 1: then they'd film a food where they just took it's like they took the worst most pedestrian jokes and made the entire show that right.
Speaker 0: so similarly I watched all of the Full Metal Alchemist TV series as did I as it came out own all the manga.
Speaker 0: even though I haven't read all of it yet I do plan to have not seen a single second of Brotherhood or any movie I remember.
Speaker 1: I was excited that the movie was coming and then it came out.
Speaker 0: I didn't watch a second of it not in one and by that point it's funny.
Speaker 1: I we were super invested in Full Metal Alchemist.
Speaker 0: that like we would all get together to watch a new episode the day it came out.
Speaker 1: that was the big show.
Speaker 1: I was huge like we went to.
Speaker 1: I remember we were at Otacon and Lark OCL did their crazy concert partly because Full Metal Alchemist and they had.
Speaker 1: they did one of the openers.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: so we were there and they showed like the first episode of the show and while we were waiting for the concert to start and even a bunch of her friends were like whoa that's what this show is about.
Speaker 1: oh my god.
Speaker 1: and it was the biggest and I thought that show was the best.
Speaker 1: it was pretty good.
Speaker 1: within a week of it ending I forgot about it didn't care anymore never remembered it have no plans never watch it again.
Speaker 1: it was one of those shows that was good in its era and everyone watched it and the no one will remember it.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm uh but yeah in the knockoff genre I did actually watch all of read or die TV.
Speaker 1: let me tell you there is no payoff.
Speaker 1: that could have been possible.
Speaker 1: that would have made that worthwhile.
Speaker 1: there was in fact no payoff.
Speaker 0: I watched all of love Hina.
Speaker 0: why did I do this?
Speaker 0: because the summer after freshman year at RIT I spent that summer doing being camp counselor.
Speaker 0: but then that didn't take the whole summer.
Speaker 0: that only takes eight weeks maybe nine weeks because of the training week.
Speaker 0: right then I had the rest of the summer to do nothing.
Speaker 0: internet was a vt16 modem and mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: wait a minute wait a minute wait a minute.
Speaker 0: so the only anime that I had available to me the only thing I had to do was I had all of love Hina which I downloaded at RIT on this hard drive.
Speaker 1: let me tell you a little story.
Speaker 1: so I'm living in the mountains with no internet working at IBM no friends within hundreds of miles of me.
Speaker 1: yeah just kind of you know being bored and I'm a hard drive.
Speaker 1: I happen to have all of gunslinger girls and all of read or die TV.
Speaker 1: so guess what I watched all of.
Speaker 0: ah yeah someone who's trapped with nothing no way to get more things is gonna watch something crappy.
Speaker 1: fuck both of those shows.
Speaker 0: fuck all three of those shows.
Speaker 0: love Hina.
Speaker 0: also love Hina has cute turtles and that's it.
Speaker 1: but I remember like when when they announced tenchi in Tokyo I was actually excited because I wanted to see the kind of mainline plot of tenchi go forward.
Speaker 1: it looked like it was gonna be cool.
Speaker 1: I watched the first episode and I never watched any more tenchi after that.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen any tenji since then.
Speaker 0: one episode of tenji gxp.
Speaker 1: uh try to forget that fact.
Speaker 1: that was that is still the worst disparity in all of history between the goodness of the opening theme song to an anime and the reality of what that anime is.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I don't know who gxp was for.
Speaker 1: nobody like not even tenji fans because the characters aren't even in it.
Speaker 0: let's wrap this up by talking about anime.
Speaker 0: we know exists but we know not to watch.
Speaker 0: so we haven't watched for example every incest show.
Speaker 0: well yes but I'm talking about less obvious ones.
Speaker 0: for example you mentioned tenchi.
Speaker 0: you always used to go to media play and what was on the shelf?
Speaker 0: Oh Oh photon that's right and you know what time.
Speaker 0: never bought it never watched it.
Speaker 0: just ignore it was there.
Speaker 0: I kept seeing it over and over again.
Speaker 1: I've seen the same poorly dubbed with weird music trailer for it in front of other anime on DVDs like a hundred times every time like oh right that show that I'll never watch exists.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm as far as I can tell it's about.
Speaker 1: I don't know it is a tenchi knockoff and the guys an idiot.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it is but I know it exists.
Speaker 0: and there's an anime called photon.
Speaker 1: anyone give us a good reason to watch one second of that show right?
Speaker 0: any other ones in that category?
Speaker 0: ah in that category something you know is bad.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of shows that other people probably haven't watched for similar reasons but it's I think usually those reasons boil down to.
Speaker 1: they're just too young and don't remember or know.
Speaker 1: these shows exist because there's no longer a culture in an anime fan society of discovering old shows.
Speaker 1: there's no more.
Speaker 1: the old guy says hey watch golden boy.
Speaker 1: so no one will ever watch golden boy.
Speaker 0: actually haven't seen golden boy though it's good it's pretty funny.
Speaker 1: yeah I like it.
Speaker 0: I know enough to know is good.
Speaker 1: or like bakuretsu hunters like no one's gonna tell anyone to watch that I do not watch that it's actually pretty funny.
Speaker 1: yeah it's free it's okay it's not.
Speaker 1: you know what it's on the level of all those shows like that from that era.
Speaker 1: they're throwaway shows that are moderately funny that were surprisingly popular in their element at the time.
Speaker 0: what was that weird?
Speaker 0: I'm never gonna remember it and I'm not gonna be able to describe it because I didn't wear it.
Speaker 0: it came in a weird box.
Speaker 0: Nicole liked it.
Speaker 0: the box is like black.
Speaker 0: that has something to do with lesbians.
Speaker 1: oh oh that was the show about the lesbian space pirates.
Speaker 1: that was just really dumb.
Speaker 0: what's it called?
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna Google for lesbian space pirates.
Speaker 0: you're gonna find the lesbian space pirates which is a comic book.
Speaker 0: that's actually really good.
Speaker 1: I actually do really like that comic space pirate anime not bodacious space pirates.
Speaker 0: that's the good one.
Speaker 0: yeah and I don't know I don't know if that's actually the good.
Speaker 1: people are gonna be mad at us because I hurt people.
Speaker 1: a lot of people say this show is pretty good.
Speaker 1: I remember debating with people about it but I just remember people told me it was cowboy bebop with an all-female cast and that is not what that show was mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: and actually you know what.
Speaker 1: there's a show that's really popular that like David Riley and Joel I really like it.
Speaker 1: but uh Black Lagoon I watched a bunch of episodes of and I just didn't like it.
Speaker 0: I watched like three episodes and I was like what the fuck this bullshit.
Speaker 1: it just seemed really kind of why I don't understand why everyone likes that show like it is the word I would use to describe that show.
Speaker 0: yeah I just don't get it.
Speaker 1: but at least we know about these shows though it's kind of bad that I can't remember the name of the show we were just talking about.
Speaker 0: yeah I can think I can think.
Speaker 0: you know I just realized it's just coming into my head now.
Speaker 0: all these shows like get backers and you know there's just so many shows.
Speaker 0: D gray man.
Speaker 1: but yeah well there was heat guy J guy J.
Speaker 0: it's just so.
Speaker 1: the problem is the anime weren't really notable because there's shows that we watched like one episode of her like.
Speaker 1: yeah this isn't any good and just didn't bother.
Speaker 1: there's a difference between that and the show that you know exists could watch and choose to never watch or the show that you watch a lot of and then stop watching.
Speaker 1: mmm.
Speaker 1: so yourself think about shows like that like try to list the shows you gave up on after having invested substantial time in them.
Speaker 1: yeah you might see a pattern.
Speaker 0: I never watched any of those crest or star banners.
Speaker 1: our crest of the stars was okay but I never watched banner of the star because crest was actually kind of too boring for me.
Speaker 1: hmm and that's coming from a man who thinks gassaraki is a great anime that everyone should see someone who did not fall asleep during sky crawlers.
Speaker 0: all right have we gone on long enough?
Speaker 0: I think we're good.
Speaker 1: all right via this lot and so I wonder how many people stopped listening to this show before it finished.
Speaker 0: hopefully they're smart.
Speaker 0: most of them.
Speaker 1: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: so buddy you get funny you get funny.