Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, February 27th, 2013.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, on this episode of Geek Nights, we will be talking about a thing, and that thing is a comic.
Speaker 0: A comic about ponies.
Speaker 0: We're reviewing the My Little Pony comic.
Speaker 1: I should just edit this episode.
Speaker 0: Do you even know how?
Speaker 1: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 1: Just take the WAV file and chop out the WAV file.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: You got a problem?
Speaker 0: You're not happy with the way I'm running this operation?
Speaker 1: We've already discussed this a thousand times.
Speaker 0: We haven't done a... I think we might have done a thousand episodes by now.
Speaker 0: I can't tell.
Speaker 1: Many times it has been discussed.
Speaker 0: But now we are talking about the My Little Pony comic, and I've just come out to review it, actually talk about what's good and bad about it.
Speaker 0: Mostly good.
Speaker 0: In fact, I like it a lot.
Speaker 0: I like it more than some episodes of season three, but we'll get to that.
Speaker 1: Any opening bits at all?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I got nothing really important going on.
Speaker 0: Some friends are coming back from out of town.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: Let's just do the show.
Speaker 0: Quick show.
Speaker 1: Okay, so check this out.
Speaker 0: I'm checking.
Speaker 1: It's one of those things is not quite news, because it's not like a thing that happened now, but it's not really a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like, oh, there was an interesting editorial sort of research article on the Onion AV Club, right?
Speaker 1: And it talks about DuckTales invented a new animated wonderland that quickly disappeared.
Speaker 1: And it talks...
Speaker 0: Is it just DuckTales or is it just that Disney Afternoon in general?
Speaker 1: He talks about the whole era really, but focusing on DuckTales.
Speaker 0: I consider that a golden age of animation.
Speaker 1: He explains it, you know, whoever wrote this article and might not even be a he.
Speaker 1: It's OK.
Speaker 1: Todd vendor where he wrote this article on February 11th.
Speaker 1: We published on February 11th.
Speaker 1: and he explains why there was this sudden surge in syndicated animation for after the after school programming block of incredible high quality beginning with gummy bears.
Speaker 1: And he talks about why it emerged, how good it was, and then why it disappeared.
Speaker 1: And it's like, oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: So can you spoil for me?
Speaker 0: why did it disappear?
Speaker 0: Summarize the primary reason that the Disney Afternoon really, really missed DuckTales and Tailspin.
Speaker 1: The primary reason the Disney Afternoon disappeared was it coincided with an executive shakeup at Disney.
Speaker 1: And those new executives wanted to push things that were using the same properties as the movie, such as Aladdin after school cartoon and such.
Speaker 0: That cartoon was awful, by the way.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And that's it.
Speaker 0: So how come?
Speaker 0: Well, no, not how come?
Speaker 0: we know why, because even in the non animation world, if you back up into the meta, you know, Scott, because while you don't care about these things, you listen to people bitch about it all the time.
Speaker 0: There is a show that nerds like and it's on like sci fi or Fox and the nerds like super into it and it's super popular and maybe it's even doing really well.
Speaker 0: And then suddenly it's canceled for no reason, even though it was actually profitable.
Speaker 0: And usually that's because there's an executive shakeup and the new executives, more importantly than maybe anything else, usually want the stuff the old executives championed to fail so they can then point out how they're better.
Speaker 0: Some fashion like that.
Speaker 1: There's a long and whatever those guys were doing, they, you know, they fucked up even if they weren't fucking up.
Speaker 1: And right, basically because think about when executives change, why do executives change?
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: don't think about what the executives are thinking, right?
Speaker 1: Think about why did the executives just change?
Speaker 1: It's because the board voted out the old guy and in with the new guy, if the board voted out the old guy name with the new guy, there's two reasons why a bunch of executives board is expecting to see something new.
Speaker 1: And if the board right sees things get worse or not change or they see that the things the old executives did were working better than things new executives did, that means the board voted wrong.
Speaker 1: You can't have that.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: The guy from the old guys is bad and fails.
Speaker 1: And then you got to make sure the new thing is also bad and fails because that's just how it goes.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But you know, appears to be an improvement or at least is different.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, what are the executives vote a new guy in for to do the same thing?
Speaker 0: There are other reasons why executives change like that, especially when a guy retired.
Speaker 0: I mean, I could cause it, but usually it's because if it isn't the board doing it, it's because a bunch of executives were either jumping ship to start their own thing or to go somewhere else.
Speaker 1: That's the sort of same as retiring.
Speaker 0: I would not say it's the same because here's the time the board voted.
Speaker 0: It's a big difference in the corporate world.
Speaker 0: If a guy or a group of people retire, it's because they were old.
Speaker 0: or they're done or they're something.
Speaker 0: If they all moved somewhere else or start their own thing, you've got a team that knows your business that is now directly competing with you and left because of some fuck up or some disagreement they had with you.
Speaker 0: So that's when a bunch of your executives leave and aren't retiring.
Speaker 0: That is a huge problem for you.
Speaker 1: Most of the problem of too many chiefs, not enough Indians has been around for centuries.
Speaker 1: So I don't think it's going to be solved anytime soon.
Speaker 0: It's not just good.
Speaker 0: There's more chiefs that tell that chief to stop chiefing.
Speaker 0: How many bronies are sitting here like clenching their fists in impotent anger like Lauren Faust.
Speaker 1: If you're a listener of Geek Nights, this article is guaranteed to be of interest to you.
Speaker 0: We should start a White House petition to get President Barack Obama to issue an executive order demanding that tailspin and be produced and returned on taxpayer dollars to broadcast television.
Speaker 1: The government is perfectly legally able to put out bids for a contract to produce a television show.
Speaker 0: There might be legal challenges about the public sector competing in private, whatever.
Speaker 0: But I digress.
Speaker 0: I don't think we get the 100,000 signatures we need or will we if we did.
Speaker 0: I'd love to see the response anyway.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I've actually been watching a bunch of anime lately.
Speaker 1: I've been watching a bunch of anime, but it's only one anime.
Speaker 1: It begins with the word ghost and ends with the word shell.
Speaker 0: Doesn't it end with the word gig?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: What do you watch?
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: Get sack first gig, right?
Speaker 1: I watched the movie.
Speaker 0: Which one?
Speaker 0: The first movie, right?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Did you watch Innocence again?
Speaker 1: I will.
Speaker 0: When was the last time you saw Innocence?
Speaker 1: I only saw it once in the theater.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I will say this.
Speaker 0: I watched Innocence again.
Speaker 1: It's fucked the fuck up.
Speaker 0: Not that long ago, but a while ago.
Speaker 0: And all I remember from Innocence that matters is that, holy shit, do I like watching Batou and Togusa talk about stuff?
Speaker 1: That's all it is.
Speaker 1: It's 99% of the movie.
Speaker 0: I would watch a show that was just Batou and Togusa and occasionally Aramaki just quoting old Japanese and Greek scholars at each other for like four hours an episode.
Speaker 1: That's all it is.
Speaker 0: I dig that stuff.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you're watching this because of Google glass, because of a rise, all these things together.
Speaker 1: Why are you watching it again?
Speaker 1: Net runner, net runner, cyberpunk season.
Speaker 0: It is cyberpunk season.
Speaker 0: The only reason I'm not watching get sack first gig again, again, is that I recently watched it again, again, again.
Speaker 0: And when it comes to anime for a long time, every time I look at the list of new shows, all I think is, are any of these shows better than ghost in the shell standalone complex second gig?
Speaker 0: Cause that was the last anime I watched that I was super excited about.
Speaker 0: What Monica I watched after that.
Speaker 1: So you didn't think Monica was exciting till after you saw it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But at the same time I watch episode ones and I read, you know, reviews.
Speaker 0: If they're out there and people I care about, about these new shows, no one's really talking about them.
Speaker 0: But Monica, after four episodes, people were flipping out on the internet.
Speaker 0: So I knew there was something going on.
Speaker 1: I got new.
Speaker 1: Let's change the, you know, usually the philosophy is, Hey, I'm only going to live to be whatever years old.
Speaker 1: I can't possibly read, watch, listen to everything that we've ever created, right?
Speaker 1: It's not going to happen.
Speaker 1: So I got to filter out and only get the best ofs.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And hopefully I can get to most of the best ofs before I die.
Speaker 1: You know, that are accessible to me.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: I got new philosophy.
Speaker 1: I've already seen all the best ones, especially in the anime department.
Speaker 1: Let's just fucking watch those fuckers over and over again.
Speaker 1: Cause nothing new is going to be any good.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is an old man, you're young punk kids.
Speaker 1: Shit sucks.
Speaker 1: I'm going to keep watching my old man shit over and over.
Speaker 0: We did do a show a long time ago on the rewatch because it seems like anime is a thing in particular, that specific fandom where fans will perennially, and I know all of you out there listening have done this, but like, you know what?
Speaker 0: I haven't seen X show in a few years.
Speaker 0: I think it's time to watch it again.
Speaker 0: Well, look at how many people think that for like Seinfeld, like, man, I should watch season four of Seinfeld again.
Speaker 1: Well, we're right.
Speaker 1: You know, the rewatching Utena here, right?
Speaker 1: Is like, it's like a new show basically.
Speaker 0: I watched it more recently again than you and I've seen Utena through five times.
Speaker 1: I think I haven't seen it since college.
Speaker 0: So this will be the sixth time through my like 1.5 time scene.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But the problem is, and I always go back to my go-to example is Kaze no Yojimbo.
Speaker 0: Cause I was watching that on Netflix DVDs when I commute Metro North.
Speaker 0: And in fact, I was watching it on a portable, dedicated DVD playing device, not a laptop because that device had way more battery than my laptop.
Speaker 1: I watched like a handful of episodes of that and then stopped.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I was watching, it was pretty good, but then an episode ended and I was sitting there and I was like, eh, I guess I should watch the next one to, you know, so I can finish the show and send the DVD bag.
Speaker 0: And then I got home and I was dicking around and I just kind of randomly watched one episode of cowboy bebop and 126 episodes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: And then I was like, you know what?
Speaker 0: Fuck how they know Yojimbo.
Speaker 0: I'm done watching B minus anime.
Speaker 0: I'll watch B anime because a B anime is better than most stuff.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I've been watching a bunch of anime lately and space brothers is super good and super fun.
Speaker 0: And I recommend you watch it.
Speaker 0: It'll make you really excited about space.
Speaker 0: But the thing I'm watching good yet, but it's given me a lot of feels I haven't had from an anime I've watched in a long time.
Speaker 0: It's Shin Sekayori or from the new world.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: No one's really been talking about it, but here's the basic deal.
Speaker 0: Watch this.
Speaker 1: People are going to come out in the form and be like, everyone's been talking about the show.
Speaker 0: Where are you been?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I poked around now.
Speaker 0: Many people are talking about it.
Speaker 0: So it's set up in sort of a nearing future, like around this time, some, or maybe the Madoka time, you know, like that, that level of near future.
Speaker 0: And suddenly one day, a whole bunch of people like individual people, like in one city, like maybe 20 to 30 people just suddenly get Akira style psychic powers and start accidentally killing everyone around them.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: And then it just, it shows you that.
Speaker 0: And it's just a bloodbath.
Speaker 0: It just like thing doesn't work out so well.
Speaker 0: It's not to look at so good.
Speaker 0: And then suddenly just stops.
Speaker 0: And then the show starts and the show looks like it's set in ancient Japan, but really it's the far future, like four to 800 years after that day.
Speaker 0: And it's basically a post-apocalyptic show, but it's post-apocalyptic as in a psychic apocalypse ruined the world.
Speaker 0: Society in Japan rebuilt based on weird old Japanese legends and myths and sort of the Shinto rituals and things to avoid another psychic apocalypse.
Speaker 0: Yes, but all based around the psychic stuff.
Speaker 0: It's creepy.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 0: It's atmospheric.
Speaker 0: Uh, if I had to say shows that reminds me of, I'm going to have to say a lot of really different shows.
Speaker 0: It reminds me of Bocorano in that it's got a bunch of kids surrounded by tragedy and high production values and good music.
Speaker 0: It's, it reminds me of Mushishi because the psychic stuff and the world around these kids has that sort of mythical self consistency and just the, the stories and the monsters and the things in the outside really just feel like Mushishi.
Speaker 0: If all the Mushi were actually really just assholes.
Speaker 1: A lot of them are.
Speaker 0: It reminds me of number six, which is the show of Scott and I are watching with Emily.
Speaker 0: That was all about a sort of like there's domes in the future with society living inside of those like 20 shows like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That show started out a lot like this where there's also, you know, precursor technology, the inside outside, like ergo proxy had, but that show got stupid, way stupid, not worth watching stupid.
Speaker 0: So this show reminds me of all of those shows and so far I really like it because it's given me a vibe that I haven't gotten from many shows ever, let alone recently, the vibe of, I want to me rim watching the show, figure out what the fuck is going on.
Speaker 0: Shows that have given me that included Escaflowne, Utena.
Speaker 1: Every good show has a terrible secret of space.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cowboy bebop had the, the terrible secret of space is not the one you care about secret.
Speaker 1: Still had a terrible secret of space.
Speaker 0: It wasn't a terrible secret of space.
Speaker 0: It was terrible secret of a few people.
Speaker 1: You know, it sure has a terrible secret to space.
Speaker 0: I was going to make a joke and say space brothers, the end.
Speaker 0: So I'm feeling the show and I just want to point out that I was, it's directed by the kind of person that tends to make the kind of show that I end up really liking.
Speaker 0: Masashi Ishiyama is one of those guys who was a key animator and animation director for a huge list of just shows all over the place.
Speaker 0: And those are the kinds of people who in my experience tended to make the shows that I actually like.
Speaker 0: And I point out, he also did the character design and the animation direction for welcome to the space show.
Speaker 0: And it kind of shows when you watch this, especially when you meet the library.
Speaker 0: So yeah, that's a geek bite.
Speaker 0: If you're looking for an anime to watch, this is the best one.
Speaker 0: that isn't space brothers that I've seen from recent seasons of anime.
Speaker 1: Don't you have an actual news in addition to your geek?
Speaker 0: This is my geek bite.
Speaker 1: I thought you had a news as well.
Speaker 0: Oh, we could talk about Otakon.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I saw a tweet a few days ago, however long ago it was.
Speaker 0: The tweet was basically they announced Otakon Vegas and I thought that was a joke.
Speaker 1: I didn't know if it was a joke or real.
Speaker 1: I was 50/50.
Speaker 1: I had to investigate to figure it out.
Speaker 1: So it's real.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is real.
Speaker 0: Not really sure what to say about that.
Speaker 0: Uh, I wish them well.
Speaker 0: I do think that I think it's a mistake.
Speaker 1: Las Vegas does have a gigantic convention center where CES is.
Speaker 1: And I do think that Vegas was the one place that was desperately lacking a geek convention that could support one.
Speaker 0: But I don't know if Vegas is the right place for an anime convention, right?
Speaker 1: Because the other things in Vegas, you don't necessarily want mixing with geeks, right?
Speaker 1: When those geeks walk out of a casino full of tourists and casino dwellers, uh, and it's not going to necessarily mix.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I don't think that's the problem.
Speaker 1: It's not like when you go out in the street and people are friendly and like, Hey, why is everyone wearing costumes?
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: It's a bunch of drunken gambling.
Speaker 0: You know, I don't actually think that's the problem at all.
Speaker 1: I have much one of the problems.
Speaker 1: I don't even wish there are many.
Speaker 0: No, I don't even register that as a problem because I I'm just going to keep saying that word for almost every place in America.
Speaker 0: You can have a convention Baltimore.
Speaker 0: It's a.
Speaker 1: You just don't leave that tiny area.
Speaker 0: There's either the Heinz that's too small and has problems with the mall next to it getting mad about stuff or the BCEC, which is a spaceship all by itself in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: that, that, that, that problem exists everywhere.
Speaker 0: No, my problems, not problems.
Speaker 0: My concerns are more along the lines of Otacon seems to try to actually continue to be an anime convention focused on anime.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is true.
Speaker 0: They have East Asian stuff.
Speaker 0: that's in their charter, but most of its anime, the vast majority of it is East Asian stuff.
Speaker 0: And the stuff they have that is not directly in that sort of, uh, wheelhouse is such a small percentage of the total content that they can get away with, uh, not messing up their five Oh one C three, which if you run conventions, you probably know exactly what that means.
Speaker 0: But my problem is that there aren't that many conventions that can do anime, anime like that and grow large and continue to draw people?
Speaker 0: because other than anime, Boston, Otacon, and maybe five or six others, most other quote, anime, convenient cons have a ton of non anime content.
Speaker 0: because that's what most people are at most conventions for.
Speaker 0: So if they're charters the same, are they going to make a new convention in Vegas?
Speaker 0: The only reason to put it in Vegas really is if you think it will get big enough to use the big convention centers there.
Speaker 1: Oh, you think that that's a good question, right?
Speaker 1: Because the Otacon brand is mostly strong.
Speaker 1: It doesn't, it's not really a national brand.
Speaker 1: It's mostly a Northeast brand.
Speaker 1: Dude.
Speaker 0: I know Baltimore who are anime fans who had never heard of it.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Who has heard of it?
Speaker 1: And is it going to be mostly people flying from here to Vegas to go?
Speaker 0: You know, they've said they want to keep it small to start.
Speaker 0: In fact, they want to make a smaller and more intimate setting.
Speaker 1: But then what if it gets too big?
Speaker 1: and if it's small, what's the point of being in Vegas?
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: That's why I'm curious.
Speaker 0: What, what, what was the course of events internal to the Otacon staff that led to someone saying, let's have a new satellite convention branded Otacon and run it in Vegas.
Speaker 1: Really want to go to Vegas or thinking long-term, right?
Speaker 1: It can grow and you could, someone could actually make use of that.
Speaker 0: Otacon uses the BCC in Baltimore to capacity.
Speaker 1: They grew into it so that they think they can repeat the winning formula.
Speaker 0: I don't know if a purely anime con could though.
Speaker 0: Otacon is big partly because of momentum and because of history and because of guests, big guests.
Speaker 0: And I have logistical concerns too, partly because I know Otacon staff culture and I don't foresee them paying to fly a large number of their seasoned staff out there to organize this small.
Speaker 1: They won't need that many and they could use the con money.
Speaker 0: Well, see saying you don't need that many is a recipe for disaster.
Speaker 1: You need less than Otacon needs.
Speaker 0: But you need to send like your core staff to manage the thing, to do it the same way.
Speaker 0: you run it in the other coast.
Speaker 0: So I don't know.
Speaker 0: We'll see how this whole thing goes.
Speaker 0: Now this is purely speculative.
Speaker 0: If I had to guess as to why Otacon is doing this and I do not have access to the staff forum anymore.
Speaker 0: This is based on no inside information I have whatsoever.
Speaker 0: I'm literally guessing a hundred percent speculation.
Speaker 0: They are a 501c3.
Speaker 0: They have a chart or most cons.
Speaker 0: Ah, yes.
Speaker 0: Now I'm of the opinion that it is in the modern era, a mistake to be a nonprofit.
Speaker 0: You're better off being a for profit cause.
Speaker 0: then you can do whatever the fuck you want.
Speaker 0: Even if you end up effectively being a nonprofit, but that, you know, Connecticut impacts all the other cons that were involved with for the most part are for profit.
Speaker 0: At least we're involved on the staff level.
Speaker 0: So, uh, because they're a 501c3 and they have a charter, uh, 501c3s can get in trouble if they make too much money and don't reinvest it specifically into furthering their charter.
Speaker 1: You think Otacon made too much money?
Speaker 0: In the long run?
Speaker 1: Pretty sure they spend all their money.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: But it is possible that they, their, their bank account, they're sort of like fund of emergency money and profits over time, especially in light of my guests.
Speaker 0: that over time there'll be fewer Japanese guests just because there's less demand for them.
Speaker 0: and you know, stuff like that.
Speaker 0: And I know they do really well to get Japanese guests better than most cons.
Speaker 0: I would not be surprised if they were, uh, advised to start another event somewhere and funnel some money into it.
Speaker 0: And I would not be surprised if independent of that, some people were wined and it was suggested that Vegas would be a great place for it and they might not have thought it all the way through.
Speaker 1: There's plenty of other ways you can dump a whole bunch of money into the mission of Otacon besides a con in Vegas.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: I'm just, this is me literally just speculating based on nothing and based on the 501c3 discussions I have had internal to other conventions in the past that have led to similar decisions.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So some crazy random guessing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is crazy.
Speaker 0: I was very open about this being crazy random guessing.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: But, uh, what's interesting is they're having it at the planet Hollywood resort and they're making it fan.
Speaker 1: I thought that doesn't exist anymore.
Speaker 1: I thought the planet Hollywood went bankrupt.
Speaker 0: Uh, I don't know where you get that information from.
Speaker 1: I'm going to look it up.
Speaker 0: I've never heard that in my life.
Speaker 0: In fact, they have announced specifically Otacon Vegas will be held at the planet Hollywood resort and casino in Las Vegas.
Speaker 0: So you're probably wrong.
Speaker 1: The company has gone bankrupt twice.
Speaker 1: Nearly a hundred stores have closed worldwide leaving about nine open.
Speaker 1: Ah, really?
Speaker 1: So one of the nine, one of the nine is that one.
Speaker 0: Anyway, things of the day they got for me.
Speaker 1: Uh, it's not for you.
Speaker 1: Uh, so yesterday I saw something that was the greatest something I have seen in a long time.
Speaker 1: It was something on the internet that actually provided lols.
Speaker 1: Something as good as Lord of the rings on the go.
Speaker 1: Something of that level of goodness.
Speaker 1: And what this thing is, it was a threat on board game geek.
Speaker 1: board game boxes with googly eyes.
Speaker 1: This is a pretty good, I really want to know like the biology of neuroscience of why googly eyes are so funny.
Speaker 0: I think it's pretty simple.
Speaker 0: Googly eyes may take anything and make it less threatening.
Speaker 1: Why does it make it funny?
Speaker 0: Because if it's less threatening, you're looking at some crazy ogre.
Speaker 0: That might be threatening.
Speaker 0: Suddenly you make it less threatening with googly eyes.
Speaker 1: Why is that funny?
Speaker 0: Because of the juxtaposition between something that should be dangerous.
Speaker 0: Now suddenly being made non-dangerous.
Speaker 1: Not everything on these boxes is dangerous.
Speaker 0: Are almost every one of those things is dangerous.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so board game boxes with googly eyes put on them.
Speaker 1: This is amazing.
Speaker 1: Even if you don't know the board game boxes, it's still hilarious, especially connect four, which you do know, uh, dude is the best one.
Speaker 1: Everyone thinks the same thing when they see that one.
Speaker 1: It's amazing.
Speaker 1: You got to check this out.
Speaker 1: And I suggest maybe checking it out while you're on your iPhone in the bathroom.
Speaker 1: So that way, if you pee from funniness, you'll be safe.
Speaker 0: There's one in particular.
Speaker 0: You'll know it when you see it.
Speaker 0: We did some very intense focus testing, uh, last night during our burning wheel game.
Speaker 0: And we discovered that that is in fact the best one.
Speaker 1: The one I just mentioned.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: So I got a pretty cool thing.
Speaker 0: This was, I'm using tumblr more and more and a friend of ours, uh, reblogged this.
Speaker 0: So this is a bunch of in the little golden book style, almost of Avengers characters as sailor moon characters that are surprisingly faithful to the ideas of both of them simultaneously.
Speaker 0: And the art is just ridiculously good.
Speaker 0: If you're a fan of either one of those things, you should look at this art.
Speaker 0: I would watch a show.
Speaker 0: In fact, I would pay a lot of money to see a show that was animated that looked even close to this sailors assemble.
Speaker 0: I don't even like this dude and whatever it is they're going to do.
Speaker 1: I think the new powerpuff girls is going to look kind of like that.
Speaker 0: I know I'm kind of excited about it, but I just wanted to bring back.
Speaker 0: You mean Accio bonus points.
Speaker 0: If you look at this and you recognize the sailor starlights and know why that's hilarious.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: You got a meta in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of Metamoments.
Speaker 1: Metamoment number one, the book club selection is the player of games by Ian M. Banks.
Speaker 1: It is the most geek nights book a book can be.
Speaker 1: That is why it is now in the book club.
Speaker 1: You should read it.
Speaker 1: If you listen to this podcast, end of story.
Speaker 1: Also in the metamoment, the next convention on the calendar is penny arcade expo EAST 2013.
Speaker 1: We are presenting mastering game mechanics.
Speaker 0: We are presenting Bob practical game theory.
Speaker 0: We may be presenting third unannounced events.
Speaker 1: Come to that.
Speaker 1: Uh, actually if you don't already have tickets and things, you're in big trouble because you're not going to be able to come to that.
Speaker 0: But yup.
Speaker 0: And if you want to see our events, uh, it's in a smaller room than usual.
Speaker 0: I can't guarantee we'll video them because there's no stage.
Speaker 0: So get there early or you may not ever see them.
Speaker 0: We may not ever run them again.
Speaker 1: Other metamoments.
Speaker 1: We have this email newsletter that's actually been doing pretty well for a while now.
Speaker 1: Uh, but apparently some people had Gmail automatically spam it or, uh, a market is spam.
Speaker 1: I sent one out today.
Speaker 1: So check if you are subscribed, check your spam folder and see the newsletters in there and market is not spam.
Speaker 1: Um, anything else we got going on at all?
Speaker 1: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: There is grand prize.
Speaker 0: Scott's baby.
Speaker 1: If you want to see if your gaming skills are greater than or less than other listeners of this show, you need to enter into the gaming FRC first annual girl pre 2013.
Speaker 0: However this goes, it is a hundred percent Scott.
Speaker 0: I got nothing to do with it other than I am competing.
Speaker 1: It's going to be very smooth.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: See why you seem to be skeptical of skeptical.
Speaker 0: I was just stating a fact.
Speaker 1: I'm totally down with it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you have until, uh, tomorrow to register straight.
Speaker 1: I thought about like letting people register late and then you could just enter in late and score zeros for the rounds you missed.
Speaker 1: Uh, I might allow that still, but really if you want to have a chance of winning, you have to register and play right away.
Speaker 1: Uh, you have to join the forum and then you have to, um, you know, just posting that thread that you want to join and your forum name will be your name on the Google doc.
Speaker 1: Uh, a lot of people are trying to join the forum lately and some people there's a, when you sign up to join the forum, you put in the reason for joining.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If you write something that looks like something a spam bot would write, I'm going to decline you.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure I declined someone who in retrospect might've been a human, but I really couldn't.
Speaker 1: There are some people who've been writing things that are sort of borderline like.
Speaker 1: one person wrote like, I think like packs question and they wrote packs with not all capitals and that it was just two words and it's like, okay, that could be a person with a question about packs, but they didn't put packs in all capitals.
Speaker 0: One guy was just, it was just video games, all one word, no punctuation.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like, you got to write, if you want me to accept you, spam is a bigger problem.
Speaker 1: Lately.
Speaker 1: One person even snuck through with their promotional shilling of something.
Speaker 1: You need to write a full sentence with correct grammar.
Speaker 0: Maybe you should update the prompting on that, uh, that page.
Speaker 1: I don't know how to, I got to figure that out.
Speaker 0: Cause you should say something like, you know, write something and give them a prompt.
Speaker 0: Uh, I know some other vanilla forums do that where they'll say it won't just be, you know, prove to me you're human.
Speaker 0: It's like, prove to me you're human and mentioned something about X or prove that you're human with a complete fully formed grammatically correct sentence.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, where they subject predicate, et cetera.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But no, if you, if you cannot differentiate yourself, if you got, if you got a, you know, a denied email, maybe then you should try again and write something proper.
Speaker 0: For example, write something along the lines of, yeah, I listened to the show and now I know why you rejected me.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: Or I have been a listener of this show for X period of time.
Speaker 1: And now I would like to join the forum, not packs info.
Speaker 1: Louis Vuitton, Louis Vuitton, bagger, bagger, bagger, Michael Jordan, air Jordan, New York.
Speaker 0: Lately, I've been getting one that looks like it's the terms of service for another website.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: Anyway, talking about ponies, I haven't talked about ponies on the show for a while.
Speaker 1: You're looking for any excuse to bring ponies back in the evening.
Speaker 0: Actually, no, I just, there was, there hasn't been any other comic or media.
Speaker 0: We haven't already reviewed that.
Speaker 0: both of us are consuming at the same time.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: So we're big fans of my little pony friendship of magic.
Speaker 0: In fact, we have a sister show we launched a while ago called Radio Free Equestria.
Speaker 0: that might get some updates soon.
Speaker 0: We just haven't had time to kind of finish that show out for the season, but a good old Katie cook did a comic.
Speaker 1: Katie cook is someone that I've known about for a very long time because her art skills were amazing and always improving.
Speaker 1: Even when I first found out about her art skills are amazing.
Speaker 1: They've only gotten better.
Speaker 1: And she does things such as the online web comic Gronk, which is hilarious.
Speaker 1: She also did, done a lot of these sketch cards.
Speaker 1: So for example, what the sketch cards are, she did this for a long time.
Speaker 1: I don't know if she's done it recently.
Speaker 1: It's let's say, for example, you went and bought, you know, collectible cards that don't play a game.
Speaker 1: I know those still exist, right?
Speaker 1: Amazing.
Speaker 1: For something like Indiana Jones, like when that non-existent movie came out, they had collectible cards you could just buy.
Speaker 1: And if you bought those cards at a comic book store, which comes in a direct market box, as opposed to the kind of box that would, they would send target, which is a different box.
Speaker 1: There was a chance that in that box somewhere in one of those packs would be a card.
Speaker 1: that was a sketch card, which is basically they sent her a blank card.
Speaker 1: She actually drew on it and then they actually inserted it into there somewhere.
Speaker 1: So she used to do a lot of those.
Speaker 1: Uh, her web comic is awesome.
Speaker 1: At conventions, she does the thing where you give her five bucks and she paints a little tiny thing on a card.
Speaker 1: I got rim before she even did the pony comic.
Speaker 1: I got rim and narwhal.
Speaker 0: It is a pretty great narwhal.
Speaker 1: I got Emily bunny and I got me a rainbow dash before she did a pony comic.
Speaker 1: Uh, but now of course that person ended up writing, not arting, writing the pony con the first four issues.
Speaker 1: And, uh, Andy price ended up arting the pony comic.
Speaker 0: Now, uh, Katie cook is credited with some art for the first issue, but I never really figured out what she did in there compared to, you know, there's two credits for, uh, issue one and then one credit for two, three, four.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Just so you know, I didn't look in.
Speaker 1: there was, there was, she did some of the, there are so many variant covers on this motherfucker.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: She, I know she did some of the variant covers and in fact, some comic book stores get sketch covers.
Speaker 1: She had a stack of these comics, pony comics with blank covers and she drew on each one differently and one comic book store got those.
Speaker 0: So I'm digging this as, as a comic.
Speaker 0: I enjoy it mightily.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It reminds me a lot of actually the Simpsons comic, right?
Speaker 1: Because what the Simpsons comic is to the Simpsons show, right?
Speaker 1: Is they basically, they take the show, the characters, the foundations, right?
Speaker 1: But they get a little bit nerdier, a little bit more inside baseball because it's a comic book and they're a little bit more free to explore.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Uh, the art style is a little different, just like the Simpsons comic.
Speaker 0: I really like the art style is that kind of super detailed, there's crap everywhere in the background.
Speaker 1: It's sort of the Sergio Aragon's thing going on where everything in the background all over the place.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Um, and yeah, it's a, it's pretty great and it's like, well, you know, if, if, you know, the show feels like it has a more broader appeal and is simpler and the comic is more like a more it's not, it's, it's, well, I'll put it this way.
Speaker 0: It is definitely like the Simpsons comic.
Speaker 0: I would say it is aimed at someone who is already a fan of my little pony.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't, I don't see many people just reading the comic and not having watched or planning to watch or are watching the show.
Speaker 1: It doesn't really introduce you to the characters at all, right?
Speaker 1: It totally expects you to know the show.
Speaker 0: And by the same token, I mean, who reads the Simpsons comic, but doesn't watch the show is never watched the show.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, it is definitely aimed, you know, so it's aimed at the fan, but simultaneously it's not the fan service that you see so often when you get a thing like this around something that has a big specialized fandom.
Speaker 1: It's not like a fan comic where it's aimed squarely at like the older, you know, unintended audience.
Speaker 1: Like this is definitely aimed at the same audience as the show.
Speaker 0: It might be aimed at a slightly older audience than the original demographic of the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I see a lot of little kids reading this.
Speaker 0: I do too, but I see a lot of little kids, uh, watching the vampire a hundred D and Robocop.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about real little, like three.
Speaker 0: I don't think you've seen three year olds reading this real little, the littlest.
Speaker 0: I don't think you have any concept of legitimately will play with pony toys for anyone between the ages of six and 40.
Speaker 1: Are you playing with your pony toys?
Speaker 1: You just letting them decorate your desk.
Speaker 0: I currently don't have any, I don't have a selection to throw at my sky castle.
Speaker 0: So the comic is just, I like the story.
Speaker 0: It's really faithful to the characters and it, like Scott said, it gets its snark on and it's inside baseball on just enough more than the show to where I would actually like it if the show were more like this comic from this point forward than the other way around.
Speaker 1: Uh, but anyway, so what is, what happens in the comic, right?
Speaker 0: So the comment, which by the way, I established via Twitter that we can effectively consider this comic canon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that Katie Cook said so.
Speaker 0: So that raises complications because you know what the plot of the five, six, seven and eight written by someone else are.
Speaker 0: You really, you know what it is?
Speaker 1: What is it quotes?
Speaker 0: A new nightmare moon has appeared.
Speaker 1: Oh, we'll see what happens there.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so the plot of the first four issues here is, uh, basically let's fight against the change lings again, right?
Speaker 0: I love seeing the changeling queen just being herself in long form as opposed to being the villain and just like one two parter.
Speaker 0: She's a great character.
Speaker 1: It's like by actually giving the villains more screen time.
Speaker 1: In fact, issue three is from the villains perspective.
Speaker 1: Uh, you can really go into those characters more because they didn't get a lot of time in the show.
Speaker 0: There's this great moment where she's, you know, she's kidnapped the CMC, so they're hanging out and she just being, it's one of those typical stereotypical things of.
Speaker 1: I've kidnapped some people and they are bothering me.
Speaker 0: But the thing is they're so perfectly on character that it's brilliant and you can almost hear a sweetie house voice.
Speaker 1: Like it reminds me a lot of that rarity episode of the show where rarity was bothering the dog dudes.
Speaker 0: Ah, true.
Speaker 0: But in particular, what I like about that bit is there's this one little bit where, you know, the CMC is basically just commenting on what chrysalis is doing and being annoying about it.
Speaker 0: And they're like, well, aren't you just like, why didn't you do X?
Speaker 0: Because that's what evil people do.
Speaker 0: And she's like, uh, you realize I'm evil for a reason.
Speaker 0: Like I, I have a plan.
Speaker 0: I'm actually after something.
Speaker 0: I'm not just evil to be fucking evil.
Speaker 0: And they like, they couldn't get that.
Speaker 0: And I just thought that was a nice little touch.
Speaker 0: It's like take the Disney villain and give them an actually realistic motivation.
Speaker 1: And there's also a nice mix of taking things from the show and sort of reusing them, like the old split the characters up and then they get together with their powers of friendship.
Speaker 0: But the fact that almost immediately afterward, all of them independently like, wait a minute, I'm pretty sure we got broken up due to changeling shenanigans.
Speaker 0: Maybe we shouldn't have split up.
Speaker 0: Let's go find each other.
Speaker 1: But you know, that kind of stuff where it's like, they got stuff from the show, but also new things.
Speaker 1: So it's like, this is clearly pony comic, but this is also clearly not just the show again in a comic.
Speaker 1: It is also a new thing.
Speaker 0: Now there aren't that many issues out yet.
Speaker 0: There aren't going to be that many issues.
Speaker 0: I mean, Katie Cook's only writing the first four, and then there's that other plot and it's going to be like, you know, there is also, there's two actual comics.
Speaker 1: There's a micro series where each issue focuses on a single character and it gives you a one character related to nothing side plot.
Speaker 1: I don't know if these are canon or not.
Speaker 1: The first one we've read already is out, is about Twilight Sparkle and it gives you the story about Twilight in a library.
Speaker 1: It was okay.
Speaker 1: But it's like, those are the, actually the kinds of things I would like to see as episodes of the TV show, right?
Speaker 1: These sort of, these sort of plots.
Speaker 0: Well, I have this hope because you know, you realize the Simpsons got to that point once they'd just been running long enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They'd be like a mo episode and that that's when Barney kind of hit a really nice stride.
Speaker 0: quilts and quilts and quills.
Speaker 0: So while a lot of people have some problems with the current season of my little pony, people say it's not as good as other seasons and I'm not going to debate that here.
Speaker 0: Uh, though I kind of agree, but not a hundred percent and not for the same reasons you assholes do.
Speaker 0: But I hope that the pony show continues long enough to get to that point where they do the, uh, five short Grable style episode or the pulp fiction style episode, you know, the kinds of like.
Speaker 0: let's mess up the format or just follow one character things that the Simpsons started doing hardcore like season seven, eight, nine.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or the, uh, Dexter's lab.
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: That episode really high concept that I appreciate much more as an adult now than I did as a child.
Speaker 1: The artistic masterpiece that it is.
Speaker 0: I tried to like shuffle my nose, like, like do my sniffle in that pattern.
Speaker 0: And I think I just hurt my lung.
Speaker 0: My lung kind of hurts now.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: But no, that, uh, all that aside, this comic is pretty great.
Speaker 0: I would say if you're not a fan of my little pony, like you're one of those people who somehow held out, uh, you know what?
Speaker 0: You should try reading the comic.
Speaker 0: It's cheap.
Speaker 1: I guess you can read an issue, but really it's more, if you're a pony person and you're watching the show, you have to read the comic.
Speaker 0: I would say if you're not a fan of the show, read the comic because one, a few people I know who public has said they're not fans of the show privately admitted.
Speaker 0: They actually do watch the show, which is weird, but yeah, someone we might know who says they don't like the show anyway.
Speaker 0: So even if, you know, if someone's not a pony fan, this comic is pretty funny and standalone in the same way that if you had some random person, the Simpsons comic, even though it's not really aimed at them, I could see them enjoying it.
Speaker 0: And then later on going to watch.
Speaker 1: I read a couple of Simpsons comics every year.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to go get them all because it's just too goddamn many.
Speaker 1: Cause that thing has been going nonstop for years, but it's like, I read one once in a while and they're always mildly humorous.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: These kind of stand on their own, but no, Scott's right.
Speaker 0: These are really aimed at, you're already a fan of my little pony in any stretch.
Speaker 0: There is no reason for you to not read these.
Speaker 0: Even if you're only a casual fan, you've only seen a few episodes.
Speaker 0: If you know anything about ponies and liked it at all, you should read this comic.
Speaker 1: You probably actually need to watch the chrysalis episodes to understand this.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But at the same time you can, it's one of those things.
Speaker 1: Like if you don't know that if you haven't seen at least one CMC episode with sweetie bell and scootaloo, you won't understand.
Speaker 0: I think it's more that with many secondary works like this, if you are like when I read, uh, that, uh, horrible green lantern thing, horribleness aside, there are, there were bits that were actually pretty well done that I didn't get because I hadn't read other green lantern bullshit,
Speaker 1: but that was a green lantern that was told to me was a green lantern.
Speaker 0: You could read not having read anything, but at the same time I could read it and get it without knowing those things.
Speaker 0: Those things would just enhance it much like how you can totally just watch Wolverine and the X-Men knowing nothing about the X-Men and it is a great show, but if you know anything about the X-Men, it is so much better because of the little sort of bits and the important parts.
Speaker 0: The fact that Scott Summers is the loser loner who's tearing everything apart and Wolverine has to get the team back together.
Speaker 0: The irony of that is lost on someone who doesn't read a lot of X-Men, but you can watch the show with or without that.
Speaker 0: It's just ads.
Speaker 0: Knowing the personalities of the three different CMC makes this comic way better.
Speaker 0: Not knowing them does not prevent you from enjoying it and figuring out that.
Speaker 1: Why did she kidnap those three annoying ponies?
Speaker 1: Why aren't they freaking out?
Speaker 0: I don't know, maybe ponies just don't freak out.
Speaker 0: You don't see a lot of ponies freaking out in this comic.
Speaker 0: Who freaks out?
Speaker 1: My little pony is about nothing but ponies freaking out.
Speaker 1: That's what the show is.
Speaker 0: In fact, Rarity keeps her cool surprisingly well when flowers attack.
Speaker 1: That's a problem.
Speaker 0: I think we're done.
Speaker 0: There's not much to review without just spoiling the crap out of the what?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, come on.
Speaker 1: And I'm kind of hungry.
Speaker 1: I want to go home.
Speaker 1: I want to do a long episode.
Speaker 0: There might not be shows next week.
Speaker 0: I might be in Colombia.
Speaker 0: Colombia.
Speaker 1: You know what happens if you go to Colombia?
Speaker 1: I play more Netrunner.
Speaker 0: But I'll tell you all this.
Speaker 0: We have like four episodes of Geek Nights presents Shoujo Kakamei Utena videoed, ready for post-production.
Speaker 0: I've just been too busy to finish editing them.
Speaker 1: Maybe you should watch some of that there.
Speaker 1: Some of that there Utena?
Speaker 1: Some of that there Utena.
Speaker 0: I got one dude already who complained about how we pronounce Utena.
Speaker 1: Except the way Wakaba pronounces it is Utena.
Speaker 0: All things aside on that debate, yes, Japanese does not have inflection like other languages do.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, someone who speaks English and speaks Japanese words will tend to speak it with an accent.
Speaker 0: In this case, in English or American accent.
Speaker 1: And he says Utena-sama.
Speaker 1: Which is Utena.
Speaker 1: Utena-sama.
Speaker 0: Utena has a slight emphasis on the T the way I said it.
Speaker 0: Utena is not how they say it in Japanese either.
Speaker 0: And Utena is ridiculous.
Speaker 1: So we told where that there Utena comes from.
Speaker 0: That there Utena is going to get saved for another time.
Speaker 0: But let me tell you, I heard a man say...
Speaker 1: I thought you weren't there.
Speaker 1: I thought this was a story that was secondhand from Lara.
Speaker 0: Lara?
Speaker 0: I thought it was from Luke.
Speaker 0: Are we that old?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Do we not know the origin of this?
Speaker 1: Maybe this isn't true.
Speaker 0: I have this clear memory of Luke and someone else being in a conversation.
Speaker 0: And Luke said something like, yeah, he's a fan of that there Utena, making fun of him saying it that way.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Do we... I think we're old.
Speaker 0: I think it's over.
Speaker 0: It's the end of the party.
Speaker 1: Some guy said he was a fan of that there Utena.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.