Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, March 13th, 2013.
Speaker 1: I'm Rim, I've got Emily here, and this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, Scott is not here, so I can talk as long as I fucking want at the beginning of the show, telling a gigantic title about how we're going to review Mama Rojoza's Wolf Children, a fantastic movie that we just saw in the theater.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So we're pretty much busy trying to get ready for PAX, which is, I believe, next weekend.
Speaker 1: I think it is next weekend, because this episode's actually going up the time.
Speaker 1: we're recording it instead of way ahead of time.
Speaker 1: But the end result is Scott is at home and not in the studio, so we have a guess.
Speaker 0: I thought he was mentoring today.
Speaker 0: He's doing his mentor thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but he was supposed to do the show yesterday, and we didn't do it for other reasons, unrelated.
Speaker 0: Right, right.
Speaker 0: Well, anyway, this is kind of an experiment, because it's weird, because usually when I'm on the show, it's the three-person conversation with, like, "Wim and Scott got the banter going," and then I'll chime in occasionally with my opinions or whatever I have to say about various comics.
Speaker 1: That different kind of banter this time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel kind of awkward, because I'm so used to having, like, these one-on-one conversations with Wim, but I, you know, I haven't had six years or seven years or whatever worth of recording it, so it's kind of like...
Speaker 1: You're not used to talking to me when I'm facing the other direction, fiddling with knobs, and scratching myself most of the time.
Speaker 0: No, I'm, like, staring at your ponytail right now.
Speaker 0: I'm staring right at your back.
Speaker 0: And so, like, the whole episode, you're gonna just feel these eye beams boring into you, like, Emily's staring at me.
Speaker 0: I feel the sweat.
Speaker 1: I've realized that I kind of... maybe I'm just vain, but a lot of listeners, whenever there's a video or anything of us, they always refer to my mane, and that goes back to even before My Little Pony.
Speaker 0: No, seriously, when you, like, shake your hair loose, when your hair is loose and, like, flopping around, then it looks very full, and it looks mane-like, so I feel like, at least when you wear it down, it merits the term
Speaker 0: "mane.".
Speaker 1: Well, that video where the demon horse at our first packs hit me in the junk.
Speaker 0: That was awesome!
Speaker 0: Well, not the hitting in the junk, but, like, your hair is flying everywhere.
Speaker 1: And basically, this dude's just like, "Oh my god, that guy's mane is longer than the
Speaker 1: horse's.".
Speaker 1: And then the horse hits me in the junk right after Scott stops recording.
Speaker 0: That was the packs I didn't go to, right?
Speaker 0: That was, like, Dante's Inferno.
Speaker 1: That was back when special guests, like me and Scott, actually got weird perks, like, we got to get into the expo hall.
Speaker 0: Half an hour, like, guess what?
Speaker 0: Guess what, Rem?
Speaker 0: Know how else you can get one of those rare perks?
Speaker 1: Uh, by enforcing?
Speaker 0: No, be a game developer.
Speaker 0: Ahh.
Speaker 0: So, I'm doing, like, the triple threat this year.
Speaker 0: I'm going as an attendee.
Speaker 0: I'm, um, we've got a booth in the NDA Mega Booth for Guns of Icarus, so I'm gonna be doing a little bit of boothing.
Speaker 0: And I'm enforcing, so, uh, it's gonna be pretty great.
Speaker 1: I'm a special guest, and I'm an attendee, but I am not a developer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the guest part I haven't tried, but I've tried the other bits, and they're pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: Packs is, like, hands down my favorite convention.
Speaker 0: Like, I don't know if I've been on the show to geek out about it as much, I mean, they constantly, like, for six months before packs, as soon as the one packs ends, they're like, "Oh my god, six months before packs
Speaker 0: feast!".
Speaker 1: And then six months till packs, it's a six mod six.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's one of those things where they're amped up pretty much constantly about packs.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I think, you know, I've always been kinda lukewarm on conventions, partly 'cause I get kinda overwhelmed in very loud social environments.
Speaker 1: You don't drink as heavily as I used to at cons, either.
Speaker 0: Well, that's part of it, like, but also, I'm not a sustained partier.
Speaker 0: Like, I really enjoy the social engagement, and I really enjoy parties and stuff, but only for, like, four hours at a stretch, you know?
Speaker 0: I think three days it gets a bit much, and I kinda just wanna curl up in a corner with a book and be like,
Speaker 0: "Whoa!".
Speaker 1: The entire, the front-room crew would go to, you know, anime cons every year, like, Katsu-Con and Otakon, those are big things, like, every year we'd all go, and then the one year we all went to packs, and then pretty much everyone we know.
Speaker 0: We were just like, "Whatever anime
Speaker 0: cons.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, now the anime cons are just like me and Scott and maybe you, and almost no one else we know goes anymore.
Speaker 0: Actually, I'm kind of psyched for Anime Boston, 'cause that's the first big anime con I've gone to.
Speaker 0: If I go, like, if I get my panel, it's gonna be the first one I've gone to in quite some time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Anime Boston's, and last year we didn't go, except to show up for exactly two hours to do two panels back-to-back, and then we immediately left.
Speaker 1: I didn't even go to the artist alley.
Speaker 0: I went to the artist alley, and the artist alley's pretty good, but it's like, I came and dropped off the DVD, and got the stink eye from the guy who's manning the room, because I was like, "Yeah, we bailed on you
Speaker 0: guys.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, never forget, guys.
Speaker 1: We performed live via DVD at Anime Boston last year.
Speaker 0: That's not performing live!
Speaker 1: That's like the opposite of performing live!
Speaker 1: It was a live performance that was then recorded and replayed, but the performance itself was live.
Speaker 0: I thought to do something live, it had to be real-time streaming.
Speaker 1: But if I watch a recording of a soccer event, was that not a live event that I'm now watching again?
Speaker 0: It was a live event, but you weren't watching it live.
Speaker 0: It wasn't coming to you live.
Speaker 0: A live feed means it's currently active.
Speaker 1: Though in this case, there would have been no difference and no way for the audience to tell, because we don't actually interact with the audience ever.
Speaker 0: That's the thing.
Speaker 0: You could have played it like, "Oh, we just don't have a microphone, so we can't hear you, but we're streaming to you live," or something, even though you'd be totally BSing, and I'd have to hide the DVD and be like, "Yeah, yeah, satellite feed,
Speaker 0: seriously.".
Speaker 1: We could have been there in person, and people wouldn't know that we were there live.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're just holograms.
Speaker 1: The other main reason Scott's not on the show now is that he didn't pirate wolf children and watch it when he had the chance, and he didn't buy tickets to the Children's Film Festival.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I warned him ahead of time.
Speaker 0: I was just like, "It's funny, because this is one of...".
Speaker 0: Actually, it is probably my favorite film festival that happens in New York City every year.
Speaker 1: I get super excited every year.
Speaker 0: It's like, I try to tell people, "New York International Children's Film Festival," because I'm a grown-up, and they're like, "Really?
Speaker 0: I don't
Speaker 0: know.".
Speaker 0: I'm like, "No, seriously.
Speaker 0: It's the best animation
Speaker 0: festival.".
Speaker 0: But it's true.
Speaker 0: It's got a mix of shorts, and you can go to the short screening, and you can also see all these animated features.
Speaker 0: And they also have a few live-action things.
Speaker 0: But it's like any international animated feature that is worth a damn, they're probably going to screen it at the Children's Film Festival in New York.
Speaker 0: So it's cool, too, because they must have a lot of pretty smart kids, because most of the films are subtitled.
Speaker 1: Guys, the questions these little five-, six-, seven-year-old kids ask the directors at these things are way better than anything you've ever asked at an anime con of a guest.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, they're still kids.
Speaker 0: They're definitely like... We'll get to that later, the first question.
Speaker 0: they asked the director.
Speaker 1: The kid was just like, "Why was the movie so
Speaker 1: depressing?".
Speaker 0: The director was there.
Speaker 0: He was doing a Q&A session with the audience, and he was just like, "Well, trust me, if you watch it when you're older, try watching this movie when you're 20, and then maybe you won't find it depressing.
Speaker 0: Maybe you'll have a different
Speaker 0: experience.".
Speaker 0: I really like... This is the second time I've gone to see and met Mamoru Hosoda, and every time he seems like a very patient person, but he's nice.
Speaker 0: He seems nice, you know?
Speaker 0: Very interesting.
Speaker 1: He gives good and direct answers, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you feel like he's not doing the PR, BS-ing kind of thing.
Speaker 1: Not like the, "Well, I was inspired by many of the people I worked with in my time at the
Speaker 1: studio.".
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, I kind of compare it to when Jeffrey Katzenberg, who was like the head of DreamWorks, came to our animation class one day.
Speaker 0: They had a big event where he came to school.
Speaker 0: You can really tell the heads of the big companies versus the artists, where they'll give very, I don't know, kind of advertising answers.
Speaker 0: Not saying a lot, but still trying to sound exciting.
Speaker 0: I mean, it just wasn't a frank conversation.
Speaker 0: That's one thing I liked about Makoto Shinkai, too, is he was actually even more direct, kind of like, "Yeah, that kind of was a tough thing," and et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 1: And you can see the interview with him because apparently I was the only journalist in the room with a camera when he was interviewed at the New York anime festival.
Speaker 1: To me, that's a crime.
Speaker 1: Well, the New York Comic-Con.
Speaker 1: I didn't even expect to record it.
Speaker 1: I literally went there because I wanted to see him.
Speaker 0: We didn't even have a tripod, did we?
Speaker 1: No, because I was done.
Speaker 1: I'd gotten all my video.
Speaker 1: I was done with my press coverage.
Speaker 1: I had nothing else to do with the con, so we went to see him.
Speaker 1: And then I looked.
Speaker 1: I realized there was no press person in the room, so I stood there holding that fucking camera for an hour.
Speaker 0: No, you earned your press credentials on that one.
Speaker 1: And only like 300 people have even watched that interview.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's kind of frustrating to me because for me, the art has always been the most important.
Speaker 0: I'm an animation fan first, and I like the anime culture a little bit, but it's more about the art form for me.
Speaker 0: It's more about filmmaking and animation.
Speaker 0: And so the fact that you'd have the chances to go see these directors that actually made the work, and people just don't seem that interested.
Speaker 1: Scott and I went years ago to Anime Central, and Rintaro was there.
Speaker 1: There was like 100 people scattered around in this big room, and most of them were just kind of hanging around in the room playing DS's and waiting for whatever was next.
Speaker 0: It's like people geeking out about these American voice actors.
Speaker 0: Who, I mean, to be fair, it's like that's good that they're getting recognition, but I'm sorry, you're gonna skip out on this director to go see somebody who's a dub actor?
Speaker 0: I don't know, that seems a little silly.
Speaker 1: But basically, the movie actually got picked up pretty much right away, and disappeared from all the torrent sites, so Scott was unable to pirate the movie and see it in time for us to do a review.
Speaker 0: But that's good, because that means Funimation.
Speaker 0: It's Funimation, right?
Speaker 0: I think is the one who licensed it.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, I think so.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's like they're on it.
Speaker 0: I think it was either them or Bandai, I forget.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it was Funimation.
Speaker 0: No, I'm talking about that.
Speaker 0: did Girl Who Leapt Through Time, and their previous ones.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, I'm pretty sure they did all of them, but I'm not 100% sure, because I haven't actually paid attention to who picked stuff up in the last four to six years.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I think the releases of his previous movies were fairly popular, so I'm glad to see that they think this one is a pretty sure bet.
Speaker 1: I think it is, it was a great movie.
Speaker 0: It was amazing.
Speaker 1: Even if you don't listen to a review and you just don't go any further, guys, there aren't that many anime feature films that aren't just the One Piece Movie 6 of Matsurita, Shakuto, Himitsu no Shima.
Speaker 0: Your Watch All anime movies aside, Hosoda is probably my favorite anime director right now.
Speaker 0: Like every single one of his recent films, basically the three he co-wrote and directed, the Girl Who Leapt Through Time, Summer Wars, and this movie, they're all, I don't know, they're incredibly emotionally resonant for me.
Speaker 0: Like Girl Who Leapt Through Time, I think is the best example in film I've ever seen of a high school experience.
Speaker 1: Not Shoujo Kakamei Utena?
Speaker 1: Because that's exactly what high school was like for me.
Speaker 0: I mean like relating to how I felt as a teenager, just the scenes where she has these easy friendships with these two guys and they go play baseball.
Speaker 0: And that was just something that's so, I don't know, relatable and down to earth.
Speaker 0: And also like her kind of being dumb about emotional stuff, like, you know, hiding from the guy and being like, but it didn't come across as exaggerated.
Speaker 0: It came across as very believable and you're like, man, that feels like, you know, it just portrayed teenager-dom so well.
Speaker 1: Well, I think he's also just, he's got enough sort of versatility and he's done a lot of things and he's taken the path that is almost the surefire way to know.
Speaker 1: it's a director that's at least in my wheelhouse.
Speaker 1: Because if you look at his credits, he's credited with being a key animator for a ton of relatively big things throughout his career.
Speaker 0: But I guess, I guess girlhood left through time.
Speaker 0: That was like, it made you feel high school.
Speaker 0: And Summer Wars, it made you feel like, you know, I have a big extended family and it's like the feeling of, you know, having all these relations and some of them, other ones are pissed off at.
Speaker 0: And like, some of them are old and bossy and some of them are young and loud.
Speaker 1: Well, even just the little bits like cutting like the kitchen and the one girl just watching the TV.
Speaker 0: It's just like the little touches.
Speaker 0: It came across as very, you know, it wasn't realistic in that like, this is exactly like a filming somebody's family, but it came across as, you know, a genuine feeling, you know?
Speaker 0: And this one, I think this one portrayed motherhood in the same way.
Speaker 0: It's just really captures.
Speaker 0: And I think it's awesome because you very rarely see fantasy movies or fairy tales told from the mother's perspective.
Speaker 1: It's even like a look at the question.
Speaker 1: The kid is like, why is it so odd?
Speaker 0: It's such a rare choice for the kid.
Speaker 1: It was a movie about, you know, I don't get to see my mom anymore because I go away to boarding school or whatever.
Speaker 1: Like, it's so sad that the brother disappeared off into the mountains and all these bits.
Speaker 1: But really, from the mother's perspective, that was the victory.
Speaker 0: That was the success was about raising a child to the point of independence.
Speaker 0: You know, it was really kind of great because it showed this character who was incredibly strong, but, you know, also dealt with her challenges in a realistic manner.
Speaker 0: So anyway, we'll talk about, tell people what it's about.
Speaker 0: You know, the poster just has this lady and she's got two kids and they have wolf ears and wolf tails.
Speaker 0: And you're like, oh, are they like, you know, kind of like cat people, wolf people with just the ears?
Speaker 0: Not really.
Speaker 0: What the premise is, is there's this college student named Hannah and she's going to class one day and she sees this mysterious man in the corner who's like auditing the class and taking notes.
Speaker 0: And she thinks he's kind of interesting.
Speaker 0: So she gets to know him and, you know, they start a relationship.
Speaker 0: And there's something she doesn't know at first is that it's a werewolf love story.
Speaker 0: But I mean, this thing is a hell of a lot more, I don't know, more heartfelt than Twilight, I think.
Speaker 1: I don't think we're going to spoil a lot of what happens.
Speaker 0: You should all watch it.
Speaker 1: But it's pretty commonly known that basically the story is that he dies pretty much right away and she's got the two kids.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it basically that's not really a spoiler because in the trailer, in most reviews, they mention the fact that they lose their father very young.
Speaker 0: And oh my gosh, you know, so it's got a similar thing in terms of the montage after they get together.
Speaker 0: It's almost a little bit like that scene in Up where it just kind of shows their life together.
Speaker 0: And, you know, music and her getting pregnant and dealing with the pregnancy.
Speaker 1: But be warned, I mean, his death is sudden.
Speaker 0: It is horribly sad.
Speaker 1: You can hear the entire audience sort of reacting to it at once because you knew it was coming and you expected it.
Speaker 1: And yet at the same time, you kind of didn't.
Speaker 0: It was very short.
Speaker 0: It was like you don't actually see his death.
Speaker 0: And, you know, the whole scene where she finds out about it is just very short.
Speaker 0: There's no dialogue.
Speaker 0: It's just shown and it's wrenching because he dies as a wolf and, you know, his body is being picked up and she's unable to claim it, basically.
Speaker 0: She's unable to say that's my husband or, you know, that's my, you know, imagine the love of your life dies and you see them in front of your eyes and you can't do anything about it and they're gone.
Speaker 1: And then from that, she basically just moves out to the countryside and then the whole rest of the movie happens.
Speaker 0: That's cutting a little bit.
Speaker 1: No, I don't want to go through the whole plot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, obviously.
Speaker 0: But you know how I was talking about.
Speaker 0: she has to go through a lot of struggles and it shows the strength of a mother because it's like she's in the city and, you know, there's this very funny scene.
Speaker 0: She has the kids at home because she doesn't know if they're going to come out as wolf or as human, so she's like kind of worried.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of scenes early on where it's like, for example, the daughter eats one of those packets that come in food, you know, the silica.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and she vomits and she doesn't know.
Speaker 1: Well, she's standing there looking at the pediatrician.
Speaker 0: She's looking back and forth between the vet clinic and the pediatrician's office.
Speaker 0: Which one do I go to?
Speaker 0: But the kids are really cute because they'll swap back and forth between the forms of wolf and human very quickly.
Speaker 0: You know, they'll kind of morph back and forth depending on their emotion and they don't have a lot of control over it when they're small.
Speaker 0: So they'll be like, "I'm
Speaker 0: hungry!"
Speaker 0: And then the mom's like,
Speaker 0: "Wait!"
Speaker 0: And they'll turn into a wolf and run around the room and chew on corners.
Speaker 1: He definitely just in general seemed to have a lot of fun with using, a lot of times when there's an anime or even a live action movie where there's transformations or something like that, they're often done kind of derpily.
Speaker 1: They're done really well in this movie because every transition is kind of well-timed and just looks good and fits the scene and actually is often kind of hilarious.
Speaker 0: Well, the character designs are fairly simple.
Speaker 0: And one thing that initially kind of bothered me about the movie is that sometimes when they were in their wolfish forms, they still looked a little too human.
Speaker 0: They had hair.
Speaker 0: It looks like, you know those like dog head girl kind of furry art on DeviantArt where it'll be like a dog but it has like anime hair?
Speaker 0: That's what it kind of looked like and so I was like,
Speaker 0: "Eh.".
Speaker 0: But then I realized that that was still, they're retaining a little bit of the human form, like the eyes and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Well, that was just it, that they're kind of at this liminality between humans and wolves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and so they kind of blend back and forth.
Speaker 1: So not to interrupt, but breaking news.
Speaker 1: Lou accepted every freaking panel we submitted.
Speaker 1: Are you listening to this?
Speaker 0: Is it going out live?
Speaker 1: All anime are the same show on Friday.
Speaker 1: We are performing anime openers from around the world.
Speaker 1: Our prize, if you've already seen it, don't see it.
Speaker 1: We're performing how to recommend anime, how to run an anime club, and judge anime by its cover.
Speaker 1: Seriously, judge it by its cover.
Speaker 0: Oh man, they're really, he's really... Oh my god, are they all on Friday?
Speaker 1: I think they're all up.
Speaker 1: No, one's on Saturday.
Speaker 0: But that's kind of awesome because we'll get it out of the way and then... Well, let's see if I got accepted later.
Speaker 0: But thank you, Lou.
Speaker 0: Hooray, we're going to anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Now I have to actually write four of those five panels.
Speaker 0: You brought it on yourself, kiddo.
Speaker 1: One of them requires a not insubstantial amount of video editing and we have to acquire some movies that are difficult to acquire.
Speaker 1: Thanks, Mike Tool, for forcing us to step up our game.
Speaker 0: Yay, you can do it.
Speaker 1: So anyway, what I found really interesting, and I think it's actually really important to the whole theme of the movie, but it was interesting that when he reveals that he's a wolf, I like how she's pretty much like, "Okay, this is cool.
Speaker 1: I can deal with
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 1: Like the way she reacts, I thought was very well done.
Speaker 0: What did they say in the booklet?
Speaker 0: It was like, "She takes this information in stride and is maybe even a little attracted to the
Speaker 0: idea.".
Speaker 0: And that's really how it comes across.
Speaker 0: Like, anyway.
Speaker 1: Yup, but the fact that he remains a wolf, sort of an anthropomorphic wolf, one could almost say a furry, as their sex scene begins.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a fade to black sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Leaning over as the camera fades out.
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 1: I think it's actually really important that that was that way, because it shows that she accepted him 100%.
Speaker 1: I've always thought it was a cop-out, whenever there's a movie where there's some sort of alien or other, some non-human thing that is a romantic interest of a human.
Speaker 1: And if they're a shapeshifter or something, it always ends up being that it's just a human.
Speaker 1: They always cop out and go back to, "Oh, it's just a human, maybe with green
Speaker 1: skin.".
Speaker 1: I mean, Captain Kirk wasn't really having sex with the alien blob.
Speaker 1: It was always the alien blob turns into a girl.
Speaker 1: But this, it really... He is not human.
Speaker 1: And that really drives home that he is not human.
Speaker 0: Well, he's part human.
Speaker 0: That's the thing.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, he's part human.
Speaker 1: But as a result, he is not human.
Speaker 1: He's not wolf either.
Speaker 1: He's something else.
Speaker 0: But really, that's the major theme of the movie.
Speaker 0: The two themes I think that are the most important, are motherhood and identity.
Speaker 0: It's about somebody with a dual identity or a dual heritage, dealing with those heritage and eventually coming to a place where they're able to find balance, becoming their own individual and managing whatever identities make up who they are.
Speaker 1: And then that all comes around full circle in the end with the girl wolf and her sort of interactions with the people around her.
Speaker 0: So I like that, yeah.
Speaker 0: But as far as it being a movie to show to kids, I think kids can enjoy it.
Speaker 0: I mean, the audience, there were a lot of kids, obviously, because this was Children's Film Festival.
Speaker 0: And I think they noted it as nine and up.
Speaker 0: It was either like seven and up or nine and up.
Speaker 1: This movie is best appreciated by someone who has achieved adulthood.
Speaker 0: I think, what did he say?
Speaker 0: The director said, "I kind of want kids to watch it with their parents and then they will appreciate how hard it is to raise children and what their parents go
Speaker 0: through.".
Speaker 0: I mean, obviously, their parents aren't going through them like turning into little canine forms and chewing on the walls and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Though, I've met many kids where, maybe you could do it straight up.
Speaker 1: If you replaced the other animal characters with just other people, this could just be a movie almost the same where she's just a single mother raising two kids.
Speaker 0: Really, really hyperactive kids.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, all that does is show to highlight that it's not easy to raise kids.
Speaker 1: The fact that they're wolves and that they're even one step further difficult.
Speaker 1: I mean, really, them being wolves just gives her this sort of confusion and fear that she's going to do something wrong.
Speaker 1: She doesn't know how to do it.
Speaker 0: She doesn't know how to raise children.
Speaker 1: Humans don't know how to raise children either and everyone kind of expects that when they're an adult, they'll just know what to do.
Speaker 0: Intuitively, yeah.
Speaker 1: So this is a way to express to someone who isn't already a parent and hasn't already gone through this just what that feels like.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, the only thing... The kid ate a desiccant.
Speaker 1: Are they dying?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: What do I do?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, the only difference is that she has to... She decides she has to hide this and, you know, it makes sense.
Speaker 0: She can't like tell everyone her children are werewolves.
Speaker 0: There is a really funny scene that I want to talk about, but there's this scene where the... Ah, I won't spoil it, but like when they're changing back and forth and there's guests over, but the guests don't realize.
Speaker 1: That's when Yuki starts getting a little bit precocious.
Speaker 0: She is so cute.
Speaker 0: Like both children are very cute.
Speaker 0: Yuki, the older girl, she's very much the tomboy when she's a little kid and Ame is very quiet and sensitive.
Speaker 0: and there's this scene that's kind of sad.
Speaker 0: It was very cute, but he's like, "Why are wolves always the bad guys in the picture
Speaker 0: books?".
Speaker 0: And he's crying because the wolves are always evil in the stories.
Speaker 1: There is also a bunch of a set of old man characters that are up Scott's alley.
Speaker 0: So this film, it's one of those stories where it's kind of like... What's that book?
Speaker 0: The Shipping News, where they move to a very rural environment and the story starts off... Stuff kind of sucks.
Speaker 0: Stuff is bad, you know?
Speaker 0: And little by little through hard work and building connections and stuff, stuff never becomes perfect, but it gets better.
Speaker 0: It just goes up and up, you know?
Speaker 0: And so I like that aspect of the movie.
Speaker 0: It's like when they're fixing up that old busted house they live in and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: And the people in the village are hilarious.
Speaker 0: All the little side character bits about them.
Speaker 0: teaching her how to farm is pretty, pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: Now the movie takes a while to get where it's going.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's a full two hours.
Speaker 1: But it really works because as a result it can really focus on the kind of the long relationship building and the long growth of the kids.
Speaker 1: You see the kids growing up through several eras of their lives and there's this great sort of montage kind of in the second third of the movie where it just keeps panning up and down a hallway like when the kids are in first and second grade and second and third grade and back and forth.
Speaker 0: And it's just so well done.
Speaker 1: I really want to see the movie again just to watch that scene again because it's so well put together.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, so I like that scene.
Speaker 0: It was interesting because it takes place in a very, very rural area but it's gorgeous.
Speaker 0: The scenery is so beautiful.
Speaker 1: - Well, you asked him a question and it was pretty straightforward to answer.
Speaker 0: - I said, both in Summer Wars and in this film you chose to set them in the Japanese countryside.
Speaker 0: Did you grow up in the country or is there any connection to the country?
Speaker 0: And he said, actually the town this is set in is based on where I grew up in the Japanese Alps.
Speaker 0: - And I was like, cool.
Speaker 0: This is kind of his hometown, so to speak.
Speaker 0: And so I thought that was pretty neat.
Speaker 0: but yeah, it's a beautiful movie in terms of the artwork and everything.
Speaker 1: - So it's independent of our general.
Speaker 1: if there is an animated feature film, you should see it.
Speaker 1: This one stands up above and beyond even that recommendation.
Speaker 0: - Yes, I mean, I have very little bad to say about the film.
Speaker 1: - So I say two things.
Speaker 1: If you're a fan of anime of any stripe, just watch this movie.
Speaker 1: If you're a fan of animation, just watch the movie.
Speaker 1: If you're a fan of Mamoru Hosoda, just watch the movie.
Speaker 1: But independent of that, I would suggest tricking your parents into seeing this movie.
Speaker 0: - Yeah.
Speaker 1: - Don't really tell them what it's about and just get them to watch it.
Speaker 1: 'Cause if nothing else, I think they'll appreciate it.
Speaker 1: And especially if you're their child, they will appreciate you offering to them to watch it.
Speaker 0: - I think this is probably the best werewolf movie I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: I love this movie.
Speaker 0: - Best werewolf movie, yeah.
Speaker 1: - No, this is totally hands down.
Speaker 1: - Because an American werewolf in London is actually kind of derpy.
Speaker 1: And an American werewolf in Paris is actually really stupid.
Speaker 0: - See, it's not a werewolf genre movie.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have, when you say werewolf movie as a genre, it's not that, but it's about werewolves.
Speaker 0: And so my favorite werewolf movie.
Speaker 1: - I'm trying to expand to any movie that's ever had a werewolf in it.
Speaker 1: There aren't that many that are good in any sense other than derpy horror.
Speaker 0: - Anyway, I don't know if there's, I have that much more to say about it.
Speaker 0: I'm relatively positive.
Speaker 0: Also, like we said, it was long, but it's like, we talked about Welcome to the Space Show and that one is really long.
Speaker 0: But that one could have been cut, exactly.
Speaker 0: I felt like that one, they had many scenes where I'm like, you really stretched it out.
Speaker 1: - Or meanwhile, Oshie's sad children fly planes endlessly forever.
Speaker 0: - But that was on purpose.
Speaker 0: I say that's on purpose.
Speaker 1: - And super slow, but form is function.
Speaker 1: It's that way for a reason.
Speaker 1: - If you didn't like it, you just have no attention span.
Speaker 1: But I digress.
Speaker 1: Wolf Children is great.
Speaker 1: You should watch it and tell Scott to watch it.
Speaker 1: That'll just infuriate him because he currently can't get ahold of it to watch it.
Speaker 0: - He never watches, don't tell him to watch it 'cause he never watches stuff if I nag him about it too much.
Speaker 0: If I go watch it, watch it, watch it, then he'll be like.
Speaker 1: - In fact, you know what, Scott's a butt.
Speaker 1: 'cause I don't know if he's never gonna listen to this.
Speaker 1: He'll never know what we said.
Speaker 1: I know how he is.
Speaker 1: Scott, you're a butt.
Speaker 1: And also, according to Emily, your microphone smells like a butt.
Speaker 0: - No, it just smells like spit and that's what microphones just smell like.
Speaker 0: - That's what all microphones smell like.
Speaker 1: You should smell the pop filter in front of this thing.
Speaker 0: - I'm always scared of spit.
Speaker 0: I don't like the smell of spit.
Speaker 0: I'm like, "Ew, there's spit on
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 1: - Well, Scott also likes to rub his face on his microphone.
Speaker 0: - Like a cat?
Speaker 1: - Yeah, well, you know, sometimes I end it out, Scott'll just kinda put his chin up to the microphone and just be like, "I gotta move my pop filter,".
Speaker 1: but he'll be like.
Speaker 0: - But I can just imagine him.
Speaker 0: I imagine Scott being all cat-like and rubbing his head on it like a cat rubs its head on your leg.
Speaker 1: - Well, you're seeing Scott doing the show.
Speaker 1: He's usually sitting with his eyes closed.
Speaker 0: - Quintus is face up.
Speaker 0: It's very cute.
Speaker 0: He's like,
Speaker 0: "Mmm.".
Speaker 1: - The trouble is he's doing that in the videos we're doing in the antenna right now.
Speaker 0: - Well, he's doing okay with the videos, but it's like, well, the other thing is he's fidgety.
Speaker 0: So it's like in the videos, he'll be like bouncing up and down and you'll be like, "Scott, it looks like you're like having a spasm or
Speaker 0: something.".
Speaker 1: - I had to stop at one point because I have an outtake.
Speaker 1: We're doing the antenna show and he just starts like moving his arm around like under the table and it just looked like he was whacking it.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it's a pity Scott couldn't see the thing with us.
Speaker 0: It's like, seriously, if you're in New York, get hip to the Children's Film Festival because... And the funny thing is, speaking of this movie, like maybe six, seven months ago or something, I tweeted at the New York Film Festival.
Speaker 0: I was like, "Oh, oh, New York Children's Film Festival.
Speaker 0: Are you gonna have wolf children?
Speaker 0: Please say
Speaker 0: yes.".
Speaker 0: And they were like, "It's a
Speaker 0: secret.".
Speaker 0: I was like, "Yes, they totally
Speaker 0: are.".
Speaker 0: So that's cool.
Speaker 0: You can subscribe to them on Twitter and every year they always have a spectacular show.
Speaker 1: - All right.
Speaker 1: And on that note, I gotta get ready for PAX.
Speaker 0: - Go to sleep.
Speaker 1: - We'll see.
Speaker 1: We might not do shows the week after PAX and then we'll start doing them again.
Speaker 1: We'll play it by ear.
Speaker 1: We've been busy.
Speaker 1: You guys simultaneously want us to do more video and want us to be at more conventions and do more geek nights.
Speaker 1: and not all those things are gonna happen at the same time.
Speaker 0: - It's hard because you travel more.
Speaker 0: Our schedules have been less reliable.
Speaker 1: - I gotta commit to PAX.
Speaker 1: Awesome, I'm going or not to.
Speaker 1: Scott doubled down.
Speaker 1: He bought a plane ticket and a hotel room.
Speaker 0: - I don't know.
Speaker 0: I wanna go, sort of, but at the same time, it's like I'm really on the fence about PAX Australia.
Speaker 0: I love PAX.
Speaker 0: Don't get me wrong.
Speaker 0: I was just talking about how awesome PAX is, but basically for the cost of an Australia trip, I could have two Europe trips.
Speaker 1: - Well, even if you don't go to Australia just for this, we can still go to Turkey and Scandinavia.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: It's like if I don't go to Australia, I might be able to go to Turkey and go to Finland and Sweden.
Speaker 0: So I was like, "Oh my gosh, I don't
Speaker 0: know.".
Speaker 0: I'm thinking about it.
Speaker 1: - Oh, and I'm just gonna show Emily something right now that proves I'm a dork.
Speaker 0: What is this?
Speaker 1: - That's my new credit card.
Speaker 0: - You've got Rarity's cutie mark on your... Wow, the funny thing is, looking at Rarity's cutie mark on a Capital One card, it actually looks just like one of those designs that they have on the standard cards.
Speaker 0: Wow, that's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: This isn't the platinum card.
Speaker 0: It's the diamond card.
Speaker 1: - I gotta whip that out in front of some punk bronies at some kind.
Speaker 0: - They're gonna steal it.
Speaker 0: Punch you in the face, steal your credit card.
Speaker 0: Anyway, good night, everybody.
Speaker 0: Thank you for having me on the showroom.
Speaker 0: I don't get to do this enough.
Speaker 1: - Well, we'll do it more often, especially if Scott's busy or lazy.
Speaker 0: - I wanna do the thing.
Speaker 0: See, Wim didn't let me do thing of the day and he didn't let me do anecdote.
Speaker 0: You know, the whole like, "Yeah, today I was riding my bike to
Speaker 0: work.".
Speaker 0: And then, of course, I wasn't riding my bike to work 'cause it's cold.
Speaker 0: - Well, we were busy.
Speaker 1: You come home later, we did stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean, we had to clip a bunny's nails.
Speaker 0: - I would have done my opening bit on how the rice cooker exploded with cake.
Speaker 0: - It did explode with cake.
Speaker 1: Well, it blurpled and then it exploded.
Speaker 0: - It blurpled most horribly.
Speaker 1: - Anyway, in conclusion, Scott, you're a butt.
Speaker 0: - No, Scott is the best.
Speaker 0: And also a butt.
Speaker 0: - Butt, butt, butt.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: - Who else?
Speaker 1: I've realized there's people.
Speaker 1: Dave Riley, if you listen to this, email me, I'm just curious.
Speaker 1: Because you seem to know a lot about our show sometimes.
Speaker 1: And I listen to you guys.
Speaker 1: actually every time you upload an episode immediately.
Speaker 0: - But then he'll hear my noob show.
Speaker 1: - He might.
Speaker 0: - Yeah.
Speaker 1: - You've been on the show before.
Speaker 1: - This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: - Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.