Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, April 16th, 2013.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we're talking about games that only Scott could love.
Speaker 0: No, I do.
Speaker 0: Not could.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Sort of a call back to back when we did a similar show about Arrow Biz.
Speaker 0: I was searching for like, "Have we done a show on
Speaker 0: this?".
Speaker 0: And I saw an episode from 2008 called, you know, "Games Only Rym
Speaker 0: Likes.".
Speaker 0: So I was like, "Hey, can we do Games Only Scott
Speaker 0: Likes?".
Speaker 1: And I was like, "What, like Kings
Speaker 1: Bounty?"?
Speaker 0: I could hardly think of any games that only Scott likes, but then I thought of a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: One of them's got to be Kings Bounty because he tried to get me to play that like four times.
Speaker 0: I don't know why I don't like Kings Bounty.
Speaker 1: I didn't get it and it wasn't fun and my character on the horse was way too big.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: That bothered me.
Speaker 1: It's good to be back on our normal schedule.
Speaker 1: I've been biking to work now that it's nice out and I don't have the flu.
Speaker 0: It's still too cold.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the fuck is wrong with you.
Speaker 0: If you check the weather, basically it's alternating between sunny and beautiful but cold and warm and awesome but rainy.
Speaker 0: There has not been a sunny and warm- Scott, it is 60 degrees out right now.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: And what temperature was it when I woke up this morning?
Speaker 1: I don't know when you wake up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like 40 something.
Speaker 1: No, because I biked to work this morning.
Speaker 1: It was not 40.
Speaker 1: It was 40 like 89.
Speaker 1: I biked to work at exactly 830 because I was running about a half hour late.
Speaker 0: It was cold.
Speaker 1: And right now, right now, which is a while after I got home, it's 59 degrees.
Speaker 1: That's cold.
Speaker 1: Which is pleasant.
Speaker 0: Cold.
Speaker 1: For biking, in fact, that's a little warm.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Call me when it's like 68, 69 at least.
Speaker 1: We'll have to do our race.
Speaker 0: When you're biking, there is a fan blowing on your entire body.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: When I'm biking, it is so hot that even on a day like today, I'm in shorts and a t-shirt trying to pull my shirt off because I'm so hot.
Speaker 0: That does not happen to me.
Speaker 1: I don't think you bike as hard as I do.
Speaker 1: We should do our race to Rockaway once it's warm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone's looking up.
Speaker 0: Apparently the beach is going to open irregularly, but some sections of the boardwalk will be closed because broken.
Speaker 1: I kind of have this perverse, selfish hope that as a result, a lot of people don't go to the beach.
Speaker 1: So when I do bike to the beach, I have a private beach.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's hard to bike to the beach when part of the boardwalk is closed.
Speaker 0: We'll have to bike on the non-boardwalk.
Speaker 1: I kind of know my way around the island at this point because I bike over there.
Speaker 0: I mean, I know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like you can't bike on the sand.
Speaker 0: So if you want to bike straight from one end to the other.
Speaker 1: There's a road that goes mostly parallel to the boardwalk.
Speaker 0: You have to use that road is what I'm saying as opposed to using the boardwalk, which is much nicer and closer to the water and with a better view and such, you know, under the boardwalk.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So in the news, it's been a while since we've really talked about current events and everything and there's not a lot of them.
Speaker 1: There's stuff coming.
Speaker 1: I mean, Monica was getting this real release and all that, but uh, an issue that has come up from multiple different places.
Speaker 1: So I kind of want to talk about the issue as opposed to all the specific people except Adam, because I have to talk about him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see, I don't want to talk about it, but the general sentiment is that multiple people like the head of Ubisoft also said something very similar.
Speaker 1: People are ready for and or okay with always on DRM being part of their console gaming experience, not just their PC gaming experience.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, despite the fact that online gamers on Reddit and other places yell and scream saying all online DRM blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: They buy the game anyway.
Speaker 0: Sim city as much as catastrophe is yelling.
Speaker 0: I didn't buy it.
Speaker 1: I'm boycotting it.
Speaker 0: I haven't bought an EA game in forever.
Speaker 1: I'm actually as much of a gamer as I am.
Speaker 1: I'm ideologically opposed to buying EA games, specifically SimCity.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't buy them just cause I don't want to play any of their games regardless of the online.
Speaker 1: I would want to play SimCity, but I refuse on principle.
Speaker 0: My interest in playing it is, is mild, but very mild.
Speaker 0: My interest came back cause I have a copy of SimCity for you can buy some city 2000 on gog.com.
Speaker 1: Some city 2000.
Speaker 1: I'm done with you suck.
Speaker 1: I've played that game out.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I've taken a city legit from nothing to all perfect arcologies and a flat grid.
Speaker 1: So I have no interest in playing that game.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is that, Oh, and two fusion plants, maybe three in case is a disaster.
Speaker 0: You put them in separate places.
Speaker 0: It just, the point is, is that despite this SimCity still sold like a jillion copies and they still made a jillion dollars.
Speaker 1: But why is that?
Speaker 0: And I would argue that is because PCs are pretty useless without being connected to the, remember we, for how many years we had PCs that didn't have any internet and we use them all day.
Speaker 0: I wrote documents for school in Microsoft works.
Speaker 0: And I played Jez ball and wasn't it the greatest.
Speaker 1: It was okay.
Speaker 1: But actually, no, even in those days I had no modems and I was playing games and fucking around with terminals.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: So if you have a computer in your house that always has internet, right?
Speaker 0: So much, right?
Speaker 0: Then why wouldn't you have a console in your house?
Speaker 0: that always isn't it?
Speaker 0: What's the difference?
Speaker 1: Well, I think the difference is that one consoles still to me are the kind of thing that they're supposed to be.
Speaker 1: Literally the physical boxes.
Speaker 1: here, I turn it on, games happen.
Speaker 1: So if it has to be always on for stuff to work, even single player games, suddenly taking your console to your beach house doesn't work out so well.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Even the console at grandma's house doesn't work out so well.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Really what this is about is, you know, people seem to be making this thing like, Oh my God, no one will be able to play games.
Speaker 0: that was always online.
Speaker 0: And yeah, internet's unreliable in a lot of places, but actually in most places it works.
Speaker 0: The real worries here are number one, I looked up some statistics and basically 70 to 80% of X boxes are online.
Speaker 0: So they're throwing away 25% of customers.
Speaker 0: So really one out of every four people has an X box now will not be able to use the new X boxes.
Speaker 0: They don't have it on the internet because maybe they don't have good internet or they don't know how to plug in more than one device.
Speaker 1: problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I saw screenshots from a guy who still had the original X box, three 60.
Speaker 0: It didn't red ring and it had the original software.
Speaker 0: Nice with the blades.
Speaker 0: They go, wow.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Crazy stuff.
Speaker 1: But it's kind of, it's like they're trying to take some of the worst or at least useless aspects of PC gaming and poured it into a console, but for no good reason, the reason they want to sell more ads, right?
Speaker 0: They want to, they want to forget the real reasons.
Speaker 1: Cause we know the real reasons.
Speaker 1: The reasons they give are such hollow bullshit reasons.
Speaker 0: They don't have a real reason.
Speaker 1: We want a solid interconnected experience.
Speaker 1: We want the social aspects, right?
Speaker 0: Because they don't have.
Speaker 0: the only reasons they have are the bullshit reasons that are evil.
Speaker 0: They don't have one single good reason that is good for the customer.
Speaker 1: You know, I have the game Mark of the Ninja.
Speaker 1: I've been playing it on my steam console because why would I?
Speaker 1: there was literally no reason it would ever need to connect to the internet because it's a single player game I'm playing through by myself.
Speaker 1: There might be benefits to connecting it to the internet, like sharing scores with your friends, but one, those shouldn't prevent me from just playing a fucking game.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: I don't even have another one.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: That's the highest order concern that they're doing it for these selfish, semi secret, but obvious reasons like trying to do DRM, trying to force social aspects that are used to guilt people into DLC or even having DLC available and
Speaker 0: tracking people's playing so that they can get data about you and you and what you play and how many hours you play.
Speaker 1: This is the social crap of Scott got.
Speaker 1: this achievement will remind people to play games.
Speaker 1: They're trying to have this ability to have their hand in your console, right in the cookie jar, pushing your buttons and getting you to go in the direction they want you to go.
Speaker 1: And I think it works.
Speaker 0: Statistically, it works on most people.
Speaker 0: So they think they're going to make more money.
Speaker 0: They think they're gonna make more money if they throw away one in four customers completely and milk the customers, the other 75% for more dollars each in the midterm.
Speaker 1: They probably will because the people they're throwing away are the people who've never heard of DLC.
Speaker 0: They'll also probably get those, you know, even with the customer service expense, right?
Speaker 0: Get some of that 25% to plug their computer into the internets.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And they're also going to be able to really push this stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean, look at this recent push toward making it impossible.
Speaker 1: You know, one thing online here I'm is used for is to prevent people from modding their own game or cheating in the single player game that they have because they're they want to push these microtransactions or upgrades or DLC or comparative scores online.
Speaker 1: And as a result, they need to prevent you from cheating.
Speaker 1: But if I want to cheat on a game that I own, that I'm playing by myself, I should be able to cheat.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If a game is offline completely, I can get a tool easily to modify the data in Civ two on the options and turned cheating to on if you wanted to cheat.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know what?
Speaker 1: I'm done with this.
Speaker 1: Let's spot a thousand nukes and make China not exist.
Speaker 0: There's no way to make me, you know, pay money for donuts in, you know, Simpsons.
Speaker 0: That's you just go onto the hard drive, find the file.
Speaker 0: This is how many donuts you have and change the number.
Speaker 1: Their end game is to make you pay money to have that cheat menu.
Speaker 1: Their end game is to turn Borderlands into will basically already is an MMO.
Speaker 1: They don't let you just pick your level because they need you to go through the grind bullshit for all the social aspects they had and the DLC.
Speaker 1: They've got all these.
Speaker 1: It's all centered around monetizing more while making less.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so Adam Arth, this Microsoft guy, basically from what I can tell, right, is that he, I don't know if he truly believes that he was saying or not.
Speaker 0: It seemed like he was sort of having a trollish sort of jerky argument battle with his friend, right?
Speaker 0: Like if you look at the actual tweets, it's sort of like two guys ragging at each other, like, you know, deal with it, man.
Speaker 0: You know, that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Like how serious was he?
Speaker 0: Not, you know, maybe he did believe it.
Speaker 0: Um, but you know, the way he was expressing himself was way jerky because I think he saw it as a one on one sort of friend troll battle.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Uh, but in reality he ended up being a jerk to everyone who doesn't have internets.
Speaker 0: And so then he lost his job either by quitting or resigning or who knows, but it doesn't work there anymore.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But his sentiment was basically everything I rail against.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: So not super sympathetic toward him because this whole DLC thing is, and microtransactions are really starting to encroach into areas they shouldn't be in gaming.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's how it is.
Speaker 1: Now what's funny is PCs, which my PC is always online no matter what.
Speaker 1: In fact, even if I lose power, I'll probably still have internet on my PC between ups and files and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: But even then I can mod my games and fuck around with my games and PCs are the place where you have the freedom to fuck around.
Speaker 1: The console is the place where you just plug it in and it just works.
Speaker 1: People who complain about PC gaming complain that it doesn't just work.
Speaker 1: If your console doesn't just work, suddenly those people are going to be really mad.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: People talk about like, you know, this sort of thing where PC gamers think they're so much better than console gamers.
Speaker 1: We are, but that's a separate discussion.
Speaker 0: And no, I'm going to say, look, you know, and they, and they sort of try to portray the PC gamer as like an elitist jerk, right?
Speaker 0: And console gamers, right?
Speaker 0: They try to say, you know, we're not, you know, you know, dumb or stupid or bad because we play, you know, on a console instead of a PC.
Speaker 0: It's like the guy who's living in Disneyland, even though most people, even though most people who are actually defined themselves as gamers and care about video games deeply are playing games on both all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, but the thing is, is that yes, if you are one of those people who is saying, you know, PC games suck because look at all these errors, you are not as good as the PC gamers who are smart enough to get games to work on a PC.
Speaker 0: If you're not smart enough to game games to work on a PC, you are definitively less smart.
Speaker 0: At least when it comes to computers as those PC gamers, therefore you are not as good as them.
Speaker 0: They are better than you empirically to make a lie.
Speaker 0: If you're complaining that it's like, Oh, it's too hard.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Cause you're not as smart as they are to make less acidic point.
Speaker 0: No, I got to be as acidic as possible.
Speaker 1: I just want to make a less acidic point.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be a little bit basic here.
Speaker 0: Max acid a hundred molar.
Speaker 1: My argument is simpler.
Speaker 1: As soon as they keep doing this stuff to consoles, consoles are going to have all the same problems that PC gaming has.
Speaker 1: Then what?
Speaker 1: As soon as you're, you're trying to play your game on your Xbox and it's like blah, blah, blah, DRM, something, something, and the game stops.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah, the real problem here is not so much that your internet will not be out, will be out, right?
Speaker 0: Because you're not even gonna have the console if you don't have internet and that's super reliable.
Speaker 0: It's that the Xbox system will go down, right?
Speaker 0: Microsoft will have an outage.
Speaker 0: And right now, if Microsoft has an outage, it means live doesn't work.
Speaker 0: So you can't chat or play online, but you can still play.
Speaker 1: My Atari and regular Nintendo still work and I can put those cartridges in and play them.
Speaker 0: But with the new system, if it's always online, if Microsoft has an outage, no one can play, even no matter how smart they are.
Speaker 1: But, but rim and Scott steam and you know what?
Speaker 1: Steam valve is one of the few companies in the entire world I actually trust to some degree.
Speaker 0: It also has offline mode and steam, which works really well.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, simply works.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: If I was going to play the new Sim city, 99% of the time I would play it sitting in airports or sitting on planes where there's internet sometimes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to pay for airport unreliable internet and a lot of airports have free wifi.
Speaker 1: Not outside of the U S I have.
Speaker 1: So increasingly when I travel, you get to an airport and there'll be a bunch of free access points and you can get free internet, but you have to send a text from a local number and then register and then they text you back credentials and then you can log on because a lot of these countries have laws against anonymous access to the internet.
Speaker 0: Those non free speech countries.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And Google voice does not often handle those that well.
Speaker 1: And a lot of countries seem to block Google voice texts for that purpose.
Speaker 0: Can't VPN.
Speaker 0: once you get connected, I can't get connected.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's the problem.
Speaker 0: Well, can't you do their bullshit registration to get connected with like a pay phone and then not send a text from pay phone.
Speaker 0: Uh, yes.
Speaker 0: Some of them, other countries have a lot fancier pay phones than we do.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, they're still disappearing outside of Japan.
Speaker 1: I have not seen a pay phone.
Speaker 1: that was.
Speaker 1: in fact, the pay phones I've seen in my travels were less sophisticated than the ones that I still see in the U S.
Speaker 0: oh really?
Speaker 0: Cause when I was in Israel in the year 2000, the pay phones are very sophisticated.
Speaker 0: You would put calling cards and credit cards directly into them.
Speaker 0: They had digital screens that showed you like who you were calling and the rate would take up and the time would go down and all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: And that was then.
Speaker 1: that has not been my experience in India, Turkey, Germany, okay, et cetera, Sao Paulo, Israel.
Speaker 0: best phones, question mark.
Speaker 1: Well, I have a better question for you.
Speaker 1: The fuck's a pay phone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: In an airport.
Speaker 1: The other case, the actual flight, I'm flying to Australia in a couple of months.
Speaker 1: I w I would play sim city cause that's the perfect game.
Speaker 1: Dick around on a plane.
Speaker 1: I'm probably not going to have internet on that 25 hour flight.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: I mean, even if you could, even if the plane had internet, you think it's going to have internet in the middle of the Pacific ocean.
Speaker 1: If it did, that'd be pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: You know, how would that work?
Speaker 1: So I can't play sim city, so I'm not going to buy it, but maybe if I can come up with a way to pirate it, then I could play it on my laptop.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: That's enough of that.
Speaker 0: Uh, so I just got a tiny news, tiny news.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, there's been trend lately of remaking the classics and I think a certain segment of the game industry has realized, Hey, it's really low effort to take these old hit games, keep pretty much everything intact and update graphics and will sells.
Speaker 0: I think bionic commander rearmed was the trigger for this.
Speaker 1: I think it was too.
Speaker 0: I mean, you got the duck tail.
Speaker 1: I can't, I still kind of can't believe the duck tails thing happened cause that came out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: So cap comments, Sega are really the big ones doing this the most, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, right.
Speaker 0: So bionic command, it was cap com.
Speaker 0: mega man nine 10 is cap com.
Speaker 0: Ducktales is cap com.
Speaker 0: Sega did Sonic four.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: I'm still amazed though that as good as bionic commander rearmed was how bad the new bionic commando.
Speaker 0: Well, forget that.
Speaker 0: So Sega is doing another one.
Speaker 0: They're re.
Speaker 0: they're re releasing Sega Genesis, Mickey mouse, castle of illusion.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: That was a good game.
Speaker 0: It was right.
Speaker 0: So they're pretty much taking all these games that are really easy to remake, updating dem graphics and re releasing them.
Speaker 0: So there you go.
Speaker 1: So speaking of updates to old games, not really, but it's in the, it's in a similar spirit.
Speaker 1: just very briefly.
Speaker 1: So Luke crane and toward been working for a while on a game.
Speaker 1: They had a working title for it, dungeoneers and dragon slayers D's and D's, but that has a little legal implications.
Speaker 1: I mean, I have a, my company had a working title of a project called F1 or formula one.
Speaker 0: That's not going to work.
Speaker 1: That's just what we called it while we were working on it.
Speaker 1: I'm not, yeah, there's trouble with that.
Speaker 1: Obviously.
Speaker 1: So, uh, D's and D's was a sort of callback to old school dungeon crawls.
Speaker 0: It was also sort of a modification of mouse guard.
Speaker 0: It was like mouse guard with a lot of the mouse, all the mousey stuff ripped off and just dungeons, but they would run a play test of this at like burning cons and nerd NYC things.
Speaker 1: And I played it a bunch of times over the last couple of years.
Speaker 1: I played it once while it was going through its paces and it was stupidly fun.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: So it has now been officially announced.
Speaker 1: Interestingly, the official first source was Forbes.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: So props to them for getting that set up.
Speaker 0: But uh, I don't know why Forbes cares about tabletop role playing.
Speaker 1: Well, it's Eric Kane, a contributor to Forbes who quote, I write about video games, the industry and the culture.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: This isn't non video game.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I guess he decides what to contribute and they say, so the actual title of the game is torchbearer and it is basically the feels you get from playing old, original dungeons and dragons without the mapping, but with all the other parts streamline.
Speaker 1: So it forces you to make the decisions instead of, did I draw the map correctly?
Speaker 1: Where are we on the map?
Speaker 1: Did you fuck up the map?
Speaker 1: What happened to the map to, are you going to carry that baby out or the treasure chest or your swords?
Speaker 0: I have a bag now.
Speaker 0: Now I have four extra slots in the bag.
Speaker 0: I'm going to put these things in the bag.
Speaker 0: You carry, you have a free hand here.
Speaker 0: Carry this.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's a monster.
Speaker 0: I put this shit on the ground and fight and then I picked the shit back up.
Speaker 1: Oh, you, uh, that's your last 10 foot pole that you just broke there.
Speaker 0: You're going to do now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You mean my one 10 foot pole I was able to carry because it's two handed.
Speaker 1: So basically look forward to this.
Speaker 1: I'll probably get Lou Crane on to talk about it in a little more detail.
Speaker 0: because I mean, another interesting thing is that this time, uh, I think Tor is credited or is the writer.
Speaker 0: writer and Lou Crane was the editor.
Speaker 0: A role reversal role reversal.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, maybe we should try to get tour on the show.
Speaker 0: I saw him at the mocha.
Speaker 0: I was just, well, I was just looking at the, in the museum thing in the back and there he was.
Speaker 1: And I was like, Luke and or Jared, we never get tour.
Speaker 1: I'll bug tar.
Speaker 1: I'll see if he'll come on.
Speaker 1: geek guys.
Speaker 1: Talk about this stuff.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: He's, he's a fun guy.
Speaker 1: So things of the day, I'm surprised we didn't talk about this sooner.
Speaker 1: The chrono jigga.
Speaker 0: I thought we did talk about this.
Speaker 1: I guess we didn't.
Speaker 1: I can't find any reference to it as a thing of the day unless I didn't put the word chrono in it.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: But, uh, the chrono jigga smash-ups between chrono trigger music and Jay Z made by this guy.
Speaker 0: I think two mellow is the guy's name.
Speaker 0: Uh, but Jay Z two mellow is the guy who did the mixing.
Speaker 1: It's too mellow.
Speaker 1: I was reading this whole thing cause it's on a YouTube channel.
Speaker 1: Bruce bonsai.
Speaker 0: This is pretty epic right here.
Speaker 0: You gotta just search.
Speaker 1: I've been listening to this shit pretty much constantly for a couple of weeks.
Speaker 0: The website, you just download the whole thing for free.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or you kids today seem to just listen to things on YouTube, so they'll probably just listen to it on YouTube.
Speaker 1: I know how you work.
Speaker 0: I downloaded, put it on my iPhone.
Speaker 1: You do.
Speaker 0: Oh, so my thing of the day, the thing of the day.
Speaker 0: So, uh, there's a show, there's a guy named Dan Levitard who's a Miami sports journalist, right?
Speaker 0: And he appears on PTI sometimes on which is a show that geek nights was loosely based upon as like, he's like a stand in guy and he started this new show.
Speaker 0: I think it's like on ESPN two or three or something, whatever.
Speaker 0: it's, you know, it's, it's one of those, you know, extra shows, but basically what he does, he sits in a kitchen TV studio with his dad who's like the funniest guy.
Speaker 0: Uh, he escaped from Cuba and they talk about sports stuff and interview people and it's so crazy.
Speaker 0: But here they watch a video of a horse race and it's probably one of the best things I've ever seen in horse racing is horse.
Speaker 0: What's the horse's name?
Speaker 0: Spicer Cub is way horse names.
Speaker 0: It's crazy fast horse.
Speaker 0: And then in the middle of the horse race, the horse just sort of like goes off and like runs to the outside of the track and everybody starts passing him like, Hey, then the horse comes back.
Speaker 0: Then it runs away to the outside of the track again.
Speaker 0: It's like, where is this horse trying to go into the crowd?
Speaker 0: Is it three possibilities?
Speaker 1: One horse is bored.
Speaker 0: Someone in the audience in the grandstand is waving carrots around three the jockey be a trash talking.
Speaker 0: Who knows what's going on, but there's something you got to see what this horse is up to.
Speaker 1: We ever done a show on trash talk?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Cause I realized this bringing, you know, we always talk about the difference between pre hoc and post hoc trash talk.
Speaker 1: You know, the Babe Ruth point before the game is very different from yeah, I beat you after the game.
Speaker 1: But there's also the trash talk of, look at this, I'm just throwing away victory points.
Speaker 1: What you can do about it?
Speaker 1: I'm actually harming yourself in the middle of the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like in the bike race, you just stop and tie your shoe baseball.
Speaker 1: You walk out and you're just like, ah, I'm just gonna butt right here and let you start get me out.
Speaker 1: All right, we got two outs on.
Speaker 1: All right, let's uh, now we'll play for real.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So meta moment, the book club bookies, the player games by Ian M. Banks.
Speaker 0: I've started reading it again.
Speaker 0: I picked up where I left off and I just got to the best parts and I'm crazy.
Speaker 0: I really want to go home and read more.
Speaker 1: I got to start reading it again, but I've been biking to work every day and I tend to read mostly on the subway.
Speaker 0: I tend to read mostly while going to sleep.
Speaker 1: So, uh, we're going to be at anime Boston, which is may 24th, 25th, 26th.
Speaker 1: We're doing not one, not two, not three, not four, but five lectures.
Speaker 0: We're doing too many goddamn lectures.
Speaker 1: Emily is doing one as well.
Speaker 1: And so is our friend Judith.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna, anime Boston is going to be rocking out and in between these events, we're going to hang out with my tool, hang out with a lot of you guys probably spend a lot of time in the gaming area of anime Boston that
Speaker 0: we hardly ever spend time.
Speaker 1: Probably eat a lot of secret breakfast, lunch, and dinner.
Speaker 0: Play a lot of net runner.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: While eating good food.
Speaker 1: So we are also going to be at Pax Australia.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: July 19th, 21st.
Speaker 1: We are doing between one and three lectures.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure yet.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: And the weekend directly before that.
Speaker 1: Connecticut where we are two of the three people who run the panels, workshops and special events department.
Speaker 1: We're in the middle of scheduling the entire convention and then we're going to be there running 13 or 14 panel rooms.
Speaker 0: If you're competent and you want to help us out, we could use some help in our department.
Speaker 1: Many enforcer friends have stepped up and I'm in the process of getting them all situated so we can do this.
Speaker 0: We mostly need people because they're actually two buildings at Connecticut on the convention center and the hotel.
Speaker 0: We mostly need people to stay in that hotel.
Speaker 1: People for a bunch more fundamental reason than that.
Speaker 1: That is brought to light by the fact that Pax Australia.
Speaker 0: So number one, people can stay in that hotel so we don't have to go over there ever.
Speaker 0: And two, so we can actually take a goddamn break at some point during the convention and maybe play a game of net runner.
Speaker 1: I am definitely not missing the days.
Speaker 1: I'm at the convention center at 7am and then I walk out at midnight 30 after we locked all the doors.
Speaker 0: That's been what it's been for back into the convention center at 7am before I'm in there, before everyone else.
Speaker 1: And last year I took a 45 minute break to have one cocktail with Dave Riley.
Speaker 0: Last year I took a break to see Super Art Fight.
Speaker 1: I also did that.
Speaker 0: That was all I took a break for.
Speaker 0: I didn't even play one goddamn board game.
Speaker 1: The only reason I get that break for a cocktail is that I happen to be out of radio range and didn't realize it.
Speaker 1: OK, so, yeah, but the main reason we're trying to get staff who aren't us and our personal close like family friends is that it was pointed out that if we ever got bored and left or say Pax Australia had been on the same weekend, basically none of us would be able to go to Connecticut and suddenly 90% of our department is gone.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So we're trying to get people who aren't us to help out.
Speaker 0: Other meta, I just want to remind everybody that we have a lot of Internet presence, whatever your favorite Internet place is, we are there.
Speaker 0: We got a Web site, frontrecruit.com.
Speaker 0: We got an email newsletter which you can subscribe to frontrecruit.com.
Speaker 0: We got Twitters.
Speaker 0: We got Facebooks.
Speaker 0: We got Google pluses.
Speaker 0: We have all.
Speaker 0: we have a forum.
Speaker 0: We have every possible thing you can imagine.
Speaker 0: We have an IRC channel that people actually have been in consistently for a long time.
Speaker 0: It's crazy.
Speaker 0: No matter what your Internet flavor is, we have that flavor.
Speaker 0: We even have a podcast and YouTube channels, believe it or not.
Speaker 0: Holy crap.
Speaker 0: Oh, speaking of YouTube channels, I posted a bunch of videos and my personal YouTube of Netrunner games.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: And on my YouTube channel, we have it.
Speaker 1: It's more anime related, but we're doing a 40 or 50 episode deep analysis of an anime called Shojo Akaka Me Utena.
Speaker 1: That's our kind of big project right now.
Speaker 1: So if you like that, spread the word.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So let's get to the main vid.
Speaker 1: So King's Bounty.
Speaker 1: Why the fuck should I play that game?
Speaker 1: Here's what I remember.
Speaker 1: And this is going back like eight years, seven years, maybe you were like, you got to play this game.
Speaker 1: You don't say because I didn't play Sega games.
Speaker 1: I was a real kid.
Speaker 1: I was a smart kid.
Speaker 1: I didn't intend to.
Speaker 1: So King's Bounty.
Speaker 1: I turn on the emulator and I see a screen like that.
Speaker 1: And there's a guy on a horse who takes up like a full sixth of the screen.
Speaker 0: That's the right map.
Speaker 1: I walked around and it looked like it was fighting on similarly small non granular maps.
Speaker 0: OK, so here's what King's Bounty is.
Speaker 0: If you've ever played Heroes of Might and Magic, King's Bounty is sort of a baby's first.
Speaker 0: It's a simplified version that you can play in a Sega Genesis.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's the reason that this is a good game.
Speaker 0: Is because it is, you know, normally you would be like, oh, well, this is the golden eye to a counter strike.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's not as good.
Speaker 0: It's baby's first.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But actually, Heroes of Might and Magic, in my opinion, is one of those games that has so much unnecessary complexity, like a million numbers that you mostly just ignore because no one can possibly pay attention to all those numbers.
Speaker 0: So this by simplifying it is actually streamlining it while still giving you all the same fun going from town to town, having people join your army, going on quests, all that same good stuff from Heroes of Might and Magic into a simpler game that you can play in a Sega Genesis.
Speaker 0: Now, they're actually if you go on steam, these new King's Bounty games, which actually I kind of like and hate at the same time.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: On the one hand, they really enhance the graphics and modernist and they're much easier to play than the old King's Bounty.
Speaker 0: I even like them better than the new Heroes of Might and Magic, which I've played.
Speaker 0: But the main one problem I have with them is that you cannot speed up the combat.
Speaker 0: As a result, it just takes forever to play because a combat that could be over in like 30 seconds lasts multiple minutes, simply because even if you speed up all the animations and turn them off and everything is just slow.
Speaker 0: It's like you click, you go and it's like, no, you got to wait for these guys to move.
Speaker 0: It's like if it moved as fast as I clicked, it's the Pokemon problem where the battle should be as fast as I can press the buttons.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then Pokemon would be amazing.
Speaker 0: But because you had to sit there and wait for the guy to go like, it's super effective.
Speaker 0: It adds like a whole minute or two onto each battle.
Speaker 0: It's like, kill me now.
Speaker 1: That is why I basically never actually beat the Nobunaga's Ambition Pokemon because it was fun.
Speaker 1: And then I just didn't want to deal with that bullshit.
Speaker 1: And I always say that Final Fantasy Tactics is baby's first tactical game.
Speaker 1: Well, Pokemon Nobunaga is baby's first tactics.
Speaker 0: So this is why I like King's Bounty, at least, you know.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, I know the episode, I guess you tried to title it King's Games.
Speaker 0: Only Scott Could Love.
Speaker 1: That's just because that's a turn of phrase.
Speaker 1: Like only a mother could love.
Speaker 0: But it's not what it means.
Speaker 1: Because I found King's Bounty to be incredibly simplistic and boring.
Speaker 1: I also don't like the Might and Magic games that much.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a difference between Might and Magic and Heroes of Might and Magic.
Speaker 0: They're in the same world, universe, fantasy land, but they are completely different genres of game.
Speaker 1: You realize I don't even like Fire Emblem.
Speaker 0: Well, you got a problem.
Speaker 1: They all pale before Advance Wars.
Speaker 1: I just don't enjoy.
Speaker 0: Because they're not about the same thing that Advance Wars is about.
Speaker 1: I know, and I don't like what those games are about as much.
Speaker 0: It's Advance Wars with dating.
Speaker 1: Ah, not quite.
Speaker 1: Not quite.
Speaker 1: It's Advance Wars with dating and not being that hard.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so yeah, what the episode is really about is most of the games I'm going to mention here are not necessarily games that I like that everyone else hates or thinks are bad games, even though some of them might be that way.
Speaker 0: They're mostly games that I think are a plus games or I really care about.
Speaker 0: that are just possibly even if people like them, they're mostly ignored.
Speaker 0: No one brings them up.
Speaker 0: No one talks about them.
Speaker 0: They're unmentioned.
Speaker 0: They might not be obscure games like you've heard of them.
Speaker 0: You know, they exist maybe depending on how cool you are.
Speaker 0: But they're games that are like high on my list.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: I think these are like some of the greats and you don't see them talked or discussed almost ever.
Speaker 0: That's most of the games.
Speaker 0: Those some of them may also be games that I like and other people hate.
Speaker 0: OK, so, you know, and the degree to which people don't talk about them may vary.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So, for example, one of the first games on my list, you know, Descent one, two, three.
Speaker 0: You don't see a lot of people talking about Descent too often.
Speaker 0: You know, I think Descent, the whole series one, two, three is some of the best there is.
Speaker 1: I actually really enjoyed Descent games as a kid.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: See, Rim doesn't hate Descent.
Speaker 0: But how often do you hear people talk about Descent?
Speaker 0: People talk about free space a lot more often than talk about Descent.
Speaker 0: But I think Descent is way better than free space.
Speaker 1: Do you hate Aerobiz?
Speaker 0: Not really, but it's not like I'm going to play it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't need to play Descent again, but I bought Descent on GOG.com and I did play it recently and still great, I guess.
Speaker 0: And I realized that back in the day I was controlling it all wrong.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I always wanted crazy mouse man mouse as you could like rotate the space.
Speaker 0: People don't know.
Speaker 0: the stick with Descent is that on the one hand, it's a lot like Doom in that you're in sort of like this maze map with all sorts of secrets and lots of bad guys coming at you from every direction.
Speaker 0: It's very similar to Doom in that sort of.
Speaker 0: it's a run and gun FPS, right?
Speaker 0: With guys everywhere and lots of items to pick up and shit like that.
Speaker 0: It's really awesome.
Speaker 0: And it also Descent has a multiplayer aspect.
Speaker 0: Descent two and three.
Speaker 0: Descent three actually had really good multiplayer, but it's full 3D, not in the way that Quake and Counter-Strike and, you know, tribes are full 3D.
Speaker 1: But as in what direction am I moving?
Speaker 0: It's full 3D like Tie Fighter full 3D.
Speaker 0: It's an FPS where you can, you know, pitch and yaw and shift left and right.
Speaker 0: And, you know, you can do barrel rolls and you can, you know, do every possible movement that a ship can move in zero gravity.
Speaker 0: It is awesome.
Speaker 0: And there's so many items you can get.
Speaker 0: And if you haven't played Descent, you should go to GOG.com and buy that right away.
Speaker 0: You notice I'm starting here with my GOG.com list.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, so the only other game that I have on GOG.com that I think people don't talk about enough is Shogo Mobile Armor Division.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: I forgot that game existed until just now, right?
Speaker 0: So people do bring up this game once in a while.
Speaker 0: And the only reason I know about this game is because I bought a three button Logitech gaming mouse when I got my, built my first computer in 1998, 1999.
Speaker 0: And it came with this game for free on a CD-ROM.
Speaker 0: And I didn't understand fully appreciate this game when it came out.
Speaker 0: But first of all, this game is the predecessor to the Fear series.
Speaker 0: You'll even notice a tribute to this game is hidden in a secret room in the first Fear game.
Speaker 0: And when I played that first Fear game after buying it for cheap on steam, I found that room not knowing it existed.
Speaker 0: just because I'm that good.
Speaker 0: I find secret rooms on my own.
Speaker 0: And I went over to a radio and pushed a button and that music from Shogo was playing.
Speaker 0: And I was like, Oh, you are fucking kidding me.
Speaker 0: I discovered it legit and I knew, and I caught the reference, but Shogo Mobile Armor Division is an FPS.
Speaker 0: in some levels you're on foot.
Speaker 0: And in some levels you're in a giant robot, but what you don't realize right away is that both of that are sort of in the same, it's not like there's two games and you switch between them.
Speaker 0: It's literally, there's some levels where you're on foot and there are the giant robots and some levels are in the giant robot and there are people on foot like shooting at you with little guns.
Speaker 0: Like they're in the same space and the robots are huge, like Gundam, Evangelion size.
Speaker 1: Sense of scale is something I've just, I've never seen it in another game done so well, especially for the era of this game came out.
Speaker 1: I mean, this was what, late nineties.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And the thing is 98 game has so many anime references and as an, and it has a typical anime plot and there's like fake Evangelion posters and you
Speaker 1: might assume that it's either some Akira looking thing or some ghost in the shell looking thing, maybe apple seed if you're a little more hardcore.
Speaker 0: If you play this and you know, anime, there is so much just in the, in the theme of this game for you, right?
Speaker 0: There's even a little plot where people talk to you over the radio, like Gundam, you know, while you're doing the mission, all these anime characters and oh, it's, it's so good.
Speaker 0: I love this game.
Speaker 0: All right, let's move on.
Speaker 0: King's bounty.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: Wait, didn't that game use the lith tech engine?
Speaker 0: Uh, I think so.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Wasn't that the engine used in that amazingly shitty diehard Nakatomi Plaza game?
Speaker 1: I remember, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Go find out.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: We'll find out anyway.
Speaker 0: Uh, so another game that is a game that lots of people love all over the place, but hardly anyone talks about these days is mech warrior two.
Speaker 0: Why doesn't anyone talk about mech warrior two?
Speaker 1: I only played it on the SNES.
Speaker 0: Mech warrior two wasn't on the SNES.
Speaker 1: There was a mech warrior game on the, it might've just been mech warrior.
Speaker 0: It might've just been mech warrior.
Speaker 0: Mech warrior two for the PC was game of the year.
Speaker 0: when it came out, I think in 95 in like PC gamer and whatever.
Speaker 0: This game was unbelievable, right?
Speaker 0: I played it.
Speaker 0: I even got the expansion, uh, which let you play as the snow clan, right?
Speaker 0: And I think mech warrior mercenaries came out, which was okay.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So I was right about the lith tech engine.
Speaker 1: You know why.
Speaker 1: I remember there's not going to be Plaza game because it's the fruit fuck.
Speaker 1: That is the origin of the fruit fucker.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 1: Next for a bajillion dollars, you receive absolutely free at the goddamn lith tech engine.
Speaker 1: Use it to make your own shitty games based on ancient movie licenses like diehard Nakatomi Plaza.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I think this was the second fruit fucker comic.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but yeah, mech warrior two also is a little tricky to play on modern, you know, computers.
Speaker 0: You got to use DOS box or whatever.
Speaker 0: And even then it was flaky.
Speaker 0: The last time I tried, it was flaky on DOS, right?
Speaker 0: I think there was a window.
Speaker 0: I think there was a windows 95 version you could get, but that would even be flaky today.
Speaker 0: You'd have to use some sort of compatibility modes.
Speaker 0: I really wish they would fucking to remake this shit.
Speaker 1: because holy crap, mech warrior two, the mech warrior in general, I'm not super happy with a lot of modern met games because they tend to focus on the aspects.
Speaker 0: I wasn't that interested because they can't, you know, in the xbox it sort of went over to mech assault and it became more about the FPS part and less like.
Speaker 0: it was less and less like battle tech.
Speaker 0: You know, mech warrior two has actually a lot in common with the on tabletop, you know, war.
Speaker 1: That's why I liked it.
Speaker 0: It was more about what weapons do you have and how many of them, whereas a lot of the other games like mech assault, you know, came, went closer to being more like tribes, but you're in a robot.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Except mech assault became one of those walk backwards shooting people from a distance.
Speaker 0: And now I guess they have, what's the one with the crazy controller that they always play at pecs.
Speaker 1: Oh, I don't remember the name of it.
Speaker 0: Steel battalion, the steel battalion.
Speaker 0: And there's, what's the new, the indie one war Hawk.
Speaker 0: Is that it?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Well there's Hawking.
Speaker 1: That's the one which has a lot of, uh, grindy elements that immediately take me out of the game.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: It's super fun, but it's still two FPS.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about some games that I know rim actually doesn't like.
Speaker 0: You're ready?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: I'm ready to talk about Yoshi's cookie.
Speaker 1: Fuck that game.
Speaker 0: I love Yoshi's cookie.
Speaker 0: Yoshi's cookie is awesome.
Speaker 0: Yoshi's cookie is if you're going to rank all time puzzle games, right?
Speaker 0: The top tier of puzzle games is Tetris.
Speaker 0: Of course is number one, battle balls, magical drop and a penalty pond, which is also known as Pokemon puzzle league, also known as, you level is not Yoshi's cookie.
Speaker 0: Uh, I guess you could also maybe put bust a move slash, you know, uh, whatever you want to call it in that top level.
Speaker 0: ish.
Speaker 0: The second level Yoshi's cookie right there, right under that level is Yoshi's cookie.
Speaker 0: I just, for some reason now I respect and also on that level, regular Yoshi, Scott, you forgot to know there was a game talk to Mario's in the top level.
Speaker 1: So here's what I think is going on with this game because our friends were into battle balls and that was their thing.
Speaker 1: Like we have a few friends who are transcendent gods at battle balls.
Speaker 1: They make us look like a little babies.
Speaker 1: that was just their game.
Speaker 1: If they had not pulled us into that game, we would never have played it.
Speaker 1: I probably wouldn't have even liked it.
Speaker 1: Yoshi's cookie is just your gem fire or your battle balls, but you don't have a bunch of other people who will play it with you.
Speaker 0: It's cause you afraid to play it with me.
Speaker 0: I'll just kill you.
Speaker 1: I played it with you.
Speaker 1: I just didn't, it didn't have a good brain feel.
Speaker 1: The kind of puzzle that it is does not give my brain good feelings.
Speaker 0: Well, I like Yoshi's cookie.
Speaker 0: Basically the way it works is you have cookies in a grid, a square rectangular grid, and you can move any row or column of cookies left or right or up or down if it's a column.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: And when you move the cookies sort of go to the other side like Pac-Man.
Speaker 0: So if you move a column to the right, every cookie goes to the right one space and the right most cookie teleports to the left side.
Speaker 0: You have to line up a complete row or column of identical cookies and there's different cookie shapes, right?
Speaker 0: There's like the checkerboard cookie, the flower cookie, the donut cookie, right?
Speaker 0: So on and so forth.
Speaker 0: And when you line up a row of cookies that are all the same shape, they clear away like Tetris and the cookies collapse.
Speaker 0: and you got to clear the cookies away completely to go to the next level.
Speaker 0: Why is Yoshi eating these cookies?
Speaker 1: When did he ever have, he has no history of cookies.
Speaker 0: Mario is baking the cookies.
Speaker 0: Yoshi's berries anyway, they're like a multiplayer version.
Speaker 0: The way it works is both players have a complete grid of cookies that is the same size that constantly is full of cookies no matter what.
Speaker 0: But when you clear a line, right, you're basically, you know, working your way towards the limit of whoever clears the most lines when sort of like magical drop, right?
Speaker 0: If you reach the number first, you win, but you can get a row of Yoshi head cookies.
Speaker 0: If you get a row of Yoshi head cookies in the single player, Yoshi head cookies are wild.
Speaker 0: In the multiplayer, the Yoshi head cookies, you want to make a line of them.
Speaker 0: And if you do that, you'll activate the superpower.
Speaker 0: And the superpowers are basically constantly rotating on top of your screen.
Speaker 0: So each player has this sort of little spot on their side of the board that tells you what power will activate if you were to line up five Yoshi cookies right now.
Speaker 0: So that thing is changing all the time.
Speaker 0: So what you have to do is if you get five Yoshi cookies, you got to line them up and you have to wait for that power to be exactly a good power that's going to hurt your opponent and then hit the Yoshi cookies quickly before it changes.
Speaker 0: And some of those things will help you.
Speaker 0: And some of those things will hurt you.
Speaker 0: And some of those things will hurt your opponent.
Speaker 0: Some of those things will help your opponent.
Speaker 0: So you have to be really careful not to, like, help your opponent or hurt yourself when you trigger the Yoshi cookies.
Speaker 0: And that's pretty interesting kind of mechanic that no other puzzle game really has of the timing being necessary.
Speaker 0: You can't.
Speaker 1: So the Tetris on the DS had the several wasn't?
Speaker 1: the power is different.
Speaker 1: It was that choosing choosing the opponent.
Speaker 0: Yes, that's correct.
Speaker 0: But there's only one opponent Yoshi's cookie.
Speaker 0: But it has that timing element of, you know, you.
Speaker 0: it's not just if you can't just clear really, really fast to win that.
Speaker 0: That's a valid strategy.
Speaker 0: But the other person waits like 10 seconds, they'll be able to really crush you.
Speaker 0: And some of the abilities you can activate are like minus the other dude's score or plus your score a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: And it's like, well, fuck, right?
Speaker 1: I guess I just I. for some reason, the kind of puzzle this is just never jive with me and I did enjoy it.
Speaker 1: And also, I just point out Nintendo Power, the Game Boy version got a three point four out of five in the surveys.
Speaker 1: And the SNES version got a three point three to five out of five.
Speaker 0: I played the NES version.
Speaker 1: I don't think there was an NES version, Scott.
Speaker 1: There was.
Speaker 0: I owned it.
Speaker 0: Don't tell me it didn't exist here.
Speaker 0: What the fuck is wrong with you?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So another game.
Speaker 0: People don't talk about it.
Speaker 0: all those on the NES that I loved.
Speaker 0: Kung Fu Heroes.
Speaker 0: Do you even know that game room?
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 1: Is that the game where you're two Kung Fu dudes in this like side view, walking around on a grid, punching, kicking the shit out of people?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I know this game.
Speaker 1: The game is awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So the thing with this game is it's pretty much every screen is just a square and you can't really scroll at all.
Speaker 0: It's you're on this one square and you to beat all the guys in order to open up the door to go to the next screen.
Speaker 0: But there's so many secrets and crazy shit and you can do like these jumps, spinning cakes and get all these abilities and weapons.
Speaker 0: And it's one of those games like everything just feels so weird and sort of, you know, it's like the craziest shit happens, like you'll punch a block and a letter P will come out and you'll punch it and a door will open like a staircase and you go in the staircase and it takes you to another world where you play a bonus game with bullets flying.
Speaker 0: And it's just totally this wacky, very Japanese kind of game, you know, that doesn't really, you know, I was amazed.
Speaker 0: it came over to the US at all.
Speaker 0: It had really good music.
Speaker 0: It was co-op, really fun to play with a friend, really fun to discover all the secrets and warps.
Speaker 0: The bosses are really crazy, like these big red monsters that look like the guy from, you know, the Bugs Bunny cartoons, the big red guy.
Speaker 0: Right now.
Speaker 1: I remember, I can't remember the title of it.
Speaker 1: There was a similar game that was more like an RPG.
Speaker 0: Ah, I actually discovered this today during my research.
Speaker 1: What was it called?
Speaker 0: There is a game for the Nintendo entertainment system that was in fact a sequel to this that I did not know existed in the game.
Speaker 0: I knew that had RPG elements called little ninja brothers.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: Because I remember I did not know little ninja brothers existed before today getting the sword because you got the sword.
Speaker 1: It was basically the baddest ass thing to have, but you didn't get XP for anyone you killed with it.
Speaker 0: There was also a Super Nintendo game called Super Ninja Boy, which was the third game in the series that I never knew existed before today.
Speaker 0: So the first game in the series, though Kung Fu Heroes definitely has really good styling.
Speaker 0: I really love that game.
Speaker 1: My little brother and I played the shit out of little ninja brothers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is one of those games where it's like, you know, and there'll be some other games like it.
Speaker 0: I talk about where it's like.
Speaker 0: we bought it when we had an NES.
Speaker 0: We didn't know we were getting into and we lucked out with something good, not like the time about Wayne Gretzky hockey.
Speaker 0: And it was shit even worse than ice hockey.
Speaker 0: Wayne Gretzky hockey for the N64 is great.
Speaker 0: And talking about NES Wayne Gretzky hockey, it's awful.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So rim loves Dig Dug, right?
Speaker 1: I like Dig Dug.
Speaker 0: You like Dig Dug two.
Speaker 1: It's OK.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like Dig Dug two a lot.
Speaker 0: I had Dig Dug two.
Speaker 0: I played more Dig Dug two than Dig Dug one.
Speaker 0: So the way Dig Dug two works is Dig Dug is on an island walking around on the surface.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And so are the pookas and the figures.
Speaker 0: And they are up to their usual shenanigans.
Speaker 0: But Dig Dug on the surface, he can dig, but he can only dig in a straight line, basically making sort of faults like the San Andreas fault.
Speaker 0: And he can only start digging a San Andreas fault at a spot where there is a stick in the ground.
Speaker 0: Sometimes there's already faults already in this island.
Speaker 0: And what happens is, let's say he completely cuts off a piece of the island.
Speaker 0: Well, obviously, that no matter what that means, you have divided the island into two pieces, not to equal pieces, but two pieces.
Speaker 0: And when Dig Dug divides the island into two pieces with a fault line, one part of the island sinks into the ocean and all the pookas and figures on that part of the island will die.
Speaker 0: But it's the smaller piece that falls into the ocean.
Speaker 0: And a lot of times Dig Dug will fuck himself by falling into the ocean.
Speaker 0: And the pookas and the fire guys will laugh at him from the still floating island.
Speaker 1: I remember they'll like throw themselves into the sea and commit suicide if you don't kill them all in time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is true.
Speaker 0: You can also use the classic pumping gun to kill them because it's Dig Dug.
Speaker 1: Thing is, the game is OK.
Speaker 1: Just what you get is Dig Dug.
Speaker 0: You keep playing this game, though, and it gets really hard and really shows Dig Dug way trick.
Speaker 0: You know, Dig Dug just really gets faster and doesn't.
Speaker 0: This really has a lot of variety in the island layouts as they get bigger and bigger with more.
Speaker 0: There's only thirty one.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: After level thirty one, the levels have the same layout as the one sixteen levels before it.
Speaker 0: But that means I almost beat this as a kid.
Speaker 0: I was only able to get to level like eighteen, nineteen, twenty.
Speaker 0: There's only thirty one unique levels.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize I was that close to winning.
Speaker 0: You don't win.
Speaker 1: It just keeps going.
Speaker 0: Give a shit anyway.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Other NES games that I bought, not really knowing what to expect.
Speaker 0: That turned out to be amazing.
Speaker 0: Alfred Chicken.
Speaker 1: No, I never liked Alfred Chicken.
Speaker 0: Why don't you like Albert Chicken?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I just didn't like it.
Speaker 0: Albert Chicken was a bet was like the original.
Speaker 0: I know it was the original puzzle platformer, but it was way more puzzle platforming than any other game I had played up to that point.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You needed some platforming skills to jump and dive and avoid getting killed.
Speaker 0: But really, a lot of the puzzle platform games that exist today owe a lot to Alfred Chicken.
Speaker 0: It's like you had to look at where you were and figure out, like, how the hell can I get through here?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it wasn't just, you know, run and jump with good timing.
Speaker 1: I will say it was.
Speaker 1: I think it was a better game than like the old Duke Nukem's.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The other thing with Alfred Chicken is that I don't know, was there?
Speaker 0: there was a Game Boy version, but the Game Boy, SNES, Super Game Boy, Amiga, Amiga CD 32.
Speaker 0: Oh, OK.
Speaker 0: And yes.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the NES and SNES versions, which came out at the same time, usually back in the day if that happened.
Speaker 1: Apparently the NES version was just a gimped version of the Game Boy one.
Speaker 0: Was it?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm reading Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: So why?
Speaker 0: But what I'm telling you is that the NES and SNES versions were basically completely different games.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like the same game and just like reduced graphics, reduced sound, which you saw a lot of the time, for example, with Yoshi's Cookie.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The NES and SNES versions of Yoshi's Cookie were almost the same game.
Speaker 0: Just one was looking like an NES game and one is looking like an SNES game.
Speaker 0: The NES and SNES Alfred Chickens are actually two different games.
Speaker 0: You might as well call them Alfred Chicken one, Alfred Chicken two.
Speaker 0: If you like one, you should play both.
Speaker 1: Well, according to Wikipedia, the NES version is essentially a watered down port of the Game Boy version.
Speaker 1: It features only five levels.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: So the Game Boy version is more than five levels?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: But it's the same five levels as the NES one?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So the NES one is the worst version ever made.
Speaker 0: But at least the NES one that has color and such that the Game Boy one doesn't.
Speaker 0: The NES one is the one.
Speaker 1: Super Game Boy one, too.
Speaker 0: Oh, OK.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot of info on the Wikipedia page.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to play that Game Boy one now.
Speaker 1: It was designed by Jason McGann.
Speaker 0: OK, what's he up to?
Speaker 1: There's.
Speaker 1: no he is not a notable person.
Speaker 1: OK, so I can't click on his name.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Alfred Chicken, a game that no one really remembers that actually has a lot going on.
Speaker 0: I mean, this game was good enough to basically be published at that time in the 16 bit era.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And all three of those systems coming out of basically nowhere.
Speaker 1: It's a feat that it was published legit.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like one of those crazy Bible games.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The publishers like played this game and said, wow, this is really fun.
Speaker 0: Well, some thought, yeah, they believe someone believe some of the money believe this could be like a new franchise.
Speaker 0: They marketed it like quite heavily.
Speaker 0: It's the only reason I even heard of it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It was in all the video game magazines with ads, even though the game magazines themselves mostly ignored it in their reviews.
Speaker 0: They took ads.
Speaker 1: I'll bet what it was.
Speaker 1: I remember Sunsoft being very good at picking the right games to port and good games to make.
Speaker 1: And Sunsoft probably was like, hey, this game on the Amiga or whatever is great.
Speaker 1: Let's get it on the Nintendos.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So let's hurry up with the rest of these here.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Even a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got a lot of them.
Speaker 0: So my friend had, you know, you go to a friend's house.
Speaker 0: They had a bunch of games.
Speaker 0: They always have weird ones that you didn't have.
Speaker 1: That's how I learned about Dr.
Speaker 1: Chaos.
Speaker 0: I was about to talk about Dr.
Speaker 0: Chaos.
Speaker 0: What really?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: My friends, they had this game called Dr.
Speaker 0: Chaos.
Speaker 0: You played it.
Speaker 0: And I was like, whoa, what the hell is.
Speaker 1: as my little brother and I said, Dr.
Speaker 1: Charles, Dr.
Speaker 0: Charles, this is a great game.
Speaker 0: It's really unique.
Speaker 0: You go.
Speaker 0: You're basically your crazy old uncle, Dr.
Speaker 0: Chaos.
Speaker 0: He needs you to watch his mansion.
Speaker 0: You get there.
Speaker 0: He's not there.
Speaker 0: It's filled with monsters and it has two games.
Speaker 0: This is a game where you walk around the mansion sort of doing a deja vu, trying to find stuff.
Speaker 0: And at the same time, we're trying to find these secret portals in the mansion to take you to the side scrolling levels where you have to fight the evil monsters.
Speaker 0: And when you beat all the side scrolling levels and get all the pieces to these machines and things, then I guess you win.
Speaker 0: I've never gotten very far at all.
Speaker 0: It's really hard to find the side scrolling levels, but even the mansion part and the exploring and like punching the walls to find secrets is really fun.
Speaker 1: As opposed to a mile on secret castle, you should try.
Speaker 0: You don't have to beat Dr.
Speaker 0: Chaos.
Speaker 0: Just like load it up in your NES emulator and poke around and you'll see like this is a game that there is no other game like that.
Speaker 1: In fact, I remember because I didn't play it until I was at my friend's house, but I'd always go to the video rental store and I'd see Dr.
Speaker 1: Chaos right next to that desert combat NES game that was basically advanced wars.
Speaker 1: And I remember standing looking at Dr.
Speaker 1: Chaos because there's this skull and this demon and all this blood.
Speaker 1: I'm like, that looks fun.
Speaker 1: But then the advanced one, I was like, ooh, military simulation.
Speaker 0: So a metal Marines, I think we've talked about metal Marines.
Speaker 1: We talked about metal Marines at packs.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I don't want to say too much about it other than I just want to bring it up again.
Speaker 1: Every level past the second one in metal Marine sucks ass.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: But the concept of metal Marines is the best.
Speaker 1: It's a great game.
Speaker 1: They just didn't execute on it beyond the console and there's the windows 3.1 version, but yeah, metal Marines.
Speaker 0: Don't forget metal.
Speaker 1: I have that laying around somewhere.
Speaker 0: Okay, now let's get real.
Speaker 0: The best game.
Speaker 0: I think this is probably, I might even say it might even be the best side scrolling platformer there.
Speaker 0: Oh, super Mario world.
Speaker 1: Legacy of the wizard.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Maybe a little bit under a super Mario world, but Wario two, one of the best games.
Speaker 0: People don't know this, right?
Speaker 0: But on the game boy, there was super Mario land.
Speaker 0: Then there was super Mario land to the six golden coins.
Speaker 0: The boss of which was Wario first appearance of Wario.
Speaker 0: It's me.
Speaker 0: Then there was a game on the game boy called super Mario land three Wario land and you played as Wario.
Speaker 0: Then there was a game Wario land to where you played as Wario and basically the super Mario land series.
Speaker 0: Once that boss of that second, you know, Mario game was Wario turned into Wario land and Wario land two is the best because what it does is it sort of has.
Speaker 0: this revolutionary thing of Wario is invincible.
Speaker 0: He wasn't invincible in Wario one that only defined his greed for coins.
Speaker 0: Wario land two, he's invincible.
Speaker 0: So it's all about trying to get through the level.
Speaker 0: We're finding all the secrets, beating it, you know, and beating a boss, but you can't die.
Speaker 0: All that can really happen to you is you can eat your ass kicked back and have to run through a spot again because you failed.
Speaker 0: It's like you fall in a pit.
Speaker 0: You don't die.
Speaker 0: You just have to go back.
Speaker 0: And a lot of times going back doesn't keep you from beating the level like annoying.
Speaker 0: It's like if you want to beat the level, it's really easy.
Speaker 0: But if you want to get all the treasures and unlock all the goodies, you have to be able to, like, you'll see these incredibly difficult, you know, secrecy filled parts of levels.
Speaker 1: There are lots of weird things to find an unlock in this game.
Speaker 0: And also when you've beat the game, it starts over and it has a sort of a Wario land plus mode where you suddenly see this, you know, the path you took to beat the game and you see all these other levels.
Speaker 0: you didn't go because you didn't find secret exits in previous levels.
Speaker 0: And there's five different endings as a ton of endings and different paths to take to ends and different.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So this game is tons of playable value.
Speaker 0: And it's not only can you beat all the levels, like, can you get the treasure in every level?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You see a lot of things today, like in Super Mario Brothers, we or whatever.
Speaker 0: It's like or well, there's the Mario Land, the 3D one, the game, the 3DS one or the DS one, the Mario one, the new Super Mario Brothers for the DS.
Speaker 0: And it's like get the big gold coin in every level.
Speaker 0: Wario Land is where that shit came from.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: This is where that game from.
Speaker 0: Can you get the treasure in every level, which involves not only finding the treasure chest, but beating the treasure chest in his little treasure chest game.
Speaker 0: OK, also, let's just do this quickly.
Speaker 0: Mario Kart Super Circuit, the Game Boy Advance Mario Kart.
Speaker 0: I bring this up all the time.
Speaker 0: It is the least remembered, least cared about Mario Kart.
Speaker 1: It's also the best Mario Kart because you want a game that is primarily skill.
Speaker 0: There is still randomness of getting items.
Speaker 0: But in Super Mario Kart, Super Circuit for the GBA, if you race perfectly, you do you drift every corner, you go at max speed, you never hit a bump, you never go off the road, you never do anything wrong.
Speaker 0: You drive perfectly.
Speaker 0: Even the blue shell will hover behind your ass without hitting you as soon as you fuck up a little bit.
Speaker 0: Boom.
Speaker 0: It goes faster than you and hits you.
Speaker 0: But if you drive perfectly in this Mario Kart, even the blue shell or the red shell will just stay behind you waiting for you to fuck up.
Speaker 0: And if you go long enough without fucking up, the shell will give up and fall off the screen.
Speaker 0: And then you can get red shells and shoot them backwards at your opponents and they're and they're fucked.
Speaker 0: So first place means first place.
Speaker 0: It's mostly a racing game as opposed to the other ones.
Speaker 0: And it has almost all the tracks from the original Mario Kart, as well as lots of additional tracks only in this one.
Speaker 1: It is that good multiplayer.
Speaker 1: I mean, it was one of the first games to really use those GBA link cables.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, I mean, it was pretty much the first game came out.
Speaker 1: I remember hanging out at Luke's fucking apartment with a bunch of GBA is playing.
Speaker 0: They came out very close to the release of the Game Boy Advance and link cable and was like the thing was the first game to use the four way link cable.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, really good.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: Conquest of the Crystal Palace is an old NES game where you basically climb up a mountain fighting bad guys and it's kind of hard.
Speaker 0: You it sort of has some RPG elements to it.
Speaker 0: At the beginning, you can choose one of three orbs to get magical powers and it's sort of got this weird thing combining like it's very Japanese.
Speaker 0: It combines like historical things because it seems like, you know, you're in ancient times fighting ancient monsters and then like some girl gives a news report and sells you items and shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That's all modern.
Speaker 0: It's pretty hard, but not Silver Surfer hard.
Speaker 0: It's like on that border.
Speaker 1: I rented it and never really got very far.
Speaker 0: I borrowed it from someone and played it a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: The thing that makes this game really great are the bosses, which are like these gigantic NES bosses that you have to fight.
Speaker 0: Really cool and lots of fun items to get.
Speaker 0: Legacy of the Wizard already mentioned your whole family to go dungeon crawling to find the secret.
Speaker 0: It really the thing that's great about Legacy of the Wizard is just how it is really big dungeon.
Speaker 0: And it really feels like sort of epic and mysterious and you know, what kind of crazy shit is going on down there.
Speaker 0: And you get lots of creepy feels going down.
Speaker 1: And it's also a really complex game for its time.
Speaker 0: It's not actually that complex.
Speaker 0: If you read a fact about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it is a kid.
Speaker 1: This game, you've got all these characters with all these different power.
Speaker 0: play this game without reading any facts.
Speaker 0: Read the instruction manual for this game.
Speaker 1: Six or seven different characters, each with completely unique power.
Speaker 0: I think there's actually only five characters you can play as I think grandma and grandpa are just like the shop and the so.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: One of them is the shop and one or the inventory and one of them is the password.
Speaker 0: But you can play as the dad, the mom, the sister, the brother or the pet.
Speaker 0: And the pet is the most interesting because he's invincible monsters.
Speaker 0: Well, he's not invincible, but monsters don't hurt him.
Speaker 0: So you basically you take the pet and you explore the dungeon and make a map.
Speaker 0: Then you figure out, OK, I can only go in there if I have the dad who can break rocks and I can only go in there with the daughter who can jump high and I can only go there with the.
Speaker 0: you know, the girl.
Speaker 0: I guess I think the mom has the magic and the you know, and then you need the main, you know, the son who can use the magic sword to beat the big dragon once you get the big sort.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And you have to figure all this out.
Speaker 0: It's pretty great.
Speaker 1: I would say it has a lot of the elements of an early almost Metroidvania.
Speaker 1: Yeah, definitely before that was a thing.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, Metroid existed.
Speaker 1: But this has the leveling up, getting items more.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot of leveling up, but there is getting items.
Speaker 1: This is between Castlevania, Metroidvania, like it's edging in that direction.
Speaker 0: It's more like it's like roguelike in a little bit in there, too, right?
Speaker 0: Except it's not procedural.
Speaker 1: You know what I would say?
Speaker 1: It's a game.
Speaker 1: If nothing else, play it.
Speaker 1: And then look at what year it was made.
Speaker 1: It was just really ahead of its time for what it was.
Speaker 0: Also, Faxanadoodoo.
Speaker 1: I hated that game.
Speaker 0: You hated Faxanadoodoo?
Speaker 0: I love Faxanadoodoo.
Speaker 1: I just didn't enjoy it.
Speaker 0: It's Fazanadoodoo or whatever you want to pronounce it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's basically you're this one dude going on this sort of quest fighting evil trolls.
Speaker 1: I held it and Astyanax like together in my head.
Speaker 0: Astyanax is not as good.
Speaker 1: I never like Faxanadoodoo.
Speaker 1: I also never liked the.
Speaker 1: I think there was the game that looked like Zelda 2, but you were Greek.
Speaker 1: Battle of Olympus.
Speaker 0: Oh, that.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 1: I hated that game, too.
Speaker 0: How about Time Lord?
Speaker 0: Time Lord or Time Lords?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Time Lord video game for the NES.
Speaker 0: That's the up Time Lord for NES.
Speaker 1: Oh, I rented this game once or twice.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: How about that?
Speaker 1: Never particularly liked it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the one game, the last game on my list here that I really want to put some time to talk about is Dynamite Hetty.
Speaker 0: Nobody who knows Dynamite Hetty.
Speaker 1: That's the game with the evil cat bear thing.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Trouble Bruin.
Speaker 0: Oh, shit.
Speaker 0: This game.
Speaker 0: Get it.
Speaker 0: Bruin is a game made by Treasure, but people mostly remember Treasure for like Gunstar Heroes and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: People don't think about Dynamite Hetty when they think about Treasure and the games they've made.
Speaker 0: But Dynamite Hetty is really crazy good.
Speaker 0: You're this guy with a head and sort of like Kirby, you shoot while he shoots his head at things.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And he can use this head to shoot it at bad guys.
Speaker 0: He can shoot it at things to grab onto them by biting and then sort of jump up sort of like a grappling hook, almost mechanic.
Speaker 0: He can jump, but he can't jump on bad guys to kill them.
Speaker 0: But he can also shoot to change his head into different things like Kirby's, like a hammer, which just can smash certain things.
Speaker 0: or you get the micro head.
Speaker 0: You know, all these heads give different powers.
Speaker 0: And so you're navigating these levels, trying to, you know, get into different places, different paths through the levels.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, each level, even though it's a platforming game, the levels are so crazy different that like each one is almost a different game into itself.
Speaker 0: There's even like shmup levels where he's got the airplane head.
Speaker 0: There's, you know, sort of like his levels like the floor tilts back and forth.
Speaker 0: So it ends up being almost like a platforming beat him up in a ways, you know, because you can only move in a small area while going sideways.
Speaker 1: The game just had a really nice sense of, yeah, weird.
Speaker 1: Like it was so varied and weird and every level was just so different.
Speaker 0: And the styling and the music is just so incredible.
Speaker 0: And the whole, you know, the story like this is huge, crazy cinematic opening where you fight a robot who's ransacking the town and there's mini game levels.
Speaker 0: And it's, you know, each, every boss is crazy unique.
Speaker 0: Usually the bosses come down to hit the weak spot, but like for example, one level boss, you're fighting trouble brewing and he's basically has his head.
Speaker 0: Oh, the first time you fight him, which is pretty much the beginning of the game, he's just there standing with his full body and you kill him and his head flies off.
Speaker 0: And every other time you see him, his head is attached to something else.
Speaker 0: So you see him later and his head is attached to this ball, which is a crazy robot arm, which has a hand at the end, the hand grabs you and basically he drags you behind stage.
Speaker 0: And this is the crazy thing about this game.
Speaker 0: is it's sort of like, you know, portal has it sort of, you go behind the wall thing.
Speaker 0: This game has that same thing.
Speaker 0: where it's like the whole game is like on a puppet show stage and you're a puppet and everyone's a puppet and things go, you can see like behind the stage all the time.
Speaker 0: And like if you die, I think the deaths, the game over screen is like you like getting kicked out of the theater, like through the back, like the stage exit door or something.
Speaker 1: I never beat the game.
Speaker 0: I've never beaten it, but I've gotten very, very far into it.
Speaker 0: I can still get very far into it.
Speaker 0: Uh, you know, I've used a cheat code to get to the ending boss, which is really hard.
Speaker 0: I can't even beat it.
Speaker 0: Um, but yeah, dynamite heady.
Speaker 0: No one talks about this game, but it is, I think incredible.
Speaker 0: Like it's as good as say Kirby's adventure, uh, in my book, especially aesthetically, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, the platforming parts are still really good even though they're not the best, but the aesthetic aspects of this game are like way above even something like super Mario world, right?
Speaker 0: It's, it's pretty incredible.
Speaker 0: So there you go.
Speaker 0: There are games that I like that no one talks about or cares about or whatever.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to you DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, geek nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: SciTech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative comments attribution.
Speaker 0: 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: Hey, it's when it's not Wednesday.