Speaker 1: It's Monday August 12th 2013.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: Scott and Google glass.
Speaker 1: Let's do this in front of a live studio audience.
Speaker 1: We've got some friends over in the other room probably listening to a shout into our microphones with the door open.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, that's how we roll here.
Speaker 1: So while we were at the beach Wildwood and I got to say I've been going to Wildwood, New Jersey, which used to have a pretty great arcade culture.
Speaker 1: In fact, I think we've talked about this on old geek nights.
Speaker 1: There used to be DDR machines up and down the boardwalk.
Speaker 1: We would literally spend the morning at the beach and spend the entire evening playing games in arcades.
Speaker 1: I think I must have dumped hundreds of dollars over the years total in all these things police 9-1-1 DDR mostly DDR sometimes air hockey and Yeah as of last year there are exactly zero DDR machines on the boardwalk.
Speaker 1: In fact, the majority of the arcade don't even have a pump machine anymore.
Speaker 1: I know they don't even have in the groove machines.
Speaker 0: They don't have.
Speaker 0: the only game I saw that was like a real game was that one time crisis 3 machine that was for sale.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the arcade was trying to sell it.
Speaker 0: I guess there was a Ms.
Speaker 0: Pac-man I guess.
Speaker 1: Yeah that Ms.
Speaker 1: Pac-man didn't work.
Speaker 1: I checked it out.
Speaker 1: Oh There's also that Kind of all the really stylish looking Pac-man versus game.
Speaker 1: That's actually a shit game.
Speaker 0: Oh Pac-man battle royale.
Speaker 1: I feel like the arcade that bought.
Speaker 1: that feels really dumb about buying.
Speaker 0: No, they probably make a bunch of money on it.
Speaker 1: Oh, why didn't see anyone playing it?
Speaker 0: We were there for a minute.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone is playing.
Speaker 0: the other the Pac-man with a million the air hockey Pac-man with a million pucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, two little kids were playing that.
Speaker 0: Oh, how family was playing it.
Speaker 0: Yeah that game not so great No, but it's good on paper.
Speaker 1: It's just so sad.
Speaker 0: I like Pac-man and I like air hockey, but that Pac-man game is butt.
Speaker 1: Yep, like the buttest of butt.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But yeah arcades are dead at least in the US.
Speaker 1: but we can at least say one thing we went to our arcades in Australia and They were about at the level of the few remaining arcades in the US that aren't butt.
Speaker 1: Maybe slightly better because they had Mario Kart, but it doesn't count for much because the Mario Kart arcade machine is actually pretty butt.
Speaker 0: Yeah Arcades are pretty.
Speaker 0: I mean the saddest thing about the arcades is really the mobile iPhone game arcade versions.
Speaker 0: the temple run arcade machine.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Arcade machine it's like that.
Speaker 1: at least there wasn't an Angry Birds arcade machine Especially because you look at this thing and it's clearly just one of those TV touch screens and an actual Regular old computer with a case around it and a dollar thing connected to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably connected into a serial port in the back of said computer.
Speaker 0: It's really just a phone with a giant touchscreen and a coin slot.
Speaker 1: I might make some money I'll get some ooh, yes, and I'll just put those in arcades.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I have another problem in my life.
Speaker 1: I have I got a Nexus S Phone and it's pretty much the iPhone is pretty good.
Speaker 1: But I still think the Nexus S has the best physical form factor of any phone.
Speaker 0: I think the Nokia Lumia the smaller one has the best form factor of any phone because it's basically it's like an iPod nano Construction true true and it has the best camera.
Speaker 0: Also, that's you know, just fact.
Speaker 1: but I got a problem that I'm on Sprint CDMA 4g but it's ymax 4g.
Speaker 1: my phone does not support Switching to LTE.
Speaker 1: sprint has been switching for a long time and has not switched yet not completely.
Speaker 1: Basically there will be a time when my 4g will stop working.
Speaker 0: that is true.
Speaker 1: and of the phones I can buy I mean, I own a Nexus 4 for world travel and I got to tell you motherfuckers who like your big phones.
Speaker 1: I Cannot sit down with that thing in my pocket.
Speaker 0: Yeah, someone finally wrote an article that was like, you know Look all these big phones.
Speaker 0: What the fuck.
Speaker 0: there's basically no small phones that are also top-of-the-line phones.
Speaker 0: All the small phones are basically gimped in terms of you know Having the fastest CPUs are the best GPUs are the best screens or whatever?
Speaker 1: No, it seems like that the iPhone consumer sentiment driving it.
Speaker 0: but it's weird because I think I think it's more marketing shaping consumer demand.
Speaker 1: Oh, you mean like with SUVs?
Speaker 0: Yes Yeah.
Speaker 1: But the people who say they prefer big phones and aren't just being facetious to troll me Seem to say one of two things.
Speaker 1: they either say I want a big screen because I play games and watch movies on it and use it as my primary computer when I'm traveling or They say Effectively I have bad eyesight and I can't see anything on tiny phones.
Speaker 0: go to the eye doctor If bad eyesight is hindering you in some way.
Speaker 0: The solution is never to change your technology like increasing the resolution on your screen to a resolution That is lower than the you know The native resolution of the display or any you know and not.
Speaker 0: that is never the right answer.
Speaker 0: The right answer is always go to the eye doctor.
Speaker 0: Right if you are modifying your technological purchasing decisions because of your visual Disability and it's not.
Speaker 0: I mean there could be a point at which you are like You know seriously visually impaired like you're blind or near blind and you need like the magnifying A large not a large majority but a large or you need some Braille shit, right?
Speaker 1: I think a surprising number of Americans for whatever reason have Significant uncorrected vision problems.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you have you know Like there was a guy at RIT who lived on my floor in freshman year and he was almost blind, right?
Speaker 0: You basically had a giant magnifying thing in front of his monitor, right that dude needs technology to help him with his almost blindness.
Speaker 0: But if you you know live your daily life and you're not almost blind You don't have a white stick dragging on the ground, right?
Speaker 0: The eye doctor is your answer and not the best vibe.
Speaker 1: Well, I do know a lot of people who have Moderate myopia or light myopia but not enough to actually prevent them from living.
Speaker 1: so as a result they tend to not get glasses when they're young and get used to the world being just kind of fuzzy.
Speaker 1: and I think that's a problem because myopia is pretty common.
Speaker 1: And I guess I was lucky in the sense that when I was young I had myopia but it was just bad enough.
Speaker 1: So, you know wasn't?
Speaker 1: I could still live my life.
Speaker 1: But when I first put on a pair of glasses and I could see it was like seeing through the matrix I was like, oh fuck and I basically wouldn't take those glasses off again Even though the doctor only told me to wear him like occasionally.
Speaker 1: I was like fuck that I want to see the guys get glasses or contacts or LASIK Get something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's why I do whatever the eye doctor tells you to.
Speaker 0: All right, so news news One of the smartest news.
Speaker 0: one of the smartest news there is okay John Carmack Our guy.
Speaker 0: he was at the quake con and doing.
Speaker 0: he was talking about pretty much everything.
Speaker 0: But then there was.
Speaker 0: he announced he's going over to oculus the people with the goggles and he's gonna be the CTO over there.
Speaker 0: I think he's still doing stuff at it.
Speaker 0: I don't think he's quitting there.
Speaker 1: I gotta say the oculus rift isn't really there yet, but in terms of 90s style immersive VR coming back.
Speaker 1: It is the furthest along of any consumer thing I have ever.
Speaker 0: basically, you know big he's winding down his little, you know space Thingy his armadillo air whatever his rockets.
Speaker 0: Yeah all the time.
Speaker 0: He was spending on the Rockets.
Speaker 0: He's now gonna spend on the you know, the Oculus rift.
Speaker 1: I actually suddenly have a lot more interest in the oculus.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the oculus.
Speaker 0: basically I'm still poo-pooing it But there are so many people going in on it and giving it the thumbs up and like lifting it up.
Speaker 0: It's like well Maybe right.
Speaker 0: It's like I'm still poo-pooing it.
Speaker 1: but Well, I can say one thing and I did this a couple of times as an experiment.
Speaker 1: But what I did back when we were playing cs16 is I set my monitor up so it was basically like right in front of my eyeball like if I couldn't really see anything but the monitor.
Speaker 1: and Then what I did and I have myopia so my eye focus is really close like it's one kind of nice side effect.
Speaker 1: So it kind of worked.
Speaker 1: and then what I did is I put on an eyepatch on one of my eyes Mm-hmm, and you know what that did.
Speaker 1: it made everything feel so crazy real in 3d that it was almost disorienting to play counter-strike.
Speaker 0: Well, I remember the first time I played descent one of the first 3d games I played on an old DOS PC back in the 90s like 97 or 98 whatever.
Speaker 0: I was getting dizzy because that's a full.
Speaker 0: that's a real 3d game.
Speaker 0: Like you can go in every facing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not disoriented like dizzy disoriented like it was too real and I would flinch when thing like bumped into things.
Speaker 0: Oh that could happen.
Speaker 0: I could see that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it's like.
Speaker 0: yeah, and the oculus is like full HD Right, and I'm pretty sure it's 3d like, you know a movie is you never put it on in a con.
Speaker 0: I think I put it on at PAX for a few minutes.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's 3d right like a movie which is.
Speaker 0: you know that is an advancement right.
Speaker 0: those the the Basically the virtual realities of the 90s were just TV screens and your eyeballs that weren't HD and weren't 3d.
Speaker 0: So it is a significant improvement, but it's still this Gigantic thing you put on your face.
Speaker 0: fine with that It's too big.
Speaker 1: Why is it too big?
Speaker 1: but smaller than my monitor maybe.
Speaker 0: But I mean you're wearing I mean Google Glass.
Speaker 0: was?
Speaker 0: he weighs nothing on your face But Google Glass you were outside if you were oculus rift outside your moron.
Speaker 1: Obviously though Imagine this I could sit down with just a TV tray on an airplane or a train.
Speaker 0: Yeah on an airplane or in the park.
Speaker 0: You need power for I think needs to be plugged in though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not sure about that.
Speaker 1: It's not yeah what you think it's gonna just be powered from USB.
Speaker 0: It could have a big-ass battery that you're wearing on your face.
Speaker 0: Not really Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm still just.
Speaker 0: I mean I've seen this before.
Speaker 0: I think this can get to a point to where like if they shave like a couple inches off the front You know and a couple pounds off of it, then it'd be like holy shit, but it's not.
Speaker 1: I think it's there.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: it's only there right now.
Speaker 1: It's at the level that the hardcore like like the people who bought the super nice TVs Before they were cheaper and a little bit better Like the.
Speaker 1: the people are on the edge of that curve either because they really care about their PC gaming or they really care about These VR sort of experiences.
Speaker 1: It's there for them.
Speaker 1: It's already there.
Speaker 1: It's only not there for the kind of super mass market.
Speaker 1: for the reasons who said I have been considering getting one Go for it.
Speaker 0: The other thing about the oculus is that if you look at the games that are hot right now It's like sure.
Speaker 0: This is great for some Counter-Strike.
Speaker 1: I see we're getting at.
Speaker 0: what does this do for you in your League of Legends?
Speaker 0: It's nothing nothing.
Speaker 0: It does but nothing right?
Speaker 0: So I think either a there aren't gonna be the games that are with the first-person perspective oculus or be.
Speaker 0: There will suddenly be a bunch of people making more first-person perspective games to support the two things.
Speaker 1: one if you Remade tie fighter, of course where you could look around the cockpit.
Speaker 0: Are you kidding me?
Speaker 1: Yeah All my money just take it.
Speaker 1: But to with a MOBA or a 2d game.
Speaker 1: a clever person could use it.
Speaker 1: Imagine this you put oculus on right.
Speaker 1: it tracks your head movements.
Speaker 0: They already have things you can buy that are head trackers that aren't God.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah, but I'm saying having the goggles there basically means that you have an infinite canvas to put information and monitors and things around you spatially to where you look to the left and you've got like all the stats for the Game and you look to the right and you've got your map and you look to the middle and you've got your guy in the Fighting.
Speaker 1: you look up and you've got it.
Speaker 1: You could zoom in and out you could do cool stuff But I don't see these games doing those kinds of things Because the people who play these games seem to get off having one oculus Having one oculus rift can simulate having like ten monitors.
Speaker 1: Yes You can basically be like I want a monitor floating right here.
Speaker 1: at this angle.
Speaker 0: You can see all the judges doing everyday computing.
Speaker 0: You can see all your virtual desktops are basically Splayed out in different areas.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's Adam.
Speaker 1: That's a future.
Speaker 1: I sit down at my desk and there aren't any monitors.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the real future is I'm wearing Google Glass version 5.0.
Speaker 0: that I think here's the thing, right?
Speaker 0: I think we better to not have this oculus rift for the weight is on your head.
Speaker 0: I think it would be better to have it more like in Ghost in the Shell or when they sit down in that one room And the basically the eyeball things are attached to the wall or the floor and they just sort of lean into it more like
Speaker 1: But they can't move their head around.
Speaker 1: you lose that spatial dimension.
Speaker 0: They're not playing FPS is they're computing by looking into that.
Speaker 1: But they're right.
Speaker 1: the ghost in the shell gets into the idea that they're doing that for a different reason.
Speaker 1: they bring this up several times at least in standalone complex that they do that just because there's.
Speaker 1: they're Overloading data into the optic nerve because that area is just the highest resolution interface into a human that is relatively safe.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I think there's different cases for it.
Speaker 1: I think there's the the overlay view and then there's the immersion view and I think we will need dedicated hardware for that until we Have brain interfaces.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I guess I still think it would be nice to go to work and just sort of you know Sit comfortably in a thing where the thing is in my face.
Speaker 1: When we used to geek knives, you'd like lay backwards with your eyes closed, right?
Speaker 0: I just don't like the idea of the weight being on my head neck, right?
Speaker 1: Boom that I pull down and attached to my face but still tracks my movement.
Speaker 0: I could be cool.
Speaker 0: It would just be.
Speaker 0: sort of you know, that would be clumsy like having the freaking racing seat in your house.
Speaker 1: You know with the for the racing games For someone like us where this shit matters and is a central part of our life.
Speaker 1: I want the Darth Vader pod.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I just want to be in the Darth Vader pod.
Speaker 1: I pull my helmet down I stick my hand and the whole thing seals you in yeah, and I move everything.
Speaker 1: I'm just moving my arms and hands around and everything's haptic and visual and immersive, you know Darth Vader doesn't there?
Speaker 0: Not what you're describing though.
Speaker 1: he is moving his arms around I know but I'm saying I want the equivalent of that and I'd be fine With that.
Speaker 0: I'd be fine.
Speaker 0: Are you gonna put that in your tiny apartment?
Speaker 1: I would fill this room with it great and you'd get to the huge and it wouldn't matter if you're physically next to me anymore.
Speaker 1: You can sit in the other room already doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: I'm not physically next exactly.
Speaker 1: So I just run an excellent.
Speaker 0: I don't even come here.
Speaker 0: Let's just Skype for now on cuz Skype is shit audio quality.
Speaker 1: So very briefly I want to point out a couple little things.
Speaker 1: one The Department of Transportation in the US is actually doing something really cool to the federal DoT.
Speaker 1: yes in the US and I highly recommend all of you pay attention to this because this is gonna come sooner than you realize and Everyone who says privacy stuff shut up.
Speaker 1: I'm more as much as I care about the NSA stuff.
Speaker 1: This stuff is separate in the sense that we need this regardless of if we fix the NSA stuff.
Speaker 1: They want to standardize on the in the nation the way that cars communicate with each other and with the road reason point.
Speaker 1: imagine if all the cars on the road were constantly generating telemetry data and traffic data and Automatically updating a standard interface for GPS direction navigation things to reroute cars if there's a problem.
Speaker 1: So if there's an accident cars Immediately are rerouted to alternate roads.
Speaker 0: This is your favorite thing.
Speaker 0: fixed protocol for cars exactly exactly I I.
Speaker 1: yeah 39 equals 3. so the other news I like to talk about is that there's been a rash of dark mail or silent mail or Secure email services going down either because of secret government bullshit that they can't talk about and wall.
Speaker 1: I think these people should fight so far.
Speaker 1: I saw one so another one shut down.
Speaker 1: They didn't say if it was because of the gut because it's a rash.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I think there's gonna be more.
Speaker 1: I think what's going to see more spring up than shut down true, but the ones that spring up have to be Technologically secure not relying upon central servers doing one and mega has kept mega up.
Speaker 0: So there you go.
Speaker 1: I guess I bring this up only because those of you who are worried about privacy and all these issues These are little too little data points you can use to argue with other people as to why this NSA stuff is kind of toxic.
Speaker 1: because if the Government can tell someone to shut down something that has perfectly legitimate uses because someone might use it for nefarious purposes and simultaneously That person is not allowed to even talk about what happened and we don't even know if they fight it or not.
Speaker 1: I can't really fault the person for not fighting it because they're kind of.
Speaker 1: that's kind of like going up against the Stasi like yeah He's a guy who's fighting it.
Speaker 0: He just can't talk about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but how do you know if you thought it then?
Speaker 0: He's saying he fought it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something happened.
Speaker 0: I can't talk about but I'm fighting.
Speaker 1: And things of the day I'll let you guys know right now.
Speaker 1: you might have heard some clicking for the last few minutes.
Speaker 1: the The mixer the geek night's mixer might have just died.
Speaker 0: You don't hear any clicking right now.
Speaker 1: There's no more clicking.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so we have plugged directly into my fire studio interface for the time being and We'll see if the audio sounds different cuz I'm gonna have to master everything very differently now.
Speaker 1: And yeah, I have to buy a new mixer.
Speaker 0: We'll see what happens there.
Speaker 0: We should kickstart it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Okay, so thing of the day.
Speaker 0: We've been waiting a long time, but finally It's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: It's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: the English version of Hatsune Miku V3 English using Vocaloid 3 is now slated to be available for download on August 31st 2013.
Speaker 1: the I'm actually kind of excited about this.
Speaker 0: the bundle with vocal editor Pia Pro Studio vsti and Presonus studio one artist Pia Pro Edition and over 200 virtual instruments.
Speaker 0: Hopefully including the swan For immediate music production goes for 150 US dollars.
Speaker 0: that's basically zero for software like that for basically software that allow you to make all the musics.
Speaker 0: I don't know how to make the musics.
Speaker 0: I don't have the music skills.
Speaker 0: My music skills are very low.
Speaker 0: I mean, they're higher than you know zero but because I did a lot of musics when I was in elementary middle high schools But I haven't done any really since then unless you count like guitar here or DDR.
Speaker 0: So my music skills are pretty low.
Speaker 0: So I feel like if I bought it for 150 it would be sort of like up not using it for anything.
Speaker 0: What a waste of money that was.
Speaker 1: I could buy it, but I don't have a good project for it.
Speaker 1: I haven't written a long time and yes, I could transcribe Existing popular songs and do what everyone else is gonna do with it But I still feel like I should buy it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you know we could do.
Speaker 1: we could use it Cleverly in geek nights, maybe yeah, I'll make the new geek.
Speaker 0: that's theme song.
Speaker 0: Miku will sing it for us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll use it as we could use it to add a third host.
Speaker 0: But anyway, there's some demo videos here on YouTube.
Speaker 0: You can hear what it sounds like.
Speaker 1: You know we could use it for this.
Speaker 1: It sounds kind of dumb.
Speaker 1: we could have it every time we want to quote something from an article.
Speaker 1: Just have Miku sing it on the show instead.
Speaker 1: Mmm, that might be really annoying really quickly.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: But yeah Awesomeness times a million.
Speaker 1: All right, so this is a cool and creepy art installation.
Speaker 1: Someone took not one not two daddy three PP but a matrix of Three by I gotta expand this window to see how big it is three by five Teddy Ruxpin's 15 Teddy Ruxpin's and made an art installation where they just kind of say creepy stuff.
Speaker 0: Well, isn't he just a cassette player?
Speaker 0: So it's basically you're hanging a teddy bear shaped cassette player on the wall 15 of them and having them play.
Speaker 1: Teddy Ruxpin did more than just play tapes.
Speaker 1: Teddy Ruxpin on one of the audio channels had someone telling a story and on the other audio channel had command and control for moving his eyes moving his mouth or Making another accessory another guy you could get that would connect to him also move around and do stuff.
Speaker 0: So basically it was had stereo audio but a mono speaker and the right or the left would have the.
Speaker 0: yeah when I was what he was saying it would just play It over the one speaker and the other.
Speaker 1: if you played the other side It would play this kind of like buzzing noise.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the other channel would just sort of you know play data that would make him move.
Speaker 1: exactly I bring it up one cuz it's kind of cool and two people are really into like chip bending or all these sort of you know Cool Things.
Speaker 0: you wouldn't even need a cassette tape.
Speaker 0: you'd be better off with sticking an Arduino inside.
Speaker 1: that appears to be what they did here.
Speaker 0: Okay, and just controlling him directly without shitty cassette tape exactly and then playing one audio track on speakers nearby With an mp3 or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah I just I bring this up only because it's kind of a cool way to use an old technology and to Whether or not you know or care who Teddy Ruxpin is I think says a lot about what year you were born.
Speaker 0: I should do the same thing with fucking glow worms glow worm and Teddy Ruxpin together.
Speaker 1: You gotta get every glow worm.
Speaker 0: is my boy Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you and glow worm.
Speaker 0: I like glow worm.
Speaker 1: I never like glow worm.
Speaker 0: Oh, it was the best.
Speaker 1: I was never a fan of me.
Speaker 1: I might have been a fan of glow worm in my pre.
Speaker 0: I had this awesome toy where there was basically a board with all these holes in it and he had a pen and the pen had a glow worm on top and you would put The pen in the holes and even put in the right hole to glow him light up.
Speaker 1: So yeah, but also you could just put other cassettes and Teddy Ruxpin and he would just kind of play him But he wouldn't move wouldn't really move.
Speaker 1: No So yeah, yeah, that's all I got.
Speaker 0: He was just a cassette player.
Speaker 0: All right time for the meta.
Speaker 1: The book of the book is Stazzyland.
Speaker 1: I'm mostly done with it.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good pretty relevant NSA scary spy shit.
Speaker 0: Pax prime is real soon the end of the month.
Speaker 1: We are presenting on Monday at noon in the Wolfman theater.
Speaker 0: bad games Oh shit.
Speaker 0: That's the last day of packs.
Speaker 0: We're gonna enjoy a bunch of packs and then sort of on this last lazy day before the omega-thon finale We're gonna do a panel.
Speaker 1: sounds good.
Speaker 1: Watch our videos on the internet.
Speaker 1: We've already uploaded two videos from Pax Australia.
Speaker 1: several more are coming.
Speaker 1: follow us on YouTube my youtube channel Scott's YouTube channel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we have a lot of things on the internet and you should go look at them.
Speaker 0: if you've enjoyed this show.
Speaker 0: They are easy for you to find including one of them that is often forgotten our email newsletter Which has content that isn't really in other things.
Speaker 0: as I write a lot of stuff in there such as a Q&A That's easy where our Q&A section is gone.
Speaker 0: So if you want to ask us something and us to answer it That's really all in the newsletter now.
Speaker 0: So email us geek nights from a crew calm and then look for another newsletter.
Speaker 0: soon I'll mail one probably this month before Pax happens and you might be answered in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah Alright, that's the end of meta moment.
Speaker 1: So, uh Scott got Google Glass.
Speaker 1: I did I don't yet mostly because I Would really like to get the water.
Speaker 1: I can put prescription glasses in it.
Speaker 1: Yep, and that's not available yet.
Speaker 0: Well, you know actually it comes with the shields and shades is what they call it.
Speaker 0: It's basically sunglasses and also a clear glass that you can use just to protect your eyes if you say Biking and it in the night or something And they just sort of snap in in between the nose thingies.
Speaker 1: Yep No, I would with
Speaker 0: your pile of money You could get someone to make you prescription glasses that have like that little connector Thingy that would go in where the shades and shields go
Speaker 1: now that is true But that would be more money than I'm willing to pay especially already
Speaker 0: spending $1,500 in the gas.
Speaker 1: There are pretty good rumors that it'll be available more generally with the prescription glass option.
Speaker 1: Just kind of working.
Speaker 1: Not that too far out.
Speaker 0: Yeah The rumor that's going around now is that it'll be available by the end of the year for 300 bucks and you know what?
Speaker 0: That's kind of annoying because I just spent 1500.
Speaker 0: It's been five times that right?
Speaker 0: not the early adopter tax Yeah, but I mean that's a huge early adopter tax.
Speaker 0: It was like oh I paid five hundred and they paid three hundred or I even if I paid seven.
Speaker 1: I don't think the three hundred dollars is a legitimate rumor even if it is.
Speaker 0: I would be okay with it if because basically if you look at the updates that Google Glass gets they're all labeled as like.
Speaker 0: Let me look for a second.
Speaker 0: I'm loading it up.
Speaker 0: I'm currently running xe8, which is Explorer Edition 8, right?
Speaker 0: So if I continue to get Explorer Edition updates and everyone else gets sort of like less updates then it's like oh, okay I get it.
Speaker 0: I'm an Explorer Edition.
Speaker 0: I'm basically in the beta.
Speaker 0: I always get you know the sort of like.
Speaker 0: if you pay $100 to Apple to be a developer you keep getting more.
Speaker 0: you get.
Speaker 0: You know, you're using iOS whatever it is right now the new version, you know Because you have to make apps for it before it comes out.
Speaker 0: So you get the new version early when it's beta.
Speaker 0: that would be okay That would be yeah I spent more money on it and I basically ahead of the curve on my Google Glass.
Speaker 0: That is something I'm you know would not be upset if they even if they came out with $300 Google Glass.
Speaker 0: Also, you got to consider, you know, those shades and shields came in a separate thing.
Speaker 0: You know, they're gonna charge extra for that shit.
Speaker 0: I basically got the full set like a fully loaded car.
Speaker 0: I think if you buy Google Glass at retail all that other stuff is gonna be like add-ons that cost more money.
Speaker 0: the only thing that was actually in the package with the Google Glass was like the carrying case and a USB cable and Not much else, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's pretty much all you got.
Speaker 0: So everything else that you would want for Google Glass is gonna be probably separate monies.
Speaker 0: So if you know, even if it is 300 if they charge like 50 bucks each shades and shields, it's really 400 You know, so hmm plus they could charge a lot more for that.
Speaker 0: sunglasses are expensive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they could charge a hundred each for those who knows what they're gonna do.
Speaker 1: So it's hard to say what'll happen with that where I'm just gonna wait.
Speaker 1: I'm in no rush right now.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm in a rush, but I'm not in that much of a rush all right, so a lot of people now that I have the Google Glass and I've been using it for Week about yeah, I got it last Wednesday.
Speaker 0: I think yeah last Wednesday We can pretty much talk about.
Speaker 0: a lot of people Really don't understand what it currently is what it is capable of what it does because they haven't had it.
Speaker 0: They haven't really read tech articles that really describe it.
Speaker 0: Even those articles don't really, you know fully explain it.
Speaker 0: Like I say it's not an augmented reality overlay Obviously right, so here's what Google Glass is.
Speaker 0: so it weighs about as much as glasses, right?
Speaker 0: It's not really bothersome to wear It's.
Speaker 0: and what it does is it basically puts a little tiny screen up in the top right corner of your vision, right?
Speaker 0: it's in your peripheral vision not in your main vision and most of the time it's just off.
Speaker 0: and when it's off basically and your peripheral vision is a little blurry spot where the piece of Glasses and that's all it does and only when you turn it on Which I'm just did.
Speaker 1: I want so observations from someone around someone with the Google Glass.
Speaker 1: You will see Google Glass people periodically just jerking their net back like whoop.
Speaker 0: Yeah one way there are two ways to turn it on.
Speaker 0: one way to turn on is to jerk your neck backwards to look up at The sky and you can set the angle of sort of attack.
Speaker 0: So I said I left mine to the default of 30 degrees.
Speaker 0: I tried lowering it because it wasn't working but then that was too much.
Speaker 0: I put it at 20. that wasn't good.
Speaker 0: So I put it back at 30 and it's okay.
Speaker 0: And basically I tilt my head back 30 degrees and it turns on right and I can now see basically a clock.
Speaker 0: Great it's 629.
Speaker 1: that was worth it.
Speaker 1: Isn't it?
Speaker 1: That is 629.
Speaker 1: That is correct One.
Speaker 1: you have a very expensive pocket watch.
Speaker 0: It is a very one thing Google Glass is is a watch.
Speaker 0: if you have a watch and you have Google Glass You don't need it and it prevents you from a having anything on your wrist.
Speaker 1: instead You have something on your head, but you have a pebble on your wrist.
Speaker 0: I don't have it on now.
Speaker 0: The pebble watch is completely Unnecessary if you have Google Glass.
Speaker 1: I'll buy it from you for a dollar.
Speaker 0: No, they're mute now.
Speaker 1: 250.
Speaker 0: No, they're mutually exclusive devices, right and two.
Speaker 0: you don't need to take your phone out of your pocket.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 0: So it's a wristwatch.
Speaker 0: That's one thing.
Speaker 0: it is right and all this is a little tiny rectangular screen.
Speaker 0: So it's sort of like, you know how you have a second monitor on your computer.
Speaker 0: It's like having a second monitor on your phone, but it's just always there.
Speaker 0: You don't have to pull your phone out of your pocket and look away, right?
Speaker 0: It's just there.
Speaker 0: the other way to turn it on is to tap the side of it.
Speaker 0: The front right side of it is basically this touchscreen.
Speaker 0: It's not a touchscreen it's a touchpad and it's sort of a long stick shaped touchpad and it only really has Four different things you can do.
Speaker 0: you can swipe forward swipe back right and that basically scrolls left and right or up and down.
Speaker 0: You can swipe downwards which is sort of like quickly and that is sort of like dismiss Which is like pushing the home button on your iPhone, right?
Speaker 0: So like go back go back or turn off and then you can also tap it and that's like clicking like select that option That I just looked at.
Speaker 0: select that option.
Speaker 0: All right, that's that's what that's all about.
Speaker 0: There are some apps where you do a two finger scroll like the web browser.
Speaker 0: That's pretty rare though.
Speaker 0: It's mostly just the one finger swipe forward swipe back down and tap Okay, so what do you use it for right now?
Speaker 0: right now, this is the sad part of Google Glass.
Speaker 0: I can't use it for all that much because a Doesn't support Google Apps.
Speaker 0: It only supports regular Gmail.
Speaker 0: So if your Gmail account is at gmail.com then you're all set with Google Glass.
Speaker 0: You can use your Google+ and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: I have to turn the Google+ off.
Speaker 0: I don't have to but if I Google+ and hung out and did all that stuff with my Google Glass it would be hanging out with my at gmail.com account or Posting to my geek G+ on my at gmail.com account.
Speaker 1: I'm not Google.
Speaker 0: I don't have anyone in my circles on my at gmail.com account.
Speaker 1: Google, Google, Google, Moses.
Speaker 0: They always fuck the people using Google Apps.
Speaker 1: guys We who use Google Apps are your hardest core users.
Speaker 0: Yeah You should give the hardest core people to shit First not after everyone else or in the very least make it to where the apps.
Speaker 1: people Can enable that stuff if they want to.
Speaker 0: even if it's off by default There is an option in Google Apps to be like give me the beta shit.
Speaker 0: if someone checked that box.
Speaker 0: Give them the beta shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I know for a fact a lot of nerds like us use Google Apps because we have a real domain But we really the
Speaker 0: only reason I use it is because I want my email address to not be at gmail.com But
Speaker 1: I want to use
Speaker 0: all of Google services.
Speaker 0: I want every Gmail Google service there is possible.
Speaker 1: I've basically doubled down on Google.
Speaker 0: I use Google for pretty much everything I do on the internet except Storing and sharing pictures yep, but yes because I'm use an apps account, and I can't link that to my You know Google glass I can't do the hangouts And I can't do there.
Speaker 0: what the hangouts do is basically it's hangout and you can even do a video hangout where they see What you see right and you can do an audio hangout where you.
Speaker 0: this is a microphone.
Speaker 0: when you talk it hears you And you can I guess do it.
Speaker 0: Maybe a text hangout?
Speaker 0: I'm not sure if it does text to speech to text for a text hangout, but yeah You can hang out with it if you have that enabled and you can share things to g+ with it.
Speaker 1: so one thing I notice You seem to be taking a lot of candid photographs that you wouldn't have otherwise taken because you always just kind of have it on.
Speaker 0: yeah, that is the one thing that I really do with it a lot is because it's not hooked up to my g+ and Because I turned off the Twitter app.
Speaker 0: even because the Twitter app is really annoying.
Speaker 0: It keeps showing you all these tweets, and it seemed to have randomly selected like four people.
Speaker 0: I was following and showed me all their tweets all the time and kept even beeping and saying hey tweet someone tweeted But it didn't show me all my tweets It just chose some people.
Speaker 0: and I'm like why did you choose those people and stop bothering me with these tweets?
Speaker 0: I just want to be able to tweet.
Speaker 0: I don't want to see tweets in my Google Glass.
Speaker 0: That's annoying as hell.
Speaker 0: So I turned off Twitter.
Speaker 0: So what I did is it made a tumblr because it also works with tumblr.
Speaker 0: So I made a tumblr just for Google Glass and I said I will share all the things From my glass to this tumblr.
Speaker 0: now You could make that another tweet, and then I used ifttt to make the tumblr Tumblr auto tweets on its own.
Speaker 0: Oh, well I used ifttt.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll go back.
Speaker 1: You can just do it in tumblr.
Speaker 0: I'll just turn that off and do it in time.
Speaker 1: if you notice how every morning at the exact same time There's I make a single tweet.
Speaker 1: That is just whatever.
Speaker 0: I thought you might have been using ifttt.
Speaker 1: Nope I actually don't have an account on ifttt anymore because once they got rid of the other direction interface for Twitter Yeah, that was the most useful thing they had.
Speaker 1: all I used I have.
Speaker 0: that was Twitter's fault for removing that was.
Speaker 1: I would take everything anyone ever tweeted at me And if it had a link in it, I made myself a feed of those links in delicious Yep, and that was super useful.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so yeah taking photos.
Speaker 0: It is a camera obviously Google Glass right and there's two ways to take photos.
Speaker 0: is you can when you turn it on You can say okay glass and that brings up the voice activated menu, which works great And that's good if you're carrying stuff.
Speaker 0: but there's also the button you can press.
Speaker 0: there's a button on top of it and you press the button.
Speaker 0: it takes a photo.
Speaker 0: if You hold the button it takes a video and I just use the button a lot and You don't have to take your phone out of your pocket, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz think about if you see something and it's like for example I was walking down the street and those a Maserati.
Speaker 0: I'd take my phone out of my pocket aim it at the thing by.
Speaker 0: that time is gone, right?
Speaker 0: But instead I guys go.
Speaker 0: boop got it.
Speaker 0: So even though the pictures are kind of shitty you can get a lot of pictures and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: That you can't you wouldn't normally get just because the camera is always out.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got this great picture of me looking really sad playing Hanabi at the show.
Speaker 0: That was a sad game of.
Speaker 0: Hanabi was the saddest.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I tend to you know, I'm like, hey, this is kind of.
Speaker 0: I'll just take pictures of pretty much every sort of moderately interesting you know.
Speaker 0: moment and Tumble them into this tumbler and see what that's all about.
Speaker 0: the way the videos work is you?
Speaker 0: basically if you tell it to take a video it starts taking a video and Then it goes for 10 seconds, then it stops and then you can send the video can't?
Speaker 0: there's no YouTube at all Which is annoying.
Speaker 0: it only goes to like G plus and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: But if you tell it to if you tap it while it's videoing the video will.
Speaker 0: the video limit will be removed and it'll video Forever until you stop it or the battery runs out.
Speaker 0: The battery has been lasting pretty good.
Speaker 0: I'm basically charging it the same times that I would charge my phone, you know when I'm at work I don't put it on.
Speaker 0: I'm not sitting with my at my desk wearing it.
Speaker 0: That's pointless, right?
Speaker 1: See I plan to wear it all the time because I wear glasses.
Speaker 0: I wear pretty much when I get up from my desk or when I'm walking around town or you know Pretty much all those times but I don't wear it in the shower.
Speaker 0: or You know when I'm sitting at my desk and there's a computer in front of me There's no point in wearing the Google Glass with its current functionality.
Speaker 0: There could be Functionality for it that would enhance your sitting at the computer experience, but none of that exists.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll make some.
Speaker 1: we need or we need.
Speaker 1: you know, we've always whenever a thing came out We're like, oh we should write some apps.
Speaker 1: We need to be the ones right glass apps because what I see people I'm gonna be writing some soon.
Speaker 1: what I see people working On or saying they want now is all bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know what to do for glass.
Speaker 1: I've been thinking about this for most of my life exactly.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, so You know, I only wear it like.
Speaker 0: I don't wear it sitting at my desk.
Speaker 0: So it's charging.
Speaker 0: so it you know between you know, the morning and the afternoon.
Speaker 0: It's like it doesn't really die, but the battery does not last long.
Speaker 0: if you heavily use it Like I'm sure it packs it's gonna die.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna make it to the Micro USB, right?
Speaker 0: It's mmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah micro USB the same as the Kindle.
Speaker 1: Could you just wear an energy around your neck and have it plugged in?
Speaker 0: You thought you could put an energy in your pocket and have a cable going all the way up to the side of your head.
Speaker 0: And yes, that would.
Speaker 0: that will I will.
Speaker 1: I think one of the first things I'll do when I get it is try to rig Something like that up.
Speaker 1: that isn't annoying.
Speaker 0: if you just get a long Micro USB cable put the energy in your pocket and if the cables long enough now if I just know no that wouldn't work.
Speaker 1: If you just did that what?
Speaker 1: where is the?
Speaker 0: the cable would be no more annoying than a headphone cable that goes to your pocket Your phone with your pocket.
Speaker 1: would it stick out the bottom of glass or the side?
Speaker 1: Let me look because if it sticks out the side There's no good because it would put it sticks out the bottom right here.
Speaker 0: So basically it would be like having a one headphone cable.
Speaker 0: Just go past your ear, right?
Speaker 1: It's your pocket cuz a lot of people make the mistake of plugging USB cables into things where there will be.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no go straight into the bottom.
Speaker 0: so it's all good in that respect Let's see.
Speaker 0: What else is there to say about glass?
Speaker 0: Oh, so some of the thing the apps that exists for it, right?
Speaker 0: So you can do.
Speaker 0: you can get Google now on it and the Google now.
Speaker 0: it works for me, right?
Speaker 0: But the problem is that again It's using this other Google accounts.
Speaker 0: the Google now doesn't have enough information about me to really do it Now is like the best, right?
Speaker 0: Basically you would love it because you're basically your Google but your Google now is attached to your account.
Speaker 0: Yeah But basically it's your Google now, so it does all that stuff.
Speaker 0: Mostly what the Google now does for me is weather.
Speaker 0: it gives me the weather and it gives me.
Speaker 0: it always tells me what restaurants are nearby so I can just be like Boop and there's the nearby restaurants with their ratings and I can just call them right.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling if I have glass I'll use now a lot more because I only use now when I pull out my phone And think I'm gonna look at my phone.
Speaker 0: Google now is basically incredible.
Speaker 0: the Google glass.
Speaker 0: I just don't have it really Using its full potential because it doesn't have enough data about me because it's using the wrong Gmail account.
Speaker 0: The other real thing that people don't understand about Google glass Is that other than being a wristwatch pebble watch replacement in that you?
Speaker 0: notifications come to your face and you don't take your phone out of your pocket and it's a you can see the time without taking Your phone in your pocket is?
Speaker 0: it is also a Bluetooth headset on crack.
Speaker 1: It's got that bone microphone.
Speaker 0: Well, so the bone microphone is Interesting because it's kind of incredible how there's nothing in your ear, but you can hear this noise as it makes But it can really only do beeps and bloops.
Speaker 0: It's really shitty at doing voice or music.
Speaker 0: basically awful at doing voice or music.
Speaker 0: I tried to make a phone call with it.
Speaker 0: It's like Right.
Speaker 0: I mean you could I could tell what they were saying, but no you use.
Speaker 0: don't use it for phone calls But it is a Bluetooth headset.
Speaker 0: So someone calls you you see who's calling you in your eyeball, right?
Speaker 0: You tab to pick up then you just talk because the mic has a microphone in it and it has the bone speaker, right?
Speaker 0: So there you go, right?
Speaker 0: It's it's.
Speaker 0: it can even do video calls and and all kinds of you know.
Speaker 0: So you see that guy walking around with a Bluetooth headset?
Speaker 0: You don't really see that guy anymore, but Google glass is that it's pretty much the best one there is on earth.
Speaker 1: Oh So the other thing that you haven't pointed out because you have an iPhone you don't have access to everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's true, right?
Speaker 0: So there are some things that Google glass does that I can't do because I have an iPhone.
Speaker 1: for example Isn't it GPS and accelerometer data?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: You might be able to.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about accelerometer data.
Speaker 1: That's what I read when I was reading the GPS.
Speaker 0: in the menu.
Speaker 0: It says like get directions and then whenever I choose that let me actually choose it right now.
Speaker 0: Okay I Get direction, so I chose get directions.
Speaker 0: Directions not available.
Speaker 0: connect to my glass for Android for GPS service.
Speaker 0: So basically if an Android phone you run this my glass app on your Android phone right the Google Glass connects to it.
Speaker 0: the Android phone does all the GPS work and Sends the data of what to tell you to the glass.
Speaker 0: and the glass tells you, you know, turn left turn right?
Speaker 0: Whatever, so, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it works great.
Speaker 0: I just can't use it because I have an iPhone and I don't have an Android phone.
Speaker 1: doesn't the glass also have to tether via Wi-Fi?
Speaker 0: Okay so Google glass has Wi-Fi in it and it will always use Wi-Fi if it can find a Wi-Fi.
Speaker 0: and the way you add Wi-Fi is to it is pretty clever.
Speaker 1: It'll
Speaker 0: always try to use an open Wi-Fi if it can right But if it can't then what you do is you go to the my glass app and which works on mobile or the website basically right and you type in the Wi-Fi credentials and then it shows a QR code and you look at it and It sends the Wi-Fi credentials into the Google Glass via QR code and then the Google Glass will now try to connect to that Wi-Fi.
Speaker 0: So it's on Wi-Fi right now in your house.
Speaker 0: So it really it is a standalone device.
Speaker 0: It gets its internet from Wi-Fi wherever you are.
Speaker 0: But you really need to have a phone to go with it because otherwise the Bluetooth headset part of it is useless Obviously right for making calls and doing all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: and B You want to tether it to your phone so that you can have data anywhere.
Speaker 0: Otherwise Having it only do its thing when there's Wi-Fi nearby.
Speaker 0: It's rarely gonna do its thing.
Speaker 0: It'll basically be turned into a useless wristwatch.
Speaker 1: if you want to try out the direction sometimes just borrow my Nexus 4.
Speaker 1: I mean the GPS data works even without a data connection.
Speaker 0: install the my glass app on there.
Speaker 1: I will.
Speaker 0: okay What else?
Speaker 0: Oh you add contacts to it So you can add basically 10 contacts to speed dial and those are like you.
Speaker 0: like if you called me I would see your face in the thingy because I added you is the one of the 10 speed dial people.
Speaker 0: alright See what other things are on here.
Speaker 0: There's an Evernote integration, which I haven't used because I don't know.
Speaker 0: cuz I don't use Evernote There's a New York Times thing which supposedly will tell you like when you know, there's a news alert It'll be like, oh my god crazy news just happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what I have.
Speaker 1: that is called Twitter.
Speaker 0: Yeah Path I don't know what app that is.
Speaker 0: I haven't used it.
Speaker 0: CNN similar to New York Times Facebook.
Speaker 0: I have that enabled but all it really does is let you post to Facebook.
Speaker 0: It doesn't actually give you anything from now.
Speaker 1: This is where really we have to write some apps because what I what with what this hardware actually is and what it does I want an app that will show me slides and speaking notes and help me control a speech.
Speaker 0: I'm giving yeah You can do that.
Speaker 0: Yes with a Google Apps integration.
Speaker 0: Definitely is capable of doing that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is a hundred percent a thing.
Speaker 0: This can do.
Speaker 1: that is thing.
Speaker 1: one I wanted to do that - I wanted to do is GPS directions.
Speaker 0: while I'm biking thing what I want to do is show me the date in addition to the time.
Speaker 1: I mean screen.
Speaker 0: It just shows you the time.
Speaker 0: It doesn't show you the date.
Speaker 0: It's like what the fuck?
Speaker 0: I want to know what.
Speaker 1: today's when the batteries get better or if I do rig up something cool with an energy battery to keep It going all the time.
Speaker 1: I would like to make an app because there's a ton of dashcam apps now for Android that do a really good job of Constantly recording like 10 minutes of video and cycling it.
Speaker 1: but then you can hit a button and it's like oh fuck and it records.
Speaker 1: It keeps everything.
Speaker 1: It's the someone attacked me.
Speaker 1: I want all the police data app.
Speaker 1: I feel like you can make a really good app for glass But the battery would be the battery will tell you.
Speaker 0: people seem to think that like this glass it can like camera all the time Like you're videoing your life like the same way if you were wearing like a Buy a GoPro.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah No, the camera will.
Speaker 0: the battery will die in like 20 minutes if you keep the video running, right?
Speaker 0: It is useless if you think you're gonna video your life with this thing.
Speaker 0: Don't even begin to think that's a remote possibility.
Speaker 0: There is forget it videoing for long periods of time.
Speaker 0: No cannot do now what you can make lines with it with an app.
Speaker 1: You could do something clever where you have it wake up and automatically take a picture every five minutes.
Speaker 0: Even that would basically have the battery life.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but if I'm gonna I'm gonna rig up my energy thing.
Speaker 1: In fact, I'll rig up an energy thing and maybe I'll get someone else to kickstart a battery pack.
Speaker 0: The only reason the Google Glass battery lasts as long as it does is because it always Errors on the side of turning off right.
Speaker 0: their philosophy at Google is, you know, don't turn it on.
Speaker 0: It should be sort of like an enhancement.
Speaker 0: It should never bother you right?
Speaker 0: even if you have the Gmail enabled which I don't because it's again not using Google Google apps It will actually only tell you if you've got mail if Gmail considers it an important email.
Speaker 0: So you have to really pay attention to that and you know that feature in Gmail with the important and not important emails.
Speaker 0: You really have to train your Gmail saying this message is important.
Speaker 0: This one's not.
Speaker 0: this one's important.
Speaker 0: this one's not so that it gets it right and will.
Speaker 0: only Google Glass will only wake up and tell you if it was an Important email.
Speaker 0: it'll show you what it was and When it shows you something it turns off right away Like when I turn it on to see the clock it turns off and like a couple seconds.
Speaker 0: This thing just really loves to.
Speaker 0: it doesn't turn off fully obviously, but it loves to go to sleep Like imagine if you turn right just like me then.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it just like it's like on off off off.
Speaker 0: It just doesn't want to stay on.
Speaker 1: well remember what have we been saying?
Speaker 1: For since 2005 when we started doing gig nights publicly the biggest thing holding back all the cool things We want to do is technology.
Speaker 1: battery is consumer battery technology?
Speaker 1: yep, and That stuff really has not progressed much in recent times because it can't.
Speaker 0: if it progresses then we make tiny grenades And it would also be really heavy on the side of your head right.
Speaker 0: the Google Glass is actually quite comfortable.
Speaker 0: I'm definitely used to it by now.
Speaker 1: We need local wireless power distribution coupled with you like in the smaller your back.
Speaker 1: You just carry a fucking battery Whatever it's gonna be.
Speaker 0: yeah, you go for it All right, I feel like we can.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to think of like other things.
Speaker 1: We're gonna talk about it probably off and on and our Monday shows for a while now because Scott's gonna keep using it.
Speaker 1: I've been playing with the API's.
Speaker 1: I'm actually once I have glass.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna write some fucking apps faster than you can blink.
Speaker 1: Really good examples, it's really easy to write stuff mmm Let's see and I'm not gonna write anything that requires a lot of complex software design.
Speaker 1: I'm writing things that are like show me the slides.
Speaker 0: Yeah Turn to these.
Speaker 0: anything else I can say about it is it worth the monies?
Speaker 1: well, maybe You know what it's where it'll be worth the money for me.
Speaker 1: Maybe Scott if you write an app or two, and it doesn't cost $300 a month from now If it costs like $800 a month from now or There's something that makes the Explorer Edition different like I what I could see.
Speaker 1: I'm guessing here totally shooting from the hip That they'll have consumer glass and Explorer glass with different update patterns or different things.
Speaker 0: who knows it's possible Whatever it.
Speaker 0: just it would be nice if they did something.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: I mean there are some other benefits of the Explorer.
Speaker 0: like I got an email that was like private party at the Explorer place in New York City the place you picked up your Google Glass on The same day as packs.
Speaker 0: great guys Thanks come on over and hang out with the other glass explorers.
Speaker 1: Can't figure out the high correlation rate between people who care about glass and people who care about packs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, New York Yeah, all right, I kind of want to go hang out with the studio audience for a bit.
Speaker 1: So I think we're done here for now.
Speaker 1: yeah Also, I don't want to do too much more audio because now that I'm recording raw audio I've been fucking with the levels the whole time because this was you know on the fly.
Speaker 1: I gotta master this goddamn thing tonight now.
Speaker 0: Yep, so we're not gonna talk more about glass now, but maybe more later.
Speaker 1: we'll talk about it when we've written some apps or I get it or as Scott discovers things about it mm-hmm, and you're gonna see a lot of pictures of me.
Speaker 1: probably maybe This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.