Speaker 0: It's Wednesday September 11th 2013.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I am Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: Aladdin the Disney movie.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: I'm the bird from Aladdin.
Speaker 0: So uh we talk a lot about our bike commutes, but no but I got to get this out Yesterday, what are you getting out?
Speaker 1: Don't let me see.
Speaker 0: so I was biking.
Speaker 0: I'm not getting my dick out.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about getting dicks out later, so I'm biking to work right and the most ridiculous Stereotypical hipster fixie bike dude I have ever seen to the point of those ultra tall ones.
Speaker 0: so now now well It was not a penny far thing.
Speaker 0: It was just this guy wearing a knit ad.
Speaker 0: he looked like such a bike hipster at this huge leather Messenger bag and this huge chain.
Speaker 0: the messenger bag had a full-size bike pump sticking out of it.
Speaker 0: it's an actual fixie fixed gear not single gear and He's biking like a maniac down the road in Queens like a maniac and he's doing that thing.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you've noticed this, but those ultra biker dudes a lot of times They like to touch stuff while they're biking Really like they'll bike and they like.
Speaker 0: they come up behind a car and they whip Around the car and they reach out and like slap the back of the car as they ride by it.
Speaker 1: Why would you touch someone's car for no reason?
Speaker 0: I don't know, but I've seen the hipster.
Speaker 0: you fixie bike guys do it all the time Okay?
Speaker 0: or like they come up to the Pulaski bridge and they bike up to it and they just like Grab the paint grab the cement right as they go past it and they grab the rail.
Speaker 0: They just touch shit all the time and he's also biking in that really aggressive way where he's standing up the whole time and doing And doing that pumpity pump back and forth.
Speaker 1: was it a fixie or one speed?
Speaker 0: it was a fixie.
Speaker 0: like I said, okay But he's jumping with it too Like you would a BMX.
Speaker 0: like he gets to a corner and he like jumps the bike into the loose slight corner He's taking and it's just he's being a douchebag and he runs red lights.
Speaker 0: He almost hits me because I was stopped in the bike lane at a red light and he like whipped his way around me and He touched the.
Speaker 0: there was a pole like a light pole and he touched it as he went by it and turned around.
Speaker 0: and he's doing all this bullshit Crashed hurt himself.
Speaker 0: so I Just laughed and kind of let him do his thing.
Speaker 0: and then every you know I kept passing him because I'm way faster than anyone.
Speaker 0: on one of those bikes I was just actually stopping for red lights.
Speaker 1: So it happens a lot to me, too.
Speaker 1: so
Speaker 0: he gets on the Pulaski and he gets stuck behind slow people that he can't easily get around and he's really antsy and he keeps sliding his bike back and forth and like
Speaker 1: Fell off the bridge
Speaker 0: and then he just fucking like crabs a guy like on the shoulder It's like yo, bro, and like slides past everyone with his bike and this is rocketing down and this really gets in everyone's business.
Speaker 0: okay, so I get down to the end of the bridge and I catch up to him again because fixies are slow and I'm watching him and he.
Speaker 0: we get to the bike lanes.
Speaker 1: in Brooklyn I was speeding down a hill on a big hill with a fixie.
Speaker 1: How did he stop at the bottom?
Speaker 0: Because well he stopped because there was actual traffic at the base of the bridge.
Speaker 1: Did he have a break on this fixie?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I guess I think he had one of those ghetto little front brakes But I might have done his bullshit slow down.
Speaker 1: I saw a dude with a fixie and only a rear brake and I was like What the fuck dude anyway, so anyway that the operative part of the story is that he gets going.
Speaker 0: now I'm waiting for the comeuppance and there's a bike lane.
Speaker 0: Mmm, but he's not in the bike lane.
Speaker 0: He's riding in the street next to the bike lane for no goddamn reason.
Speaker 0: Okay blocking traffic.
Speaker 0: So there's cars lined up behind him because he's going way slow and he's in the middle of the lane biking as fast as he can and like going left and right and left and right like Woodley Woodley Woodley Woodley Woodley and People are just passing him in the bike lane and the cars are honking and he's being a douchebag.
Speaker 0: and then out of nowhere he does his Woodley to the left and comes down and His front tire just snaps off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and he goes too much Woodley and he goes tumbling and his messenger bag lands on the ground and explodes In just garbage everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the bike goes flying and he goes rolling and he's laying there.
Speaker 0: So I Bike up next to him and I slow down.
Speaker 0: I'm like you okay, bro And he is obviously not okay like not like he's not gonna die, but he was not in a good way.
Speaker 0: And he's like, yeah, man, I'm fine.
Speaker 0: And I look and the car that had been stuck behind him.
Speaker 0: who watched all this firsthand?
Speaker 0: The guy is laughing so hard.
Speaker 0: He can't even breathe.
Speaker 0: the guy is just like holding on like he's holding out of the wheel and he's just got his head up in the air like It was one of the greatest things I've ever seen in my life Instant justice.
Speaker 1: if you had a video justice.
Speaker 1: porn is why I need a GoPro.
Speaker 0: if there was a guy if there was a god Like Poseidon of bikes that is what he would do to do God of bikes.
Speaker 1: Alright, that's me.
Speaker 1: It's got Ruben.
Speaker 0: You sure it's not just Poseidon.
Speaker 1: you got Scott Armstrong Scott Lamond.
Speaker 1: now, I don't know.
Speaker 0: So that was my commute.
Speaker 1: sure I took the subway today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I had to get my laundry in the morning.
Speaker 0: Also guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah elves and burning wheel kind of hacks Even though dwarfs are just as much hacks Non-humans X. Yeah I'm kind of worried now that people not hex really.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're not as a rat people.
Speaker 0: They're not that great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're good at some things.
Speaker 0: not not looking forward to win that last episode of attack on Titan comes down the pipe.
Speaker 1: Gotta read the poorly drawn manga.
Speaker 0: read the manga not gonna know.
Speaker 1: I'm telling you what's in the basement.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna tell me shit.
Speaker 0: You're gonna spoil anything and make me wait and I'm gonna wait.
Speaker 1: You know what and you'll never know what's in that basement.
Speaker 0: They're gonna make another season.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well that season get to the basement.
Speaker 0: Probably really Scott.
Speaker 0: I have waded through ridiculous cliff.
Speaker 0: Remember the end of Big O one?
Speaker 0: Yeah, why did Big O one end?
Speaker 0: Big O one ended?
Speaker 0: Hey guys, that whole plot we building up to the whole time that plot that you've been waiting for resolution on?
Speaker 0: well No, no, no the end nothing.
Speaker 0: You had to wait a whole you to wait years for a season two to even be made and there was no guarantee that season Was gonna even happen.
Speaker 1: Anyway, meanwhile, I don't know how many years exactly there were between big O's one and two.
Speaker 0: Or how about giant robo?
Speaker 0: every episode ends on a cliffhanger and that shit came out sporadically.
Speaker 1: Let's see big.
Speaker 1: Oh the big oh not.
Speaker 1: big O notation.
Speaker 1: season 1 yeah 99 to 2000.
Speaker 0: Yep season 2 Yeah Yeah, three year you had to wait a while.
Speaker 0: All right, Scott giant robo every episode is the cliffhanger right.
Speaker 0: episode 1 July 22nd 1992 episode 2 February 20th 1993 so eight months.
Speaker 0: Yeah episode 3 August 67 months.
Speaker 1: episode 4 January of 94.
Speaker 0: episode 5 October of 94. episode 6 June of 95.
Speaker 0: Episode 7 the grand finale January 25th, 1998 three years Between the second last and last episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I dealt with full metal alchemist and I can deal with Attack on Titan.
Speaker 0: I can wait for the anime.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: You didn't wait for those giant robots.
Speaker 1: You watched all at once.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know But I'm just saying there have been worse.
Speaker 1: Also, yeah anyone who read bone in single issues.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, not in one volume edition I would I couldn't have.
Speaker 0: I would like kidnap the dude making it.
Speaker 0: I would like flipped out and I don't know what I would have done But ask a flow name.
Speaker 0: I watched the the second-to-last VHS tape that ends on possibly the biggest cliffhanger in anime history and then mind away in a month For another VHS tape to come out.
Speaker 1: You're gonna be waiting more than a month for Attack on Titan after.
Speaker 0: that's fine because a whole bunch of other stuff is starting up And actually it's it's kind of anime season again for me.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be pony season.
Speaker 0: I know we're gonna have ponies which we care.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: Do even pony.
Speaker 0: well thing is I still like that concept of my little pony But I am dubious that the upcoming season will be worth watching my rear-view mirror and I see sharks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that have been jumped over.
Speaker 0: I would have been a lot less worried had equestria girls not happened Yeah, but I had to see it.
Speaker 0: kind of like how he that really poisoned the waters.
Speaker 0: kind of like how would you sharks when?
Speaker 0: You see a car going at high speed toward a brick wall.
Speaker 0: Then you know, it's gonna hit the brick wall.
Speaker 0: You don't look away because it's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Anyway, there's nothing you can do about it.
Speaker 0: He's got to see it.
Speaker 0: That is why I watched equestria girls.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 0: So, but I mean I watched in second yori, uh that there's like four other anime I want to watch like.
Speaker 0: it's a lot of good anime out that Scott's not watching.
Speaker 0: It's just me and Emily like I should do.
Speaker 0: yeah, like what play netrunner.
Speaker 1: Yeah You doing watching anime, yeah, yeah playing netrunners.
Speaker 1: at least the social activity.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll start doing a video again.
Speaker 0: A lot of people are really clamoring for our geek knives present.
Speaker 1: I've been using my elgato and streaming playing video games.
Speaker 1: How about that?
Speaker 0: What if we should stream live the the making of one of our route 10 episodes?
Speaker 0: Whatever people will be really sad to see that the making of is identical to What they actually get because we don't actually edit that shit anyway anyway.
Speaker 1: So in the news in the news news something happened that I feel like has happened before But perhaps see okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway Miyazaki retired even at a price conference Retired right.
Speaker 1: so I see this and I'm like Brett Favre right He's done this before.
Speaker 1: he is not really retiring but I'm
Speaker 0: sort of maybe
Speaker 1: Convinced he actually is because he had a big press conference about it as opposed to just sort of saying he's doing it, right Yeah, and also if you look at it, it's like yeah He hasn't really done anything super great in a while, right?
Speaker 1: He wants to go out while he still hasn't made anything awful.
Speaker 0: I'm still convinced that what he was attempting to do.
Speaker 0: Well, not necessarily attempting I think a tiny part of him to be perfectly honest was hoping that he would eventually die in the middle of his last work.
Speaker 0: Because you notice whenever there's like look at Satoshi con everything he did.
Speaker 1: He's really trying to get lung cancer pretty But seriously look at so she got.
Speaker 0: everything he did was gold, right But the last thing he was working on that didn't get finished.
Speaker 0: has this mystique because the people who recognize his gold are desperate for anything more.
Speaker 1: Anything you will see plenty of lost works of Miyazaki.
Speaker 0: Right, I would love to see a director like this like work with his animators and Secretly create a movie that no one knew about.
Speaker 0: that's only released after his death.
Speaker 0: Sure, like it's hidden somewhere in 20 years later.
Speaker 0: Someone calls it people do this.
Speaker 1: It's called fake Van.
Speaker 1: Gogh's.
Speaker 1: they have them.
Speaker 0: So we should we make should we get people to make fake Miyazaki's did?
Speaker 1: good luck with that.
Speaker 1: It's a lot harder than making a Van.
Speaker 1: Gogh.
Speaker 0: Hahahaha We'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, girl girl did better with his uh more recent girl.
Speaker 0: Make good anime girl run tournament.
Speaker 0: good I don't know.
Speaker 0: is this his second work was better than the first work that he made?
Speaker 1: Yeah, also, I know seems to be getting in on that biz.
Speaker 0: We'll see that that is still a rumor.
Speaker 1: at best It's still you know.
Speaker 0: Though if it were going to happen the rumor is that Anno would like to or has a line toward making a Sequel to Nausicaa.
Speaker 1: Okay, you need more manga to do that.
Speaker 0: If I. well the thing is them the anime Really covers pretty the first volume of the manga and actually has a pretty different tone from the overall model.
Speaker 1: It also adds an ending that sort of isn't in.
Speaker 0: yeah, because the end of that manga is yeah We got a long way to go here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if I were Anno I would not in any way make it a sequel to Miyazaki's the you know the Ghibli one.
Speaker 0: instead I would just make it a separate set of movies that follows the manga more whole set of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, that'd be cool.
Speaker 0: That would be really cool.
Speaker 1: Actually that shit.
Speaker 0: I feel like Anno could pull it off the series.
Speaker 1: Yeah Now should get TV follows the manga.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would watch the fuck out of it.
Speaker 1: I think everyone would save anime.
Speaker 1: everyone watch the fuck out of it.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of thing that could cause a girl of course attack on me.
Speaker 0: that could be an a anime that could do For anime what Akira did for anime.
Speaker 0: Yep Because a lot of people are talking about an anime Renaissance.
Speaker 0: recently because of attack on Titan and Well, the thing is it's true, but that's misleading attack on Titan got Existing anime fans excited about anime again.
Speaker 1: It did not get new people in anime and I think you know what the Nausicaa TV could do.
Speaker 1: obviously all speculation, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like you look people who aren't anime fans hardcore.
Speaker 1: They're just say watch anime like my mom or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they only really watch anime movies and really only you know, the Miyazakis and maybe the Satoshi Kans.
Speaker 1: There's one step me on goes to the shells of the Akira's.
Speaker 0: there is one to be out of the normal people who?
Speaker 0: They watch the movies and they have seen like one anime series like a cowboy beaver.
Speaker 0: Yeah They've seen like cowboy bop or put.
Speaker 1: the TV series are pretty much nerds.
Speaker 1: only what TV series is accessible Like.
Speaker 1: do all them, you know the moms who watch Miyazaki movies.
Speaker 1: What TV series do they watch in America?
Speaker 0: Because if you say the world says I saw him sure, right?
Speaker 1: But if there was Miyazaki TV series like Nausicaa TV Boom suddenly anime TV series becomes a thing for all those people.
Speaker 1: if you write and it wouldn't be hard.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, wouldn't be hard.
Speaker 0: but attack on Titan is Energizing anime fandom and a lot of people I see who were really into anime and just weren't watching a lot.
Speaker 1: recently Suddenly with attack on Titan they started watching anime as it's got the people who were anime fans who haven't watched anime in a while To watch an anime?
Speaker 0: I suspect it.
Speaker 0: I think it also got a lot of people who previously were not using crunchyroll to start using crunchyroll.
Speaker 1: I got me I was using crunchyroll now.
Speaker 1: I temporarily paid money to crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: exactly I think a lot of people are paying for crunchyroll now And I think a lot of these people when attack on Titan stops gonna stop paying for crunchyroll No, I think they're gonna start watching some of the other anime that's on there.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of good shit going on right now sure, but I'm not gonna keep paying like I watch it for free All the shows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but all those shows.
Speaker 1: I could just watch them for free.
Speaker 1: And the only reason I need to pay is because you know simulcast.
Speaker 1: Yeah I don't think you get.
Speaker 1: there has to be another show that I want to simulcast as badly as attack on time.
Speaker 0: I don't think you get full quality if you don't pay on all of them.
Speaker 1: That's a shame
Speaker 0: I'm not sure because we've had to pay account forever, so it's kind
Speaker 1: of
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean seriously There's a ton of other pretty good stuff lately and there's been good shows that have come out for a while But nothing is energized anime fandom until attack on Titan.
Speaker 0: It's doing what Fullmetal Alchemist did.
Speaker 1: Madoka did.
Speaker 0: Madoka did but I not as much Madoka energized.
Speaker 1: Even though it's better.
Speaker 0: I think Madoka energized a smaller Harder core.
Speaker 0: Madoka energized people like us.
Speaker 0: We were like oh fuck anime.
Speaker 1: Everyone, all the attack on Titan.
Speaker 1: people who are excited about anime suddenly Watch Madoka.
Speaker 1: You've got time.
Speaker 1: There isn't gonna be a new frickin attack on Titan episode for like a week or something.
Speaker 0: Yes, and if you have time to watch Madoka Yeah.
Speaker 0: And attack on Titan people.
Speaker 0: if you what you want a show with ridiculous cliffhangers where you start watching and then you have to watch Everything.
Speaker 0: that's Madoka.
Speaker 0: and you know what if you watch Madoka and you still need a show like that?
Speaker 1: Ava.
Speaker 0: Escaflowne.
Speaker 0: and Ava.
Speaker 0: Escaflowne is not the best show ever, but you know what?
Speaker 0: It's got that cliffhanger.
Speaker 0: You're gonna watch one episode then you're gonna watch 23 and then you're gonna watch 26.
Speaker 0: Yep So I don't really have a news but Scott Briefly talked about a new comic called Trillium.
Speaker 1: It's not the I am client.
Speaker 0: No, it is.
Speaker 0: it is Jeff Lemire is our man is pretty much the number one most talked about comic creator on geek nights.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we really like Jeff Lemire.
Speaker 1: He's a Canadian hockey liking comic drawing dude.
Speaker 0: I know and he draws sad hockey players.
Speaker 0: So well sad melancholy thoughtful wistful hockey players.
Speaker 1: But Trillium.
Speaker 1: Pretty much him and Brian K Vaughn are just owning everybody, right?
Speaker 0: So Scott came over one day and he handed me a floppy.
Speaker 1: Actually I gave it to you at Pax.
Speaker 0: You handed me a floppy of Trillium and I was and I was like floppy and He was like just read it and I was like, okay I read it and it was and it was two comics.
Speaker 0: like you know the whole flip over like it's a floppy That has one comic one way and then you flip it upside down.
Speaker 1: I didn't even realize what was going on till I got to the middle and you start from the other side.
Speaker 0: Then you read his different comic.
Speaker 0: It's one of those.
Speaker 0: so We both read it.
Speaker 0: now we've read one floppy of this and it is already.
Speaker 0: I Equally want to read more of this to how badly I want to read more of Saga.
Speaker 1: I've read almost every comic Jeff Lemire has ever written in his life that he's published Professionally.
Speaker 1: right underwater welder for everything, right?
Speaker 1: This is the best one of those.
Speaker 1: it just based on the first issue.
Speaker 1: It's the best.
Speaker 1: one and two Uh Yeah, as terms of comics that exist that are being coming out as of this moment.
Speaker 1: Not all comics ever right cuz watchmen if you sit right Yeah, Will Eisner come on, but comics that are being published today that are coming out in comic book stores as we speak.
Speaker 1: Saga number one Trillium chewing on its asshole.
Speaker 1: It's that close there.
Speaker 0: Well, they're neck and neck but we have such.
Speaker 0: we have one data point right now.
Speaker 1: That's all you need.
Speaker 1: It is so strong.
Speaker 0: Don't want to say anything about it because so here's a Trillium is about.
Speaker 0: okay, I'm gonna give the summary.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this is so far as we know there is.
Speaker 1: which side did you read first?
Speaker 1: Indiana Jones side of the space.
Speaker 0: I read the space side first.
Speaker 0: I read the space side first by chance cuz I also chose to do it by chance.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know that it was flipped before I read it.
Speaker 1: I just picked it up and started reading and then I was like, oh there's another side.
Speaker 0: I knew it was flipped and what I did is I looked at it and I was like Random, so I just flipped a coin and it was tails.
Speaker 0: So I read the space one.
Speaker 1: So in the space side, there's some girl who's a space space anthropologist in a in a Really really future society and she needs to go and get this plant to get.
Speaker 1: keep her people alive from some horrible disease or something Yep, but she's an anthropologist.
Speaker 0: It's the typical sort of she has to talk to the aliens.
Speaker 0: you talk to the aliens.
Speaker 0: We need their bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the military is like no We're gonna go get it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, if you can't convince that an alien sent her on a quest to basically prove her worth on the other hand on earth At least it looks like earth.
Speaker 0: It's like the 20s.
Speaker 1: There's some Archaeologist investigating Mayan ruins Aztec ruins.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: He's a world war one veteran as far as I found, you know.
Speaker 1: He's investigating the ancient hidden ruins Legend of the hidden temple in that very British sort of ho.
Speaker 0: ho off into the jungle with fifth helmets hurrah and they meet.
Speaker 1: Yeah issue one.
Speaker 0: Yeah The two comics.
Speaker 0: you read one it ends at a point where they meet.
Speaker 0: you read the other one.
Speaker 0: it ends at the exact same Point from the other perspective and it's wonder if the next issue is gonna be flipped.
Speaker 1: Probably not and I wonder how it's gonna look in the trade.
Speaker 0: There's spoilers.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: It's one.
Speaker 0: What really was interesting is I read the space one first I get to the end of it and I'm really invested in this character because there's a pretty big thing going on that the body She sees inside of that temple man and what they were wearing.
Speaker 0: And then suddenly this guy with a machete covered in blood is just like yo, I'm like what?
Speaker 0: who's this guy with a machete?
Speaker 0: Me no trust.
Speaker 0: and then I read the other one and it is I perfectly understand why his machete is covered in blood.
Speaker 0: duh, but now I see both from his perspective how threatening she looks and from her perspective how Threatening he looks in a way that could not have been done in a different format Comics.
Speaker 1: Yeah best you can't do this shit in some movie.
Speaker 0: Just have a movie that you.
Speaker 1: you watch one movie in the left eye and one in the right eye at the same time And then once here's the way you do it you release the movie to theaters, right?
Speaker 1: 50% of theaters watch movie a and 50% watch movie B, but they have the same title and then everyone's like oh fuck There's a second movie and then you have to go back and watch the second one.
Speaker 1: Yeah If you get the first one again shit, what could be like clue?
Speaker 0: it could be like clue.
Speaker 0: that would be the best anyway.
Speaker 0: anyway things of the day Speaking of dicks being out.
Speaker 0: This is a video.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty well done video and basically it's the top 10 scenes that people would pause and rewind a movie for In other words Easter eggs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or like you notice something weird Like did that munchkin just hang himself?
Speaker 0: what pause rewind?
Speaker 0: or was that a ghost in the background of three men and a baby?
Speaker 1: Did that guy have his dick out?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: He did.
Speaker 1: but was a dick in that movie?
Speaker 1: an exposed male Peanut credit.
Speaker 0: what it doesn't have is the scene in back to the future where the kid flips the camera off and points at his dick.
Speaker 0: But what's interesting is that this video is great for modern times and this is the reason I make it a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: When I was a kid, I heard the rumor of a munchkin being hanged in the background.
Speaker 1: So I was like, oh fuck so I did and the movie is on your TV is blurry as fuck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I was looking for UFOs with your camera.
Speaker 0: We had an expensive goddamn VCR.
Speaker 0: So I was doing this tracking frame by frame and I'm like that kind of looks like someone hanging themselves.
Speaker 0: I really can't.
Speaker 0: we're like my brother and I are like drawing pictures of it and tracing over the TV and If you watch the HD version it is obvious It's a bird like so obvious and a lot of these are like that like the three men and a baby thing.
Speaker 0: I remember when I pause that since we've had HD cameras.
Speaker 1: There's a lot less talk about aliens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, UFOs except among the crazy separate CG generated ones that people have made as hoaxes.
Speaker 0: Yep I want to see a lot more hoaxes like that though.
Speaker 0: So yeah, that's my video That's my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Okay, that's what I got my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: So you all are aware if you go to YouTube to the cartoon hangover, there is a TV show.
Speaker 0: Bravest Warriors is like my fifth favorite thing in the world right now.
Speaker 1: I like Bravest Warriors a lot.
Speaker 1: I see comic book and there's a lot of people cosplaying and cat bug got really popular.
Speaker 0: if I had to rate things that are on right now or recently that I like that are Visual media.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much adventure time.
Speaker 0: Bravest Warriors Venture brothers, even though the season recently ended Archer even though we're waiting for the new season my little pony Even though the sharks the sharks might be circling anyway, but being puppycat is right up there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so being puppycat is the other thing that is on cartoon hangover.
Speaker 1: People seem to like it more than Bravest Warriors.
Speaker 1: They're heathens.
Speaker 1: Not that being puppycat isn't great.
Speaker 0: I like being puppycat more than Bravest Warriors.
Speaker 1: It is pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: However, it's just not Bravest Warriors.
Speaker 0: 90% of why I like being puppycat more is the voice acting the vocaloid.
Speaker 1: No, the main girl the main girl.
Speaker 0: I love the way she talks and 9% is her actual dialogue.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's pretty much all that show has I'm sure sure.
Speaker 0: glad there was nothing sharp on my couch.
Speaker 1: Use the sword as a sword All right, so You should watch both those things but beginning tomorrow or perhaps today.
Speaker 1: Wait, there's a third thing.
Speaker 1: It says coming this Thursday and they posted it yesterday and today is Thursday.
Speaker 1: So this could be posted anytime today.
Speaker 1: They have a trailer though, which is what I'm gonna link to.
Speaker 1: the trailer is for a third show Dr.
Speaker 1: Lollipop the unicorn doctor.
Speaker 0: this appears to be from what Scott showed me the greatest.
Speaker 0: Dr McNinja little pony the bee and puppycat time It combines our Lee the things I like about all these domicile dobutsu.
Speaker 0: Oh my god There it is domicile dobutsu.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so
Speaker 0: because you know that assistant raccoon looking guy in the background is gonna be the best
Speaker 1: the thing I want to point out about this is like at PAX There was a lot of like cat bug Bravest Warriors going on and not just because we love fine with selling it right people were doing it and I find it really awesome that this is like hey, this is just a TV show that just posted on YouTube.
Speaker 1: There's no friggin, you know, it's not in a TV network.
Speaker 1: It's not doing anything.
Speaker 1: and Bravest Warriors It's appropriate for all ages, but it you know, it does things that would not be allowed on TV.
Speaker 1: Straight up right?
Speaker 1: It would be very different if it was actually on Cartoon Network or Nickelodeon or some shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yet you see almost as much of it as you see Adventure time around like it's around because The afford for basically for people YouTube is finally TV.
Speaker 0: No YouTube is only TV for people for nerds my people and people under the age of 14 people go to pegs and young people.
Speaker 0: Yeah for very young people and for nerds it YouTube replaced TV a while ago But we're so we're passing.
Speaker 1: now we're finally seeing full production value.
Speaker 1: TV shows just on YouTube free.
Speaker 1: We've seen them like on Netflix, you know streaming.
Speaker 1: but this is on YouTube free real TV show not.
Speaker 1: some guy made it at his home.
Speaker 1: TV show and animation.
Speaker 1: and There's not too many of those.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there's definitely not too many of those, you know, there are something I'm not saying.
Speaker 1: these are the first ones is the first ones where people are buying merch all over.
Speaker 1: the convention is what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: So in the meta moment book club book is Stasi land.
Speaker 1: Haven't even read page one.
Speaker 0: You should read it.
Speaker 0: I already picked my next book club books.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna have to way ahead of the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah In fact, I've already since I finished Stasi land.
Speaker 0: I've read three more culture books.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah, I haven't been reading it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Consider Phlebas was uh, pretty rough.
Speaker 1: I didn't finish it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, how far did you go?
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, I'm at the place where they're inside the planet that they were Looking for the.
Speaker 0: you know, the mind somewhere pretty much the whole rest of the book is that they're in the train tunnels looking for Stuff, you know that trains gonna move duh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's Chekhov's fucking train Chekhov's train Chekhov's uranium pile Chekhov's everything Chekhov's mind Chekhov's shape-changing ability.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I uh, I really like the culture books a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, look at all our stuff on the internet.
Speaker 0: meta moment that was it.
Speaker 0: oh do you have any other meta?
Speaker 0: Nothing.
Speaker 0: That's burning con.
Speaker 0: burning con is coming.
Speaker 0: It's got 10 tech like I think some of it.
Speaker 1: because he's I'm still not I gotta figure that out still right because Apparently there's a special.
Speaker 1: I would normally under no circumstances skip burning con once a year.
Speaker 1: burning con for netrunner tournament Which is twice a month.
Speaker 1: Never would I do that, right, but it is not sold out yet.
Speaker 1: Oh, it is a special special netrunner tournament where the fantasy flight people are coming and doing all sorts of fancy stuff And this is could be a once-ever Situation.
Speaker 1: but they're doing one at the strat on Saturday and they're doing another one somewhere in Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: That's hard to get to on Sunday.
Speaker 1: So it's like huh?
Speaker 1: I could skip the Sunday burning con and go to some weird store in the middle of nowhere Brooklyn somehow or I could skip like the first two sessions a burning con on Saturday and Go to the strat which is not a weird place with the people I know and maybe I'd still probably be able to make It to the night session of burning con on Saturday and then go to burning con Sunday.
Speaker 1: We got to see how it goes down.
Speaker 1: I got to figure it out.
Speaker 0: We'll see you by air.
Speaker 0: We got.
Speaker 0: we got videos on the internet videos of our lectures from a million conventions.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be at magfest doing the same bullshit.
Speaker 0: We do every year.
Speaker 0: Maybe some new bullshit that we're not gonna talk about because We're trying we're putting we're trying to put together something really magical something magical But we actually can't talk about it until we get a little further into the.
Speaker 1: I don't want it The only.
Speaker 1: normally I just talk about everything but it might not happen.
Speaker 1: But the thing is I don't want to.
Speaker 1: if I say something we you know, somebody else might be upset.
Speaker 0: It's also weird.
Speaker 0: It's we have to make a lot of things line up for this to work the way we want it to work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I don't want people to maybe start spreading this but I will say if this happens The upcoming magfest will be the most magical magfest ever because not only will the magic happen Machine supremacy is gonna be performing there.
Speaker 1: They better not schedule any of our stuff during the machine supremacy tournament a concert.
Speaker 1: I'm God, I will email it because if they do I'm just skipping my own shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah Over a decade to go to this concert to just have to do a panel which I can do which I do ten times a year.
Speaker 1: All right, Vic.
Speaker 1: It's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So Aladdin Yeah, I played that game on the Genesis.
Speaker 0: great game on the gen is actually a pretty good game really good mostly because that was one of the earlier games that had that Lion King and the Genesis is also really because they had that rid.
Speaker 0: They were just mediocre platformers really, but they had that ridiculous animation.
Speaker 1: How about that Aladdin tiger LCD?
Speaker 1: That was a good one.
Speaker 0: tiger LCDs were all without exception.
Speaker 0: Bullshit Aladdin.
Speaker 1: good one terrible Street Fighter.
Speaker 0: They were all terrible good one.
Speaker 0: Every one of them was terrible.
Speaker 0: They're original.
Speaker 1: The one was just lights and it was football.
Speaker 1: That wasn't.
Speaker 1: even I don't even know tiger made that.
Speaker 0: that was good as like the first one I had I had of an ancient one from like the 70s.
Speaker 0: That's baseball good.
Speaker 0: It's not tiger.
Speaker 1: I like those ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, except there was a glitch now with the pac-man one that looks like a little arcade machine.
Speaker 0: So in mine, it actually had a controller was to player right and a controller stuck out.
Speaker 0: you took turns pitching and batting.
Speaker 0: There was a way to hit the buttons in such a fashion as pitcher to where it was impossible to hit the pitch Nice, and my little brother would cry because he couldn't figure it out and I was an asshole and never told him Okay, so there we go.
Speaker 0: But no Aladdin the Disney film 21 years old.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were born when Aladdin came out.
Speaker 1: you can drink have a beer Aladdin.
Speaker 0: and yet when I thought oh Let's do a show on Aladdin.
Speaker 0: I Didn't feel like it was that long ago.
Speaker 1: If it was way long ago, yeah But yeah when I was a kid Aladdin was a big deal because basically Disney movies had.
Speaker 1: you know There was this time period when I was young when Disney was like on And then they sort of came back like Little Mermaid boom and they sort of.
Speaker 1: there was that period where every single summer There was an animated Disney movie.
Speaker 1: That was super high production value and awesome and it was just boom boom Boom hit hit hit.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: and Aladdin was I mean the Little Mermaid?
Speaker 1: I didn't care about too much but Aladdin I cared about a lot.
Speaker 1: We had a VHS tape and we wore that thing the fuck out.
Speaker 0: Well 92 saw Aladdin the Mighty Ducks Newsies the Muppet Christmas Carol and people say it was honey I blew up the kid.
Speaker 1: all the same year people say right like oh you you know movies aren't any worse than they used to be.
Speaker 1: It's just your perception.
Speaker 1: No go look in the 90s pretty much every year had multiple all-time great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was 1992. go back one more year.
Speaker 0: You also get Beauty and the Beast White Fang Rocketeer Rocketeer and wild hearts can't be broke.
Speaker 1: Well that one fuck that one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's about horses and girls even know what the hell that is.
Speaker 0: girls and horses.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's not a memorable one not rated very highly.
Speaker 1: go on Google and type in like.
Speaker 1: 1992 movies 1993 movies 1994 movies.
Speaker 1: you'll just see greats greats greats and just as you keep going there is a gradual decline Starting around the early 2000 just like oh, there's less and less greats every year.
Speaker 1: Where did they go?
Speaker 1: and it's all superhero movies and sequels.
Speaker 1: now the end.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, there was a big dearth.
Speaker 0: I mean Oliver and company was the last movie that was big.
Speaker 0: that came out before the Little Mermaid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then it was Little Mermaid rescuers down under Beauty and the Beast Aladdin Lion King.
Speaker 1: Then after Lion King they kept trying to keep it going but but it was hard and I think around Tarzan was the last one.
Speaker 0: Well when Pocahontas came out I remember because I was in middle school, and I was like really you're gonna make Pocahontas and The main love interest isn't even the guy she married in the real world Really, and then when it was hunchback.
Speaker 0: I was like fuck this table Didn't watch Disney movies for a long time?
Speaker 1: no at least as a kid, but Aladdin was still Magical literally and figuratively Right.
Speaker 1: so first of all Aladdin was way cool, right.
Speaker 1: It was all kind of action II with the magic carpet.
Speaker 0: You know I remember watching Aladdin over and over again as a kid.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 1: Secondly Robin Williams genie you can't you can't ignore that.
Speaker 1: that's like 90% of the movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how can we not?
Speaker 1: you can't.
Speaker 1: that's like the first thing and I feel like it.
Speaker 0: funny still good It worries me.
Speaker 0: I think that that was the first Disney movie to do That level of pop culture reference to that degree.
Speaker 1: But notice the pop culture references were two things that were way old.
Speaker 1: They didn't do any references to things that were contemporary.
Speaker 0: is contemporary bullshit exactly?
Speaker 0: Aladdin would be like referencing I don't know Bugs Bunny today exactly.
Speaker 1: so Aladdin all its references are really old so it comes off like a Looney Tunes.
Speaker 1: It doesn't come off like a Shrek or it's you know if you made a.
Speaker 0: you know Looney Tunes were not References to old things when they were happening.
Speaker 1: no they weren't but it works now.
Speaker 1: So when Shrek is way old is it gonna look like Looney Tunes.
Speaker 0: No because Shrek movies are bullshit.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: And Aladdin doesn't have that many.
Speaker 1: Aladdin isn't heavy on the pop culture references.
Speaker 1: It just has a few up.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't say it's heavy on them because there's a lot of other stuff going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it is they.
Speaker 0: they're a significant portion of the humorous dialogue.
Speaker 1: Some amount of it.
Speaker 1: it says it's just gonna genie does impressions a lot.
Speaker 1: That's the biggest part of that you know.
Speaker 1: and there's also some other Some jokes in one-liners here that refer to things.
Speaker 0: I think it was also just that.
Speaker 0: in general a lot of the cast was pretty big.
Speaker 0: So there was a. you know this is kind of from the era when Billy Crystal was still a big deal.
Speaker 0: he wasn't in this movie, but people like that were doing voice acting for movies and Now there's nostalgia for a lot of those kinds of actors because they're not in the cut those kinds of things as much anymore Mmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's you know.
Speaker 1: Aladdin has what a lot you know pretty much the right mix of all the things right.
Speaker 1: It's got the pile of comedy.
Speaker 1: It's got less of the mushy mushy stuff that you know.
Speaker 1: say Beauty the Beast would have more of you're gonna.
Speaker 0: What is this 1992?
Speaker 0: That's right?
Speaker 0: Wish he was.
Speaker 1: how old was I?
Speaker 1: when I watch this I'm trying to go back into the past.
Speaker 0: Yeah when I was the I'm right Jack my only impression of the mushy mushy stuff in Beauty and the Beast was that the beast was Way cooler as a beast and was kind of lame when he turned back into a person.
Speaker 1: 100% true Yep, 100% right, but the other thing Aladdin really had is that the bad guys?
Speaker 1: Were actually somewhat likable and interesting.
Speaker 1: Jafar is one of my favorite Disney villains ever right, and he's got you know Iago sidekick I'm the bird from Aladdin.
Speaker 1: You kidding me all right so but you look at say Beauty and the Beast right, and it's what that Gaston guy.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: no one likes him.
Speaker 1: He's just a jerk.
Speaker 1: there was someone at Kinetic on cosplaying is there was good great cosplay But it's like he's just an asshole.
Speaker 1: It was the bad guy in Little Mermaid.
Speaker 1: there really isn't one.
Speaker 0: Gaston wasn't the bad guy in Beauty and the Beast Beauty the Beast was much more complicated.
Speaker 0: There wasn't course.
Speaker 0: the bad guy was the Beast himself.
Speaker 0: He was his own bad guy, but villains villains are.
Speaker 1: What makes awesomeness right?
Speaker 0: What makes awesome Disney animated Star Wars Luke Skywalker?
Speaker 1: No?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Darth Vader.
Speaker 1: Yes How it is.
Speaker 0: Obi-wan also yes.
Speaker 1: Han Solo also yes, but not as yes as Darth Vader.
Speaker 0: 3po not so much.
Speaker 1: What was the number?
Speaker 1: there are many reasons why episode 1 is shit.
Speaker 1: the number one reason?
Speaker 1: Episode 1 is shit cuz Darth Maul was shit Right.
Speaker 1: if it should have been if there's more mall that would have saved half that movie.
Speaker 0: Darth Maul should have been a square boss.
Speaker 1: That's exactly should have been.
Speaker 1: so he was.
Speaker 1: they had all the character design the double lightsaber.
Speaker 1: They could have made him the next Darth Vader instead.
Speaker 1: no one gives a fuck about Darth Maul.
Speaker 1: fuck him.
Speaker 0: I gave a fuck until I saw that movie.
Speaker 0: But Jafar and Iago way awesome Jafar wins for one reason one primary Jafar is a lot like rezo.
Speaker 0: He's so thin and his face is so tall and his mouth is sometimes so tiny and sometimes bigger than his head.
Speaker 0: That is why I like Jafar also.
Speaker 0: He's evil, and he's smart.
Speaker 0: look at his plot.
Speaker 0: He's like.
Speaker 0: I'm doing this I'm doing this.
Speaker 0: I'm doing this and it basically does it.
Speaker 0: It's just he gets the lamp, and he's like yeah What now I wish I'm the most powerful wizard ever.
Speaker 0: fuck y'all that's right.
Speaker 1: boom goes the dynamite.
Speaker 1: What you gonna?
Speaker 1: Do?
Speaker 1: what are you gonna?
Speaker 1: Oh, it's a Disney movie, otherwise.
Speaker 1: I would not have lost.
Speaker 1: yep uh Let's see what else.
Speaker 1: What's not good about Aladdin.
Speaker 1: Uh well Culturalism yeah that I didn't recognize it But now is so blatantly obvious.
Speaker 0: the thing is it's it doesn't bother me for the reasons You'd expect because when the movie came out American culture really was completely tone-deaf to that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: no one's no one even noticed.
Speaker 0: No in general pop culture and but look it's like you know.
Speaker 1: if we did had made progress by that point right it wasn't song Of the south.
Speaker 1: we've learned that lesson up.
Speaker 1: We just didn't learn.
Speaker 0: what bothers me is not the things people complain about about this movie in a general sense with Arabic or Persian culture.
Speaker 0: what bothers me about it is that the characters themselves do not act in any way like the archetypes of Those actual kinds of stories and do not draw at all from that culture except to the most superficial manner.
Speaker 0: yeah Aladdin is not an Aladdin.
Speaker 0: He's not a character from that world in that era at that time.
Speaker 0: Aladdin is a 90s American Stereotypical snotty boy, that's right.
Speaker 0: He is a Bart Simpson.
Speaker 0: He is a Zach Morris.
Speaker 1: Totally is way more Zach Morris than a Bart Simpson.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's an earlier Bart Simpson, but yes Jack What are they?
Speaker 0: they're the.
Speaker 0: they're the cool slacker kid.
Speaker 0: yep the they're they're they're sticking their.
Speaker 1: No one likes Aladdin.
Speaker 1: everyone like this.
Speaker 1: it's all about sidekicks in this movie.
Speaker 1: right Iago Genie carpet Apu the monkey.
Speaker 0: yep right even the tiger a tiger tiger, right?
Speaker 1: It's all about the sidekicks all the all the main characters.
Speaker 1: Sultan sucks.
Speaker 0: I like the Sultan right in fact for even though it's for Aladdin and Jasmine, so I don't know why but for whatever reason Every time I picture the Emperor in the Prince of Nothing I picture him is looking like the Sultan from Aladdin.
Speaker 0: Yes, what?
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: because that makes everything.
Speaker 1: I think of him looking like evil Julius Caesar Who's got like some sort of wilting disease except that he's old.
Speaker 1: so I know you're talking about the cinemas, or are you talking about?
Speaker 1: This deal whatever?
Speaker 1: yeah Not zinnim is Serious.
Speaker 0: yeah, I'm talking about serious right anyway.
Speaker 1: No not canvas.
Speaker 0: no No canvas is like a perfect Adonis of a stupid people with their ex named ex like six religion sins.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I picked.
Speaker 1: your confidence is like Alexander the Great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, which is picturing this his uncle as being the Sultan from Aladdin.
Speaker 0: That's just how I picture him great But yeah, but my problem is just that the characters act from 90s Western culture perspectives despite the fact that they are superficially Persian.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: that is the part that bothers me not the the lyrics of that opening song or anything else and the stereotype of the evil Vizier.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: in the real world viziers are 99% evil.
Speaker 1: yeah No, I'm more bothered by the stereotype of the guy at the beginning like it was like the little the like the the Bedouin You know merchant ghosting in his song.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: He's like.
Speaker 1: Oh check this lamp.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you this story.
Speaker 1: Oh, I am all stereotypical.
Speaker 0: I might as well be in punch-out Yeah, but he bothered me less than the fact that Aladdin just looked like.
Speaker 1: so Yeah, I mean he bothers me as much as soda pop in ski vodka drink.
Speaker 0: Right it's.
Speaker 1: it's the same amount of.
Speaker 1: you know nationalistic Stereotype you know racist bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yep if anything what this movie taught us between this and the Lion King is that Disney hates uncles.
Speaker 0: Sure uncles and viziers are the worst possible people.
Speaker 1: So it's got some songs.
Speaker 1: Musical like a Disney movie is but I think what puts it ahead of other Disney movies is that Multiples of the songs are good.
Speaker 1: like I would listen to that if I came up on mp3 player.
Speaker 1: I would not push next.
Speaker 0: You know it's funny because I have a digital piano like with weighted keys like it's a full-on piano.
Speaker 0: It's the kind of thing you'd use on a stage in a concert if you didn't want to have a real piano for a lot Of reasons.
Speaker 0: a professional electronic piano, but it's old.
Speaker 0: it costs a lot of money.
Speaker 0: But we got it in the 90s.
Speaker 0: so it holds up pretty well today, but for its time It was good technology.
Speaker 0: it has MIDI capabilities And it was pre-loaded with a bunch of songs to kind of show off how what it can do.
Speaker 0: Two of those songs are from Aladdin nice nice.
Speaker 0: So that really shows you the widespread idness of Aladdin getting in everyone's business.
Speaker 1: like other Disney movies You know even the musical ones.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: maybe they have one song you like or maybe they have zero.
Speaker 0: There is a song from from another Disney movie that is better than any song in Aladdin Which is be prepared in The Lion King.
Speaker 1: that one's okay?
Speaker 0: That's that might be my favorite Disney song ever.
Speaker 1: Jungle Book.
Speaker 1: it's hard to beat Alright Robin Hood you and your Robin Hood.
Speaker 0: I really like that Robin Hood.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen it.
Speaker 0: I I have not seen that Robin Hood since I was a little kid.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to see it again.
Speaker 1: Anyway, and also Dumbo tough tough to beat whoa.
Speaker 0: wait a minute.
Speaker 0: There's a. I just learned something crazy about that Robin Hood that I got to remember to look up later What it had an alternate ending.
Speaker 0: that's way different cool?
Speaker 0: Well, there's a lot of words.
Speaker 0: I gotta read those later.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I didn't know that anyway anyway, uh I Wonder if we watch this now if we would find the genie at any point fun.
Speaker 1: Well, I I think I'd find it funny when I was a kid, but I'd memorize.
Speaker 1: That's pretty good.
Speaker 0: It's all jokes like that those.
Speaker 0: just the thing is those jokes feel likely.
Speaker 0: those kinds of jokes that kind of delivery is cliche in Animated kids movies today, but back then it kind of made the cliche.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 0: So it's kind of like when you read old Heinlein you're like What is this super stereotypical sci-fi bullshit, it's like no that was the first story to do that.
Speaker 1: shut up shut up Yeah, I think I still find it funny mostly because when I was a kid I watched it so many times.
Speaker 1: it lost funniness simply because I 100% memorized everything and now I've forgotten as much of it over the course of 20-something years that It's probably some of it will come back to me like oh, I remember that lols.
Speaker 0: I remember being annoyed at his wishes because he was just dumb.
Speaker 1: but that okay Yeah, I forgot to mention, but the real Aladdin was dealt.
Speaker 1: the real Aladdin the real Aladdin The story of Aladdin was equally done with his way No, but I think that what bothered me not so much was what he used the wishes on Aladdin because Aladdin is already done.
Speaker 1: It's the manner mostly of the second wish right where he's just sort of like drowning and the genie shakes him And that makes his head nod and he's like okay, and that counts as a witch.
Speaker 0: It's like fuck you, but he would have died.
Speaker 1: that doesn't count as a wish.
Speaker 1: you could pick him up nope He did all sorts of other stuff for him without making a wish.
Speaker 0: See if I were him I would have wished to have all the powers of a genie without any of the restrictions of a genie.
Speaker 1: But it's like he wished to be a prince.
Speaker 1: He's like okay, but he gets all this other shit to go along with it.
Speaker 1: It's like where the hell that come from that's all the yakuza amount of being a prince Yeah, and it gets like free travel to places like prismo only.
Speaker 0: It's the reverse of a monkey spa.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he basically gave him way too much stuff for free and then you know he gave him the the freebie to like you know Get him out of the desert or whatever.
Speaker 0: Why didn't he?
Speaker 0: just well because princes don't come from tombs.
Speaker 1: no remember He was like oh that you know there's a. he tricked him in early in the movie And he like.
Speaker 1: he's like oh, you know a man I'd like to gather this desert or whatever or out of the cave and he tricked him and they went to an oasis.
Speaker 1: Right and they didn't cost him a wish for that.
Speaker 1: So why did it cost him a wish to go out of the bottom of the ocean?
Speaker 1: the genie is clearly capable Basically if you can't off girth the rules of just kind of a dip.
Speaker 0: maybe the genie has inscrutable rules.
Speaker 1: Because he is the genie was not sticking to the letter of the law.
Speaker 1: a rules lawyer would affect that.
Speaker 0: The rules are incomprehensible to mere mortals, and he is acting on a different plane that we cannot apprehend sure Notice?
Speaker 0: I said apprehend and not comprehend right whatever?
Speaker 0: It could be something like that.
Speaker 0: Hmm, but Aladdin should just wish to be an all-powerful wizard, and then done all the rest of it himself also.
Speaker 0: a Part of the moral of the story is if you want to get with a girl You need to totally fake it until to trick her into going with you And then you can apologize later for that and still get all you did.
Speaker 1: all you did wrong was just lie about Being a prince, and then she totally saw through it because he's a doof and it didn't matter.
Speaker 1: But that the only thing she was mad about was the fact that he lied.
Speaker 1: yep the end, but it's like If she was you know as intelligent as she you know acts right.
Speaker 1: she acts like she's really smart.
Speaker 1: you believe that she's smart.
Speaker 1: But if she's so smart she like oh He obviously has to do this because he doesn't realize I don't care.
Speaker 1: So if I just said that I don't care he would have been like oh, okay good.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm just Aladdin, but she didn't say that It's like.
Speaker 1: obviously he has to lie.
Speaker 1: you couldn't get in the palace.
Speaker 1: otherwise what the fuck was he supposed to do?
Speaker 0: Wish to be an all-powerful wizard and just appear in the palace be like yo It's me Aladdin.
Speaker 0: Yeah, seriously.
Speaker 1: She didn't be like.
Speaker 1: oh, it's you Aladdin.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I slowly saw through your thing.
Speaker 1: You don't have to be lying anymore because whatevs I like you even though whatever, but she didn't say that.
Speaker 1: so really it's they're both dumbasses.
Speaker 0: Did you ever watch the sequel?
Speaker 1: okay?
Speaker 0: So sequels.
Speaker 1: I watched the second and third movie.
Speaker 0: I watched the second.
Speaker 0: I got it on a VHS tape from a supermarket.
Speaker 1: the return of Jafar.
Speaker 1: people do not like But I like.
Speaker 0: here's my problem with.
Speaker 0: I like the genie's powers Severely diminished.
Speaker 0: you come bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I don't even matter anymore.
Speaker 1: But the second one has one good song in it which right for a direct-to-video.
Speaker 1: That's pretty damn good right there right to pull off with that movie.
Speaker 1: the second movie did with a direct-to-video.
Speaker 1: I like it.
Speaker 1: I saw it less times.
Speaker 1: We did have it on tape.
Speaker 1: I couldn't had it on anything else.
Speaker 1: yeah, and I saw it less times and less reason might have it.
Speaker 0: You got a laserdisc.
Speaker 1: no But that second one I liked third one was basically the same as the Aladdin TV show.
Speaker 1: take it or leave it.
Speaker 0: Huh apparently Robin Williams originally didn't want to play the genie.
Speaker 1: Really, what did he want to do?
Speaker 0: they created a reel of his stand-up?
Speaker 0: And they animated it with the genie and then they just forced him to watch it and he laughed so hard He's letting.
Speaker 0: he agreed to do the project.
Speaker 1: Yeah, could you not?
Speaker 0: yeah, I wonder if that's available.
Speaker 0: What do I can find that real?
Speaker 0: But yeah, I did not like.
Speaker 1: that would be the most amazing thing.
Speaker 0: if you could find it on YouTube I'm gonna type for it right now.
Speaker 1: I've been like Robin.
Speaker 0: Did you watch the TV show?
Speaker 1: I watched some episodes of the TV show.
Speaker 1: It's not that good It's terrible.
Speaker 1: It looks like those are just clips from the movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can't find it with.
Speaker 1: I might have to do a little more research to find it sure But yet the story behind the TV show I read this whole article about.
Speaker 1: I think I might have made it thing of the day News once or something but basically there was an article that I'm not gonna search for now that talked about why Disney Afternoon died and basically it was cuz.
Speaker 1: Executives at Disney kept switching around and the there's some executives at Disney that really valued the high quality Animation on TV and that was the era of the Disney Afternoon.
Speaker 1: and the executives switched Right sometime in those early 90s around the Aladdin, you know times and those executives are like hey We just want to make a lot of monies.
Speaker 1: Let's take our hot movie properties turn them into TV shows and use that and that way we can sell the same movie and TV merch and Monies.
Speaker 1: and who cares about if it's any good and it wasn't any good.
Speaker 0: No good.
Speaker 1: Not where you know DuckTales.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you want to watch.
Speaker 1: it does a torrent for every DuckTales.
Speaker 1: You're downloading that shit - nobody's serving or downloading the torrent of every Aladdin TV episode.
Speaker 1: I shouldn't say that because someone probably is but DuckTales torrents probably got mad seeds.
Speaker 1: Yo mad seeds.
Speaker 0: So Maybe we should watch the movie again and we can do a little follow-up to see if it holds up.
Speaker 1: I bet it does.
Speaker 0: I'll bet it does too.
Speaker 0: I Really want to watch the furry Robin Hood again.
Speaker 0: now all you how about the Aristocats?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's okay.
Speaker 0: I remember really liking the Aristocats as a kid.
Speaker 1: I mean a lot of them are not you know bad It's all.
Speaker 1: these movies are pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's just not as good as the other ones like Dumbo Mickey the mean thumb.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.