Speaker 0: It's Monday, November 18th, 2013.
Speaker 0: I'm Rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights Tonight, streaming live.
Speaker 0: Streaming live.
Speaker 1: Mom.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Alright, go ahead.
Speaker 1: You're way too excited for Monday.
Speaker 0: I'm not that excited.
Speaker 1: You're being loud and eh.
Speaker 0: How am I being- I'm not being really any different from how I normally am.
Speaker 1: Eh, quiet down.
Speaker 0: What are you?
Speaker 0: You got a case of the Mondays, Garfield?
Speaker 0: Monday no good?
Speaker 1: I need some lasagna?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: This morning, I think it started off bad because I was making some breakfast.
Speaker 0: Wait, Juan, making breakfast, that's your mistake.
Speaker 1: Dude, I bought a package of bacon, and I just been making bacon every day.
Speaker 0: I do not have the wherewithal to get up early in the morning and make anything.
Speaker 1: I just have a pan, and I put fire under it, and I put the bacon in it, and that's it.
Speaker 0: See, I make bacon for dinner.
Speaker 0: I'll take bacon and like wrap it around a spera.
Speaker 1: I might do that, too.
Speaker 1: You should do that.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm only one person.
Speaker 1: A whole package of bacon is so much bacon.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I was making some English muffin, and you know, you cut a muffin in half over the sink.
Speaker 0: Juan, you don't cut, you tear.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: English muffins are already perforated.
Speaker 0: Just tear it in two.
Speaker 1: No, because I got the high, high density English muffins.
Speaker 0: Even then, just tear it in two.
Speaker 0: That way you have nice nooks and crannies.
Speaker 0: You don't want a clean cut.
Speaker 1: The clean cut still has nooks and crannies due to the nature of an English muffin.
Speaker 1: The nook and cranny is identical.
Speaker 0: I would argue.
Speaker 1: You just lose less crumbs if you cut it with a knife.
Speaker 0: But the crumbs stay in if you tear it off effectively.
Speaker 0: You're just bad at this.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I'm cutting it over the sink, so crumbs fall in the sink.
Speaker 1: All right, and then I drop the English muffin in the sink.
Speaker 0: Was it your last English muffin?
Speaker 1: No, but they only come in even numbers, so now I have only, that one was no good, so I got rid of it because it was full.
Speaker 0: Wait, how do them coming in even numbers in any way impact your use of them?
Speaker 1: Well, because I lost one, and I had to eat two, so now there's only one left.
Speaker 1: So even though I buy another package, I'll have seven.
Speaker 0: So you eat two per day?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't eat one at a time.
Speaker 1: So now it's like I'll always have like this one oddball English muffin unless someone comes to my house to eat it or something.
Speaker 0: You know, sometimes when I come home from work, I'll just toast an English muffin and put some butter on it.
Speaker 1: Just one?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Aren't you hungry after?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then you know what I do after we do Yink Nights?
Speaker 0: I make dinner.
Speaker 1: No, I can't.
Speaker 0: It's just a snack.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and one English muffin is not.
Speaker 0: One English muffin is a snack.
Speaker 0: It's like eating some crackers.
Speaker 1: Daddy two English muffin.
Speaker 1: There's a reason they're stacked up too high in the package.
Speaker 1: So.
Speaker 1: I think it even says serving size two muffins.
Speaker 0: So well, the other option, Scott, is to get the gigantic English muffins instead.
Speaker 0: They come in four packs and they're twice as big as a single English muffin.
Speaker 1: But then if I drop one in the sink, that's even worse.
Speaker 0: But then you don't have this even odd disparity.
Speaker 0: You're just down one and nothing else changes.
Speaker 1: That's correct.
Speaker 1: But I've lost so much.
Speaker 0: Imagine Homer talking to Dr.
Speaker 1: You're putting more eggs and less baskets.
Speaker 0: It's like Homer talking to Dr.
Speaker 0: Hibbert when he was like, we could cut off the other's thumb for symmetry.
Speaker 0: Yeah, symmetry.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So, uh, having my glass, I have to say that your experience of people asking you dumb questions has not been my experience.
Speaker 1: I think my theory is that it's where you work.
Speaker 1: I work in tourist town and you work.
Speaker 0: I work in like downtown in Tribeca, like financial, like right next to World Trade Center, where all the exchanges and all the B.S.
Speaker 0: is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it's different people down there.
Speaker 0: But the best questions I got were from this punk kid like this, this most thuggy looking like little punk kid who was just having some sort of fight with one of his other punk kid friends.
Speaker 0: You know, punk kids doing their punk kid thing.
Speaker 0: And he's like, whoa, is that Google Glass?
Speaker 0: And he comes over.
Speaker 1: So he did ask if that was Google Glass.
Speaker 0: But he knew the answer.
Speaker 0: Is that Google Glass?
Speaker 0: Oh, shit, man.
Speaker 0: And then he starts asking me all these specific questions about it.
Speaker 0: Like, how's the screen look?
Speaker 0: Is it as high res as they say?
Speaker 0: Can you see the pixels?
Speaker 0: Like he starts asking these really specific and detailed that specific that that was the beginning because he saw the resolution online and, you know, the documentation that's out there.
Speaker 0: And he was like, can you see the pixels?
Speaker 0: Like how far away does the screen look like it is?
Speaker 0: Do you turn it on all the time?
Speaker 0: Is it only on when you're doing stuff?
Speaker 0: Can you make vines with it?
Speaker 1: No, you can't make vines.
Speaker 1: That's going to be a killer act.
Speaker 0: The only thing is useful for the vine people that are making app day one.
Speaker 0: They better already be working on the vine.
Speaker 1: It's Twitter and they have the Twitter app.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, I fixed my Twitter thing.
Speaker 1: People may not know there's a hidden feature of Twitter that I learned about.
Speaker 1: Go to Twitter on the website and go to click on your own profile and then delete the account and that will make Twitter more usable.
Speaker 1: And then click on the part where it lists everyone that you are following.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So it's the big list of everyone that you are following.
Speaker 1: And then next to each person will be a little picture of a person.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The person icon that looks like a Fisher Price Main Street person.
Speaker 1: And you click on that as a little pull down menu.
Speaker 1: And one of the items in that pull down menu is turn mobile notifications on or off.
Speaker 1: You can turn on mobile notifications, for example, on, say, the PAX Twitter account.
Speaker 1: So every time it tweets, no matter what, you'll get a notification just as if they were to say at message you or direct message you.
Speaker 1: And you can basically make certain Twitter accounts like higher priority.
Speaker 1: So you'll just always get notified by them no matter what, because those are like tweeting important things.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So I somehow was getting all these tweets on my Google Glass and I didn't know why.
Speaker 1: And that's why I stopped using the Twitter app on Google Glass.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, I had curated that configuration extensively.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know it existed.
Speaker 1: And then apparently I don't even know how some of the oldest it seems like probably early on when I was using Twitter, every person I was following had that no matter what.
Speaker 1: It's like my 10 oldest things I've been following.
Speaker 1: all had that.
Speaker 1: So I had to go and I found out and I was like, oh, and I turned them all off.
Speaker 1: And now everything is cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm still using it.
Speaker 0: I still I found now that it looks like the relationship between Rochester Optical and Google is a semi-official.
Speaker 0: Like I saw some press releases.
Speaker 0: They're going to have prescription glasses official through them.
Speaker 1: Too bad you don't have your free prescription glass money anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I still have an FSA that I put money into pre-tax.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't put any money in there.
Speaker 0: But I don't know if I want to wait till January to get non because right now the fake lens, like the lenses I put in to make this work that I just had laying around my ski goggle inserts, they look like glasses that a dad would wear if he was nerdy in 1982.
Speaker 0: So I might get an optician to make me custom lenses ahead of January because I don't want to wear it looking like this for the next two months.
Speaker 0: And I do want to wear it at MAGFest.
Speaker 1: Oh, and you just get laser eye.
Speaker 0: Because they say if you get lazy, you shouldn't use Google Glass.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: Google straight up warns against it.
Speaker 0: It says, talk to your optician seriously or your optometrist, actually.
Speaker 0: Don't use Google Glass if you got LASIK unless your optometrist says it's OK.
Speaker 1: What could possibly happen?
Speaker 0: Well, LASIK causes a few issues with your.
Speaker 0: I mean, they basically change the shape of the outside of your eye, the cornea.
Speaker 0: They don't change the lens.
Speaker 0: So there's some issues.
Speaker 0: like my mom got the old radial carotonymy and she lost a lot of her night vision.
Speaker 0: She'll get lens flares when they're bright lights at night, like on the road.
Speaker 0: That's just a trade off.
Speaker 0: Also, my vision is pretty bad.
Speaker 0: So I have a higher risk of failure for LASIK.
Speaker 1: It's a new eyeball.
Speaker 0: That's coming someday.
Speaker 0: I think in my lifetime I get new eyeball, Bato Eyes.
Speaker 1: I'll sign up for Bato Eyes, even though mine are perfectly fine.
Speaker 0: Because Bato Eyes look fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: Plus, would you really help Netrunner if people can't tell what cards I'm looking at?
Speaker 0: Just wear sunglasses like those poker people do.
Speaker 1: Not doing that.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: No one does that.
Speaker 0: So you would replace your flesh and blood eyes with cybernetic Bato Eyes, but you wouldn't put on a pair of sunglasses.
Speaker 1: Indoors, you would look really fucking stupid if you did that.
Speaker 0: I kind of often wear sunglasses indoors.
Speaker 0: It's really comfortable.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so in the news, I got two related things here that are related in a way that's tangential, because the core issue is that phone numbers, you know, phone numbers, like the number you use to dial someone on a phone, are obsolete.
Speaker 0: And I really wish they'd just go away.
Speaker 0: Like, they're sort of this link to a legacy world that no longer needs to exist.
Speaker 0: We just don't have a good...
Speaker 1: We could have it obscured by some sort of system.
Speaker 1: the same way DNS obscures IP addresses.
Speaker 0: We could.
Speaker 0: Or we could have a system where you register an email address and that email address is your phone number for all intents and purposes and have some laws to make sure that all voice over IP or voice landline or cell phone, whatever, carriers have to respect and use it.
Speaker 0: But I digress.
Speaker 0: Two things that are happening with phone numbers right now are kind of interesting.
Speaker 0: One, there's an article on Slashdot about giving phone numbers a reputation score.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: You need a database of all phone numbers.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Now, the idea is, and it seems like there's a couple of companies who want to try to do this, is that if you have phone numbers and let people flag them as spam and not spam and sort of gather data long enough, you could pretty much do what Gmail does to phones and just automatically block all those calls from the Democrats asking for money.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I really look forward to this future and all the people who are complaining about the privacy of this.
Speaker 0: Shut up.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I care more about not getting spam than I care about the privacy of a five to nine digit number that can be used to send audio to me.
Speaker 1: Same goes for everyone complaining about Google Plus comments on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Same deal.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: The Google Plus comments on YouTube thing.
Speaker 0: I, I would be with you guys from an ideological standpoint, except that the YouTube comment, I don't know, world ecosystem has proven that it is the bottom of humanity.
Speaker 0: So fuck you guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like if you want to comment anonymously on a YouTube video, that's a stupid thing to do anyway.
Speaker 0: Comment anonymously on your anonymous blog about that YouTube video.
Speaker 1: What is the point?
Speaker 1: Nobody will read it.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Nobody reads it on YouTube anyway.
Speaker 0: The net result is identical.
Speaker 0: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: Seriously, the people complaining about this are like, like they're appropriating all the words that actual freedom movements have used.
Speaker 0: And I'm just waiting for them to start using images of Shay to fight the oppression.
Speaker 0: But no, the other thing Google is doing that's scaring a lot of people, again, kind of unduly, I think, is there's a lot of buzz that with the new version of Android, they're going to use their own database to generate caller ID for you instead of using the phone system's database.
Speaker 1: Well, you can fall back on the phone system.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the people aren't mad that they're going to get the data.
Speaker 0: They're mad that their data is going to be used to populate it.
Speaker 1: So basically, if I call, they're going to look at your contact list and they're going to know, no, it's pretty simple.
Speaker 0: If you ever used a registered a phone number with Google for any reason, like if you authorized a super big YouTube account or something like a special thing or to like a recovery phone number for your Google voice or your Gmail,
Speaker 1: if you give someone information, they have it and they're going to use it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So the way they're going to use it, he didn't want to use it.
Speaker 1: Don't tell him to them in the first place.
Speaker 0: So if you ever call anyone with that phone number and they're using.
Speaker 1: Graham, I want to keep a secret from you.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So now I'm going to tell it to you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm going to tell you a secret by wrapping it in an encrypted container and then giving it to you without the private key with which to decrypt it.
Speaker 0: That's how you give someone a secret without giving it to them.
Speaker 0: But then I'd notice how I didn't tell Scott the info.
Speaker 0: But I digress.
Speaker 0: So if I call Scott and he has the new Android, then he will see a caller ID with my name and my Google Plus profile and all that stuff, even if my caller ID information was otherwise spoofed or wrong.
Speaker 0: Again, I'm totally OK with this because I don't think phone numbers have a reasonable expectation of privacy.
Speaker 0: I also think that the sort of the fact that we don't have access lists or any sort of controls to easily block and forward and reroute phone numbers like we can with everything
Speaker 1: else
Speaker 0: means that any loss of privacy is more than a billion times over, brought back in returns on the fact that I can use this information to not answer phones, phone calls that are from the Democrats.
Speaker 0: They seem to call me more than anyone.
Speaker 0: That's what I get for giving money to Obama back in.
Speaker 1: I finally have reached a point where I get no calls.
Speaker 1: I don't get snail mails.
Speaker 1: Well, part of it is I did nothing for the longest time.
Speaker 0: I had that Google Plus, not Google Plus, Google Voice integration through Sprint.
Speaker 0: So my phone number was a Google Voice number, but it was also my main number and my phone integrated with that.
Speaker 0: So I had spam blocking and all those things through Google Voice.
Speaker 0: But now I'm on Timo again.
Speaker 0: That whole deal with Sprint seems to have disappeared.
Speaker 0: And now I get all those phone calls that Google has been flagging and blocking for the last couple of years, mostly calls from the Democrats.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Don't give people money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the moral.
Speaker 0: Never give the Democrats money.
Speaker 1: So I bought this iPad Mini Retina.
Speaker 1: And the reason I bought it is because it's statistically well, not as easily.
Speaker 1: It does, period, have the best screen that a consumer can buy with money.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That is pretty good, right?
Speaker 1: In terms of pixels per inch and, you know, everything, every, you know, resolution.
Speaker 1: I mean, there are more pixels in this tiny thing than there are on your giant Dell right there.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Never mind all anyone who thinks that 1080p is high resolution.
Speaker 1: Seriously.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So, you know, just the fact that the screen exists, I probably would have bought just the screen if there was nothing attached to it.
Speaker 1: Just like, oh, here, have a screen, plug it into whatever you want.
Speaker 0: If I could buy a retina monitor right now for less than like two thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: Even this little tiny one, I would have bought four of these tiny ones and then made something that hook them up together in like a quad situation.
Speaker 0: Hell, I'd get rid of this giant goddamn monitor.
Speaker 0: I got here and just hang a retina display in front of my face and use that as my monitor.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I mean, this is it's basically the iPad Mini with retina is the same iPad as the iPad Air.
Speaker 1: It's only smaller, which means it's better because it has the same resolution.
Speaker 1: So the pixels are just, you know, much, much smaller.
Speaker 1: But there's just as many of them and the CPU is the same.
Speaker 1: It's just like underclocked, like a like a tiny, insignificant amount and is otherwise identical.
Speaker 1: So I don't see any reason to get the big one.
Speaker 1: It even weighs less than the big one.
Speaker 1: So the thing is, I want to warn people.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Why did I get an iPad and already had an iPhone and all this other stuff?
Speaker 1: Well, the reason is because I wanted to use it.
Speaker 1: I know I already said this before, but it's like, yeah, what would an iPad do for me?
Speaker 1: It would be more comfortable in bed and such like.
Speaker 1: every morning I wake up and I poke my phone and every night before I go to bed, I poke my phone.
Speaker 1: Now it's more comfortable to do so because it's slightly larger to use an iPad than an iPhone.
Speaker 1: And also, if I'm doing computing, that doesn't involve, say, doing a presentation at a convention or coding or doing anything for reals, then it's much smaller to carry around this tiny iPad.
Speaker 1: So basically, I have to do a podcast than a giant laptop.
Speaker 0: Any time you're looking at stuff as opposed to making stuff.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: If I don't need a keyboard, this thing is way smaller than the laptop.
Speaker 1: So my load is much, much lightened.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And the other thing is I can do cool stuff like there are certain things that use my phone for or it's better to use the iPad for.
Speaker 1: Like if I use my iPhone, I take pictures on my camera and then the camera sends the pictures to the phone.
Speaker 1: Well, now I can take pictures on my camera and send the pictures to the iPad where it's much easier to Photoshop them with the iPad Photoshop.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So I learned some things.
Speaker 1: Thing I learned number one, iPad apps and iPhone apps aren't necessarily the same.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 0: I have heard that from other people before.
Speaker 1: Sometimes, for example, you'll have a bad situation where I bought the real Photoshop for my iPhone.
Speaker 1: I go and I try to get the real Photoshop for iPad.
Speaker 1: No, that's a completely separate app, even though they're both called Photoshop Touch or whatever.
Speaker 1: They're completely separate.
Speaker 1: to buy both of them separately.
Speaker 1: Fuck you.
Speaker 1: I bought it anyway because that was one of the number one reasons I bought this thing.
Speaker 1: But fuck you.
Speaker 0: That appears to not be the case with any Android apps.
Speaker 1: And it has a lot of creative cloud integrations and stuff.
Speaker 1: So, you know, and like Adobe idea, that's free.
Speaker 1: So it's like it's all right.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: OK, so fuck you on that, too.
Speaker 1: Some apps are only iPhone apps.
Speaker 1: So it's like I want Delicious on here.
Speaker 1: That way I can like bring up a thing of the day I saved.
Speaker 1: It's like, nope.
Speaker 1: So I just got to go to it in the Web browser because the Delicious app is an iPhone app.
Speaker 1: It's not an iPad app.
Speaker 1: So fuck you.
Speaker 1: Three, some things are iPad apps and not iPhone apps.
Speaker 1: One time, Puerto Rico, the board game was on sale.
Speaker 1: So I bought it for like a dollar and then it wouldn't install on my iPhone.
Speaker 1: And I was like, fuck.
Speaker 1: And now that I have an iPad, it installed.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, oh, right.
Speaker 1: I bought that for a dollar because it's on sale.
Speaker 1: Now the user interface on it is God awful.
Speaker 1: Is it's pretty much play Puerto Rico in an emergency.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Play Puerto Rico with a physical board, guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then there are some good situations, though.
Speaker 1: Neuroshima Hacks, same app, works on both the interface.
Speaker 1: Just it's the same exact app, just bigger.
Speaker 1: It's when it plays on iPad.
Speaker 1: It actually the interface is different slightly, but better because it's bigger.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: As the same app and I paid for it already.
Speaker 1: So I had to pay for it again.
Speaker 1: I didn't have to pay for the armies again.
Speaker 1: It was just.
Speaker 1: it's the same app.
Speaker 1: It just looks different on the different devices of different sizes properly.
Speaker 1: So you don't have to pay for it again and again and again.
Speaker 1: And good job.
Speaker 1: Neuroshima Hacks.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: A plus.
Speaker 1: The thing I got to say about this is that you think, oh, I don't need an iPad.
Speaker 1: I already have an iPhone.
Speaker 1: I already have whatever.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That may be true.
Speaker 1: But the best the thing that this is really the best at that I didn't realize it would be the best at is if you are someone like me who has a two room abode.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: A bedroom and a living room.
Speaker 1: And you only have one television in the living room.
Speaker 1: The iPad is basically the perfect bedroom television.
Speaker 1: You do not need to buy a bedroom television.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You can just use this.
Speaker 1: And there are basically so many goddamn apps between Crunchyroll, Twitch, YouTube, Amazon Video, Netflix.
Speaker 1: I stopped paying for that, though.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I have a U-verse app, which is my parents have U-verse cable.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So I have their log in so I can use the U-verse app.
Speaker 1: So I can watch anything they've recorded on the DVR, anything that's on their on demand and a bunch of live channels just on the iPad, even if I'm not in their house.
Speaker 1: And if I am in their house, I can like program their DVR or remote control their TV with it and shit.
Speaker 1: It's pretty crazy.
Speaker 0: They really shouldn't have given you that password, should they have?
Speaker 1: I can also use it to like watch like the Red Zone and all kinds of crazy stuff.
Speaker 1: So that's pretty great.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, it's like it's like a bedroom television.
Speaker 1: The only thing now is that I may or may not see it.
Speaker 1: There's a Kindle app, right?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So it's like, oh, there's a Kindle app for iPad.
Speaker 1: Do I really need a Kindle?
Speaker 0: My answer is yes.
Speaker 0: For one, the Kindle battery lasts for like months, as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: Two, the Kindle is just.
Speaker 0: it's so light and small and one handed and simple that I and the way the screen is, the fact that the screen is a sort of a different kind of screen, the non backlit screen is a big difference.
Speaker 0: So I would keep my Kindle separate even if I had an iPad retina.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The thing is, it's like, yeah, that is those are slight reasons, but they're not humongous reasons.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it's like the battery in this already lasts a hell of a long time.
Speaker 1: And the text does look better if, you know, the backlight isn't bothering you.
Speaker 1: And right.
Speaker 1: It's the only thing, though, is that you the only books are going to.
Speaker 1: you can't drag books onto this.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The way you can drag books onto your Kindle like it's.
Speaker 0: So you only get the books that are in the app.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And not if you email something to yourself with that special email address, I think it'll show up for both.
Speaker 1: Maybe, but it's really hard to get pirated books onto the Kindle.
Speaker 0: Oh, I see what's going on here.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The pirated books aren't going to get on here that easily.
Speaker 0: So, you know, are you sure there isn't just like a directory you can stick stuff in for the app?
Speaker 1: Like, you know, search iPads are not hard drives, remember?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm wondering there's got.
Speaker 0: I'm wondering if there's someone who's already solved this problem.
Speaker 1: Maybe I don't know.
Speaker 0: Pirates.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it's possible book, but it's just not worth the effort.
Speaker 0: Retina text juggling e-book uses Dara to track pirates.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh, OK.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the only other thing I got to say is that Super Hexagon is way easier on an iPad, but all my skills are gone, so it's super hexagon was easier for me once.
Speaker 0: I just got my Nexus 4 because the processors faster.
Speaker 1: The processor on this is crazy fast for, you know, such a small device for them.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So a new Sony console came out.
Speaker 0: If you guys didn't notice the PS4, I maybe it says something about me and the kind of gamer I am lately, but I didn't notice that it came out until I saw Dave Riley tweeting something about how he was going to go try to get a PS4 on Amazon.
Speaker 0: I was like, what?
Speaker 0: That came out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's actually selling really well.
Speaker 1: But I'm surprised because as far as I know, there aren't really any games.
Speaker 0: Well, I think someone asked me, like, hey, if I got a PS4, what's the best game to buy for it?
Speaker 0: I think my response was same as the Xbox one Netflix.
Speaker 0: So this is a video, a news event, a news segment, I guess, from 1991 when another big company released their big console, the Super Nintendo Entertainment System.
Speaker 0: And this video is parents primarily complaining, how come Nintendo has got to release another one of these things?
Speaker 0: It's just going to cost us money and our kids got to stop playing these fucking video games, except for that giant study that just came out that said, yeah, yeah, great.
Speaker 0: No, they weren't saying it would make them violent or anything.
Speaker 0: They were just like.
Speaker 0: part of their complaint was the SNES cost twice as much as the NES.
Speaker 0: for what?
Speaker 0: Some better pictures.
Speaker 0: This watch this video on people who are old people now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, think of it this way.
Speaker 0: The people who are there are a lot of kids for whom the PS4 is going to be their first console, their first console, where Final Fantasy 14 is the first Final Fantasy they'll have ever heard of.
Speaker 0: They won't even believe their friend who says, yo, dog, I played Final Fantasy two.
Speaker 1: That is right.
Speaker 1: It's like if you think about it, you know, when you're into something, it's like the beginning, you know, it's like movies, TV, whatever.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like you don't see.
Speaker 1: kids were like Harry Potter.
Speaker 1: six is the first Harry Potter and they never saw Harry Potter one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that doesn't happen.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But I guess today I've never played Zelda one.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, you know, for Zelda, it was like Zelda 64 or even later Wind Waker, even later, you know, Minish Cat.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's like never played the old Zelda.
Speaker 1: You know, I feel like there's a show that really only happens in video games more than other media.
Speaker 0: It's not like Great Gatsby 2.0 comes out and like the new movie and everyone's like, no one reads the book.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Other media's don't have those long keep more keep coming things like that, you know, or when they do.
Speaker 0: It's a long running TV show like you have that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Some kid read starts reading Spider-Man today.
Speaker 1: He never read.
Speaker 0: What about Dr.
Speaker 0: Who?
Speaker 0: Most people who watch new Dr.
Speaker 0: Who never watched old Dr.
Speaker 0: Who.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they've seen all the new Dr.
Speaker 1: Who.
Speaker 1: They just haven't seen the old one.
Speaker 0: True.
Speaker 0: But I think there's a there's a differentiation.
Speaker 0: This is a Tuesday show idea coming or maybe a Tuesday panel, a gaming panel.
Speaker 1: So it's Simpson Simpsons.
Speaker 1: People saw some recent seasons of Simpsons.
Speaker 0: Some game sequels are a new and different game like Mario one and Mario two are different enough to where they're both completely valid.
Speaker 0: Well, if you're an American that are worth playing and don't find Mario one and Doki Doki Panic, they're worth playing on their own independently of one another.
Speaker 0: But then there are games like Call of Duty and a center Counter-Strike even where if you start playing today, you'd might as well just play the newest one and not bother with the old one.
Speaker 1: Well, they're not.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not like single player.
Speaker 0: Whatever it is, the difference between the replacement sequel and the here's a different game sequel.
Speaker 1: I think my kids do start playing Magic today.
Speaker 0: Right, except they have the lore about the old cards and they're all obsessed with Black Lotuses.
Speaker 0: But it's funny, like these kids, I see kids in like Netrunner and everything who will use the word tutor and they know what that means.
Speaker 0: But I doubt any of them have ever actually seen a demonic tutor.
Speaker 1: Everybody who is in the Netrunner scene in New York is someone who used to play Magic or you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, that's New York.
Speaker 1: I mean, like in the in the net runner scene is all people who know what gaming is like.
Speaker 1: It's 10.
Speaker 1: It's like PAX.
Speaker 1: It's older people, right?
Speaker 1: You know, I don't see a lot of young people playing.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like people said that my 20s, 30s, my experiences with Ingress were different from theirs.
Speaker 0: And I realize that's probably, again, because New York, there's like 200 portals within a short walk of any point that I'm at.
Speaker 0: It's not like out in the middle of Bumblefuck where there's literally one portal at like the interstate turnover.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So you know how.
Speaker 1: the bottom of the periodic table, there's all those elements and we know that they're made in the lab.
Speaker 1: You can't just find a way.
Speaker 1: Do you mean?
Speaker 0: do you mean the bottom, like the highest numbers or the series that's at the bottom because it's split out so the table fits on a piece of paper?
Speaker 1: Both of them.
Speaker 1: You got like the Einsteinium and then you've got the Unilenium and all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: I assume you're talking about the heavy ones, not the ones in the middle.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about all of them, all of the elements that have to be made by people.
Speaker 1: And you don't just find them lying around in the ground.
Speaker 1: OK, but pretty much anything heavier than uranium.
Speaker 1: OK, OK.
Speaker 1: So, you know, we know that they're made in a lab, but it's like, well, how how did the hell do they do that?
Speaker 0: By bouncing different sized atoms and molecules against each other to try to get them to stick.
Speaker 1: Well, here's here's an awesome YouTube video that shows you exactly how the hell they did that.
Speaker 1: So basically at Berkeley Lab, back in the day when they discovered Mendelevium, right, they discovered Mendelevium and then they created a video that reenacted the discovery of Mendelevium with the actual scientists who did the work and the actual labs where they did it.
Speaker 1: So it's like they did it.
Speaker 1: And then they made a video where they pretended to do it again and to show you exactly how it was done.
Speaker 0: Not bad.
Speaker 1: And the best part spoiler is they're in like the physics lab where they're where they're basically showering this thing with alpha particles to create the Mendelevium.
Speaker 1: And then they got to bring it up to the chemistry lab to do some fancy chromatography to to prove the Mendelevium is in there.
Speaker 0: You know, that was a moment I had in physics, like when I was taking AP physics in high school, we got into quantum stuff and we were learning about, you know, annihilation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, positron, antipos, you know, that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: And we, you know, that graph of the two spirals that they always show.
Speaker 0: So we were looking at that image and then our professor, our teacher says, yeah, that image is literally how they figured it out by measuring the curves with rulers on that picture.
Speaker 0: And then you look at a complex one of those pictures and realize that all these things they're deriving are from very low res, fuzzy looking pictures.
Speaker 1: But anyway, they try they bring this sample basically from one lab to the other, literally in a turbo Volkswagen Beetle.
Speaker 1: And it's like they're going because it's going to decay really fast to get it there.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And they actually, you know, the the exact car they use of the exact people, they drive it uphill like zipping around campus, trying to get the sample of the lab as quickly as possible.
Speaker 1: Pretty cool stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Now, if they'd only settle the name of Illyrium 115.
Speaker 1: That's what I would name it.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, live streaming because we're kind of streaming this episode in a moment.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: I guess we got the metamoment.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, I just got a bunch of live streams up.
Speaker 0: Rim is obsessed with streaming things live because you have done way more live streams than I have.
Speaker 1: exhibitionist Rim just wants people to have eyeballs on him.
Speaker 0: Oh, you want me to go to a YouTube playlist and you don't see anyone looking at me, the person.
Speaker 0: Let's see how many live streams Rim has done.
Speaker 1: I'm showing off things and I've shown off myself.
Speaker 1: Rim is, Rim is arrogant and trying to show himself off.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Camera's pointed at you now, not me.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: I don't want it to be pointed at me because it's a bad day.
Speaker 0: All the way zoomed in.
Speaker 0: I'm sad for my shoulder shoulder on the way here.
Speaker 1: I'm sad for my English muffin still.
Speaker 1: I'm in mourning.
Speaker 0: You had to write a Marceline style song about the English muffin.
Speaker 0: English muffin.
Speaker 1: Why are you so wet?
Speaker 0: You know, that's the worst when you drop a food that you really wanted to eat and there's that moment when you consider eating it anyway.
Speaker 1: At least I hadn't toasted it yet.
Speaker 1: It was going to the toaster.
Speaker 0: So like I remember I but I had an English muffin that had I dropped it, like imagine if it already had like the cream cheese on it.
Speaker 0: Had I dropped the English muffin pre buttering, I might have just kind of blown it off and eaten it, but I'd put the butter on and it fell face down.
Speaker 0: I picked it up and there was kitchen floor on that butter.
Speaker 1: There was all kinds of sink water all over the muffin.
Speaker 1: I thought it maybe was just on like a corner of it.
Speaker 1: I could have cut that corner off.
Speaker 0: The worst thing is when you've got some clean dishes and you knock one of them into the sink and you're like, ah, man, so I wash that shit again.
Speaker 1: I was putting a dishwasher tab in the dishwasher.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it was.
Speaker 1: it was like it was a weird dishwasher tab.
Speaker 1: It was malformed.
Speaker 1: So it's kind of big and oddly shaped.
Speaker 0: I had one of those break open like on my hand.
Speaker 0: Had this moment of.
Speaker 0: I hope this doesn't start burning.
Speaker 0: Mine are the solid ones are minor like powder and stuff in a bag.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I used to use that kind.
Speaker 1: Now I use the rock kind.
Speaker 1: I have a huge tiny way.
Speaker 1: I was putting it in there and this one was weird malformed.
Speaker 1: So I had to start to cram it in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But then when it actually washed the dishes, it didn't pop out because it was crammed in there.
Speaker 1: So it's like now I have to go like chisel it out of there because it cleaned the dishes.
Speaker 1: But I don't know if it.
Speaker 1: if, you know, it's like not even half of it was disintegrated.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it worked.
Speaker 0: All right, Scott, of the live streams we have done, let's see.
Speaker 0: Gemfire with Rim, Solar Jetman with Rim, Megaman 2 with Scott, Legend of Zelda with Scott, more Legend of Zelda with Scott.
Speaker 1: How many how many am I in personally seeing my face?
Speaker 0: None of our faces are in any of these.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about this right now.
Speaker 1: This is your idea.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's a bunch of listeners watching this live.
Speaker 0: I can see them commenting.
Speaker 0: And yeah, they're really sad.
Speaker 0: Mostly I did it to prove a point about streaming because.
Speaker 1: No, you did it because you were all excited, like, oh, man, people are going to look at me just like people looking at you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm saying I do like people looking at me, but that the end case closed.
Speaker 0: I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to deny that.
Speaker 0: the whole reason I started Geek Nights is that I wanted to have fans after I left RIT anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: News at eleven fans.
Speaker 1: I'm not doing it for you.
Speaker 1: Rim is and Rim's not doing it for you either.
Speaker 1: He's doing it because he wants you to eat for him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm doing it for me.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: That's how I roll.
Speaker 1: But the reason I'm doing it for the world is partly because the world needs geek nights.
Speaker 1: The geek nights it deserves.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I feel like streaming video games and live streams of things are beginning still to do the metamoment really stupidly popular late.
Speaker 0: The book club book is I don't know by William Gibson.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We've got a bunch of live streams that you can watch.
Speaker 1: Go to Magfest.
Speaker 0: We're going to be at Magfest.
Speaker 0: We're probably going to be doing a 90 minute version of the bad games panel that we did a pack.
Speaker 0: So I got to buy a couple more copies of E.T.
Speaker 0: to throw into the audience.
Speaker 1: I'm sure you can get some.
Speaker 0: I've got three.
Speaker 1: I'm sure on eBay we can find a lot of them.
Speaker 1: I actually what I kind of want to get a space, not a lot as in many, but a lot like a lot of 10.
Speaker 0: I'm confident that I could probably get enough cartridges of E.T.
Speaker 0: without spending much money to give to everyone who shows up to the panel.
Speaker 0: I don't think I'll do that because it's a pain in the ass, but I probably could.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Pax East is sold out.
Speaker 0: So if you didn't get badges, that really sucks.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: I can't say fuck you, because unlike ancient past when we told people to buy badges and then after the badges sold out, we asked you, why did you buy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the badges sold out like immediately.
Speaker 0: There's really nothing you could have done.
Speaker 0: It's just random.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights might be on again, off again during the holidays, but it'll pick up with gusto shortly after Magfest and the New Year.
Speaker 1: Because it's Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: It's Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Never stop.
Speaker 0: And yeah, that enough metamoment for you?
Speaker 1: It's OK enough.
Speaker 0: You want to do some more?
Speaker 0: You want to talk about our awesome forum?
Speaker 1: I think we've talked about that enough.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, live streams are getting really popular lately.
Speaker 0: I mean, the fact that a consumer product like the Elgato exists at the relatively low price point that it does says a lot about how popular live streaming stuff is getting right now.
Speaker 0: So I don't want to talk about the like gaming ramifications or anything of it.
Speaker 0: We're going to talk about the technology, how and why and what not not what you're not the societal reasons about like why people want to stream stuff.
Speaker 0: Who's going to watch it?
Speaker 0: How to make a good stream?
Speaker 0: No, we're talking about RTMP and bandwidth.
Speaker 0: bandwidth.
Speaker 0: I think is Scott's primary limiting factor in doing good streams.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing is that this streaming is becoming much more popular.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But so many of people's Internet connections are like tons of downstream with no upstream.
Speaker 1: Even Google, Google Fiber, which is fast in all the directions, had in like the user agreement, like no running servers.
Speaker 1: And that now they changed it to be like, OK, you can't basically run a business.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And what all they really want to do is keep is make you get hosting if you're going to run like, you know, a big Web site, because that's not what they expect you to use it for.
Speaker 0: But like I might.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like but I still want to be able to upload, say, videos to YouTube or, you know, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the issue is just that you have what, Time Warner?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, that you're fine.
Speaker 0: There's nothing that's like when you got Optus in Australia.
Speaker 0: So I have files, I have a lot of bandwidth and already you saw there's that article a while ago, like weeks ago, talking about something like more than half of the bandwidth consumed in the U.S.
Speaker 0: is just streaming video.
Speaker 1: That's yeah.
Speaker 1: But that includes like Netflix.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I'm saying that's consumer side.
Speaker 0: That's just the people watching.
Speaker 0: So if everyone's watching video, then we've got this asymmetric load where there's tons of downstream bandwidth that everyone needs to stream their HD video all the time.
Speaker 0: But if everyone's streaming stuff live up, then there's two more things that matter.
Speaker 0: You need upstream bandwidth, like Scott said.
Speaker 0: You need reliable bandwidth, which is kind of the same thing.
Speaker 0: And you also need the ability to encode that video live on the fly.
Speaker 0: Like when we do a lecture for Geek Nights, like those videos we upload from Apex, they're an hour long lecture, right?
Speaker 0: It takes my relatively powerful computer 12 to 20 hours to encode that video to then upload.
Speaker 0: It then takes it like two hours to upload and then it's on YouTube.
Speaker 0: So a lot of people are going to want to start streaming and not really realize that there's some severe limitations they're going to run into.
Speaker 0: And there's not a lot of help technologically to get you going.
Speaker 1: Well, the softwares that are available to consumers do a pretty good job of seeing how fast your computer is and seeing how fast your Internet is and adjusting the quality basically down until the stream is, you know, smooth, as smooth as it's going to be considering your CPU and your Internet connection.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, a lot of people will turn on streaming and it's like they'll be playing, I don't know, a PS4 with the Twitch built in stuff or who knows what or their PC with, you know, the some kind of X split or what's that?
Speaker 1: other thing people love?
Speaker 0: Flash Media Live.
Speaker 1: No, no, the I forget what it's called.
Speaker 1: Open broadcast.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: Well, I remember I had the Ustream thingy that I used at one point.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And they'll be using that.
Speaker 1: And the thing is, when they actually go to look at Twitch, it's like, oh, my screen is like 1080p and super awesome looking with full frames because I have a great video card.
Speaker 1: How come when I actually go and look at Twitch, it's all pixely and shitty?
Speaker 0: Or never mind the fact that a lot of people will try to capture video from their gaming PC with like flaps or something.
Speaker 0: Forget even streaming and simultaneously try to play the game on the same device.
Speaker 1: And then, yeah, my computer, which is too expensive, does that.
Speaker 1: But my old computer, if I tried to flaps, the frame rate on the game would go.
Speaker 0: Or even then, some people say you have the external device and you're doing the encoding in like an Elgato and it's all external.
Speaker 0: But then you plug that USB into your laptop and it's sharing the same network connection as your counter strike and your ping starts going up.
Speaker 0: You need a lot of bandwidth to upload video.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm uploading right now the stream live, which is 720p and not really great quality.
Speaker 0: I'm uploading at four megabits per second, four megabits per second.
Speaker 0: That's actually a lot of bandwidth.
Speaker 1: It is quite a bit.
Speaker 0: And that's actually a heavily compressed video, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my my whole Internet connection at home.
Speaker 1: I only have two up theoretically on paper.
Speaker 1: So I usually set the stream to like one point eight and I'll only stream like a single player game, not an Internet game that way.
Speaker 1: And I turn out all the other Internet's off in the house.
Speaker 1: So the stream basically gets to use all the upstream and leaving only like that point to just for whatever, you know, margin of error.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And that doesn't that doesn't get me to 1080p right.
Speaker 1: The quality is going to be like 480p or 720p at best.
Speaker 0: Even worse, a lot of people just don't understand how compression works.
Speaker 0: So they'll set their streaming thing to say, yeah, 1080p.
Speaker 0: But then they have low bandwidth.
Speaker 0: So they're uploading at a bandwidth that would really only be suitable for 480i, let's say.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So as a result, it sends 1080 pixels so heavily compressed that it looks way worse than if they just set it to 480 in the first place.
Speaker 1: I feel like the software should just not even give you the option if you're not a pro.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And just do things the right way.
Speaker 0: Let's get into this.
Speaker 0: The technology one, assuming you have no specialized hardware, you need software that's going to basically read your frame buffer, like read the video that's being displayed, compress it using something like H.264, and then upload the stream of the audio and video live at a consistent rate to another location.
Speaker 0: And separately, if you want a copy of it locally, also write it to the disk.
Speaker 0: like the stream right now is not being written to any hard drive in our house.
Speaker 0: I'm just streaming it.
Speaker 1: So if YouTube fucks up, it's gone forever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's gone forever.
Speaker 1: Except for the audio part.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the audio part is being saved in like four locations.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: the consistent part is the really hard part with home Internet connections, because like, yeah, theoretically I have two megabits per second, but it's like, you know, you're watching Netflix and sometimes even the downstream, it'll be like, oh, pixely for a second, oh, laggy for a second and we're back to HD.
Speaker 1: The upstream is even worse.
Speaker 1: if you lose a little bit of upstream.
Speaker 0: Suddenly it's like, so thus a lot of you kids will be streaming something, right?
Speaker 1: You're still.
Speaker 1: the computer is like still CPU encoding, like the same quality, the same bit rate, the same everything.
Speaker 1: So the network hiccups, it's sort of like a big traffic jam.
Speaker 1: And it goes, oh, shit.
Speaker 1: And it fucks everything up.
Speaker 0: So a lot of you kids will complain that you're looking you're trying to play your game through the thing you're streaming with.
Speaker 0: And then the stream that you see is delayed by several seconds.
Speaker 0: That's because you got to buffer that shit, son.
Speaker 0: Now, the other trouble is that a lot of the consumer oriented software designed to do this stuff doesn't let you twiddle all the bits that you might need to twiddle to do it all right, because
Speaker 1: if you're if you're not a tech person, you're not going to know what bits to twiddle anyway, so maybe less is better.
Speaker 0: But then, like even with external hardware, like the Elgato is a device that's designed for morons.
Speaker 0: It has HDMI in and HDMI out.
Speaker 0: So HDMI comes out of my ex-boss into this thing, out of this thing to the TV.
Speaker 0: So it just sits in the stream, reads the raw video.
Speaker 1: It does the encoding.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't matter if your CPU sucks because it does the encoding part.
Speaker 0: And then it sends the encoded data over USB to a computer.
Speaker 0: that then sends it on to YouTube or whatever and has an interface where you tell it.
Speaker 1: I don't know why they didn't just make an Elgato that was HDMI in and out and then power and a ethernet cable.
Speaker 1: So it just, you know, streams itself.
Speaker 1: Why do you?
Speaker 0: Because that would have been more complex.
Speaker 0: The software does a lot of the work with this thing, actually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but what you could do is you could.
Speaker 1: just for if you plug the Elgato into your networks, it streams directly to wherever it's going to stream to.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And when you want to connect to the Elgato to control it, it's running a web server and you visit its website like one nine two one six eight one dot whatever.
Speaker 0: Scott, how many people do you know that can't find their own router on their own network to configure it?
Speaker 1: There would be a software that came with the Elgato that you would double click on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like the readiness software that I've watched people fail to use.
Speaker 1: You double click it when you put in a disk or whatever or go to the website, you double click on it and it would pretty much just send your web browser to the Elgato.
Speaker 0: And here's the real answer, in my opinion, because this is not prosumer.
Speaker 0: It is consumer consumer level media equipment or just consumer level.
Speaker 0: Anything.
Speaker 0: the difference between consumer and prosumer is that a consumer level thing will not do anything that is useful for an expert if it costs any amount of money to do.
Speaker 0: Having an ethernet and having to configure all that and have that in the device would make the unit marginally more expensive.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, doing all of that in software, relying on the fact that the software is running on a general purpose computer is cheaper.
Speaker 0: Some developer in India or whatever is way cheaper than a hardware guy, I guess, and way cheaper than the incremental cost of manufacturing.
Speaker 0: Also, for the kinds of people who are using this device, they would not not buy it if that feature wasn't there.
Speaker 0: I mean, we both bought it.
Speaker 0: The problem is that a lot of the software like the Elgato is a great example.
Speaker 0: You tell it like, oh, I want to stream to YouTube and you type in your credentials and it just works, meaning if you start streaming, it immediately starts sending your stream to YouTube live and everyone starts seeing it immediately.
Speaker 0: But you can't like really preview it to see if it'll work.
Speaker 0: You can't like time the start.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you start streaming and watch every stream people put up.
Speaker 0: There's a few minutes of like, hey, is this thing working?
Speaker 0: I don't know, like poking around trying to make sure it's working before they start.
Speaker 0: Because these things don't give you good error messages.
Speaker 0: They don't give you any insight into what's actually happening.
Speaker 0: In fact, the Elgato only recently got an update that lets me do raw RTMP so I can ignore all of its bullshit and I can use the real YouTube live event interface and just say, here's the URL and the streaming key.
Speaker 0: And then I get this whole command console.
Speaker 0: Like right now, I can see who's looking at the stream.
Speaker 0: I can see all the streams I'm sending and if my bandwidth is good and pretty much everything.
Speaker 0: So I can actually see if the stream is going to work first and then start it when I'm ready, as opposed to losing my Gemfire stream because I didn't realize it stopped working because the Elgato didn't tell me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the one thing that really bothers me is that, you know, you can make RTMP streams or you can stream with like Twitch API, like directly to the service you're using.
Speaker 1: And you're really.
Speaker 1: why would you want to use it these days?
Speaker 1: I think you stream and such are pretty much dead.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much just Twitter, YouTube for pretty much anything you can do.
Speaker 1: But it's annoying that you can't use like a streaming device as a webcam.
Speaker 1: Like it's a webcam is different to a computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Then a streaming device is because a webcam has to be nominally real time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sure.
Speaker 1: But it's like I want to be able to use Google Hangout with the Elgato.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So then we can, you know, or I want to be able to have like a webcam and my Elgato going to a Google Hangout so we can all webcam and see each other's faces in the hangout.
Speaker 1: We can also see the game I'm playing and talk about it or, you know, stuff like that.
Speaker 1: But there's no way to do that because, you know, the on your local computer, Google Hangout is looking for a webcam using webcam API.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because normal people don't care about using anything other than that or other than a screen shot.
Speaker 1: If I take a real camera and plug it into the Elgato, I can't use that in Google Hangout.
Speaker 1: I can only.
Speaker 0: why would you bother?
Speaker 0: Google Hangout compresses the video so much and you have so little.
Speaker 1: It's not about the quality of that video.
Speaker 1: It's about the content of that video.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: If I have, you know, I can get different, you know, my webcam is like a little USB cable and I can only move it so close to whatever computer.
Speaker 0: Scott, you want you want a USB cable extender?
Speaker 1: No, that's not even going to help the situation.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You're going to hold this little tiny webcam, whatever.
Speaker 1: If I have, you know, my GoPro or some sort of, you know, real camera that, you know, is got like an HDMI cable going to the Elgato, then, you know, I can do things like, you know, I can get much better shots.
Speaker 0: And even if the quality is low, your use case is not in any way profitable to pursue because nobody can stream a video game into Google Hangout.
Speaker 1: You can't do that with a webcam.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But that's because that's not what it's designed for or what anyone cares about.
Speaker 1: There are people who want to do that.
Speaker 0: Not enough people to be first for it to be profitable to set something like that up.
Speaker 1: I don't even know why.
Speaker 1: Why is it different, though?
Speaker 1: It should just be, you know, why aren't all streaming devices just seen as WebKit?
Speaker 1: It's no different.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Just make everything the same API.
Speaker 1: It's streaming video into the computer.
Speaker 0: Well, because it's not it's not.
Speaker 0: you have that with things like Firewire, Scott.
Speaker 1: No, but that won't go to Google Hangout.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, you realize why is a webcam any different?
Speaker 1: It should all be the same.
Speaker 0: Scott, partly it's because webcams all rely upon the software that's installed.
Speaker 0: Life cams don't work for shit unless you install the special Microsoft life cam software.
Speaker 1: No, there's just.
Speaker 1: it's like there is in Windows and on OS X and on Linux.
Speaker 1: There's like, you know, this in the operating system is like a webcam API where the operating system is drivers and recognizes webcams.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a specific kind of device.
Speaker 0: And you have to follow that contract.
Speaker 0: I'm saying most people don't care.
Speaker 0: So there's no reason to do that.
Speaker 1: I think there's more people who want that than you realize.
Speaker 0: I'm not if there were if there's enough people that want that.
Speaker 1: Google Hangouts on air become pretty popular.
Speaker 1: They've even added some features for Google Hangouts on air to where you can like take questions and all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: And I'm saying that it only works with a webcam.
Speaker 1: So it's like if you're doing some cool Google Hangout with right, you can't use your real streaming stuff for it.
Speaker 0: So buy a real, real streaming device that gives you all those capabilities.
Speaker 0: It has like four HDMI ins and it's a PCI Express card and it's crazy expensive.
Speaker 0: Buy one of those things.
Speaker 1: But it's just all.
Speaker 1: they could even do with the Elgato if they would just write a stupid webcam driver for it.
Speaker 0: Yes, but why haven't they?
Speaker 0: Because no one's going to not buy it if it doesn't have that functionality.
Speaker 1: Sure, whatever.
Speaker 1: That's the reason I'm just saying it's it's.
Speaker 1: it's a concern, right?
Speaker 1: Is that different different places to stream to and from and different softwares?
Speaker 1: Well, Scott, look, it's the same thing with audio.
Speaker 0: It's the same thing with audio.
Speaker 0: If you have like I have a really good mixer and I have a lot of really good Firewire audio equipment.
Speaker 1: But it's all just recognized as sound.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: It is in a sense.
Speaker 0: But if you want to use Steam or something and you want to tell it, yeah, use incoming interface eight from this device B as my microphone in Counter-Strike, it won't fucking do that.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: Because it won't.
Speaker 0: It'll only.
Speaker 0: it'll only use the first interface it saw because no one wrote the software to handle this.
Speaker 0: because no one cares.
Speaker 1: It works for me when I try to use different inputs.
Speaker 0: Which inputs on which kinds of device?
Speaker 1: If it shows up as an input device.
Speaker 1: Yes, as an audio input device in Windows.
Speaker 1: Then you can go to the Windows Audio Center and set it as your default input device and then go to Steam and say input microphone.
Speaker 1: This is choose that one.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: So I set the Mackie Onyx as my input device.
Speaker 0: It has like 24 channels that it can send.
Speaker 1: Aren't those all seen as separate devices?
Speaker 1: No, they're not.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's a problem.
Speaker 0: That's most audio software and most audio hardware.
Speaker 1: It should show up if it's got it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it could show up.
Speaker 0: The software just doesn't support it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it should show up as like 20 sound cards.
Speaker 0: Case in point.
Speaker 0: My I have a device that's just a firewire input.
Speaker 0: It's just a plug.
Speaker 0: It's not a mixer.
Speaker 0: You just plug a bunch of devices into it and it gives you individual channels via firewire to the PC.
Speaker 0: If you tell the Ogato to use that device, it'll only ever see audio from microphone one and doesn't even see the line inputs or any of the other inputs.
Speaker 1: See, the people who wrote the software for those firewire devices should have written it as such that Windows didn't see this one magic weird device.
Speaker 1: Instead, it saw like 20 normal boring.
Speaker 0: And my point is that no one cares enough to bother because it's not worth money to do.
Speaker 1: do it a different way.
Speaker 1: Do it something that makes some non standard proprietary thing.
Speaker 1: That's always easier.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it usually is for these people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's people who make hardware always write the shittiest software.
Speaker 0: Dude, good hardware has shit drivers in general.
Speaker 0: The Mackie drivers.
Speaker 0: Not so great.
Speaker 0: Wake up every hardware that great.
Speaker 1: Every software that ever comes to the hardware is always been shit forever.
Speaker 1: And it's like all they do is make things worse.
Speaker 1: Why do you even write the friggin software at all?
Speaker 1: If you make hardware, don't even write drivers for it.
Speaker 1: Just let the default OS drivers just take care of it.
Speaker 1: Don't do anything.
Speaker 0: That's not going to work so well.
Speaker 0: for like a mixer.
Speaker 1: It could work just fine because it would show up as like it was a 20 channel mixer.
Speaker 1: Show up as 20 completely normal generic sound cards.
Speaker 0: That's not how it would ever work.
Speaker 0: And that's not how it works now.
Speaker 1: You could easily make it work that way.
Speaker 0: They're not separate devices.
Speaker 0: They have a synchronized clock.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of reasons why it's not that way.
Speaker 1: They could still be synchronized.
Speaker 1: They would just show up as far as Windows is concerned as 20 normal sound cards.
Speaker 1: That way, everything that used sound cards would work with them.
Speaker 0: Except, you know, it wouldn't fucking work.
Speaker 0: Adobe Audition needs to see the device as a unit.
Speaker 0: If it showed up as 20 devices, you could only record from one of those at a time.
Speaker 1: Oh, so that it would.
Speaker 1: just why can't you record and do things at a time?
Speaker 0: Because their clocks won't be synchronized.
Speaker 0: You can still.
Speaker 1: it would be synchronized on the other end.
Speaker 1: You don't know.
Speaker 1: that needs to know about that.
Speaker 0: It doesn't know that.
Speaker 1: It doesn't need to know.
Speaker 1: You can.
Speaker 0: It also it depends on if you like as API or was API and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: It's that's all.
Speaker 1: it's one of those things where we've already been dug into a hole and there's no way out anyway.
Speaker 0: At least try getting all this to work on Linux.
Speaker 1: So kill yourself.
Speaker 0: So, guys, the way we stream stuff now.
Speaker 1: By the way, Atari car E.T.
Speaker 1: cartridges are like a dollar on eBay.
Speaker 1: So I'm sure you can get a stack of them at like Magfest or something.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: So the way we stream stuff is.
Speaker 0: we bought these Elgato devices like we keep mentioning because they're just a box HDMI in and out.
Speaker 0: I don't even use the HDMI out most of the time.
Speaker 0: I don't use it in stream.
Speaker 0: I just use it as it's like a ghetto video capture.
Speaker 1: I actually got a video, an HDMI splitter for my Elgato.
Speaker 1: So that way, for example, let's say I have my PC in a stream.
Speaker 1: What the PC is showing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But I want to stream it using that PC as well.
Speaker 1: Usually my HDPC.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'll take the HDMI out from the HDPC into the Elgato.
Speaker 1: If I take the HDMI out from the Elgato into my TV, then I won't be able to see what's on the TV unless the Elgato gets turned on.
Speaker 1: The only way to turn the Elgato on is to turn on the Elgato software.
Speaker 1: But how can I turn on the Elgato software if I can't see anything?
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I use case for the Elgato is?
Speaker 0: I got my Xbox and I want to stream my Xbox in.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So what I do is I will just with the splitter that, you know, the output from the splitter goes to the TV so I can always see what the HDPC sees on the screen.
Speaker 1: And there's just an output going to the Elgato to the Elgato's in.
Speaker 1: And I'm not using the out from the Elgato for anything at all that.
Speaker 1: And you get this cool sort of infinity effect when you open Elgato software.
Speaker 0: But so we use the Elgato just because it does the encoding and everything in a separate device where you have to worry about any hardware.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it won't slow your computer down.
Speaker 1: But, you know, your CPU in your computer is only playing the game and isn't doing any video encoding.
Speaker 1: It's only doing a little bit of TCP/IP to do the uploading.
Speaker 0: So right now I have my, the Geek Nights camera basically kind of pointed at us and the HDMI out of it, which just shows raw video pre-encode over HDMI from what the camera sees.
Speaker 0: It's just showing whatever the camera sees.
Speaker 0: In fact, if I turn the screen around, I think it'll actually show like the camera's stats and everything, like all the menus just in the stream.
Speaker 0: And that's just going into the Elgato and I'm running the software and it's streaming to a YouTube live event, which I set up to be a 720p stream.
Speaker 0: And I set the bandwidth and I set all this stuff and it gave me a streaming key and a streaming URL.
Speaker 0: And I plugged it all in and it just worked.
Speaker 0: When I stream video games or something, I just put the Elgato in line between my HTPC and the TV.
Speaker 0: The Elgato is plugged into my laptop, which is sitting next to me with a headset plugged into it.
Speaker 0: And then that's how I get my voice into the stream.
Speaker 0: And again, I use the YouTube live event or the Twitch, whatever, and it just works.
Speaker 0: So I wonder at what point we're going to see the prosumer level stuff, because right now with this kind of work, there's consumer and pro.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot in the middle ground yet.
Speaker 1: No, not at all.
Speaker 0: Not a lot of software, not a lot of hardware.
Speaker 1: But as more and more people are streaming, especially on Twitch, you know, the demand for things that help you with that is only going to increase and the upstream bandwidth required by, you know, the ISPs is only going to increase.
Speaker 1: So and I don't see the popularity going down anytime soon.
Speaker 1: People freaking love to watch other people play video games, which I don't understand.
Speaker 0: Like I saw a lot of people watch that stream.
Speaker 0: I did a Gemfire.
Speaker 0: And seriously, that is a tedious fucking game.
Speaker 1: Salty bet.
Speaker 0: But Salty Bet is not tedious.
Speaker 0: Watch Gemfire that game.
Speaker 1: I'm not watching Gemfire.
Speaker 0: But like I went through and watched a whole bunch of like popular let's play videos.
Speaker 0: They have like hundreds of thousands of views.
Speaker 0: And I can't imagine why anyone would watch them.
Speaker 1: One guy at my work, he watches like these Ocarina of Time videos a lot.
Speaker 1: I guess it's because his game.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it's he says it's because he doesn't have time to play games anymore.
Speaker 1: So he just watches them.
Speaker 1: But why did you get takes the same amount of time as playing it?
Speaker 1: No, because he just like has it on while he's doing work.
Speaker 1: He's like Scott Johnson driving multitasking bullshit.
Speaker 0: Just experiencing what the game looks like without playing Ocarina of Time before.
Speaker 0: So why does he need to experience that again?
Speaker 1: He's minorly reliving Ocarina of Time.
Speaker 1: I guess he's also watching speed runs and shit.
Speaker 1: You know, I guess.
Speaker 0: Well, so here's an example of the complexity of what.
Speaker 1: maybe somebody will watch the video and someone will find do something you wouldn't do and show you things you never saw.
Speaker 0: So here's a complex thing that we can do with streaming.
Speaker 0: We think we're going to try to set this up at Kineticon.
Speaker 0: No promises.
Speaker 0: So in one of the panel rooms, we want to take our two Elgatos, plug them into laptops.
Speaker 0: And have two cameras hooked up.
Speaker 1: We're not going to have any Internet in there.
Speaker 0: We're going to get physical drops if we do this.
Speaker 1: How are we going to get them?
Speaker 0: You can just pay the convention center for it.
Speaker 1: Who's paying for it?
Speaker 0: The Kineticon.
Speaker 1: Are they really?
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: Unlikely.
Speaker 0: We're talking about it because it would be a good promotional thing.
Speaker 0: It's in discussions.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not that expensive to set the stuff up.
Speaker 1: Why some panel room?
Speaker 0: Because we're going to do it ourselves.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't.
Speaker 0: I don't control main events, so I don't want to spend all my time working on main events.
Speaker 1: So I'm saying as far as the con is concerned, why not?
Speaker 0: Wouldn't the con want to stream main events?
Speaker 0: You would want to stream like the you'd have.
Speaker 0: you need a video person to like pick the right camera angles live and stream that thing.
Speaker 0: And there aren't as many events in there.
Speaker 0: It's lower risk to do a streaming live thing of the panels first.
Speaker 0: But anyway, plus we're just doing it.
Speaker 0: I mean, who's going to do it if we don't do it?
Speaker 0: So we can set up two Elgatos with two cameras and we can actually send two streams to YouTube in a YouTube live event.
Speaker 0: The YouTube live event will let viewers pick which stream they want to watch.
Speaker 0: That's OK.
Speaker 0: Like camera angle a camera angle B.
Speaker 1: Can they get picture in picture?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I've never used it before.
Speaker 0: I only know on the back end.
Speaker 0: if we wanted to be redundant, we could have four Elgatos, two cameras with two camera angles streaming directly to YouTube and via like a different connection, like a 4G something at a lower resolution to a backup URL on the off chance that something goes wrong along the way.
Speaker 1: If your Internet goes down, your stream is still alive.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Lower res maybe.
Speaker 0: We can use the Mackie Mixer that I can stick in the room to get the good audio from the microphones in the stream instead of either camera's audio.
Speaker 0: And then we can also and this is key.
Speaker 0: And whenever you're streaming stuff, you really need to think about this.
Speaker 0: The stream workflow, the path of signals that gets to the YouTube stream is entirely independent of the archival record.
Speaker 0: If you want to do something with video later, you need to record all the audio and video raw locally to hard drives completely independent of your stream.
Speaker 0: So we would also have laptops recording everything.
Speaker 0: And I'm a ranch.
Speaker 1: Well, the Elgato software has a record button you can press.
Speaker 1: that does the job.
Speaker 0: But you got to make sure you do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Push the button and have enough hard drive space.
Speaker 1: Usually an external one, because the one in your laptop is not going to be big enough.
Speaker 0: But unless you have a shitty laptop without an SSD, then you probably got like a terabyte in there.
Speaker 0: And then if you ever so then you'll have the live stream event.
Speaker 0: And once it's done, you have to take all that video and edit it into your sort of final cut and then upload that later, much higher quality, because the stream will never be as high quality as what you could encode with a better encoder that takes longer.
Speaker 1: What I want to be able to do is add graphic and I know how to add graphics to something that's recorded.
Speaker 1: Just go to After Effects and put them on there.
Speaker 1: How do you do it to the live stream?
Speaker 1: Like which software?
Speaker 1: Everyone's doing it.
Speaker 1: But what software are they doing it with?
Speaker 0: See, because I use the Elgato, I have no way to do that.
Speaker 0: You need something in the live stream, like between the video being recorded.
Speaker 1: I want to know what the hell these people are using, because I can't do that.
Speaker 0: Have you done any research?
Speaker 1: A little bit.
Speaker 0: Do you think like explain because Ustream could do that?
Speaker 1: Well, no, I don't think it's not using Ustream.
Speaker 1: They're on Twitch.
Speaker 0: I know I'm saying the software I used for Ustream could just do that.
Speaker 0: Google Hangouts can just do that.
Speaker 0: I'm sure whatever software they're using has some panel where you can have PNGs with transparency that you just turn on and off, something like that.
Speaker 0: There's no good way to do that in YouTube.
Speaker 0: So if I wanted to do any sort of motion graphics in my stream, I'd either need another camera angle to switch to, or I would need to have something in my HDMI workflow before it hits the Elgato, inserting that stuff.
Speaker 0: The real answer is if you care and you're doing this for real, buy a TriCaster.
Speaker 1: If you're mad rich.
Speaker 0: Kickstarter guys, buy Rim and Scott a TriCaster.
Speaker 1: Sounds like a good Kickstarter to me.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.