Speaker 0: It's Monday, May 6th, 2013.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, what to do with your bits when your meat stops working.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I won't belabor the point, but many of you noticed on Twitter, in recent memory, I was arguing a bit with Ask.com because they stupidly responded to my tweet.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Usually that kind of place is not going to respond to an aggressive tweet.
Speaker 0: I never understand.
Speaker 0: It's like, well, the thing is, do not engage.
Speaker 1: Usually they do not engage.
Speaker 0: It's telling that Oracle did not engage at all.
Speaker 1: I don't think Oracle engages with anybody.
Speaker 0: Because Oracle does actually know better.
Speaker 0: But Ask.com engaged, especially Ask.com Eric, and then magically they suddenly stopped engaging once the retweets started happening.
Speaker 0: So the funny thing at the very end of that, I guess they saw the Streisand effect coming in the headlights.
Speaker 0: Well, I kind of gave them a hint in my Tumblr where I was basically like, if you're Ask.com, don't engage people like me.
Speaker 0: My job is to catch you saying something stupid in public.
Speaker 0: But really the reason I bring it up now is that I am actually mad about the fact that semi-legitimate software like Java has bundled shitware in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, usually that's the realm of shit software, right?
Speaker 1: It's like some guy makes a piece of shit program.
Speaker 1: You know, he includes some, you know, auto install nonsense in the installer to make money.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of thing that shady crapware does not super pro real.
Speaker 1: So you don't see Adobe doing that.
Speaker 1: Oh, wait, you do McAfee when trying to install a flash plugin.
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But you know, usually real software does not do that.
Speaker 1: It's a low life thing to do.
Speaker 0: So I don't know what to do about it because Java, I mean, unless Oracle drops it, it actually causes problems.
Speaker 0: Pretty much everyone who has a company that makes Java using software and it's not easy to just rewrite everything in another language.
Speaker 0: So I'm just mad about that lately and I'm not going to let it go.
Speaker 0: That's all I got there.
Speaker 0: That's my opening bit.
Speaker 1: Well, I actually, because of this, I learned about this really interesting thing I didn't know about before.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: You sent me a link about this called Ninite or nine night N I N I T E right.
Speaker 1: And what this thing is, I think I'm going to start using this.
Speaker 1: Um, it's malware.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: I verified this.
Speaker 0: How'd you verify it?
Speaker 1: I went and asked around and I went to, did you ask people?
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Just cause a lot of people we know install a lot of wares.
Speaker 1: I also checked around the internet in multiple places.
Speaker 1: that are the kind of places that verify malwares and can be trusted, right?
Speaker 1: Including like security websites.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: And yeah, there's a lot of like.
Speaker 1: NASA uses it like legit NASA or NASA and it's not just because it says on the front page that NASA, Harvard and Tupperware all use this.
Speaker 1: I actually went and checked to see if NASA actually used it and they do.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So the way this thing works is you go to this website and there's a bunch of check boxes, right?
Speaker 1: And this check boxes, I realized looking through it for pretty much every app that I would install on a windows computer.
Speaker 1: Here's the ones that I would pick up.
Speaker 1: Chrome, Firefox, steam, Google earth, maybe.
Speaker 0: Um, you know, I always install Google earth.
Speaker 0: I haven't actually used it in like three years.
Speaker 1: Skype, maybe Google talk or pigeon or whatever.
Speaker 1: All the IM clients are on there.
Speaker 1: iTunes, VLC, maybe Hulu, Winamp, maybe right.
Speaker 1: Spotify maybe.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So it's basically like a repo, but for windows, Java, uh, Adobe air shockwave, silver light flash, right?
Speaker 1: Um, pretty much everything.
Speaker 1: VNC client launchy.
Speaker 1: I use launchy seven.
Speaker 0: I don't use launchy anymore.
Speaker 0: I used to win RAR because windows just kind of does that now.
Speaker 1: The window, the thing in the start menu when you push the window key is not that good.
Speaker 0: I've never started typing something and not had it immediately give me what I wanted.
Speaker 1: The thing is I have launchy configured to do one thing.
Speaker 1: It's just, I have in my home because you know how sometimes you get applications that you double click set up that exe and they install properly, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And they go into program files and they create start menu icons.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: And the window key works great for that, right?
Speaker 0: Window key works for bullshit.
Speaker 0: I dragged putty onto my desktop and it shows up in there really.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But what happens to me is I'll take something like door fortress, which is an unzip and I'll put it inside, you know, users me applications, a folder I made.
Speaker 1: If it's an unzip type application, I put it in there and window key hasn't been finding those.
Speaker 1: and I don't really want to go through the effort of making a start menu shortcut.
Speaker 0: I think there's a way to configure it because window key finds bullshit that I drop in like my home direct.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Also, I really like the keyboard shortcut.
Speaker 1: Alt space as opposed to window key.
Speaker 0: Ah, true, true.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's a minor whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Putty is actually something that's on here.
Speaker 1: Um, but yeah, basically you go to this website, you check the check boxes for all the apps you want to install and you click get installer.
Speaker 1: Then it'll give you an exe, right?
Speaker 1: And you run that and it will install all the apps you chose.
Speaker 1: So you don't have to go around the internet like finding all the windows apps that you normally get and you know, collecting all these things except I guess Nvidia drivers not on here.
Speaker 1: Uh, but other than that, right, you just go to this one place, get one installer for all your apps and run it and your windows boxes set up so fast.
Speaker 1: This is even has useful stuff.
Speaker 1: You get the pro version for like assisted men administering a whole bunch of windows machines.
Speaker 1: You can like, you know, set all the windows machines to like, okay, everybody upgrade when amp everybody install open office.
Speaker 1: You can do star Libra office now, right?
Speaker 1: You can do stuff like that with this thing.
Speaker 1: So this allows you to install a Java without an ask toolbar, the sun Java and people were, I think Adobe I think was going after night for cause it was skipping the McAfee, whatever
Speaker 0: the fact that Adobe went after, it seems to be how most people learn that exists.
Speaker 1: It was a Streisand effect for me for sure, but um, this thing is totally awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm going to use this the next time I have a windows box.
Speaker 1: I need to set it from scratch,
Speaker 0: but it's interesting because years ago I would have said that the biggest problem normal people have with their computers, especially laptops, is all the shit where that OEMs bundle and then Microsoft kind
Speaker 1: of allows them to, I'm telling you if Microsoft, right, here's the thing with windows.
Speaker 0: Well, I was about to say it doesn't matter anymore because people don't use computers.
Speaker 1: They use already too late, but windows got a bad rap with a lot of people in the world, right?
Speaker 1: Because of all these perceived problems with it, especially windows Vista and such, right?
Speaker 1: If windows would have put a Microsoft would have put their fist down their foot down and said, if you install anything on a computer that is pre-installed with windows besides windows, you do not get a discount from us.
Speaker 1: You have to pay full retail price for every copy of windows.
Speaker 1: Every single OEM, like Dell and everybody, it was the least bad and they still bundle a bunch of shit, but at least you can uninstall it properly.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Every single one of those people would have stopped immediately, right?
Speaker 1: Or they would have fought first, but they would lost.
Speaker 1: They would have stopped installing garbage, like replacing the windows, wifi with a bullshit wifi manager.
Speaker 1: All that shit would have gone away, right?
Speaker 1: Except drivers.
Speaker 0: I just still don't understand how the ecosystem got to the point where that worked.
Speaker 1: I mean, windows would have had a much better reception among people because using it would have been much more of a pleasure.
Speaker 1: It would have been the intended experience and not this fucked up.
Speaker 1: Oh, my computer's broken because the person who sold your computer broke it.
Speaker 1: It's not Microsoft.
Speaker 0: Who like, how is, where did the money actually come from?
Speaker 0: So maybe McAfee pays like Lenovo to include it in their bullshit.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 0: I can understand those cases, but then how does McAfee make that money back?
Speaker 1: Who is paying right?
Speaker 1: I understand that like McAfee will pay Lenovo to include like antivirus free trial.
Speaker 1: That makes sense.
Speaker 1: Who pays Lenovo to include Lenovo wifi manager?
Speaker 0: I think they do it on their own for a better user experience, but it's, it ruins it.
Speaker 1: The built in windows wifi manager is amazing and great.
Speaker 1: It works perfectly fine.
Speaker 1: Why would you cover it up with this Lenovo one that sucks and is ugly.
Speaker 1: And at the same time, everyone gets really confused.
Speaker 1: Cause now there's two wifi managers.
Speaker 0: You're only ruining it.
Speaker 0: I think what I find the most amusing is that Lenovo and other people always do this kind of ineptly.
Speaker 0: They'll add things to the task bar and they try to make them look like a battery manager.
Speaker 0: Now, but the thing is the battery manager, like.
Speaker 0: obviously it's just slightly the wrong color and just like kind of the wrong bezel.
Speaker 0: And it's obvious that it shouldn't be there.
Speaker 0: Though at least to us, to normal people, they have no fucking battery manager does include some things you can't do with the windows one involving actually controlling some deep parameters in the battery, right?
Speaker 1: You should be doing that in a driver, right?
Speaker 1: For the battery.
Speaker 1: That handles the battery properly without changing the user interface, right?
Speaker 1: Whatsoever.
Speaker 1: And windows actually includes facilities to do things like that properly.
Speaker 1: Like in video, when you go to video properties, right inside your video properties, there's like a thing for the video driver to go to the Nvidia control panel.
Speaker 1: It's done correctly, even though it's this extra thing, right?
Speaker 1: It's still done properly in the windows way.
Speaker 1: It's not some like ugly hack where to change resolution, you can't use the windows change resolution thing anymore, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, no, they put the extra Nvidia controls in the Nvidia area in a special tab and all the windows stuff is still the windows stuff.
Speaker 1: It's done correctly.
Speaker 1: Got to do with that.
Speaker 1: You know, anyway, the no one would complain.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't complain if I bought a laptop that had the Nvidia driver preinstalled.
Speaker 0: I think the moral is pretty simple.
Speaker 0: Don't tolerate bullshit.
Speaker 0: bundle where and whenever a semi legitimate company includes it, call them out on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I'm tired of this shit.
Speaker 0: I'm tired of uninstalling like nine toolbars when I visit grandma.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I mean, this is an issue that's like 10 years old.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: Kind of like how Congress only recently was like, maybe they shouldn't be allowed to make the volume higher on ads on TV now that no one watches TV anymore.
Speaker 1: Good job old guys.
Speaker 0: Why don't we close that barn door that seems to have opened a little while ago?
Speaker 1: Oh, it'll get all warm in here if we don't have the ventilation.
Speaker 0: So you got any news?
Speaker 1: I don't have a news, but I have something I discovered today.
Speaker 1: Oh, so you know, a Google authenticator, which everyone should be using, right?
Speaker 1: The two factor authentication because you know, there's a big problem these days of basically people have shitty passwords and everyone guesses them and then they say they got hacked when really they just had a shitty password.
Speaker 1: I think about over 99% of the time when someone says someone was hacked, it was password got guessed or password got found out.
Speaker 1: Well, if someone finds out my password for something, even though he's a different password for everything, that's okay because they would also need not to only have something I know my password, but to have something I have my phone.
Speaker 1: I'm the only one who has my phone because they need Google authenticator to log into my mails and such, right?
Speaker 1: So that is the best security we have in the modern day because the odds of someone stealing your phone and knowing your password are pretty low.
Speaker 0: Though, if you're stupid, there's probably a way to steal your phone.
Speaker 1: You'll know your phone is stolen and you can disable it and reset everything before they are able to do it because they're already logged into your mail in your phone.
Speaker 0: They disabled two factor with the settings and then they reset all your passwords.
Speaker 1: Basically, we can do this smart and they physically stole your phone.
Speaker 1: You're already fucked.
Speaker 0: Well, the moral, actually, it's interesting because physical security used to be a big deal in computers, but really in the modern era, email security is more important than everything else for normal people.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: If your email account gets compromised, you're fucked and there's almost no way to unfuck yourself.
Speaker 1: This is why you need to use two factor authentication for security, even though it may be a hassle, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: You say it's a hassle now and you don't use it.
Speaker 1: And then when someone guesses your shitty password that you have as a really easy to guess password because you were lazy and it's a hassle, right?
Speaker 1: I'm going to say, I told you so.
Speaker 1: You deserve it.
Speaker 1: Your life is ruined.
Speaker 1: Good job, loser.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so there are other things, though, besides Gmail, you might want to have two factor authentication for.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Now, if you're a rich company, you pay for like the RSA little key fobs with the counting down numbers.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Or you could get a YubiKey, but that requires a piece of hardware that's a USB and can only be used on things with USB like laptops and computers.
Speaker 1: Not really so much as phones.
Speaker 1: So if I like have a YubiKey secured website and a log in for my phone, I can't do that easily.
Speaker 1: That's very hard to do, if not impossible.
Speaker 1: What phone has a USB on it that works and can allow a USB keyboard to be plugged?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, my phone technically has USB storage internally.
Speaker 1: Yes, but what if I probably four pins that I could.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So if you if I take a USB keyboard with a mini adapter and plug it into your phone, well, you can recognize it as a keyboard phone.
Speaker 0: Find the USB pins that are connected to the store.
Speaker 1: Even if you did that, does it have the drivers in Android for USB human interface device for keyboards?
Speaker 1: I'm actually kind of curious that so that a keyboard would work.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying it'll work.
Speaker 1: I'm saying that's what it would take to make YubiKey.
Speaker 0: It would work.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so you really would like to use this Google Authenticator, which is where you just open an app on your phone and it shows you the number and the numbers change all the time.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But that's for Google, right?
Speaker 1: It's not for anything else.
Speaker 1: Well, I enabled two factor authentication for Linode this week when they added it and I realized, oh, look, they're using Google Authenticator.
Speaker 1: How are they doing that?
Speaker 1: Did they make a deal with Google?
Speaker 1: What what the hell is going on here?
Speaker 1: How they do this.
Speaker 1: And here's how they do this.
Speaker 1: There is this completely open thing called TT TOTP time based one time password algorithm.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Or I guess time based one time pad.
Speaker 0: You get the idea.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: So the way it works is this Google Authenticator is really just a client for TOTP.
Speaker 1: You can use it with any TOTP.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: He doesn't have.
Speaker 1: you can even use it as a TOT.
Speaker 1: It basically might as well just call it generic TOTP client.
Speaker 1: And Google happens to be using TOTP and it just branded the app with Google.
Speaker 1: But the app actually has nothing to do with Google.
Speaker 1: It's like a generic client like MRC is an IRC client.
Speaker 0: So good on Google for that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So what you do is you open up your authenticator and you press plus and to add another thing.
Speaker 1: And you push scan barcode and this will scan a QR code.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: To add basically a new client to your Google authenticator.
Speaker 1: So when you go to line node and you say add two factor authentication to my phone or account, they display a QR code.
Speaker 1: That QR code has a shared secret.
Speaker 1: You take a picture of it with your phone.
Speaker 1: Now the shared secret is online node and it's in your phone and it's nowhere else.
Speaker 1: And line node will never display that secret again.
Speaker 1: And your phone will never display that secret again.
Speaker 1: And now your phone and line node can use the time of day to the second to figure out, you know, the one time of two factor authentication code.
Speaker 1: And you're all set.
Speaker 1: And there's nothing.
Speaker 1: doesn't even have to hit Google's API or anything like that whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Google doesn't.
Speaker 1: There's no part in it.
Speaker 1: Even though the app says Google, you can in fact get your own TOTP client or write your own TOTP client.
Speaker 1: And if you could get the shared secret out of your Google authenticator app, you could use that instead.
Speaker 0: So good listeners, if you're a coder and you know what you're doing, you can really impress your company by having two factor authentication that just works with.
Speaker 1: it's trivial to add two factor authentication to any app that doesn't require the users to spend any money on devices or anything of that nature, as long as everyone has a smartphone that could run Google authenticator, which is every Android and iPhone and possibly others.
Speaker 1: Also, even if they don't have a smartphone, you can use something like Twilio or your own Astra server or something to use text messages or emails for the two factor authentication.
Speaker 1: You just email someone the numbers, right?
Speaker 1: That's what steam does for their two factor, right?
Speaker 1: Emails you a code when you log in from a new computer and it's like, type this code into your steam.
Speaker 1: I don't trust you.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So in other semi related news, mostly in terms of DRM security and piracy and all that, the internet is a buzz and slash.is angry because Adobe has decided to stop selling thousand plus dollar packages of Adobe products and just have the subscription only Adobe cloud model.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I have the Adobe subscription.
Speaker 0: I'm also glad I have that.
Speaker 0: And I think this is a good move for Adobe.
Speaker 0: And I also think it's a good move for me, the consumer.
Speaker 0: and good God are people on slash knee jerk, ridiculous assholes.
Speaker 1: Well, OK, so on the one hand, they have a point.
Speaker 1: And the point is that, well, wait, what do you think?
Speaker 1: slash jobs point is such this point is they want to own the software and pirate it or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much without paying for it, because no one.
Speaker 1: basically this means that future versions of Photoshop be unpiratable almost right now.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to say that they'll pirate everything.
Speaker 1: But anyway, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: If you pay the fifty bucks a month for the creative cloud, that is right, less money than if you were to buy the master suite of creative suite and keep it upgraded all the time.
Speaker 0: Now, the Nard will say, but I don't need to upgrade all the time.
Speaker 0: I'm wasting money now.
Speaker 1: This is there are people who want to buy like just Photoshop, CS6 and never upgrade it ever.
Speaker 1: And if you just buy one thing and never upgrade it ever, even for hundreds of dollars, that will in the long run be cheaper than paying for the creative.
Speaker 0: Now, those people say that, but they are very short sighted and usually wrong because I'm sure those people have a perfectly legitimate copy of cool edit that they continue to use to this day on their Windows PC instead of paying the whatever hundreds of dollars for audition.
Speaker 0: The fact is, the reason software like this and enterprise software and all those things is so expensive is that there isn't the biggest market for it.
Speaker 0: But simultaneously, it's actually really expensive to have good enough developers and design teams to add features to stuff like this.
Speaker 0: If you think you're going to code up a Photoshop competitor in your basement, you're wrong.
Speaker 0: And if you think that GIMP is that you're wrong.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I used to be that way five, 10, not five, 10 years ago.
Speaker 0: I was like, yeah, the GIMP does everything I need and all my art.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Cause you're not an artist and you don't know shit about drawing or video or audio.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: One guy on slash I was like, well, I guess I'm just going to go back to the GIMP.
Speaker 0: And the post under that is just brilliant.
Speaker 0: I'll paraphrase.
Speaker 1: At least there was like one brilliant post.
Speaker 0: It basically says, yeah, go back to the GIMP.
Speaker 0: That's basically the equivalent of Photoshop.
Speaker 0: CS2 doesn't support shit.
Speaker 1: If you think you can get away with the GIMP, I have to pay a hundred dollars a month for my Ferrari instead of a hundred thousand dollars once.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess I'm going back to driving my Pinto.
Speaker 0: If you think you can get away with using the GIMP, you never should have been paying for show Photoshop in the first place.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: If you can get away with the GIMP, why were you using Photoshop?
Speaker 1: Unless you were pirating it?
Speaker 1: and if you were pirating it, why do you care how they charge for it?
Speaker 1: You're just going to pirate it again.
Speaker 0: You can get away with the GIMP.
Speaker 0: If all you do is crop images, change the format of images, apply shitty filters to images.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: Photoshop is just better.
Speaker 0: and yeah, Audacity is, you know, okay.
Speaker 0: But if you know anything about audio, you'll hate Audacity and it won't do anything you want it to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, this is, you know, pro tools.
Speaker 1: It's not pro tools, it's professional tools,
Speaker 0: but the people who say they want to buy it and never upgrade are pretty much always lying because it's always the same people who complain when CS5 comes out and it has new features they don't have in CS4 and they get mad.
Speaker 1: But they also complain that they upgrade and it changed and like, oh, I don't like how it changed, but they upgrade anyway.
Speaker 0: That is what I was getting at.
Speaker 0: The most common complaint about this that I see on the internet is that people are mad that now they're just going to get updates to Adobe stuff all the time and they hate it when the UI changes.
Speaker 0: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: People like you are holding software back and have been since the dawn of software.
Speaker 0: The people who complained that, oh my God, Office added ribbon menus.
Speaker 0: Well, fuck that.
Speaker 0: I'm using Microsoft works 2000 for the rest of my life.
Speaker 0: You are the problem.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't be working anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the Scott kind of rant right there.
Speaker 1: Because I do that for a living now.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: In my job, I moved a UI element because the old element was poorly designed in the new version and despite release notes, despite no one else's.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Despite everything.
Speaker 0: And despite the fact that it was clearly superior and clearly intuitive, I had to deal with people who could not figure the new one out.
Speaker 0: That was just better.
Speaker 0: And actually open tickets asking us to restore the functionality they lost.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: And it was the equivalent of it's a ribbon menu now in a steadier old file menu.
Speaker 0: They're basically the same.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: People who can't deal with good changes or evolutionary changes or or even revolutionary changes to professional software are no longer professionals, in my opinion.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: They're no longer professionals in the field that requires the use of that software.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I'm going to bring a tangent rant that's related.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So get, you know, yeah, I'll admit it gets a complicated motherfucker.
Speaker 0: I don't know it that well.
Speaker 0: I have to, I have to reference every time I do anything more complicated than commit.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it's also a powerful motherfucker.
Speaker 1: It's the whole hog.
Speaker 0: Back to the whole hog.
Speaker 1: You know that whole hog.
Speaker 0: Everyone who listens to Gignac should know about the whole hog.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: If you haven't searched for a whole hog, H O L E space H A W G. You'll find a, uh, basically an excerpt from the book.
Speaker 1: in the beginning was the command line by Neil Stevenson.
Speaker 1: Read that excerpt anyway.
Speaker 1: So, but everybody these days has to use the get or at least lots of people do, especially with get hub taken over the world.
Speaker 0: There's a, I'd say 30% of the people who should be using get are using mercurial because they move.
Speaker 1: You're giving material too much credit.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: I'm saying they moved to mercurial before get existed or they knew about it and they're not going to move again.
Speaker 1: There's not too many mercurial users left out there in corporate America, even bit bucket, which was the get hub of mercurial added get support and is now basically 60 to 70% of people who need complex revision management are using get.
Speaker 0: the other 30 to higher percent than the other 30 to 40% want to be using it and are stuck currently with the mercurial and are desperately trying.
Speaker 1: I think most people who aren't using get, I think a lot of them are just stuck on subversion or something else like visual source safe.
Speaker 0: I find, luckily the most, most of the people who use subversion as their primary change control are using it for non code where it actually does a pretty good job.
Speaker 1: A get is even better at non code, but, but non code implies non coders.
Speaker 0: Do you know how hard it is to explain the concept of revision management to someone whose only job is to draw pictures?
Speaker 1: And this is my point that I was getting to in this rant.
Speaker 1: I don't care if your job is draw pictures, right?
Speaker 1: Are you a professional picture drawer, right?
Speaker 1: Are you working with people on a digital product?
Speaker 1: Maybe you are drawing pictures for a website or drawing pictures for an application, right?
Speaker 1: I don't care if get is primarily a programmer's tool, right?
Speaker 1: It is a revision control tool.
Speaker 1: It doesn't care if you're working with code or pictures or videos or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: And it is a tool you need to learn for your job.
Speaker 1: If you are professional fucking learn it.
Speaker 0: None of these easy cover up thing is not the problem.
Speaker 0: The reason is that people don't have to learn it for their jobs because the majority of companies do not have good processes and everything's so slow and inefficient that it doesn't matter if they know how to use good tools or not.
Speaker 0: It'll be just as slow.
Speaker 1: It's true, but I see many.
Speaker 0: I'm going beyond you and I'm going to say this.
Speaker 0: Yes, you can probably get a job to make just fine money.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, you can
Speaker 0: if you're, if you only know how to do one thing and do it well, but the people who will be employed for their entire lives, the people who will make ridiculous money, the people who will run shit are the people who know how to do one thing really well and know how to use computers,
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: But this is not the aspect I was getting at.
Speaker 1: The aspect I am getting at is that you look online and even in hacker communities of programmers, people are making things such as the very popular get flow and all the and gooeys and all these cover ups of the get command line to sort of limit its power into just a few things so that someone who's a dumb ass can still use it without having to learn it.
Speaker 1: They don't want to learn it.
Speaker 1: They say, I don't want to learn that complicated thing.
Speaker 0: I want to, but I ask God, you're so mad you.
Speaker 0: So in two years I have not touched a knob on the compressor and I had to touch a knob because how angry you are right now.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: But the point is if you're a professional, you should fucking learn that shit.
Speaker 1: Don't be like, Oh, I want to cover it up.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: If you're covering it up and making it easy for yourself or reducing the power and cause you're avoiding learning, you are not a professional.
Speaker 0: Now don't get us wrong.
Speaker 0: You might still be really good at drawing pictures.
Speaker 0: I know Scott really well.
Speaker 0: Don't get us wrong.
Speaker 0: We are not saying that intelligent defaults and gooeys are a problem.
Speaker 0: A good gooey is always better than a good command line, except the barrier, the bottom level.
Speaker 0: to being good gooey is unattainable by the majority of UI designers.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't even make gooeys that are that good or that transcendent.
Speaker 1: There are git gooeys that are good gooeys.
Speaker 1: There are some that are bad, but the good ones and the bad ones both severely reduce the power of git by reducing the things that you can do, right?
Speaker 1: The only way to actually use and understand all of git is to use the command line.
Speaker 1: There is no other way.
Speaker 1: That's just, it's just so powerful.
Speaker 1: There's so many buttons and knobs, right?
Speaker 1: It's like a whole hog.
Speaker 1: If you, you know, and using a gooey on top of it is like using a cheap plastic drill.
Speaker 1: Again, you might as well not use git.
Speaker 1: It'd be, you know, you're, you're limiting its power so much.
Speaker 1: Why don't you just use subversion then?
Speaker 1: So
Speaker 0: to get back to the news and the main point of this, uh, my main point is simply that the people who are complaining that the UIs of their professional software are changing are one of the biggest problems in corporate, not America, corporate world today, because that is why so much software is so stagnant.
Speaker 0: If you're, if you're actually a professional audio engineer and you know your shit, if you load up audition one day and some stuffs move around, you'll not only notice that it moved, but you'll understand where it moved and why intuitively almost all the time.
Speaker 0: And if you can't, either you're not actually a professional or that software got worse and it's very rarely the latter.
Speaker 1: Usually it's that you didn't learn, you know, like if you learn word processing, you can use Microsoft and you've used Microsoft word your whole life and I give you Abby word and say use this or I give you Libre office and I say, use this.
Speaker 1: You should be able to just use it without having to ask any questions.
Speaker 1: If you use, if you understand the concept of word processing, but too many people learn, for example, they learn a workflow or a product.
Speaker 0: They don't learn a concept or a skill, right?
Speaker 1: If you learn a Microsoft word to the, and you only just remembered specific buttons to press in Microsoft word in a specific order such that if Microsoft word changes, you don't know what to do.
Speaker 1: Or if you have to use open office, you don't know what to do.
Speaker 1: Then you didn't really know what the hell you were doing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I don't want to hire that kind of person.
Speaker 1: I want to hire someone who if they know word processing and can use any word processor, I want to know someone who knows audio engineering.
Speaker 1: And if I, if one workplace they go to as Pro tools and another one has audition, they should be just fine.
Speaker 1: If they have a problem switching like that and they just can't figure out the differences on their own, that's not a person of high skill who I want to hire.
Speaker 1: And I would probably, if I was hiring people, that's the kind of thing I would try to figure out is like, Oh, can this person, do they really understand the core concepts?
Speaker 1: Could they do their job using a different tool set?
Speaker 0: Well, that's why I noticed how, like when I interview people, when
Speaker 1: it would be always no one to hire, when people
Speaker 0: like us interview programmers, a lot of times, at least I will, I'll ask them just to make sure that they know what they're doing to explain to me how they would go about architecting a simple problem in code.
Speaker 0: Because if they can't without reference, I don't need them to write code in front of me by hand.
Speaker 0: That's stupid.
Speaker 0: But if they can't like get the concept across of how they would do something in a vacuum, then they probably couldn't write code to do that thing, given all the reference in the world.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this is a great thing for Adobe to be doing for very simple reasons.
Speaker 0: One, it's not to prevent piracy.
Speaker 0: This is not why they're doing it.
Speaker 0: It's going to indoctrinate more people to use their software.
Speaker 0: Cause it was just 50 bucks a month, probably with student discounts and whatever, instead of thousands of dollars every year or so.
Speaker 0: And you get every Adobe product instead of paying the thousand plus dollars just for a subset like production premium, like I used to do.
Speaker 0: I'm using a lot of Adobe software I never would have touched before.
Speaker 0: My entire workflow of media has moved entirely within Adobe software.
Speaker 0: I can't leave now.
Speaker 1: I don't even use it that much.
Speaker 1: I could leave, but it became in the ads.
Speaker 1: It's like I use Lightroom a ton and I use Premiere probably second most and Photoshop third most.
Speaker 1: I really don't use a lot of the other stuff.
Speaker 0: I use After Effects, InDesign.
Speaker 1: I use After Effects a little bit.
Speaker 0: I'm using it more and more.
Speaker 0: I'm using InDesign more and more.
Speaker 1: I uninstalled InDesign because I couldn't figure it out.
Speaker 0: You know what you're going to use it for?
Speaker 0: If you publish a tabletop game, InDesign.
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I'll teach you.
Speaker 0: I'm starting to learn.
Speaker 1: I actually installed Flash Builder, which is a fork of Eclipse that lets you make Flash apps and things like that.
Speaker 1: And I was like, whoa, I didn't know this.
Speaker 1: I sort of knew it existed, but I was like, whoa, this is actually pretty great.
Speaker 0: Also Adobe media encoder.
Speaker 0: I'm using it a lot more.
Speaker 0: Not just exporting out of Premiere.
Speaker 1: I use that the most because I'll record everything with fraps and I'll just turn them into MP4s and delete the raws.
Speaker 1: So anyway, two.
Speaker 0: Now anyone who's using Adobe software is always going to have the current version.
Speaker 0: You never have to again deal with that shitty contractor who actually only has CS3 and can't import the file you gave him with revisions.
Speaker 1: Three.
Speaker 0: The reason all this enterprise software sucks is because the old model of pay for it doesn't work when you actually need to keep updating the software to fit with modern times.
Speaker 0: Shit's changed since Kool Edit came out.
Speaker 0: I need to be able to edit five point one surround audio.
Speaker 0: Old Kool Edit can't do that.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: Audition can do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Audition can do more things than Kool Edit could.
Speaker 1: Even Vermeer can do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So anyway, this is great for Adobe.
Speaker 0: And I've seen almost no legitimate complaints other than I want to pirate it, but you still can.
Speaker 0: Non-professionals or people are being disingenuous about why they're mad.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So do you remember at the famous penguicon?
Speaker 0: The penguicon where Neil Gaiman, the only penguicon we went to and told stories to us and hung out with our friends and Steve Jackson made that chaos machine and we totally blew him off because we didn't know who he was.
Speaker 1: So the chaos machine.
Speaker 0: We had Wi-Fi on a cell phone driving through Canada in an era where none of us had cell phones.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But I'm talking about the chaos machine.
Speaker 0: OK, so the chaos machine is basically Marble Works unplugged.
Speaker 1: It was crazy as Marble Works.
Speaker 0: I will link to some pictures of the chaos machine that I found recently.
Speaker 1: So what did we try to do with the chaos machine that we failed to do?
Speaker 0: Perfect error handling.
Speaker 0: No, that's what we tried to do.
Speaker 0: That's what I was trying to do.
Speaker 1: Me and Steve Pomeroy attempted to make an adder.
Speaker 0: Oh, OK.
Speaker 0: You were doing that.
Speaker 0: I was trying to deal with.
Speaker 0: occasionally a ball would pop out.
Speaker 0: I was trying to make a system that would catch all the errors and feed them back in.
Speaker 0: So the machine would run forever.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So the batteries ran out.
Speaker 1: No, it was plugged into the wall.
Speaker 1: I had the elevator.
Speaker 1: Remember.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But we got to a point where the elevator could not deal with the load because too many balls were in it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Too tall.
Speaker 0: But so I got.
Speaker 1: that was so we couldn't make an adder because there was no way to store state.
Speaker 1: We basically needed a switch to make an adder, something that when a marble hit, it would flip such that the next marble would do something different than the previous marble.
Speaker 0: I believe there was one switch that would flip between go left, go right.
Speaker 0: It would always go left and right.
Speaker 1: But we couldn't use it to store a state.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: We needed to do something if a ball came in the right.
Speaker 1: And if another the next ball, like the first ball that comes in the right, like you need to store a state.
Speaker 1: And we couldn't do that anyway.
Speaker 0: Now, if you just have things, if you just have a series of things that flip and the first ball goes left and left and go right, you could do stuff with just that.
Speaker 1: So here is a guy who has made an adding machine out of wood using marbles.
Speaker 1: This actually was uploaded in 2007, but I didn't see it until today.
Speaker 1: And it's pretty much an adder made of wood that uses marbles.
Speaker 0: You know, it's interesting.
Speaker 0: That design looks almost identical to a machine that I made with a bunch of my friends for an event in Science Olympiad called Mission Possible.
Speaker 0: Because so this is great.
Speaker 0: We entered the first year and the rules were like, you make a Rube Goldberg machine.
Speaker 0: You get points for all this bullshit.
Speaker 0: And then you also get points based on how close to exactly two minutes your machine runs to completion.
Speaker 0: So we had a clock that we made out of wood with a pendulum.
Speaker 0: And then we had a Rube Goldberg machine that did all this bullshit as fast as possible, million points, and then waited a minute and forty five seconds and then did the last thing.
Speaker 0: Next year, they changed the rules and said that you can't have parallel processes like that.
Speaker 0: So we found a loophole.
Speaker 0: We made a machine that looks exactly like what you just showed me.
Speaker 0: That would basically.
Speaker 0: the only difference is our channels had holes at certain points so that when the state machine got to a certain point, it would trigger behavior to continue the Rube Goldberg machine.
Speaker 0: And we won again and they changed the rules again to prevent us from doing that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, this is an adder.
Speaker 1: If you were if you wanted to know how your computer or a pocket calculator adds things together, which it pretty much does constantly, this is how it does it only with electricity instead of marvels.
Speaker 0: Now, that's when computers get kind of amazing.
Speaker 0: I mean, you think about one megahertz, one million things per second going on.
Speaker 1: So adding shit every time one of the things in this machine goes click, that is a hurt, basically.
Speaker 1: So one hurt, not a million of them in a second.
Speaker 0: So my computer's processor is a lot of gigahertz.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it's just adding bits together.
Speaker 1: Oh, and isn't it quad core?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So it can do for it's at the same time if you programmed it to do so.
Speaker 0: My computer can play video and all it's doing is adding numbers together over and over and over again.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And you might think, but rim, it's also subtracting now.
Speaker 1: It's subtracting is adding and multiplying is also adding.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Dividing is also adding and shifting.
Speaker 0: Now I've got a GPU that has some more specialized functions, but we digress.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Everything your computer does is adding.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Or you've got a complex instruction that does well.
Speaker 1: Your computer ads, shifts, copies, moves and writes and reads.
Speaker 0: We did a show on risk and CISC a long time ago, right?
Speaker 0: Probably pretty sure we did.
Speaker 1: We did a show on architectures.
Speaker 0: Anyway, my thing of the day, this is just kind of cool.
Speaker 0: It's really short.
Speaker 0: I'm going to do more stuff with it later.
Speaker 0: So last year on the eve of hurricane Sandy, Scott and I were at burning apocalypse.
Speaker 0: Well, just burning con.
Speaker 1: I think it was burning apocalypse.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know if it was called that or if it was just called burning con again.
Speaker 1: I think it was, it was burning con the triad under it because not only was the first burning con was burning con, then burning apocalypse con, then burning con the triad under it.
Speaker 1: Cause it was the third one.
Speaker 1: And because it was not just Luke crane and Vince Baker's games, it was also the guy forgets in the game.
Speaker 0: So I can, I participated in a four hour, 100% in character LARP called inheritance run by Lou Crane.
Speaker 0: It was easily one of the three or four greatest role playing or gaming experiences of my entire life.
Speaker 0: And this is that entire four hour game.
Speaker 0: In about 11 seconds we had a camera take a time lapse photo and I just ran it at 30 frames per second.
Speaker 0: And it's just kind of cool to watch and I'm going to have more things about this later, like a slowed down version and whatever.
Speaker 0: But this is my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool to watch.
Speaker 0: And yes, that is Vincent Baker.
Speaker 0: I'm standing over.
Speaker 0: I murdered him because the priestess told me to right.
Speaker 1: Oh, also John Harper is the third guy whose games that you could play anyway.
Speaker 0: So, uh, we should go quick on this book.
Speaker 1: club book is player of games.
Speaker 1: I finished reading it.
Speaker 0: I haven't started yet.
Speaker 1: I am now reading the first book in the culture series.
Speaker 1: Flip is considered or consider Phlebas.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure which one it is.
Speaker 0: If it starts raining, I'll probably finish the book pretty quick because I'll be reading it on my commute, but it's been sunny and I've been biking every day for now.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: We've got a bunch of video on the internet.
Speaker 0: We're going to be at Connecticut doing a bunch of panels and running the panels and workshops.
Speaker 1: All that matters right now is anime Boston.
Speaker 0: We're going to be at anime Boston doing not one, not two, not three, not six, not four, but five.
Speaker 1: All you need to know is that we'll be at anime Boston and you'll see us there.
Speaker 0: Emily will also be doing a lecture.
Speaker 0: A friend Judith will also be doing a lecture.
Speaker 0: A bunch of people.
Speaker 1: We don't need all the details.
Speaker 1: Just say, go to anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Let's move on.
Speaker 0: Look for us.
Speaker 0: We're going to be at PAX Australia.
Speaker 0: We're probably going to be at PAX dev and packs us or a pecs prime and then packs east again.
Speaker 0: Magfest, Magfest, then paxies video forums, grand prix.
Speaker 1: So, Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: The grand prix backgammon round ended.
Speaker 1: New round starts tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Anyone who wasn't playing backgammon, you have a chance.
Speaker 1: Come back and play.
Speaker 1: This one's going to be easier logistic.
Speaker 0: What did I say?
Speaker 0: People are going to abuse the doubling cube to get an advantage.
Speaker 0: They didn't get an advantage.
Speaker 1: They basically fucked themselves because a lot of the people who, this is what I said, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, sure, you doubled and you lost.
Speaker 1: basically these people were doubling in the game to pump up the score of the person who was beating them while the person was beating them.
Speaker 1: And then of course, if I had used that other, if I had used that as the tiebreaker, that person would have been severely punished because they were stupid and give a bunch of points to someone else.
Speaker 1: So Scott, but they were also punishing other people with the same number of wins as them.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Which was the thing.
Speaker 1: They brought themselves down and also brought others down.
Speaker 0: What you failed to account for is that knowing that this is a possibility, roughly a third of the players were going to take advantage of another third to use that to greatly enhance their tiebreaker.
Speaker 1: Here's what I could have done.
Speaker 1: I realized only now, right?
Speaker 1: Is that what I should have used as the, as the tiebreaker was not opponent wins as in strength of schedule.
Speaker 1: It should have been how many points you gave up to your opponents in total, right?
Speaker 0: I suggested that early on.
Speaker 0: Yes, I did.
Speaker 1: That way you would be punished for how bad you sucked as opposed to rewarded for how hard your opponents were doing.
Speaker 0: Anyway, Grand Prix.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: So someday, someday Scott is going to die.
Speaker 0: Gabe and Tyco are going to die.
Speaker 0: Hero from mega Tokyo is going to die.
Speaker 1: Obama's going to die.
Speaker 0: The awesome lady.
Speaker 1: Though I do not threaten his life.
Speaker 0: Nor do I.
Speaker 1: Don't come secret service again to Rims house.
Speaker 0: All human beings who are alive today are likely to die.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: So even a baby that was born just now will die one day.
Speaker 0: Well, well, so I say likely because statistically, because of how many people live today compared to how many people have likely ever lived, the statistical death rate is not a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: Maybe, but, uh, even if we discover some sort of way to like cut telomeres so that they stop shrinking and you won't die by getting old.
Speaker 1: If you live long enough, you're likely to die by car accident.
Speaker 0: So all I'm saying is that statistically the death rate of humans is not a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: I disagree because if you live long enough, the odds of getting in a car accident approach, you study humans, forget your anecdotal bullshit.
Speaker 0: If you study humans, the dad, the absolute death rate, which doesn't just include firearm deaths and car deaths, but kids starving to death in Africa, the death rate is still not a hundred percent because so many people are being born so fast compared to the number of people who have ever died.
Speaker 1: I don't think like, anyway, you will die.
Speaker 0: So many statistical articles talking about this amusing statistical anomaly that might not be rectified.
Speaker 1: Everyone who is Bible bet all my life.
Speaker 1: That's everyone who was born now and born for the foreseeable future will one day die.
Speaker 0: Oh yes, but I'm saying that the statistical rate is not a hundred percent ever.
Speaker 0: And I think it's probably too late for us, but I think there will be, we're on, we're on the cusp as humans of having people who are effectively ageless.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: When we discover, I said the genetic engineering to, you know, make telomeres stop ruining themselves.
Speaker 1: We will have people that basically don't age and will only die of, they'll be like elves.
Speaker 1: The only desire of disease or murder car crashes or crazy or murderers or poison or whatever.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I'm saying is that that'll let that, I think it is possible that in my dying days I will see the first people for whom this is true.
Speaker 1: I hope that they do not discover it when I am very old and then try to give it to me.
Speaker 1: Thus locking me in at oldness forever unless they can also rejuvenate.
Speaker 1: Very unlikely.
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: think what I'm really hoping for is that we have the ability to dub or record or store the state of an existing brain and that I do not succumb to severe senility so that there will be an ability to record some simulacra of my personality and put it on the internet to piss around and annoy people for the rest of eternity.
Speaker 1: Is not the data I have already placed on the internet very close to that simulacra?
Speaker 0: I would not realize, people who listen to geek nights but do not know us in person tend to have the opposite idea of what our two personalities are like in the real world.
Speaker 1: That may be so, but it is an inaccurate simulacra, but a simulacra nonetheless.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: Our simulacra are out there.
Speaker 0: How many kids are changing and saying penis on the Parthenon even though they're not really sure of where that came from?
Speaker 1: None.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I put as many bits on the internet as I can, perhaps, you know, I guess, I don't know what the word would be, but it is a vain attempt at grasping immortality of the digital nature.
Speaker 0: Because while I cannot likely be immortal, I would like for there to be some kid somewhere who's listening to geek nights and looking at the memes I put out there basically becomes me.
Speaker 0: And I would love for someone else, because I'm not going to do it, to write a sci-fi story where a guy basically programs a series of memes on the internet such that someday in the future, a child will grow up, encounter all of these memes, and his personality will be reprogrammed to be exactly that person.
Speaker 1: That sounds exactly like Diamond Age.
Speaker 0: Not Diamond Age.
Speaker 1: Also Ready Player One.
Speaker 0: Diamond Age has a somewhat different but similar idea.
Speaker 1: I'm saying it sounds like somewhere, right?
Speaker 1: Diamond Age, Damon, Ready Player One, all three of those are like that, similarly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, similar.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but the reality is, Scott's probably going to die.
Speaker 1: You're definitely, but not before you.
Speaker 0: Not before you do.
Speaker 0: Your last words are going to be, "Rim still
Speaker 0: lives.".
Speaker 0: Rim yet lives.
Speaker 1: It's going to be a John Adams, Thomas Jefferson situation.
Speaker 0: That's what we're going for.
Speaker 0: That's our last goal.
Speaker 1: That's the best possible scenario.
Speaker 1: Do you want me to dance on your grave or pee on it?
Speaker 0: Or drag my butt on it?
Speaker 0: I was going to say I plan to drag my bottom over your grave.
Speaker 1: Well, that's not going to happen because you'll never see my grave.
Speaker 1: Because I won't.
Speaker 1: even if I die, I won't have one.
Speaker 0: Cremation's not an excuse.
Speaker 0: I'll find your ashes, pour them out, and I'm not going to fuck up.
Speaker 1: You're going to drag your butt in the ocean or something?
Speaker 0: I'm not going to fuck up like the big Lebowski.
Speaker 1: All right, put him in a volcano.
Speaker 1: That way, drag your butt on that.
Speaker 1: Toss me, go to the tropical island where I want to go and then ashes in the volcano.
Speaker 0: So Scott's going to die.
Speaker 1: Rim's going to die.
Speaker 0: I'm glad you finally noticed that I didn't imply that I was going to die.
Speaker 0: Our bits, we put so many bits out on the internet.
Speaker 0: What's going to happen to them?
Speaker 1: Well, a lot of them will stay there for a while, right?
Speaker 1: For a while.
Speaker 1: You know, bits that are like sort of held by a company, it's how long does that company live, right?
Speaker 0: Well, it's over talking about the Internet.
Speaker 0: Let's go crazy here.
Speaker 0: So companies are not human, but they.
Speaker 0: but they have a sort of agency that is the collective will of all the humans that they had.
Speaker 1: They don't necessarily have to die.
Speaker 1: They are like elves and they will not die of age.
Speaker 1: They will only die of being murdered or killing themselves.
Speaker 0: Do things that are not the will of any one individual running those companies.
Speaker 0: But there's sort of this metal.
Speaker 0: Well, they're basically gods or aggregores, which is kind of fucked up that corporations have become gods.
Speaker 0: Yet we have not.
Speaker 0: Yes, but well, I could be.
Speaker 1: a corporation such as Google can keep my website in its cash or the wayback machine can keep my websites in its cash for ever, as long as those organizations continue to exist.
Speaker 1: And even if all the people working for those organizations die, as long as they hire new people and the organization survives and does not change its mission, that those bits will survive.
Speaker 0: But there's one other caveat that's very important.
Speaker 0: if they want to.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: So but if I'm dead, do I care what they do?
Speaker 0: But I thought you put all your bits out there to make more use appear later.
Speaker 1: I do care.
Speaker 1: But once I'm dead, I don't care anymore because I care now.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem.
Speaker 0: Our society is pretty fucking shit at planning beyond the realm of one or maybe two human lifetime.
Speaker 1: See what it really is, is it's not?
Speaker 1: how much do I care about my bits after I'm dead, I'll be dead.
Speaker 1: It's how much do other people care about my bits when I'm dead?
Speaker 0: It's also how much do you care while you're alive about leaving an impact after you're dead?
Speaker 1: So you'll know dying that you because you're a, you're a vain and egotistical monster.
Speaker 0: How long have you known me?
Speaker 0: So the problem is our society has not dealt with this.
Speaker 0: We, our legal system, our Congress, our laws, our rules, our terms of service do not deal with this at all.
Speaker 1: Some of them do, but very poorly.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: So let's go about through the geek nights.
Speaker 0: use cases of you and me.
Speaker 0: So first off, we both got g mail accounts.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: Several of them.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I only have one.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So if I die, who can anyone get access to that?
Speaker 1: Google can.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So what about my mom?
Speaker 1: I would have to put something in a will.
Speaker 1: Well, your mom, I hope will be dead before you.
Speaker 1: Not that I want your mom to die, but you know, she's older than you.
Speaker 1: You're threatening my mom now, but I'll make them your mom joke.
Speaker 1: Um, right.
Speaker 1: It's you gotta, you put in your will for it to go to somebody and I guess Google have to obey that shit.
Speaker 0: Uh, probably.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Because you can argue that it's your property.
Speaker 0: You could leave instruction.
Speaker 0: So here is where I want to skip.
Speaker 1: Is it your property?
Speaker 0: The usual discussion that happens around the legal business.
Speaker 0: Now I want to skip the usual discussion and I want to get right to the uncomfortable hypotheticals and the unpopular opinions that die.
Speaker 1: Sad and alone.
Speaker 1: There's no one to leave shit to.
Speaker 0: No one.
Speaker 0: I personally believe that we need to move beyond the idea of the rights of the dead.
Speaker 0: And I Jenna, I think in a ideological pro views from an ideological perspective that once you're dead, your data should be public domain.
Speaker 0: But pragmatically, I recognize that that is problematic for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: Well, think about this, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say, right?
Speaker 1: Someone, I have my emails, the emails become public domain.
Speaker 1: I would actually be like, yeah, just publish my emails when I'm dead.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But that includes emails sent to me by others who may be yet live.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, if you were alive, you're perfectly within your rights to publish them while you're alive.
Speaker 1: Maybe, maybe it's one of those emails from a company that says, don't publish this as private one.
Speaker 0: Do those even hold up in court?
Speaker 0: The answer is no.
Speaker 0: And two, maybe I have a moral, a moral ability unless I signed an NDA to publish anything you give me, because is it a crime for me to relate to you?
Speaker 0: The conversation I had with our friend Scott Johnson regarding your mom.
Speaker 1: If it is not a crime though, am I being a Dick?
Speaker 1: Even though I'm dead, given the finger from beyond the grave.
Speaker 0: But could, can you ever say that someone is being a Dick for doing something so simple as simply speaking the truth?
Speaker 0: Are you not a Dick for opposing truth in any situation?
Speaker 1: I approve of saying truth, right?
Speaker 1: But when it upsets people, but most people do not like truth saying as per the Boas' comic.
Speaker 0: If uncle Joe dies and suddenly everyone in his family looks at his email and finds out just how many furry porn pay sites he was subscribed to and all his internet girlfriends and how much Viagra he was buying and how much he hated aunt Myrtle and how he cheated with aunt Myrtle on uncle Mark.
Speaker 1: Then that's a great one.
Speaker 1: We need to make a movie out of that.
Speaker 0: I mean, I have chat.
Speaker 0: I am.
Speaker 0: And every online conversation I've ever had since 1996, I have a lot of them.
Speaker 1: I don't have, I haven't been quite so diligent as rim and keeping them all, but the first thing I ever said to Scott, a lot of them, and I'll paraphrase.
Speaker 0: They don't have it handy right now is, Hey, it's me, that long haired guy from anime club.
Speaker 0: You want to go to Gracie's?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: And then Scott's like, sure.
Speaker 0: Be there in five.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: So, so what do we do about this?
Speaker 0: That forget the technical standpoint from an ideological standpoint, ideological or practical art.
Speaker 0: What should forget?
Speaker 0: both combine them?
Speaker 0: What should we do?
Speaker 0: What should the law say about an email account of someone who died?
Speaker 1: If they did not say anything in their will, then it should belong to the, I guess, are they, is it cloud email or do they host it on a computer?
Speaker 0: They're paying for hosting email because everyone uses Gmail.
Speaker 1: These days, I guess Google can just make whatever policy they want.
Speaker 0: So is that moral?
Speaker 0: Should it be considered property that goes to the estates?
Speaker 0: or is it a violation of the dead person's property or, or privacy to give it to the estate?
Speaker 0: If the estate was not directly willed it and there was no prior cause to say the person wanted it to be public.
Speaker 0: Well, how about this for person say, I never gave anyone the password and I die.
Speaker 0: Should Google be allowed to give the password to my mom?
Speaker 1: If I gave no instructions.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Uh, you know, that's the thing is like, is there, what if I didn't want mom to see it?
Speaker 0: or maybe find out about your adult baby diver play?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Maybe I really did want mom to see it cause there's a nice message in there.
Speaker 1: Like mom, I miss you.
Speaker 1: I'm dead.
Speaker 1: Well, if I send my mom an email from beyond the grave and my, but my account just listened to a pretty good pseudo pot about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, it was basically a guy like gets lost driving.
Speaker 0: So he calls, I don't know.
Speaker 0: This is when cell phones first got ghost plans.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So he calls his wife.
Speaker 0: He's like, yeah, I'm lost.
Speaker 0: Can you come and watch?
Speaker 0: like God, fine.
Speaker 0: I'll come get you.
Speaker 0: Just hang out there talking on the phone.
Speaker 0: And then she comes around the corner and she sees an accident where, and it's his car and he's clearly dead and he's just lost somewhere on the phone.
Speaker 0: And it was, it was actually a pretty well done and creepy story.
Speaker 1: Nice.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I have plans for being a ghost.
Speaker 1: That's why I'm not going to write anything in a will cause I'll just take care of it from the afterlife.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm going to haunt your ass if you're still alive, which you won't be, but you know, I don't know you, but I plan to be a fight King.
Speaker 0: That's pretty sweet.
Speaker 1: I'm going to haunt some motherfuckers.
Speaker 0: You know, it's funny cause you just watched adventure brothers, adventure brothers, adventure time in venture brothers.
Speaker 0: There's a whole bit about ghosts and who they're allowed to haunt and why that I can't reference cause you haven't seen that show.
Speaker 1: I just want to haunt everybody.
Speaker 0: You don't really want to haunt everybody.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: What if it's like ghost and you're just a hobo on a subway car and it sucks.
Speaker 1: I want to be like, Ooh, I'm like Casper.
Speaker 1: Everyone's afraid even though I'm nice.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm, I kind of feel like we need some sort of generic societal change such that information that could be retrieved about dead people should be retrieved maybe by the government if there's no instructions otherwise or even if there are and released to the public domain, maybe after an interval.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I think you could have an interval of like a generation.
Speaker 0: Like maybe 50 years.
Speaker 0: If you die the 50th year after you die, every piece of digital information that can be found about you is public domain.
Speaker 1: All right, now let's talk about a slightly different situation, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say I've got, you know, a bunch of data and I have it hosted on a hosting company like Lino.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, you know what?
Speaker 0: There are like 1200 episodes of geek nights on lips and that will disappear there all day.
Speaker 0: What are?
Speaker 0: our credit card runs out, right?
Speaker 1: So the bill might, we still have backups here on a physical hard drive.
Speaker 1: So someone who can collect that hard drive in a will can collect the episodes, but they will not be available on the internet anymore to download.
Speaker 1: If that Libsyn account stops getting paid and I die, it'll stop getting paid.
Speaker 0: Now what I'd like to do because once my bank account is empty, we've got an interesting situation in general that all these web comics and online media never existed before.
Speaker 0: The generation that made them is primarily young, so we haven't run into this yet, but eventually they're going to be comics and TV shows, entire youtube TV shows that the creators just made moderately popular
Speaker 1: ones will stay on youtube as long as youtube lives,
Speaker 0: but will youtube keep an account forever if there's zero activity on it?
Speaker 0: 10 years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so far they have.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so far they have no poll.
Speaker 1: They don't delete videos and this is a copyright person asked for it to be deleted or something.
Speaker 0: All right, so someone suddenly starts sending copyright notices and there's no one to respond.
Speaker 1: Well, let's say somebody puts up MP4 videos just on their website or like on Amazon S3 and they stopped paying the bills.
Speaker 0: Now, I don't think private companies are under any obligation to keep that stuff up.
Speaker 1: They are under none whatsoever.
Speaker 1: In fact, they will just turn it off because you're not paying the bills and they'll delete your shit.
Speaker 0: What do we do?
Speaker 0: Our society is gonna hit this brick wall where people who are about our age are going to be old and have grown up watching TV shows effectively where there's no corporation to keep them alive.
Speaker 0: So suddenly they disappear from the internet forever.
Speaker 1: Well, some cases you have right where you know somebody has a backup somewhere who cares about that thing and keeps it alive, right?
Speaker 1: For example, even things we have today that are old, like really old busted video games from a long time ago, someone downloaded it back in the day.
Speaker 1: Someone has the floppies and they put it on the internet and then someone else downloads it and gets a emulator and puts it up on the internet again and keeps, you know, there's so data that it's as long as someone cares, right?
Speaker 1: The people who are alive as long as they care, they fight to keep it available and it's up to them.
Speaker 0: So in that case, we need to update copyright law for it to have found media and sort of orphaned media protections so that people can redistribute stuff when there's no one left to redistribute it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It'd be like a digital museum law.
Speaker 1: Like if you find something old and loss that's digital, you can host it on the internet with your will.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I mean, you know what?
Speaker 0: Scott did that just fine until we extended it so long that by the time it hits the public domain, it might already be too late, but what about the things that no one cares about?
Speaker 1: But we should still, I believe philosophically keep everything alive even if no one cares.
Speaker 1: You're basically saying only the things people care about.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to propose, here's the other, here's the trans human transcendent.
Speaker 0: Cool idea.
Speaker 0: Forget the government doing it.
Speaker 0: Our government can't do anything.
Speaker 0: Forget.
Speaker 0: I think we need, someone needs to found something akin to the modern equivalent of a monastic order of technologists.
Speaker 1: You mean the archive dot org?
Speaker 0: Yes, but it needs to be a little more like foundation, a little more monastic and a little more even maybe dogmatic such that we have this body that is greater than the sum of the people who run it so that it'll run in perpetuity and sort of have an almost religious or almost fanatical devotion to maintaining forgotten data forever.
Speaker 1: There are already a lot of lots and lots of lost data.
Speaker 1: I mean, there are movies that were set on fire entire seasons of doctor who since the library of Alexandria shows that were never recorded.
Speaker 1: Library of Alexandria.
Speaker 1: Come on.
Speaker 1: This has been happening for a long time.
Speaker 1: Art that was lost.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Castles blown up by Nazis.
Speaker 1: Castles blown up by the allies that were in Germany.
Speaker 0: So I think there should be in the constitution of the?
Speaker 0: u s at least, you know, our constitution is very clear about the purpose of copyright.
Speaker 0: Its only goal is to promote the creation of useful work progress of science.
Speaker 0: So everything else is just bs.
Speaker 0: Our goal is just as long as people keep making more stuff that that is the goal and everything should serve that goal.
Speaker 0: I think we should add a secondary clause and to maintain the existence of previously created works for the Congress, the power to do something.
Speaker 1: It doesn't give them a mandate to do it, which is what we really needed.
Speaker 0: Well, all right, so forget government.
Speaker 0: We should found a monastic order, right?
Speaker 1: Like archive dot org, but with dogma and that takes care of your arts and things like that.
Speaker 1: But there is more data than just art out there.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, you write a lot of that.
Speaker 0: data is just noise, right?
Speaker 1: But do you want to save that with my tweets?
Speaker 0: I think so.
Speaker 0: Well, someone needs to because the thing is tweets are and I'm not joking or making light of it.
Speaker 1: Tweets are the modern equivalent of open letters in a lot of my text message history or my voicemails or which I've deleted most of ever.
Speaker 0: All voice may voice mail.
Speaker 0: I'm saying why would you mail voices?
Speaker 1: There's a lot of data.
Speaker 1: I know that is, you know, just out hanging out like what if I use some startups GPS tracker of like a bike route I took one day?
Speaker 1: Do we got to keep that?
Speaker 0: So I'm thinking I might for serious update my will to literally say that upon my death, everything I have ever created over which no one else has joint copyright is public domain.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 0: I'm thinking about doing something like that.
Speaker 0: See what I'm thinking about doing, but the thing is the problem is even if you think, yes, I'll do that.
Speaker 0: People don't know technology, especially not lawyers.
Speaker 0: So you need to set up a technological means to make that happen.
Speaker 0: You need a USB stick and a physical piece of paper in a safe deposit box with the passwords to ever.
Speaker 1: I was about to say, I thinking about going and getting a safe deposit box and putting in instructions, how to get in all my accounts with a hard drive, like four USB sticks and all of them are encrypted and the password to decrypt them is in my will.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I'm going to put all this stuff in a safe deposit box.
Speaker 1: And there's another reason I'm going to do that besides the practical reason.
Speaker 1: So that if I go to a fancy bank in Manhattan as a real fancy state deposit box, you can go in and use all those services.
Speaker 1: It's going to be like, oh, look at the fancy ass lobby and there's a giant ass safe and I get to go in there like it's a movie.
Speaker 1: Oh, is Ocean's Eleven coming in here soon?
Speaker 1: It'll be fun.
Speaker 1: And I'll probably have to pay money for it, but it's not that much.
Speaker 1: How much do they cost?
Speaker 1: I get the tiny one.
Speaker 0: I've never had a safe deposit box.
Speaker 1: I my mama.
Speaker 1: Well, let me search Manhattan.
Speaker 0: See, I mean, I when I was a kid, I had a safe.
Speaker 1: What's the fanciest bank in Manhattan?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 0: it's probably.
Speaker 0: it's probably something you've never even heard of because only rich people can even use it.
Speaker 0: It's secret.
Speaker 1: I'm going to go to.
Speaker 0: it's not FDIC insured.
Speaker 1: First Bank of Manhattan.
Speaker 1: It looks like they would have one anyway.
Speaker 0: So the moral of all this is there's no good answers.
Speaker 0: Even at a young age, you should think about what you want to happen to all your data.
Speaker 0: And if you care and if you care at all, set up some means for your wishes to be fulfilled, but more importantly, set up the technology such that they will be fulfilled.
Speaker 0: And if you don't know what to do, at least think about what your family or your friends might want to have happen.
Speaker 0: Because imagine if you die and no one could get access to your email.
Speaker 0: And they're really sad about that.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, imagine if they got access to your email.
Speaker 0: And it's all I've already talked about.
Speaker 0: different fetishes.
Speaker 0: trying to think is the worst thing they could find in there.
Speaker 0: They find out your cat pictures your whole life.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: What I think you can do is if you're the same philosophy as me of that, you're dead.
Speaker 1: Who cares what happens after you're dead?
Speaker 1: That's why I won't buy life insurance for myself because like, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: You know, I buy life insurance on someone else.
Speaker 1: Not for me.
Speaker 0: Would you let someone else pay for life insurance on you that pays out to them?
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: I don't give a fuck.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to pay my living money for money.
Speaker 0: So, uh, so me and a thousand listeners are going to get life insurance policies on you as long as you're not guilty of fraud.
Speaker 1: I got lost saying there's.
Speaker 0: that gives us a pretty high incentive for you to not make it too far.
Speaker 0: It's fine.
Speaker 1: It's fine.
Speaker 1: I was protecting me, but you're dead when you can't spend your life insurance from jail.
Speaker 1: You don't think the detectives, the first thing he's going to do in the murder case is look and see who has life insurance on me.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: Uh, you eventually get some, you have.
Speaker 0: thousands of people have licensed life insurance policies on you.
Speaker 0: Eventually one of them is just fucking crazy.
Speaker 1: Oh, you think you're open?
Speaker 1: The other guy will do it.
Speaker 0: I didn't, I'm not going to do it.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to pay out.
Speaker 1: It's going to be low when the numbers get too big anyway.
Speaker 0: No, because I have one of the first, I've had like a million dollar policy.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is that, you know, if you believe that you should worry about the people who are alive and what the people who are dead think doesn't matter because they're fucking dead, right?
Speaker 1: Then if you're concerned about your things and your data after you're dead, ask the people who are still alive what they want.
Speaker 1: And then because of laws require you to put in a will, just put whatever they want in the will, the people you care about so that they get what they want because you're dead.
Speaker 1: What the fuck do you care?
Speaker 0: what you want?
Speaker 0: Make sure you enable the technology, store the password, set up a way for it to actually happen.
Speaker 0: Otherwise it won't.
Speaker 0: Don't trust the companies that have the data like Facebook to follow the instructions of the will.
Speaker 0: Make sure the password's in the will somewhere.
Speaker 0: And if you want to commit awesome crimes 20 years from now, be a lawyer and be the one who takes everybody's wills.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: [inaudible].