Speaker 0: Hey, it's Thursday, January 24th, 2012.
Speaker 0: Thirteen, I ran.
Speaker 1: Did you say Tuesday or Thursday?
Speaker 0: I think I said Thursday.
Speaker 0: I definitely said Thursday, and tonight we're talking about parking.
Speaker 1: Parks-ing.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So as many of you know, it was recently my birthday.
Speaker 0: I survived carousel and all that.
Speaker 1: Or did you?
Speaker 1: Maybe in the world of Logan's Run.
Speaker 1: It's so far in the distant future, right?
Speaker 1: I have a theory.
Speaker 0: You have a theory?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Logan's Run is so far in the future that when they say 30 years, a year for them is not the same as a year for us.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: That has no relevance on whether or not I made it to 30.
Speaker 1: No, it does.
Speaker 0: And look at the people they killed in Logan's Run.
Speaker 0: They're all about 30.
Speaker 0: You've seen Logan's Run.
Speaker 1: But people also age differently in Logan's Run.
Speaker 0: Ah, I don't think they actually did.
Speaker 1: I'm saying they did.
Speaker 1: See, they're actually 300, but 300-year-olds in that world look like 30-year-olds in this world.
Speaker 1: So you didn't actually survive carousel until you're 300, so you're good.
Speaker 0: So our friend Judith came over, and her Natalie, and she made me some cupcakes for my birthday, made with whiskey and beer.
Speaker 1: Making cupcakes, making whiskey cupcakes.
Speaker 1: You like that?
Speaker 0: I like your reference to Adventure Time, the thing you haven't actually seen.
Speaker 1: I can do that.
Speaker 1: Just like you can do that.
Speaker 1: Except the only difference is that when I do that, I don't pretend to have seen the thing.
Speaker 0: What have I referenced that I don't know anything about?
Speaker 1: All the things.
Speaker 0: Like what?
Speaker 0: Name one thing.
Speaker 1: Everything ever.
Speaker 0: I did enjoy how you were at a magfest.
Speaker 0: You were like, "Check out that cute
Speaker 0: scarf."
Speaker 0: And it was clearly LSP, Lumpy Space Princess.
Speaker 1: I have no idea what that is.
Speaker 0: From Adventure Time, but you didn't know who that was.
Speaker 0: And you thought it was cute, which I thought was ironic, because if you watch the show, of all the characters you've ever seen in pretty much any animated thing, Akio, you probably hate the most.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure you're gonna hate Lumpy Space.
Speaker 1: I hate Akio the most.
Speaker 0: Who do you hate more than Akio?
Speaker 1: I mean, Akio's bad.
Speaker 0: He is the worst.
Speaker 0: You hate someone more.
Speaker 1: But it's not like annoying when Akio's on screen.
Speaker 1: That's the character you hate the most.
Speaker 1: It's the one where it's like every time they come on screen, you're like, "Get the fuck
Speaker 1: off.".
Speaker 1: Why are you even in the show?
Speaker 0: So Wesley Crusher?
Speaker 1: Every scene with you is an annoying scene.
Speaker 0: You see, Scott, if you were gonna make a Star Wars joke like your non-joke before, not having seen Star Wars, you're just Star Trek.
Speaker 0: I keep saying Star Wars.
Speaker 1: Well, it's funny you mention Star Wars, because my example was going to be Jar Jar Binks, right?
Speaker 1: Not evil and hated like the Akio, right?
Speaker 1: But hated as in, "Get the fuck out of here.
Speaker 1: Why are you in the show?
Speaker 1: I hate you because I don't want to see
Speaker 1: you.".
Speaker 0: That's basically a meta hate, like you hate for a meta reason.
Speaker 1: When someone says hating a character, that's usually the kind of hate that I usually think about.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll separate the two, because Jar Jar Binks is more annoying than Akio, and I like seeing Akio on screen, but he is just a bad person.
Speaker 1: Because I usually don't hate characters in fictional things for being evil, because it's not like they're actually Hitler.
Speaker 1: It's a fictional person.
Speaker 0: You're gonna pull the Luke Morgan.
Speaker 0: The evil's just doing its job.
Speaker 1: Well, no, I'm not saying that.
Speaker 1: Evil is still bad.
Speaker 1: But it's like, Megatron.
Speaker 1: He's totally sweet.
Speaker 1: I don't hate him.
Speaker 0: Because he's awesome.
Speaker 1: It's like, evil dudes in fiction are just the best, awesomest characters.
Speaker 0: Well, really, Starscream.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, Starscream is totally sweet, even though he's a dick, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like, I don't hate him.
Speaker 1: Soundwave.
Speaker 1: You love Soundwave.
Speaker 1: Come on.
Speaker 0: So we went out to the diner, and we had one of those moments that just paralyzed everyone with laughter.
Speaker 0: So we're sitting there, right?
Speaker 0: We got some water at the diner, about to get some food.
Speaker 1: Was there a hobo fucking a rabbit outside the diner?
Speaker 0: Making a hobbit.
Speaker 0: So, Judith... I told her, I'm gonna talk about this on Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: I took pictures of this.
Speaker 0: I was like, this is the moment.
Speaker 0: So we're sitting there, and she doesn't say anything.
Speaker 0: She lifts her arm and just kind of fumbles it.
Speaker 0: And basically, if you were just watching as a bystander, she just straight up fucking punches a glass of water off the table, and water goes everywhere.
Speaker 1: Did she really do that?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: She just punched the water, and it goes flying.
Speaker 0: So we all pause.
Speaker 0: No one does anything.
Speaker 0: And she puts her head down, and she's almost about to laugh.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, you realize the only thing you can do after this is stand up, flip everyone off, and walk out of the diner.
Speaker 0: Because then they'll think, we're the assholes.
Speaker 0: So then she starts laughing harder.
Speaker 0: And while she's laughing, the diner dude comes over with the biggest safety cone I have ever seen.
Speaker 0: And puts it on top of this spill of water like, oh shit, look out.
Speaker 0: And that was the end.
Speaker 0: This thing was huge.
Speaker 0: It was almost as tall as I am.
Speaker 0: It was like five feet tall.
Speaker 0: Was it wearing a Naruto costume?
Speaker 0: No, it was yellow.
Speaker 0: It wasn't orange.
Speaker 0: Orange?
Speaker 0: But I have another anecdote that I'm surprised not many people really commented on.
Speaker 1: Orange crayon?
Speaker 0: So I tweeted something.
Speaker 0: Well, has anything happened to you in the last day?
Speaker 0: Before I pull up my Twitter and read verbatim the tweet I tweeted recently?
Speaker 1: The only thing that's happened to me in the past day is, number one, woman it's cold.
Speaker 0: It's cold.
Speaker 1: And number two, your apartment smells real bad.
Speaker 1: I've had to spend time in its smelliness.
Speaker 0: It smells like wet plaster because a pipe exploded, but that's not my anecdote.
Speaker 0: That's an anecdote for another day.
Speaker 0: So yesterday I tweeted, and I tweeted something that not many people responded to.
Speaker 0: Quote, me, an older gentleman just straight peed on my shoe.
Speaker 1: Did a guy really pee on your shoe?
Speaker 0: Yes, an old man peed on my shoe yesterday.
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: He peed on my shoe.
Speaker 0: No words were exchanged.
Speaker 1: When did you tweet this?
Speaker 1: that no one saw it?
Speaker 1: Because that's the kind of tweet that people would see and reply to.
Speaker 0: You'd think that, and I tweeted it at 1256
Speaker 0: p.m.,
Speaker 0: which is right when the dude peed on me.
Speaker 1: Why were you doing in a place where someone could pee on you at 1
Speaker 1: p.m.?
Speaker 1: ?
Speaker 0: I was in a bathroom at least.
Speaker 1: Oh, you were in a bathroom and he peed on your shoe.
Speaker 1: It wasn't on a subway platform.
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't like.
Speaker 0: he walked over, opened up, and just peed.
Speaker 0: But he did pee on me.
Speaker 0: So one guy tweeted back, he's like, what, on the subway?
Speaker 1: He was thinking the same thing as me.
Speaker 0: And one other guy was like, he peed on your shoe, and you still consider him a gentleman?
Speaker 0: I don't know, I use the word gentleman to refer to old men, basically.
Speaker 0: So here's the deal.
Speaker 1: Use the word gentleman ironically or sarcastically.
Speaker 0: And I walk in at the same time as an old man and a younger man.
Speaker 0: And all of us go into stalls.
Speaker 0: I'm going into a stall because I've got to poo.
Speaker 0: I think the young man was going into a stall because he was intimidated that there were other people.
Speaker 0: And some people can't pee on a stage.
Speaker 1: Weird people.
Speaker 0: And the third old man went into a stall to pee, I don't know why, as an old man.
Speaker 0: So the stalls are shaped kind of weird, so I have not yet gone into the stall I'm going into.
Speaker 0: So I'm standing outside of it, about to open the door and get into it.
Speaker 0: And I'm standing next to the side of the other stall.
Speaker 0: So I'm standing there, and suddenly all this water splashes on my shoe, like a ton of it.
Speaker 0: And I thought, did water just fall from the ceiling?
Speaker 0: And I look up, and there's no way water could have fallen from the ceiling.
Speaker 0: Then I realized that the old man had started peeing and had that thing happen where you just fucking missed the toilet.
Speaker 0: For the first, like, I don't know.
Speaker 1: So the pee came out from underneath the edge of the stall wall?
Speaker 0: Like the line went under the stall wall, didn't hit the stall wall, went under it at the perfect angle, and just hit my shoe.
Speaker 1: So your shoe was pretty close to the stall wall, on your side.
Speaker 0: I was like seven inches away.
Speaker 1: So his pee crossed the wall.
Speaker 0: Yes, it was a cup, like this wine glass worth of pee, like boosh, all at once.
Speaker 1: That's a lot of pee.
Speaker 0: The guy just kind of keeps peeing, and...
Speaker 1: He adjusted his aim?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I just kind of stood there, like, did this dude just fucking pee on my shoe?
Speaker 1: What did you do about it?
Speaker 0: So, I just kind of stood there, and I didn't say anything.
Speaker 0: I was waiting to see if he said anything.
Speaker 0: What was I going to say?
Speaker 1: You peed on my fucking shoe?
Speaker 1: Buy me a new shoe, asshole.
Speaker 0: Well, luckily the shoe was waterproof.
Speaker 1: It's not pee-proof, it's still smell, man.
Speaker 0: I get the impression the guy was senile.
Speaker 1: Then why was he doing?
Speaker 1: in your fancy work building?
Speaker 0: There's like four other offices on my floor.
Speaker 1: Is it these senile old people taking care of place?
Speaker 0: It's like four lawyers, and then one mental health care facility, but the old man was... I think the old man is one of the lawyers that works in the building.
Speaker 1: Then he can afford to buy you a shoe.
Speaker 1: Or two.
Speaker 0: So, I rinsed my shoe off, and I went back into the office, and I walk in, and I'm like, "An older gentleman just fucking peed on my shoe,".
Speaker 0: and everyone's like, "What?
Speaker 0: On the
Speaker 0: subway?".
Speaker 0: Where's the shoe?
Speaker 1: I got to stay away from it.
Speaker 0: I was just so surprised.
Speaker 0: Mostly, it's like that time I spit that water all over you.
Speaker 0: Like, what do you do?
Speaker 0: You just stand there.
Speaker 0: You don't say anything.
Speaker 0: You didn't say anything when I did that.
Speaker 0: You just stood there looking at me.
Speaker 1: Did you pee on my shoe?
Speaker 0: No, I spit water all over you.
Speaker 1: That was a different situation.
Speaker 1: That was a lot of water, though.
Speaker 1: That was an intentional, hilarious situation.
Speaker 1: Not a guy peed on my shoe situation.
Speaker 0: So, it's Thursday.
Speaker 0: It's the lounge.
Speaker 0: You got anything to talk about in the lounge?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it's like... It's, you know, the lounge for this week is Scandals.
Speaker 0: You know, I've never set foot in there, and I really don't plan to.
Speaker 1: Google Latitude says otherwise.
Speaker 0: Poor George.
Speaker 0: He keeps recommending, because he comes here all the time.
Speaker 0: It's like, "Hey, were you just at Scandals?
Speaker 0: Do you want to go to Scandals?
Speaker 0: Hey, only two hours to
Speaker 0: Scandals.".
Speaker 0: Though I did learn recently in Latitude, you can backtrack and retroactively check into places.
Speaker 0: Like, if you didn't check in, like, you go through your history on the website, it'll be like, "Hey, on this day, here's all the places we think you were.
Speaker 0: Check the ones you were, and we'll add it to your
Speaker 0: timeline.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, my inferior iOS Latitude app does not do that.
Speaker 0: But that's the website.
Speaker 0: That's not anything in the app.
Speaker 1: But, I mean, the data just doesn't make it to the website a lot of the time.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: So...
Speaker 0: I mean, I can generate, like, heat maps of everywhere I've been.
Speaker 0: Oh, look, our friend Chie is in New Zealand right now.
Speaker 1: We know that.
Speaker 0: Let me zoom in to exactly where she is.
Speaker 0: She's in Invercargill.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God, that's the greatest name.
Speaker 0: Invercargill.
Speaker 0: She's on... What street is she on?
Speaker 0: She's on Alice Street.
Speaker 0: I think she's at the Waihopai School right now, which is next to the Southland Boys High School.
Speaker 1: Ooh.
Speaker 1: What am I gonna?
Speaker 1: street view?
Speaker 1: She's picking up high school boys.
Speaker 0: How can I get... Ah, there's no street view in Invercargill in Australia.
Speaker 1: I wonder why.
Speaker 1: Or in New Zealand.
Speaker 0: It's near the Winton-Lourneville Hoei.
Speaker 1: There's a giant park outside.
Speaker 0: It's not that big.
Speaker 0: It's the Queen's Park.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I wonder if it's the Queen apostrophe.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's near an airport.
Speaker 1: Is it Queen's Park with an apostrophe or not?
Speaker 0: There's no apostrophe.
Speaker 1: Oh, so it means it's the park of many queens and not just possessed by a single queen.
Speaker 0: Perhaps, unless the mark was simply lost.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, it's been a...
Speaker 0: We don't have anything?
Speaker 0: You haven't done anything?
Speaker 0: Nothing's going on?
Speaker 1: Week of Netrunner, I guess.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we already talked about Netrunner.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 0: I don't think I need to talk about it again.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much all that's going on is Netrunner and NS2.
Speaker 1: Those are my things right now.
Speaker 0: Oh, one thing I did do recently is I have a backlog of like 5,000 pictures I've taken that I just haven't uploaded to Flickr or anything because it takes a while to actually go through and sort them all.
Speaker 0: So I finally started doing that.
Speaker 0: So I started uploading my Flickr again and you know what, Flickr's getting better.
Speaker 0: Like they're adding little features and changing stuff.
Speaker 1: I uploaded all the stuff that I didn't over the past few months and during my sick day and it's pretty much the same as it was.
Speaker 1: Uh, you know, the only thing it really updated is the iOS app.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Android app updated substantially and I'm setting up some stuff in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the website is still pretty much the same UI.
Speaker 0: No, the organizing of sets and things, they added some more layers and stuff around that.
Speaker 1: Not that I saw.
Speaker 1: The organizer was pretty much the same as it was.
Speaker 0: It looked different.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter because I don't use any of that.
Speaker 0: I do it all in Lightroom anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know, right?
Speaker 1: But it's, you know, looks pretty much the same.
Speaker 0: So I guess I got a lounge news.
Speaker 0: I don't know where you all stand.
Speaker 0: I wanted to do a show on gun control, but Scott was like, hey, I don't want to talk about it.
Speaker 1: Don't give a shit about this bullshit.
Speaker 0: And Scott suggested we do a show on poop, which I was down with, but then he refused to do it.
Speaker 1: That was a suggestion just to be for argumentative purpose, not a legitimate suggestion.
Speaker 0: See, the problem with making the disingenuous, uh, uh, suggestion is that I am perfectly willing to go down that road.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't actually go down that road.
Speaker 0: It's like if someone tries to be passive aggressive with me, someone's like, ah, alright, I guess we can go to Applebee's.
Speaker 0: I'll be like, we're going to fucking Applebee's.
Speaker 1: I'll just set up that road, point it out as a, you know, sort of Pajamkin's village.
Speaker 1: The problem is, you know, actually going to go live there.
Speaker 0: Thing is, I know what Pajamkin's village is.
Speaker 0: Also, I think a poop show would be pretty funny.
Speaker 0: So I was totally willing to do it.
Speaker 1: A poop show is a Pajamkin's village of a show.
Speaker 0: I wanted to do a show on Texas.
Speaker 1: We did one already.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: In like 2007.
Speaker 1: And we only talked about taxes in the US.
Speaker 1: Has tax law changed that much?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes, it has actually.
Speaker 0: Also.
Speaker 1: Are you an expert on those changes?
Speaker 0: Uh, in the sense that actually a lot of tax stuff is way different from me now.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you, I'll discuss one thing about taxes that I learned at work today.
Speaker 1: A coworker remarked to me that they had not filed in three years.
Speaker 1: I was under the assumption that if you fail to file, you go to federal pound me in the ass prison.
Speaker 0: No, it takes about three years for them to notice that you didn't file a pretty simple process.
Speaker 0: I went through all this.
Speaker 1: So when they lost my 2009 tax return, apparently what happens when you don't file is if they owe you money, you just don't get it back to.
Speaker 0: if you owe them money, they eventually after a long ass time, figure out what you should have owed and send you a bill.
Speaker 1: They figure out what you should have and send you a bill plus 10% interest.
Speaker 0: It can be more than 10%.
Speaker 1: I'm saying a lot of interest.
Speaker 0: So let me know.
Speaker 0: So that happened to me.
Speaker 0: Now I didn't.
Speaker 1: This is news to me.
Speaker 1: Why have I been so fucking responsible?
Speaker 0: Because you don't want to pay that.
Speaker 0: If
Speaker 1: I ever start a business, I'm basically just going to ignore taxes until I'm making mad money and then pay all the back taxes plus interest because if my business exceeds it, you succeed enough to pay that and if the business fails, well, I just never wasted my money on paying taxes.
Speaker 1: What do you do?
Speaker 1: Come and get me my $0.
Speaker 0: remember about a year ago when I got a tax bill out of nowhere from New York state claiming I owed them like 10 grand and I ended up owing them, we talked about, I ended up owing him negative $20 after all that.
Speaker 0: So it was okay.
Speaker 0: But I was, I thought we could do a show about taxes, you know, just change.
Speaker 0: It's been six years.
Speaker 1: You already talked about that story.
Speaker 1: And we talked about the taxes on that episode.
Speaker 0: I got a lot to say about taxes.
Speaker 0: I was going to talk about civic structures and my feelings on like the legitimacy of taxes, how I would like to change tax code, all that stuff down.
Speaker 1: We're done with taxes.
Speaker 0: I have plenty to say on taxes.
Speaker 1: You can do your own podcast lately.
Speaker 0: I've been doing this a lot on the show because every time I do it, you listeners always seem to agree with me.
Speaker 0: So I'm asking you again, would you like to hear us do a new show on taxes?
Speaker 1: They're always going to say yes to anything you say or do you want to say anything?
Speaker 0: I say it's got, what was your idea, but I had no idea.
Speaker 0: So I do have one non idea.
Speaker 1: They'd say yes to that too.
Speaker 0: Since we're not going to talk about gun control, even though I got a complicated opinion on that, as always, I do want to bring up one thing because it's the lounge.
Speaker 0: I can bring up one thing.
Speaker 0: The thing I want to bring up is that it doesn't, I don't care where you stand on the gun control debate.
Speaker 0: There's a reasonable debate to be had in all directions.
Speaker 0: I don't want to get into that.
Speaker 1: But you wanted to have an episode on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't want to get into it right now, but you can make intelligent arguments on many sides of the gun control debate, however, independent of all of that, the NRA is fucking crazy.
Speaker 0: And if you're a member of the NRA, you should quit.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: So why are you bringing this up?
Speaker 1: Even though it has been true since 19 what year, what year, what now?
Speaker 0: The NRA was fine back then.
Speaker 1: It was never not crazy.
Speaker 0: No, actually it's only in the last couple of decades that the NRA has actually gotten weird.
Speaker 0: This is not news, nor is it excite, nor is it, you know, all right guys, tell us, would you like to hear my opinions on gun control?
Speaker 0: Would you like us to talk about this?
Speaker 1: Would you like me to talk about X?
Speaker 1: insert anything X and the answer will always be yes.
Speaker 0: Apparently they don't want us to talk about the great Gatsby.
Speaker 1: if they are, no, they do want to hear it.
Speaker 1: They just don't agree.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: If the people are spending time out of their day to listen to this fricking show, they want to hear us say anything, no matter what it is, we could sit here and say the, the, the, the, the, for 20, but someone is going to listen to it like Hypnotoad and they'll be fooled at least once and they'll like it.
Speaker 0: So anyway, things of the day, what do you got for me, Scott?
Speaker 1: I'm not sure if this is a improv everywhere.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's kind of thing that they would do, but it's posted not on their YouTube account.
Speaker 1: It's posted on a panhandler party, YouTube account.
Speaker 1: And of course the video is panhandler party.
Speaker 1: I think it's a YouTube account that was made just for this video.
Speaker 1: And what it is, the New York city subway and a panhandler comes on pretty typical.
Speaker 1: And then another one and then another one, it's this comedy sketch where a whole bunch of panhandlers all get on the same subway car at the same time.
Speaker 1: If you're a New York person, you can appreciate this video a lot.
Speaker 1: So if you're not a New York person, it might still be funny, but you will appreciate it less.
Speaker 0: Oh, that reminds me of something I was going to use this thing of the day a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I'll save it for another time.
Speaker 0: But basically it was this girl telling a hyperbole and a half style, uh, like blog image thing of her attempt to get home to Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: That was the thing of the day that I used on the thing of the day.
Speaker 1: It was the thing of the day, that's how you found out about it.
Speaker 0: I'll make it a thing of the day and see.
Speaker 0: if anyone notices like a year from now, I'll just do it.
Speaker 1: Why do you keep reusing it?
Speaker 1: We might as well just take an old geek nights episode, post it and change just the beginning part.
Speaker 0: No, I want to redo old geek nights episodes.
Speaker 1: I mean, we should just take an old episode, change the date at the beginning of the audio file and repost that audio file.
Speaker 0: I want to do episodes again without listening to the old ones and see if we have different opinions now.
Speaker 1: You just want to avoid the only part of the show that is hard work, which is coming up with a show idea.
Speaker 0: I just think it would be fun.
Speaker 0: I'd love to listen to like myself talk about, you like to listen to yourself talk, you say talk about something and then talk about the same thing from like seven or eight years ago in my life.
Speaker 1: That'd be cool.
Speaker 1: I do not want to do this.
Speaker 0: I mean, I read like, remember those articles I used to write for Gracie's dinner time theater.
Speaker 0: So I read those again and it's interesting reading those from my 10 year later perspective.
Speaker 0: So anyway, I have a related thematic thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Bill Cosby, funny man, I think his funniest routine ever is still to Russell, my brother whom I slept with.
Speaker 1: I like the one where he says and the chicken out of New York City, my favorite one of his, I don't know what the name of it is, but it's the one where he's like tread water.
Speaker 1: No parents don't want justice.
Speaker 1: You want quiet.
Speaker 1: And it's like, cause that is the number one thing when I, when I was a kid is I'm a kid, I wanted justice.
Speaker 1: I saw justice.
Speaker 1: I was taught justice everywhere.
Speaker 1: People would teach you about the justice system and fairness, but then they wouldn't just expense it.
Speaker 1: And I'd be like, fuck you.
Speaker 0: So relevant to this bill Cosby did a bit a long time ago, which is still relevant to this day, except it's no longer 15 cents, but the New York city subway is pretty special.
Speaker 0: There is a nut in every car.
Speaker 1: It's like multiple nuts in every car.
Speaker 0: So last time Emily and I went skiing, like the previous time, not this most recent time, we get up, you know, butt ass early in the morning to get on a subway to go to times square.
Speaker 0: And it's right around the hoboing hour.
Speaker 0: Like when the hobos are all going to wherever they go at the end of the night, you know, three, four or five in the morning.
Speaker 0: So we get on a car and it's vomited poop, the hobo.
Speaker 1: So how'd you get a different car?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: So the door opens, we are about to step in and we see it's the empty car.
Speaker 0: There's one hobo laying on the ground, passed out, covered in poop and vomit, getting a different car.
Speaker 0: We go root into another car just before the doors closed.
Speaker 0: Same deal.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Two adjacent hobo cars.
Speaker 0: I think it was the hobo commuter hour.
Speaker 0: That was the danger zone.
Speaker 1: But did you get from a bad one to a worse one or the worst one to a slight thing?
Speaker 0: I didn't want to risk it.
Speaker 0: It's like Russian roulette.
Speaker 0: And the problem was now...
Speaker 1: No, Russian roulette, there's only one bullet.
Speaker 1: This is the opposite of Russian roulette.
Speaker 1: This is five bullets, only one.
Speaker 1: safe empty chamber.
Speaker 0: Hard mode.
Speaker 1: Russian roulette and hard mode, bullet in every chamber.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess, no, that's all but one.
Speaker 0: Expert mode, it's a semi-automatic.
Speaker 1: Expert mode, it's an automatic, you have to hold it down for a second.
Speaker 1: So... A full one Mississippi.
Speaker 1: Tick, tick, tick, tick, tick.
Speaker 0: So in a moment, Geek Nights is going to be at the Penny Arcade Expo East doing not one but two panels.
Speaker 0: We are doing both on Saturday currently.
Speaker 0: We are going to be doing practical game theory and mastering game mechanics to brand new lectures.
Speaker 1: Oh snap, we should do something about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, I gotta write those things.
Speaker 0: I got a bunch of videos up from MagFest.
Speaker 0: We were on two panels and we presented a lecture.
Speaker 0: Two of those are up.
Speaker 0: The third one is going to be up shortly.
Speaker 0: We are going to be at Kineticon.
Speaker 0: It's a ways out but I only bring it up because panel submissions are open, y'alls.
Speaker 0: Submit your lectures, your panels, your events because me and Scott and one other person, a third person we've added to our head staff, the directors, the directorates, we're the ones who decide what panels get scheduled.
Speaker 0: So if you submit, I don't know, like precursor technology in science fiction, I'm probably going to accept it.
Speaker 0: If you submit Homestuck Jeopardy, probably not going to accept it.
Speaker 1: If you submit my rant about this one thing that bothers me, probably not going to accept that.
Speaker 0: But if you're, for example, James Portnow and you submit his rant about video game genres, I'm going to accept that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that's in 56, well PAX East is in 56 days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we got to get on that.
Speaker 1: Clock is ticking.
Speaker 0: And the book club book is The Great Gatsby which apparently is controversial even though it's really short and easy to read.
Speaker 0: Alright you punk kids, I swear to God, I am so sure that you alone, of all people in the last hundred years, have figured out what's wrong with this book that for almost a hundred years people have been talking about.
Speaker 1: And is super famous and is considered the great American novel and is taught in many schools and is hailed by many experts and academics.
Speaker 0: To make a side point, because I could make a lot of funny points about this.
Speaker 1: I'm sure that you, some punk kid on the internet who was very young, knows better than all those people.
Speaker 0: It's like on Slashshot, there's an article, Slashshot will have an article like check out this new kind of subway train.
Speaker 0: And there's all the posts that are like, but what if the train crashes, but what if the air is just like, yes, really Slashshot dude, I'm sure you thought of this.
Speaker 0: You thought of the obvious problem.
Speaker 0: Like what if it falls off the tracks that no engineer for the past 20 years of design and development even considered.
Speaker 1: Yeah, these guys, their only job in the world is to make trains, they are train experts, but you random guy in Slashshot who does something else for a job or possibly has no job.
Speaker 1: You read one article and you know more than all these train engineers.
Speaker 0: You have clearly figured out why our carrier fleet and our naval strategy is so flawed and can be taken out trivially by North Korea.
Speaker 0: Clearly you know better than him.
Speaker 0: So I'm not making that argument right now.
Speaker 1: I'm sure the top, the chief admiral of the entire Navy is on Slashshot.
Speaker 1: That's why.
Speaker 0: So kids, if you're evaluating the quality and relevance of a piece of literature, you cannot judge it by whether or not you agree with the point it is making or can understand or relate to the perspective it is putting
Speaker 1: forth or whether you find it personally entertaining to you.
Speaker 0: I guess people are confusing.
Speaker 0: For example, hunger games, a lot of people didn't like hunger games because they didn't like reading the main characters thoughts.
Speaker 0: You don't have to like it, but those main character thoughts were a pretty good representation of what like a 14 year old girl thinks like as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: Not many people want to read what a 14 year old girl's thinking about.
Speaker 0: But a lot of people, they're complaining about the Great Gatsby.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, all these people are vapid and stupid and they're making bad decisions.
Speaker 1: Isn't that a point?
Speaker 0: And then they're like, but that story has been told a million times.
Speaker 0: Why is this book special?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: You guys weren't really complaining too much about the Kingkiller Chronicle.
Speaker 1: Don't spill the load on this episode now.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Because I don't want to make the Great Gatsby show be about the punk kids who are just bringing out the haterade.
Speaker 1: Well, my favorite, my favorite video to explain this phenomenon, right, is if you go to YouTube and your search for why is the Mona Lisa, why so famous?
Speaker 1: It has almost a million views and explains to you why the Mona Lisa is so famous.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So now tell me, if you look at the Mona Lisa, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a painting of a girl.
Speaker 1: It's not bad looking, but it's not like I want to put it on my wall.
Speaker 1: It's not like I'm making my desktop wallpaper.
Speaker 1: It's not like I like it so much.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But I'm not going to go on saying it sucks.
Speaker 1: And you watch this video, it explains to you why it's so fucking famous.
Speaker 1: So you can just apply this
Speaker 0: to
Speaker 1: every other classic work in every medium of art that you don't understand or like and assume there are reasons along the lines of these same reasons that those things are so famous and hailed by academics and you just are not educated enough to know them or you just don't know them yet and you need a YouTube video to explain them to you.
Speaker 1: So assume Great Gatsby has those things because you know, it's a classic, you know, it's super famous.
Speaker 1: Therefore, it must have things of this nature making it so.
Speaker 0: And it does like I do with the anime kids like, yeah, you all say Evangelion is so overrated and so stupid.
Speaker 1: You don't have to like it, but it has things like this.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's why Evangelion?
Speaker 1: Why so famous?
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: It's super overrated.
Speaker 0: Let's say I agree with you.
Speaker 0: How come?
Speaker 0: not only are we talking about it, but you're talking about it.
Speaker 1: Why are you talking?
Speaker 1: And it's how many years old and you're still talking about it?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Talking about love.
Speaker 0: Hina was talking about it.
Speaker 0: Toussaint.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: No time.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: Digital target.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Nobody.
Speaker 1: Nobody's talking about it.
Speaker 0: Maybe Darryl Surratt.
Speaker 1: Barely.
Speaker 1: I don't even think he talks of a great digital target.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So anyway, the book club book is The Great Gatsby.
Speaker 1: Read it in or be a plebe.
Speaker 0: I think most of you didn't read it because or didn't like it.
Speaker 0: So short because you had to read it in high school.
Speaker 1: I didn't have to read it in high school because I never read it.
Speaker 1: It took me like a couple hours.
Speaker 1: It's so short.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you can play the game now.
Speaker 1: I played the game a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's OK.
Speaker 0: It's actually a pretty good platformer.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So this was Scott's idea for a show.
Speaker 1: It was not my idea in the forum.
Speaker 1: I went to the show ideas thread and I kept going back until I found an idea.
Speaker 1: that was a Thursday idea.
Speaker 0: And so this is possibly the most succinct suggestion we've ever had a post in there.
Speaker 1: And the post said one word parks.
Speaker 1: Now that could be taken as like public parks or playgrounds or, you know, the word park means many things.
Speaker 1: Parking parkour.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So I figure we should have park week.
Speaker 1: We could do parks, parking parkour as parker brothers, parking someone named Parkington.
Speaker 1: that I don't know.
Speaker 1: Just go on Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: I guess we're really we could talk about cool hand Luke.
Speaker 1: What does that have to do with parks?
Speaker 0: Why was he in jail?
Speaker 1: He was a thief.
Speaker 1: He was.
Speaker 0: What do you do?
Speaker 1: That's why he was cool hand Luke.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: What did he do?
Speaker 0: You don't remember.
Speaker 0: Do you?
Speaker 1: I just thought he stole because the beginning of the movie isn't bringing him into the jail.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The first scene I remember from the movie is like one of those behind the guy feet shots as he's walking in the he's handcuffed and the guy's walking him over to the to the.
Speaker 1: the jail.
Speaker 1: The well, the labor camp.
Speaker 1: It's not a jail.
Speaker 1: Jail.
Speaker 0: Well, it's a jail.
Speaker 0: It's just also a labor camp.
Speaker 1: And imprisoning.
Speaker 0: I have quotes.
Speaker 0: Lucas Jackson, played by Paul Newman, is arrested for cutting the heads off of a small town's parking meters.
Speaker 0: One drunken night.
Speaker 0: You don't remember that scene where he's laughing and walking around with that like pipe cutter just cutting all the heads of the parking meters off and laughing the whole time vaguely.
Speaker 0: That's.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: In fact, when they when they arrest him, he said something like, I was just bored.
Speaker 0: I forget exactly what he says.
Speaker 0: Like the cops.
Speaker 0: Like, what are you doing?
Speaker 1: I'm glad you don't get sent to labor camp for that these days.
Speaker 0: Should we bring labor camps back to show labor camps?
Speaker 1: We need to think to some.
Speaker 1: We you know, we have a labor camp kosha.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm sure there's someone on earth who needs to be in one.
Speaker 1: But most of the people who are in them do not need to be in them and should not be in them.
Speaker 1: And they're in North Korea or China or places like that.
Speaker 1: And, you know, so we even though there might be some people here that need to be in them, we probably shouldn't go doing that until you remove the other people from them to sort of even the scale.
Speaker 0: Scott, are you in parks or parking?
Speaker 1: It's up to you.
Speaker 0: It's up to me.
Speaker 1: I don't really get anything that begins with the word park.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So until I lived in New York City, fuck umbrellas.
Speaker 0: I thought umbrellas were stupid.
Speaker 0: Never used one.
Speaker 1: What does it have to do with parking?
Speaker 0: Because I drove everywhere and I parked with the car in a parking lot and I lived in the suburbs.
Speaker 0: So every place I would ever, ever go had parking that was basically next to the entrance to whatever it was I was going to.
Speaker 1: Even when I was in the suburbs and I drove everywhere, I would still often have to park in a parking lot that was relatively far from the entrance such that an umbrella would give me a significant amount of dryness depending on the amount of rain that was coming down.
Speaker 0: But the reason I still thought umbrellas were stupid was that if it was raining enough to where I couldn't wait for it to stop raining and enough to where getting wet mattered, wouldn't fucking drive anywhere.
Speaker 1: That's also true.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't go to the mall if it was raining.
Speaker 0: There were often cases though where I would- But in New York City now, I'm walking everywhere.
Speaker 0: You cannot avoid being outside no matter what.
Speaker 1: There were also often cases where I would drive to a place a significant distance on a schedule and the weather I had no control over.
Speaker 1: And when I arrived, I would park in a place and it just, well, it was raining that day.
Speaker 1: What choice did I have?
Speaker 0: See, my schedule, I really never had a schedule except school.
Speaker 1: In school, I'd be like, I'm going to so-and-so's house in New Jersey today, vroom, and then I get to New Jersey and it's raining.
Speaker 0: But if it's his house, I park in his driveway.
Speaker 1: Except there were these people and they have these gigantic driveways and maybe it's a big party and you park all the way at the street because people already filled up the driveway.
Speaker 0: Now, on the off chance that that happened, you know what I did?
Speaker 0: I had a coat because I'm going somewhere where I can hang my coat up.
Speaker 1: I had a lot of coats.
Speaker 0: And I just walk quickly to the door and don't get that wet.
Speaker 0: So I only needed an umbrella.
Speaker 1: My head still gets wet.
Speaker 0: In fact, I only owned an umbrella the day I no longer had a car and lived in New York City.
Speaker 0: And then I was like, oh, if it's raining, there is no way to avoid this.
Speaker 1: What if you went to an outdoor event and it happened to rain that day?
Speaker 0: What, I'm going to walk around?
Speaker 1: For example, a music festival.
Speaker 0: If someone brought, if I was at like a concert at Pine Knob and some asshole had this giant umbrella, it would probably get broken.
Speaker 1: You don't bring your umbrella up to the mosh pit, right?
Speaker 1: You sit on the hill on the side with your umbrella where you're not blocking anybody.
Speaker 0: No, you're going to get soaking wet anyway because water is going to stream down the hill into your blankie.
Speaker 1: You mean my portable folding chair?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And my waterproof boots.
Speaker 0: Again, events like that, if it rained, usually were canceled.
Speaker 1: No, a lot of them keep going.
Speaker 0: No, they were mostly canceled.
Speaker 1: Look up mudstock.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would not be involved in that.
Speaker 0: I would just go home.
Speaker 1: It was too late.
Speaker 1: It was already set like a long time in advance.
Speaker 0: I also never went to big things like, like if I went to a concert.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying I went to these things either.
Speaker 1: I just came up with an example of where an umbrella could be useful.
Speaker 0: I'm saying those examples were irrelevant to my life.
Speaker 1: So what does that do with parks, parking, parkour?
Speaker 0: Because I only needed an umbrella.
Speaker 0: Now we're only talking about parking.
Speaker 0: So I only needed an umbrella when I kind of, it could have been parks, I guess.
Speaker 0: I could, I could have been a long, uh, that could have been a red herring.
Speaker 0: So I was, it's funny because yesterday I was talking about this at RIT.
Speaker 0: I would drive to campus and park not that much closer, like surprisingly less closer to the building.
Speaker 0: I was trying to just walk to school and it wouldn't have been that much further than But it was further enough to where we would both drive anyway.
Speaker 0: Why was that?
Speaker 0: Why did you drive?
Speaker 1: Because the shuttle bus sucked.
Speaker 0: So why did it suck?
Speaker 1: Because the schedule sucked and it dropped you off in a shitty place.
Speaker 0: They always dropped you off like by the SAU cafeteria.
Speaker 0: It's like, great.
Speaker 0: That's like a half hour walk.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, it was weird because especially when we lived in the dorms, like I wouldn't drive because it would take me 20 minutes to walk.
Speaker 0: If I even had a car out to, what was that special lot for freshmen that was basically next to colony.
Speaker 1: Fuck you lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Cause Ken had his car when we were freshmen.
Speaker 0: So he'd park out there.
Speaker 0: whenever I'd go grocery shopping, I'd have to walk like 15 minutes to get to his car and then we'd have to walk with our fucking groceries all the way back from that.
Speaker 0: It was awful.
Speaker 0: But no, I drive to campus and then walk probably three quarters of a mile to get to the classroom I was going to from, I mean, I was lucky if I could find it was warm the two days.
Speaker 1: It was warm.
Speaker 1: I biked to class.
Speaker 1: That was good.
Speaker 0: I never biked really because I didn't have my bike at RIT, but I would roller blade to.
Speaker 1: I bought one at RIT.
Speaker 0: So that was the bike that eventually exploded.
Speaker 0: What I remember the ironic moment when I realized that one, I could pretty well, I could get around most parking tickets at RIT by having a collection of old parking tickets that I could just kind of write over the current date on and just put it on.
Speaker 1: Sometimes that works.
Speaker 1: And sometimes that's one of those high risk high reward.
Speaker 1: It never didn't work.
Speaker 1: There are times when it did.
Speaker 1: I read stories in the Internet of it not working for people and them getting royally fucked because of it.
Speaker 0: The thing is, the alibi is I just never took the parking tickets off of my car.
Speaker 0: There's like four of them there.
Speaker 0: You know, they just mail you and they, you know, no, the thing is usually they wouldn't put another ticket on your car usually.
Speaker 0: The other thing was funny.
Speaker 0: I remember is that it was a fifteen dollar fine to park in a place that was not a parking space, but it was a thirty five dollar fine to park in a lot.
Speaker 0: you're not allowed to park in.
Speaker 0: So I would park in the grass next to the lot that was closest to the school because if I got a ticket, I basically paid fifteen dollars for priority.
Speaker 1: But if the if the non parking space spot you parked in was too egregious, they would just park like in the middle of the car.
Speaker 1: They would just tow your ass and impound you.
Speaker 0: So I guess you have to park somewhere where they couldn't get a tow truck.
Speaker 1: We are also lucky that we did not go to a school.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they do now.
Speaker 1: that employed the boot.
Speaker 1: A lot of places use the boots.
Speaker 0: However, I've seen many places that are many places online where the boot has been confounded by the angle cut grinder.
Speaker 1: I have also seen this, but I would not attempt it myself.
Speaker 1: But luckily, I've never been booted.
Speaker 0: I've also never been booted.
Speaker 1: Nor would I get booted.
Speaker 0: I once got a parking ticket.
Speaker 1: I thought about getting a boot, like just buying one on eBay and just stick it in on someone's car.
Speaker 0: But I got that degree.
Speaker 0: So someone did that to the subway door and then throw away the keys in Queensboro Plaza.
Speaker 1: And then they would call like it would be in like some parking lots.
Speaker 1: They maybe have a Wegmans.
Speaker 1: They go to Wegmans and be like, how did I get booted?
Speaker 1: They call the local cops.
Speaker 1: How did I get booted?
Speaker 0: And he's like, you better get to put a fake parking ticket that goes to like some number.
Speaker 0: That's just some random dude's cell phone number from like the Yellow Pages.
Speaker 1: No, your worst enemy.
Speaker 1: No, that might trace it back to you.
Speaker 0: The best crimes are the ones that have zero motivation.
Speaker 0: in a parking lot with no security cameras to the security camera sees a nondescript dude wearing jeans and a T-shirt and a hat and sunglasses.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 1: Get into a car with your license plate number and drive away after booting a car.
Speaker 0: Scott, you park in like the shopping center next door and you walk through those little tiny wooded areas to get back to your car after taking a roundabout route.
Speaker 1: They see a guy carrying a boot to this other parking lot.
Speaker 0: He's in a backpack.
Speaker 0: Scott, I guess I put a lot more thought into elaborate pranks that might involve the police than you have.
Speaker 1: So who are you booting?
Speaker 0: I've never booted anyone, but I have conducted elaborate pranks in those regards.
Speaker 1: Let's buy a whole bunch of boots.
Speaker 0: I just boot every car like on a street.
Speaker 1: Just go somewhere where we like hate people parking in the city and just keep booting them.
Speaker 0: Except I don't really care.
Speaker 0: Cars in Manhattan are beneath my content.
Speaker 1: They are indeed.
Speaker 0: Though parking in Turkey was interesting.
Speaker 1: How is it different?
Speaker 0: Because we had a car.
Speaker 0: We fucking drove around Istanbul.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: It's mostly the same as driving in Jersey.
Speaker 0: The roads are kind of the same.
Speaker 0: We're driving down the main drive.
Speaker 1: So it's not like India.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: God, no.
Speaker 0: We're driving down the main drag in Istanbul, like north in the Mazlak area.
Speaker 0: And my coworker who was driving in this particular time turns to me and says, this reminds you of Route 9.
Speaker 0: And I was like, this is Route fucking 9.
Speaker 1: So your coworker is, how does that work?
Speaker 1: Are you allowed to drive in other countries?
Speaker 0: Every country has different rules.
Speaker 0: In Turkey, they just want to see an American driver's license.
Speaker 0: You're good to go.
Speaker 1: They don't need an international driver's license.
Speaker 0: There's no such thing.
Speaker 0: That's a scam.
Speaker 1: I didn't know that.
Speaker 1: You don't need a super license.
Speaker 1: That's a real thing.
Speaker 0: In fact, international driver's license, as far as everyone I've ever talked to who travels a lot has told me, are complete bullshit.
Speaker 0: Any modern language, any modern country will just take the driver's license from any other modern country and let you drive a car.
Speaker 0: They'll let you rent a car.
Speaker 1: I'm sure you can just go to the State Department website and they'll tell you, right?
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, actually they will tell you.
Speaker 1: I wonder if you like, what if the only driver's license I had, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say I lived in New York City.
Speaker 1: And I chose to get the state ID instead of the driver's license.
Speaker 0: I don't think that.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't think they let you drive with that, obviously.
Speaker 1: But my occupation was F1 driver.
Speaker 1: And I had a FIA super license with which to drive F1 cars.
Speaker 0: So here's my guess.
Speaker 1: I could not drive myself to the track, but once I got to the track, I was allowed to drive the F1 car.
Speaker 0: Here's my guess.
Speaker 1: Could I use the super license to drive cars on the regular road?
Speaker 0: In any country where F1 is popular, they would let you do it and would probably hook you up with some cool bullshit.
Speaker 1: I just want to be able to have the cop pull me over and say license registration and show F1 super license.
Speaker 0: Oh man, Captain Jack?
Speaker 0: Is that Captain Jack?
Speaker 0: Oh my God, Captain Jack.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone remembers that.
Speaker 1: He's like, "Oh, you want to see my license?
Speaker 1: How about this?
Speaker 1: Super license.
Speaker 1: And would you like to see my black card size in Joe Turr?
Speaker 1: How about my license to kill James
Speaker 1: Bond?".
Speaker 0: So one thing that bothers me about parking in general is that even at RIT, like every year they'd have that like, you know, petition the campus, like what would you like us to change on campus?
Speaker 0: And everyone was always like, "We need a parking garage.
Speaker 0: There's not enough parking on
Speaker 0: campus.".
Speaker 1: There was enough parking.
Speaker 1: There was never a time when all the spots were full.
Speaker 0: There were, however, certain time periods when the nearest spot was literally more than a mile away from where you needed to be.
Speaker 1: The only spot that you were permitted to park in was far away from where you needed to be.
Speaker 1: And all the spots that were close were given to people more important than you.
Speaker 0: Thing is, it wasn't more important.
Speaker 0: The way they prioritized was actually, it wasn't really even based on seniority because I was a senior, like my sophomore year.
Speaker 1: I still couldn't get the...
Speaker 0: I was a senior and I couldn't get it.
Speaker 0: I never got the fancy parking.
Speaker 0: And even when I wanted to pay for it, the waiting list was longer.
Speaker 0: They were like, "Yeah, you'll graduate before you get through the waiting
Speaker 0: list.".
Speaker 0: And I was like, "Then why is there even a waiting list?
Speaker 0: How can anyone get on
Speaker 0: it?".
Speaker 0: And they were like, "Well, some people go for it
Speaker 0: anyway.".
Speaker 0: So anyway, they gave parking passes primarily to the commuter students.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Well, because obviously they need it more for a legitimate reason.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, some people were commuter students, which meant they just had an off-campus house instead of an apartment.
Speaker 1: They could have lived right next to the on-campus apartment in a house.
Speaker 0: Oh, like those three rear houses that were next to Colony that were rented out by people?
Speaker 1: That was on the same exact road.
Speaker 1: They could have lived across the street from RIT, literally, but they counted as a commuter student because they didn't live in on-campus housing.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, I live in Colony.
Speaker 0: that's fucking like on the other... It's barely on campus.
Speaker 0: It's like in the middle of this marsh all by itself.
Speaker 1: Well, they also gave all the parking passes to faculty and staff.
Speaker 1: Those people just could park wherever the hell they wanted.
Speaker 0: Granted, for a while, what I did is I took the RIT sticker off my car for a while, because I didn't drive to campus that often.
Speaker 0: It was for like a couple months, and I parked in the visitor parking lot with no identification on my car whatsoever.
Speaker 0: So, basically, a car parked...
Speaker 1: But don't you need to get a visitor pass to do that from a building and then go stick it on your car?
Speaker 0: Yes, but from what I learned from people who worked there, basically, they only looked in that lot to see if there were RIT stickers, because if they weren't, they assumed it was like a parent or something who was going to get the visitor pass, because you can only go to that little booth if you're trying to park in that roundabout.
Speaker 0: What was interesting is if you had an RIT sticker, they would not even let you drive into that roundabout.
Speaker 0: They would only let you drive in.
Speaker 0: I had the Anime Club Super Pass, because I ran the club, that let me go in there, because I could load and unload.
Speaker 0: But otherwise... No, it wouldn't let me park.
Speaker 0: There were only like four parking spaces there anyway.
Speaker 0: I think like... The president parked there.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway.
Speaker 0: But everyone would always be like, "Yo, we need a parking
Speaker 0: garage.".
Speaker 0: One, it takes so long to park in the top of a parking garage, you're better off just parking a mile away and walking.
Speaker 1: Well, unless the parking garage has an elevator that goes right into the building, like a convention center or a hotel, right?
Speaker 0: Two, parking garages are way expensive, and in Rochester, would not last that long.
Speaker 1: No, you know, it's cold.
Speaker 1: Well, remember the parking garage collapse in Vigipsy?
Speaker 0: Oh my God, I remember that.
Speaker 0: We went to the mall one day, we're like, "Whoa,
Speaker 0: ho-ho.".
Speaker 1: I've parked on that.
Speaker 1: I've parked under that.
Speaker 1: And I knew it was shady when I parked on that.
Speaker 0: Every time we went there, we're like, "Man, this place is some shady shit right
Speaker 0: here.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, eventually I'm glad I started parking out by the Target, Target.
Speaker 0: I'm actually gladder.
Speaker 0: There's the one time we drove, you know, every weekend we drive up the road to the mall just because it's what you do, and one day I was like, "Wait a minute, we don't need
Speaker 0: anything.".
Speaker 0: And the arcade doesn't... Like, Initial D doesn't really work anymore, there's no more DDR machine.
Speaker 0: Why are we even... Let's just go home.
Speaker 0: And then we just stopped, we never went up the road again.
Speaker 1: We did, just not often.
Speaker 0: When we were forced to.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: By emergencies.
Speaker 1: Well, we went to Dragon's Den sometimes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we even went there less and less because malls fell apart.
Speaker 0: We did.
Speaker 0: Remember we used to run their website?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Those were dark days.
Speaker 1: For all five minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh.
Speaker 0: So, how was that alternate side parking when you had the car here?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I brought my car to New York City when I first moved here, and I used the car to move here by making a bunch of trips.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I borrowed that car the last time I drove it when I took it to the Oticon staff meeting.
Speaker 1: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, I had it here just because I didn't know what to do with it, and I used it rarely, like once or twice a month.
Speaker 1: But there's alternate side parking in New York City, which means they like to sweep the streets to keep them clean, and the street sweeper comes through.
Speaker 1: So you have to move your car to the other side of the street.
Speaker 0: I learned something recently.
Speaker 0: In rich neighborhoods, they do it less often because the rich people don't want to have to move their cars as much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it depends.
Speaker 1: Every neighborhood is different, every street is different.
Speaker 1: So where I lived, it was basically this side of the street Monday, Friday, that side of the street Tuesday, Thursday, and some days they cancel it, like holidays and snow days, you know.
Speaker 1: And you basically have to check the news and the Twitter and those things to find out when alternate side parking has been suspended.
Speaker 1: So when it's suspended, you could park anywhere.
Speaker 1: If it's not suspended, that means you can't park on that side of the street between the hours of eight in the morning and 10.
Speaker 0: If you do, they'll put a sticker that you basically can't get off your window.
Speaker 0: that basically says I'm a douchebag, and they give you a ticket.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's not good.
Speaker 0: So basically, if you I saw a car once in the Bronx that had like 20 of those stickers, like blocking a window.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So if you work, this basically means you have to move your car back and forth across the street, you know, three, four times a week.
Speaker 1: So that's what I did for a month or two before I got it for you.
Speaker 1: It's really not fun at all.
Speaker 1: I know some places, though, it's just like once a week at one time.
Speaker 1: So it's like just don't be don't have your car on that side of the street on Thursday night.
Speaker 1: And that's pretty easy to do.
Speaker 1: It's less troublesome.
Speaker 1: But, you know, basically, I'm never going to have a car in New York City unless a all of the above.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: A, I have enough money to afford the car.
Speaker 1: And, you know, where I don't even give a shit.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because I'm trying to save money.
Speaker 1: I'll rent or zip car.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Where I don't even give a shit about saving money to I can.
Speaker 1: I don't give a shit about money so much that I can buy a permanent parking space.
Speaker 1: That is my parking space in a driveway or a garage right now in my building.
Speaker 0: I could get one for a hundred and fifteen dollars a month.
Speaker 1: That is similar to what they charge in my building, which only has four spots, all of which are occupied.
Speaker 1: And two, I can get a car that's worth owning that I'll own for a really long time.
Speaker 1: That'll be really reliable and last a long time.
Speaker 1: So those things are all unlikely unless I win the lottery or get mega rich or who knows what.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's part of the reason why I'm so disencompassed to move to any non New York City, because even if I did that, even if I did all those things.
Speaker 1: How often would I use that car?
Speaker 0: Almost never.
Speaker 0: I would use cars a lot because I ski pretty much every weekend.
Speaker 0: And while the bus is good, be really nice just if I can get up and I don't I don't ski.
Speaker 1: So when would I use the car?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, you lead a closer life.
Speaker 0: Plus, you have your bicycle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So where am I going to go with this car?
Speaker 1: Maybe I would get the car, put the bicycle on top and go somewhere to bike differently.
Speaker 1: Thing is, we're going to.
Speaker 1: I could just bike there.
Speaker 0: Plus, if we're going to do that, like if we're doing something crazy, like we're going to take our bikes, like, I don't know, Albany or something, you mean Emily, you're going to take a zip car anyway.
Speaker 0: That's way cheaper.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying that's now I'm talking about the.
Speaker 1: even if I was mega rich and bought a car in a parking space, when would I use that car?
Speaker 1: It's got to be unused.
Speaker 1: You also have it once a month.
Speaker 1: I'd use it.
Speaker 0: You also have a driver and we all share the driver, even if I had a driver.
Speaker 1: How often would that driver actually need to drive me somewhere?
Speaker 0: I you know what?
Speaker 0: Pretty often, you know what I would use it for?
Speaker 1: Just going to work.
Speaker 0: No, God, are you kidding?
Speaker 0: In the winter, if I wanted to eat out all those awesome places in Brooklyn that I can bike to in the summer, but not in the winter, I would drop you off in front of the restaurant and then have him pick you up in front of the restaurant.
Speaker 0: I would eat in Brooklyn a lot more often if I didn't have to take the G down there, because right along Greenpoint Avenue, there's a lot of really good restaurants.
Speaker 0: And I actually like whenever I do eat over there, I really almost want to move there just because there's so many good restaurants.
Speaker 1: Maybe twice a year I would have him bring me to and from the Javits before the seven is extended.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And the next year it might be almost done.
Speaker 1: I saw pictures of boring ass tunnels.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The tunnels look so clean, though, but they're boring.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they are kind of boring.
Speaker 0: Well, they're boring.
Speaker 1: No, I think they finished that part.
Speaker 0: I think they did cut and cover actually for the end.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the anything else.
Speaker 0: This is why I could never moved was like New York City is like one of the only cities I could live in.
Speaker 0: Moving anywhere else would really fuck up my jam, because the whole reason to live here is that I literally do not need a car.
Speaker 0: Parking is not something that exists for me anymore.
Speaker 1: No, even though there's so many cars here and so much parking and people are fighting over the parking, have trouble with it and they fight over it.
Speaker 1: But it's like, why are you driving?
Speaker 1: I don't need to drive.
Speaker 1: Even if I moved your handicapped or old or, you know, you have those reasons that you need to drive.
Speaker 1: But not all of you have those reasons.
Speaker 1: Most of you don't have those reasons.
Speaker 0: But even if I moved to like Boston or Seattle, I'd still need a car because their mass transit systems are kind of weak sauce.
Speaker 0: Well, even if they're kind of OK, like Seattle, I wouldn't because you can walk across the entire city in like 30 minutes.
Speaker 1: But even in Boston, where it's kind of OK, the system, it shuts down at night.
Speaker 1: Then what do you do?
Speaker 0: And, you know, the last time I brought this up, a bunch of people were like, but what are you doing out like three in the morning?
Speaker 0: Like you kidding?
Speaker 0: Do you know how often I'm getting out a subway train to go home?
Speaker 1: OK, not even three in the morning.
Speaker 1: tomorrow after work, there's going to be Netrunner.
Speaker 1: that starts at six p.m Those guys, a lot of them leave at like midnight.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Guess what?
Speaker 1: That none of the other subways in the world are running at that hour.
Speaker 1: But I can just get on a choo choo train and go home really quick.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: For, you know, ostensibly two dollars and change, but really zero dollars.
Speaker 0: So would you believe that I while I learned to parallel park and I could do it because I had a driver's license, you have to learn that stuff?
Speaker 0: because, yeah, parallel parking is a really good test of whether or not you actually know how to drive.
Speaker 0: If you can't do it, you're actually probably a pretty bad driver.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I know you're in an unfamiliar car.
Speaker 1: You're not sure how far the back is.
Speaker 0: You know, I've only once or twice ever seen you successfully parallel park.
Speaker 1: I parallel park all the time.
Speaker 0: I've seen you fail many times.
Speaker 1: When have I failed?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So it was two or three times ago when you still had your car.
Speaker 0: And I recall very specifically we went up to Albany or something.
Speaker 0: We parked.
Speaker 0: We're going to parallel park to go get food.
Speaker 0: And you went it and your front was taken out and you went to get in.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: And it was pretty funny.
Speaker 0: And I laughed at you.
Speaker 1: I got in eventually.
Speaker 0: But you failed in the first go.
Speaker 0: You did not have a clean delivery.
Speaker 1: Not, you know, even people are experts in parallel parking, right?
Speaker 1: You know, who parallel park every day of their lives.
Speaker 1: They live like in Flushing or something and they parallel park in front of their house every single day.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you just know nothing.
Speaker 0: But net you never miss.
Speaker 1: Listen, even professional basketball players, you know, foul shots.
Speaker 1: No one has one hundred percent.
Speaker 1: No one.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Just because, you know, Michael Schumacher, he won most of the races.
Speaker 0: So would you believe in every race until two thousand and three or four?
Speaker 0: And I've been driving since I was 14.
Speaker 0: I'd never actually parallel park.
Speaker 1: Well, you're in Michigan.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Parallel parking was this crazy thing.
Speaker 0: Like you learn it in driver's ed, but it's literally like just an exercise.
Speaker 0: Like, why would you ever parallel in Connecticut?
Speaker 1: They didn't actually make us parallel park.
Speaker 1: They made us back into a parking space.
Speaker 0: A lot of parking lots actually don't allow you to do that.
Speaker 0: I have rules against it.
Speaker 1: Well, the diagonal ones should have rules against it.
Speaker 0: But the straight one should do.
Speaker 0: basically if you ever back into a regular parking space, you're doing it wrong.
Speaker 0: You're not.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to do.
Speaker 0: there is.
Speaker 1: There are incredibly rare circumstances where there may be a reason to do it, but they are most extremely, extremely rare.
Speaker 0: Most people who I see doing this there, I've kind of talked to people I knew who did this.
Speaker 0: They'd always be at the train station in Beacon and they'd be like backed into the space.
Speaker 0: They'd always say because I can get out of the parking lot quicker at the end.
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 0: That is actually false, because why do front end loaders and pallet jacks and forklifts have the wheels in the rear that turn instead of the wheels in the front?
Speaker 0: Because it's more maneuverable.
Speaker 0: Getting out of a parking space, you want the wheels that are turning to be furthest into the parking space for maximum maneuverability.
Speaker 0: It's easier to trap someone in if they're facing forward than they're facing backward.
Speaker 1: That is correct.
Speaker 1: However, the only rare example I'm trying to think of those rare examples is you do the pull through, but then you didn't back in.
Speaker 0: You just pulled through.
Speaker 1: Well, what if there is snow and it's unplowed and your front wheel drive, it may be advantageous to put the front wheels closer to the street part, which may become plowed.
Speaker 1: Thus making it easier to shovel your way out, because then you can shovel in front of those front tires as opposed to having to get between the cars plowed.
Speaker 0: You're going to be plowed in.
Speaker 1: Now you have to.
Speaker 1: only you have to overcome that hump with your front wheel drive right right there.
Speaker 0: If you have rear wheel drive, you might actually know you pretty much have even worse problems with rear wheel drive.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But either way, with the rear wheel drive, you know, you have to figure you might factor this in which direction you park, knowing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm going to gut.
Speaker 0: I'm going to gut it and say that I think you still in any situation where there's that this is going to suck at the snow no matter what.
Speaker 1: But you might if you depending on the drive of your car, you may have better chance of getting out of the spot easily, depending on the direction.
Speaker 0: So more importantly, if you don't set the parking brake when you park your car, you are stupid.
Speaker 0: You're a bad person.
Speaker 1: That is correct.
Speaker 0: You are.
Speaker 0: You're just.
Speaker 0: you're a bad human being.
Speaker 1: That is right.
Speaker 1: Most people don't do it.
Speaker 1: They just put the car in park and then they take their foot off the brake and the car goes schlump.
Speaker 1: Right when the car goes schlump.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You basically put the weight of the car on park P, which is this thing in a transmission park.
Speaker 1: That is not good.
Speaker 1: If you would put the emergency brake on and then take your foot off the brake, your car doesn't go schlump.
Speaker 1: It just sort of stays where it was.
Speaker 1: And now the weight of the car is resting on the parking brake, which is a ten dollar piece of metal and a spring and a cable, as opposed to a multi-thousand dollar transmission.
Speaker 1: You know, not saying that leaving your car and I bring this up because it's going to break your transmission.
Speaker 0: But I'm just saying there were several instances at RIT where I had a bunch of drink and I had someone else to drive my car back like from a party or something.
Speaker 1: They didn't undo the parking.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They start to drive and they start driving.
Speaker 1: You do it and they wouldn't put the brake undo.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And they start driving with the parking brake on going.
Speaker 1: And it's like, OK, you're destroying my ten dollar piece of plastic and also hurting my car.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Actually, my car couldn't back out of the parking space with the brake fully pulled in.
Speaker 1: I had that that tempo could actually drive with the parking brake.
Speaker 0: I know because we left it engaged one time because it wasn't obvious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I remember that old cars.
Speaker 0: So parking now, the last time I drove anywhere.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, you use that parking brake even if you're on a hill, even if you're not on a hill.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: Even if you're on a hill, that's like if you if you're a soldier and you have a gun, you use it even if you're in a firefight.
Speaker 1: When you're on a hill, when you're not on a hill, when you're no matter what, when you stop the car, you have your foot on the regular brake.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You turn you put the car in park, then you pull the park or neutral if it's a manual.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You turn the manuals are obsolete technology.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Except for race cars.
Speaker 1: You turn the car.
Speaker 1: I said it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then you engage the parking slash emergency brake and then you take your foot off the regular brake and then you get out of the car and leaving from parking.
Speaker 0: You get in your car, you start the engine.
Speaker 0: You had your foot on the regular brake, put your foot on the brake, then you release the emergency brake, then you take your car out of park.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Into our or or whatever it is.
Speaker 0: It's probably our or or it could be.
Speaker 0: Could be the deal with the O around it, the cartouche.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever it is you put it into neutral.
Speaker 1: You're on a hill.
Speaker 1: You're going to roll down.
Speaker 0: So I won't in a name, but I think the saddest anecdote in this is one time me, Scott and someone we know, we're in my car, my sunfire.
Speaker 0: We were in Beacon and we drove up to up to Fishkill across to eat at a restaurant.
Speaker 0: You park the car parallel park wise and I stop and our friend opens.
Speaker 0: He's in the passenger seat and Scott's in the back and he opens the door and finds that his weight.
Speaker 0: Has brought the door down such that he cannot actually open the door and the door becomes jammed in the grass.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: Remember that?
Speaker 1: No, I remember when we were at a station and we got out of the car and he went, we saw that the shock in the car had been so depressed by the weight of people in the backseat that we had to sort of push the car back up to sort of refill the shock with gas.
Speaker 0: So there I remember that there was a worse situation than that.
Speaker 0: This was when I was driving to New York City with Lisa one time the night before.
Speaker 0: I think you were with me and Pete was with me.
Speaker 0: And no, I was with you and I was like, my rear tire is kind of low.
Speaker 0: I should go put some air in it.
Speaker 0: You're like, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: Pick Pete up first.
Speaker 0: So we go to pick Pete up.
Speaker 0: We get to Pete's place and Pete's like, dude, your tire is fucking flat.
Speaker 0: It's fucking flat.
Speaker 0: It's flat as fuck.
Speaker 0: So I limp over to a gas station and I'm like, all right, let's try to fill it.
Speaker 0: Now it's done.
Speaker 0: So I'm propping the car up to put the donut on.
Speaker 0: and remember I start jacking the car up and the car goes up and the tire is still touching the ground because the shocks are just fucking shot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do remember that aspect.
Speaker 0: So I got the real tire like fitted on the rim again and working.
Speaker 0: And then I lowered the car back down and the one tire is just like up on a still like doop.
Speaker 0: So I had Pete like push it back down and then I drove on that dubious piece of shit to New York City the next morning.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.