Speaker 0: Hey, it's Monday February 11th 2013.
Speaker 0: I'm ran I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight talking about routers.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I'm walking down that long ramp just now coming back to the studio and from the four five six to the seven train Under Grand Central.
Speaker 1: Oh that ramp long ramp.
Speaker 0: It's pretty wet.
Speaker 0: So it's kind of slippery and it's downhill.
Speaker 0: I'm walking I'm walking and a girl next to me wearing these tall boots just like falls out of nowhere Just like our age.
Speaker 1: that'll happen.
Speaker 0: She just falls and she goes like and doesn't get up right away.
Speaker 0: So I kind of paused and do the kind of New York thing If you look a little bit just to see if it's something you should get involved with.
Speaker 0: Yep, and her ankle is 90 degrees Okay, and she probably some weird-ass shoe and she's like trying to get up and like she can't get up and she's not yeah No for a second.
Speaker 0: I'm like, whoa But she's not really yelling or anything.
Speaker 0: So she her friends like get her up on her feet and then she reaches down and pulls her boot back up.
Speaker 0: She fell because her foot misaligned in the boot and the boot itself turned 90 degrees Yeah, and her foot was like six inches up in the boot.
Speaker 1: What the hell?
Speaker 1: Why don't you put your foot in your shoe?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: So basically her fail was that she was wearing jank as boots.
Speaker 0: So I went from thinking she had broken her ankle sideways which would have been Kind of disturbing and I probably wouldn't have brought it up on geek nights to kind of funny instead.
Speaker 0: and it what seals?
Speaker 0: It is her friend Once like picks her up and she's like man.
Speaker 0: I told you these boots are shit.
Speaker 1: As brings up you are these things.
Speaker 1: this brings up something that is a bother of mine, right?
Speaker 1: That is often Exposed when people come to the city where much walking must happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then we had a friend who wears high heels when they visit us not even high heels But I am.
Speaker 1: I am opposed to any shoe that is not functional, right?
Speaker 1: It's like what is the point of a nice-looking shoe?
Speaker 1: you buy it because it's super nice-looking even though I don't agree that those Shoes are even nice-looking.
Speaker 1: personally That egg cannot be worn or walked in or run in or anything, right?
Speaker 0: I have one metric in New York City.
Speaker 0: Can you walk as fast as I plan to walk For at least a mile on New York City streets without with neither discomfort Nor damage to the shoe because they are damaged to your foot because if you cannot you probably either shouldn't wear those shoes.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't come to New York, right?
Speaker 0: If you're way shorter than me then you basically we have to prorate your speed of walking to how long your legs are.
Speaker 0: I'll give you that.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: I 4.6 miles per hour down the street at a sustained rate because for them that's running.
Speaker 0: But I guess I got a much more related thing that happened.
Speaker 0: So work today.
Speaker 0: coworker Had a problem.
Speaker 0: He has an old laptop and basically the reason I Like a year - that's not that old.
Speaker 1: It's kind of old.
Speaker 0: So basically I'm asking you this Kim curious if you would suggest what I did because I was the office hero Because I gave advice and he was able to recover the data hard drive and Laptop got immersed in water.
Speaker 0: Oh, let's forget about how laptop fucked.
Speaker 0: Done forget the laptop.
Speaker 1: Okay, take the hard drive.
Speaker 0: Yep, he dried it and everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you waited days But like you do, you know if a hard drive if you get a phone or something What you turn it off take the battery out and just wait a few days And hope it dries out and see if it'll start at the end.
Speaker 0: So he does that.
Speaker 0: and what he does?
Speaker 0: he takes one of those external enclosure.
Speaker 0: things up good idea plugs it in Mm-hmm, and just turns on the power.
Speaker 0: doesn't look into a computer just turns on the power.
Speaker 0: It's a good idea.
Speaker 1: Good idea.
Speaker 0: And all it does is go click Click Oh click nothing happens.
Speaker 0: Oh, so he of course tries plug into a computer same thing.
Speaker 0: It just goes click click.
Speaker 0: So Scott.
Speaker 0: My question to you is in that situation.
Speaker 0: It's magnetic.
Speaker 0: Obviously what?
Speaker 0: yes it's a spinning disk a Ladled standard laptop size SATA spinning disk.
Speaker 0: I think it's 80 gigs or 120 something like that.
Speaker 0: Mmm, what would you suggest he do?
Speaker 1: There are three tricks I know each of which are the more extreme option.
Speaker 1: right option number one smack it once then try again.
Speaker 1: option number two The old freezer trick.
Speaker 1: but I would be hesitant on the freezer trick because of the water possibility But with the three days of drying I would be.
Speaker 1: so.
Speaker 0: the freezer trick works, of course straight up.
Speaker 1: they basically You put in a ziplock bag you put it in the freezer you take it out You know start up and you get the data off really quick before breaks again.
Speaker 0: So basically, yeah We thought along the exact same lines.
Speaker 0: We know.
Speaker 1: and an option three is the bathroom clean room.
Speaker 0: Scott I think you and I know the same amount about hard drives.
Speaker 1: Why wouldn't we?
Speaker 0: Well, there's some things like.
Speaker 0: I know more about networking.
Speaker 1: You had a freezer at work that you used.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how long?
Speaker 1: how long did you put it in the free?
Speaker 0: and so basically he's like Well, how do I get the data off?
Speaker 0: and I was like, did you try hitting it?
Speaker 0: He's like what?
Speaker 0: and I'm like, well you get his.
Speaker 0: I explained like the torque and how you want to get it spinning again.
Speaker 1: Maybe just the thing is off the edge of the discs and you know the reader and if you smack it'll bounce back.
Speaker 0: Okay, but now that's not gonna work.
Speaker 0: So basically I'm like, alright Here's what I would suggest and I explained like let's put it in the ziplock bag put it in the freezer.
Speaker 0: I said at least two hours, which is about right for a consumer freezer.
Speaker 1: I would have been slightly wary because of the water but it's already dead.
Speaker 0: So I mean I would assume that the water was gone because it's been dried for a long time And if water got in like fully water is very unlikely to get in.
Speaker 1: It's most likely to be on the contacts on the board if the water was still in there.
Speaker 1: Then it's fucking water is very unlikely to get in where the discs are But it'll get maybe into where the bearings are.
Speaker 0: That's what I was thinking.
Speaker 0: the main reason these tricks work is because you're trying to just reduce the the Torque necessary to get that disc spinning.
Speaker 0: because once it's spinning you're good.
Speaker 1: Unless the control you have to get the the reader has to fly on the surface.
Speaker 0: It might if it falls off, but those are all secondary problems.
Speaker 0: and the click click click was obvious.
Speaker 0: It can't spin the disc up at all.
Speaker 0: If it did nothing.
Speaker 0: I would assume the controller was dead if it had spun up, but there was no data.
Speaker 0: I would assume there's some problem in the platters, but the fact that it did the click click Click like that meant it was trying to spin the disc up.
Speaker 0: hmm So I'm explaining like what to do and he's looking at me and now the whole office is watching like what?
Speaker 1: What did you bet money on it?
Speaker 0: No, I was like it can't hurt just trust me.
Speaker 0: So he does it and sure enough spun up just fine got all the data off of it.
Speaker 1: Can't they never heard of the freezer trick?
Speaker 1: now you hired a whole bunch of Technological people to work at a company that make software and not one of them knows guys are trick.
Speaker 0: most tech people I know Don't know how to recover data from hard drives.
Speaker 0: hmm because that is a skill that was only relevant in the day Back when one you and I we could only afford one hard disk.
Speaker 1: now I have some more than I need.
Speaker 1: I got rid of a bunch of them.
Speaker 0: You'd buy a new hard disk But you're gonna fill it up with stuff and the old one you never to put that data.
Speaker 0: We didn't.
Speaker 0: couldn't afford an external hard disk back then no and also back then spinning discs.
Speaker 0: We're way more prone to failure.
Speaker 0: They were yeah, so we and Even if I backed up my data I couldn't afford to buy a new disc.
Speaker 0: so if it has died like anything I could do to get it spinning again just To use it for another day.
Speaker 1: Why don't we try to put the old?
Speaker 1: The old disc in the freezer?
Speaker 0: you know that my oldest.
Speaker 0: you think I didn't try that You think I didn't try.
Speaker 0: it's the platter thing.
Speaker 0: I think is the only way to get that data.
Speaker 0: hmm though I looked and apparently it's only a few thousand dollars now for like those data recovery people instead of the few tens of thousand.
Speaker 1: Is it worth a few thousand dollars to get that mp3?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it might be.
Speaker 0: Maybe they'll kick start.
Speaker 0: I'll kick start.
Speaker 0: Let's see if we can get that mp3.
Speaker 1: That's all you Tell you.
Speaker 0: so it's a it's Monday.
Speaker 0: It's not the lounge.
Speaker 0: It's tech day.
Speaker 0: So you got any news?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there's a rumor going around and I love this room.
Speaker 1: There's no real good news going on.
Speaker 1: so it's good as rumor news is rumor of Apple watch.
Speaker 1: But this rumor was an old rumor and it's been reinvigorated and I kind of want one.
Speaker 0: I've wanted one forever.
Speaker 0: the only reason I didn't kick start the pebble is that Because the pebble and this is just me with my own uninformed opinion not slandering or labeling or anything.
Speaker 0: To me a thing like the pebble coming through Kickstarter mostly out of nowhere Implies that it'll probably work and do what it says.
Speaker 0: But the time to market for something like that versus say if Apple or Google did it for their respective platforms the time to market is gonna be so much shorter for Apple or Google and they have so much more access to R&D and manufacturers that even if the pebble comes out tomorrow a Month after that the Apple one is gonna be a hundred times better.
Speaker 1: It's funny that you said that because I just got an email today and you know what the email said.
Speaker 0: Your hexbrite flashlight shipped.
Speaker 1: your pebble watch has shipped.
Speaker 0: Oh you kick-started it.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: And so the thing is if this Apple watch comes out You can expect an eBay listing pebble watch for sale.
Speaker 1: But yeah the thing about this app new Apple watch rumor is it's combined with a non rumor of Corning willow glass and Corning is pretty much number one glass there is.
Speaker 1: Their factory is in New York.
Speaker 1: I've been there.
Speaker 1: It's cool.
Speaker 1: and the willow glass is basically this flexible glass and Theoretically you can.
Speaker 1: right now when you make an LCD you have to basically make it in layers.
Speaker 1: So it's like you get the color layer and the light and then a piece of glass and another piece of glass and then the Touchscreen glass goes on top right with this willow glass Everything in the willow glass which is in itself thinner than any of those individual layers and is flexible.
Speaker 1: so This you know.
Speaker 1: there could be some ridiculous Apple watch.
Speaker 1: I guess on paper.
Speaker 1: that would be like ultimate future where it's a strip of glass There's a strip of glass with a watch in it, and you wrap it around your wrist even though It's entirely made of glass.
Speaker 0: This is what people are saying.
Speaker 0: the problem with high with with Kickstarter But more in general that just that.
Speaker 0: the idea of yeah Why don't I have a watch?
Speaker 0: That does what you know.
Speaker 0: back in the day the watch was just a convenient way to show a very useful metric of information.
Speaker 0: Now I have so much information on my phone Why don't I just have another display on my wrist?
Speaker 0: like why don't we have that?
Speaker 0: the answer is?
Speaker 0: Material science battery science wireless science.
Speaker 0: there wasn't enough a consumer market processing power.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of reasons we're right about at the time where that can happen And it's a sure thing.
Speaker 0: so the actual specific implementation details of how it's done hardware and software is Literally all that matters.
Speaker 0: this has been the obvious idea for a decade.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I hate watches mostly because I always lost Because I have that information somewhere exactly so and then it's like well Why do I want something that has a timer and a stopwatch?
Speaker 1: should I have that in my pocket?
Speaker 1: well now?
Speaker 1: It's at the point where aha if the watch doesn't suck Then that means I never have to take the thing out of my pocket Which is annoying.
Speaker 1: to do so.
Speaker 0: I actually have a kind of reason Why I'm gonna try out all these fancy watches.
Speaker 0: so back in the day like middle school I know I got watches.
Speaker 0: I wore this watch in middle school because I wanted to know exactly what time it was Because I could do the cool thing like middle school kid like when you need to go out on that high note.
Speaker 0: You know middle school equivalent of a high note.
Speaker 0: it's the one day where you're sitting in class like in June right before school gets out and You're sitting in like fourth period English or something and your watch is timed where you know the exact second the bells gonna ring.
Speaker 0: Yep, so you just kind of get up and start walking toward the door, and it's usually like hey Where are you?
Speaker 0: and then the bell rings the second you hit the threshold?
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: you you your whole middle school career to pull something like that off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then in high school I realized that I don't want to know what time it is all the time But I want the ability to know what time it is But I don't want the time to always be like.
Speaker 0: oh You know if I'm waiting for like an allergy shot or something.
Speaker 0: I don't wanna be like.
Speaker 0: well four minutes have passed 401. fuck I'm bored, but I needed to know what time it was for example at RIT.
Speaker 0: If am I going to miss my class?
Speaker 0: I just get up.
Speaker 0: yes, I just woke up in an unidentified room I think in building six.
Speaker 0: who am I?
Speaker 0: what time?
Speaker 0: is it something?
Speaker 1: I just want to point out of all these watches right the pebble is like a hundred bucks.
Speaker 0: the Apple one who knows what it'll be right if it ever exists, but Pay six hundred bucks for one that did what I want like an awesome one.
Speaker 1: the point is even six hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: Compare that to the price of like the extremely fancy like Tag Heuer Folex.
Speaker 1: I mean Rolex real Rolex right it's like.
Speaker 1: it's ridiculous that the best watch in the world you know Technology-wise like a few hundred dollars.
Speaker 1: But like there's people still trying to sell watches for a whole jillion dollars because rich people buy Fashion statements.
Speaker 1: Rolex gotta put computers in that shit with no.
Speaker 0: that would actually ruin the reason Those people buy those things.
Speaker 0: Why they buy them purely for the fashion statement?
Speaker 0: They don't look at those watches.
Speaker 0: I've seen dude Scott.
Speaker 0: I go to business meetings.
Speaker 0: I meet people at conventions who have more money in their checking account than I will ever have made in my entire life.
Speaker 0: All right those dudes are wearing the $10,000 watch.
Speaker 0: they pull their cell phone out and look at it.
Speaker 0: See what time it is Straight up.
Speaker 1: isn't the watch really uncomfortable and big?
Speaker 0: I don't know they.
Speaker 0: they wear them.
Speaker 0: They probably wearing a watch for the last 40 years.
Speaker 1: That's the number one thing.
Speaker 1: all these watches is the discomfort.
Speaker 1: But I imagine a strip of glass that is flexible might be more comfortable.
Speaker 1: I just hope it's more comfortable than a stupid wristband thing that you get it mag fast.
Speaker 0: So I want to do there's a lot of obvious things that we could say.
Speaker 0: so I want to talk about the less obvious things.
Speaker 0: But this is an article talking about basically how and why?
Speaker 0: Professors and this extends to just teachers and faculty in general in educational institutions reject classroom technology and And there's a lot of easy low-hanging fruit things we could say about this.
Speaker 0: but obvious things yes.
Speaker 0: But to summarize them all one a lot of these teachers Just literally know nothing about technology.
Speaker 1: That's not a.
Speaker 0: Independently of that the people making the purchasing decisions for you know the IT Equipment or the software know nothing about technology, so they buy a busted ass like written in Delphi.
Speaker 0: it's a bird like Scheduling stain it's a plane and then they give it to the teacher who all who not only sucks at computers But also is going to suck it using this thing that itself sucks.
Speaker 1: It's captain obvious.
Speaker 0: meanwhile the kids I'll have their iPhones and their tablets, and they know better.
Speaker 0: But there's also a kind of a side that despite all of that.
Speaker 0: It's not just that these people don't know technology But reading some of the quotes of like what these people say about technology.
Speaker 1: Oh are they hilarious?
Speaker 0: it basically means That these people even if that you know they don't recognize that maybe the software They're getting is bad, but there could be a good solution.
Speaker 0: They reject the fundamental idea of bringing new technology into the classroom.
Speaker 1: well a lot of people You know what is to be gained?
Speaker 0: This is a quote for students by bringing IT into the class.
Speaker 0: there isn't any.
Speaker 0: you could teach all of chemistry with a whiteboard.
Speaker 0: I don't really think you need IT or anything beyond a pencil and a paper.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 1: That's true You could teach chemistry with a chalkboard Could write software with a notepad.
Speaker 1: in my life scheme If you have a classroom full of children who are from this millennium and not the last one They're gonna be bored to fuck with your slow-ass boring whiteboard.
Speaker 1: And maybe if you had some IT that did cool stuff You could keep their fucking attention on the chemistry and then actually learn it.
Speaker 0: not even that there's basic things like the teachers like Managing grades and scheduling things that should be trivial, but it's the teachers seem to and obviously I'm generalizing, but the people who are the are going to bear the brunt of my ire in this article.
Speaker 0: anyone who's anti-technology are the people who are.
Speaker 0: They deny the fundamental idea that technology can be used to make something better because they're small minded.
Speaker 1: They don't.
Speaker 1: they're not technologically minded, then they see a technology in use that is bad.
Speaker 1: They don't know how to use it and make the most of it.
Speaker 1: So then they can't imagine one that doesn't suck because they don't know.
Speaker 0: But I ran into this all the time when I worked in the hospitals.
Speaker 0: I mean I had this one moment I talked about.
Speaker 0: this is the whole world 2006 or so on geek nights, but basically we were installing in a bunch of hospitals in New York State Prescription printers, so there you use some system to you know say it's the stickers that goes in the bottles right.
Speaker 0: no No, the actual prescription you take to the pharmacy
Speaker 1: okay,
Speaker 0: so rather than having a doctor write gibberish on a piece of paper
Speaker 1: Oh, it prints out a piece of paper The only
Speaker 0: way to write a prescription
Speaker 1: is to
Speaker 0: go into the system and say this drug This patient this dosage you know whatever and it has.
Speaker 0: then the printers are locked and have a serialized.
Speaker 0: So it prints with a unique barcode.
Speaker 0: Oh, so it's totally legit, so you can't fake a prescription and the doctor can't mess up a prescription.
Speaker 0: Hmm, and it's a. it was a great system.
Speaker 1: That's really good about.
Speaker 0: it is great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one doctor in particular, and this is the most egregious thing that happened But this sort of thing was the norm and not the exception.
Speaker 0: Literally I knocked on his door, and he's a little private office, and I was like hey I'm here to install your and he says get the fuck out of my office.
Speaker 0: And I'm like.
Speaker 0: but we scheduled this.
Speaker 0: I did and he's like I don't want your technology bullshit in my office I don't need a printer.
Speaker 0: and I point out he did not in fact have a printer in his office.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna write my prescriptions, New York State can't tell me what to do.
Speaker 0: do not leave it here.
Speaker 0: I'll throw it away.
Speaker 0: Now I didn't really care about my job at that point cuz I decided to quit.
Speaker 0: anyway I would have fought with that guy so hard.
Speaker 1: I would have been like fine I guess I'll take all your x-ray machine - how about the stethoscope?
Speaker 1: because you apparently don't like technology.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so now instead what I did is I said fine And I left then went back to his office when he wasn't there.
Speaker 0: unlock the door because I have the master key And I installed it anyway mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Did he throw it out?
Speaker 0: Yes?
Speaker 0: He threw it away Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: he literally threw it in the garbage.
Speaker 0: We got a report from the loading dock people.
Speaker 0: They're like hey, it looks like someone threw away brand new equipment.
Speaker 0: you want to come take a look at it And I go and it's that printer.
Speaker 0: I'm like let me guess where this came from.
Speaker 1: Why don't you go tell his boss?
Speaker 1: If I was that would just be like you're fired.
Speaker 1: welcome to the 20.
Speaker 0: Why I did not tell his boss.
Speaker 0: This is this is completely non technology related rim anecdote.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well cuz you didn't care.
Speaker 0: so I've only ever quit one job In style.
Speaker 0: I believe it was that one.
Speaker 0: I believe firmly that everyone needs to quit at least one job at one point in their life in style.
Speaker 1: the big fuck you Just for one day then quit in style just to fulfill now.
Speaker 0: It's got to be justified.
Speaker 0: but so basically I was done with that fucking job and I but I In that court you know I had that printer right and I like took it and put it in this storage thing Temporarily, and then it was like the.
Speaker 0: it was like three days before I was gonna quit.
Speaker 0: so I take the printer and They'd like the office like oh you got to bring it back to the office so we can like do something with it.
Speaker 0: So I go to walk out of the hospital.
Speaker 0: the security guards like you can't leave with that without your requisition form.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna have a confiscator if you try to walk out this door.
Speaker 0: And I looked at him, and I was like all right.
Speaker 0: I handed it to him, and I just walked away.
Speaker 1: nice
Speaker 0: He was like ah and he really did not know what to do and was and I don't know what he did And then I quit and that was when I got swore at and then in the exit of you I told everyone what I thought of them and Don't regret doing that.
Speaker 0: no So I got one other little article I want to bring up because I can.
Speaker 0: we can answer this question very easily.
Speaker 0: Someone asked on slash shot is it possible to erase yourself from the internet?
Speaker 1: no no Depends how much you put on the internet.
Speaker 1: if you have never been on the internet ah You're already erased from it.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: I disagree okay.
Speaker 0: Here's the reason why.
Speaker 0: now yes, there might be a special case, but I Do not have a Facebook account mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Let's assume that I have no other internet presence.
Speaker 1: I have friend who's never had a computer in your life.
Speaker 0: I just don't use the internet at all mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: so one now How do I even know?
Speaker 0: to you Thinking that I'm a Luddite just make a Facebook account put my name on and start tagging me and stuff.
Speaker 0: now There's a whole trail about me on the internet.
Speaker 0: people are taking pictures of me It's all there And I have no control over that.
Speaker 0: anyway the metadata of the people around you will involve you.
Speaker 0: the question of Erasing yourself from the internet is patently ridiculous as is the question of keeping yourself off the internet.
Speaker 1: You could just be someone who's.
Speaker 1: there are people.
Speaker 1: there is six billion people seven billion people on earth.
Speaker 1: Most of them have information about them on the internet, so yes the edge cases Most of humanity is as no information about.
Speaker 0: okay, so if you want to get into that argument among the first world elite Everyone's on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yes, the first world problem.
Speaker 0: Can you erase yourself from the internet?
Speaker 0: Yes?
Speaker 0: You know how go to the third world physically and never come back, but you do.
Speaker 0: information from your time Would still be in the internet But you can argue that it could no longer reach you because if you abandon your first world lifestyle You're still.
Speaker 1: there is data about you on the internet.
Speaker 1: You're not erased from it.
Speaker 1: even if you are dead you can kill yourself.
Speaker 0: But so the best you're doing there is preventing further information from appearing.
Speaker 0: so This kind of article appears.
Speaker 0: I don't know every year and the answer has always been no.
Speaker 0: Now why do people keep asking do people not get that we're in a fundamentally new kind of society?
Speaker 0: no Except the people who are ready for the new kind of society Yeah, or the people who throw their internet away, so no one can put it in their office.
Speaker 1: You know you can see.
Speaker 1: it's all those people who turn their heads and the major walks down the street And she's just looking straight ahead.
Speaker 0: That is perhaps the best analogy to everything.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day that now I kind of want to make it the opener to ghost in the show.
Speaker 0: Anyway, tomorrow is the new ghost in the show.
Speaker 1: is it really tomorrow.
Speaker 0: I suppose Title tomorrow.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: all I know is that that event in Roppongi Hills is I believe tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Roppongi Hills yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway my thing of the day, so we and geek nights not on the show But in the forum.
Speaker 0: the debate about gun control and whatever's been going on for a while I'm not talking about.
Speaker 0: well.
Speaker 0: No I the prop.
Speaker 0: my problem with that debate is not the issue.
Speaker 0: my problem Is that every debate about it on the internet is the same.
Speaker 1: points being made in every debate about everything on the internet.
Speaker 1: is the?
Speaker 1: Same and people have it over and over again, and they can't shut up.
Speaker 1: The only need one.
Speaker 1: leave it there and just greet it again, and don't type anything new Any of the topics that you know or bring.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 0: there is one difference.
Speaker 0: the problem is everyone has this sort of generic Bullshit argument.
Speaker 0: if you're gonna debate something like gun control on the internet the only reasonable way to have that debate is to put forth your personal Specific full opinion on the issue and Then get enough people to do that and look for consensus.
Speaker 0: But I digress.
Speaker 0: one of the topics that always comes up is What about when we can just print guns?
Speaker 0: because that's why my we've talked about this a hundred times we have but it's always been A pretty big hypothetical.
Speaker 1: I mean it's day of the day.
Speaker 1: What are you doing?
Speaker 0: I could make a zip gun but if I make a zip gun with PVC pipe and put anything other than like a 22 round in there not that gonna work out to so well.
Speaker 0: So here is a video of the straight-up lower receiver firing what appears to be a 5-7 pistol round and It works just fine.
Speaker 0: so someone printed.
Speaker 1: well It doesn't work just fine and breaks.
Speaker 0: eventually it fires six shots and then breaks with a lot of shots for a commodity You know printed with like current maker bot technology without a lot of like extra work.
Speaker 0: That's pretty impressive because I'm thinking on the horizon of five years from now You can print an assault gun that lasts for one rampage worth of activity Because once you get one rampage out of it.
Speaker 0: You're pretty much good to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much So.
Speaker 0: the probably the reason I bring this up is thing today because one it's cool to see the lower receiver.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually discuss this often many times, but this is actually a video of it working a gun that someone printed.
Speaker 0: So if you're gonna have the debate use this video to piss off all the people who are trying to argue about gun control Because gun control is gonna be moot.
Speaker 0: as soon as we have maker bots that print metal Just like copyright law is moot gun control law will be moot.
Speaker 0: Except how come copyright law is not yet moot and a lot of people are getting really fucked over by it.
Speaker 0: Oh wait, because the same thing will happen with guns exactly.
Speaker 0: But I'm telling you in the next few years You're gonna get a printed assault rifle that has at least one rampage worth in it.
Speaker 1: Let's put have a betting pool.
Speaker 1: Everyone picks a date on the calendar to when the first Murder with a printed gun will occur.
Speaker 0: Here's a problem This.
Speaker 0: here's the problem with that betting pool Scott.
Speaker 0: I let's say I bet December 25th 2014 you do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if the toy sure go for it Go for it.
Speaker 0: So what do you got for me?
Speaker 1: So check this out.
Speaker 0: I'm checking.
Speaker 1: You know when you have some printed text right on and they can see a newspaper if your vision is good You can sort of sit comfortably if your vision is bad.
Speaker 1: You might have to get close to it You might have to squint you might have to use a eyeglass, you know, I'm at these various things.
Speaker 1: Control plus yeah, if you got a computer you might have to press some control plus control minus to make the text bigger smaller At least in a browser if it's not a browser.
Speaker 1: good luck, right?
Speaker 1: So what we have here is someone made a web page with this incredibly clever thing.
Speaker 1: It uses the HTML 5 webcam API to basically have the web page look at your face and it figures out based on facial recognition where your face is and how far away your face is from the Webcam assuming you have one of those webcams attached to the monitor Or built into the monitor like in a laptop and then as you get closer to the screen with your face It makes the text smaller and when you get farther away from the screen of their face.
Speaker 1: It makes the text bigger.
Speaker 1: have a girl.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and so you might think well wait I can't read the text so I get closer and it gets smaller.
Speaker 1: That doesn't help.
Speaker 1: I'll press ctrl plus a few times right to get it to be the right size and now it'll be really useful.
Speaker 1: I see this being the most useful and not sitting at the computer, right but these days.
Speaker 1: Well TVs maybe yes But also let's say you've got a tablet sitting on the counter and with a recipe Or something like that right and you take a few steps away to go to the fridge.
Speaker 1: you turn your head around to look at it and the text is Real big because it knows you walked far away from it.
Speaker 1: now It says motherfucking cucumber and when you get back to it, you can see the whole recipe.
Speaker 0: while this is cool and cute Augmented reality will happen before it's practical and useful.
Speaker 1: I think in the extreme short term.
Speaker 1: if someone deploys this into a tablet because they all have webcams built in if someone makes this Feature built into the tablet OS the same way that say swipe is built into some Android devices It would have to be obviously much smoother.
Speaker 1: Yes, it would have to be improved here.
Speaker 0: Here's the main problem with it.
Speaker 0: It keeps reflowing the text.
Speaker 1: That's only because the webcams janky.
Speaker 0: No, but I'm saying every time you change the font size you're reflowing text.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Reflowing text is impossible to read wall.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's the problem.
Speaker 0: It's the use cases around this.
Speaker 0: it would be to calibrate it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even then basically as soon as someone's moving whenever you're reflowing the text is unreadable till they stop moving.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure if Apple tried to put this in iPads and built it into iOS.
Speaker 1: It would work great.
Speaker 1: Now I'm just saying wouldn't take them more than maybe a month to get it right.
Speaker 0: getting from clever girl to in a production product Is what I kind of do now for a living and that I foresee.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, it's not like swipe is taking over the world either right now, but it could reach that same level.
Speaker 0: This is really awesome right now.
Speaker 1: It's something some guy made on a web page.
Speaker 1: It's just cool to mess with and I'm betting it actually won't ever be used in any way for reals.
Speaker 1: But I'm just saying it's possible.
Speaker 0: make a bet.
Speaker 0: So what I would do is that pushed it.
Speaker 1: who is a device manufacturer?
Speaker 0: Here's what I would do with this.
Speaker 0: So remember there is a prank a long time ago where you could Oh use it for a prank website.
Speaker 1: Were you getting close and it goes now?
Speaker 0: I was gonna say this.
Speaker 0: so remember when people would make an image and people still do this.
Speaker 1: Like if you go to 4chan, yeah, we have a few seconds and it goes.
Speaker 0: No, no much more clever.
Speaker 0: so you can have an image that from up close looks like one thing but from far away It looks like something completely different.
Speaker 0: So I click on the image.
Speaker 0: I'll see a picture of a kitten because I'm sitting next to my monitor, but then my boss across the room sees a penis Like.
Speaker 0: that's pretty easy to do so.
Speaker 0: Another thing you can do is you have a thumbnail that looks like one thing because the way the thumbnail is compressed.
Speaker 0: But when you click in the full image, it expands to the penis.
Speaker 0: So you could set this up to where it's always showing the penis to everyone except you.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: so it manipulates.
Speaker 1: it looks at one face.
Speaker 1: So if your face is close to this, okay So obviously wouldn't be perfect.
Speaker 0: but say there's someone across the room.
Speaker 0: if I get close to it It's gonna make it so that the big you know It'll make like the big image where I see what I'm looking at, but my boss sees the penis But if I get far away, it keeps you.
Speaker 0: maybe it just keeps showing me the cat so I'll never figure it out Because it's locked onto your face.
Speaker 1: I think a better idea is just the real problem Is that to give to give the browser your permission to use the webcam so it'll get to say yes You can make a prank where someone gets their face closer and closer to the screen and then it goes They get all oh shit and it makes a good YouTube video because it's simultaneously capturing.
Speaker 1: They're you know getting closer and surprise it is with the webcam while it's also evaluating their face distance dual purpose webcam.
Speaker 0: So in the meta moment, we're gonna be at PAX East doing two or three lectures.
Speaker 1: We don't even know.
Speaker 0: mastering game mechanics Practical game theory and a one that is TBA and or TBD.
Speaker 1: This is in March something something I'm not gonna bother to look it up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think April or May is anime Boston.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I assume we'll be there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Connecticut submit your panels.
Speaker 0: We are currently scheduling.
Speaker 0: I have personally scheduled like 11 panels.
Speaker 0: It's not public yet because we're gonna schedule in batches and then release them all.
Speaker 0: if you want to do a panel lecture workshop Juggling event, whatever submit them now because the longer you wait the less likely it is.
Speaker 0: I won't even look at your submission.
Speaker 1: the weekend after Kinetic on Paxos We gotta start working on all we gotta decide.
Speaker 0: we gotta decide for sure.
Speaker 0: if we're gonna go and start looking at plane We should get the time off where you get the hotel at least for that weekend in the Melbourne.
Speaker 1: Melbourne.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we should at least get the hotel for the convention and we can worry about the other stuff.
Speaker 0: and I'm debating.
Speaker 0: You know Otacon ever since they blacklisted us basically never accepts panels from us anymore.
Speaker 0: So I'm debating just giving up entirely and just never going again hurt to send an email Yeah, but it.
Speaker 0: but then again I'm at the point now where if so many other big cons going on that if Otacon was like accepts.
Speaker 0: It would be a shame if they blacklist us for years after doing like a decades worth of panels for them.
Speaker 0: They unblacklist us and we immediately turn them down depends on the weekend.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't even know what Otacon is.
Speaker 0: guys Tell us if you want us to be at Otacon and also tell Otacon if you want us to be at Otacon.
Speaker 1: I think people already did that.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they did or not.
Speaker 0: I think you were accused of a Conspiracy to incite a riot the last time we suggested that people suggest to Otacon that we come.
Speaker 0: I think I still.
Speaker 0: I think I saved that thread in the staff.
Speaker 0: Everyone should go to the feedback panel and say something and then even though someone else already said it Later I get an email from some Otacon staff guy who's like we've got a Situation that we got to talk about.
Speaker 0: your co-host is trying to incite a riot.
Speaker 0: This is kurtie thing.
Speaker 1: I was like what I was like.
Speaker 1: Look, they really got to mail the badges and know what they still fucking have to mail the badges.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everyone.
Speaker 1: if since they're not gonna mail them go up.
Speaker 1: This is what I said.
Speaker 1: I said everyone should go to the feedback panel go up to the microphone and say Mail the badges and then you sit down and then even though they already heard mail the badges which they hear every year anyway Someone else should go to the microphone and say mail the badges again and everyone who goes up should keep saying it
Speaker 0: Really
Speaker 1: drive it home and embarrass them mailing
Speaker 0: the badges.
Speaker 0: if your convention has more than like five thousand I mean Connecticut, I wish we would mail the badges.
Speaker 0: I want it to happen.
Speaker 0: I'm working for it as much as I can in my little fiefdom.
Speaker 0: Magfest really fucking needs to mail the badges.
Speaker 0: Oh good guys, though.
Speaker 1: Their line isn't too bad, but still mail the badge.
Speaker 0: Oh, the line is not bad now But Magfest is growing rapidly and also mailing the badges means that they're gonna have to give up on their stupid wristband Which is my primary motivation there That wristband.
Speaker 0: All right, so in our topic.
Speaker 1: Oh the book club book is well the Greg Gatsby.
Speaker 0: We read it.
Speaker 0: We're gonna do shows probably next week.
Speaker 1: We'll do the episode.
Speaker 0: Scott you pick another book yet Maybe yeah, you're not gonna say I'll tell you next Thursday.
Speaker 1: All right, when I've really picked and of course forum videos you're ten of all that stuff.
Speaker 0: It's out there.
Speaker 0: It's happening.
Speaker 0: So routers We did.
Speaker 1: I tried to think of something we didn't do an episode on and I saw we did a printer episode and I think We did a mouse keyboard episode.
Speaker 1: So it's like well, let's try to cover all the equipment We didn't cover.
Speaker 1: so I want to point out we did an episode on home networking where I think we covered a lot of this area But we didn't do a show specifically on routers.
Speaker 1: so whatever loophole.
Speaker 0: so here's the.
Speaker 0: here's my deal.
Speaker 0: I go to Rick Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: I have a router just for the show just in case you're talking about the power tool.
Speaker 0: So the descent.
Speaker 0: there is a disambiguation page and of the four things here I think one of them really doesn't deserve to be here.
Speaker 0: Let's see if you can pick out which one.
Speaker 0: Okay router woodworking a rotating cutting tool.
Speaker 0: Yep router computing a computer networking device Routing electronic design automation software.
Speaker 0: MC router born 1986 nerdcore rapper, but Never even heard of him.
Speaker 1: really MC router.
Speaker 1: He has a Wikipedia page.
Speaker 1: You should mark him as not notable.
Speaker 0: She has a Wikipedia page.
Speaker 1: Okay, nice But yeah mark is not notable unless they're notable and I've just never heard of them because I'm not that into it.
Speaker 0: Ah She is looking at these press things about as notable as we are But I don't think she deserves to be on the router disambiguation page.
Speaker 0: Like if the I don't know podcast disambiguation page was like geek nights.
Speaker 1: Well, if you were on the geek disambiguation page like geek or the night disambiguation Night the time of day opposite daylight geek nights.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, we're talking about computer routers in Computing.
Speaker 1: okay.
Speaker 1: So what for those of you who are really out of the loop?
Speaker 1: what the hell does at least a home router do?
Speaker 1: and basically what it does?
Speaker 1: is you get a cable modem or a DSL or a FiOS or something and it's only got one ethernet cable coming out of that motherfucker and you got five motherfucking computers.
Speaker 1: How do you plug a whole bunch of computers to get internet for that one guy?
Speaker 1: You plug a router into that guy then you plug all the computers into the router.
Speaker 0: Well, well, let's back up a little bit because in the home world, you know, there was a time where?
Speaker 0: Switches were not generally available to the consumer.
Speaker 0: No, nor were routers.
Speaker 0: No, you had to buy a hub so I would have a cable modem and Directly plugged into that would be my computer.
Speaker 1: Well in the dial-up days you couldn't do shit, right?
Speaker 1: The computer had basically had a dial-up modem in it And if you wanted to share the internet you had to share it had an external modem, right?
Speaker 1: You had to basically share the internet from that computer that had the modem on it to the other computer.
Speaker 0: You want to share your 300 bod exactly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you kids even know what bod means without looking it up and why we don't use that term anymore.
Speaker 0: bod.
Speaker 0: I had a 300 bod modem I Yeah, then I upgraded to a 2400 bod which could almost play mad maze but not quite anyway, so Really?
Speaker 0: Let's talk about terminology here.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna back out from the home routers a bit.
Speaker 0: Whenever someone you go to a network class like you think oh there's switches and there's routers and there's hubs, but really those terms just refer to sort of multi-port versions of other more fundamental things.
Speaker 0: So if you think about networking the way you think about say electronics, you know, there's an integrated circuit, but then there's a logic gate.
Speaker 0: so our hub is Really just a hub.
Speaker 0: it's the same thing as a repeater, but it repeats out multiple ways.
Speaker 0: We don't need to talk about the details.
Speaker 0: beyond that hubs don't exist in the modern world anymore.
Speaker 1: No one uses hubs anymore.
Speaker 1: The only place I still see hubs is at land parties that don't have a big budget usually have like these.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have like these hundred port hubs that they stack up at the end of the table.
Speaker 0: They're all like 10 megabit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they have 10 or 100 megabit.
Speaker 0: It's got 100 bucks.
Speaker 0: You can buy a 54 port 48 gigabit backplane like switch from a gray market, right?
Speaker 1: But a lot of these land parties bought this equipment in the olden days and it still works so that they have no reason to Replace it and it actually if you can play land games on a hub like that
Speaker 0: No, you really can't with too many computers on them.
Speaker 0: It depends not anymore.
Speaker 1: They used it.
Speaker 1: packs had no problems.
Speaker 0: Are you sure?
Speaker 0: are you sure those were hubs?
Speaker 1: next time we're at pecs look at the end of the road.
Speaker 0: Okay, I'm just asking if you were sure they were hubs.
Speaker 1: look like hubs to me.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, how?
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: What does a hub look like compared to a switch?
Speaker 1: You can tell by the blinky lights the way the way they blink is there.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That is not true.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so a repeater, you know in the old days you're sending data Over a wire and say your cables really long.
Speaker 0: you put a repeater in the middle.
Speaker 1: There's a limit on that length.
Speaker 1: You can't make a cable infinitely long here.
Speaker 0: receives all the data coming in.
Speaker 0: now, it's analog electricity But we interpret it as digital.
Speaker 0: So there's no loss and we just make new packets a new digital signal coming out the other end Electricity and then it rewrites the same electricity.
Speaker 1: So it goes in and not.
Speaker 1: well our Lost some power over the wire.
Speaker 0: It's a little more subtle than that which is why I want to make the distinction that an amplifier takes the electricity and Kind of regenerates like Chris like adds to it to make it the right electricity again.
Speaker 0: Not a whole hub aka a repeater actually reads the signal and does something to interpret it as digital data inside of itself and Basically makes an entirely new signal from scratch.
Speaker 0: Yep, if it didn't do that.
Speaker 0: It's not technically a repeater.
Speaker 0: It's an amplifier.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well an amplifier might you know amplify too much or not enough because you don't know the exact strength of what's coming.
Speaker 0: You need a variable amplifier.
Speaker 0: the problem with an amplifier is that or it also amplifies the noise.
Speaker 0: So it doesn't really buy you much with digital communication exactly in this context.
Speaker 0: so hub is just a repeater where anything that comes in one part goes off all the other parts.
Speaker 0: a switch is Basically a multi-port bridge and all a bridge says is I'm gonna do what a hub does But if I know that the dude a packet was for is not on the other side of this I'm not gonna repeat it.
Speaker 0: So all bridges do is limit the amount of traffic on any given network segment.
Speaker 1: I thought that the switch is also smart enough to know.
Speaker 1: Aha.
Speaker 1: I know this is for dude number three on hole three.
Speaker 1: I'm only gonna send it on hole three.
Speaker 0: I said a bridge does that.
Speaker 0: a switch is just basically a large multi-port set of bridges That are configurable centrally.
Speaker 0: Hmm It says this is a packet that I could repeat everywhere.
Speaker 0: But I'm only gonna repeat it to the places that I know someone actually cares about the data.
Speaker 0: Hmm, so it just.
Speaker 0: it means you have more bandwidth overall than collisions.
Speaker 0: forget all that stuff.
Speaker 0: a router Basically is the next step where the it has logic.
Speaker 0: beyond that This is where we're not just talking about one networking.
Speaker 1: a router at its core connects multiple networks to each other Mm-hmm actual networks, for example your home network to the ISPs network or Google's network to sprints network to Microsoft's network.
Speaker 1: All right, I'll have routers in between right?
Speaker 1: That's why the routers are always at the edge of the network, right?
Speaker 1: Even if it's an internal or external network or a sub network The routers are always at the edges.
Speaker 1: You never see a router in the middle of a network.
Speaker 1: That doesn't really help you that much.
Speaker 0: So what is a network?
Speaker 0: Well, we did a whole show on this I think a long time ago, but to super summarize it one set of IP addresses and a subnet mask Which you know cider like.
Speaker 0: if you think of class a class B class C and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: That's really kind of obsolete.
Speaker 0: But anyway, or the you know, the 255 255 255 0 What the face I made was pretty great.
Speaker 0: one Network is like a set of IP addresses that are all together.
Speaker 0: So in the old days assume there's no network, so I got just a giant hub all my computers connected together.
Speaker 0: So I don't even need IP.
Speaker 0: Nope, all my communication can happen down at layer 2 at the data link level all on one big network.
Speaker 0: I assume anything I put in that network anyone can see if they give a shit about.
Speaker 1: yeah You double-click on network and windows and you see fucking every computer that's plugged into the hub.
Speaker 0: So if you have two separate networks You can basically pretend that anything that's on a different network is a completely alien world and Nothing on your home network has any direct way to talk to anyone over there.
Speaker 0: So what a router does is Your your OSI stack, you know your TCP IP stack and I'm skipping all the stuff that isn't relevant to TCP IP Because that doesn't matter to any of you who are listening to this.
Speaker 1: We're using normal everyday computers Which 90% of what they do is TCP IP.
Speaker 0: So if I want to send a message from the rim network to the Scott network, my network has its own rules of engagement.
Speaker 0: Let's say I you know My addresses are 10 dot.
Speaker 0: so 10 dot 0 dot 0 dot 1 is my computer and 10 dot 50 dot 1 dot 109 to 1 is my NAS, you know, whatever I set up I can do any arbitrary bullshit.
Speaker 0: It does not matter at all what Scott's network looks like because he can do whatever he wants on his own.
Speaker 0: He might use the exact same addresses as me Yep, so the router is just a complicated set of logic that can deal with two different networks simultaneously and figure out how to get data between the two.
Speaker 0: That is at its core what a router does.
Speaker 0: it interfaces networks together thus allowing us to have an internet.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Oh my god, it's a collection of multiple internet works networks.
Speaker 0: It's yo-dog.
Speaker 1: It's the internet.
Speaker 0: So The way a router does this and then we'll get back to the more interesting stuff that you guys probably care about but it's relevant Because almost no one I talk to especially developers really understands this.
Speaker 1: No, they know how to plug it in.
Speaker 1: They plug the ISP into the big separated hole and they plug all the computers in the other hole.
Speaker 0: So let's assume we have a router and on my network.
Speaker 0: So this router has three interfaces.
Speaker 0: It has an interface to some ISP somewhere like internet for internet access.
Speaker 0: It has a second port in the rim network and I give it an arbitrary address.
Speaker 0: in my network It is the third port in the Scott Network and Scott gave her whatever IP address he wanted as well.
Speaker 0: If I send a packet somewhere, you know, I put an IP address in that packet But I also put some other information in that packet.
Speaker 0: So if I'm sending something to a PC on my network I say the IP address of that PC and at the low level some arping happens.
Speaker 0: So basically my my computer sends a packet out to my whole network that says yo dog I'm looking for the motherfucker that has IP 10.1.1.1. and whoever has it Gets that data link packet and says yo dog.
Speaker 0: That's me.
Speaker 0: Here's my MAC address.
Speaker 0: Now you can send shit to me for reals and then everything else I send is directed just at that guy.
Speaker 0: No other people might see it.
Speaker 0: the network cards and the switches job is to filter out the stuff that people don't need to see.
Speaker 0: but I say hey, I have this address on my network.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to get to someone else who has an IP address.
Speaker 0: every computer has two addresses, you know MAC address IP address.
Speaker 0: So Whoever has this IP tell me how to get to you on the network.
Speaker 0: Those MAC addresses don't need to be unique between networks.
Speaker 0: Let's assume that my network and Scott Network We have identical MAC addresses.
Speaker 0: MAC addresses never leave the network.
Speaker 0: So if I want to connect to Scott's network, I say with an IP address, yo I'm looking for this IP address Now, let's say well, no one no one on your network has that IP address.
Speaker 0: Yeah so no one would respond and there's no way on earth I can find the MAC address of anyone on Scott's network.
Speaker 1: and Even if you could it wouldn't do anything exactly because my router which the fuck is this?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they might overlap You don't know it's a different network.
Speaker 0: I can't just send my networks garbage on the Scott's network.
Speaker 0: That's the whole reason.
Speaker 0: we have routers and the internet, you know, someone's MAC.
Speaker 0: What's all MAC address of anything at Google?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So my computer says yo dawg.
Speaker 0: I'm looking for IP address 192 168 69 69.
Speaker 0: Well, nobody answers.
Speaker 0: Nobody has that except Someone does answer.
Speaker 0: the router says yo dawg.
Speaker 0: I can get you there.
Speaker 0: So send that shit over to me.
Speaker 1: I thought that sometimes what happens is the router doesn't answer but your computer has configured a default gateway.
Speaker 1: Okay, so when no one answers he then says, alright, I'll just ask mr.
Speaker 1: Default gateway.
Speaker 0: So let's get a little more complicated.
Speaker 0: You have a default gateway, which is actually just a route that you've configured on your.
Speaker 1: you basically tell your computer Hey computer, the router is at this address.
Speaker 1: That's where router be.
Speaker 0: so you can basically you can set up complicated routes on your computer.
Speaker 0: So say I have multiple networks, which is this is the coolest ever.
Speaker 0: get to the end.
Speaker 0: I can say yo computer for any 10-dot address Use this physical interface or this gateway or whatever for these other IPs.
Speaker 0: use this other gateway.
Speaker 0: So I could have my internal network and my computer could be connected to three different networks simultaneously.
Speaker 1: I can do all sorts of crazy crap.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe you got for example, you're out of college and they got internet one and internet two.
Speaker 1: So that router says hey any IPs that you know for internet one go this way any I internet to go that way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Basically, yes your computer to skip the details because without drawing a diagram of it You're just gonna ignore me talking until I finish talking about this bit.
Speaker 0: Your computer will basically have the default gateway which says yo Anything that's not on your network is over at this guy.
Speaker 0: And what the router does is you actually at the data link layer send your packets directly to the router With its MAC address and the router takes care all the earth.
Speaker 0: That packet says all right now it acts like a computer.
Speaker 0: So it says it is a computer.
Speaker 0: I have a computer on Scott's Network and it said now it follows Scott's rules and says yo guys I'm looking for this IP address.
Speaker 0: My MAC address is X. So any messages Scott sends back to me He sends them to the MAC address of the router.
Speaker 0: The router does all the translation and all the bullshit.
Speaker 1: So that is probably his router.
Speaker 1: pie talks to another router which talks to another one.
Speaker 1: Another one which talks to mine which talks to the computer on my network which then talks all the way back around.
Speaker 1: But really everything only talks to the network that they're on and the only machines that ever talked to more than one network at a time are routers.
Speaker 0: Basically, yes now a computer can serve the function of a router.
Speaker 1: router is just a computer.
Speaker 1: Yes install IP route on your computer and now your computer is doing routing.
Speaker 0: Congratulations, so What other than Connect me to the internet and net and pat, you know Network address translation port address translation all the stuff that your router is doing that You actually don't need to do at the router?
Speaker 0: There's other ways to do it.
Speaker 0: skip all that other than the basic stuff.
Speaker 0: as in you've got a router.
Speaker 0: It connects you to the internet.
Speaker 0: There's actually a lot of cool stuff you can do with your router.
Speaker 0: You should log into its admin interface and take a look.
Speaker 1: Well, first of all, depending on how much money you spent on your router There's more stuff you can do.
Speaker 1: and also maybe you've installed a special firmware such as DDW RT or tomato Onto a crappy router to give it much more functionality that it could have had.
Speaker 1: because remember router again Just a computer with a bunch of network cards in it.
Speaker 1: So there's no reason it can't do a lot of things Except they may be too CPU intensive and the router will shit itself.
Speaker 1: try to do them.
Speaker 0: Yep, not a lot of power in there now.
Speaker 1: So one thing a lot of routers have wireless access points built in.
Speaker 1: That's pretty obvious.
Speaker 0: Yeah now Notice if you set that up, usually what it's actually doing is your wireless has a separate set of IPS.
Speaker 0: It's actually a separate network.
Speaker 0: Some routers do that automatically.
Speaker 0: Yep, or you know something like that.
Speaker 0: Now you can do clever stuff there.
Speaker 0: You can set up your router such that all right.
Speaker 0: Anyone can connect to my wireless.
Speaker 0: But I'm not gonna let that network access my internal network.
Speaker 0: I only route them directly to the internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can have the router right.
Speaker 1: remember the router connects networks together.
Speaker 1: You can tell the router to make multiple networks Like my house has like three networks as a wireless one a wired one and then it has a guest Wireless.
Speaker 1: or if anyone connects in the guest wireless like they can't see my nose because it's not on the same network as them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't want people to get on my nose.
Speaker 1: They might delete my files.
Speaker 0: I did a different.
Speaker 0: I put my security different level.
Speaker 0: My NAS is accessible on my entire internal network.
Speaker 1: But you put security in the NAS itself.
Speaker 0: Yes, the NAS itself is set up to where anyone can get media files off of it But they can't write to it and I actually have a Dropbox or anyone can dump anything but can't read back off of it.
Speaker 1: I got all sorts of cool stuff set up there that it was easier for me to just say NAS be Completely accessible drive that way to configure anything.
Speaker 0: The reason I set up the way I did is that a lot of times people come over and say oh Hey, you've got anime X. Can I borrow and I say yeah, just pull it off the NAS and they fail to do so.
Speaker 0: No, they succeed.
Speaker 0: the people who fail to do so are not the ones.
Speaker 1: I offer that to look how many people still be like trading hard external drives and USB sticks.
Speaker 0: and there are reasons for that sometimes Technological.
Speaker 0: if I'm getting like I'm downloading I'm all right.
Speaker 0: I am allegedly downloading a target right now.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: It is all of Seinfeld in the HD remaster.
Speaker 0: It's 130 HD remaster of Seinfeld.
Speaker 0: It's like a booray release yourself.
Speaker 1: Does it have an Removed laugh track.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: All I know is it's a hundred and thirty two gigabytes.
Speaker 0: Okay, so It might take a little while to transfer that over my wireless to someone's laptop.
Speaker 1: Do they even have a hundred and thirty two gigs exactly?
Speaker 0: It might be easy.
Speaker 1: They're gonna have hundred thirty two gigs stick.
Speaker 0: It might just be easier to hand them a small external hard drive with like two terabytes on.
Speaker 0: just they bring it back.
Speaker 0: Oh, and it also has all the robot openers and everything else I've ever collected on it.
Speaker 0: cuz whatever It's my throwaway external hard drive.
Speaker 0: great Other cool things you can do.
Speaker 0: set up segregated networks for different things.
Speaker 0: For example One thing you can do on a router is there's always this option called the DMZ the demilitarized zone.
Speaker 0: Sounds cool.
Speaker 1: Most people ignore it sounds really cool But only really weird.
Speaker 1: people use it.
Speaker 0: what it basically means.
Speaker 0: you can have one computer that is on the outside of your router So that people if they connect to your external IP address, whatever it might be That computer is basically what they hit.
Speaker 1: Yeah Right now somebody tries to connect to whatever IP address my ISP gave me.
Speaker 1: They're gonna hit the router itself and maybe the router will do something and maybe it won't.
Speaker 0: Usually your router is set to not let anything through unless it's part of an existing connection Exactly.
Speaker 0: So because you don't want some jackass just SSHing into your box.
Speaker 1: If I put a computer and I plug it into the router that's gonna be on the inside.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be on my network.
Speaker 1: But if I click on the router, I say hey make that computer DMZ.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be as if that Computer is actually between the router and the internet or sort of next to the router on the other side.
Speaker 1: So I could put you know a web server on there and if someone visits my IP address Of my house in their browser, they'll see a web page.
Speaker 1: It comes from that computer.
Speaker 1: I could put a counter-strike server on there and then I won't need to fuck around with the port forwarding nonsense It'll just freakin work.
Speaker 0: Yeah Another cool thing you can do that I haven't.
Speaker 0: I'm actually working on setting this up now a lot of modern routers.
Speaker 0: You can set them up to receive VPN connections.
Speaker 0: So then if you have a laptop with some VPN software or you set up your phone your smartphone with certain VPN software And you use something like dyne DNS So you have an external DNS name that maps to whatever bullshit IP your ISP gives you that might change.
Speaker 0: You can just be like boop and have a direct VPN that's secure and encrypted to your own personal internal network.
Speaker 0: to like our desktop on your PC or pull something off your NAS.
Speaker 0: Yep, how totally useful is that?
Speaker 1: super useful?
Speaker 1: The kind of person to keep stuff in your house Right now what a lot of people do because that's such a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: They use like go to media not go to meeting.
Speaker 0: they use like use all sorts of cloud go to or they use like go To my PC or those janky.
Speaker 1: Well, not just that but like they use Dropbox and all these other sorts of cloud services Right where it's like.
Speaker 1: hey I can't send the files directly to the computer in my house or get them from the computer in my house while I'm at Starbucks.
Speaker 1: So what I'll do is I'll pay someone else who has computers out in the cloud on the internet Right that aren't behind routers.
Speaker 1: Yeah all locked up I'll upload files there go home and download the files.
Speaker 0: You have a computer that's already on the internet.
Speaker 1: Why can't you send them directly from your laptop to your house and back and forth because you have this router in the way That's not doing fancy things for you because you didn't configure it because it's not that easy.
Speaker 0: Now the use case is this for example, I use Google Drive for that like my laptops and everything.
Speaker 0: Yep, all just you know, I have access to all my Google Drive stuff everywhere.
Speaker 0: But you know what that's only five or ten gigs.
Speaker 0: I'm not.
Speaker 0: it's not everything.
Speaker 0: That's the stuff that I know I want to back up and share.
Speaker 0: But what if say I'm on vacation and oh shit the Dave and Joel fast karate for the gentleman episode didn't upload, right?
Speaker 0: Well, I didn't put that on my Google Drive.
Speaker 0: Nope Well, if I don't have a VPN back to my house, there's literally no way to do anything about that.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm that actually happened many years ago.
Speaker 0: So we had to wait an extra week until we got home from our week at the shore.
Speaker 0: our writers retreat after Otacon to Put up the fantastic episode of geek nights that Dave and Joel did for us.
Speaker 0: Had I set up a VPN on the home router I could just logged in Sent a wake on ethernet to wake up my PC and just done it.
Speaker 0: Yep What other cool things could we do that you guys would actually do?
Speaker 0: because there's crazy stuff you can do that You probably shouldn't do.
Speaker 1: it shouldn't do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like don't unless you know what you're doing.
Speaker 0: Don't fuck with your DHCP setting.
Speaker 0: You're just gonna break everything You know.
Speaker 0: one DHCP thing you should do actually is if you're having your router do your DHCP which most people do You probably shouldn't just because routers kind of suck at that and have problems sometimes.
Speaker 0: But at the same time you can only get off of the router if you have another PC in your house.
Speaker 0: That isn't your actual PC.
Speaker 0: that is guaranteed to always always always always always beyond.
Speaker 0: Yep But then you can set up your DHCP to pass Google DNS to all your internal PCs instead of your ISP.
Speaker 0: is garbage DNA, right?
Speaker 1: or what you have to do Otherwise is go to each and every PC in your house and change the DNS settings to use the Google public.
Speaker 0: The whole point of computers is to make that stuff easy.
Speaker 0: Did?
Speaker 0: the whole point of DHCP is you don't have to configure anything Your computer or you can set up a computer that's always on that is a DNS server and have that.
Speaker 1: use the Google DNS And all the computers in your house use that but then you have to tell your DHCP Server to tell all your computers to use.
Speaker 0: that is the deal.
Speaker 1: You already have a computer.
Speaker 1: That's the computer That's always on doing the DNS To turn off its DHCP.
Speaker 0: because let me tell you son you got two DHCPs on your network.
Speaker 0: It's a bad day.
Speaker 0: bad day especially because the kinds of people who will let two DHCP servers be on their network are not the kinds of people who know how To recognize that.
Speaker 0: that's the problem.
Speaker 1: And if you have a DHCP server either in your router or separate from your router You can go to it and say hey look see the mat see this computer That's connected to you right now make that IP address on that computer 192 168 110 and make it always 110. so your desktop will always have the same internal IP all the time Which makes it really easy.
Speaker 1: if like you connect between your computers a lot It's like you won't be like.
Speaker 1: where'd my NAS go?
Speaker 1: it moved from 15 to 17. well shit if you can make it So it's always 15 all the time no matter what.
Speaker 0: yep now I actually didn't bother with that.
Speaker 0: But that's partly because since I'm on a one network my NAS and everything just show up because everything's kind of broadcast.
Speaker 1: Well, they're using like the windows stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what's the?
Speaker 1: what's the frickin Apple Apple?
Speaker 1: Bonjour uses that.
Speaker 1: yeah, whatever Apple yeah Another really cool.
Speaker 0: I don't need to run a win server anymore.
Speaker 1: something That's incredibly useful if you have a lot of people use on your network.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: especially Untrustworthy of evil is to use QoS which is called stands for quality of service.
Speaker 1: But really what it means is you fucking choke a bitch.
Speaker 0: I log into my router and I can see you know like Scott's a laptop because he's on the network.
Speaker 0: I can log in right now, and it gets his host name.
Speaker 0: it gives him IP and I can see oh, that's Scott's laptop That's the IP and I know his MAC address.
Speaker 0: I could set it up to where.
Speaker 0: hey anytime that fucking MAC address connects Only give him five megabit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can make sure don't let him torrents.
Speaker 1: well Yeah you can regulate people's bandwidth and set rules based on which computer and Also based on time of day and all sorts of other factors.
Speaker 0: have your router Automatically throttle down your torrents when you're home and let him go nuts when you're at work?
Speaker 1: Yep, so you can just leave your torrents running all the time and the router automatically forced the torrents to all be like one megabit.
Speaker 1: You know whatever when during hours when you would be at home and let it be.
Speaker 1: use up all the bandwidth when you're not at Home.
Speaker 1: or maybe you've got a neighbor that's stealing your Wi-Fi, but you want to let them steal your Wi-Fi for some reason.
Speaker 1: Maybe they're paying you to share something because they're lazy.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe you're just.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't recommend it.
Speaker 1: I say get your own ISP and don't let anyone else use it.
Speaker 0: now There's a very good reason why you let all your neighbors use it.
Speaker 1: Plausible deniability.
Speaker 1: you better of using your neighbors or pause not had to be ability.
Speaker 0: They don't know a combination of the two.
Speaker 0: you do your legal shit on theirs And if they do anything on yours, or if you accidentally do anything on yours I don't know much, but anyway You can say limit neighbors to 500 K So they can't really do anything nasty.
Speaker 0: or if you want to do crazy stuff.
Speaker 0: so say you get a VPN like I predator.
Speaker 0: Right yeah, so you can put that in your router and set up a routing table.
Speaker 0: You could do something like this something so cool and clever, and it'll all be automatic.
Speaker 0: every time you start up a torrent It just automatically goes through I predator.
Speaker 0: hmm, but nothing else goes through I predator.
Speaker 0: Yep Or you can set it up to where every time I'm connecting to my illegal offshore bank account to finance the barge.
Speaker 0: It knows all those routes go through I predator.
Speaker 0: So you can still do your normal stuff on your computer and you can set up routes for all these different connections.
Speaker 1: Usually when you pay for one of those VPN services like I predator you can only have one computer attached to it at a time.
Speaker 1: So if I were to attach to it would say my desktop well my laptop and my phone Which is still in my house would not be able to send their traffic over it to Sweden before they send it to the internet.
Speaker 1: But if I have my router connect to I predator well not.
Speaker 1: all the internet traffic in my house Could be encrypted and sent to Sweden and anonymized before it's sent to the internet.
Speaker 0: Or I could set it to where the only traffic that gets sent over I predator is my burner laptop That doesn't have a hard disk in it.
Speaker 0: You know that Burner laptop guys if you're gonna commit crimes.
Speaker 0: This is the crime aside.
Speaker 0: We should make that a bit in geek night.
Speaker 1: crime aside Get it get it commit crimes and get away with it by geek night.
Speaker 0: get a cheapo laptop with an optical drive Though a USB.
Speaker 0: you could do with USB.
Speaker 1: now don't put any hard drives in it.
Speaker 0: No hard drives optical drive only optical drive and as much RAM as you can.
Speaker 0: fit in that motherfucker.
Speaker 0: Boot a Linux live CD and hibernate it, but never turn it off.
Speaker 1: Yeah and remove the Linux live CD.
Speaker 1: then Install you know download and install whatever illegal things you have to install from the internet.
Speaker 1: configure them while the laptop is on.
Speaker 1: Attach the laptop to some wireless network in a Starbucks or something.
Speaker 1: hide it somewhere Plugged into power or keep it in your house.
Speaker 0: set up to route through I predator and do all your evil shit there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, have it.
Speaker 1: Well I predators maybe not that secure Inequivalent of I pray.
Speaker 1: yeah, but the point is you know just have this laptop doing all this evil shit.
Speaker 1: And if the police ever find it or the FBI ever come for it and they confiscate it cuz that's what they do They're gonna unplug it or whatever or maybe they'll try to turn it on and look at it, and it's like okay They can't really log into it, so what is their usual game plan?
Speaker 1: They take the hard drive out and they examine it and if it's an encrypted hard drive well You know they can try But if there is no hard drive, then what the fuck did they do?
Speaker 1: they just turned it off.
Speaker 1: all the evidence.
Speaker 0: now There are basic ways to deal with that.
Speaker 1: But you can run that is you can put the RAM in the freezer really quick.
Speaker 0: in the time Between when they beat down my door, and they get to my room I can probably pull the plug on the laptop yep, and then you want to be extra paranoid.
Speaker 0: There's no battery in there either.
Speaker 1: if it's the kind of laptop that'll run with that Just unplug it and there's no battery in it and boom everything's toast.
Speaker 0: and that was the gig night's.
Speaker 0: crime aside That's right.
Speaker 1: They can't scan a hard drive if there isn't one.
Speaker 1: Oh, no you found the CD.
Speaker 0: That is a Linux live CD, so what's the moral of all this you know?
Speaker 0: What routers do now which is basically anything a computer can do?
Speaker 0: Log into the admin interface of whatever your router is and look at what options you have and think to yourself.
Speaker 0: Normally we say come up with something you want to do and then look up how to do it But in this case my homework for all that you didn't know you could do.
Speaker 1: that you probably do want to do.
Speaker 1: you just don't.
Speaker 0: So if you want to learn about networking computers everything just log into your router look at all the options and think all right What can I do with that option?
Speaker 1: also if you have a cheap router?
Speaker 1: You're probably not gonna have the options right.
Speaker 1: I have the net gear WNDR 3700 which is a really expensive and fancy router that does all sorts of fancy shit.
Speaker 0: I have the shitty files router.
Speaker 0: this is actually pretty good But I got to buy another router to put between it and my network.
Speaker 1: you do do yeah You should do that.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Speaker 1: ok for the logos be sure to visit our website At front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.