Speaker 0:
Speaker 1: Hey, it's Tuesday January 22nd 2013.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm sky and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We're back.
Speaker 1: We're bad.
Speaker 1: We're talking about Android netrunner.
Speaker 1: Let's do this Woman it's.
Speaker 1: uh you know usually I'm the first one to make fun of people who actually say that it's cold outside because It's cold I mean if it's once it's close to zero degrees a real zero degrees the f-zero That's when I get a little bit.
Speaker 1: It's a bit woman out.
Speaker 0: According to NOAA it is yeah Negative seven Celsius, it's 20 Celsius 20 degrees Fahrenheit whatever it's cold.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we're back.
Speaker 1: if you none of you've been paying attention We were out of town for our New Year's party, which was in town.
Speaker 1: We just didn't fucking do shows.
Speaker 1: and then magfest mm-hmm, and then I went pretty much straight on to Istanbul mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And then I spent this last weekend skiing mm-hmm, and we're finally back.
Speaker 1: I think you were sick for almost a day.
Speaker 0: I was sick sort of yesterday and today ish.
Speaker 0: I was like half sick, and I'm now.
Speaker 0: I'm feeling actually pretty good Yeah, just feeling that.
Speaker 1: but I realized we were talking about this just before we started doing the show.
Speaker 1: Lot happened in the last few weeks, so we got a lot we could start with and we're gonna forget pretty much everything That we could talk about.
Speaker 0: yeah it's like we.
Speaker 0: so many things happened between this episode and the previous episode that we could talk about and maybe one of those things will be in this opening bit, but Next episode the only things that we could think of for opening bits will thing or things that happened between this episode ending and The next episode.
Speaker 0: Which is really annoying because if we could figure out how to send our memories back in time before this episode And you think oh we got we could bring up like enough opening bits for half the year you'd think oh Just take notes or something.
Speaker 1: you know what?
Speaker 1: I have some notes that are written on the board next to the studio.
Speaker 1: Do you know what I have written to X RFE?
Speaker 1: and then two words?
Speaker 1: I can't read.
Speaker 1: I think one of them is oranges or dragons.
Speaker 1: I can't tell.
Speaker 0: And Luigi says go straight, it's gonna have.
Speaker 1: I'm not even sure who wrote that.
Speaker 1: I think it was nerd.
Speaker 0: I think Luigi saw a ghost.
Speaker 1: yeah Work emails like.
Speaker 1: I don't know if that was a show idea, and then I wrote M show utana gig nights behind the scenes.
Speaker 1: What Oh pro wrestling?
Speaker 1: I guess we said we do that a long time ago, and Guys, and they're under we're grabbing each other.
Speaker 1: We were gonna do a show on a hundred percenting a.
Speaker 0: We've done that show I don't know.
Speaker 0: it's not a bad.
Speaker 1: You see why taking notes does not affect to actually help us.
Speaker 1: It's not a bad show.
Speaker 1: and despite all I mean I was in Istanbul for three days We had crazy crap happen.
Speaker 1: all I can think about right now is that I listened to Dave and Joel on the way to work Today and they watch not see you crisis, and they both simultaneously thought that the song sounded like Van Halen's jump.
Speaker 1: And I listen to the song and it kind of does.
Speaker 0: That's a listen to that song.
Speaker 1: that's what's running through my head right now Makes me want to watch like bad 90s style anime all over again.
Speaker 1: So yeah, what'd you do while I was in Istanbul?
Speaker 0: That's a good question.
Speaker 0: I went to work.
Speaker 0: Yeah Played a lot of netrunner.
Speaker 0: There's a runner meetup in fact Laid around.
Speaker 1: well, I mean it's funny.
Speaker 1: our friends Phil and she I mean we brought netrunner to magfest and then they well It's a two-player game, so they started playing.
Speaker 0: Save it.
Speaker 1: We'll save it, but yeah suffice it to say they took Scott's copy with them on trips around the world.
Speaker 0: I watched a whole lot of Korean television shows.
Speaker 1: I'm actually you know talking about stuff.
Speaker 1: We've been watching lately.
Speaker 1: I mean archer started up.
Speaker 1: Which is good because Emily and I basically are trick hard in the netrunner box.
Speaker 1: Maybe you should look at it, so Emily and I burned through all of adventure time and this is a problem that spans all geekeries.
Speaker 1: when you have something that's episodic Like maybe you're going through all the Megaman's or something or you're watching like all of a TV show that you never watched before You kind of get addicted to the fact that there's another one right there ready as soon as you're done like if you start playing Half-life 2. now it's like man.
Speaker 1: I got all this half-life 2 and then I burned through episode 1 and episode 2. and then what do you mean?
Speaker 1: There's no episode 3. what?
Speaker 1: when's it coming out?
Speaker 0: never?
Speaker 1: So I watched the like four seasons of adventure time and it went from being a show I'd heard of to a show I liked to Second only to ponies in terms of current shows.
Speaker 1: okay, really like that show.
Speaker 1: It is a great show, but They're 15-minute episodes.
Speaker 1: I watched so many I can hardly remember them and I hit the most recent one and now every day.
Speaker 1: I look on pirate bay to see if there's another one.
Speaker 0: Why don't you just look at Wikipedia to see what the TV schedule is?
Speaker 1: I could I just don't because if it's on pirate bay I just click download Ponies.
Speaker 0: I check them.
Speaker 1: well the thing is I've been why I've all right.
Speaker 1: I never had a point where I could watch a whole bunch of pony in a row.
Speaker 1: So I'm already in tune with the cycle of ponies.
Speaker 1: I very recently hit the adventure time wall.
Speaker 1: You should watch that show.
Speaker 1: I'd like to do a show on it.
Speaker 1: We could.
Speaker 0: you know me shows are hard to watch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know, but it's it's got.
Speaker 1: I'm telling you I put it second to ponies.
Speaker 0: see unlike you right I have chosen to watch running man, which has an episode Every single week no matter what of the year there is never there is.
Speaker 0: since the show has started there has not been a Missed week.
Speaker 1: It is a black and media.
Speaker 0: the show is really long.
Speaker 0: It's like at least an hour long each episode.
Speaker 1: if I watch cowboy bebop again, right?
Speaker 1: Eventually it ends like if they were just more episodes forever.
Speaker 1: I would just be beyond that event horizon forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if there is more if there was half-life 3 I just been forever.
Speaker 1: I just be in that event horizon forever, but those things all end and I can escape running man.
Speaker 1: You can't get out There's no escape.
Speaker 1: You're done.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm It'll and some of these shows do get cancelled and the ratings get bad.
Speaker 1: But doesn't look like that'll happen to running man, right?
Speaker 0: Well, not soon I mean there.
Speaker 0: apparently there was a time when it may have been cancelled and the ratings are low But I guess they passed that and it's pretty popular.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's gaming day.
Speaker 1: Skip all the anecdotes about shit.
Speaker 1: I did in Istanbul and Mag Fest.
Speaker 1: we barely talked about like the crazy crap that happened at Mag Fest.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But so yeah speaking of sports and games the hockey's back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Really wanted to boycott hockey cuz I'm kind of pissed about the whole, you know thing.
Speaker 1: But I was at a kind of burger joint in Brooklyn Eating a burger and having some poutine and there was some hockey.
Speaker 1: and there was hockey on an HD 16-inch screen like right in front of my face and I look up and I'm like, oh Right Hockey is the fucking bad.
Speaker 1: It's hockey.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Well, didn't you see that goal?
Speaker 0: That was my thing of the day I think in last episode that was one of the better goals I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: that's like top 10 or 15.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but so I'm.
Speaker 1: the hockey is there.
Speaker 1: I'm watching the Rangers live at MSG right there from Brooklyn and then right then There's a face-off.
Speaker 1: like two seconds after I start watching Gloves drop to fistfight and there's two guys in this joint who turn up and they're like, whoa Are those guys fighting?
Speaker 1: Why aren't the ref stopping him?
Speaker 1: So I turned.
Speaker 1: I'm like so you realize in hockey There's rules about this sort of thing.
Speaker 1: They're like there's rules about fighting and I explained to these guys how hockey works.
Speaker 0: never seen hockey.
Speaker 0: They just didn't really from Brooklyn.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: it was just two dudes.
Speaker 1: and meanwhile the owner comes out.
Speaker 1: He's an LA guy.
Speaker 1: He's like, yeah fucking break his nose.
Speaker 0: Yeah LA just won the cups.
Speaker 0: He's excited.
Speaker 1: So the fight ends and one guy's got a clearly broken nose that he's hiding.
Speaker 1: so we won't have to leave the game And everything's cool.
Speaker 1: next face-off another fight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think those are the first two hockey fights of 2013 Huh?
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm sure that wasn't the first game of the day.
Speaker 1: I think they were the first proper.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know sometimes fights just kind of start.
Speaker 1: Those are the first like two guys at the face-off give each other the look of.
Speaker 1: as soon as that puck drops Let's drop our gloves.
Speaker 1: Anyway, those are my favorite kind of hockey fights.
Speaker 1: No second favorite.
Speaker 1: My favorite is when the goalies get involved.
Speaker 1: exciting You got any news?
Speaker 0: I do so.
Speaker 0: Kotaku posted this article top five or so board games to get excited about in 2013 And normally this kind of thing is one of those link bait top whatever list.
Speaker 1: Yeah it's also really hard for me to get excited about new games because I mean every board game that comes out is Going up against Puerto Rico teeny
Speaker 0: But anyway, so I looked at this list and you know It actually was kind of handy because usually I don't pay shit attention to what games are coming out Later, I pay attention to board games after they come out.
Speaker 0: I see that they're starting to get hot and then I get grab Yeah, it's like oh what.
Speaker 0: after like a month or two?
Speaker 1: I'll be like, what's this game?
Speaker 0: and some dude who knows Huh, a lot of people are talking about and playing this game.
Speaker 0: or wow I see this game at every retailer and every convention.
Speaker 0: I wonder what the deal is granted.
Speaker 0: Oh this game shot all the way up to the top of the board game geek list That I saw before.
Speaker 1: it was out that I was really intrigued about was castellan, but I don't think it's out yet.
Speaker 0: Yes, I'm gonna look for that though.
Speaker 0: So here's the games.
Speaker 0: they talk about the cave.
Speaker 0: based on their description the cave looks like Infiltration but you're discovering a caves as different paths is branching Right.
Speaker 0: Uh Space cadets seems to be a lot like space team or you know Artemis bridge simulator where everyone has a different board and does things on their board and it affects the Universal board and everyone else is bored, right?
Speaker 0: Kemet seems to be relate.
Speaker 0: I guess they say that it's a successor to a different game called cyclades Cyclades, I guess it looks like Greek gods fighting or something or Seen that somewhere auctions to appeal to the different Greek gods.
Speaker 0: I don't know like.
Speaker 1: I've seen that in a board game library and for some reason ignored it.
Speaker 0: roll for the galaxy Which I guess is race for the galaxy X couriers, which?
Speaker 0: Race for the galaxy is okay couriers is me So combining them, you know, whatever the one that's really interesting here that I think I'll buy no matter what is called Tammany Hall.
Speaker 0: and yes, the theme is part of the reason part of the reason I'm buying this.
Speaker 0: So apparently Tammany Hall was the game that was released a while ago in oh seven But only printed 500 copies and that was it period.
Speaker 0: so but it got.
Speaker 0: people liked it a lot.
Speaker 0: on the theme alone This appears to be an el grande of downtown New York broke it into areas and you put Italians Irish Germans and different races of New York City immigrants into the different neighbor.
Speaker 1: It sounds like a perverse Zularato, it's like get a red.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah You know if ever a game was gonna be sold to me on theme alone and also has a little bit of die marker I guess cuz it's political.
Speaker 1: the only game that's grabbed me on theme alone before this I think was Not glory to Rome but the goth game gluttony in whatever Rome.
Speaker 1: yeah, whatever that was called that game actually sucked but It was actually fun the first time.
Speaker 0: the second time I realized second time We saw it was going on and how most of the cards were just new.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you could if you made a better deck of cards that game could be good.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we did an episode on that.
Speaker 0: Oh, there was actually I completely forgot about it.
Speaker 0: There is actually a more important news.
Speaker 0: It's recording, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, why would it not be because we stopped and started again?
Speaker 0: There is a more important news that I forgot back the veil that I forgot and remembered.
Speaker 0: Are you ready for this news?
Speaker 0: It's actually a big news.
Speaker 0: some you know how we always complain companies don't do smart shit and we're like company.
Speaker 0: Why don't you just do smart shit?
Speaker 0: Fuck you?
Speaker 0: Fuck you do it.
Speaker 0: Come on What if I told you a company did a smart shit?
Speaker 0: the smartest shit?
Speaker 1: Is it a company that is not valve or Google?
Speaker 0: it is.
Speaker 0: it is a company that is not.
Speaker 0: in fact Hasbro subsidiary wizards of the coast wizards of the coast.
Speaker 0: Yes So you could also in fact truthfully say Hasbro has done a smart current.
Speaker 0: stewards of fuck out of them stewards of Dungeons and dragons and guard the kind and more duck magic the guy that ain't.
Speaker 0: if you go to the website www.letter D letter N letter D classics.com This website will sell to you for American dollars.
Speaker 0: Shut up and take my money.
Speaker 0: every D&D book ever in a DR apparently DRM free PDF you can just buy.
Speaker 0: look here It is D&D something.
Speaker 0: I just bought on eBay made out of paper.
Speaker 0: D&D classic, you know basic set rule book by.
Speaker 1: So when you say every are we talking like all the original individual things plus like the cyclopedia edition.
Speaker 1: Is this everything?
Speaker 1: everything name a book the Dungeons and Dragons rules cyclopedia rules Cyclopedia because that is the original D&D that I knew.
Speaker 0: Hold on I think I typed it wrong.
Speaker 1: It might have the AE Diphthong in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think I'm spelling it wrong.
Speaker 1: See why CLO P a DIA search engine is slow.
Speaker 0: great It's pretty slow.
Speaker 1: doobie doobie doo doobie doo doo.
Speaker 0: Their website is not the greatest.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: All right, I'll figure out if they Rules compendium three and a half Three and a half.
Speaker 0: Hold on.
Speaker 0: They still they got all the additions.
Speaker 0: one, two, three, I think.
Speaker 1: wait one.
Speaker 1: That's a D&D.
Speaker 1: What about regular D&D?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they have.
Speaker 0: they have all the D and D's.
Speaker 1: Do they specifically have the rules cyclopedia, which is correct slightly.
Speaker 0: So I'm looking.
Speaker 0: it's Cyclo.
Speaker 0: Hey, dear God, do I have to do?
Speaker 1: I have to use Google myself?
Speaker 1: CYCL o it's like encyclopedia without the end.
Speaker 0: It's not a good book though.
Speaker 0: That is no it's not.
Speaker 0: everybody I have talked to says you should use in fact this other book.
Speaker 0: That is the number one best-selling book on here the D&D basic set rule book.
Speaker 1: Okay Tell me what the differences are and maybe I will trust you.
Speaker 0: somebody.
Speaker 0: Luke Crane says so.
Speaker 0: he plays.
Speaker 0: he's played these game Recently.
Speaker 1: ask Luke Crane what the difference is.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: But anyway They have.
Speaker 0: they sell you here D&D basic set rule book five dollars.
Speaker 0: They give you a watermarked PDF.
Speaker 0: as the PDF doesn't seem to have DRM It just has some sort of watermark on it by mold vay or mensa or whatever it is.
Speaker 0: I forget which one was the guy who wrote which one.
Speaker 1: all right doesn't have the second edition psionics handbook.
Speaker 0: All right psionics.
Speaker 0: The search engine is really slow.
Speaker 1: Yeah Cuz the Cyclopedia is the oldest D&D book I have right expanded sound exam book.
Speaker 0: three and a half and HR for a mighty fortress wait three and a half.
Speaker 1: No, I need the a D&D one.
Speaker 0: Well this second edition.
Speaker 0: Let's see edition second edition.
Speaker 0: Let me try browsing for it because their search engine is awful.
Speaker 1: Oh so far that the books I'm most interested in or not in here.
Speaker 0: This site is so slow.
Speaker 0: Oh my god Oh my god, but supposedly this has all the books.
Speaker 1: We'll do a follow-up review of this thing as I see if the books that matter in there or not.
Speaker 0: But at least on paper This is kind of awesome.
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: because now you don't you know the rules?
Speaker 1: Cyclopedia contains all major rules compiled and revised from the dungeons and dragons basic rules as Well as the expert rules companion rules and master rules box sets.
Speaker 0: Yes, suppose like on in theory the Cyclopedia is just supposed to be BECM all in one book.
Speaker 0: right but apparently there are things that are different right.
Speaker 0: Luke Crane told me whoever told you to get the Rules Cyclopedia was wrong.
Speaker 1: He told me those words, okay I just want to find out what the difference is.
Speaker 1: the rules.
Speaker 1: Cyclopedia has extra optional things in it.
Speaker 0: No, he said that there were in fact Changes in it that were bad.
Speaker 1: I'm dubious.
Speaker 1: I trust the man, but I'm dubious of this second gen.
Speaker 1: hearsay Okay, anyway, but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: so Technology when it comes to audio has actually been progressing pretty rapidly for the last decade Despite you know people might not realize this because music seems so ubiquitous.
Speaker 1: Audio seems so kind of standard like people don't think what is improving in audio but when you think about like autotune as We know it today is a relatively modern invention and the old ways to do it like vocoders and things.
Speaker 1: We're a lot more manual like automatic shit.
Speaker 1: Just kind of works in audio.
Speaker 1: now, so There's some people and this was on Boing Boing So I'm gonna link to two of these.
Speaker 1: it's the same people as far as I can tell who did these two videos.
Speaker 1: they took REM's losing my religion and Metallica's nothing else matters and all they did was transform every minor third into a major third to make the song be in a major key and I think it sounds great.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's interesting to listen to though.
Speaker 1: If you read the comments a lot of people claimed that it made them feel sick Listening to it But most of those people also admitted that they were big fans of you know Either Metallica or REM and had listened to the song so many times that like it bothered them that it sounded different.
Speaker 1: What's funny is a lot of people seem mad that they were doing this Like actually angry that someone was taking these old songs and doing something cool with them.
Speaker 0: I don't understand why people can't angry about shit like it's like.
Speaker 0: would you repaint the Mona Lisa?
Speaker 0: I'm like, yeah sure Yeah, why not?
Speaker 0: Original.
Speaker 0: it's not like if someone fucked up the original Mona Lisa and painted on it I would like shoot.
Speaker 0: that'd be like what the fuck is wrong with these guys.
Speaker 0: But if some guy stands next to the Mona Lisa and paints a new one Who?
Speaker 1: and it was a funny little Charlie Chaplin mustache on it.
Speaker 1: I mean who cares?
Speaker 1: but what's cool is the Metallica one is from about a year ago and the losing my religion one is from very recently and Even now the difference in a year's technology is like night and day in terms of how well it's done.
Speaker 1: So I urge you to listen to these and it's interesting that one losing my religion Like if you don't think about like chords and intervals and things I mean back in the day the church would write at length about the effects of different chords and different intervals on the human psyche.
Speaker 1: and listening to the song in a major key has a very different feeling from listening to it in a minor key to the point that the It's like the underlying maths of the music itself Independent of the lyrics has an equally profound effect on the way you feel the music to the actual words in the song.
Speaker 0: But is it?
Speaker 0: you know, but the thing is it's like we you know, the rules of music It's like there are no like the rules of music are not an inherent thing of the universe like Inherent thing of the human brain exactly.
Speaker 1: Well, we know I got to qualify that a little bit.
Speaker 1: They are based on Certain things where like there are the ideas of harmonics, right?
Speaker 0: But the point is is that all it is is there are sounds.
Speaker 0: we can only hear this frequency through that frequency Right, and we tested over centuries how people feel when different sounds different frequencies are heard And then we categorize them, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like oh my god Minor makes you feel this way to major makes you feel that way.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like yeah because we just we group those sounds together because they made you feel that way.
Speaker 0: We said let's take all the sounds that make you feel this way and call those the minor and You feel this way.
Speaker 1: We'll call those major not quite because what minor and made.
Speaker 1: it's just the difference between one specific interval That's defined by a frequency difference between two pitches, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like they group, you know, it was Named it the minor as opposed to the major, right?
Speaker 0: But the point is they came up with that system based on you know They categorize them in you know Realized that made a difference in feeling and that is why there is even any, you know definition there at all any categorization.
Speaker 1: Well, my point is just that listening to a song that you know, very well that it's not a cover It's not like someone covered it and sang it in a different key, which is pretty easy to do.
Speaker 1: This is the exact original Identical in every way except it's in a major key.
Speaker 1: It's uncanny.
Speaker 0: That's what keys are.
Speaker 0: Be like, you know, we define foods by the way, they taste to us.
Speaker 0: We put this food here.
Speaker 0: We call it salty because it's all actually.
Speaker 1: no we defined We define that because we can only taste four things right and we put this food over there.
Speaker 0: We call it bitter because it's bitter because we can only.
Speaker 0: oh my god.
Speaker 0: I changed.
Speaker 0: I took this food That's usually a salty food the potato chip and I took out the salt and I replaced it with bitterness and oh my god It is bitter now.
Speaker 0: Okay, I changed it.
Speaker 0: I changed now.
Speaker 0: It's a bitter potato chip.
Speaker 1: Holy shit All I'm saying is these are really cool and the technology to do this autumn fairly automatically is relatively recent.
Speaker 0: That is.
Speaker 0: the interesting part is that usually if you wanted to have a song in a different key.
Speaker 1: you would have to read, you know, re-score and re-perform the song or Be basically sit and master the entire thing kind of by hand which we change the frequencies it or use a really harsh Automated system.
Speaker 1: that usually were really bad like old vocoders Kind of sound like shit.
Speaker 1: one of the reasons why you have those sort of synthetic voices and a lot of old You know early days of electronica music is because you couldn't make it sound natural.
Speaker 1: So instead we went the other direction made it sound cool, but not now.
Speaker 0: It would also be much easier to do this If you had the original Recordings of all the separate tracks so that we could like take the guitar and change it and take the singing and change it Whereas if you know to change it when they're all already mixed together is much more difficult.
Speaker 0: So the fact that technology can now do this when they are mixed together, you know It probably does like an FFT to separate everything out then change it and mix it back together again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's actually probably a little more subtle.
Speaker 1: Do you know what FFT stands for the fast Fourier transform?
Speaker 0: actually because that keeps coming up all the time and is a programming thing I've actually done Some research on what that's about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I actually use those in the the mag fest videos that I uploaded to remove a couple of specific actually use notch filters And other things too.
Speaker 1: There were some hisses and some weird like background noise from the con that I had to kind of edit out because some of the panelists Were way fucking quiet.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway thing of the day.
Speaker 0: So this guy I guess he has a chicken in his yard or something All right chicken in the yard.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the chicken lays fucking eggs cuz that's what it does.
Speaker 0: And one of the eggs it laid was huge.
Speaker 0: Like we're talking way bigger than the chicken no, but like Really big.
Speaker 0: you can see it in this video how big the egg is, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if it was around it might be a tennis ball.
Speaker 0: It's a big egg And he's.
Speaker 0: he gets his video and he's like check out this egg and compares it to a grocery store egg.
Speaker 0: It's like look how big it is.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, and then he cracks it open over the stove To show, you know over a pan on the stove to show you.
Speaker 0: because and he's like, all right We're gonna see what's in here.
Speaker 0: everybody on video.
Speaker 0: We're gonna see what's in here and watch the video and see what's in there.
Speaker 0: It's not what you expect to be in there.
Speaker 0: I Mean, you know, I was expecting, you know a chicken of some kind.
Speaker 0: No, there was not a chicken in there it was so it was something else.
Speaker 1: So was it that some other animal laid an egg under the chicken?
Speaker 1: Nope All right.
Speaker 1: I have not watched this video.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I know you're gonna watch it and find out.
Speaker 1: I'll watch it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so in the meta moment the book club book Which I'll finally add to the website is F Scott Fitzgerald's The Great Gatsby.
Speaker 0: It's actually.
Speaker 0: I read it completely.
Speaker 0: It's actually way short.
Speaker 1: I'll read it relatively soon.
Speaker 0: I did not realize how short it was because I had a digital edition of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you guys just don't know.
Speaker 0: you look at those percentages you don't have and then you don't know how long it is.
Speaker 0: unless you either check to see how many pages or Start reading and you see how much the percentage goes up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like at the end of chapter one.
Speaker 0: I'm like six percent.
Speaker 0: This is gonna be short.
Speaker 1: We were just at magfest.
Speaker 1: I've uploaded two of our panels and lectures.
Speaker 1: I've uploaded beyond candy land to YouTube.
Speaker 1: you can watch it.
Speaker 1: I've also uploaded one of the panels.
Speaker 1: we were on video game genres and I'm thinking about submitting that same topic to PAX dev But assembling a an expert group of panelists for it And I've already sent some emails to people because I think it'd be a good topic actually for dev with a with like people who?
Speaker 1: Are prepared and have specific things to say already?
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: It's my crab people.
Speaker 0: The next thing she's coming out PAX East.
Speaker 0: I'm enforcing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I submitted to enforce.
Speaker 0: They're looking for more enforcers so you can join our club.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 1: I did not.
Speaker 1: I you know I will do whatever they ask me but I'm actually not going for like panels or the things you guys know I'd be good at.
Speaker 1: I'm going for like something crazy.
Speaker 1: I've never done.
Speaker 0: I'm just going for whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't really give a shit.
Speaker 0: I'm going for like back-end operations or something I mostly just don't want to have to do something where I sit in one place for a long time.
Speaker 1: That's why I want to do back end like like haul something around.
Speaker 0: I don't really want to do like, you know stand and check badges or Sit at the tabletop library and check games in and out.
Speaker 0: I want to do something like stand there and help people or You know walk around doing work Whatever.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: it should be fun.
Speaker 1: We should also be doing one or two panels I sent in our geek nights workshop.
Speaker 1: like we always do Might do something a little bit different if they give us a room for that thing again.
Speaker 1: Hmm probably involving power grid.
Speaker 1: After that kinetic on.
Speaker 1: submissions are open.
Speaker 1: submit your panels.
Speaker 1: We're gonna start scheduling in a few weeks Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: You can keep submitting after that but Prime spots will slowly disappear for his dibs.
Speaker 1: Yeah dibs dibs Jerry the dibs.
Speaker 0: We're gonna go to Pax Australia man.
Speaker 0: Things are just coming up fast.
Speaker 1: We've got to start looking for that I know and of course if you want us to speed up our utenna show or radio free equestria or any of these other videos Spread them around.
Speaker 1: the view counts have to go way up.
Speaker 1: where I'm gonna take my sweet fucking time and uploading these things Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I like doing them, but that means I'm gonna do them at the rate that I want to do them.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna force it.
Speaker 1: But if you get if radio free equestria gets like 10,000 views in the next couple weeks We'll put out one every week or so.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'll do whatever if you guys start watching them.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so Android netrunner.
Speaker 0: Here's the deal.
Speaker 1: I keep wanting to call it an Android.
Speaker 0: So here's the deal.
Speaker 0: right for people who don't know this needs some explanation.
Speaker 0: Back in the day when magic came out.
Speaker 0: There was another CCG called netrunner, right?
Speaker 0: I saw it in the stores But I ignored it because and I was I rightfully ignored it because every CCG that wasn't magic sort of died, dude I tell spellfire.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I played jihad.
Speaker 1: There was.
Speaker 0: there were so many CCGs that came out when the Star Wars one right.
Speaker 0: there were so many that came out when magic first came out That we're trying to compete with magic.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh my god, this thing caught on.
Speaker 0: Let's copy it.
Speaker 0: Right but They almost all failed.
Speaker 0: None of them succeeded until The second round right when you know, like Pokemon and Yu-Gi-Oh came out all that.
Speaker 0: There was a Star Wars.
Speaker 0: There was a Star Trek.
Speaker 0: There was.
Speaker 0: there were so many CCGs as Lord of the Rings one.
Speaker 0: I had a couple cards from yeah There's the l5r one that I played a little bit right and netrunner was one of those and it there was jihad Which is the ultra rare.
Speaker 1: I was saying jihad.
Speaker 1: I mean day one.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I have like a whole deck and everything.
Speaker 0: So netrunner was unique in that it was unlike those other ones.
Speaker 0: It was also made by Richard Garfield who made magic the gathering.
Speaker 0: he considers it one of his best game designs ever.
Speaker 0: But you know, it disappeared it was ignored and it was a CCG.
Speaker 0: So we had no interest in it Even if we knew about it.
Speaker 0: because number one, you know I mean remember when I quit playing magic when fallen empires came out.
Speaker 0: I started playing magic shortly before fallen empires came out.
Speaker 1: when fallen empires came out I was like wow stop these expansions are really just alliance's came out Alliances.
Speaker 1: the last tournament I played in was like the day after.
Speaker 1: it was a middle school thing, basically Yeah, and I played in a type 1 tournament.
Speaker 1: is the last tournament I played in right?
Speaker 1: I wanted to use my Sol ring and my mocks.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so and so netrunner was a game.
Speaker 0: it didn't come, you know, and they didn't promote it.
Speaker 0: They didn't make it win because why would they promote a competitor to their own product, right?
Speaker 0: They didn't do that.
Speaker 1: now It'd be fine if they'd have different niches, but you're basically gonna tap the same pool, right?
Speaker 1: Why should we same pool?
Speaker 0: Why should they take players away from magic to get them play netrunner?
Speaker 1: I can only tap the pool.
Speaker 0: No one can afford to play two games.
Speaker 0: It didn't work out.
Speaker 0: So anyway, apparently fantasy flight games.
Speaker 0: It was a great current publisher of games.
Speaker 0: It was published many good games.
Speaker 0: They publish Citadel's and a whole bunch of other games.
Speaker 0: they have this thing called a living card game and Apparently they've been going.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize that they've been going for a while.
Speaker 0: I've always wanted a living card game at least on paper and I didn't realize they were already making them.
Speaker 0: They have a call at Cthulhu one and a Game of Thrones one.
Speaker 0: They've been around for a while and what a living card game is is much like a CCG you customize your deck and then you play but Like Dominion, you don't have to buy boosters and starters and collect cards.
Speaker 0: You just buy every single expansion once and you will have all the cards and then you make whatever deck you want And then you play against your friends.
Speaker 0: So you do.
Speaker 0: it is not a cheap thing to do, right?
Speaker 0: It's about it might even be slightly more expensive than Dominion.
Speaker 0: You do have to keep paying money like a subscription to get more cards, but I'm not buying Booster pack exactly to get the rare.
Speaker 1: I'm looking.
Speaker 0: there are no rares.
Speaker 0: There are no uncommons or commons, right?
Speaker 0: You just buy all the cards.
Speaker 0: It's like a subscription to a game you pay 15 bucks most months and you will have every card.
Speaker 0: one annoying thing is that you know They have these data packs that come out every month.
Speaker 0: that are $15 or so and those include three copies of every card that is in them Which is the most you're allowed to have in a deck.
Speaker 0: So you only to buy a data pack once and you're set.
Speaker 0: but the base set of netrunner the basic box Which you need to buy at least once.
Speaker 0: Some of the cards in there.
Speaker 0: they give you three copies.
Speaker 0: other cards in there.
Speaker 0: You only get two copies and other cards in there.
Speaker 0: You only get one copy.
Speaker 0: So if you are all alone and you want to have Every possible if you want to have available to you every possible configure configuration of deck You need to buy the basic netrunner three times, which is bullshit Bullshit, but I did it anyway, and at least when you but do it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you can give a lot of those cards to other people and now they don't have to buy as many other basic sets Unless they really want to have those cards that only appear once.
Speaker 0: There's only like a handful of them.
Speaker 0: So really you can get away with two sets pretty well, and it's actually not an expensive game.
Speaker 0: It's like 20 something bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I've spent quite a bit more money on Much worse.
Speaker 0: to buy two netrunners is the same as buying one, you know, really fancy board game.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I'm not too upset but it is bullshit.
Speaker 0: They should they should sell some sort of like completion thing.
Speaker 0: That's like buying the netrunner base box.
Speaker 0: then buy this and you'll have everything but whatever anyway, so You get all the action of a CCG without any of the.
Speaker 0: oh he won because he has fancy expensive Black load as I can't afford.
Speaker 0: that's all gone.
Speaker 0: There's no pay to win It's just pay to play a lot like say Warhammer.
Speaker 1: where you think what I find much more interesting is, you know All that aside just the fact that it's straight up Asymmetric and there's two separate sides with sort of sort of separate goals and very different ways of playing.
Speaker 1: That is what seals this for me.
Speaker 1: That is what pushes it away from being just right.
Speaker 0: So I wasn't actually sure how.
Speaker 0: I thought that this new Android netrunner, which it takes place in the Android universe Which is I guess fantasy flight is a game called Android which doesn't look to be too good.
Speaker 0: It looks like clue at least based on the description of it.
Speaker 0: and then they released Android infiltration, which we've talked about, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is a great game.
Speaker 1: I like it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and now they have Android netrunner.
Speaker 0: Android infiltration is made by the Dominion guy Vacarino whatever.
Speaker 0: so they're putting out these games in this Android cyberpunk universe, which seems to be not a bad universe.
Speaker 0: I like cyberpunk styling.
Speaker 0: So Android netrunner is.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize how identical it was to the original netrunner.
Speaker 0: It's very identical in the way it plays.
Speaker 0: It's an asymmetrical game like rim said.
Speaker 0: yeah one player is the corporation and one player is the runner.
Speaker 0: and the corporation is trying to win either by a Flatlining the runner so that they're dead.
Speaker 0: They can't hack into the corporation anymore or two Advancing their corporate agendas.
Speaker 0: so they play agendas advance them and score them and if they score seven points worth of agendas they win.
Speaker 0: the runner is trying to either a Deplete the corporation's research and development their deck down to be empty so that the corporation will you know?
Speaker 0: Not be able to research anything and lose or be Steal the agendas from the corporation steal seven points worth of agendas Right.
Speaker 0: and what this game is all about is, you know, you got a little bit rock-paper-scissors and the deck customization.
Speaker 0: Yeah a little bit.
Speaker 0: But really what it's all about is the corporation is bluffing.
Speaker 0: They're setting up servers with all these face down cars.
Speaker 0: They're sending out defenses in front of the server.
Speaker 1: might not be bluffing.
Speaker 1: I mean you might not have any traps in there
Speaker 0: or might be setting up, you know Facedown defenses in front of the servers and the runner has to attack these servers, you know In you know with their icebreakers and their hacking tools to get past the ice the defenses the facedown defenses And to get into the servers and then access the servers and see what's in there.
Speaker 1: now the fact that one player is the attacker And one's the defender.
Speaker 1: the problem is in game and pretty much all games.
Speaker 1: I just I really enjoy playing defense.
Speaker 1: So I really really like playing the corporation.
Speaker 1: I got to play the runner more to kind of get around a feel for it and also to figure out holes in my current Corporation strategy which by the way involves a Haas Biaroid because I really like them.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so I've been playing this game a lot.
Speaker 0: There's actually a meetup in the city.
Speaker 0: There's people who play it a lot.
Speaker 0: They've been playing it since it came out of Gen Con some of them and I even went to a tournament at the complete Strategist.
Speaker 0: and the only problem with that tournament was that it took all day from like 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: To 6.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess for maybe it took a while right which you know is knowing but you basically have to play both sides.
Speaker 0: And the weird thing is when I first started playing this game with just people I know like it There's go Joe's party.
Speaker 0: I played with Alex a bunch, right?
Speaker 0: The corporation was just sort of unbeatable.
Speaker 0: We didn't understand how to run properly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that was.
Speaker 1: that was you know, the jinteki default deck and whatever the runner device.
Speaker 0: At the tournament, you know, I had to play against four people.
Speaker 0: It's a Swiss kind of system.
Speaker 0: the rules are on the official website and I won three out of four times as runner and I lost three out of four times as corporation.
Speaker 0: but I ended up losing overall because in the matches I split I Gave up points some number of points as the you know winning runner But as the corporation I wasn't able to score as many points as I gave up in.
Speaker 0: you know The time that it right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the other person won overall Which means I really only won one out of four times, which is not enough My early magic tournaments.
Speaker 0: I did not do super Well, so it's weird that you know, two people who didn't never played the game before and we're learning it.
Speaker 0: Corporation just couldn't be beat was invincible.
Speaker 0: We're like, what the hell.
Speaker 0: it was way more fun to be corporation.
Speaker 0: But now I'm way good better at running.
Speaker 0: I think it is running.
Speaker 0: I suck ass at corporation.
Speaker 1: I think what it is is that just thinking about the way we play games cuz look we were mostly used to these crazy German games we're used to.
Speaker 1: you know, we I tend to take very Conservative strategies and tend to minimize my risk.
Speaker 1: in all games like I'll do I'll make decisions like like in netrunner.
Speaker 1: I think things like up.
Speaker 1: I should wait another round to run because I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: I gotta build my deck out that rat.
Speaker 1: You know if he raises that extra ice, I might not be able to beat it.
Speaker 1: I don't take any damage.
Speaker 1: No, you just gotta fucking go for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's usually in all games and this is explained in our favorite book characterisms games by Richard Garfield When you're ahead.
Speaker 0: well all it's more it's also by these other people.
Speaker 0: yeah George Scaf Elias you guys should buy.
Speaker 0: you never mentioned them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we should.
Speaker 0: it is written by Those guys.
Speaker 1: be like we interview you about your boy It's.
Speaker 0: the other two authors are George Scaf Elias and Robert Gucera.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so it talks about how when you're ahead in a game you tend to play conservatively and when you're behind You play very risky moves Because they're high-risk.
Speaker 0: high-reward move is if you succeeded that you might catch up and if you lose if you fails.
Speaker 0: Well, you were losing anyway, right?
Speaker 0: That's why when you're losing in football, you'll do an onsides kick.
Speaker 0: Maybe you get the ball back.
Speaker 0: It's a very small chance.
Speaker 0: But if you do that gives you an opportunity to catch up big time.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's also a second time when you play very aggressively and that's when you're in a sort of equilibrium.
Speaker 1: Hearts is the best example of this.
Speaker 1: for people who play perfectly conservative hearts and are smart enough to keep track of everything The game ends up being pretty random or maybe it comes down to like cards yet Oh, yeah or psychology to a little bit like a little bit of bluffing and everything.
Speaker 1: So then The way to win is, you know, basically you have a 25% chance of winning against everyone.
Speaker 1: You're almost better off being the one guy who just fucking goes for it and tries to shoot the moon Even if you're not a hundred percent sure because you only have a 25% chance of winning the whole thing.
Speaker 1: Anyway, go big or go home early on because if you go big early on and succeed You can play conservatively the rest of the game and probably win.
Speaker 1: So you can increase your odds of winning in a situation where everyone is very skilled and everyone is playing conservatively But it gets very tricky Figuring that out.
Speaker 0: So anyway, the way netrunner is constructed if you try to play Conservatively on either side.
Speaker 0: You're just gonna get hosed, right?
Speaker 0: Even if you get ahead and then start playing conservatively that basically is just letting the other guy catch up like Basically, you know in football they say you're running up the score, right?
Speaker 0: And the reason I keep using footballs analogy is the thing.
Speaker 0: netrunner is the football of tabletop gaming, right?
Speaker 0: There's so many, you know.
Speaker 0: Mechanically, it doesn't have so much in common with football, you know But in terms of the way it plays out and the flow of it.
Speaker 1: It is very hand egg Extremely, it's got that like the damage you do to the runner Like I can do like if Scott's running against me I can do damage to him or deuce his hand.
Speaker 1: He only has a few cards in his hand.
Speaker 1: if I get him down to zero I immediately win.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know you have to get him down to negative one.
Speaker 1: If I yeah, I have to get you down to zero and then force you to draw.
Speaker 0: Yes by doing you have to do one more damage than cards in hand.
Speaker 1: So I always feel like ah I just gotta push him over the edge and you'll always get so close to that ninth yard and that tenth yard and Nope got a kick.
Speaker 0: Yep but anyway, I Was in.
Speaker 1: But like I would like with the corporation like an example of conservative play say you've got you know You never discard an asset into your archives because you don't want to have to spend resources defending them.
Speaker 1: They're not defended yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you've got agendas.
Speaker 1: You're not discarding them into your archives Simultaneously, maybe you've only got two remote servers with ice.
Speaker 1: So if you've got two agendas in your hand and you've already deployed two agendas.
Speaker 1: What are you doing with these agendas in your hand?
Speaker 1: The runners gonna eventually attack your hand?
Speaker 0: It's like if you take your sweet-ass time only putting down agendas and super safe Servers that are very very iced up that the runner can't get into Your hand.
Speaker 0: you have to draw a card every turn.
Speaker 0: your hand will fill with agendas.
Speaker 0: You need to defend HQ Also, it's very very difficult to defend that and enough remote servers.
Speaker 1: Your hand will fill with agendas and you'll be in deep deep shit and it's fine to discard them if you're also defending archives But suddenly you're back in the situation.
Speaker 1: We're not having enough ice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or you can start putting them out into into other servers and be like I dare you.
Speaker 0: I you know That aren't as well defended.
Speaker 1: but the bluffing game is fun because twice I was in a situation where I put out What was the trap and I go advance advance and then if the runner doesn't attack it I'm fucked.
Speaker 1: because if I advance it more but don't finish it, it's obvious.
Speaker 0: It's a trap And you're wasting credits on it.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: You have to.
Speaker 1: you know, it's like but if I didn't advance at all They'd probably also not.
Speaker 1: you know, it's it.
Speaker 1: there's a point beyond which it is.
Speaker 1: Just which cup is the poison in?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but like poker Humans are kind of stupid in the sense that psychology can matter and I think it's very difficult Especially because a lot of the people are gonna be playing this game.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be the pros and the kind of serious gamers.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be a lot of punk kids like magic, too I mean even in magic tournaments for fun.
Speaker 1: I would play with like 300 card decks and still beat some of these scrubs.
Speaker 1: I'm like, yeah, I got five colors in here.
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 1: Actually four.
Speaker 1: I never actually did five.
Speaker 1: that would be probably too crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway, you know playing aggressively as the runner, right?
Speaker 0: It's like yeah If you're the runner you could choose only to run against servers that you know You can definitely get into safely without getting hurt, right?
Speaker 0: If you do that, you're not going to run often enough To actually, you know score any points.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you only run run once per round.
Speaker 0: fine I start scoring agendas, right now I did, you know and not eat, you know.
Speaker 0: It's like if you don't win that guy has three face down ice on that server.
Speaker 0: You just you're like, oh shit if I run there I could just die.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah But if you don't run there That means that he is not.
Speaker 0: the corporation is not forced to spend the credits required to rez all those ice.
Speaker 0: You're just letting him have a perfect defense without having to pay for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah I just be three chums in a row.
Speaker 0: Yeah You have to go and basically face up on my desk as the runner.
Speaker 0: to have any chance of success You have to risk Take big risks at losing or getting hurt or losing credits or taking damage or who knows what in?
Speaker 0: order to force the corporation to spend Resources defending to at least slow them down Even if you don't actually score on that move that you're making All right you basically have to spend some amount of resources to make them lose resources to slow them down so that you can catch up and Try to win and maybe take damage in the process and hope you can recover from it.
Speaker 0: It's the only way you can possibly.
Speaker 0: so it's like both people.
Speaker 0: the corporation is forced to take risks either, you know secretly putting agendas in the trash or Putting them in less defended servers.
Speaker 0: well at the same time the runner is forced to take risks running into dangerous territory to force the corporation to spend credits rezzing ice and If you if either side doesn't do one of those things They're gonna be in trouble, but it seems like and this is why I think in the early games I played with Alex the corporation always win is that if both people are ultra conservative the
Speaker 1: corporation's free.
Speaker 0: The corporation will win.
Speaker 0: but when both people sort of know what they're doing, you know, at least for me I'm doing bad at corporation when people know what they're doing Yeah But I'm doing very well at running when people know what they're doing.
Speaker 1: So yeah The thing is ice combos are tough because you can't really guarantee having cards in the right order.
Speaker 1: Like there's one ice that basically says if you hit this ice and you don't break it go back to the beginning of this Run.
Speaker 1: so if you put that first and you have three other ice in front of it you effectively have six ice in front.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you have to play that first and it's useless first and it's expensive.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: or there's cars.
Speaker 1: They're like, you know draw a bunch of cards.
Speaker 1: if any of them arise just stick them out there for free.
Speaker 1: But they might not be ice, you know, you got to play that the.
Speaker 1: you know The deck building game with magic of all right.
Speaker 1: I got four lightning bolts.
Speaker 1: I got four fireballs.
Speaker 1: I got.
Speaker 1: you know, you got to maximize on what your deck is intended to do.
Speaker 1: But the more you maximize onto one specific strategy the more open you are.
Speaker 1: But the biggest difference between this and magic is that once you made your deck in magic Unless you're talking about sideboards and shit in tournaments That was 90% of the game the decisions you made in magic were not where they were trivial.
Speaker 1: I was never.
Speaker 0: yeah early magic's been changed a lot now since we've played it.
Speaker 1: Creatures are way more powerful and I played creature decks back in the day with revised.
Speaker 1: I played a green and blue deck.
Speaker 1: that would rock your shit.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Also green and white occasionally.
Speaker 0: So what did you do when you played that guy who just had wrath of God and killed all your creatures?
Speaker 1: Because I was blue I could also I. basically my strategy was tons of creatures which will take a guy out Unless they're the kind of deck that's strong against creatures in which case creatures whatever those are just there.
Speaker 1: I'm mostly wheedling down their deck with my millstones and my other shit.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Or I had the creature poison deck.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, but what I'm saying is that any netrunner magic that we played was mostly rock-paper-scissors, right?
Speaker 0: What your deck was pretty much determined you're winning or you lose.
Speaker 1: Yeah But a netrunner you the decisions you make in the game at least for now and this is Obviously with all games.
Speaker 1: this changes as people start to refine strategies.
Speaker 1: You can change your strategy mid game.
Speaker 1: You can play cards different ways.
Speaker 1: You actually right now the decisions I make playing Like.
Speaker 1: I'm not making all trivial decisions.
Speaker 1: I'm making complicated decisions.
Speaker 1: Sometimes I'm calculating them out.
Speaker 1: I don't have an overarching strategy to play the game yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah magic.
Speaker 1: It was drama.
Speaker 1: cards play the optimum order.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the thing is, you know, I said, you know to bring back the football analogy, right?
Speaker 0: Is that you know netrunner, you know people who like like us like high-skill games And why do we like high-skill games that have less luck?
Speaker 0: Because then if you win it's because you won and because of your awesomeness and you lose is because you weren't simultaneously Like tennis.
Speaker 1: remember when we played that horse racing game in Albany that one time?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that game was random bullshit.
Speaker 1: You know, what?
Speaker 1: It's just as fun, right?
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is there's an amount of luck that can make it to where the better player is still gonna win.
Speaker 0: But the luck and randomness makes the game kind of more interesting and makes decision-making much much harder, right?
Speaker 0: When I make a decision in Puerto Rico, all right, I'm like, well if I do this He loses three and I get four right in netrunner.
Speaker 0: It's a similar decision.
Speaker 0: I'll do this, but he has a 60% chance of losing three and I have a 70% chance of getting four.
Speaker 0: All right, let's you know, it's that percentages that are in there.
Speaker 0: So you're still, you know, you know what the odds are on certain things.
Speaker 0: You know what the costs and resources are in certain things But there's a certain element of chance to it right where it might not go your way.
Speaker 0: It might go your way But you can sort of calculate the odds Mostly and not do things that have a load low chance of success.
Speaker 1: There is one other case though that the simulation the edge like certain kinds of war games and games can be fun where?
Speaker 1: There is a lot of random bullshit But that's because they're kind of a simulation of reality and the process of going through the game and seeing what the results are Is the primarily interesting
Speaker 0: part I'm saying just like, you know in sports right any sport, you know There's a. you know, tennis is the example is less luck But I mean even football.
Speaker 0: the wind blew the ball around or you know, the guy just had a slippery finger, you know There's so many little things that just can't you know that are so far beyond your control, right?
Speaker 0: And netrunner has a lot of those things just little things everywhere.
Speaker 0: They just might go wrong might go right You know, you don't know what that one card was and it throws a loop in your whole thing.
Speaker 0: Uh, you know you draw five cards to start the game.
Speaker 0: what those five cards are is kind of can change everything.
Speaker 0: You know one game I played at that tournament.
Speaker 0: I won almost instantly.
Speaker 0: I felt bad.
Speaker 0: It was so unfair.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna remember that guy in that game because We just mean him just couldn't shut up about how bad that game went for him how much bullshit it was, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then again, I mean he even Accelerated beta test drew three cards.
Speaker 1: No ice I mean in magic sometimes I draw all land.
Speaker 1: call the farmer hand draw land again.
Speaker 1: Like it can happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah You know or is a netrunner the same exact deck?
Speaker 0: You're only allowed three cards of any one type, you know of the same name in the deck.
Speaker 1: now if any you can About that rule.
Speaker 0: There's a reason that rule is Yeah, and you have to have a minimum deck size and you have to have a certain number of agenda points in a corporation deck.
Speaker 1: So it's like, you know you when you draw five you can draw drastically different hands and that changes how you play a Lot, but meanwhile in magic drawing the hand you don't make a decision You just play the hand out no matter what it is.
Speaker 1: You're not thinking like well do I want to risk this now considering that I drew all my assets?
Speaker 0: Also in making the deck right the deck construction rules You can only bring in so many influence points worth of cards from other factions.
Speaker 0: So, you know that any deck you play against you see their identity card.
Speaker 0: You know what most of their cards can be right.
Speaker 0: there will only be a few cards that aren't cards you expect from them so you can look at how they play and sort of play this meta game once you know all the cards because there aren't that many of What did they bring in right?
Speaker 0: if you don't see a lot of cards of that don't go with their identity?
Speaker 0: You know that they probably just have a few really powerful cards from the other identities.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: four point, you know influence cards like scorched earth which do for damage.
Speaker 0: But then again if you see a lot of cards of different colors right out on the table And that means they don't have a lot of high influence cards.
Speaker 0: So now you don't need to worry maybe about a scorched earth in a deck that isn't Wayland And that means that you can take tags and not really worry about getting instantly killed.
Speaker 1: And you know, but then again the the high-risk strategy of you've got all little cars You've got one fucking scorched earth in there.
Speaker 0: just one and one isn't enough.
Speaker 0: You gotta have two at least right and you really if you're gonna do any if you're gonna base your game around a card You gotta have three.
Speaker 0: The other thing is when you're making the corporation deck you to put agendas in.
Speaker 0: well You have to put a certain number of agenda points.
Speaker 0: So if you're what you want to do is the rules.
Speaker 0: the minimum deck size is 45 But if your deck contains between 45 and 49 cards, you have to have 20 or 21 Agenda points.
Speaker 0: So ideally ideally what you would do is make a 49 card deck with 20 agenda points thus to maximize the.
Speaker 0: you know, the did lessen the chance of an agenda card coming up.
Speaker 0: you don't want you know that way.
Speaker 0: when the the runner accesses your hand to your deck the odds of them getting an agenda card are low, but You might want to put in agenda cards that are only worth one point each because you can score those quickly without having to Defend them very much which makes the points much easier to get.
Speaker 0: if you get a really powerful agenda That's worth three points.
Speaker 0: You have to leave it on the table and advance it a whole bunch before you can score.
Speaker 0: It's in a very vulnerable position.
Speaker 0: You know, there's a bunch of ice in front of it.
Speaker 1: So if you're gonna do like if you're gonna do smaller number of high point ones You probably want to play someone or you can have a bunch of traps, too Right, but it's it's like you have to balance this out.
Speaker 0: Right, if I have a whole bunch of cheap agendas, my deck has a lot of agendas in it The runner is gonna score But they're not gonna score a lot of.
Speaker 0: you know, they're gonna score a whole bunch of ones But if I put a bunch of threes they still might score.
Speaker 0: the odds are still like one in four of them getting an agenda.
Speaker 0: They're still not great for you But when they do score they're gonna get two or three points and that means that in your deck there will be less non Agendas.
Speaker 0: so this game gives you all kinds of crazy things to think about and new cards coming out all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it costs money.
Speaker 0: But hey, it costs a fixed amount of money.
Speaker 0: You never had to spend crazy amounts of extra money collecting, you know to get all the cards you need or buying singles or any of that nonsense and at the same time you can know what all the cards are and Really that turns out to be one of the things we're knowing.
Speaker 0: what all the cards are matters a lot.
Speaker 0: But I sort of you know I've played only for like a couple weeks and I already know most of the major cards and Some of them.
Speaker 0: it's like just the first time you play it's obvious what the good cards are.
Speaker 0: on magnum opus.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right It's not a big fan of the toll booth.
Speaker 0: Yeah the toll booth and magnum opus are like the most obviously good cards and you just read through the cards and it's like oh I Get it.
Speaker 0: I get it.
Speaker 0: I get.
Speaker 1: you can't underestimate the economy though.
Speaker 0: It's it's all about economy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Know it's a super fun game that we'll probably review in much more depth.
Speaker 1: That's where you play it a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: and the thing I the real thing I see here right is that You know, we look at all the kinds of tabletop games out there, right?
Speaker 0: You got the high investment ones the miniatures the RPGs the eclipses, right?
Speaker 0: They take a long time to play.
Speaker 0: you have to learn a lot of complicated rules.
Speaker 0: They're really satisfying though, but you need a big table.
Speaker 0: You need a big investment, right?
Speaker 0: So it's really hard to get anyone to play those but mean it like magic.
Speaker 0: I would just play with like a friend In the cafeteria, you got the medium investment the Puerto Rico's and the power grids and those types.
Speaker 0: You got the low investments like the spot is right.
Speaker 0: But the thing is those low investment ones, you know to learn is not so much But you know to bust them out and play them is very quick, right?
Speaker 0: But it's not as satisfying strategically really.
Speaker 0: what you get with the CCG Right like magic is a game you can just sort of bust out and play casually like a instant play Whatever.
Speaker 0: you can play it with someone who knows how to play and has it as Easily as you can play.
Speaker 0: spot it because they know how to play.
Speaker 0: you know how to play.
Speaker 0: you both have cards.
Speaker 0: Just bust it out and play really quick.
Speaker 0: One, two, three, right nutrunner takes a little while a little longer than spot it But it's not a high investment.
Speaker 0: You can just sort of be sitting around, you know wasting time with it.
Speaker 1: You know, it's also got the single person not player But person component of like the deck building and the fucking around when you're just messing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can be sitting around at home just flipping through the cards.
Speaker 1: Like I wonder if I should replace one of those eyes.
Speaker 0: It gives you something to do.
Speaker 0: You can play the game when no one else is around by looking through the cards and customize.
Speaker 1: Well, like we play we used to play a battle tech a lot in our IT and you know what?
Speaker 1: Half the fun was just fucking around in a mech builder a mech maker making max
Speaker 0: Yep, even
Speaker 1: if I never played with those mess,
Speaker 0: you know by having just one of these games Even if you don't pick netrunner, maybe you pick a CCG then you want to waste all your money.
Speaker 0: Maybe you pick another living card game.
Speaker 0: I know some people play the Game of Thrones one.
Speaker 0: I think there's a Cthulhu one also, you know, maybe you know.
Speaker 0: But whatever it is It fills that niche of.
Speaker 0: you can spend time on your tabletop hobby when no one else is around customizing your deck.
Speaker 0: or you know miniatures painting or you know in it, right and It's a game where if there's other people around you know how to play it.
Speaker 0: You can bust it out with low effort, even though there's still an effort to learn it or buy it You can bust it out with low effort.
Speaker 0: So like me and Rimmer hanging out, you know We can play it as easily as we could play spot it and that's you could not say the same thing for a big Board game.
Speaker 0: that requires setting up pieces and all that kind of nonsense.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean, I would play magic just all the fucking time for years.
Speaker 0: Yep so it really fills that niche of the tabletop spectrum.
Speaker 0: if you've got one one of these games and You know the low-end spot it type games dixit types You know the medium German board games and the high investment games that covers every possible tabletop gaming scenario you could be in.
Speaker 0: there'll be a game for all seasons for all times of day for all flavors for all numbers of people for All everything and this is sort of the one that was missing and it also has a serious competition aspect.
Speaker 1: That is pretty interesting You know, I'll have to decide if I'm going to engage on that or not.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know how serious I'm gonna be.
Speaker 0: I guess, you know I'll go.
Speaker 1: I was pretty serious about magic like I would make my parents drive me to these tournaments.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I went to one local tournament.
Speaker 0: It was kind of fun.
Speaker 0: I'd probably go back.
Speaker 0: It's like I think what it is is if it doesn't conflict with my existing schedule.
Speaker 0: Why not go?
Speaker 0: You know, I'll go check it out.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: and I'm only gonna get serious.
Speaker 0: I'll.
Speaker 0: you know, I'll try to win obviously with my usual level of tabletop skill, but if I start winning right, seriously Then I may attempt to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like if I start kicking everyone's ass locally like these people who are really good the stars.
Speaker 1: if you were really good You might run into the situation of the Street Fighter champion among friends who can't beat anyone in the pro circuit.
Speaker 0: I may I may but if I do start winning a whole bunch and I surpass everybody I may go one step up to see if I can beat people.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: What'll be interesting to see is that in the old days of magic before they really settled on these draft Tournaments before they really settled on like, you know, I don't know what they call them now But the old days they had type zero type one and type two.
Speaker 1: Type two being you can only use like the current base set and the previous two released expansions to like limit the card set.
Speaker 1: so it prevented the problem to a degree.
Speaker 1: couple of the fact that there was barely an internet back then where there were to merge like a handful of decks that were just like the best and You could just find like the deck list and they were kind of like traded by
Speaker 0: The net runner like world champion.
Speaker 0: deck lists are online.
Speaker 0: You can go look at them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know so you can make them go for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it'll be interesting to see if I get to the point where I am building decks to change how I play or I end up taking a deck that is known to be the champion and learning how to play it.
Speaker 0: There is significant meta game.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: if you try to play the champions deck in the next tournament You'll just lose because there are people who are doing the sort.
Speaker 0: of which cup did I put the poison in?
Speaker 0: I'll make the deck that beat the champions deck from last year.
Speaker 0: But there's people who are playing two steps ahead of that saying well Everyone's gonna try to beat the champions there from last year.
Speaker 0: So I'll make a deck that beats the deck that could beat that deck.
Speaker 0: and then other people are you know?
Speaker 0: So it's really.
Speaker 0: you just have to pick a strategy and play well.
Speaker 0: And you know the meta game is only some aspect right like the scorched earth we talked about.
Speaker 0: it does for damage.
Speaker 0: There were a lot of people who are saying yes score It's so obvious.
Speaker 0: play NBN because that's the easiest to tag someone.
Speaker 0: they need to be tagged to do the damage and then put scorched Earth into it to kill them.
Speaker 0: and a lot of some people played that deck But everyone enough people are playing that deck that everyone sort of can beat it now.
Speaker 0: It's not so dangerous.
Speaker 1: Well look at the early days of magic.
Speaker 1: It was like Oh red deck.
Speaker 1: It's all just fucking fireballs and lightning bolts, and you just burn your way down 40 card deck bare minimum.
Speaker 0: Just attack attack attack.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's a card plastic Greek carapace.
Speaker 0: people are just putting two of them in their decks now to make sure that scorcher doesn't work.
Speaker 0: And now it doesn't work, so now what do you do if you're playing the scorcher deck?
Speaker 0: sure it might work.
Speaker 0: sometimes I got hit by it.
Speaker 0: there were.
Speaker 0: there were a few scorched earth still going around in the tournament I was at but for the most part scorched earth didn't win the tournament.
Speaker 0: right it won a few matches here and there.
Speaker 0: But it's like yeah, you know everyone knows about that.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna.
Speaker 0: the meta game is not gonna work.
Speaker 0: people know what's coming.
Speaker 1: But eventually the things can crystallize to a degree like there will eventually be unless they start cutting out old cards.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they planned like I'm sure they designed.
Speaker 0: you should read the tournament rules.
Speaker 1: You know I'm saying I'm sure they that the designers designed the first several sets all at once.
Speaker 1: So they're just kind of yeah.
Speaker 0: They have like previews of like sets for months from now like five sets down the road.
Speaker 0: even only two data packs are currently on Sale.
Speaker 0: I think the third one's coming out.
Speaker 1: It'll be interesting to see if tournaments start converging on a small handful of decks.
Speaker 1: because if if that happens rapidly I'm going to take one of those decks and then modify it for myself and my style of play.
Speaker 0: I doubt it because I think it's a circle of you know Rock-paper-scissors in all sorts of different directions.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's a deck that you know.
Speaker 0: for any deck that you make no matter how good You you might just come up against the guy who happened to make the deck.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, the shit might be a deck that in that rock-paper-scissors Statistically wins more on average.
Speaker 0: I think this is why I'm interested in this game because I think you know you look at the way that the rules are.
Speaker 0: The playing matters more than the deck making.
Speaker 0: you could not.
Speaker 0: you could not make a deck That's just.
Speaker 0: you could make a deck.
Speaker 1: see the thing is eventually the playing all game like Stratego Was like that, but eventually you come up with very strong heuristics.
Speaker 0: well Yes, they're.
Speaker 0: obviously there are decks you can make that are just fucking stupid and aren't gonna win.
Speaker 0: all right They can't win because you didn't put enough economy cards You didn't put enough ice or you didn't put an icebreaker for code gates.
Speaker 0: You can never break a code gate you can make it just a stupid broken deck.
Speaker 0: But overall amongst the good decks you can make you know there's enough variation that it's interesting Yeah, but there's nothing that you can do.
Speaker 0: That's just better.
Speaker 1: And it doesn't matter how you play it only in the sense that we have not had enough statistical data To see if there are particular strategies that statistically win more than other strategies other than basic stuff.
Speaker 1: So it'll be interesting to see over the next few years if the game becomes more popular.
Speaker 0: But I mean I had there.
Speaker 0: there are already other living card games the Cthulhu one in the game.
Speaker 1: So and it is not happening with those seat now you say that But I don't know how much data there is for those games.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of people playing those games.
Speaker 1: there are but those kinds of games draw different kinds of gamers.
Speaker 1: I don't think there's a huge competition between like the player Serious tournament, I know they do but so does Yu-Gi-Oh.
Speaker 1: yeah, Yu-Gi-Oh is one of the most popular card games with huge tournaments.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well you know Yu-Gi-Oh, but the rules of Yu-Gi-Oh are such that you know.
Speaker 0: It's you know vanilla coke I know.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that players will eventually solidify on pretty strong heuristics for play.
Speaker 1: There will definitely be a subset of possible decks Who are able to play sufficiently randomly when it comes down to enacting their strategies in terms of you know What percentage chance do I bluff?
Speaker 1: and all that once those are kind of down?
Speaker 1: It will fall back on just deck building at the highest level of play.
Speaker 0: I do not think it will fall back on.
Speaker 1: it has to because the game isn't that complex in the sense that a player there's no way there are.
Speaker 1: there won't be players who come up with if Not perfect in a mathematical sense, but effectively perfect human directional heuristics I think for a deck that they have constructed in which case the deck itself is what matters.
Speaker 1: they have a strategy They're gonna follow.
Speaker 0: I think I think you could fight that.
Speaker 0: you could take the world champion decks give them to us.
Speaker 0: We know how to play but we're not the world champions right.
Speaker 0: and let's say when those two world champions played against each other the People in the finals deck a beat deck be 60% of the time with us to playing.
Speaker 0: You know not playing the way that they played, but yeah My argument would not be 60% of the time.
Speaker 1: It doesn't refute my argument.
Speaker 0: the other deck might win.
Speaker 1: that doesn't refute my argument at all because if I play enough to develop those Strong heuristics, then my statistics will probably match those of the expert players.
Speaker 0: I do not think so.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure that's what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: anyway There was one other thing I wanted to say trying to remember.
Speaker 1: I mean I'm digging the game I bought into it.
Speaker 1: I'm buying every set.
Speaker 1: I ordered sleeves for my cards.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh, I gotta show you a sleeve shuffling trick.
Speaker 1: I learned I watched a bunch of YouTube video.
Speaker 0: No the YouTube videos do not teach you the most important trick That I have learned from a guy.
Speaker 1: You learn something from some guy.
Speaker 0: I did all right.
Speaker 1: You should make a YouTube video.
Speaker 0: I will.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I think we're done.
Speaker 0: We have talked a great deal about this game.
Speaker 0: We will probably be talking about it a lot more in the future if we play it a whole bunch more Which at least I know I'm gonna get there.
Speaker 0: you spend enough money on.
Speaker 0: I gotta get my mom's work.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website At front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.