Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, November 20th, 2013.
Speaker 1: I'm Rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights!
Speaker 1: Tonight, short reviews of Yoamushi Pedal and The Wind Rises.
Speaker 1: Let's do this!
Speaker 1: So I've been playing that Pokemon X now.
Speaker 1: It's about time.
Speaker 1: No, you're not.
Speaker 0: You're playing... Oh, you are playing Pokemon X. Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm still playing Pokemon Black 1.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: I skipped... I played the original Pokemon, I played Pokemon Pearl, and now I'm playing X, and nothing in between.
Speaker 0: I beat every Pokemon from red up to... well, one per generation, right?
Speaker 0: I beat one Pokemon per generation all the way from the beginning, when that was the only Pokemon there was, up to... I'm in the middle of black, so I'm not gonna break my chain.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: Fuck all those games, because of all the Pokemon that have come out recently, X is just the best iteration, by far.
Speaker 0: The best Pokemon has almost always been the best Pokemon.
Speaker 0: I know, but this one... It is rare, it is rare that the newest generation is not the preferred generation.
Speaker 1: But in terms of my own enjoyment of Pokemon, one, this game, like, you walk in, and you do your basic stuff, and then right away the game's like, "Yo, dog, here's some rollerblades, you can go fast.
Speaker 1: Yo, dog, you want another starter?
Speaker 1: Yo, dog, here's everything you want to make the game awesome right the fuck
Speaker 1: away.".
Speaker 1: XP share, that's just an option.
Speaker 1: You get it, like, five minutes in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's leaning towards what we want, which is just pick your stats, pick your level, but it's not quite there yet.
Speaker 1: ED training, you can just click on that, but there's three things I've noticed about this game that I kind of want to talk about briefly, guys.
Speaker 1: So one, the sexual overtones related to balls in the side dialogue...
Speaker 0: Have always been there since the very first Pokemon.
Speaker 1: ...is a little more prominent in this one.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Every fifth or sixth person I talk to is like, "Yo, I've got the best balls around.
Speaker 1: You want to see
Speaker 1: them?".
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like, it's kind of amazing.
Speaker 0: Are they dark balls?
Speaker 0: Dusk balls?
Speaker 1: But two, you pick a guy or a girl, and they have the whole dress-up thing.
Speaker 1: You can spend lots of Poke dollars to dress your character up.
Speaker 1: The guy's options are basically, do you want black pants or dark brown pants?
Speaker 1: Like, they suck.
Speaker 1: So, I'm playing as a girl because there's lots of cool fashion stuff you can do.
Speaker 1: Guys basically don't get to play that game.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Way to go, sexist Japan.
Speaker 1: And you know all these kids, like, there's all these kids, which are kind of annoying because they keep showing up and talking to you like you're their friend, and you're just trying to get them to go away so you can continue to fight and get Pokemon.
Speaker 1: But of all of them, there's Tierno, who's like this fat otaku kid who's kind of awesome.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: What kind of Pokemon does he have?
Speaker 1: I already don't remember.
Speaker 1: He had some dumb Pokemon.
Speaker 1: I haven't fought him too much.
Speaker 0: I'm sure they would be nerdy, right?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: He's just a nerdy guy.
Speaker 1: Like, he's wearing a "that guy" shirt, and he was really into dancing.
Speaker 0: It has a picture of a wolf Pokemon howling at the Pokemon.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: What's a wolf Pokemon?
Speaker 0: I can't think of one.
Speaker 1: Well, there's that new Poodle Pokemon, which I have named Woodle.
Speaker 0: I would not use a Poodle Pokemon.
Speaker 1: So I tried to name...
Speaker 0: I only use evil Pokemon and horrifically cute Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so one of the Pokemon I picked up, I named him Murasame.
Speaker 1: He's just this floating fucking sword.
Speaker 1: And his story is, some guy got fucking killed, and his soul is trapped in this sword.
Speaker 0: That is my kind of Pokemon.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: That is a Scott Pokemon right there.
Speaker 1: He's all, like, dark and steel and ghost and dangerous.
Speaker 0: Fuck yes.
Speaker 0: Best Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Swords, evil, perfect.
Speaker 0: Also, the best Pokemons are cute, like Combee.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some of these fairy Pokemon are going to be up your alley.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: I saw a Combee, but...
Speaker 0: Was it which kind?
Speaker 1: Uh, the unevolved Combee.
Speaker 0: Was it male or female Combee?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: You should be able to tell just by looking at it.
Speaker 0: What kind of Poketrainer are you?
Speaker 0: You didn't even look at your Pokedex.
Speaker 1: Apparently, I'm the best fucking Pokemon trainer ever, because everyone I talked to was like, "Whoa, there's some kind of crazy aura emanating from Lady R. Wow, she's just beating everybody.
Speaker 1: Oh my
Speaker 1: gosh.".
Speaker 1: But I tried to name my Bulbasaur Bulbasaur, and it was like, "I guess you don't want to name your Pokemon
Speaker 1: anything.".
Speaker 1: And it wouldn't let me.
Speaker 1: But then he evolved into Ivysaur, and I was able to then change his name to Bulbasaur.
Speaker 1: So my Ivysaur's name is Bulbasaur.
Speaker 1: But there's a girl character.
Speaker 1: She's like, "What are your
Speaker 1: friends?".
Speaker 1: And she... You know, there's friend stuff in this game.
Speaker 1: She, like, wants to be friends with you.
Speaker 0: Instead of one rival, it's like a team of rivals?
Speaker 1: You have a team of rivals, but they're all also friendly with you.
Speaker 0: So it's like ten Garys?
Speaker 1: The girl is totally crushing on me.
Speaker 1: And there's this scene where, like, you do a bunch of stuff with her, and then she's like, "Oh, let's go watch the fireworks
Speaker 1: together.".
Speaker 1: And then you get this whole FMV where you guys sit and watch the fireworks in this castle.
Speaker 1: And it's all super romantic, and she's like, "I will treasure this moment that I spent with you for the rest of my life.
Speaker 1: This is... I hope we can be very close
Speaker 1: friends.".
Speaker 1: And she's totally hitting on me, and I'm totally a girl, and I love this.
Speaker 1: I like the fact that this is a character who is...
Speaker 0: Did she show you her balls?
Speaker 1: She showed me all of her balls.
Speaker 1: She has more than two.
Speaker 0: Yeah, usually people carry six.
Speaker 1: I like the fact that she is really, obviously, hitting on my character.
Speaker 1: And two, she has the same dialogue regardless of what gender you choose.
Speaker 1: So this sort of gender-neutral relationship thing going on is pleasing to my eyes.
Speaker 0: At the start of the game, they're totally sexist, not letting the dudes play dress-up, but then they're totally...
Speaker 1: Well, the dudes can play dress-up, it's just the dress-up options for dudes suck.
Speaker 0: And then they're totally the opposite later on.
Speaker 1: I think it's just whoever designed the clothes for guys was really uninspired.
Speaker 1: Also, you can sit down.
Speaker 1: You can just sit down on stuff.
Speaker 1: I kind of like that.
Speaker 1: Very Ragnarok style.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I'm enjoying my Pokemons.
Speaker 0: Is that it?
Speaker 1: That's what I'm doing right now.
Speaker 0: All right, let's...
Speaker 1: And I've noticed, now that I'm carrying my DS around, my 3DS, every single person I've met in StreetPass for the last week has been playing Pokemon.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: Every single one.
Speaker 0: A full load of 10.
Speaker 0: Except me, everybody.
Speaker 0: Every day.
Speaker 1: All Pokemon, except one kid who was playing system settings.
Speaker 0: Except me, everybody.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't know what you've been playing.
Speaker 1: I gotta go see.
Speaker 0: Rune Factory and Picross.
Speaker 1: I've got Rune Factory.
Speaker 1: I haven't played much of it yet, but I'm totally hitting on that dragon.
Speaker 1: I want to hit on the mayor of town, the dragon girl.
Speaker 0: You're the mayor of town.
Speaker 1: The girl I fell on, like the dragon whatever, but I don't think I can, so I think I'm going to hit on the town guard.
Speaker 0: That's who I've been hitting on.
Speaker 1: She's way more powerful than everyone else.
Speaker 0: That is the only person worth hitting on.
Speaker 0: Everyone else is kind of stupid.
Speaker 1: So anyway.
Speaker 0: I guess second choice might be like flower shop girl.
Speaker 1: She's okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or piano music girl.
Speaker 1: Actually, if I were a girl in the game, the guys I can hit on, I think are way better choices, but...
Speaker 0: Are you going to hit an old guy?
Speaker 1: Not old guy.
Speaker 1: So yeah, brief news.
Speaker 1: We are vaguely aware of this Vanguard thing.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Basically, at Kinetic Con two years ago, we did this "Come and do your panel" panel, which is like...
Speaker 1: Like a panel gong show.
Speaker 1: Or panel auditions.
Speaker 0: And some guy came in, did this panel about Card Fight Vanguard, which is some collectible card game I never heard of before, and the way he presented it, I was like, "Oh, that game actually doesn't sound half bad for a collectible card
Speaker 0: game.".
Speaker 1: Guy did a good job.
Speaker 1: But then we started noticing it around.
Speaker 1: We saw a bunch of this...
Speaker 0: Yeah, then once I knew what it was, I started seeing it everywhere.
Speaker 0: And at PAX OZ, I saw it a lot compared to other places.
Speaker 0: I've seen it more there than anywhere else.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like once you see a bear in the woods, it's just bears everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Card Fight Vanguard is some sort of CCG.
Speaker 0: I still don't know how to play it, but it has all sorts of licensed properties amongst its cards.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's multiple anime, there's a manga, there's a live action.
Speaker 0: But it's like you can get Hatsune Miku cards up in there and shit.
Speaker 0: It's pretty crazy.
Speaker 1: You know what that is?
Speaker 1: It is what the Penny Arcade fighting system game was supposed to be.
Speaker 0: I guess, I don't know.
Speaker 0: But it's sort of... The system has like, you know, gigantic numbers, so it's a lot closer to like Yu-Gi-Oh!
Speaker 0: or some JRPG, where it's like, "5,000 damage,
Speaker 0: whoa!".
Speaker 0: So,
Speaker 1: my news is that you guys, if you care at all about this sort of industry, as opposed to just the fandom or whatever, but if you care about the industry, pay attention to this Vanguard thing, because it's got tentacles touching every aspect of anime and gaming in a big way.
Speaker 0: I feel like this is one of those things that's pretty big and nerdery outside the US, and is a little bit in the US, but is growing everywhere quite a bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think this is going to be simmering for a while, and then it's going to blindside a lot of people down the road.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this doesn't seem like one of those things that just like, you know, some side, you know, deal.
Speaker 0: It seems like a slow, low bubbler that just takes a long time to boil.
Speaker 1: So, the artist of Yu-Gi-Oh!
Speaker 1: R manga is doing a Vanguard manga called Card Fight Vanguard.
Speaker 0: That's what the name of the thing is.
Speaker 1: And Vertical licensed it to release it in the US.
Speaker 0: I guess they've recognized that it's gaining popularity.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: If Vertical licensed it and has noticed Vanguard enough to bother with this, then there's something going on, so keep an eye on all this business.
Speaker 0: But if you want to play a card game...
Speaker 1: Don't play this game.
Speaker 0: Play Netrunner.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Netrunner's your game.
Speaker 0: Don't play Card Fight.
Speaker 1: Well, first comment on Anime News Network.
Speaker 1: That's a really unusual grab.
Speaker 0: For Vertical?
Speaker 0: I mean, Vertical, you know, they're changing their game anyway.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't be surprised if Vertical was paid to license this.
Speaker 1: What the fuck is this?
Speaker 0: See?
Speaker 0: No one knows.
Speaker 0: I know what it is.
Speaker 0: We just know more than those people.
Speaker 1: So yeah, thank you, dude, for doing that panel at our gong show about Vanguard.
Speaker 1: So now we notice all the bears shitting in the woods.
Speaker 0: So everyone knows this already, right?
Speaker 0: But, you know, Miyazaki retired and everyone was like, "Oh, he's not actually going to
Speaker 0: retire.".
Speaker 0: We were totally right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well...
Speaker 0: He's making another manga.
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm pretty sure he said he was retiring from filmmaking.
Speaker 0: Sure, whatever.
Speaker 0: He's making another manga.
Speaker 0: I don't think he's made a manga that I know of since Nashika.
Speaker 0: I mean, maybe he's made some small ones, but he hasn't made, like, a major one since then.
Speaker 0: And that was forever ago.
Speaker 0: And the new one is all samurai and awesome, and there's some pictures of it, and people are freaking out when they see the pictures, because, oh my gosh, how could you not freak out looking at that?
Speaker 0: I freaked out also.
Speaker 0: And then people are basically just dying.
Speaker 0: I've seen tweets that are along the lines of, "All I want to do is read each page as he writes
Speaker 0: it."
Speaker 0: "I am only continuing to live my life so I can read this manga," and such and such.
Speaker 0: And... okay.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, really interesting.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: It's just, you know, that's the news.
Speaker 0: Because if you haven't heard that news, what rock were you living under?
Speaker 1: Yeah, guys, you shouldn't get your news from Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So, I did that Gemfire livestream.
Speaker 1: That's not my thing of the day, but because of it, I kind of got curious about Gemfire, because it's a really simple SNES game.
Speaker 1: It's in the genre of there's a map with a bunch of numbers, and you move guys around.
Speaker 1: Very Nobunga's Ambition.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, it's that kind of game, and it's pretty simple, but there's all this stuff in the game that as a kid I noticed, like all these icons that never made sense and weren't really explained, and all these hereditary things and complicated crests.
Speaker 1: The game had this really sort of apparent depth that had no bearing on the actual game.
Speaker 0: Like all the lore I never read.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this is in the SNES era where there was no lore to read.
Speaker 0: There's no memory to put any lore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the game was it, and there wasn't a supplementary thing that I could ever find.
Speaker 1: So, after doing the stream, I went to Game Facts, and good fucking god, I think Gemfire for the SNES wins the award for the most ridiculously complex bullshit that could come up in gameplay, but will never actually matter, and I can't believe people took the time to figure this shit out.
Speaker 1: They've had a while.
Speaker 1: So, here's an example.
Speaker 1: Characters, you know, you have vassals and lords and people and families and whatever.
Speaker 1: Characters have an age.
Speaker 1: It's pretty arbitrary.
Speaker 1: Most of the guys are like in their 20s, 30s, 40s.
Speaker 1: Some of them are in their teens.
Speaker 1: Doesn't matter at all.
Speaker 1: The game progresses through time.
Speaker 1: Turns out, the characters age.
Speaker 1: Like, their age goes up on their birthday every year.
Speaker 1: They can die of old age.
Speaker 0: The game will never be that long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you suck at this game, and you somehow beat it, and it takes you forever, it might take you maybe six or seven years to beat the game.
Speaker 0: No one will die unless they die in battle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, six, seven, maybe like ten or eleven years.
Speaker 1: Oh, they can't die in battle, for one.
Speaker 1: So, six to ten years maybe to beat this game.
Speaker 0: Shows how much I play Gemfire.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if someone makes it to the age of 75, every year from that time on, there's a random chance they'll die.
Speaker 1: And if the head of a family dies, then the crest of the family may change because someone in the family who is an heir to the throne, and there's icons that tell you who's the heir to what, can become the head of the family.
Speaker 0: Maybe you're supposed to play, and instead of playing just to win, just play to roleplay, and just slow roll it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, here's where this gets crazy.
Speaker 1: If you contrive a situation such that the heir to a family, the final heir to a family, is banished, or dies of old age, then the family disbands, and every person who's the highest rank in each property, like every person who controls one or more of the realms that you have control over, their family crest appears on the map, and they're now a new family that they're the head of.
Speaker 1: So you can break a family up with ridiculous contrived bullshit, form brand new families that have all their own lore and all their own shit, and then win the game with that, and there seems to be a dedicated subset of people on the internet who do this for fun.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: So, look at the-- Why don't you get one of their save games?
Speaker 1: Yeah, read through these game facts, and then look at the game, and try to reconcile in your brain between the two.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So, thing of the day, huh?
Speaker 0: Alright, Demeter.
Speaker 0: What's Demeter all about?
Speaker 1: Uh, the harvest and such?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know why they chose this name.
Speaker 1: Uh, what do you mean "they"?
Speaker 0: So, if you go to-- The Greeks?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's one thing-- The Greeks?
Speaker 1: You're saying why the Greeks-- No.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: My thing of the day chose this name.
Speaker 0: So, uh, you know, I'm not a fan of perfumes.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of places in New York that sell them to tourists, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like, you just want to make yourself smell like something?
Speaker 0: It's like, it's kind of weird.
Speaker 0: I mean, there are some perfumes that smell holy shit good.
Speaker 0: Well, I like-- And I enjoy smelling them, but I think it's kind of stupid to spend a zillion dollars on a good smell when you can just get a thing that smells good, like a food.
Speaker 1: Or get a cheaper perfume that smells the same, because no one can actually tell.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you want to smell like strawberries, just rub some strawberries on your ass.
Speaker 1: Oh, because that doesn't hold as-- anyway.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so this website, demeterfragrance.com, is a website where you can buy perfumes, gels, oils, things that smell, right?
Speaker 0: And they have, you know, typical, you know, kind of things, right?
Speaker 0: But all of their smells seem to be branded in some way.
Speaker 0: So, for example, right now they're advertising the Nigel Barker Signature Fragrance Collection, which has smells such as "Nigel Barker," which I guess smells like a dog?
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: Or-- Right, Times Square, that's supposed to smell like tourists, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I imagine it smells like some combination of urine and tourists.
Speaker 0: Sure, but they have lots of, you know, in addition to all these normal smells like cranberry lotion, not too weird, they've got things like fuzzy navel, or pizza, or pumpkin pie.
Speaker 0: So it's pretty much that, you know, what's that soda company that always has-- Joan Soda?
Speaker 0: It's the Joan Soda of perfume.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, remember that year where we got that Joan Soda and we were like-- They've got Hello Kitty perfumes, they've got Elvira, Mistress of the Dark perfumes, Tootsie Roll, officially licensed perfumes.
Speaker 0: I guess if you want to smell like a Tootsie Roll, or a slice of pizza, or who knows?
Speaker 0: So this shit is cray cray.
Speaker 0: I kind of want-- I don't want to pay any money for any of this, but they do have 100% money back guaranteed, no questions asked, so maybe I should buy some, smell them, and send them back just because I want to see what they smell like.
Speaker 0: I'm sure we will-- I think it's like the Jelly Belly of perfumes.
Speaker 1: I'm sure we'll encounter some of this at convention dealers' rooms at some point.
Speaker 0: They're promoting their candy cane truffle, so seasonal.
Speaker 1: Huh.
Speaker 1: You know what, actually, you've got to cross-brand that with Adventure Time, and make all the different princesses.
Speaker 1: Smell-- oh man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I tell you what.
Speaker 0: What does Lumpy Space Princess smell like?
Speaker 1: I know one old man who's going to be first in line.
Speaker 0: He's like, "Ah, I smell even more like Lumpy Space Princess than I usually
Speaker 0: do."
Speaker 0: With his Lumpy Space Princess perfume.
Speaker 1: So because my Thing of the Day was tedious and it's a lot of text, I have a secondary Thing of the Day for you people with short attention spans.
Speaker 1: It's a nine-second video of the most terrible toaster in the world.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: In a moment.
Speaker 0: The Book Club book is-- Aye-da-doo, by William Gibson.
Speaker 0: A classic.
Speaker 0: I didn't even start.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: You're going to go to Istanbul.
Speaker 0: I'll have plenty of time to read it.
Speaker 1: I'll have it done on-- Already.
Speaker 0: You had it done already.
Speaker 1: I know, but it's been a long time since I read this book, so I'm going to read it again.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So anyway, we can do the episode real soon.
Speaker 1: then, instead of having a huge, long time between the-- Yeah, I don't know why we had such a long time before.
Speaker 1: I can't imagine what happened there.
Speaker 0: Anyway, maybe we could even do a Book Club book every Thursday episode.
Speaker 0: No, won't happen.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I'm at a moment.
Speaker 1: Watch our live streams, watch our videos.
Speaker 1: Come see us at MagFest, which is coming up real soon.
Speaker 0: No shows next week because I will, ironically-- There will be a lack of shows between now and December.
Speaker 0: There's going to be more than one show, but less than full number of shows because holidays in the United States-- And then MagFest and then recovery from MagFest.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: In January, there will be a return to full showness until-- Full show consequences.
Speaker 0: Until PAX East.
Speaker 1: But I'm going to be, ironically, in Turkey over Thanksgiving, so I'm going to miss out on all the--.
Speaker 1: --Thanksgivica that's going on because it's really not a holiday anywhere, but North America.
Speaker 0: That's a shame.
Speaker 1: It's fine.
Speaker 1: It'll be worth it.
Speaker 1: It's going to be in chill time over there in Turkey.
Speaker 1: You can hang out.
Speaker 0: Enjoy your no-turkey eating.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: I think-- You're going to go find an American hotel that will serve a Thanksgiving dinner?
Speaker 1: I think as I'm sitting at a five-star restaurant overlooking the Bosphorus, drinking wine, and just enjoying the silent, breathtaking view of one of the most historic and notable rivers in the world, eating the fanciest, finest food with my own sommelier, I think I'll be okay.
Speaker 0: I think I'll be in my apartment gazing out over the most important city of the world, the capital of the world, eating Thanksgiving leftovers, which are more delicious than anything in any restaurant ever.
Speaker 1: Yes, and you know what I'm not going to miss?
Speaker 1: Thanksgiving leftovers.
Speaker 1: That shit's going to be waiting for me when I get home.
Speaker 0: Will it?
Speaker 0: From where?
Speaker 1: Up, Emily.
Speaker 0: Yeah, where's she going to get it from?
Speaker 1: Thanksgivings.
Speaker 0: Which Thanksgiving's she going to?
Speaker 1: People other than you have relatives.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, sure.
Speaker 0: But they don't have the same leftovers that I have.
Speaker 1: What is this?
Speaker 1: Okay, I got distracted by-- I'm watching drama in a thread related to a convention that's popping up in my Google Glass.
Speaker 0: Why are you doing that?
Speaker 1: Because it keeps popping up, and it's drama.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: It's funny drama.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So yeah, Scott and I have each seen an anime that the other one has not seen.
Speaker 0: Right, we do one anime each.
Speaker 0: That way, the episode's real easy-like, and we don't have to sit here going, "All right, what have we both
Speaker 0: seen?".
Speaker 0: "All
Speaker 0: right.".
Speaker 1: We were going to both do the thing that Scott saw, but-- But Rin didn't watch it.
Speaker 1: I went-- I fell asleep instead of watching it last night.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was tired.
Speaker 0: You even finished gaming early.
Speaker 0: We had plenty of time.
Speaker 1: I know, but you know what I did instead?
Speaker 1: I played Wizards and Warriors.
Speaker 0: You just kept playing it?
Speaker 1: I'm going to livestream Wizards and Warriors now that-- How much did you get, far?
Speaker 1: Not much further than I got before.
Speaker 1: That fucking lava, fuck that.
Speaker 0: You need to get the lava boot.
Speaker 1: When I play through again, I'm not getting that goddamn horn.
Speaker 0: The horn?
Speaker 0: The thing is, in the next level, you're going to want that horn, because it reveals the secrets.
Speaker 1: I am keeping my boots, because the boots are better than anything.
Speaker 0: If you reveal the secrets, you can get the magic wand, whatever thing.
Speaker 1: Don't care.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Don't care.
Speaker 1: My knife skills will see me through the night.
Speaker 0: Mad treasures.
Speaker 1: That game sucks, dogs.
Speaker 1: It is mad hard and not fun, but anyway.
Speaker 1: So, your anime.
Speaker 0: My anime.
Speaker 0: So, this is anime I've been thinking about watching, because it's about bikes.
Speaker 0: It's called Yoamushi Pedal, which is about bicycling, and Yoamushi, Emily says, means weakling.
Speaker 0: So, it's like weakling pedal, right?
Speaker 0: What's it about?
Speaker 0: It's about an otaku.
Speaker 0: He goes to high school.
Speaker 0: He's an otaku who has no friends, but he's not a bad guy.
Speaker 0: He's not that guy.
Speaker 0: He just likes animes and likes mangas and likes capsule toys and such and such.
Speaker 0: He likes to sing anime theme songs, but he doesn't have any friends, even though he's not socially inept.
Speaker 0: He's just introverted, and he goes to high school, and he bikes to high school, right, on his stupid, you know, one-gear old lady bike, and when he gets there, he tries to join an anime club.
Speaker 0: Anime club's closed.
Speaker 0: Not enough nerds.
Speaker 1: Ha.
Speaker 0: No nerds, and he was totally, all he wanted to do, it was like us going to RIT.
Speaker 0: He's like, "Finally, there's going to be some nerds.
Speaker 0: I'll have friends.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: No.".
Speaker 0: But, much like Takumi of Initial D, right, in that Takumi magically gained car racing skills by delivering tofu, this kid, his name is Onoda Sakamichi, right, he biked all the way to Akihabara every week on his shitty bike, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, and does he have the cadence of the gods?
Speaker 0: He has the cadence, because basically, when he was very, he got the bike when he was like in fourth grade or some shit, right?
Speaker 0: And his parents didn't want him to go very fast, so his mom changed his front gear to a small one, thinking, "Oh, he'll just go to the train station and then take the train to
Speaker 0: Akihabara.".
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: He biked with the tiny gear all the way there and back really fast, so he had the cadence of the gods.
Speaker 0: And when he gets to school, there's a bike racing club that Siri is biz, and there's a nice girl who works at the bike shop that her brother runs and her family owns who used to go to the school, and all these people, they notice him, because they see him biking up the back hill of the school, which is the crazy hill, and he was biking up it comfortably while singing an anime theme song, and someone saw him do that and was like, "Whoa,
Speaker 0: snap!".
Speaker 0: And then, you know, they discover that he likes, he's good at biking, and he discovers he likes biking, and it's the most generic anime in the entire universe.
Speaker 0: I have never seen an anime more average and generic than this anime.
Speaker 1: Is it the initial D of biking without music?
Speaker 0: It is the initial D of biking with better animation and no music.
Speaker 1: Like, "Oh, look at his dual-braking technique, front-back, he's
Speaker 1: alternating.".
Speaker 0: That hasn't happened yet.
Speaker 0: So far, it's been like, "Raise your seat up, oh snap,".
Speaker 0: or, "I installed a front derailleur on your bike, oh my god, I changed gears,".
Speaker 0: or, "Get behind me, the wind is
Speaker 0: coming.".
Speaker 0: All that, right?
Speaker 1: Just like initial D, "Wow, he's doing a drift, yes, his car is a front wheeled drive,
Speaker 1: therefore.".
Speaker 0: Now, the only thing I can say about this show that actually makes it a little bit not as good as initial D, besides lack of music, is the pacing is slower, right?
Speaker 0: There was just a whole episode where all they did was bike to catch up to a yakuza driving in his rice car so that they could throw a cigarette butt back into the window.
Speaker 0: That was an entire episode.
Speaker 0: The show moves so slowly, right?
Speaker 0: It's like in the opener, it's like you see him with a helmet, and he's got a new road bike, and not his old lady bike.
Speaker 0: You know the show's going there, right?
Speaker 0: To where he's going to join the bike club and race, and he's going to make friends with all these people, right?
Speaker 0: But I'm already on episode four, and he hasn't even met more than two bike club people, and he's not in the bike club, and he doesn't have a helmet, and he doesn't have a new bike yet, and he's just like, "Oh my god, this thing's gonna-".
Speaker 1: Well, there are 12 episodes announced so far.
Speaker 0: Right, well, so far there's seven on Crunchyroll, so this thing better pick up the goddamn pace, because it's not going anywhere right now.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh, episode eight is entitled Sprint Climb, get some uphill action.
Speaker 0: So I wish it would move along faster, it might be more interesting, but I think what it comes down to is because this show is just so exactly average anime, 100%, not bad, not good, just cookie cutter anime- So sea level anime.
Speaker 0: To the maximum, it is the cookie cutter anime.
Speaker 0: If you care about bikes, you should watch it.
Speaker 0: If you don't care about bikes, and you don't wanna start caring about bikes, don't watch it.
Speaker 0: So here's my question.
Speaker 0: It's not worth your time.
Speaker 1: Is it accurate, at least, the bike stuff?
Speaker 0: It is 100% realistic, no supernatural nonsense whatsoever in terms of bikes.
Speaker 0: The only thing that is not accurate is that some of the bikes, they change the brand names.
Speaker 0: Like the guy with the Trek, it says like,
Speaker 0: "Trac.".
Speaker 0: And the guy with the Scott bike, it says,
Speaker 0: "Skult.".
Speaker 1: You know what that tells me?
Speaker 1: It tells me that this is not going to be, or never was as popular as, Initial D. Because Initial D was the cars.
Speaker 1: From day one.
Speaker 0: If you ... Clearly, whoever made this is a bike nerd, though, right?
Speaker 1: You know what would be a good thing to do?
Speaker 1: Make a super cut of all the bike advice from this show, and turn that into a, "Listen, shithead.
Speaker 1: Here's how to use your goddamn
Speaker 1: bike.".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: But yeah.
Speaker 1: So Emily and I saw the last screening in Manhattan of The Wind Rises, Hayao Miyazaki's last movie.
Speaker 0: Quote last, last movie.
Speaker 1: We'll do a full review later.
Speaker 1: Emily and I have seen it.
Speaker 1: Scott hasn't yet.
Speaker 0: I'll definitely see it before I die.
Speaker 1: The one thing I can say is that, as we say with every anime movie that isn't just a Pokemon One Piece sequel.
Speaker 0: You should see it.
Speaker 1: No matter what.
Speaker 0: There aren't too many of these.
Speaker 1: If you like anime, you should watch every anime movie that comes out.
Speaker 0: Except for the Pokemon ones.
Speaker 0: And maybe even those.
Speaker 1: Every anime movie that comes out that does not have a number in the title.
Speaker 0: One Piece movie 20.
Speaker 1: Though even then, there's the one that was done by Hosoda that we reviewed, The Baron Omatsuri.
Speaker 0: Which I didn't really like that much.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: I didn't like it either.
Speaker 1: But it was memorable.
Speaker 0: I like One Piece TV more than that.
Speaker 1: You think that.
Speaker 1: Try watching it again.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: But the thing is, One Piece manga, it's like.
Speaker 0: I liked it when it moved along, and I didn't like it when it didn't move along.
Speaker 1: I just want happy pirates that move quickly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that that happened in parts of the TV and the manga.
Speaker 1: So the wind rises.
Speaker 1: If you don't know anything about it, it is a huge departure from what any casual fan of anime would expect a Miyazaki movie to be.
Speaker 0: It is about.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: It is not even similar to Poco Rosso or anything.
Speaker 1: So it shares some similarities to Poco Rosso, but it's historical drama.
Speaker 1: It is a fiction.
Speaker 0: So it's Poco Rosso plus Grave of the Fireflies.
Speaker 1: This is a fictionalization of the life of a real person.
Speaker 1: OK, controversial person, Jiro Horikoshi, a fighter jet or fighter jet fighter plane designer for Japan, Imperial Japan, World War Two.
Speaker 1: You know, the guy whose prototypes led to the development of the zero and obviously controversial for all the reasons that should be eminently obvious.
Speaker 0: Well, he's can't be.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah, obviously.
Speaker 0: But I mean, is the guy who designed the F-15 controversial?
Speaker 0: So is it any different?
Speaker 1: That's kind of what this movie is about, actually, right?
Speaker 1: Because the story of the movie is that he has this dream as a kid.
Speaker 1: and the dream is about Giovanni Battista Caproni, Italiano, who basically did the same thing that Jiro did for Italy and World War One and made the Red Baron's plane.
Speaker 1: The running theme is that Caproni and Jiro both did the same thing.
Speaker 1: They ignored but were aware of the ramifications and uses of what they were building, the war machines they were building, because their dream was to make beautiful flying machines.
Speaker 1: And there is no way to make them except to make them for people who will use them for bad things.
Speaker 0: What if you make them for people who will deliver the mail with them?
Speaker 1: There weren't people like that who would give you the opportunity to make them.
Speaker 0: Oh, what about in France, L'Arpostare?
Speaker 1: Yeah, when did that happen?
Speaker 1: And where did the original planes come from?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm just saying.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So the movie is beautiful.
Speaker 1: The movie, if I have to sell you on the movie.
Speaker 0: What Ghibli movie is not beautiful?
Speaker 0: Even stupid Earthies are beautiful.
Speaker 1: And one notable thing I want to bring up about it is that the soundscape, the foley, the sound design is is like something I've never heard before.
Speaker 1: I could never.
Speaker 0: How could that be possible?
Speaker 1: A sound that people all of the sound effects in this movie are humans doing the helicopter blade, helicopter blade, helicopter blade thing.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: Yeah, literally.
Speaker 1: The sound effects are like when planes explode and things happen, it's people going.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: That sounds dumb.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that can't be true.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So watch the movie and you'll see what I mean.
Speaker 0: Did they filter it heavily to make it?
Speaker 1: They filtered it enough, but it is obvious that it is humans.
Speaker 1: And there's a sort of undercurrent that is backed up both by the sound design and the way planes are drawn and the way people dream about planes.
Speaker 1: That planes, the planes there.
Speaker 0: Is the whole thing like someone reading a storybook?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: And that's why it makes it?
Speaker 1: The plane is a literal, here is Japan.
Speaker 1: It starts with the Kanto earthquake.
Speaker 1: It ends with the end of his life, post World War Two.
Speaker 1: And it shows all the areas of Japan accurately, historically, accurately.
Speaker 1: And he is sort of floating through this world dreaming of making these planes.
Speaker 1: You could argue that the planes are literally, in a sense, made out of the blood of the bodies of the people who are killed by them.
Speaker 1: And the sound design being people and the planes being made of people kind of drives and drives and drives to this point.
Speaker 0: I get it.
Speaker 1: And yeah.
Speaker 1: And there's something, Caproni says something, you know, the Italian designer to the effect of, see this plane?
Speaker 1: That's the beautiful plane I made that was used as a fighter, a bomber.
Speaker 1: None of them came back.
Speaker 1: Toward the end, you see the planes that Jiro designed that were used in World War Two, and he says the same thing.
Speaker 1: And that is what this movie is about.
Speaker 1: And I don't want to say anything else because it's a Miyazaki movie.
Speaker 1: There's no reason not to see it.
Speaker 1: But it is the most complex movie Miyazaki has ever made, in my opinion.
Speaker 1: And it was amazing and soul crushing at the same time.
Speaker 0: I wonder who did make that 15.
Speaker 0: Do you know?
Speaker 0: Is it a 15?
Speaker 0: Is it a person that we know?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But it's complicated because this the movie doesn't even like.
Speaker 1: Hitler is mentioned in this movie.
Speaker 1: He meets at one point this German guy who fled from Germany and he has this whole conversation with the guys like Japan is going to explode.
Speaker 1: Germany is going to explode.
Speaker 1: None of this is going to end.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 1: And you see the rise of Imperial Japan and the rise of fascism.
Speaker 1: And it all just kind of rises around him.
Speaker 1: The wind rises.
Speaker 1: You have no choice but to be blown over by it or to survive it and to survive it.
Speaker 1: You have to sort of go along with it.
Speaker 1: There's sort of this undercurrent implied that had he resisted this, the planes would have been made anyway by someone else.
Speaker 1: The wars would have happened anyway.
Speaker 1: And his choice was to die or make these dreams come true, even though those dreams will kill people, because the people will be killed anyway.
Speaker 1: The wind rises.
Speaker 1: You can't stop it.
Speaker 1: It's sort of undercurrent almost that the Kanto earthquake and the military, at least if you're in that position, you could equally inevitable from the position of an individual person.
Speaker 0: Well, from that person.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: There's someone else who could be ever could have done something right.
Speaker 0: But he couldn't.
Speaker 1: So it's a complex movie.
Speaker 1: And you should all see it.
Speaker 1: If you were fans of anime, we'll do a sort of deeper review once Scott's seen it, too, and maybe we'll do a three way, an awkward three way, like in our Burning Wheel game last night.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: The party at this girl's house.
Speaker 0: I think we're cool because my stamps always help her out.
Speaker 0: She is fine, but her friends are kind of this and thatness.
Speaker 0: But with me, I better help her find her in her Katniss.
Speaker 0: So I dance with my manager Vance asking if I could just get a friendly payment in advance.
Speaker 0: He blows me off, so I scoffed on my smock, check the clock, take it off, check my wad, feeling soft.
Speaker 0: All I got is 5.45 and it's 5.45, got to get a whopper and a 40 right.
Speaker 0: Well, I got 5.45 and it's 5.45, got to get a whopper and a 40 right.