Speaker 0: It's Monday April 8th 2013.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We're talking about the distribution of high bandwidth data.
Speaker 0: exciting exciting times.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: It's real good to not be coughing up my lung.
Speaker 0: I'm post flu.
Speaker 1: Geek night says return we're back.
Speaker 0: until I might go to Turkey.
Speaker 0: We got anime Boston coming up got to finish our five.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess four panels because the fifth one Might be a rerun of one we've run in the past and I don't know.
Speaker 0: almost every convention we go to.
Speaker 0: yeah So yeah, if you're into anime openers from around the world dogs, I have not updated that shit at all.
Speaker 0: So today I go to work, you know I'm finally like not sick and in my office and doing my thing and When my co-workers comes up and he's like, yeah, we can't go out of the building.
Speaker 0: There's a bomb.
Speaker 1: Okay, so yeah, they like shut down the whole street and if only you had been there You could have opened that bag and saved the bombs.
Speaker 1: quite all that money.
Speaker 0: I want someone out there to make this for me.
Speaker 0: I want to make a see something.
Speaker 0: shut the fuck up.
Speaker 0: it's probably someone's underwear and Spray-paint that or put it on top of this.
Speaker 0: see something say something signs.
Speaker 1: if you see something to see something open it.
Speaker 0: See something.
Speaker 0: don't be a pussy open that shit.
Speaker 0: It's someone's underwear.
Speaker 1: save us all a lot of goddamn time.
Speaker 0: So this time I'm like, alright, whatever.
Speaker 0: so I was actually wanting to go get coffee.
Speaker 0: So I go downstairs and of course You can't go out the front of the building because the streets all blocked off the service entrance.
Speaker 0: So I just walked off the walk out the other Completely normal entrance on the other side of the building.
Speaker 0: that I guess no one is paying attention to of course And I did my business and by the time I came back everything's gone and I see a cop.
Speaker 0: He's just kind of standing there and I'm like, so what was in the bag?
Speaker 0: and he looks at me and he Smirks and he says and I quote two bricks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm like what he's like.
Speaker 0: it was a bag with two fucking bricks in it.
Speaker 0: Here's like just bricks.
Speaker 0: and he was like, well, there was a rolled-up newspaper too, but there wasn't anything in the newspaper.
Speaker 0: So I was like, so why - he's like, I don't know.
Speaker 1: How does a bag of two bricks in a newspaper even fucking And you know what?
Speaker 0: It wasn't even in front of our building.
Speaker 0: It was in front of the staples.
Speaker 0: So I guess someone wanted to send a message to staples that they're not gonna take these bricks anymore.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm so sick of the see something.
Speaker 0: say something cuz there's it's never something That's right.
Speaker 1: If you see something shut the fuck up and save us all a lot of hassle.
Speaker 0: If you see like a dude with a gun Doing something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because okay.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: All right, if you see like a guy You should probably tell someone here's the problem is it's yeah.
Speaker 1: If you see something say something a bag laying in the street is not something that's it's the something part is the problem, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you see something say something but you know what.
Speaker 1: something is not a blade of grass not a bag.
Speaker 0: something is Scott Scott if I if you see a fire a blade of great a blade go by something is a guy going crazy.
Speaker 1: Right something is you know Scott.
Speaker 0: What if I'm watertight a fire?
Speaker 1: Right something is Some dangerous shit.
Speaker 1: a dude with a dangerous weapon who is not a military or police person, right?
Speaker 1: That is a something.
Speaker 0: well Something what about all those open carry states where there's those assholes walking around with like an ar-15 just openly just like yeah It's my right.
Speaker 0: It's my right Cuz then you can't even say something about that.
Speaker 1: That's not even something right.
Speaker 1: It's a difference between that guy just walking in the street with it slung over his back And a guy walking down the street amazing people going holding it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like in Israel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everyone's fucking got ar-15s walking around everywhere right from military people.
Speaker 0: If you sing really the hobo whitey song the shotgun then you might want to say something right.
Speaker 1: You know, it's an Israeli walk down the street.
Speaker 1: Everyone's got friggin m16s everywhere, right?
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 1: It's not something cuz.
Speaker 1: no one's holding them ready to shoot.
Speaker 1: They just all got him on their back like it's you know, or an umbrella or something.
Speaker 0: But that is not my opening bit.
Speaker 0: My opening bit is that Amazon fucked up for me in a pretty amazing way.
Speaker 0: Okay, it was a confluence of multiple fuck-ups that it I couldn't even use their automated like.
Speaker 0: something's wrong with my order thing.
Speaker 0: I had to talk to a human being.
Speaker 0: Okay, and the human being had to investigate and then deal with it.
Speaker 1: They usually just tell you to keep whatever they sent you if they fuck up.
Speaker 0: Oh, well legally I'm still entitled to keep the thing they sent me.
Speaker 0: that's true and I might cuz it's actually like $70 worth of Star Wars miniature game piece.
Speaker 1: Maybe someone bought it for you as a present.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I thought that that is not what happened.
Speaker 1: Okay, so how could you get this game that we know about that is a nerdy thing sent to you?
Speaker 0: So I got the Millennium Falcon.
Speaker 1: that seems like too much of a coincidence for a nerdy thing to be said.
Speaker 0: Yes, it does.
Speaker 0: This is why I was confused and it took some research to be able to go to Amazon and say yo guys Here's what I think happened.
Speaker 0: I've done the research deal with it because when I went to them the first time they were like says your package is delivered.
Speaker 0: I'm like, yeah, that's why I'm trying to contact you it.
Speaker 0: I don't have the items I ordered.
Speaker 0: they're like, but it was delivered and I was like, well, you see not really but kind of.
Speaker 0: so Yeah, so I got slave one first.
Speaker 0: I was like did Matt Morgan or someone send me this Game?
Speaker 1: if I wasn't playing netrunner, I'd be playing that game.
Speaker 0: That's kind of shady shit.
Speaker 1: I saw some guys play in that game at PAX East.
Speaker 1: They look pretty good.
Speaker 0: You imagine like, you know we could do.
Speaker 0: we could find a friend who we know would get addicted to netrunner and just mail It to them just mammal corset.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just be like start sending out corsets to everyone Yeah, and then they'll be stuck buying all the expansion.
Speaker 0: So at first I was like, oh, I guess someone sent me this.
Speaker 0: I wonder if it was Matt cuz.
Speaker 0: he's the most into this of anyone.
Speaker 0: I know who knows my address But it had like no note in it.
Speaker 0: No nothing.
Speaker 1: Usually there's a note on the white receipt that says yeah Nothing the gift and mess.
Speaker 0: So I just set it on the table and ignored it and then like a week later It's like wait a minute.
Speaker 0: I ordered something on Amazon that never arrived.
Speaker 1: What did you order that never arrived ahem?
Speaker 0: So what I ordered on Amazon that never was it netrunner cuz.
Speaker 1: that's when the same company it actually was not.
Speaker 0: that would have Made a lot more sense.
Speaker 0: It was a completely unrelated order of the mosquito expansion For the hive the ladybug expansion for the hive nice a new Jimmy wallet cuz mine finally wore out and they don't seem to fucking Make him any solos in Amazon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't buy them from the Jimmy website anymore.
Speaker 0: I think they're done.
Speaker 0: Go to the Jimmy website.
Speaker 0: They list almost everything is out of stock And if you actually try to order the things they list as in stock, you just get shopping cart errors.
Speaker 0: Store like it doesn't work.
Speaker 0: I know I I called the Jimmy number and no one answered.
Speaker 0: I went on Amazon.
Speaker 0: I found one dude.
Speaker 1: your shopping cart is empty.
Speaker 1: It is not orderable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so there's no guy.
Speaker 0: think they're gone.
Speaker 0: I think it's done.
Speaker 0: So that last Jimmy I tried to order two Jimmy's because I need one and I want.
Speaker 0: You know, it's an aside.
Speaker 0: but on Kickstarter, it seems like wallets are the most popular thing to kick start.
Speaker 0: There's like a million.
Speaker 0: I made a wall.
Speaker 1: I guess my next wallets gonna be a kick-started one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: I looked at every Like.
Speaker 0: they all are better.
Speaker 0: if I didn't know about the Jimmy They're pretty great compared to a normal wallet, but you know what?
Speaker 0: I've had a Jimmy.
Speaker 0: none of them come close.
Speaker 1: Why don't we make a wallet and he's better Jimmy and kick-start that?
Speaker 1: motherfucker?
Speaker 0: What would I change in the Jimmy?
Speaker 0: I would.
Speaker 0: it holds the right number of cards.
Speaker 0: I would have a separate slot to hold thin cards like Metro cards and things.
Speaker 0: that has exterior access Mmm, just for Metro car.
Speaker 1: You got it.
Speaker 1: We got to get designer industrial designer.
Speaker 0: We happen to know a few.
Speaker 1: Gee, that's like we know if you have everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, we don't know a few of that.
Speaker 0: I actually could really use a lawyer who is also a financial accountant Isn't?
Speaker 1: they had some sort of financial lawyer?
Speaker 0: ish he might charge money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what people do.
Speaker 0: We'll go into a joint business venture with me paid entirely in stock is actually a website.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it still exists But it's actually a pretty new website that comes close to my stack overflow of lawyers idea But not quite what it is.
Speaker 1: Is it sort of all these lawyers?
Speaker 1: It's almost like you know those websites you go to to hire tutors where they list like the qualifications and their hourly rate.
Speaker 1: It's like that for lawyers.
Speaker 1: you tell them where you are and what kind of lawyer you want and it shows you all these lawyers and all their rates like Hourly and people are like 20 minutes free, you know 30 bucks.
Speaker 0: well our.
Speaker 0: after that I actually kind of am in the market as it well as geek nights because Yamato SRL is escalating to the point that I might have to issue some full-on DMCA counter notifications at which point The only recourse they have is to actually sue us.
Speaker 1: I mean, let me search my delicious for so anyway.
Speaker 0: And I ordered a razor death adder black 3500 high-precision 3.5 G infrared gaming mouse.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with the gaming mouse?
Speaker 0: You have steel series X AI fucking broke.
Speaker 1: How did it break?
Speaker 0: I wore it the fuck out.
Speaker 1: How could it be worn the fuck out?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the fire button does not a hundred percent reliably click anymore, which literally my counter strike Performance dropped off about 80%.
Speaker 0: Like one day I was playing counter-strike and I just wasn't like.
Speaker 0: my kill ratio was one to one instead of my like five To one.
Speaker 0: I'm like, what the fuck I'm doing terribly.
Speaker 0: So I go into a server where no one's there and I go to a wall and I go click click click click click.
Speaker 0: And it went shoot shoot nothing shoot Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So I did some testing and yeah, the fire button is unreliable now and the cord frayed the fuck up and I had to Fix it with tape.
Speaker 0: So I'm never buying a steel series mouse again.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure any mouse you get will have that happen.
Speaker 1: If you know this war you seem to like breaking your things on purpose to have an excuse to buy replacements I bought a less good mouse.
Speaker 0: I bought a cheaper less high-quality gamer mouse to replace this one.
Speaker 1: So I found the lawyer website.
Speaker 1: It's called lawn law Dingo and you can go there and get simple questions answered cheap and you can also browse lawyers to find a lawyer That is can help you with whatever your dingo eat your.
Speaker 1: and the thing is, you know, normally it's like Who's gonna trust this website?
Speaker 1: Well, it's not really the website.
Speaker 1: You have to trust its lawyer, right?
Speaker 1: And the thing is I sort of feel confident in this because any lawyer on here is a lawyer who is Internet II enough to put themselves on here and
Speaker 0: also not doing well enough to where they have real Clients to such a degree that they don't they have time for this bullshit Meaning.
Speaker 0: they'll probably actually work with me and they might be cool enough to talk to me Maybe.
Speaker 1: but yeah, I mean, you know, you can't hurt yourself by just calling someone on the phone if you see them on the site Right.
Speaker 1: What's the worst they can happen?
Speaker 1: They're a fake.
Speaker 0: They're a real lawyer.
Speaker 0: they send you an invoice for the five minutes of their time at $900 an hour.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so yeah law dingo, I guess try it out.
Speaker 1: See how it works.
Speaker 1: room You can review it for us.
Speaker 0: I'm not at the point of lowering up yet, but I'm preparing to lawyer out because Usually when companies file stupid lawsuits on copyright the people About anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah The people in the right usually don't have the ability to fight and I never fault someone who does not have the ability to fight.
Speaker 0: Not fighting but whoa betide you come after me and Scott because we've got enough money and enough righteous indignation to burn.
Speaker 1: Usually the way it works is it's like let's say someone sues me, right?
Speaker 1: Well, I could win but if I win it'll cost me all my moneys to win and I'll basically lose even though I was.
Speaker 1: If I lose, of course, I also lose a whole bunch, but if I just settle with them, I give them a little bit of money I don't die, but they get free money, but even if they're wrong, so the question to always ask is are you right?
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: If I feel that I am right like if I'm wrong, I'll just admit I'm wrong, right?
Speaker 1: But if I feel that I'm right, which I usually do because I'm not gonna do something I think is wrong I will set myself on fire to get justice and I hope one that threat will scare people away and Two and two it'll be fun.
Speaker 1: I actually will set myself I will burn all my money and go bankrupt if you come after me, right and you're wrong Yeah, and I think you're wrong.
Speaker 1: So watch out anyone trying to sue me because I will take it all the way.
Speaker 0: So This package did not arrive, but it said delivered.
Speaker 0: and I had this other mysterious package that arrived on the day.
Speaker 0: They said that one was delivered.
Speaker 0: So first I look and the tracking numbers match.
Speaker 0: That's the crazy thing.
Speaker 1: They probably just put the wrong label on the wrong box.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they will.
Speaker 1: so they see someone else out there who ordered his x-wing fate miniatures.
Speaker 0: He's also a nerd.
Speaker 0: But in that box was an invoice With the price and everything and it was more money than my other order for these Star Wars pieces.
Speaker 0: Nice and a different order ID from my order.
Speaker 0: I had to explain all of this information to Amazon so many times for them to finally be like, oh Like maybe we sent you the wrong package.
Speaker 0: I was like, yes That's nice This order ID that or ID copy paste.
Speaker 1: I guess you get to keep this and they're gonna send you the new.
Speaker 0: well They're sending me a shipping label to send this back really interesting.
Speaker 0: And they already gave me a refund for the order that they didn't send.
Speaker 1: so you guys reorder that.
Speaker 0: I have to reorder it Manually because they no longer have the ability to resend orders that fail apparently Mm-hmm because most of their art most of the things people order are from third-party resellers and not from them direct.
Speaker 0: Or it's them doing fulfillment and the order IDs change and it was a giant pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: Thanks Amazon for fucking up and doing.
Speaker 0: I actually really need this gaming mouse like I'm.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm not a new mouse doing well in counter-strike.
Speaker 1: I bought the logitech.
Speaker 1: I bought a new mouse for work.
Speaker 1: I bought a new egg Logitech yeah new egg.
Speaker 0: I like the razor death adder because it's got the shape that I like of mine.
Speaker 1: I don't like any weird mice.
Speaker 1: I get these the default logitech mouse.
Speaker 1: That's the one that everyone Like mice.
Speaker 0: I have a little too much of a hump.
Speaker 1: not that it's the.
Speaker 1: you know It's the gaming mouse that everyone uses.
Speaker 1: the what's it called?
Speaker 0: I don't like humps.
Speaker 0: I like.
Speaker 0: I basically like pucks.
Speaker 1: You're crazy.
Speaker 0: I also need a thumb button Anyway at home.
Speaker 1: I have the g500 but at work.
Speaker 0: I have the g something else I really like my steel series, but it wore out way too quick.
Speaker 0: for how much money I spent on this fucker Whatever?
Speaker 1: Okay, okay Let's do some newses, so what do you got?
Speaker 1: so this is company called ario?
Speaker 1: I don't know if anyone's heard of them.
Speaker 1: We may have mentioned them before.
Speaker 1: I actually there's a billboard for them right outside on the Not right outside the window, but over by the subway where the end sort of starts to turn.
Speaker 1: It's like right in that area.
Speaker 0: I guess I never noticed.
Speaker 1: yeah, so what ario does is they set up TV antennas and catch oh?
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: I know who this.
Speaker 1: they catch the over-the-air TV, and you can pay them money And they will send you over the internet the over-the-air TV that you should be getting.
Speaker 1: so let's say you live in an apartment.
Speaker 1: It's really hard to set up a good antenna, but you're in a space like your apartment is in, New York.
Speaker 1: You're entitled to those free over-the-air channels that are the radio waves of which are penetrating your apartment, right?
Speaker 1: You were supposed to be able to watch those for free legally.
Speaker 1: so what ario does is they put up an antenna for you.
Speaker 1: They catch the TV and Then they stream those TV stations over the internet to you for a small fee.
Speaker 0: now one I would argue not giving any money to the TV stations themselves, and you know what I am totally okay with that.
Speaker 1: And the court is seems to also at.
Speaker 1: the court case is obviously far from over.
Speaker 1: Yeah But so far ario is winning.
Speaker 0: what I've read from brief summaries of this is that it Part of this is hinging around the fact that Fox Can't prove any harm to them because they're giving it away for free.
Speaker 1: another thing He was judge also pointed out how you know they're not letting people watch TV stations from far away.
Speaker 1: It's all.
Speaker 1: you only get the ones that would be available in the spot that you live yeah, and you only get it for you.
Speaker 1: It's not like.
Speaker 1: you know you can do it, and then you know have people all crazy places You know start watching you can with a sling boxers.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying right because I Know that's not the point right.
Speaker 1: so the judge is like yeah, I see nothing wrong with this right.
Speaker 0: This is just an extension of the recent Re-emergence of the weird debate over Whether or not it's okay to block ads on the internet right the same thing It's no.
Speaker 0: once you in my opinion if you provide content in a way That is actually free and available then people have the right to consume that content however They wish.
Speaker 1: well, we're gonna get back to that in a second with my second news right, but anyway.
Speaker 1: so the area news number one.
Speaker 1: You got two.
Speaker 1: area news isn't in the second news.
Speaker 1: yeah, so area news number one is that they're winning in court.
Speaker 1: area News number two is that Fox in response to the fact that they realized they were losing this is this is rich?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they said all right if we lose an area keeps operating We're just gonna stop broadcasting over the air and we'll go cable only with Fox.
Speaker 1: And you know I have to say to that awesome go for it right.
Speaker 1: yeah Because the Super Bowl is really gonna want to be broadcast on it.
Speaker 1: You know it's only people with cable.
Speaker 1: They're gonna know the NFL is not going to allow you to broadcast football games only on cable.
Speaker 0: five I think it'll.
Speaker 0: actually I don't.
Speaker 0: I'm hoping more and more that these companies that are so mad about anything related to internet distribution Actually do wall themselves off Just like all these news sites that are bit by bit Hiding behind paywalls.
Speaker 1: cuz actually the news sites are starting to come out of the paywall.
Speaker 0: a few of them are doubling down.
Speaker 1: I'm sure.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's kind of weird there.
Speaker 1: You know they're all trying different stuff.
Speaker 1: They're all dumb.
Speaker 0: Well the other thing is that the the area of business model?
Speaker 0: I'm not a lawyer.
Speaker 0: I am NOT a business analyst.
Speaker 0: This is a pure raw opinion, so don't come suing me for anything.
Speaker 0: I think it's the same basic business model as crunchyroll was originally.
Speaker 0: in my opinion.
Speaker 0: You know what this may or may not be legal.
Speaker 0: who gives a fuck?
Speaker 0: we're gonna do it anyway.
Speaker 0: We're a fight the lawsuits and we'll probably win and get a pile of money in the end.
Speaker 1: There's a guy.
Speaker 1: I don't I'm not sure where he is it, but he's basically.
Speaker 1: he's got a dish and He is rebroadcasting all the Mets games this year every single one right and he's basically adding value right to this number one.
Speaker 1: His stream is the best illegal sports stream.
Speaker 1: I've ever seen in terms of quality.
Speaker 1: It's ultra HD, and it doesn't lag at all ever - he's keeping it sort of private like I found out about it.
Speaker 1: so it's not that private, but he's pretty much keeping it with like a small group of Mets fans and He's building a community around it.
Speaker 1: So it's like when I when you go to this thing and I did it at work once when there was a day game last Week there's a chat room and everyone's chatting and there's maybe only 50 people watching.
Speaker 1: right and you're all watching this thing together.
Speaker 1: and when a commercial comes on he pushes a button to cover up the commercial and Show you like scores from around.
Speaker 1: that you know.
Speaker 1: and it's like because he's a fan of the same team as you Right not just some European guy rebroadcasting to make money on ads.
Speaker 1: He's just doing it out of the goodness, right?
Speaker 1: You know he's like.
Speaker 1: You know showing he's flipping to the games that like a Mets fan would care to see that aren't the Mets game And he's.
Speaker 1: you know it's.
Speaker 1: it's pretty much the awesomest.
Speaker 1: so I Hope more shit like this happens, and you know what.
Speaker 1: this is what the baseball people should be doing But they're not.
Speaker 1: they block.
Speaker 1: you know if I pay for MLB TV, which is actually not that expensive, right?
Speaker 1: I Can only watch out-of-market games.
Speaker 1: so if I'm in New York they don't let me watch the team I actually give a shit about.
Speaker 1: it's like yeah I'm not paying you any money for those other fucking teams.
Speaker 1: who gives a fuck.
Speaker 1: I don't want to watch Marlin's friggin Giants.
Speaker 1: fuck that shit right.
Speaker 1: I would give you that money if you only showed me the Mets game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but since those the only ones you don't show me.
Speaker 1: I guess you don't show me Yankees games either, but fuck those right.
Speaker 1: I'm paying you nothing and I'm gonna watch this illegal stream guy Who's also providing a happy community to watch with.
Speaker 1: you could do that, but you didn't.
Speaker 1: but you didn't I?
Speaker 0: Would pay and watch a lot of hockey if it was easier to watch hockey.
Speaker 1: Anyway news number two which relates to your point about ad blocking.
Speaker 1: right there are two incidents that have happened recently That are interesting.
Speaker 1: now with ad blocking Some website some server sends HTMLs to you, and then you're with your web browser.
Speaker 1: You decide what to do with those HTML.
Speaker 0: I mean in the old days like not everyone could display images some blind people have things transmitted in a different way, right?
Speaker 1: what if your ISP were to set up some sort of squid proxy server and Modify the HTMLs on their way to you?
Speaker 1: is that okay now?
Speaker 0: I would argue no Because I am paying for direct access to the internet to connect to people that I want to connect to directly.
Speaker 1: So there are two instances.
Speaker 0: instance number one I can name a lot more instances going back about a decade right now.
Speaker 1: instance number one is the not so bad instance But still troubling.
Speaker 1: Comcast has done a thing recently where if you're hitting near your bandwidth limit They'll basically insert a JavaScript a really shitty one into every page you visit.
Speaker 1: that will pop up a bandwidth limit Warning that tells you how much you have left and that you should stop internetting right, so That's not really the worst in the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm still not okay with it.
Speaker 0: Obviously it can be handled well you'd be.
Speaker 0: it's rare for me to say something like this.
Speaker 0: that is better handled by a text message or a phone call an application That will give you notifications on your computer if you should yeah, if you shouldn't have to install that yeah Call you or whatever or they should have reasonable prices and bandwidth policy.
Speaker 1: that's also true.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I digress but yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: number two There's apparently some small-ass ISP out in the middle of fuck nowhere and what they're doing is evil.
Speaker 0: They are inserting ads into major websites that don't belong there And that has happened so many times in the history of the internet.
Speaker 1: right and the company that does the ads Hasn't commented and it's shady shady shady.
Speaker 1: So it's they have screenshots like going to apple.com and there it is right at the bottom apple.com.
Speaker 0: fuck them Something else.
Speaker 0: the FCC destroys them and someone goes to jail.
Speaker 1: I don't know if the FCC would go after them.
Speaker 1: the guy called the FCC.
Speaker 1: They say they call the FTC.
Speaker 0: I was gonna say so.
Speaker 1: There's at least one guy who noticed this on his parents computers.
Speaker 1: He did all sorts of tests like SSL.
Speaker 1: it doesn't show up.
Speaker 1: That'd be like if my only age only shows up on major websites.
Speaker 0: Cable network was distributing the Super Bowl and when the Super Bowl ads came up.
Speaker 0: I showed my own ads.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean they do have some spots that are for the local cable channel.
Speaker 0: They do but that would be like if I was putting ads in other places, right?
Speaker 0: so That's all fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, really interesting stuff there.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, what do you have for news?
Speaker 0: so what I want to talk about?
Speaker 0: because I I Realized that the Streisand effect people use that term a lot on the internet.
Speaker 1: I was gonna use it for an April Fool's Day episode of geek nights, but our episode wasn't on.
Speaker 0: Hopefully we'll remember in a year or so, whatever.
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: So I want to bring this up because this is such an amazing example of the Streisand effect and it also Reiterates something that I've talked about a lot on geek nights that for all we complain about the United States We still pretty much even with a lot of our terrible copyright stuff that
Speaker 1: keeps getting worse
Speaker 0: have the freest Internet and free speech on the entire.
Speaker 1: is that the slowest?
Speaker 1: if we also had the fastest things would be Average.
Speaker 0: we have the slowest.
Speaker 0: I mean there there.
Speaker 1: I don't have this one of the slowest.
Speaker 1: we just have slow compared to other countries That are equal to us.
Speaker 0: At the same time if you ignore all of our rural areas and small markets and only look at our big markets We're in we're near the top.
Speaker 1: We're not No free in like in Netherlands.
Speaker 1: they have gigabit, right?
Speaker 0: But that bandwidth does not translate to the rest of the world.
Speaker 0: when they connect to things further away Like in the United States, they have a lot less bandwidth and a lot of content is still in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Korean's got it pretty fast.
Speaker 1: I think a lot Many megabits per person.
Speaker 0: They have a lot more local content than Scandinavia Japan a little faster than us.
Speaker 1: I think right many megabits wirelessly, right?
Speaker 0: But at the same time it really depends on where you look because there are neighborhoods in the?
Speaker 0: u.s.
Speaker 1: Japan and extremely fast internet and Japanese don't need area because their mobile phones can watch broadcast over-the-air television.
Speaker 0: That's the separate thing all together.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying but anyway this is some harsh shit and I already wasn't super happy with the government of France, but this goes to a new level.
Speaker 1: I never had with the government of France.
Speaker 0: what the some of the French government basically Contacted a random Wikipedia admin and their criteria Apparently for choosing this Wikipedia admin was they were able to identify the person's real name and address and that person lived in France.
Speaker 1: Okay, so they found the only Wikipedia admin with publicly available information who lives in France.
Speaker 0: And what they did is they basically took that person in and said delete this article about this military base in France or we will arrest you.
Speaker 1: So why that you know, they could have just deleted that article themselves.
Speaker 1: It's Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Um, I think the article had been deleted and it was reinstated because that's how it goes.
Speaker 1: It's called the tough shit rule.
Speaker 1: this admin apparently tried to explain to them The futility of this never mind the fact that this I would have been like, okay, I'll delete it Push the delete button and go home.
Speaker 1: So basically that's what they did in the end and and then of course it comes back in five minutes later came back.
Speaker 0: And now that is one of the most translated Wikipedia articles in the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah It is now in the English Wikipedia instead of just the French specific one.
Speaker 0: This military base is now a tourist destination.
Speaker 0: nerds have been showing up and taking as many pictures of it as they can.
Speaker 0: People everyone is talking about.
Speaker 1: this must be something going on there.
Speaker 0: You may not be old enough to remember who Barbra Streisand is.
Speaker 0: Park then, you know, uh, that's some pretty old South Park.
Speaker 1: Meka Streisand is old Meka Streisand.
Speaker 0: I would bet that at least a third of the kids who saw that episode have no idea what that's referencing.
Speaker 1: I I'm pretty sure that Barbra's I mean, I don't know famous people Scott, but I know Barbra Streisand is.
Speaker 0: we're 30.
Speaker 0: I Know for a fact based on a conversation I had at anime Boston two years ago that a lot of kids have never even heard of.
Speaker 1: like Celine Dion That's that Canadian lady who's in Vegas.
Speaker 1: Even I know who that is.
Speaker 1: Yeah Even I know who.
Speaker 1: that is not on who people are Scott.
Speaker 0: the internet today was abounding with people who?
Speaker 0: Hated or loved Margaret Thatcher, but don't seem to actually know who she was.
Speaker 1: Well, that's just people.
Speaker 1: when I noticed when people don't know something and that the first thing they read about it on the internet is Everything is suddenly You know law and they'll defend whatever that first thing they read was like dude breed.
Speaker 0: Bard really isn't the best place to go.
Speaker 1: It's like maybe one of our listeners right doesn't know who Barbra Streisand is.
Speaker 1: So if we say she's good, they'll say she's good and that'll be what they believe forever.
Speaker 1: And if we say she's bad, then that'll be what they believe.
Speaker 0: So guys Barbra Streisand is important for one reason.
Speaker 1: She you'll get that South Park joke.
Speaker 1: That's the important reason.
Speaker 0: there were pictures that she wanted not on the internet and not in newspapers.
Speaker 0: No one gave a shit about those pictures until she started trying to sue people to get them taken down.
Speaker 0: then the entire World cared about those photographs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz as soon as you say take those down everyone's like, oh someone wants the pictures taken down.
Speaker 1: I wonder what's in those pictures?
Speaker 0: Doesn't want this picture.
Speaker 1: My curiosity is exploding suddenly And also even if my curiosity is not exploding my contempt and my desire for free Information is exploding.
Speaker 1: So guys fight you I will spread them even though I don't give a fuck in this day and age in the year 2013 the Streisand effect is more powerful and you can possibly imagine Possibly you try to strike something down.
Speaker 0: In fact I would bet that there are a number of times where people try to invoke the Streisand effect in a false flag against themselves Because there is no sure way to get the entire world at least the industrialized world to talk about something Than to tell them not to talk about it.
Speaker 0: That's right, and the internet is making this so easy and so awesome.
Speaker 0: So France seriously, I Words cannot describe the contempt I have for the people who decided that this was a good idea.
Speaker 0: but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: so Ahem there's a guy and you know, there are many geekeries and on geek nights.
Speaker 1: We celebrate all the geekeries.
Speaker 1: there's this dude named I guess George Sprave, at least that's the name of his YouTube account and his geekery is Slingshots.
Speaker 1: he runs the slingshot channel.
Speaker 1: slingshots are his thing.
Speaker 1: That is an awesome thing to be the geek of power to this guy so Separately from the slingshot channel, which could be a thing in the day of itself.
Speaker 1: Bill and Melinda Gates have put forth the condom challenge.
Speaker 0: basically They think that condoms suck, you know, there's a frat boy condom challenge.
Speaker 0: That is a is probably not not that kind of condom challenge.
Speaker 0: that challenge is how many condoms can you put on right?
Speaker 1: They're basically saying condoms are flawed, you know, they're they're clumsy.
Speaker 0: I didn't read a star in a research paper many years ago that basically said that condoms are like 99.9% effective if used properly, but they're actually only like 70% effective because people just can't fucking figure them exactly.
Speaker 1: So, you know Bill Gates is like, hey, I'll give you a hundred thousand US dollars if you can improve condoms.
Speaker 1: You know product design wise right?
Speaker 1: Because obviously you're not gonna be able to educate those 30% of people who fuck it up Right.
Speaker 1: All you can do is improve the condom.
Speaker 1: So Slingshot guy has a way to improve the condom.
Speaker 1: He wants his hundred grand.
Speaker 1: Here's his YouTube video proposal.
Speaker 0: So a while ago, we did a book club book on the Great Gatsby.
Speaker 1: Actually, I found out today the Astoria Historical Society, which is in this mansion on Steinway called the Steinway mansion.
Speaker 0: I've seen the Steinway mansion.
Speaker 1: It has a Greek Gatsby exhibit right now.
Speaker 0: We should go to that this weekend.
Speaker 1: We can go to that because that sounds pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz Emily just read the Great Gatsby.
Speaker 0: You know geek guys book club and she really liked it and I reread some parts and remembered that it I really like good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, good book.
Speaker 1: for a reason There was.
Speaker 0: there was a kids that we talked about in the forum from a web series called crash course And it was a gentleman with some animation Basically explaining why the Great Gatsby is one of the greatest books ever written.
Speaker 1: Oh, so it's I thought.
Speaker 1: see I saw the links to these and I didn't watch them because I thought they would just be cliffnotes.
Speaker 1: But is it actually explaining why it's great as opposed to here's the deal.
Speaker 0: Crash course is three separate series this literary analysis series world history and u.s History, okay He has tons and tons of episodes on things like World War two the Mongols the American Revolution.
Speaker 1: I want to watch that.
Speaker 0: Mongols one Mongols.
Speaker 0: I don't know as much about the Mongols on the Cold War Islam and they are one super well-researched two super well-produced three Incredibly entertaining and four there's a ton of them.
Speaker 0: You should watch every video that's been uploaded by the crash course YouTube channel, I know what I'm doing what I can undo at work.
Speaker 0: They're gonna get educated watched every one of these.
Speaker 0: I think my favorite ones are the ones on US politics because he goes into just enough inside baseball To where you'll learn like interesting things that you wouldn't otherwise learn.
Speaker 0: It's not just a superficial view but at the same time it's enough of a breadth of overview that you learn useful things and anecdotes and It's pretty accurate.
Speaker 0: There are very few points He raises that I would take any umbrage with at all and they're so minor that I just couldn't be bothered.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: these are so well done.
Speaker 0: This is the level of flash and production values that we eventually strive for with geek nights presents And I'm gonna try to get this guy on geek nights to talk to him because these are so it's a good idea.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I really want to know about the Mongols because I'd really don't know as much about them as I should.
Speaker 1: He does this thing in the world history one where all I know about them is Genghis Khan conquered most of the world in my.
Speaker 1: he lived in Mongolia.
Speaker 0: every time he talks about and also My shitty wall you or anything He will always point out the exceptions to a rule like, you know empires can't be governed in this particular way Unless you're wait for it.
Speaker 0: And then he shows this same 10-second montage of clips from some Mongols movie from like the 60s.
Speaker 0: and The Mongols are always the exception.
Speaker 0: They're like the odd man out in all of world history.
Speaker 1: They're just Keep ignoring them because then every time your teacher who teaches you something you'd like aha What about the about the Mongols?
Speaker 0: It's like yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were the exception.
Speaker 0: now shut up.
Speaker 0: I want to go check that out now, but these are so great and they're funny too.
Speaker 0: He's a really funny guy.
Speaker 1: This is well cutting to clips from a 60s movie.
Speaker 1: That's be funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but he's a funny guy.
Speaker 0: independently The writing's good.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: I have nothing but good things to say about this.
Speaker 0: John Green is a minor hero of mine and you should watch every video that he's up.
Speaker 1: Does he really have to send those x-wing guys back?
Speaker 0: I'll legally.
Speaker 0: I could probably keep them.
Speaker 0: It's it's.
Speaker 0: it's not an egg.
Speaker 0: It's a slave one and it's a Millennium Falcon.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's enough to play with.
Speaker 0: no, it's not.
Speaker 1: then forget it.
Speaker 0: So in the meta moment, we're gonna be at anime Boston.
Speaker 0: we are doing five lectures offhand, I think they're That's the first one anime openers from around the world how to how to recommend anime how to run an anime club all Anime are the same and judge an anime by its cover.
Speaker 0: All right better start working on those.
Speaker 1: We actually only really need to work on the.
Speaker 1: all anime are the same.
Speaker 1: the rest we can do off the cuff.
Speaker 1: pretty much.
Speaker 0: I know I gotta put slides together of like talking points But I mean for judge an anime by its cover we can.
Speaker 1: all we have to do really is well Here's the latest anime chart and cut it up into individual slides and then we'll do it out live.
Speaker 1: We'll judge the cover.
Speaker 0: do is the first half of that panel.
Speaker 0: We're gonna do like that live and the second half.
Speaker 1: We're gonna explain what we did maybe or we can do it as we're you know.
Speaker 1: at the same time, right?
Speaker 1: We judge it and then we say why we're judging it.
Speaker 0: next one You know we can do in the.
Speaker 0: in the end in the second half take some old shows that everyone has seen That we all everyone already knows the deal like cowboy bebop and show the equivalent sort of like what it will like what the cover Would be and point out why those covers elicit such a different Feeling and why those shows tend to be better.
Speaker 1: That's too much work.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I can work on that one.
Speaker 0: I'll work on.
Speaker 0: I'll work on the other four and you handle the complicated one with all the clips.
Speaker 1: I'll handle on the complicated all the clips.
Speaker 1: if you get the source movies, uh Actually, I've been working on that.
Speaker 0: I got some really high quality of two of them.
Speaker 0: I just need to get some of the ponds.
Speaker 0: Darryl Surratt said he can help me out.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think the one the assassin island one because that one had a lot of the cliches of that type Because there's like they go to an island.
Speaker 1: an island always works, right?
Speaker 1: Especially compared to the one-piece movie Yeah, and the Slayer's movie, right?
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: It's always on an island separate from everything else.
Speaker 1: Actually, we just use those three right the Slayer's movie the one-piece movie and the Lupin movie on the island.
Speaker 1: Right because those all have those the.
Speaker 1: there's a female on the island.
Speaker 1: It's got the hots for Lupin Luffy slash He's got the weird cutaways.
Speaker 1: It's a secret villain who's just on that island, right?
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, yeah Then you get a little insight into how we plan panels.
Speaker 1: Sure Other meta moments after anime Boston is kinetic on.
Speaker 0: We're scheduling now.
Speaker 0: if you didn't submit your panel already the odds of you getting a time slot that isn't like 8 a.m on Sunday decrease rapidly.
Speaker 1: third and week after anime Boston packs Australia.
Speaker 1: we have sound fuck under everything.
Speaker 0: three Panels slash lectures and we'll see how many get accepted two of which are what we've been guaranteed.
Speaker 0: one that's for sure and Two of them are old standbys that have been reinvigorated for a modern era and I'm pretty sure Australians haven't seen them.
Speaker 0: and the third one is something new that we haven't even really discussed because I don't think that'll be picked because I basically said if you want something totally new and Not something we've already done and you really don't want the other two, which we'd prefer to do You can have this one and then we'll have to write
Speaker 1: it.
Speaker 1: and then Actually like a month and a half after packs Australia is packs Seattle.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: packs prime
Speaker 0: packs prime and packs dev
Speaker 1: Whoa,
Speaker 0: and in between all that I might be going to Turkey and I might be going to Munich and I'll
Speaker 1: be biking around New York City and biking around New York City
Speaker 0: and right after anime Boston playing
Speaker 1: that runner
Speaker 0: We might have a private party at a house somewhere
Speaker 1: and I think and we're
Speaker 0: already planning our New Year's extravaganza for magfest
Speaker 1: Okay, we're not giving the machine supremacy.
Speaker 1: Whatever This Friday at 2 p.m.
Speaker 1: Are the NS two?
Speaker 1: NSL finals in Germany.
Speaker 1: It is Nexol verse RK.
Speaker 1: RK is the evil team base of the Yankees.
Speaker 1: They never lose.
Speaker 0: I'm rooting for them now.
Speaker 0: I don't care that they're evil.
Speaker 1: front-runner Nexol is the American team.
Speaker 1: the players on that team are actually independent of nationality much nicer cooler people and I really want them to win and beat the evil team.
Speaker 0: See I want them to win and beat the evil team but so badly.
Speaker 0: Having been at RIT and then having been a part of the fan culture around the evil team I Kind of like being on the evil team.
Speaker 1: So the mighty decks are gonna beat you.
Speaker 1: that the end.
Speaker 1: You know what in the mighty ducks wasn't?
Speaker 1: that was the where it comes from right?
Speaker 1: The bad Yes was called the evil team, right?
Speaker 0: So no it was.
Speaker 0: it was actually called the evil team in Shaolin soccer.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's right.
Speaker 1: Shaolin soccer was the evil team.
Speaker 0: They were the evil team, but they weren't called or the evil team.
Speaker 1: Yes It's called the evil team.
Speaker 0: Remember that episode RK is the Shaolin soccer evil team with the steroids Episode of South Park where the underdog team goes to play against the Detroit Red Wings.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's basically what's most likely to happen on Friday.
Speaker 1: Yeah sadly But yeah, and there's actually like thousands of dollars in prizes.
Speaker 1: So if you you know and NS2 is really the first video game I've highly enjoyed spectating outside of omega-thon finals.
Speaker 1: So if you care at all, it's worth watching video game.
Speaker 0: I've enjoyed Spectating.
Speaker 0: I enjoy spectating Counter-Strike Pro matches in a big way.
Speaker 1: I haven't watched too many.
Speaker 1: I've only watched one or two.
Speaker 0: I've been trying to play increasingly competitively.
Speaker 0: So I either spend a lot of time watching the previous round or I spend a lot of time dead in the serious scrim watching everyone else.
Speaker 0: It's funny like I play on pubs and I'm basically neo like and unto you gods above and then I go to like the anarchy death server and I am easily like the second-to-last person on the server in terms of goodness the last person being bot Dave
Speaker 1: Way to go about Dave
Speaker 0: Bob Dave.
Speaker 0: I hope you don't ever die here again.
Speaker 1: the book club book is the player of games Coincidentally and sadly written by Ian M banks who after we selected this book we have learned is gonna die soon.
Speaker 0: I hope against hope that this does not assert a precedent of the geek nights book club being fatal.
Speaker 1: Yes, otherwise, we should pick.
Speaker 0: wait a minute.
Speaker 0: We hate us.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I've got the conservative people You don't like.
Speaker 1: Fitzgerald isn't alive anymore either, but he didn't start Announce that he was going to die dirt after I chose his book.
Speaker 0: He's been dead for a while our Scott backers still alive so we're all good.
Speaker 1: He's healthy very healthy.
Speaker 1: as far as we know.
Speaker 0: no date announced yet for the next prince of nothing book.
Speaker 1: Not not either for We either kill people or we kill their writing ability, I think the trick is to never read this book clubs cancel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's gonna get better.
Speaker 0: I mean the first Kingkiller book was okay.
Speaker 0: the second one after we reviewed it is sex kung fu.
Speaker 1: sure Some people really like that.
Speaker 0: apparently more people like that than the Great Gatsby because apparently there is terrible readers.
Speaker 1: they're shallow and They like fan service because they're fans anyway, so There you should go to front row crew.
Speaker 1: calm if you listen to this show.
Speaker 0: There was a problem that we as technologists in the world Solved before Scott and I were born and then with the advent of a different society.
Speaker 0: We have now unsolved it.
Speaker 1: So the basic fundamental problem here is I have some data.
Speaker 1: I want to send this data to not just one person But a lot of people and I wanted to send it to all those people simultaneously and quickly.
Speaker 0: How do I on that?
Speaker 1: how do I do this now?
Speaker 0: Here's the trouble.
Speaker 1: we're talking obviously Primarily about video now in the old days because that is that videos the thing that's gonna take a lot of day.
Speaker 0: We use broadcast because sure HD broadcast even today is a lot of bandwidth.
Speaker 0: But it's one way and the amount of bandwidth is static.
Speaker 0: It's as though you're streaming it once to one person.
Speaker 0: just everyone can piggyback on that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you have this piece of this.
Speaker 1: You know part of the frequency of the spectrum in the sky
Speaker 0: or on the cable or whatever
Speaker 1: specifically dedicated to this and only that all the time 24/7 and all you do is take your antenna Drain the fucking power plant to boost the antenna and broadcast and keep the antenna on all day and Anyone who wants to watch it works Even if everyone in the city watches at the same time.
Speaker 1: it works Even if everyone in the world assuming your antenna is that powerful and you have reflectors to reflect to the other side of the world.
Speaker 1: Everyone watches all the same time.
Speaker 1: You're that's it.
Speaker 1: You're good It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: and even with compression if you think about it the amount of data that is broadcast via Cable television alone like HDTV today is Ridiculous and staggering.
Speaker 1: Yeah, think about this right now.
Speaker 1: I'm in New York City, right.
Speaker 1: unlike some other places in the world We have a lot of local TV stations coming over the air Right, like two of every major network is like pretty sure the Connecticut stations can reach us.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 0: You know, it's interesting when I think when I lived in Detroit It was the same deal.
Speaker 1: think about how many radio stations am and FM right and think about how many satellites are Beaming their shit down at us.
Speaker 1: We are basically being crazily and how many.
Speaker 1: Wi-Fi is not a counter right.
Speaker 1: and this
Speaker 0: is a new because actually in the old
Speaker 1: Way for decades
Speaker 0: in some senses in
Speaker 1: if not a century
Speaker 0: before HD in some ways It could be argued that we were sending more data partly because of the lossy analog nature of all that crap and Just the really inefficient mechanisms used to
Speaker 1: ever since they invented the radio.
Speaker 1: This has been true.
Speaker 1: We are being bombarded by all sorts of radio waves all the goddamn time and if you choose which one we can tune to any One of them we like.
Speaker 0: so that's all well and good.
Speaker 0: But then the future came and now I want to watch Game of Thrones.
Speaker 0: right now Scott wants to watch Game of Thrones Starting about five minutes after me on his own computer and a million other people want to watch it at all sorts of different times.
Speaker 1: Well, everyone can get a DVR and everyone will just has to have their antenna working at the time.
Speaker 1: It's broadcast.
Speaker 1: Remember what was broadcast and then they're all good.
Speaker 0: Now that is actually the old model that worked very effectively called a VCR.
Speaker 0: Yeah that you would just time shift that the data is still going out.
Speaker 0: You're subscribed to this giant.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, if you want that data You got to be on at the time that data is going out.
Speaker 1: You'll get the data and then do with it as you please.
Speaker 0: now It's interesting that even when the VCR came out there were immediate lawsuits to basically try to keep that technology out of the hands Consumers because the media industry and strangler was terrified of the idea that someone could tape something and watch it.
Speaker 1: That's why it was actually another reason.
Speaker 1: It was very rare to put like big movies on TV.
Speaker 1: Like would be an event when a big movie was on TV.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like on net broadcast television.
Speaker 0: when Alice in Wonderland the animated movie was on Broadcast TV like me and all my little friends watched it at the same time
Speaker 1: It'd be like, you know, there'd be that Disney thing like on ABC like Tinkerbell would fly across the screen and you'd be like Oh shit, it's time for a real fucking movie on actual fucking TV.
Speaker 1: You would schedule your life around a thing that would happen.
Speaker 0: People would know that shit was coming when they had their VCRs ready And we're not talking scheduling around like oh Seinfeld's on at 7 got to be home to watch that.
Speaker 0: It was like hey, you're all watching the Merlin thing on Saturday, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're gonna show it twice and that's it.
Speaker 1: Those days are fucking over.
Speaker 0: so no, I'm cool and internetty and I just want to click on stuff and watch it when I want to watch it and I want individual streams sent to me and we don't really yet have good ways to do this.
Speaker 1: No, now right because if different people aren't all watching at the same time you can't just spray the data out all at once right that doesn't work because someone's gonna turn it on and tap into the feed and Suddenly they're in the middle
Speaker 0: now at the same time Really?
Speaker 0: You could if we engineered the internet a little bit and there's some of the some of these facilities.
Speaker 1: Then if we engineered the internet that way it'd be really bad for the other things using internet Visiting websites.
Speaker 0: they exist in parallel and what you do is have something called a content distribution network.
Speaker 0: We have those Yes, but they're not part of.
Speaker 0: because of the way the internet is it's hard to do what I'm about to propose.
Speaker 0: I'm not necessarily saying this is the best way to do it and I'm gonna really really simplify the idea.
Speaker 0: but in IP You know IPV4 IPV6.
Speaker 0: There's the concept of Multicast.
Speaker 1: that's hardly ever used ever.
Speaker 0: It's used a lot internal to organizations Like if you've got some Tibco middleware, but I mean on the cap the capital.
Speaker 1: I internet hardly ever used.
Speaker 1: It's mostly used on.
Speaker 0: the idea is that you have data that just go into your network all the time.
Speaker 0: It just goes to your routers and your router knows who has requested that stream or not.
Speaker 1: So basically anyone who's connected to the router.
Speaker 1: Let's say it's a 10 port router.
Speaker 1: the people on ports one through five.
Speaker 1: Just tell the router Hey, I want to subscribe to that shit and then that comes in one hole on the router.
Speaker 1: The router will copy and send it to all five holes.
Speaker 0: I think I actually want to go in one step more detail than that because you wouldn't actually have five people connected to the Router.
Speaker 0: you can act.
Speaker 0: networks to routers not devices.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 0: It's true It's true, but this this kind of shows why this is such a scalable idea in theory.
Speaker 0: So you've got your route err.
Speaker 0: Yeah as opposed to your switch err Yeah, so the router knows, you know, it's getting the the stream from the source like it's Game of Thrones.
Speaker 0: It's whatever the hell it's going to the router.
Speaker 0: The router then knows.
Speaker 0: the sweat basically from the switch will say things like this someone on this vlan It wants this data.
Speaker 0: now as soon as you're giving that data to that vlan at all Anyone on that vlan can get the same data with no increase in bandwidth usage at any level.
Speaker 0: beyond that switches actually Individual ports because modern internet modern ethernet is basically full duplex one device per port Mmm, so as a result, once you send it to that subnet either everyone's getting it or no one's getting it.
Speaker 0: And the switch does even further Optimization where the packages don't go out to places where there aren't people to listen in the first place.
Speaker 1: So if 20 people in the office building all want the data, right?
Speaker 1: We actually only need to have one copy of that data coming into the building from the outside and our internal networking Equipment will sort of copy it for everybody as it comes in now
Speaker 0: This is
Speaker 1: our bandwidth bill for our external internet will be 20 times lower than if we had 20 copies coming
Speaker 0: in now.
Speaker 0: This still doesn't solve some of the other problems.
Speaker 0: For example, so this multicast stream starts.
Speaker 0: It's going fine.
Speaker 0: What if I subscribe five minutes late?
Speaker 0: Usually there's no mechanism to get the part.
Speaker 0: I miss mmm.
Speaker 1: You'd have to have some sort of DVR built into the network now.
Speaker 0: It's interesting because In middleware as in corporate middleware things like 59 West TIB RV You know those kinds of things JMS even you had.
Speaker 0: you can have concepts where you'll have multicast data like that But you have a secondary Channel where someone can start subscribing but then they can hit a secondary channel and request just the data they miss Mmm, so you can have architecture that requires storage to hold that data.
Speaker 0: Yes, but then you have not.
Speaker 1: a lot of routers have big hard drives in them.
Speaker 0: But then again, maybe you have a mechanism there where you have a caching server that sits next to your router.
Speaker 1: I'm your network a big old box of drives and RAM under your router.
Speaker 1: But maybe it only caches for the current day or the logs to our likes 24 hours of all the multicast data.
Speaker 0: Basically, yeah Yeah.
Speaker 0: And then it can retransmit just the data you miss or it can be pre-loaded with data to start people Subscribing or seeding things early.
Speaker 0: the sky's the limit.
Speaker 0: The problem is that the sky's the limit.
Speaker 0: These are all proprietary things that are usually written or architected for individual use cases Like we built it out at my old company for market data to subscribe to market data.
Speaker 0: It was a really great solution.
Speaker 0: So if you wanted level 1 and level 2 market data from US equities markets, there is a solution for you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but let's say you know what it all this equipment right for normal Also within a network that we controlled a hundred percent right.
Speaker 1: all this equipment for normal people would have to be set up at The ISP.
Speaker 1: so the ISP is gonna install a special thing just to help Netflix out.
Speaker 1: That's not cool.
Speaker 1: Well, there's so many people that they could possibly help out the install one for Amazon.
Speaker 1: Also, you come on iTunes.
Speaker 0: So Google offers that as a service and almost all ISPs that are large enough take advantage of it.
Speaker 0: They will put Google caching servers that cache big chunks of YouTube.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Google's paying for that shit.
Speaker 0: That's not a hundred percent clear.
Speaker 0: I've seen different reports of how the arrangement works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not a publicly available thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, isn't that sort of a not net neutrality?
Speaker 0: Um, I would argue no because the way that works is basically you have an ISP, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so a lot of your customers are coming to Google.
Speaker 0: They're hit they're going through the peering of the internet and they're hitting Google's like customer gateway and streaming their data.
Speaker 0: So it's in everyone's vested interest if you have a cache of that super high demand high bandwidth data Inside of the ISP's network to take off that sort of front load.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but unless the ISP allows anyone to do this right and to make this deal It's not fair that Google can put their stuff in there.
Speaker 0: But at the same time by doing that that frees up the actual External pipes for all the other content and ends up being better for everyone.
Speaker 1: yet our internet still slow as fuck.
Speaker 0: That's a separate problem, I'm still battling.
Speaker 0: in recent remember way back and we talked about those tricks that seem to make YouTube faster.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm still investigating that.
Speaker 0: I've had long conversations with Verizon text and I'm not yet at.
Speaker 0: I can't say I'm not at liberty to disclose my findings because I have not found anything That I would report on because I'm not confident enough in the things I've discovered.
Speaker 0: Suffice it to say Everything's dysfunctional in the American Internet at this peering level of internet works, but that's a separate problem.
Speaker 0: But at least in theory the idea of a content distribution network like that and Akamai and Amazon There's all these ways where you basically take your content and you distribute it to far away scattered endpoints So that users can get it first from there and then it is getting it.
Speaker 0: So it gets the current copy of say your front-end database from your central server And maybe it only updates once every minute, but then you have billions of people updating every nanosecond From that gateway beyond.
Speaker 0: the customer is constantly hitting it, but you're not using bandwidth upstream from that caching server.
Speaker 0: Yep now architecting that as you've probably dealt with because it's a big part of your job is Architecting and optimizing that especially if it's two-way communication is not necessarily the easiest thing in the world.
Speaker 1: Usually you don't use it for two-way.
Speaker 1: use it for one way right, but two ways.
Speaker 1: the holy grail it is So like if you got a website think about this, right?
Speaker 1: There are some parts of the website that are different every time someone visits, right?
Speaker 0: So ad rotation, right?
Speaker 1: I mean like if you log into Facebook, right your newsfeed is different for every different person.
Speaker 1: It's not the same, right?
Speaker 1: So you need when someone visits Facebook Facebook needs to generate that part of the page just for that person and that person alone.
Speaker 1: Right, but the Facebook homepage doesn't fucking change.
Speaker 1: Anyone who visits that shit is seeing the same exact HTML, right.
Speaker 1: and also everyone is seeing the same exact like Facebook logo image.
Speaker 1: They're seeing the same Facebook CSS file and that stuff is not trivial.
Speaker 0: I mean guys our RSS feed uses almost as much bandwidth as gig nights, right?
Speaker 1: It's like there's a lot of files that don't change.
Speaker 1: every person visiting sees the same file and A lot of people are getting those files all the time.
Speaker 1: So what you do is someone will visit your website and it'll be like IMGSRC equals Not facebook.com.
Speaker 1: slash image slash whatever.
Speaker 1: It'll be like CDN something something Facebook something image And basically that image even though the web page came from a Facebook server made you that page For just for you and send it to you.
Speaker 1: all these other parts of the page that don't change ever are on some caching server that Facebook set up not at your ISP but near you geographically and You're gonna get all the images and CSS and JS files and things from there instead and that's hardly ever updated by Facebook.
Speaker 1: So that means that bandwidth only has to go between you and there and not between you and the big Facebook server all the way At the Facebook data center.
Speaker 0: now, there's an even further complication.
Speaker 0: all these ideas We talked about the counter distribution are kind of assuming that you don't care if other people, you know Everyone can see the data.
Speaker 0: but like a lot of broadcasts of things like HBO shows They only want certain people to be able to see the data.
Speaker 0: meaning if they use any sort of content distribution network The internal traffic has to be inaccessible and probably encrypted Yep Which adds a whole nother layer.
Speaker 0: and to illustrate this point because I realized as Scott and I were talking about this.
Speaker 0: I don't think many people on the internet know the sort of sorted history of satellite television Let alone how satellites work right.
Speaker 1: but think about this way, right?
Speaker 1: So in terms of the you know, the encrypted send right.
Speaker 1: so your HBO, right?
Speaker 1: You have a server that has the TV shows on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a hundred people want to watch and the show is 20 megabits per second.
Speaker 1: So that means you need 200 megabits per second of bandwidth.
Speaker 1: You don't have that much right?
Speaker 1: You only have a hundred.
Speaker 1: what do you do?
Speaker 1: Let ten people not watch.
Speaker 1: you're gonna decrease the quality by half.
Speaker 1: What are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: So what you do is you sort of stream that data to the CDN's, right?
Speaker 1: So there's one.
Speaker 1: there's maybe three CDN's around the world US Asia and Europe, right?
Speaker 1: so you really only have to send 60 megabits per second 20 to the first CDN 20 to the next CDN and 20 to the Third CDN.
Speaker 1: and then those all those users those all that will be you know Getting to the CDN's which will copy and resend the data to all them separately.
Speaker 1: So even though you do still need in total the all those CDN's aren't cheap Right, and they still have to have that total 200 megabits of bandwidth for all the users Which sucks compared to say the radio antenna?
Speaker 1: Well, you still at your central server you own.
Speaker 1: you need much much less bandwidth So each into no individual piece of equipment really needs to be that ridiculously crazy.
Speaker 1: Imagine trying to get like everyone in the whole world right watching the Super Bowl off one server.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna happen, right?
Speaker 1: You can split it up to a bunch of servers all across the world that are individually small and easy to set up and have You know a reasonable amount of bandwidth each and then no single piece needs to have a ludicrous amount of bandwidth Even though in total you have that ludicrous amount.
Speaker 0: So I want to illustrate all these points by explaining how Satellite television evolved in the United States because this this is a nice one.
Speaker 0: if you're interested in this because it's actually kind of a cool story You can read there's a Wikipedia page that will go into ludicrous detail about how this all works.
Speaker 0: But I want to clear one big misconception.
Speaker 0: If you have like a satellite receiver for TV, it's not or internet.
Speaker 0: It's not sending anything back to that satellite.
Speaker 0: Your upstream is not slow because you're sending it to the satellite.
Speaker 0: your little dish can't transmit for shit.
Speaker 0: You have a modem that's connected via a regular old phone line to your ISP.
Speaker 1: Why don't you just pair like a cable modem with the dish?
Speaker 0: Some people have done things like that.
Speaker 1: But then if you have a kid modem, why do you have a dish?
Speaker 0: The only reason you would ever have a satellite internet is if you live somewhere where phone lines are Probably the best thing you can get me.
Speaker 1: whenever you see pictures of like, you know Most countries on earth don't really have the cable TV, right you watch, you know Any pictures of like.
Speaker 1: a lot of countries just everyone has dishes.
Speaker 1: just satellite dishes.
Speaker 1: You were in India.
Speaker 1: satellite dishes everywhere, right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see everyone just has dishes.
Speaker 1: then get all the fucking channels in the goddamn universe.
Speaker 0: so in the in the 70s the way a lot of syndicated television would work is there would be satellites that would Broadcast the data because that was the easiest way to send it to all the different local networks both You know later cable providers But also over-the-air providers.
Speaker 0: a syndicated show would be sent up to a satellite and then beamed over basically the entire United States.
Speaker 0: Yep, because only rich television stations could afford satellite dishes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there would be a few rich people like one person in my grandma's neighborhood would get this gigantic motherfucking dish on their roof.
Speaker 1: Oh, just like that horror movie that was reviewed by Cinemassacre that we also saw with amber.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: So the reason for that is that so that they broadcast like that There was a really easy distribution mechanism.
Speaker 0: No one ever thought to encrypt.
Speaker 1: the satellites were expensive But once they're up there, they're up there.
Speaker 0: So in the later 70s a hobbyist.
Speaker 0: I forget the dude's name.
Speaker 0: He basically wrote software and Came up with devices that could take that satellite signal and turn it back into a usual usable picture That consumers could use.
Speaker 0: so consumers who were savvy Realize they didn't have to pay for premium content and they could consume television From all over the world not just their local broadcast.
Speaker 1: you put a big-ass dish on your roof.
Speaker 0: You aim it at the satellites physically, right basically plugged it through device into your TV.
Speaker 1: Yeah And then you could watch any Channel pretty much anywhere in the world that you could aim your dish at.
Speaker 1: so I guess you couldn't watch something from the exact Opposite side of the world.
Speaker 1: but maybe you could get a reflection and catch it.
Speaker 0: and it turns out a lot of things were broadcast In multiple markets and you could see a lot of things.
Speaker 0: I mean expected you to aim real.
Speaker 1: I mean, there are those ham radio guys who talked to Australia early in the morning, right?
Speaker 1: So I bet if you early in the morning, you could probably see Chinese TV.
Speaker 0: There was also a huge community in Canada that would do this because they couldn't get a lot of American TV.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: So obviously as soon as enough smart people were doing this they started to show their friends how to do it.
Speaker 0: and then some companies started selling the equipment.
Speaker 0: and Two things happen one bunch of lawsuits and a bunch of court debates and a bunch of congressional debates To the people who were sending out this data over the air started to try to figure out how to encrypt it.
Speaker 0: Yep, and two things happen as a result of this one.
Speaker 0: There was a big debate in the public consciousness in the late 70s and early 80s This is largely forgotten today about whether or not this echoes back to the beginning of the episode.
Speaker 0: You have a right to decode signals that are being broadcast into your own home.
Speaker 0: Yep Funny how the same debates happen over and over again and never get resolved.
Speaker 1: thing Remember if you want to save a lot on this bandwidth cost and not make copies of everything to send them to specific people.
Speaker 1: You can save by just spraying your data everywhere without worrying about who receives it.
Speaker 1: But then anyone can receive it who wants to.
Speaker 1: so what you?
Speaker 1: the only way?
Speaker 1: To limit it to certain people is to encrypt it send it out And then even though anyone can pick it up and take a look at it Only the people who have the key can actually look.
Speaker 0: so you can see how this echoes all the debates we're having today.
Speaker 0: There were arguments made and there were court cases around the idea that maybe it should be illegal to encrypt these broadcasts.
Speaker 0: Because then theoretically are you not trespassing by sending these signals into everyone's homes that they are not legally allowed Nor are they able to decrypt simultaneously?
Speaker 0: Pirate television arrived.
Speaker 0: people started you know the hobbyists who made the original devices Pretty trivially figured out the encryption schemes and started selling black boxes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, black boxes in that era meant devices that would decrypt cable TV or satellite signals Without a cable box.
Speaker 1: right because remember if you encrypt and broadcast this thing right you're only sending one copy.
Speaker 1: It's all encrypted the same way for every person.
Speaker 1: everyone is the same key.
Speaker 0: So if I figure out the case someone gets that keys just like DRM.
Speaker 1: It is DRM.
Speaker 0: both my uncle and a friend of my dad's had oscilloscopes and crazy satellite dishes And they were.
Speaker 1: one person pays for DirecTV.
Speaker 1: everyone else gets free DirecTV.
Speaker 0: They were cracking analog satellite and cable signals in the 80s.
Speaker 0: Yep like that.
Speaker 0: That is a level of hacker dedication.
Speaker 0: We don't often see it now.
Speaker 1: There is still plenty of unencrypted broadcast and satellite television.
Speaker 1: right like I remember at RIT They had a dish up and they would watch like Apple keynotes by satellite Which you couldn't watch in those days.
Speaker 0: my point is simply this the history of satellite television and distribution The court cases the lawsuits of your people arrested the hackers the debates in society about whether or not you have a right to Data that's being handed to you.
Speaker 0: We had that argument in the 70s, and it didn't go anywhere.
Speaker 0: We had that argument in the 80s.
Speaker 0: We had that argument in the 90s.
Speaker 0: We had the argument in the 2000s.
Speaker 0: We're having the argument now in the 2013s.
Speaker 0: there's been no consensus.
Speaker 0: there have been very few definitive court cases and Frankly almost nothing has changed.
Speaker 0: the technology has just gotten more sophisticated along the way Yep, so everything that apply no one wants to take.
Speaker 0: no one wants a TV anymore cuz it sucks I know but everything that applied to the debates in the 70s and 80s about satellite TV.
Speaker 0: Change some of the proper nouns the technology and post it to reddit.
Speaker 0: It'll sound exactly like what every kid is arguing about today.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website At front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.