Speaker 0: It's Monday December 2nd 2013.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nods.
Speaker 0: We're back tonight.
Speaker 0: We're talking about that penny arcade job posting rims.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Now.
Speaker 0: I should note we're gonna try to avoid talking about any of the non tech aspects of because they're obvious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're obvious.
Speaker 1: the way you shouldn't work zillion hours a week.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well the only exception would be if work is also life, but That's a sad person.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: What if?
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: if my job Scott mm-hmm is to hang out on the beach and relax I'm putting in extra hours for that job.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna murder you and take your job.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so but in that case or you're gonna put in a good word for me And I'll get hired and you'll get as high signing bonus.
Speaker 0: I mean I spent a lot of late nights working on geek nights when I could have been asleep Back in the day when it would take us a couple hours to actually put a show together after we recorded it.
Speaker 0: But I digress that's in the second part of the show, but yeah, I was in Istanbul all last week Ironically in Turkey over Thanksgiving, so I did not have any turkey.
Speaker 1: is that really ironic?
Speaker 0: uh no It's ironic.
Speaker 0: That's why I said ironic with an ironic lilt perhaps but Nobody who everyone I talked to who knew that I was gonna be in Turkey over Thanksgiving Had to basically make some Observation along those lines of ah you're gonna be what?
Speaker 1: Instead of having been the turkey what three times now?
Speaker 1: more than that I mean the turkey.
Speaker 1: the Turkish people know that the name of their country in English is the name of a bird.
Speaker 0: I so so right let us know that they do.
Speaker 1: and what do they think about that?
Speaker 0: They don't think about it.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: They do eat turkeys on Christmas, which they celebrate even though they call it turkey.
Speaker 0: I don't know because everyone I do business where.
Speaker 1: what is the Arabic word for Turkey?
Speaker 0: so they don't speak Arabic.
Speaker 1: I thought they speak it up.
Speaker 0: They speak Turkish.
Speaker 1: I didn't know.
Speaker 1: Turkish is a different language.
Speaker 1: Wow What's that?
Speaker 1: was it different?
Speaker 0: It's completely different.
Speaker 0: It's more based on Greek than it is based on Anything else.
Speaker 1: did not know this?
Speaker 0: Wow really okay?
Speaker 0: You listen to 12 Byzantine rulers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't know.
Speaker 1: how much do you think I remember?
Speaker 1: I can't remember.
Speaker 1: I can't remember anything all right.
Speaker 0: So so a few highlights.
Speaker 0: then I saw the chain As in that chain from that podcast the one that hung across the Bosphorus that kept the Ottomans at bay Until they eventually took the tower and took it down.
Speaker 0: the chain is just there in the museum Mm-hmm, and I think the funniest thing was.
Speaker 0: I saw all these Egyptian Artifacts and for a second.
Speaker 0: I'm like what?
Speaker 0: why is there so much Egypt?
Speaker 0: Oh right Romans conquered Egypt Greeks conquered Egypt, this is all
Speaker 1: Cleopatra
Speaker 0: yeah, and I think older stuff yeah lot a lot of the artifacts that Rome and Parts of Rome have laying around like in their museums today are things that the Romans themselves looted from places They conquered more than a thousand years ago.
Speaker 0: These are things that were conquered taken looted and put in museums Before so-called Jesus wasn't born mm-hmm I just find that awesome and interesting, but now that my trouble with Turkey is that I Would like to learn Turkish because I go there enough and the business is big, but
Speaker 1: they mostly speak English.
Speaker 0: well Let's be everyone in the industry.
Speaker 0: I engage with speaks English Pretty well too very well too better than a lot of Americans.
Speaker 1: hello my friend.
Speaker 0: I want a lot of people in the street at least in the urban centers also speak English.
Speaker 0: So as a result I don't have any chance to really use.
Speaker 1: do they speak English even to each other?
Speaker 1: or only they are able to speak English But don't speak it as their primary language.
Speaker 0: They will never speak English to each other, okay?
Speaker 0: But they speak it very well when they're speaking with me or when I'm in the room.
Speaker 0: but All the books I can find to teach myself Turkish are ancient and teach like Turkish from the 1920s like no one.
Speaker 1: Why don't you get ripoff Rosetta Stone?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I'm probably going to pirate Rosetta Stone.
Speaker 1: Why don't you do the thing that Emily does with the Skype and with the Turkish person because that service did not have Turkish?
Speaker 0: Really there are not a lot of English to Turkish language resources because there's not a lot of interest in the English-speaking world and learning Turkish.
Speaker 1: sadly why don't you find the person who is like?
Speaker 1: Translating Turkish books or something and ask them if there's something you can do?
Speaker 0: yeah I'll just pay them to come over and teach me Turkish.
Speaker 1: I mean like go to the Turkish bookstore right and find like the most popular fucking book right and it's probably gonna be have an English translation look up in the credits who did the translation and then find the person on the internet and call them.
Speaker 0: well I think I'm gonna probably start by pirating Rosetta Stone, and I'm still doing some research.
Speaker 0: I found a couple of books.
Speaker 0: the problem is the books.
Speaker 1: Why don't you look at the person in the credits of the Turkish Rosetta Stone who made it?
Speaker 0: Oh?
Speaker 1: maybe Those people may probably just tell you to use Turkish Rosetta Stone, but still.
Speaker 0: But I I only learn words related to food and coffee because they have coffee and tea and stuff like that Constantly.
Speaker 0: it's awesome.
Speaker 1: usually the first thing people learn is when they're learning a new language.
Speaker 1: late in life is swear words.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you probably haven't learned any.
Speaker 0: nope I haven't learned any.
Speaker 0: I've overheard.
Speaker 0: I think what you say We're lucky in Turkey.
Speaker 0: nope I can.
Speaker 0: I can order a Black Turkish coffee by getting saute coffee.
Speaker 0: okay as opposed to art.
Speaker 0: Oh coffee, which is Turkish coffee with a little bit of sugar in it and the word for tea is chai.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's a hard word.
Speaker 0: It's spelled differently.
Speaker 0: It's spelled C a y but I can read Turkish.
Speaker 0: I can read Turkish words and know how to pronounce them Which actually took me a little while to figure out I could do that with Hebrew and I was like in kindergarten.
Speaker 0: they use a lot of Diocratics like way more than I'm used to and they have a much bigger impact on the words Like.
Speaker 0: also the most vexing thing is that there's I with a dot and without a dot and they're different.
Speaker 0: So they're gonna be an uppercase I with a dot and uppercase I without a dot.
Speaker 0: All right, yeah that also causes problems in Java and other languages if you don't handle it properly.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: because there's a lowercase I with the dot so it gets uppercase to do an uppercase Dotted I. that doesn't display in most Western character sets.
Speaker 0: Thus problems.
Speaker 0: text editor you TFA yeah But even then which character?
Speaker 0: if you have?
Speaker 0: if you type an I that's a lowercase I in English It'll have the dot by default mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So if you if you take that in Turkish and then uppercase it it'll still have the dot Mm-hmm, but you don't want the dotted uppercase I. in that case most likely You want the non dotted uppercase I especially if it's English just being typed in Turkish.
Speaker 0: There's also issues.
Speaker 1: That's the problem.
Speaker 1: is someone on a Turkish keyboard put in their Turkish lowercase I when they meant to put in an English lowercase I yep, or the other way around.
Speaker 0: you put in English lowercase I. that gets uppercase to a uppercase I with a dot which doesn't exist in English.
Speaker 1: It's a different letter right.
Speaker 1: you just pretend it like that lowercase Turkish I ah but this is the problem in English.
Speaker 0: we have.
Speaker 0: we have lowercase I with a dot and uppercase I without a dot.
Speaker 0: So we have.
Speaker 0: we have like half and a half is our problem anyway.
Speaker 0: but yeah, that that's how I was in Turkey.
Speaker 0: it was awesome and Lions won the Thanksgiving Day game The first time.
Speaker 0: it doesn't my life that I can remember that I cared.
Speaker 0: it doesn't matter matters a lot Matters a lot.
Speaker 0: if I if you're you know if you've ever lived in Detroit it matters a lot doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so we got some news got a news got news.
Speaker 0: We're back.
Speaker 0: It's geek nights news.
Speaker 1: I think I closed my tab with my news.
Speaker 1: Let me remember was all right, so RMS as In Richard Stallman why are we talking about him?
Speaker 0: So I decided that he's the opposite of relevant has proven that Bitcoin has made it and you know how we know.
Speaker 0: Bitcoin has made it because Richard Stallman is calling for an anonymous alternative to Bitcoin.
Speaker 0: Okay He doesn't tell anyone how or doesn't know how?
Speaker 0: of course not but basically Bitcoin has become useful enough to where he is calling for an alternative to it Because of its flaw the flaw being that it's not actually anonymous Which is funny because most people who talk about Bitcoin seem to laud how anonymous it is not knowing that it's actually the opposite of that.
Speaker 0: And the point of it is not that it's anonymous, but that it's intrinsic.
Speaker 0: This article just if you want to see what slash shot looked like in 1994 this article from today is basically slashed out in 1994.
Speaker 0: It's got all the keywords RMS alternative to whatever hot technology They take.
Speaker 1: your Bill Gates face with the Borg on it.
Speaker 0: It's actually got a picture of a Bitcoin because they have a Bitcoin category because there's so many articles about Now.
Speaker 0: Maybe we do need an anonymous equivalent of Bitcoin because cash is increasingly difficult to use by tech nerdy people and And Intrinsic currencies are useful for the segment of the population that can't use credit cards aka Teenagers who are increasingly spending a lot of money online and have no good way to do that.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Anonymous ones would be good for the black market the internet underground buying drugs.
Speaker 0: Bitcoin is kind of good for that too, but you have to be technologically savvy Mm-hmm, but now my real news is that Amazon announced the kind of thing that's usually a Don't know April Fool's joke.
Speaker 1: I thought it was an April Fool's joke at first or a parody and I had heard.
Speaker 0: I mean there have been rumors about this For a long time and I assume this is the kind of thing that you'd see on One of those TV shows back when they were like what's new in tech with Soledad O'Brien on TV back in the day like square Whatever TV, but I forget what all those channels were called but Amazon actually announced that they're gonna have little drones that will deliver packages and They actually have come a long way and they've got working prototypes like this is not as far away as people think it is.
Speaker 1: I just see like two things.
Speaker 1: I'm seeing really often lately, right?
Speaker 1: The one thing is Where people like they misunderstand where technology currently is in both directions, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they'll underestimate what they're capable of doing right now realistically and they'll also overestimate in different areas Point Google Glass.
Speaker 0: people think it's like this real-world overlay Device that shows you this heads-up display that fully fills your vision like yeah people do have no under no realistic Understanding of what it actually does right, but then they don't realize that robot cars already work like they already work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they exist.
Speaker 1: they work for real in real cities but and and the thing is in either direction right the over or underestimating people have a completely unrealistic Expectation about timeframes as well, right?
Speaker 1: It's like when they underestimate They think you know, the thing is actually way old.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, I've been doing that for like a hundred years.
Speaker 1: Where have you been right?
Speaker 0: Well, like when Facebook come up, you're like, wow, this is the first thing like that ever.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah Never mind ICQ and orca.
Speaker 1: and then when they overestimate it's like, you know, they think it's gonna be right around the corner.
Speaker 1: It's like no, that's you're not, you know, we've been talking cars, right?
Speaker 1: It's like we've been talking about.
Speaker 1: it's like Google Glass, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's here, right?
Speaker 1: You're overestimating what it's capable of But you think it's.
Speaker 1: you know, even if you get that right you think it's good.
Speaker 1: You're gonna be capable of it like really soon.
Speaker 0: It's like no not anytime soon, but at the same time they really underestimate that what glass is Right.
Speaker 0: He much already exists.
Speaker 0: They say be out soon.
Speaker 1: the whole world just has this, you know Anyone who's not in technology has a completely Wrong understanding of where we are at and what things can do and including right.
Speaker 1: this news story is the perfect example because even 60 minutes a very reputable news program right is acting all like this.
Speaker 1: shits like around the corner.
Speaker 0: no nerds We're talking about this back when Amazon started sure.
Speaker 1: But the other thing is like when is this actually?
Speaker 1: realistically when I'm what day am I going to receive a package by Amazon?
Speaker 1: by air like this.
Speaker 1: Five years minimum more like ten.
Speaker 0: I think this brings up the Fundamental underlying point.
Speaker 0: I'm glad that you went in this direction The biggest problem in technology, but they have a news story like if we're gonna have this today just because we can theoretically Yeah, well, I mean that's the people are acting like this is some crazy thing.
Speaker 0: No, this is this.
Speaker 0: technology has existed for a while.
Speaker 0: It's not new Amazon saying they're going to do and then they go.
Speaker 1: Oh my god U.m.
Speaker 1: Play gods.
Speaker 1: a package is gonna fall on someone and kill him.
Speaker 0: Yeah But the it's the same thing is with robot cars.
Speaker 0: that technology exists today.
Speaker 0: It is not Technologically infeasible to roll it out assuming no concerns.
Speaker 1: It might.
Speaker 1: I can be economically infeasible In mass.
Speaker 1: in mass you can definitely deliver one package for sure.
Speaker 0: No problem It would depend on where this would be the most feasible in a place like New York City Sure, where it could just deliver.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have to go very far But there's a lot of people that can deliver to Exactly and you could get to the places that are difficult to get delivery trucks to.
Speaker 1: but how is it gonna?
Speaker 1: How are you gonna for anyone from robbing it?
Speaker 1: I'm not worried about that because those are the kinds of things I would just stand look around for them Shoot them down and take whatever they got.
Speaker 1: especially I would use my binoculars a scope and if it's a new egg, boom If it's right if it can that hard drive will make the it'll survive the descent fireman person catching that.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling that that is.
Speaker 0: you know This is something you're doing the thing that people on slashdot did.
Speaker 0: they do all the time whenever there's an article about hey We're gonna make a subway that goes in space.
Speaker 0: The first comments are armchair engineers saying yeah, but because of the whatever radiation it couldn't actually work.
Speaker 0: It's like dumb shits if the engineers are working on it.
Speaker 0: They probably thought of the most low hanging fruit dangers that you think of my gogo 13 attack.
Speaker 0: You know what if gogo 13 attacks that it's fucked.
Speaker 0: that's what I'm saying, that's fine if gogo 13 attacks a tank tanks fucked.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: but in terms of this the biggest problem with technology today in terms of rolling it out is the gap between government regulation and technological availability and Fear of people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the fear of people kind of ties in that Technology exists today to do this.
Speaker 0: Amazon could start doing this on a small scale today.
Speaker 0: There is literally no Technological limitation preventing them from doing so.
Speaker 0: just like we could have robot cars give you windy driving.
Speaker 0: Well, then it doesn't go until the next day.
Speaker 0: So yes today or tomorrow, you're never getting deliveries.
Speaker 0: Well, then they do some sort of blimp thing instead where a blimp goes up rides the wind and then lands and then someone just Goes around later and picks up all the blimps like once a month.
Speaker 1: I Military's been doing that for like as long as we've had planes.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: You think the military doesn't.
Speaker 1: They can deliver stuff wouldn't create with a parachute old Invention.
Speaker 0: if the military can deliver a Hellfire missile into someone's living room whenever they want via a drone They can deliver a package with some hard drives and a USB cable.
Speaker 0: Yep, if they did it via missile, that'd be pretty cool, dude.
Speaker 0: But seriously the only reason we don't have limited trials of Commercially available robot cars or things like this is simply that our government is and on any level on the local level the national level The federal level state level town level old people 100% incapable of even discussing these issues.
Speaker 0: Do you know how will New York City as a specific example even get to the point where anyone involved in our government?
Speaker 0: Even begins to understand how to go about regulating private drones using New York City's airspace?
Speaker 1: They're still discussing whether to put like a traffic slowing curb in my neighborhood.
Speaker 0: They're already fighting whether they're already realizing that because of state laws They can't reduce the speed limit to 20 miles an hour because there's state laws that prevent it.
Speaker 0: So we have a problem where increasingly and I think this is going to happen more and more within the next 10 years We're gonna hit a crisis point with this.
Speaker 0: technology is advancing so fast that we will have things that are so just start.
Speaker 1: I think that right and this is why what you see in Silicon Valley so much is These companies sort of jerkily right in most cases just start deploying their technology in direct Scoffing and violation of any laws and regulations.
Speaker 0: a crunchy roll did that back in the day, right?
Speaker 1: Exactly like uber.
Speaker 1: They're just like fuck your taxi laws.
Speaker 1: We're doing it and they just do it and it's like what do you do?
Speaker 1: stop us and they do try to stop them By forcing the battle.
Speaker 1: that's the only way to actually make anything happen is by just starting to do it.
Speaker 1: So if I was Amazon They have plenty of fucking money.
Speaker 1: if you got this shit to the point where it worked and you were ready to make it happen Just start doing it, right?
Speaker 1: Just do it and make the guard and force the government to discuss it and do something about it.
Speaker 1: Force them to shoot down your little drones or do whatever because this is the only way you're actually gonna be able to get it Set up.
Speaker 0: I do a little more subtle and a little more 80s movie villain.
Speaker 0: I would find a small town that Really needed it that really needed me.
Speaker 1: the post office never goes there.
Speaker 0: Yeah like one of those small towns and I would work with them and get them to pass all the local laws that would make it Work and tell them don't worry about federal and state bullshit because we got your back and then just deploy in that town and then as soon as there's trouble and the government gets involved.
Speaker 0: suddenly you've got a government fighting with you not just individual people and Neighboring towns, there'll be people who want these things and you could.
Speaker 0: you could just dump lobbying money into.
Speaker 1: You think people would.
Speaker 1: actually the problem is in the small town.
Speaker 1: No one will want them.
Speaker 1: you have to do in the city where people.
Speaker 0: you gotta find the small city like this like the Silicon Valley like mini like these little cities that have a bunch of tech workers.
Speaker 0: Anyway, like Raleigh would be possibly a good place for something like that.
Speaker 0: A lot of tech workers despite being a relatively small city on the grand scheme of things.
Speaker 1: All right News.
Speaker 1: so this isn't really news, right?
Speaker 1: It's just something I always had troubles with.
Speaker 1: Alright, you know, I'm pretty good at setting up computers and whatnot.
Speaker 0: Yep, but mail servers Nope, you know, nope, you know the last time I set up a mail server Well one Scott and I try to get squirrel mail working at our IT.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: Yeah some point it did.
Speaker 0: It technically works.
Speaker 1: Who knows if I was spamming or whatever, but yeah.
Speaker 1: So anyway There's a website here at flirty calm and it's how do you set up a mail server on a new slash Linux system?
Speaker 1: Step by step guide you install post fix.
Speaker 1: it would do plus post fix plus courier.
Speaker 1: I'm at plus my SQL plus mf as the new plus spam assassin.
Speaker 1: plus clamor plus sazzle plus telus plus around cube plus post gray, it tells you how to set up every Single piece.
Speaker 1: I wish they would just give you a fucking CD where it was set up already and when the CD turns on You type in your domain.
Speaker 1: it gives you the MX records you paste them and you push go and it's set up.
Speaker 1: That's what they should make and maybe I can make that from these instructions.
Speaker 0: Maybe and then make it a virtual image.
Speaker 1: just make it.
Speaker 0: Make it an AMI so you can just boom your email on Amazon with a little back door to where years from now You can use it to take over all these networks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, great Take over your emails.
Speaker 0: No, seriously.
Speaker 0: I mean your job at least is programming.
Speaker 0: So it's understandable that you would not have deep expertise on email server administration.
Speaker 1: I can administer any other kind of sir.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my job was IT.
Speaker 0: My career was IT.
Speaker 0: My degree is in IT.
Speaker 0: I am no more capable of getting email servers working than Scott is.
Speaker 1: I'm very capable.
Speaker 1: I read these instructions.
Speaker 0: Yeah but the last time I set up email to work was like one of my capstone projects at our IT in system administration - Hmm I had to set up an email server a Wins server which already is starting to date me.
Speaker 0: So anyway things of the day Little video game thing of the day here.
Speaker 0: Uh, Scott was not aware of these differences.
Speaker 1: I was not aware at all.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 1: I don't know what to do with my life.
Speaker 0: I was aware of some of the everything I knew is wrong.
Speaker 0: My worldview is shattered, but not all of them.
Speaker 0: So there's a history of Japanese Nintendo games being way harder than the American equivalents because Japan has a Final Fantasy 4 1 Mega Man 2 having the easy mode which doesn't exist.
Speaker 0: Final Fantasy 6 Yeah.
Speaker 1: So every game.
Speaker 0: pretty much Japan had a very low opinion of the intelligence of the average American gamer.
Speaker 0: not Unfounded.
Speaker 0: they also had a very low opinion.
Speaker 1: or was it a self-fulfilling prophecy?
Speaker 1: Maybe if they had given us the real Mario 3 and such then we would be better at games.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: but at the same time maybe they rightfully assumed that Americans would give up in frustration rather than rising to the challenge.
Speaker 0: I Don't know because I played Final Fantasy 4j and I came as fucking hard.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, so this is a complete enumeration to the best of my knowledge of all the differences between the United States release and the Japanese release of Super Mario Brothers 3.
Speaker 1: Some I thought they were identical.
Speaker 0: Yeah, some of the differences are subtle.
Speaker 0: like there's some graphical changes.
Speaker 0: like the throne rooms are just different for no reason.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably for memory reasons.
Speaker 1: It's an NES.
Speaker 0: Uh, there's a door that's in a different place because it's harder if the doors in that's play in that place in Japanese only slightly and I wouldn't die there in American Mario 3. if you have say the fire flower and you get hit you turn into big Mario You get hit again.
Speaker 0: turn into small Mario get hit again.
Speaker 0: you die in Japanese Mario 3 just like every other Mario.
Speaker 0: if you're fire flower and you get hit small Mario hit again dead.
Speaker 1: It's Super Mario world different between Japan and us.
Speaker 0: I'm Not sure.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: actually I Only knew about Mario 3 because of Nintendo power features and a lot of research as a kid.
Speaker 0: Okay, but there were some things like this crazy glitch.
Speaker 0: I did not know about with a fourth warp whistle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know what the hell that is.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's weird that they changed like that end to like.
Speaker 0: Maybe they just realized at the end of this cuz level 5 was kind of glitchy.
Speaker 0: in general you get the impression that it was The rushed one and they cut a lot out at the last minute.
Speaker 0: and I feel like oh, yeah I don't know.
Speaker 0: sky world had the most weird glitches that currybows shoe just kind of hanging out.
Speaker 1: That's not doesn't sound like something that you just sort of you know.
Speaker 1: Spit out quickly, right?
Speaker 1: They put a lot of work in a curry bow shoe and also that tower where you go up and down.
Speaker 0: They did but I feel like because that's our sky world always felt kind of different from all the other parts of Mario 3.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we can talk about that on a Tuesday.
Speaker 1: Yeah Alright, so another thing of the day.
Speaker 1: This is just a YouTube channel.
Speaker 1: Not a specific YouTube video.
Speaker 1: I found out about this.
Speaker 1: There's a YouTube channel KBS world TV and KBS is just a Korean TV stations one of the biggest ones and They just put a whole bunch of shit on YouTube with subtitles legit totally legit full HD.
Speaker 1: Whatever who like constantly like all like you just watch their dramas.
Speaker 1: You can watch your whatever.
Speaker 1: It's just all on there and it's like whoa, how come like other TV channels don't do this.
Speaker 1: How come I?
Speaker 1: you know, it's like yeah, obviously You know the Koreans pretty good at spreading their culture on the Internet's better than the other countries.
Speaker 1: But you know, how come there isn't like.
Speaker 1: I don't know the French Broadcast network putting their shows up on it, you know, the BBC does it with their stupid?
Speaker 1: I player you can only watch if you have a VPN or live there or what, right?
Speaker 1: It's like everyone is getting this wrong here.
Speaker 1: is there is a real TV station getting it, right?
Speaker 1: I hope other people follow suit because if you look even the unpopular videos They post are getting like hundreds of thousands of views.
Speaker 1: It is not unpopular All right, so I want to see a day We're pretty much just every TV station just puts all their shows on YouTube with subtitles to spread them around the world Perhaps with a pre-funding model.
Speaker 0: Yeah being puppy care.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you don't need some shady fucking fansubbers posting it on weird websites and whatnot.
Speaker 1: They just post legit.
Speaker 0: So yeah in the meta moment the book club book is I do by William Gibson.
Speaker 0: now I started reading it again because I had a lot a bunch of long flights.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 0: Haha, well, I finish it again and then start reading further.
Speaker 1: I have a week a week vacation between Christmas and New Year's.
Speaker 1: That's my time.
Speaker 0: So I started reading it.
Speaker 0: I read just like the first chapter and with all the cyberpunk jargon and awesome just Stereotypical cliched cyberpunk crap that happens in the beginning.
Speaker 0: It's easy to forget that it wasn't cliche when this book was written.
Speaker 0: guys This book was written in 1996.
Speaker 1: yep 1996.
Speaker 0: I in Upgraded to a thirty three six KBP PS modem.
Speaker 1: I was a freshman in high school.
Speaker 1: I was maybe like 14 years old.
Speaker 0: There's cyber the.
Speaker 0: the ideas and books like this were not common.
Speaker 0: It's the one of those situations where something seems cliche and you forget that it came about before that thing was cliche.
Speaker 0: This book is kind kind of awesome.
Speaker 0: So I actually I'm really looking forward to reading the rest of it again.
Speaker 1: Yep Okay, other things mag fest go to egg fest.
Speaker 0: We're going to be there the I don't know if we're allowed to say it Or not, but I'll at least say that we're doing.
Speaker 0: we're going to be on three panels at mag fest two of which We can't talk about yet Scott are splitting up.
Speaker 0: We're actually four panels total.
Speaker 0: Scott and I are gonna split up and each sit on a different panel about a different topic.
Speaker 0: I think Scott's on something about Video game controllers and I'm on something about privacy and games.
Speaker 0: and We're both going to be on one about Games of the future like gaming 30 years from now kind of kind of like y plus 30 But without any trademark infringement whatsoever on that name.
Speaker 0: And we're going to be doing a longer harder version of bad games that we did at PAX Mmm, we have an extra 30 minutes.
Speaker 0: So Prepare yourself.
Speaker 0: I gotta find more cartridges of et before we get there.
Speaker 1: They're easy to get.
Speaker 0: Magfest is awesome.
Speaker 0: You should all be there.
Speaker 0: It is the only convention better than it for gaming is packs.
Speaker 1: Yep What else is there?
Speaker 1: not much?
Speaker 1: It's December.
Speaker 1: It's the holidays in the United States.
Speaker 1: in most of the world It's also really cold in the United States at this time of year in the New York northern parts of relive.
Speaker 1: So shows may be spotty until January in which point shows are have been historically steady.
Speaker 0: Yep, usually we kind of fade around the holidays and then we appear with crazy stories and bullshit between January up to March April which is PAX East anime Boston time.
Speaker 0: I mean think we're gonna come back from magfest and the holidays and New Year's and everything in January and Then we're gonna have all the videos of our lectures from magfest.
Speaker 0: We're gonna have all the stories from magfest.
Speaker 0: We're gonna have all our holiday crap.
Speaker 0: We're gonna.
Speaker 0: we're gonna come out strong again But there's gonna be a time soon where it's gonna be.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be slim pickings.
Speaker 1: anyway.
Speaker 1: for you geek nights fans You should go to our website front row crew.
Speaker 1: calm.
Speaker 0: You should go to our awesome forum Which is newly hosted on vanilla with the new version of vanilla and you should go to all our places like YouTube and shit.
Speaker 0: Yes, the more you spread around our YouTube videos the faster we will continue to produce geek nights presents And All our.
Speaker 0: I don't think Scott wants to do any more of them But I am going to record my own episode of another radio free equestria because unless Scott wants to not really Did you watch the all three episodes of the new season?
Speaker 0: Yes, so the the ghost and mr.
Speaker 0: Chicken episode where they get scared with a pipe organ, yes Okay, so I noticed something.
Speaker 0: Yeah When she drinks that potion that gives her magical memories.
Speaker 0: logo on that potion is the logo on another bad thing from before and When she cast the spell to make it work.
Speaker 0: It's the same bad magic that somber used and that she used when she was interacting with somber stuff.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Yeah, I could I could do a show on that.
Speaker 0: if you wanted to do a show on that.
Speaker 1: That's the whole show.
Speaker 1: You just did it.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but I didn't go in detail.
Speaker 1: There's not much else to say.
Speaker 0: That's some theories.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: All right listeners.
Speaker 0: Do you want us to do it or not?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the people who are pony fans are gonna say yes, please and everyone else is not gonna say anything.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'll say this cuz no one's gonna say no don't do that Cuz they just won't watch it if you do it if they don't care.
Speaker 0: No people have said no don't do that.
Speaker 0: Okay All I have to say is ponies is back and you know what after the most recent episode It's holding on.
Speaker 0: I can just pretend that equestria girls was never made.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the new.
Speaker 1: it's not awful It's just not.
Speaker 1: well, I don't like.
Speaker 1: I want to watch it so badly Like I want to watch South Park so badly or Wednesday or adventure time Adventure time adventure now.
Speaker 0: I want to watch more badly than ponies But not well because your time is doing the things that if ponies did similar kinds of things They'd be both a tier shows.
Speaker 1: The only thing I really want to watch badly.
Speaker 1: It's Kill La Kill.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, did you watch the newest episode?
Speaker 0: No, I did not.
Speaker 0: Oh But I am caught up on adventure time, okay I saw James.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like this.
Speaker 1: This is a good guy.
Speaker 0: I like how both ponies and and adventure time have had the direct continuity episodes.
Speaker 1: You notice James had the brack voice actor.
Speaker 0: notice how James had a red shirt on those proving that peeps Planned him to be what he was from the beginning.
Speaker 0: She brought him to be used for that purpose if things went wrong.
Speaker 0: Okay, yeah sure I would do radio for you but Scott doesn't wanna you can do your own radio for you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe I will do with Judy sue actually.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe I should.
Speaker 0: Judith I know you listen to geek nights.
Speaker 1: What why?
Speaker 0: Let's let's do it let's do it radio for you.
Speaker 0: Okay anyway So there is a little bit of a brouhaha on the internet.
Speaker 0: This is all you a little bit hubbub about a job posting from one penny arcade incorporated.
Speaker 0: I Don't want to talk about the social side of this because it's obvious I don't want to talk about the the all the issues except the actual job posting because a lot of the complaints.
Speaker 0: Here's the deal.
Speaker 0: They posted a pretty accurate job posting for the kind of tech guy they wanted because the tech guy they have is leaving to do something else.
Speaker 0: so the internet went crazy about it and About a third of the people maybe half the people who are complaining about this We're complaining about the wrong thing.
Speaker 0: and the people who are complaining in the manner that we're about to talk about.
Speaker 0: There's a reason those people do not have high paying jobs.
Speaker 0: So a complaint.
Speaker 0: well here.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read the job.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean a lot of people are complaining simply because they're penny arcade haters.
Speaker 1: They'll hate on anything penny arcade does ever.
Speaker 1: they'll find a reason to make it like a huge, you know Catastrophe where it's like this 10,000 job postings just like this every day about companies You don't care about.
Speaker 1: so you're not making a hullabaloo.
Speaker 0: now there have been.
Speaker 0: don't get us wrong.
Speaker 0: there are penny arcade Catastrophes.
Speaker 1: my crew lick like this one also.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this is it.
Speaker 1: This is yeah the I mean asking someone to work a zillion hours is awful.
Speaker 1: the end.
Speaker 0: well I'm not sure how many hours they actually work.
Speaker 1: the guy said he there was a posting by the guy who had That post up.
Speaker 0: I read that.
Speaker 1: he said yeah, basically you can't go anywhere because you're on a call.
Speaker 1: You're the only guy.
Speaker 0: there's two separate things There's the on-call thing and then there's the actual working hours thing.
Speaker 0: because not to disparage him But based on reading that and seeing just kind of how this all evolved I don't think other than the on-call aspect the amount of work.
Speaker 0: It would take to do.
Speaker 0: what they need is Maybe Maybe 20 hours of work a week.
Speaker 1: right but if you work at penny arcade who's gonna make you stay there for a zillion hours A week, and it'll look down on you if you leave at 5 every day?
Speaker 0: Maybe maybe not.
Speaker 0: maybe what have you got everything?
Speaker 0: what if you came to the office just fucking hung out and play games cuz there Was no work to do cuz you did it all who would fire you?
Speaker 0: maybe I?
Speaker 0: Don't know.
Speaker 0: if he's smart you definitely give you a talking to?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: not because there's there.
Speaker 0: It's that that's one of the biggest problems with tech.
Speaker 0: is the?
Speaker 0: you know what?
Speaker 0: it's the same thing that managers of Terrible fast-food jobs will say.
Speaker 0: you'll hear this phrase a lot.
Speaker 0: They'll say if you got time to lean you got time to clean Meaning they're paying you for your time, so if you if you finish all the work It's your responsibility to find more work to do and to work more because otherwise why are they paying you?
Speaker 1: Why are you?
Speaker 1: maybe you should have hired paid hired me for half the time that you hired before?
Speaker 0: My fault that you mis-hired me, but the problem is they'll hire you for half the time But then pay you half as much, and then you don't have enough money to live.
Speaker 0: We kind of have this messed up to pay me twice pay me more per hour And then we have this messed up situation in America.
Speaker 0: This is why you're expected to have a full-time job of 40.
Speaker 1: Technology which is why we're not talking about this part.
Speaker 1: We're talking about the technology part.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I feel you itching to talk about it.
Speaker 1: No, that was all I just said.
Speaker 1: the end now.
Speaker 0: so here are the requirements of the job.
Speaker 0: mm-hmm You need to have an attention level of attention to detail that everyone writes that in every job description ever it means nothing I know except it.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: It doesn't mean it means nothing except that anyone who doesn't I would not hire.
Speaker 0: Sure, I mean if I get an email from someone that has a how do you measure someone's attention to detail?
Speaker 0: Simple if they follow the instructions that I put on the job posting and there are no misspellings in their resume or the email they Sent me
Speaker 1: done
Speaker 0: if they don't meet that record that they basically if they don't have that then There's
Speaker 1: no reason to write that on the res on the job posting.
Speaker 0: yeah, maybe I don't know.
Speaker 0: Maybe you need to write things like not creeper.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you should write that.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 0: Strong project management skills okay, which is something most people who say they have do not have.
Speaker 1: it's such a subjective not you know?
Speaker 0: Measurable yeah, so whatever motivated self-starter who can overcome and work around issues independently Yeah, okay flexibility to travel 30% of the time Not uncommon in tech.
Speaker 0: I Travel almost that person.
Speaker 1: I mean you got to be going to PAX is you're gonna be good right?
Speaker 0: I mean look I was just in Turkey for a week right?
Speaker 0: I go to Turkey I go I travel overseas.
Speaker 0: so much for Work that I had two sets of extra pages added to my passport, and I will still probably fill it before it expires.
Speaker 0: You have no problems working in a creative and potentially offensive environment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, definitely not a problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's penny arcade.
Speaker 0: Flexibility adapting to deadlines changing schedules priorities.
Speaker 0: You know the same old work well under pressure Ability to communicate and work in a team environment.
Speaker 0: Yeah again.
Speaker 1: I can't work with people you can't work.
Speaker 1: Go work on go be an author right woods have no problem appearing on camera.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay, what's for a lot of people?
Speaker 0: tech people even complain about that one they?
Speaker 0: People we know okay said things like they would have.
Speaker 0: someone would have to pay me extra.
Speaker 0: I feel like that's a huge negative of being on camera Which I guess is just the different kinds of jobs don't go out in public ever.
Speaker 0: like I never leave I have tech job clothes on your blinds.
Speaker 0: I worked for one financial company where I was basically the guy in the back room making everything work.
Speaker 0: now I work for a tech company where I do private lectures that are videoed for Gigantic audiences on a regular basis.
Speaker 0: like that shit comes with the territory I consider being on camera a perk Not a negative.
Speaker 0: you could pay me less if I get to be on camera and get some personal Legend of Krauser not just the back end credited Legend of Krauser, yeah Okay, the messed up one because this is kind of relevant to the tech world.
Speaker 0: if anything breaks in the middle of the night You were expected to be on call 24/7.
Speaker 1: No, you're supposed to have multiple people in on call shifts so that people can have lives or not?
Speaker 0: everything is production critical 24/7.
Speaker 1: obviously I mean Seriously know what you can't.
Speaker 1: I mean you know it is penny arcade is?
Speaker 1: you know?
Speaker 1: this website and all these people are living off Of it, so if it goes down you're losing money, and that feeds the people who work there, right?
Speaker 1: But if people can't read a webcomic until I get in in the morning And then at nine o'clock in the morning they can read the webcomic again.
Speaker 1: That's not a big fucking deal.
Speaker 1: That is a very very small deal.
Speaker 1: It's not a bank.
Speaker 1: It's not a hospital.
Speaker 1: It's not you know fucking military systems.
Speaker 1: It's not the stock market.
Speaker 1: It's not something.
Speaker 1: That's so disastrous.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: you can't read a webcomic for six hours.
Speaker 1: I can fix that in the morning.
Speaker 1: You don't have to wake me up for that right just because you care about it that much.
Speaker 1: the rest of the world doesn't care About it that much.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Let it go.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna skip all the work-life Balance stuff because that's a Thursday topic not a day topic and you'll skip the.
Speaker 0: have to live in Seattle Which is not New York Yeah which is Not as bad as it could be.
Speaker 0: there was the other job posting that for packs event manager.
Speaker 0: that requires you to live three weeks In Seattle and one week in godforsaken, Connecticut.
Speaker 0: Yep every month.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not gonna spend that much time in Connecticut.
Speaker 0: Nope So real cut real actual requirements.
Speaker 0: BA or BS degree in computer science or related field.
Speaker 1: You got to have that.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: That's a fine requirement.
Speaker 0: internet In my personal experience.
Speaker 0: I have met very few Competent tech people who don't have one of those.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry But a lot of people know how to code or they know how to set up a server.
Speaker 1: But the diff I know people who do have that and don't know how to cook.
Speaker 0: Yeah the people who have the degrees at least from a reasonably good school tend to have all of the skills they can set up a server and write code.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: a minimum of three years in development and project management.
Speaker 1: That's not much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, preferably in a professional.
Speaker 1: Basically, they don't want someone fresh out of college.
Speaker 1: They want someone who has been able to do this before because you are going to be responsible for their livelihoods effectively.
Speaker 1: So they want you to at least know what you're doing.
Speaker 0: some Yeah, but also not just someone who can write code but also someone who can manage the code itself.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and those are two different jobs.
Speaker 0: That's why RIT had computer science and software engineering.
Speaker 0: Strong experience in PHP MySQL JavaScript CSS Apache jQuery Ajax, duh modern technologies Relatively speaking.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're a web person of any kind those things should all be on your resume already.
Speaker 0: Strong experience in one of Java Python Ruby or any other object-oriented language.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't really matter.
Speaker 1: You just gotta be able to write code.
Speaker 0: Yeah If you if you know Python and you do web development and you have to do something that's Java instead You can just do it.
Speaker 0: if you're a good programmer, of course Maybe you'll have to look up a few keywords and things along the way.
Speaker 0: change an IDE setup, but it's not hard.
Speaker 0: a history of running running and configuring multiple server environments including load balancers web accelerators caching systems databases.
Speaker 1: Not hard.
Speaker 0: a history of running multiple server environments load balancers varnish.
Speaker 0: So I do that.
Speaker 0: the complaint I saw from a lot of people on the internet Was that that set of requirements does not describe one person it describes a number of people.
Speaker 0: That no, well the hours of all those skills the hours describes a number of people but these skills describe If you ignore the 24/7 support thing Well for a shop like penny arcade the number of hours of someone competent.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah a 40-hour can we work?
Speaker 0: week would cover all of that?
Speaker 1: Absolutely.
Speaker 1: I mean that's I do all that.
Speaker 0: So most of the night working less than 20 hours 40 hours a week who are complaining that Nobody has all those skills Including also being I have all those skills Basic IT in the office like configure the office firewall cuz something changed.
Speaker 1: all those skills and more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyone with competence in tech could do all those things and and could learn the few things.
Speaker 0: They don't know, right?
Speaker 1: There's a lot there's a lot of people out there I noticed because I hire people and I interview people and they have Instead of being generally knowledgeable with computers They know one thing like.
Speaker 1: they did Ruby on Rails Tutorials and they made web apps with Ruby on Rails and all they did was write Ruby on Rails code and they learned Ruby on Rails But they didn't learn anything else.
Speaker 1: so they can't.
Speaker 1: if you ask them to do something the same exact thing and something else they can't Do it because they didn't learn HTTP or how the web works.
Speaker 0: they just learned Ruby on Rails Ruby on Rails and they don't know how to type app get install Ruby.
Speaker 1: They hosted it on Heroku right which did all the hosting work for them, so they never learned how to set up a Linux server.
Speaker 1: They did everything on their Mac right following a tutorial to set it up once right the development environment.
Speaker 1: They don't know how to set up the server environment at all because Heroku did it for them.
Speaker 1: They paid a bunch of money extra to Heroku for the more expensive hosting And that's pretty much it right.
Speaker 1: It's like they know exactly one thing and they don't know any other things.
Speaker 1: They don't understand how computers work or anything about that and they probably don't have the BS in computer science.
Speaker 1: So they're not good for having any sort of real job.
Speaker 1: I would never hire you for anything unless I really just needed like an army of Ruby on Rails.
Speaker 0: guys who only know one Thing and now yeah, so guys aside from the 24/7 work-life balance thing for support Yeah, the the technical requirements of this job are very minimal actually.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like that's a baby like really really low-hanging fruit like anyone fresh out of college Would probably should be able to do these things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so they want.
Speaker 1: they just want someone who's they're sure can do those things and isn't?
Speaker 1: probably I could have done that job Out of college.
Speaker 0: Oh easily easily.
Speaker 0: I Could not have just I'm not really a developer like it would have If I did it, it would have taken me 80 hour weeks just to learn They should have posted a job when I was coming out of college.
Speaker 1: They would have gotten me.
Speaker 0: I've been too naive and dumb and take like like when I saw that other posting they had before for packs event manager And I read it and it literally was this is a list of everything.
Speaker 0: rims good at mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Just write down the list.
Speaker 0: rim rim rim rim rim Sure, of course then I would have.
Speaker 0: I would have I don't know.
Speaker 0: Imagine a weird alternate reality.
Speaker 0: We're fresh out of college.
Speaker 0: Those two jobs got posted and we applied for them.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm sure this happens in lots of other fields too, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you never passed by a car dealer and it's like they specialize in one kind of car and it's like dude You know how cars work.
Speaker 1: shouldn't you be able to repair any car, right?
Speaker 1: But no, it's like it's not just the ones that are on the dealership, right?
Speaker 1: It'll be like it's like some, you know independent mechanic, but it's like the whole parking lot is all Benz's.
Speaker 1: It's like we fix Benz's.
Speaker 1: that's it.
Speaker 1: And it's like if you brought him a Ford, I'd bet they'd fuck it up.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: shouldn't you understand cars fundamentally on some fundamental level mechanics?
Speaker 0: Well, it might be the expertise of you know, they're good at working with these cars don't want to work on cars.
Speaker 1: They're not good at working with I'm sure but it's like I feel like if I knew mechanics and I was a mechanic I would be able to fix any car.
Speaker 0: Oh Scott, I'll put it this way.
Speaker 0: If you brought me an HP UX server and something wasn't working I could probably fix it.
Speaker 1: I could definitely fix it.
Speaker 0: But it would take me twice as long and I'd be pissed off the whole time because it's HP UX.
Speaker 1: It takes me just as long to Google HP UX as it takes me to Google.
Speaker 1: It actually takes me slightly longer to Google HP UX than it takes me to Google BSD because it's one more character to type.
Speaker 0: Ah, here's the trouble HP UX.
Speaker 0: you won't find as much up-to-date modern useful information because it's not commonly used.
Speaker 0: It's old.
Speaker 1: I could still do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could but it'd take you longer than someone whose thing was HP UX.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see you would?
Speaker 0: we got it?
Speaker 0: Whatever race.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll set up an HP UX server and then I'll break something on it.
Speaker 0: I'll find some old surprises.
Speaker 1: break NTP.
Speaker 1: That's what you do.
Speaker 1: You'd be like out the clocks off by like a millisecond.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, yeah, it's working.
Speaker 1: who gives a shit about a millisecond.
Speaker 1: It's a webcomic.
Speaker 0: So funny story.
Speaker 0: back at RIT one of my capstone classes was this sort of like holistic class of all the aspects of IT and system administration together into one and One of the final labs was we had a team and me and Katsu were on this team with some people and we had this complex environment with some servers some clients a wireless access point that they connected through and a router.
Speaker 0: and we had this whole lab Set up and we got it all working and we had to make it secure and all that BS.
Speaker 0: and then for one of Our lab practicals we had to leave the room and the professor's broke six things.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and we had to Bring them back up as quickly as possible and document what we did.
Speaker 1: reimage done.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we came back in and we look at oh sure enough, you know our clients can't connect to the servers and one of the server demons had crashed.
Speaker 0: here we did we rebooted everything and Then it still didn't work.
Speaker 0: and then we looked and the firewall like the config file was corrupt because of our log message.
Speaker 0: So we fixed that and then it was fine.
Speaker 0: then we came back and we were like, yeah We fixed it all immediately.
Speaker 0: There was only one problem and they got really mad at us and it turned out that all the changes they had made Like they did all this really complex crap.
Speaker 0: One of the things they did is they put dummy records in the ARP table of the router So that traffic would only flow one way from certain hosts.
Speaker 0: Okay, the ARP tables wiped out.
Speaker 0: if you just recycle the device There was no point in troubleshooting it.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: We saw it wasn't working.
Speaker 0: We just recycled it and it was fixed.
Speaker 0: Sure They ended up having to give us an A but they were not happy.
Speaker 1: No I would be a lot smarter than that.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: What would I do to a computer to make that would break it?
Speaker 1: But you would have a hard time finding that anything was broken.
Speaker 1: Well, I still there has to be a bug report or it's unfair.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there has to be a description of a behavior That's incorrect.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Yep, like can't log in.
Speaker 0: It says password incorrect or I run the application in the web browser and it works except it doesn't display any of the images.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like what I could do is I could be like, okay No one can log in.
Speaker 1: and then I would like the Etsy password file and the shadow file would still be correct.
Speaker 1: But actually I would find I would reconfigure it to actually be using some shadow file that's hidden somewhere So that you wouldn't even you have to find the config file that points to which shadow file is being used.
Speaker 0: I just said yeah I'd set the total number of file handles that you can have open to something really small so stuff would break or I would be.
Speaker 1: The sound isn't only working in some apps and I like what I did to you is I like swapped out your kernel modules To change the sound driver or something.
Speaker 1: It'd be like, yeah, you'll never see that in a million years.
Speaker 0: But yeah again not talking about the 24/7 support stuff the work-life balance all those things.
Speaker 0: There's a discussion to be had there.
Speaker 0: Don't get me wrong.
Speaker 0: I think the 24/7 support requirement is ridiculous bullshit.
Speaker 0: I Refused to be on call.
Speaker 0: the part of the reason I have the care I have is that I was done with being on call Ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the other thing with this right is like not only are these people sort of ridiculous saying Oh one person can't have all these skills It's bad if you don't have all of them, right?
Speaker 1: Like what is someone I know in people who are like system administration skills and development skills?
Speaker 1: They set up a web server and it would be the most insecure Wrongly network configured thing in the universe and then the thing would just get taken down as soon as anyone tried to attack it ever.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it's like why did I just get taken down?
Speaker 1: Well, you didn't do any IP tables at all.
Speaker 1: You did SSH with passwords.
Speaker 0: Oh most people in the world turn off IP tables the first thing they do.
Speaker 1: Why does it should?
Speaker 1: it's turned off usually by default.
Speaker 1: You have to set it up to actually add things to it Oh, and then they'll turn off.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know what I would do if I was gonna fuck up your server I would just turn on se Linux and not tell you.
Speaker 1: Yeah But yeah, it's like, you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: there's things that you have to do, you know.
Speaker 1: They didn't turn on automatic security updates and then they didn't constantly maintain the server every single day with the new security update.
Speaker 1: So this no, this is zero day.
Speaker 1: wouldn't you just put out a patch?
Speaker 1: I read the patch, you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know you haven't installed that patch yet.
Speaker 1: I nail you with it Whatever it is, right because you haven't done it yet because you didn't set up auto update to install as soon as it would do Pushed it out.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Good job because that's not something that's on by default.
Speaker 0: Now the other hilarious thing was the speculation about salaries because they make this point in the thing about salaries negotiable quotes.
Speaker 0: But you should know up front.
Speaker 0: We're not terribly money motivated group.
Speaker 0: We're more likely to spend less money on salary.
Speaker 0: invest that in making your day-to-day work life better Sure.
Speaker 0: Now that could reek of startup culture of hey you work somewhere cool, but we don't pay you.
Speaker 0: We don't know.
Speaker 1: but I'm not motivated by money either.
Speaker 1: But there's still had.
Speaker 1: I am motivated almost entirely by money, but you still have to pay me a lot of money.
Speaker 1: You can't not pay me a lot of money.
Speaker 1: So I saw someone Someone who actually someone who's competent and has all those skills.
Speaker 1: They obviously didn't put any numbers so we can't judge.
Speaker 1: they might you know, because they're so rich They might be like, yeah, not a lot of money 300k, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever I was going to apply for this job.
Speaker 1: I Would ask oh if they first of all they had absolutely they must get rid of the on-call, right?
Speaker 1: So if they agree to get rid of the on-call nonsense Then you'd probably had to pay me like 150 to 200,000.
Speaker 1: I was gonna say I would ask for 150 because I think the fringe benefit someone with those Someone with those skills is rare and that's the market value.
Speaker 0: I would argue that someone of those skills is not that rare.
Speaker 1: It's more rare than you think.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess go try to hire someone Those tech skills and the social skills required for a job like this.
Speaker 1: Yeah find someone who has all that whole package.
Speaker 1: Yeah, kind of rare and especially they're geographically limiting me.
Speaker 0: I was gonna say I would only ask for 150k because the fringe benefits of a job like this actually would be pretty sweet.
Speaker 0: Yeah But if that was at borrowing Oh I saw a post on Twitter a tweet that said something to the effect of Wow Anyone who applies to this should better at least ask for 50k.
Speaker 0: Jesus like what?
Speaker 0: I got paid that at my internship.
Speaker 0: Like do you people have no conception of what the tech world is like?
Speaker 0: 50k is what teachers make.
Speaker 1: It's not enough money.
Speaker 0: that's close to the poverty line in New York City.
Speaker 1: that is not yeah And Seattle's not much better right now.
Speaker 1: Where are you gonna live?
Speaker 1: And the hostel the other?
Speaker 0: a lot of people because there's the no salary number is listed here.
Speaker 0: that that is tip.
Speaker 0: people seem to Just really think that this job means that they don't pay anything.
Speaker 0: I get the impression they're gonna pay a reasonable amount of money.
Speaker 0: They're just not gonna pay some ridiculous amount of money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I might be wrong.
Speaker 1: I don't know but probably gonna play slightly less than the market rate.
Speaker 1: I mean no one.
Speaker 0: they'll probably shoot for like 80 or 90.
Speaker 1: anyone who has these social and technical skills to be Considered for the job.
Speaker 1: right you're in Seattle.
Speaker 1: It's probably gonna be like an ex Amazon employee.
Speaker 1: They said don't relocate you Yeah to Seattle, but it's like it's someone who's willing to live in Seattle.
Speaker 0: So it's well, they're obviously going after the single nerd demographic.
Speaker 1: It's an intelligent city person is gonna know what their own market value is exactly and is only gonna mark my noble Smartly negotiate it down a little bit.
Speaker 1: if you're not smart enough to do that You're probably not smart enough to be considered for the job in the first place.
Speaker 0: now the well Yeah, I don't want to get into the 24-7 any of the social stuff.
Speaker 0: But if you out there some tech nerd and you're gonna try to apply for this job.
Speaker 0: Here's my advice to you one Don't list me as a reference unless you've talked to me at least once before now.
Speaker 0: Okay kids I Yes, people have done that.
Speaker 0: I've written a lot of college recommendation letters and reference letters in the last couple of years and I Only actually write them for people who I can actually vouch for.
Speaker 0: so those of you who got letters from me It's because I actually have some respect for you.
Speaker 0: Those of you who I didn't write them for it's because I had no idea who you were.
Speaker 0: So if you think that you can list people like us because we lecture at penny arcade, you know at the packs penny arcade expo Unless we know who you are.
Speaker 0: That's not gonna help.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna recommend you.
Speaker 1: I don't know who you are.
Speaker 0: do Ask for the salary you think you need notice how they didn't say what a salary is.
Speaker 0: That's common in tech jobs.
Speaker 1: ask for more.
Speaker 0: ask for what you think you need plus plus 10 or 15 K. I mean I made a big mistake when I applied to my first job in the.
Speaker 1: I could have made a lot more money if I Would have asked for more monies in the olden days.
Speaker 0: I asked when I when I got that first job for that broker dealer I asked for 60 K. I was like, yeah, I need at least 60 K and they were like sure done.
Speaker 0: You're hired Yeah, I was like, oh shit.
Speaker 0: I fucked up fucked up fucked up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then a month later.
Speaker 0: They're like, okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're good.
Speaker 0: And then they raised it to 90.
Speaker 0: They're like, yeah, you really asked for the wrong amount of money kid.
Speaker 0: So even I. so don't make the mistake I made.
Speaker 0: if you ask for the amount of money That's reasonable and you are skilled and you don't get the job then you didn't want the job.
Speaker 0: You don't want a job that will pay you less than you actually need.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night But with me.
Speaker 1: I better help her find her in the Katniss.
Speaker 1: So I dance with my manage advance asking if I could just get a friendly payment advance.
Speaker 1: He blows me off.
Speaker 1: So I scoffed on my smock.
Speaker 1: check the clock.
Speaker 1: Take it off.
Speaker 1: Check my wad feeling soft.
Speaker 0: All I got is Gotta get a whopper and a 14.
Speaker 0: Well, I got 545 and it's 545 Gotta get.