Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, October 29th, 2013.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we talk about Burning Con 5?
Speaker 0: Pentec or whatever?
Speaker 0: The most recent Burning Con.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Little late getting going on the show tonight due to a jackass.
Speaker 0: Because it's live and people live here long enough and use the subway enough, you'll start to recognize that they tend to be very circumspect and/or generic when they announce why there's a problem on the subway.
Speaker 0: They'll say, "Train traffic ahead of
Speaker 0: us."
Speaker 0: Or, "Due to an incident at another
Speaker 0: station."
Speaker 0: Or, "A police
Speaker 0: investigation.".
Speaker 0: But occasionally, you'll have the person who either is new, or angry, or fed up, or has a sense of humor who will tell you what actually went down.
Speaker 0: And today, that happened to me.
Speaker 0: Took me like an hour to get home, but I'm going to get on the subway, and I take the 45 up to Grand Central.
Speaker 0: And I go down, and when you walk down the subway stairs, you see a huge crowd, which is usually a warning sign that something's fucked up.
Speaker 1: Well, a larger crowd than usual for that time and place.
Speaker 0: When I say large crowd, I mean a newly large crowd.
Speaker 0: Not the expected thousand people, but more than a thousand people on the platform.
Speaker 0: So I kind of fight my way down there, and I look around, and then the thing must have just happened, because there's an announcement, and a train comes back into the station on the other track.
Speaker 1: Backwards?
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is always... Yeah, trains.
Speaker 0: So an announcement comes on.
Speaker 1: The only thing worse than that is the garbage train.
Speaker 0: Oh my God, the garbage train is the scariest thing, especially if you don't expect it.
Speaker 0: It's like seeing a skeleton when you didn't expect to see a skeleton.
Speaker 0: So the train comes back, and then they make an announcement that seven trains are all holding in station, which is kind of...
Speaker 1: Not seven trains, but the trains with the number seven on them.
Speaker 0: Yes, the seven trains in New York City, the seventh line.
Speaker 1: It's not like the eighth train got passed.
Speaker 0: So then another person comes on and says, and I'm paraphrasing here, "Due to a jackass on the tracks, all seven train service is suspended while the police go try to a police investigation at Fifth
Speaker 0: Avenue.".
Speaker 0: As best I can tell, someone got into some sort of altercation, and then jumped down on the tracks and ran off into the tunnels.
Speaker 0: So they cut the power so the police could go chase this guy.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that was resolved, but simultaneously they start announcing that passengers would be advised to go take the N, Q, R, or E service to Queens.
Speaker 0: And yeah, it turns out the E was not running due to an unrelated problem, and the R was not fully running to an unrelated problem.
Speaker 0: What this meant was that there were only two trains that go where I wanted to go, and tens of thousands of people per half hour who want to go in the same direction.
Speaker 0: So imagine the tunnels that have the stairways that go to all these subways in Grand Central, so full of people that you literally cannot move, because people are trying to go in both directions, and the news is not quite disseminated yet.
Speaker 0: So a wall of people trying to get on the 7 confronted with a wall of people trying to get away from the 7, and then a wall of people trying to get back to the 7 after being told the E wasn't running, not aware that the 7 is also not running.
Speaker 0: Long story short, I climbed the side of a stairwell, like on the railings, to get past a crowd and shimmied my way up an escalator on the edge to shove my way onto an N train, and that's how I got home.
Speaker 0: I was very proud that I made it home, because the crowds behind me were immense and starting to get smelly.
Speaker 0: Also, bonus points for jackass playing music so loud on the 59th street N platform that no one could hear the announcements, and extra bonus points for the old lady who starts yelling at him to shut up with his goddamn music.
Speaker 0: So that was my commute home.
Speaker 0: That's my openy bit on Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: I also took the NQ and it just went straight here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the NQ was just running, like there wasn't anything wrong with it.
Speaker 1: No extra crowd, no problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the issues were all on the other trains, and it takes a while for things to cascade out.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it's Tuesday, we're back from Burning Con.
Speaker 1: Burn it up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a non-hurricane interrupted Burning Con for once.
Speaker 1: Did you know that, speaking of trains, did you know that today the Brooklyn R and also I think the Rockaway trains are running free?
Speaker 1: Free rides?
Speaker 0: I did know that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there you go.
Speaker 0: Due to the fact that about one year ago New York got fucked by a hurricane, and we still haven't repaired most of the damage.
Speaker 1: Kind of wish there was a hurricane, not because I want anything to get fucked the fuck up just because I want to stay home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was kind of nice to stay home for that week, partly because we live in a place that one, high ground, two, no substantial damage, three, didn't lose power or internet at any point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm on the third floor.
Speaker 1: I don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: You can flood the fuck.
Speaker 0: Not only are we on the third floor, but our building has exceedingly high ceilings, so we're actually like four and a half stories up effectively.
Speaker 1: It's like, for a flood to reach me, you need some biblical shit.
Speaker 0: And our building is on the high ground.
Speaker 0: The evacuation center for serious flooding, like where everyone in this part of Queens would go, is the same city block as my apartment building.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mine is like on the border between like, if you look at the map of different levels of danger.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they have zones.
Speaker 0: They have zones that are like, at what point are you fucked?
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically I'm in the, like across the street is one zone worse than me, and across the street the other direction is like one or two zones worse, and mine is like the one zone better.
Speaker 0: I'm weird.
Speaker 1: It's like literally across the street is worse.
Speaker 0: Where we are right now is the Mad Max zone, because if where we are got flooded, then it's Mad Max in New York City.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about some games.
Speaker 0: All right, so I had the privilege at PAX, thanks to our good friends Ro and Jeremy, this is going back a ways, to play Castellan, the Steve Jackson game.
Speaker 1: That's a game we saw at PAX years ago.
Speaker 1: I think PAX East I first saw.
Speaker 0: I was sold purely on the pieces.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I looked at the game.
Speaker 1: and what is the game?
Speaker 1: It's castle towers, castle walls, and little castle bits, and I'm like, the game where you build castles, shut up and take my money.
Speaker 1: I love castles.
Speaker 0: Don't even care how the game works.
Speaker 1: Don't even give two dams, build castles, A plus game, best game ever, build castles.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I think I might've mentioned this briefly on the show, but I played it, and I've looked into it further, and I've read other people's play reports.
Speaker 0: Don't buy it.
Speaker 0: It is a bad game.
Speaker 0: It is actually a really bad game.
Speaker 1: I don't get to build castles.
Speaker 0: Now here is why, because actually a good friend of ours who has the same taste in games.
Speaker 1: I should make a good castle building game.
Speaker 0: And the same, it's our friend Pete whale shark in the forums.
Speaker 0: He said something to the effect of I paid $25 for Castellan and it was definitely worth it.
Speaker 1: You only played the two player?
Speaker 0: Now, it might be worth it if you like fiddly, random bullshit games or games that are literally impossible to play effectively without pissing off the person across the table.
Speaker 0: Here are the problems with Castellan.
Speaker 1: One, it is just dots and boxes.
Speaker 0: It breaks down mathematically the same way.
Speaker 0: The heuristics are basically the same right down to the long chains.
Speaker 0: Whoever is forced to take action first blows their load and then the other player just wins.
Speaker 0: The game, you have literally three options in terms of how you want to play this game, and one of those options is illusory.
Speaker 0: It only exists if your opponent is dumb.
Speaker 0: Option one, take your turns really quickly.
Speaker 0: Try to just play by the seat of your pants.
Speaker 0: Make the game as unstable as possible and hope that your opponent takes a cue and also moves quickly and that you're anticipating a little bit ahead of them.
Speaker 0: A smart opponent will take their goddamn time on their turn and that won't work.
Speaker 0: Option two, take your goddamn time.
Speaker 0: Fully analyze the entire game.
Speaker 0: state every turn.
Speaker 1: Takes forever.
Speaker 0: Because that lets you win.
Speaker 0: It works.
Speaker 0: The game is fully analyzable.
Speaker 0: It's perfectly symmetrical.
Speaker 1: Wait, but what if we both do that perfectly?
Speaker 1: Does player one win or player two?
Speaker 0: That I did not determine because it was not worth the effort.
Speaker 0: What I did determine was that the only way to play effectively is to analyze based on the cards you can see, the cards your opponent has already played, and the state of the board, every possible combination of options you could make for the rest of the game, which is theoretically possible.
Speaker 0: There aren't that many cards.
Speaker 1: So we should write an AI where when you play against it, it just crushes you horrible every single time.
Speaker 0: An AI, much like with dots and boxes, could be written that was highly effective at this game.
Speaker 0: Or option three, which is what you're actually doing when you play this game, act randomly, completely randomly, until you hit the point where you can calculate the entire rest of the game and then follow your calculation.
Speaker 1: Without a lot of effort?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: And then it's not a matter of who's better at the game.
Speaker 0: It's a matter of who figures out who won first.
Speaker 0: The game is dots and boxes in every possible meaningful way, and it presents no interesting questions, no interesting decisions, and part of this is because the way the game works is.
Speaker 0: you can sort of take as many, like play as many cards as you want on your turn, and the game moves until you've run out of your cards.
Speaker 0: So you can blow your load, kind of like how in dots and boxes you fill in and start doing one of those entire chains, where you get like 10 in a row, but then you've blown your load and your opponent can then blow his load freely because you've already blown your load.
Speaker 0: It's dots and boxes.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to play this game.
Speaker 0: It's not fun unless you play randomly and consciously decide to not seriously try to win.
Speaker 0: It might be fun if you have an egg timer and you force everyone to take no more than one minute on their turn and build in a consequence for failing to move by the end of that one minute.
Speaker 0: Maybe, or something similar, but I don't see anyone actually doing that, and I don't think it would actually be a fun game.
Speaker 1: You need to come up with a game that is fun that just has castles because castles...
Speaker 0: Yes, the pieces are so great, and I can imagine a lot of games that would use these pieces.
Speaker 0: So I'll say this.
Speaker 0: If you design games or have aspirations of doing so, go ahead and buy Castellan.
Speaker 1: Just to get some pieces to build other games with?
Speaker 0: Top notch.
Speaker 0: But don't play Castellan unless you really fucking like dots and boxes.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So I also played some games.
Speaker 1: There's a new place that opened up in New York City.
Speaker 1: I kickstarted it called The Uncommons.
Speaker 1: They're trying to make snakes and lattes in New York, which is... I support that.
Speaker 0: Yes, it's hard to do in New York for a lot of economic reasons.
Speaker 1: It's just south of Washington Square Park.
Speaker 1: Location's pretty good.
Speaker 1: The actual place it's in doesn't have a ton of space, but it has enough, and the tables they have are really good.
Speaker 1: It's well lit.
Speaker 1: It's quiet.
Speaker 0: Wait, actually well lit?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a good place to play a board game if you get a seat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is not a lot of seats.
Speaker 1: This is a moderate amount.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so part of the thing I kickstarted was I got a ticket to the opening night.
Speaker 1: I think it was sold out because they had a number of backers equal to the number of seats, but it seems like a lot of people didn't show.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of people might not actually live here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I was wondering if I was even going to see anyone I knew there, but buddy Matt was there, so we played a bunch of games.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: You know, I could talk about a lot of them, but I think I'm going to save them for later, but there's one that I think is only Geek Byte worthy, and that is called Dungeon Dice, I believe was the name of it.
Speaker 0: Dungeon Dice.
Speaker 1: Let me take a look.
Speaker 1: It comes in like...
Speaker 0: Dungeon Dice relaunch, collect dice, and bash.
Speaker 0: This game?
Speaker 0: I got it up on my screen.
Speaker 0: That game.
Speaker 0: What I'm pointing at right now.
Speaker 1: Didn't look like that.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's the game, Dungeon Dice.
Speaker 1: Okay, well, maybe it looked different.
Speaker 0: Okay, captain.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to edit anything out here, so...
Speaker 1: What was the name of this thing?
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: Oh, it is called...
Speaker 0: Dungeon Dice?
Speaker 1: No, Dungeon Roll.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Dungeon Roll.
Speaker 0: So there is another game called Dungeon Dice.
Speaker 1: Yes, it's definitely Dungeon Roll, which comes in a little treasure chest, right?
Speaker 1: Yes, 100% Dungeon Roll.
Speaker 1: So, Dungeon Roll, which I just said the name of 20 times in a row, is pretty bad, but the theme is so good.
Speaker 1: So here's how this works.
Speaker 1: You have this treasure chest, and you take the dice out, and this white dice and black dice.
Speaker 1: The white dice are the good guys, and the black dice are the bad guys.
Speaker 1: And inside the treasure chest are a bunch of little cardboard bits that are the treasure.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: And on your turn, you basically, it's a little, it's a lot like Yahtzee.
Speaker 1: On your turn, you roll the white dice, all of them, once.
Speaker 1: You don't get to re-roll any of them.
Speaker 1: On the white dice are a bunch of different kinds of, you know, heroes.
Speaker 1: Champions, fighters, mages, rogues, and sometimes scrolls also.
Speaker 1: And you just, that's your party.
Speaker 1: You roll it once, that's your party to go in the dungeon with.
Speaker 1: You go to level one of the dungeon.
Speaker 1: The person to your left rolls one black die.
Speaker 1: It might show up like goblin.
Speaker 1: It might show up treasure.
Speaker 1: It might show up who knows what, right?
Speaker 1: And you have to send someone in your party to deal with it.
Speaker 1: So let's say it rolls goblin.
Speaker 1: Well, any hero can defeat any one monster, but each hero has a specialty.
Speaker 1: So for example, a fighter can kill one of anything or any number of goblins.
Speaker 1: So if you go down to level three of the dungeon and the guy rolls and it comes up three goblins, well, one fighter can take care of all of that.
Speaker 1: Or a mage and a rogue and something, right?
Speaker 1: You get the idea.
Speaker 1: So level one, he rolls goblin.
Speaker 1: You have to kill all the monsters.
Speaker 1: You can't continue level two.
Speaker 1: So you pick one of your guys to kill the goblin.
Speaker 1: Okay, next.
Speaker 1: He rolls two dice, a skeleton and a treasure chest.
Speaker 1: You send one guy to kill the skeleton, one guy to kill the treasure chest.
Speaker 1: And notice you're losing white dice.
Speaker 1: Each level you spend white dice to kill off the black dice and continue.
Speaker 1: You don't have to open the treasure chest, but if you send the guy to open the treasure chest, then you get to reach in and get treasures, which are usually more guys, right?
Speaker 1: And sometimes they're XP.
Speaker 1: And basically you keep going further and further down the dungeon until, you know, every time you beat all the guys, you can say I'm stopping and you get one XP for every level you have completed.
Speaker 1: If you say I'm gonna keep going and you die, you get no XP because you spent all your guys, right?
Speaker 1: They didn't make it.
Speaker 1: And that's how it works.
Speaker 1: So it's thematically that works, right?
Speaker 1: The mechanic perfectly, 100% matches the theme.
Speaker 1: You have a party of guys.
Speaker 1: You go down fighting into the dungeon.
Speaker 1: You go deeper and deeper.
Speaker 1: There's more and more bad guys, less and less good guys.
Speaker 1: And eventually you give up and run out with all the treasures you've got and experience you've gained.
Speaker 0: So Yahtzee torchbearer without roleplaying.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: And then the next person, after you're done, the person to your left rolls the hero dice and the person to his left or his or her left then rolls the evil dice and you keep going around until everyone goes on three delves and whoever has the most experience after three delves wins.
Speaker 1: It's 100% solitaire.
Speaker 1: What the other people do doesn't matter except did they get more experience than you?
Speaker 1: So it actually matters on your final turn.
Speaker 1: For example, I was on my final turn and basically I could go one more level, but the odds of me surviving that one more level were basically nil.
Speaker 1: But with the amount of experience I had, I did not have enough to win.
Speaker 1: So I had to take ridiculous odds on that third one and I kept going.
Speaker 1: And of course I died, but it didn't matter because I wouldn't have won anyway.
Speaker 1: And that's the only interactivity in the whole game.
Speaker 0: So it's not worth playing.
Speaker 1: It is not worth playing at all.
Speaker 1: It's just really cool to see how the mechanics of this Yahtzee went so well with the idea of a typical dungeon delve.
Speaker 1: It is uncool in that there is no reason to ever play this ever.
Speaker 1: Yes, there is no reason to ever play it ever.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess there is the reason.
Speaker 1: if you don't already have a good Yahtzee game such as Yahtzee Roll Through the Ages, Skyline, etc.
Speaker 1: King of Tokyo.
Speaker 1: If you don't already have a good Yahtzee game, Zombie Dice.
Speaker 0: Oh, and by the way, if you own 5D6, you have Yahtzee already.
Speaker 0: No kidding.
Speaker 1: If you don't already have Yahtzee, this could be the one Yahtzee you have and it would be okay.
Speaker 0: Huh.
Speaker 0: You know, maybe the reason to play this game is if you're a developer of games who is young.
Speaker 1: You won't need to buy this.
Speaker 1: You just learned everything you need to know from this listening to me.
Speaker 0: Hopefully they did.
Speaker 0: Maybe they need to viscerally feel it.
Speaker 1: Watch it on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Touch fire to find out that fire bad.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: It does come in a really cool treasure chest, so the manufacturing of the game is already pretty good.
Speaker 0: So this and Castellon.
Speaker 0: High production values on everything but the game.
Speaker 1: The production value wasn't high.
Speaker 1: It was just this cardboard treasure chest full of dice and cardboard.
Speaker 0: Oh, so it's just cool.
Speaker 0: It's not high production.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's well designed.
Speaker 1: It's not well made.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: It was average made.
Speaker 1: It wasn't poorly made.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like the treasure chest was like, "What an awesome
Speaker 1: chest.".
Speaker 1: It was just like, "Oh, look.
Speaker 1: It comes in a cardboard chest.
Speaker 1: That's
Speaker 1: sweet.".
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: I got a little cluster of things here.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna put them in a big thing on Tumblr instead of making a ton of things of the day.
Speaker 0: Way long time ago when we used to do four nights of geek nights a week.
Speaker 1: What kind of crazy people do that?
Speaker 0: For many years before we realized how people with no lives.
Speaker 1: You don't live in a city.
Speaker 0: How soul crushing that was.
Speaker 0: You see that thing I linked to about reverse commuting?
Speaker 0: How people our age are more and more if they don't live in New York.
Speaker 0: Reverse commuting because all the jobs are in the burbs but they want to live in the downtown.
Speaker 1: My cousin has lived in New York and she worked in New York.
Speaker 1: She got forced to reverse commute because they moved her job.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: She doesn't want to work out there.
Speaker 1: They moved the job to the burbs.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: But people used to want to live and work in the burbs.
Speaker 0: People our age want to live in the city and work wherever there's jobs.
Speaker 0: So they'll live in the city even if that means commuting to work in the burb sucks.
Speaker 1: She always lived in the city and she did work in the city and she forced her out.
Speaker 0: Remember when you used to have to reverse commute?
Speaker 0: We already lived outside of the city and you had to commute even further away from the city.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But they bought you that car.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway, what we used to do because it was hard to come up with four things the day a week is that I would do theme weeks like that born to be alive Hitler week that I did that one time.
Speaker 0: I found those videos again recently.
Speaker 0: So I have a themed thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I'm going to blow it all right now.
Speaker 0: I found this video.
Speaker 0: Emily and I were doing our usual watch colleague humor and South Park and stuff.
Speaker 0: And it was called a late for meeting.
Speaker 0: It was apparently a sequel to another video by the same person whose name on Twitter is bad.
Speaker 0: mocap called goes to store.
Speaker 0: And the description of goes to store tells you everything you need to know about this video.
Speaker 0: Normal guy, normal walk.
Speaker 0: The videos are pretty funny, but the part of the reason I bring this up is that these there is a huge community of people who have remixed this idea with everything.
Speaker 0: There's a team fortress to going for intelligence.
Speaker 0: There's a sequel going to store best real remake, and all of this is delightful.
Speaker 0: So I invite you all to watch this normal guy who is normally walking to a normal store.
Speaker 1: All right, I do.
Speaker 1: So here's this awesome website I found called ASCII flow, and it basically is MS paint for ASCII flow charts.
Speaker 1: The tools available to you are Arrow, which is just the cursor to click on and select things box.
Speaker 1: It lets you draw an ASCII box, the kind with the pluses in the corners, the pipes in the side and the hyphen on the top and the bottom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the kind of thing that I often see people using in bullshit game facts.
Speaker 1: Another box that has a heading on it, sort of like for UML.
Speaker 1: one that allows you to draw an arrow from one box to another box.
Speaker 1: Another one that lets you draw a different kind of arrow from one box to another box, one that lets you draw text, one that lets you erase.
Speaker 1: and one that lets you just draw a bunch of X's in a line wherever the hell you want.
Speaker 1: This thing is so awesome.
Speaker 1: You can use this for making like maps for rogue you likes or actual flow charts to post into forums.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good for simple databases, maps of dungeons for a tabletop RPG like tables and basically UML diagrams.
Speaker 1: This thing is so freaking useful.
Speaker 1: I want to figure out how to download it in case the website ever disappears, such as medieval tapestry.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was duly impressed with this.
Speaker 1: Nightly build GitHub.
Speaker 1: Yes, you can get it on GitHub.
Speaker 0: If it's on GitHub, we should just integrate it into the forum.
Speaker 1: We can't now.
Speaker 1: We'll talk to that in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So in the meta moment, you might've noticed that Scott did something pretty big.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So here's what the deal was.
Speaker 1: Our forum was all busted, right?
Speaker 1: And because it was so old and un-updated ancient version of vanilla, there's no way to update it.
Speaker 1: Cause basically what they did is they haven't updated their open source version in forever and they mostly were hosted in their cloud version.
Speaker 1: So I said, fine, you win.
Speaker 1: There's no other forum to switch to.
Speaker 1: We'll pay for your stupid cloud hosting.
Speaker 1: So it's costing us like one 50 a month, which is a ton of fucking money.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's more than the collected entire archive of all of geek nights.
Speaker 0: That's online.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: So if you want to, uh, send us some monies to help with that, we will set up numerous ways for you to send us money, both in return for gratitude and in return for things like t-shirts.
Speaker 0: So stay tuned.
Speaker 1: Uh, so yeah, but yeah, the forum is now all updated and way better.
Speaker 1: If you want to register, we don't even need to approve you anymore because the filtering to keep spammers out is pretty damn good.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: All you got to do is just register for it.
Speaker 1: Like you'd anything else out there.
Speaker 0: And now that the searching is better and everything's better, I think a lot of dormant people are going to come back and our forums already pretty fucking bad ass in terms of its community.
Speaker 0: But I sense that the ivory tower of our forum is going to explode in the coming months.
Speaker 1: But anyway, uh, so the forum is way better now than it has been in a long time.
Speaker 0: In fact, you might remember we gave a lecture at a PACS many years ago that was basically, here's why the community in your PHP VV is shit and why our forum community is awesome.
Speaker 0: And it's because of the design of the GUI of the forum itself.
Speaker 1: So yeah, go to the forum as usual, but also, uh, the, our ability to do things such as modify the forum in that way.
Speaker 0: For example, you might've noticed that like a year ago, the new episodes stopped having a link to the forum threads for set episodes for the plebes who did not otherwise already use the forum.
Speaker 0: And they would come to the website like, Oh, I want to comment on your episode because I disagree with you.
Speaker 0: And then there was no link.
Speaker 0: So they'd never actually go find the forum and they disappear into the miss angry and alone, but now they can complain on the forum soon after we fix that part.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm going to be doing a whole bunch of stuff in regards to that, uh, pretty soon.
Speaker 0: So expect a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: And speaking of a bunch of stuff, uh, we did resume production of geek nights presents Utena.
Speaker 0: And in fact, uh, episode nine just finished uploading.
Speaker 0: I started uploading it when we started the show and it just finished.
Speaker 0: So yeah, eight gigabytes in about 23 minutes.
Speaker 0: I love files.
Speaker 0: So episode nine of geek nights presents shoujo kakame.
Speaker 0: Utena will be available as soon as YouTube finishes encoding it into all the various bit rates.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: This episode is 35 minutes long.
Speaker 0: The episode of Utena is 21 minutes long.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 0: So yeah, that's the rate.
Speaker 0: we're going here.
Speaker 1: Uh, uh, the book club book is actually almost finished reading it.
Speaker 0: I have read six and a half books in the time.
Speaker 0: It's taken Scott to read this in fact.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So if you only count right, the actual hours of reading time has taken me to read.
Speaker 0: this takes like two hours to read.
Speaker 1: This book is way not long to read.
Speaker 1: It's, I've just not been reading books in this time period.
Speaker 1: I've been doing other things of this.
Speaker 0: exercise to get people to read things outside of their comfort zone.
Speaker 1: I do know is to get people to read things period.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they're reading things.
Speaker 0: They're reading a mr nice guy's penis adventure that Patrick Rothfuss bullshit.
Speaker 0: They're not reading real books.
Speaker 1: Some people are reading that, but some people aren't reading at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: My goal is just don't read penis adventures.
Speaker 0: Read real.
Speaker 1: You're aiming too high.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of people who just don't read.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would at this point, I'd almost rather you not read than read captain nice guys adventures because good God fedora dig captain fedora's nice guy penis adventures.
Speaker 0: That's what the king killer Chronicles are.
Speaker 0: But, um, I'm most of the way through the new Locke Lamora book.
Speaker 0: It's okay.
Speaker 1: It's the same as the other one.
Speaker 0: It's identical to the other ones, except it takes place in the magic land.
Speaker 0: Ooh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: I remember.
Speaker 1: I'm starting to remember that world.
Speaker 0: Remember the falconer.
Speaker 0: Remember when they did a thing?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So now they're going to deal with that.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Good luck guys.
Speaker 0: Books.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: It's not great, but it's more of the same and you know what?
Speaker 0: The same was pretty good.
Speaker 0: It's entertaining.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Learn anything about elder glass.
Speaker 0: Uh, I learned that there's some mysterious elder glass shit deep in the ocean that you can see bubbling up and no one can get down there deep enough to look at it.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's where shit comes from.
Speaker 0: I also learned a little bit about magical.
Speaker 0: I worry that Scott Lynch has read one of the, uh, captain penis nice guy adventure books because he mentioned something about magic and sympathy in a way that just brought back flashbacks to penises anyway.
Speaker 0: So yeah, book of the book Stasi land relevant in light of the fact that if you guys didn't notice, the UK is actually trying to crack down on free speech about the NSA leaks.
Speaker 0: So yeah, this stuff is increasingly important and you should at least attention.
Speaker 0: We don't want to be like East Germany.
Speaker 1: I doubt that lab.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But other parts of the world are edging toward those sorts of things.
Speaker 0: And despite the fact that the U S is the place doing that spying, we also are maintaining your freedom of speech, which creates a sort of interesting,
Speaker 1: read a great article talking about how, you know, basically the U S not being able to keep secrets will eliminate hypocrisy in the U S because basically the government won't be able to do one thing and tell other people to do a different thing because everyone can see that we're only pretending to do what we say we do, and we're not.
Speaker 1: So then we'll be forced to actually do what we tell other people to do.
Speaker 0: I also read a similar article that said the same thing was happening specifically to the far right Republicans in the U S because in the old days they could go to their base and say, yeah, we're going to keep the black people down.
Speaker 0: And then in the public, they'd say we're fiscally responsible, but now the racist stuff they say to their base is all on YouTube right next to the things they say in public.
Speaker 0: They can't have two faces anymore.
Speaker 0: Politicians only get one face, at least there's still the lobbyist face, but they can't have the base face and the centrist face.
Speaker 0: And that hurts Republicans way more than it hurts Democrats.
Speaker 0: But anyway, uh, I think that's all we got in the meta moment.
Speaker 0: Look for us at magfest.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Look for us at anime Boston.
Speaker 0: Look for us at tax East New York city.
Speaker 0: Look for us at, uh, I don't know what other conventions we're going to in the near future runner world tournament.
Speaker 1: I think it was within a week.
Speaker 1: Not going to fucking Minneapolis.
Speaker 0: Hell no.
Speaker 0: Zenkai con.
Speaker 0: We're going to be there doing some panels.
Speaker 0: Oh, and, um, it's a long ways in advance, but, uh, as you know, Scott and I are two of the three people who run the panels, workshops and special events department for Connecticut, which is a moderately to surprisingly sized nerd convention in Connecticut every year, uh, panel submissions for next year around July are already open.
Speaker 0: We've already gotten like three panel submissions.
Speaker 0: So yeah, that other convention, take that certain unnamed conventions that don't have their panels scheduled together in the weeks before the con.
Speaker 0: take that I'm making two middle fingers right now.
Speaker 1: I'm already playing four middle fingers between us all raised high.
Speaker 0: I'm already looking at panel submissions.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking about, do I want anime in this room at this time?
Speaker 0: Or do I want video games?
Speaker 0: Connecticut is huge and awesome.
Speaker 0: Our panel rooms are awesome.
Speaker 0: We're getting bigger.
Speaker 0: The people who run the panels department, me, Scott, and the eggs know exactly what's up.
Speaker 0: We are cool.
Speaker 0: Other many listeners of geek nights, our panelists at Connecticut, they will tell you how awesome it is.
Speaker 0: Uh, many of them are now our own personal enforcers or at Connecticut.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah, go submit your panel.
Speaker 0: I get an email on my phone every time you do this.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So talk about what we're gonna talk about.
Speaker 0: Burning con.
Speaker 1: Burning con is usually real good this year.
Speaker 1: I missed some burning con because there was a net runner tournament.
Speaker 1: I've talked about this before, but basically normally I would never skip burning con once a year for net runner tournament, which is like twice a month.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: That's ridiculous.
Speaker 1: You always go to the thing that is rarer to go to, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, for something that is less rare or more rare.
Speaker 1: But in this case, the net runner tournament was not just any net runner tournament.
Speaker 1: It was the plugged in special net runner.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: So Scott, which went from a once a month event to a once ever so once ever beats once a year.
Speaker 0: So Scott decided that schwag for his net runner game.
Speaker 1: I didn't win any schwag at all.
Speaker 1: I don't care about the schwag.
Speaker 1: I care about going to play net runner with the peoples.
Speaker 1: So regardless, Scott missed a good chunk of burning con, which I showed up for the third session on Saturday at the party on Friday and both sessions on Sunday.
Speaker 1: But I missed the first two sessions on Saturday.
Speaker 0: He also missed the after party.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So burning con.
Speaker 1: We've talked about burning cons before, but this burning con was a lot like the other burning con.
Speaker 0: Suffice it to say, burning con is a curated convention run by the burning wheel crew like Luke Crane, Jared Sorensen, people like Vincent Baker.
Speaker 0: There's different combinations of game designers every year.
Speaker 0: And the idea is that games created by all the people who collectively are curating the con are the only games that can be played.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So this year the people were Jason Morningstar, Jared Sorensen, John Harper, Vincent Baker and Luke Crane.
Speaker 1: So the games you could play are fiasco.
Speaker 1: You could basically only play games they design.
Speaker 0: Fiasco, Durance, Carolina Death Crawl, Gray Ranks, Shab al-Hari Roach, Inspectors, Lacuna, Action Castle, Free Market, Lady Blackbird, Danger Patrol, Ghost Echo.
Speaker 0: I got Dogs in the Vineyard, Apocalypse World, Kill Puppies for Satan, Rock of Tahamad, Burning Wheel, Burning Empires, Torchbearer.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: Those that you can't are not allowed to play any other games like that.
Speaker 1: And everyone who attends the convention has to either A run one of those games or B join the beginners track where they teach you how to run a game.
Speaker 0: But then you still have to run games.
Speaker 0: You have to run games to play games.
Speaker 1: Everyone runs one game and then plays games in the other four slots.
Speaker 1: It's always been that way.
Speaker 0: It always will be that way, which I think engenders a much better role playing culture than any other gaming con ever.
Speaker 0: Because even if you're a noob one, you're now you're a noob running a game for the first time with a bunch of people who are either noobs just like you who are similarly dedicated to role playing or seasoned experts and or the people who created the games.
Speaker 0: And you might think it's intimidating to run a game for people who are experts.
Speaker 0: It is so much easier to run Burning Wheel for people who helped write Burning Wheel than it is to run Burning Wheel for people who don't know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: Unless Luke's in your game.
Speaker 0: But I digress.
Speaker 1: So I guess what did you do in the two sessions?
Speaker 1: I wasn't there?
Speaker 0: So the first session, which I had first priority for, I joined Jared Sorensen's inspectors game because I never get to play inspectors.
Speaker 0: It's the game I usually run at conventions for other people because I know all the rules.
Speaker 0: I can teach the rules in 30 seconds.
Speaker 0: It's easy.
Speaker 0: And it's a great game for people who aren't so much into role playing because I ran it for some people at PAX Prime when I was doing that thing.
Speaker 1: And it actually went really, really well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because it has that moment where someone rolls and they roll really well.
Speaker 0: And I turn to them and I say, all right, tell me what happens.
Speaker 0: And they sit there for a second.
Speaker 0: Like, what do you mean?
Speaker 0: Tell you.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh, well, I, uh, I find in the microfiche that the guy hasn't aged.
Speaker 0: I'm like, yeah, so tell me more about this.
Speaker 0: Tell me how awesome you are.
Speaker 0: And then they get it.
Speaker 0: And then role playing happens.
Speaker 0: But I'd never, you know, the rules are what they are.
Speaker 0: But I played in a game as a player where Jared Sorensen, the guy who wrote the game, ran it.
Speaker 0: And the first half was basically him doing standup comedy of why do you people want to play my shitty game?
Speaker 1: But it was actually that when he played free market a long time ago.
Speaker 0: But that started being incorporated into him running the game.
Speaker 0: Like he, he puts the character sheets out and he's like, all right, everyone write your names under name.
Speaker 0: And then he looks around and he's like, that's not your fucking name.
Speaker 0: Write your name, not your character's name.
Speaker 0: We don't need characters.
Speaker 0: It's inspectors.
Speaker 0: Bullshit.
Speaker 0: You don't need some character.
Speaker 0: Just play yourself.
Speaker 0: It's you and the game set here in New York and yep.
Speaker 0: Lazy, but you know what?
Speaker 0: It was stupidly fun.
Speaker 0: And I will spare you the details of the end of the game, but suffice it to say it was a great experience and I'm going to use the way he ran the game as my model for running this game for other people in the future.
Speaker 0: One, he forgot a bunch of rules, which is kind of funny.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: He forgot a bunch of rules on purpose, like in the beginning, like as jokes, but then he legit forgot a rule later.
Speaker 0: And when we realized that he wasn't joking, he actually forgot.
Speaker 0: It was the most funnier.
Speaker 0: And I realized something important about the way he runs the game.
Speaker 0: So you know, you have the franchise dice, right?
Speaker 0: When you get enough, the plot is resolved.
Speaker 0: So the way he did that, once the plot was resolved, we kept rolling and the game just continues.
Speaker 0: You don't stop and any up and then continue.
Speaker 0: You just continue and you still have to roll for stuff.
Speaker 0: You just don't get franchise dice, but you still get good or bad results until you get another case.
Speaker 0: And also, if you do something that was interesting, but doesn't further the plot, he does not award you franchise dice.
Speaker 1: Oh, see, that's the thing is when I played it, I basically gave franchise dice as per the rules and you would have enough franchise dice to basically beat the mission before it was actually resolved.
Speaker 0: So if your description does not actually further the plot, then he doesn't give you franchise dice and he continues to use the mechanics between missions.
Speaker 0: And as a result, the missions start to link together in a much more fluid way.
Speaker 0: Playing the game that way is a huge, it works way better.
Speaker 1: Maybe he should print inspectors 2.0 if he thinks that's such a good idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So the next game I played in that you weren't involved in, we were all two life path apprentices in Burning Wheel and we were there and the hook was pretty cool.
Speaker 0: So we're there and it was an awesome friend, listener who ran this game, our friend, Jane.
Speaker 0: And the deal is we're all two life path apprentices.
Speaker 0: Like I knew one spell, like literally that's a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: One spell.
Speaker 0: I got nothing else.
Speaker 0: And our masters all went into the dungeon to fight the chaos or whatever.
Speaker 0: And we were told to wait here until the signal comes out.
Speaker 0: If it's blue, come in and help us carry the loot out.
Speaker 0: If it's one, if I land two, if I see, if it's red, run back to the king and tell him to bring the army because shit's fucked.
Speaker 0: So 40 days go by, nothing happens.
Speaker 1: How did you survive for those 40 days sitting outside a cave?
Speaker 0: In our camp with food.
Speaker 0: Food's running low, but we still have food.
Speaker 0: A purple signal comes off, not from the cave.
Speaker 0: One of the adventurers runs out with a huge treasure chest and says, we're going to get the fuck out of here.
Speaker 0: Everyone else went evil.
Speaker 0: And then shit goes down.
Speaker 0: It was, that was a great Burning Wheel game.
Speaker 0: It was playing.
Speaker 0: those punk ass characters was actually super fun.
Speaker 1: All right, well, you know, then came Saturday night, I showed up and we played some Torchbearer.
Speaker 1: And I mean, basically Torchbearer, I had played it once before when it was called Dungeoneers and Dragonslayers.
Speaker 0: I played it when it was just called my book.
Speaker 1: My book had just arrived in the mail and I was like, all right, let's play this shit for reals.
Speaker 1: I want to see how this goes down.
Speaker 1: And we played it with Miguel and he's so excellent.
Speaker 1: He brought all these pieces and he was so good.
Speaker 0: Miguel was more prepared than anyone else.
Speaker 0: And the exception of those people with all those weird snake props.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then Tor was in the game.
Speaker 1: So that made it even better.
Speaker 0: It added an air of legitimacy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it was just, oh, that game was just so good.
Speaker 1: We just went into this dungeon and we did basic Dungeonee stuff.
Speaker 1: But once you're doing that basic Dungeonee stuff in Torchbearer, it's like that became the only game I wanted to play.
Speaker 0: What helped was in the game before Miguel was in the game I played before.
Speaker 0: And he was like, I didn't know him too well.
Speaker 0: Like he's one of those people that he was a lot of people at burning con.
Speaker 1: You go there every year and you recognize everyone and you know everyone, but you don't know everyone's name.
Speaker 1: Or you just never like, you know, it's like you see them, you know who that is, but you don't know them, know them.
Speaker 0: Or even if you know them, maybe you've never role played with them.
Speaker 0: Like you just don't end up there.
Speaker 0: Miguel had this, like he let his master murder him after giving this heartfelt speech.
Speaker 0: And it was just, it was like the persona point right there for him.
Speaker 0: And then he ran that Torchbearer and that little touch where he started just using, he started talking for the arcs.
Speaker 0: That was pretty good.
Speaker 0: Torchbearer is so fun.
Speaker 0: It was a good game.
Speaker 0: What else can I say about it?
Speaker 0: You should all buy Torchbearer.
Speaker 0: It'll be available very soon.
Speaker 1: So I went home and took a nap for the whole night because it was sleepy time.
Speaker 1: And then I woke up and I went back to Burning Con.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We went back to Burning Con and then you played in another Torchbearer game.
Speaker 1: We did.
Speaker 1: Well, no, uh, it was the mornings.
Speaker 1: I ran my game because I had the morning slot.
Speaker 0: Oh right.
Speaker 0: And I joined your game.
Speaker 0: and Scott, every year at Burning Con, Scott sits there when it's time for his game.
Speaker 0: He's like, I don't want to run my game.
Speaker 0: I hope no one joins it.
Speaker 0: And then he tried to like shoo players away who kept showing up.
Speaker 0: So I sat down at his game along with our good friend Chris to force his game to happen.
Speaker 0: And it was okay.
Speaker 0: It was kind of fun.
Speaker 0: I think my human pyramid plan would have worked.
Speaker 1: You and your human pyramids.
Speaker 0: I think my glory moment was when Scott just puts us in the dungeon.
Speaker 0: Well explain your, your premise.
Speaker 1: So I always like to do games where everyone's just boring as townsfolk.
Speaker 1: That's my thing.
Speaker 1: I love that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So I had a game last year.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I talked about it where it was like, everyone's boring as townsfolk and a night shows up in town and then there's a giant and whatever.
Speaker 1: the one I came up with this time was everyone's pretty much boring as townsfolk, except for the sorcerer.
Speaker 1: And you all get thrown a dungeon, but not a dungeon the way, you know, D and D dungeon, like just an actual dungeon, the King's dungeon.
Speaker 0: It was committed crimes.
Speaker 0: Scott, you ran it like a prison drama.
Speaker 1: It was it.
Speaker 1: you're in jail.
Speaker 1: It was a dungeon.
Speaker 0: dungeon is like Scott had this set piece of like, you all get your sentences and then you get carted off to the dungeon.
Speaker 0: So of course immediately we try to break out.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So that's a lot of game happened there.
Speaker 1: And that early part, which I kind of wanted, but I didn't realize like just how good that part would be.
Speaker 0: We almost escaped before we got to the dungeon.
Speaker 0: Like we were real close.
Speaker 0: In fact, if a certain unnamed person had not fucked shit up in our plan, we would have gotten away.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So that was really good.
Speaker 0: And then he just like fucking grabbed the key and started a fight.
Speaker 0: And I mean, that was what they got carted off.
Speaker 1: They got thrown in the dungeon and then they were in the dungeon.
Speaker 1: And then of course, they're still thinking the Sutton up with this dungeon.
Speaker 1: So I had to make them think Sutton was up with the dungeon because otherwise rim wanted to just practice for the rest of his life.
Speaker 0: Luke was, I was sitting there and Scott was like, well, you're in the dungeon.
Speaker 0: So I was like, all right, I look at the practice rules and let's say anything happens.
Speaker 0: I spend the next 10 years practicing climbing and lock picking and observation and stealthy and Luke crane over her.
Speaker 0: He was in the room at the time taking pictures and Scott looks at him like what?
Speaker 0: And Luke's like, that's an awesome plan.
Speaker 1: He's like, this is legit.
Speaker 1: So of course I wasn't going to let that.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: There was already something was going to happen even though I was sort of making it up and I was like, all right, they think something's going on.
Speaker 1: Let's make a dude disappear.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then they'll think there's something going on because there was nothing they could figure out to do in their cell except they were going to, God, did you have like, where did that guy go?
Speaker 1: Uh, I think that just like the, the, you know, he was an unwanted, uh, person amongst the guards and I think the guards just like killed him and him somewhere because they didn't like, they killed him by accident.
Speaker 0: I was just curious.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, it was something mundane.
Speaker 1: Like, oh yeah, the guards didn't like him.
Speaker 1: They killed him and then they were like, oh shit.
Speaker 1: And then they hid the body or something like that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so pretty much the routine in the jail, which I came up with was, it's a really shitty dungeon.
Speaker 1: It's not nice.
Speaker 1: So you get to exercise for a couple of hours in an underground room and then you go back to your cell and if anyone misbehaves in your cell, your whole cell gets punished.
Speaker 1: That way I could keep the party together and also discourage misbehavior in the dungeon.
Speaker 1: And I think I did a pretty good job of making you feel depressed like you're in a dungeon.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the crowning glory of the game was that we had this great plan with the human pyramid.
Speaker 0: that just didn't really come together the way it should have, but we ended up busting out and getting into this like abandoned part of the dungeon.
Speaker 1: I can't believe you rolled well enough to break down a cement wall with almost nothing.
Speaker 0: I know, following Bernie Wheel rules too.
Speaker 0: Like we pulled that shit off.
Speaker 1: I was following the rules like as hard as I could, even looking up appropriate obstacles and everything.
Speaker 1: Cause I was just like, let's just keep it real.
Speaker 0: So we bust into this abandoned part of the dungeon and we're going and going and lower and lower and lower.
Speaker 0: And we find this great and we smash it open.
Speaker 1: It's like they were so thrilled to escape the dungeon.
Speaker 1: They were willing to go lower.
Speaker 1: It's like, I was like, you're going down.
Speaker 1: And they're like, okay, let's go.
Speaker 1: We run.
Speaker 1: We're running down.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, it's an old unused part of the dungeon with like skeletons and shit.
Speaker 1: And they're like, let's go further.
Speaker 1: Keep going down.
Speaker 0: And it's like down.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: You're trying to escape.
Speaker 1: Shouldn't you want to go up?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Up where the guards are.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So we get down, we find this great, we smash it open.
Speaker 0: We make a rope.
Speaker 0: We throw it down there.
Speaker 0: We climb down.
Speaker 0: We fall in the rope breaks.
Speaker 0: And then we realize according to the rules also, that we had found an oubliette that at itself been forgotten.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And I'm assuming that we some of the other prisoners or guards might've caught up.
Speaker 0: Well, no, we could have gotten out with the human pyramid.
Speaker 1: I think the room, the room was a little too high.
Speaker 0: Human pyramid, I think would be an ops.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: You get some people together, make a human pyramid and see how high you can get.
Speaker 0: I've seen some pretty high human pyramids of trained gymnasts, which you were not.
Speaker 0: We didn't need to get that high though.
Speaker 1: Trained non-trained gymnasts wouldn't get high at all.
Speaker 1: They wouldn't even get to the second level of human pyramid, which is the required level.
Speaker 0: Second level of human pyramid, OBS one speed test.
Speaker 0: Third level I'd make like, I don't know, plus one OBS per level, plus two OBS per level, something like that.
Speaker 1: With four people.
Speaker 1: What kind of pyramid are you going to make?
Speaker 0: Well, we had a lot more people before for the original human pyramid plan.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: And then the last slot.
Speaker 0: I ran my game, which every year I tweak, it went pretty well.
Speaker 0: The, uh, the characters went right for their obscenities and they found some obscenities and it ended with possible war between nations.
Speaker 0: I don't know what I can say.
Speaker 0: I don't want to really say much about my game because every year I keep tweaking it and I think I'm running the same game.
Speaker 1: We can't come up with new game like me.
Speaker 1: I've come up with new games, but I got another new game for next year.
Speaker 0: This game.
Speaker 0: I'm going to tweak a little bit to try to move faster.
Speaker 0: I change.
Speaker 1: No, my game is for next year.
Speaker 1: Townsfolk just in town and there's no crazy adventure shit at all.
Speaker 1: It's just townsfolk in town.
Speaker 1: The end.
Speaker 0: So the vague idea I want to do, town drama, I wanted to be town drama and then adventures come to town.
Speaker 1: That's what I, that's the game I did last year.
Speaker 0: That's what I want to do.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: My game next year is just you're in a town.
Speaker 0: The thing is my game, the problem I had with it was that it moved too slowly.
Speaker 0: So I made the beliefs a lot more direct and I added a lot more sort of forward momentum and stuff to do.
Speaker 0: But this time the players got really interested in the lore and started doing a lot more research early on to slow the game back down.
Speaker 0: I gotta, I gotta come up with a way around that because I want to get to the genocide much faster.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: In the last slot, I just like playing torchbearers so much on Saturday night.
Speaker 1: I played it again.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: And this time we went to some goblin keep and we got horribly murdered.
Speaker 1: The end.
Speaker 0: Well, you shouldn't have tried to kill those orcs.
Speaker 1: That is a thing about torchbearer, but he was such an evil orc.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So drive them away and deal with them later.
Speaker 0: Don't try to kill him.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: If we drive them away, they want to meet him along with some friends.
Speaker 0: The way conflicts work in torchbearer comes down to the idea that there's some nuance to it based on might levels and things, but like if you're fighting a dragon, it might just kill you, but you can frame the parameters of the conflict and you always get to sort of set that.
Speaker 0: So if you're trying to drive other people away, the consequences involve you being driven away instead.
Speaker 0: If you try to kill someone, the consequences involve you being killed instead.
Speaker 0: So you sort of pick what you want, but that also sort of frames what the consequences will likely be if you fail.
Speaker 1: And we forgot armor, so we died.
Speaker 1: If we would have remembered our armor, we would have been fine.
Speaker 0: We forgot to bring your armor into the dungeon or forgot the rules for armor.
Speaker 1: We had the armor.
Speaker 1: We forgot to count it.
Speaker 0: BurningCon is great fun.
Speaker 0: What's interesting is how many people fly and drive here from far away to play in BurningCon.
Speaker 0: Like, I just live here.
Speaker 0: I just go show up.
Speaker 0: People come from pretty fucking far away to play in these games.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: They sure do.
Speaker 0: And I see the same faces every year, but also a lot of new faces, even though I didn't interface with a lot of those new faces.
Speaker 0: I was also given a gift of a game that we have to try out at some point.
Speaker 0: I'll show Scott the details of that later.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: And yeah, BurningCon was super fun.
Speaker 0: And I hope to go to the sixth one, even though Luke swore that there will never be another BurningCon.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: He has sworn that at the end of every BurningCon to date.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Meaning there's going to be another BurningCon.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: Torchbear is going to be for sale publicly real soon.
Speaker 0: Buy it.
Speaker 0: Just buy it.
Speaker 0: Even if you never play it, the book is a delight to read.
Speaker 0: Emily was home with Scott and I was like on my way.
Speaker 0: And according to her, Scott was reading the Torchbearer book and just giggling periodically.
Speaker 1: Yeah, funny parts.
Speaker 0: The book is also so beautiful and it gives me every feels that I felt when I used to read that old Second Ed AD&D Player's Handbook.
Speaker 1: Only it's playable.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You should play Torchbearer.
Speaker 0: You should.
Speaker 0: Torchbearer is tits.
Speaker 1: That's like if you're in a dungeon, if you have any game involved and you want to play a game that involves going into a dungeon with monsters and loot, this is the only game that you should be playing revolving around that.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.