Speaker 1: It's Tuesday October 1st, 2013.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: We're back.
Speaker 1: We're bad.
Speaker 1: It's time for a gaming news roundup.
Speaker 0: We did not get shut down.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we were at PAX.
Speaker 0: That was a long-ass time ago already.
Speaker 1: And we were at that other PAX and one thing led to another And basically I got sent to Istanbul and I just got back.
Speaker 1: So we missed a bunch of extra Geek Nights We didn't expect to miss.
Speaker 0: But we should be good until Magfest.
Speaker 1: Magfest?
Speaker 1: Not yet.
Speaker 0: So regular Geek Nights Regular Geek Nights for a few months.
Speaker 1: We also have a brand new mixer that I'm still working on and tweaking.
Speaker 1: I'm very proud of the fact that we no longer Most of you will not know or care what I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: We have had a Samsung compressor Between us and the internet for many many years.
Speaker 1: We no longer need that.
Speaker 1: I have enough bit depth to record the fullness of our volume Raw and then do everything in post.
Speaker 0: So why don't we just sell that and give us money?
Speaker 1: That compressor now is worth maybe 80 bucks.
Speaker 0: Sweet, money.
Speaker 1: Besides, actually.
Speaker 0: Give me the 80 bucks.
Speaker 1: You know when we're gonna use this thing?
Speaker 1: If we're doing live video kinds of things or streaming Where we can't wait to do it in post.
Speaker 0: So true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are situations where we'll still need this thing.
Speaker 0: But that is not a digital compressor.
Speaker 0: So we can't use this mixer with it, can't we?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you can.
Speaker 0: You just put it before the mixer.
Speaker 1: No, you don't put it before the mixer.
Speaker 1: You put it in the mixer.
Speaker 1: Oh It's called a channel insert.
Speaker 1: I have a special cable.
Speaker 1: Actually, the cables are dangling down right here.
Speaker 1: I'm holding it now I see.
Speaker 0: I see what you do.
Speaker 1: If you plug that into the back, it's TRS.
Speaker 0: Does that go before or after you preamp in the mixer?
Speaker 1: It goes after preamp, but before fader.
Speaker 1: So before this fader and before this equalization.
Speaker 1: But what I'm recording here is also before this.
Speaker 1: Look, I can turn on volume all the way down.
Speaker 1: It still records just fine Whoa.
Speaker 1: Because we're recording raw.
Speaker 1: Check that shit out.
Speaker 1: But this would cut off the Elgato stream.
Speaker 1: Okay, basically I'm nerding out because for many years We used an analog mixer that connected to, for a while, a USB device and then a firewire device.
Speaker 1: But now I have a fully digital workflow.
Speaker 1: Good fucking God.
Speaker 1: I should have spent this money a long time ago.
Speaker 1: It was worth every red cent.
Speaker 1: So stay tuned.
Speaker 1: We'll ferment a moment where we'll talk about all the new streaming kind of stuff We're gonna start doing.
Speaker 0: So I just have an opening bit.
Speaker 0: I just want to say something real quick.
Speaker 1: Something quick?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, you know, I'm wearing this Google Glass trying to see if I can make some use of it Right, and of course people come up and ask me about it.
Speaker 1: Well, they always ask you the same thing, too.
Speaker 0: They ask how is it and how is?
Speaker 0: it is slightly an annoying question But not too annoying because I guess it sort of is a question I just don't know what to say.
Speaker 1: Say you were eating a sandwich and I was like, how is it?
Speaker 0: It's a sandwich.
Speaker 1: But what about it?
Speaker 1: Like you're eating a DiBella sub.
Speaker 0: What about it?
Speaker 0: Do you want- this is such a generic question, right?
Speaker 0: I needed something more specific.
Speaker 0: Like does that say how does the sandwich taste?
Speaker 0: I'd be like, oh, it tastes great.
Speaker 1: But how is?
Speaker 1: it is a question of the overall Disposition of the sandwich.
Speaker 1: Right, but how is it?
Speaker 1: Pretty good.
Speaker 1: How is it?
Speaker 1: Kind of shitty.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is what it is.
Speaker 0: Anyway, what bothers me even more is this question suddenly that the how is it's have been disappearing and being replaced with an even dumber Question.
Speaker 1: How could it be a dumber question?
Speaker 0: The question is and I've got this twice today.
Speaker 0: That was just today.
Speaker 1: I'm guessing this is gonna be something surprisingly and weirdly wrong and specific not just like what is that?
Speaker 0: The question is is that Google Glass?
Speaker 0: So wait, you know what Google Glass is.
Speaker 1: That's what I was about to say if I would excuse someone who didn't know what it was.
Speaker 0: But if they've heard of it, you've heard of it that you know the name of it And you say is that what that is?
Speaker 1: Is this Homestuck?
Speaker 0: Is that Homestuck?
Speaker 0: it's like if I was walking down the street holding an ice cream and you'd be like is that ice cream?
Speaker 0: and So basically my first I was like, I'm gonna give the sarcastic answer like no It's just something I made on my own and people are like they.
Speaker 0: I guess their sarcasm detector wasn't working Scott.
Speaker 0: I sound sarcastic just now Scott.
Speaker 1: When it comes to technology people really don't know right?
Speaker 1: So if you're like, yes I made this and they think you're a nerd they will assume that you did.
Speaker 0: in fact even in my sarcastic tone of voice.
Speaker 1: Also, you always kind of sound like that.
Speaker 0: I was but I was sad a super second.
Speaker 1: Anyway, there's super super sarcastic.
Speaker 1: Yes, I made this myself Okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so This huge this hugely complicated tiny piece of precision machinery, that's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's so my new response that I started working on is what else could it be?
Speaker 1: That's pretty good.
Speaker 1: I like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's good.
Speaker 0: So They were like, oh And that basically made them realize they were dumb.
Speaker 0: So if you want to if you see someone right and I you know, like for example, I met a listener at the Maker Faire.
Speaker 0: He was a cool dude, right and he didn't really ask about the Google Glass.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: funnily enough I met a different list.
Speaker 0: He didn't ask really dumb questions or anything.
Speaker 0: He was totally cool guy, right?
Speaker 0: You know, whatever, but he just didn't really say anything like you just like hey, uh, nice to meet you.
Speaker 0: You're Scott, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm a god.
Speaker 0: I like your show whatever and I'm like, okay Thanks.
Speaker 1: Oh the guy and I was like, hey blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: Why don't you grab a drink, right?
Speaker 0: he didn't.
Speaker 0: but and he was just like.
Speaker 0: I'm just like, okay and It's like, you know and I sort of came off as jerky and he tweeted later like oh I don't.
Speaker 0: he thought he was bothering me.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: no you weren't bothering me, dude You just didn't really say anything.
Speaker 0: stop talking to start a conversation.
Speaker 0: wise you were just sort of saying like, you know I like a show.
Speaker 0: I listen all the time.
Speaker 1: you were talking You know, he said.
Speaker 0: he said that the reason he came to the show is good.
Speaker 0: So the Maker Faire is because I told him about it.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's cool But you didn't say anything.
Speaker 0: that prompts a discussion.
Speaker 0: So now I have nothing to say to you.
Speaker 0: You're the person who knows who I am.
Speaker 0: I don't even know your name.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about you.
Speaker 0: So I have nothing to say to you.
Speaker 0: if you want this discussion to continue in any kind of way You need to give me something to work with.
Speaker 0: right maybe ask me something.
Speaker 0: You know, it's funny It's not.
Speaker 0: is that Google glass?
Speaker 0: but like so have you played eggs video game?
Speaker 0: or have you seen anything at the Maker Faire?
Speaker 0: That was really cool.
Speaker 0: Or did you see this cool thing over there?
Speaker 0: I saw a man.
Speaker 0: It was so awesome.
Speaker 0: You know something like that.
Speaker 1: There was just a comic that someone tweeted today that I saw it when I was catching up on all my tweets.
Speaker 1: You know while I was pooping and the comic was basically Annoyance at that situation where someone else prompts conversation and then doesn't follow up after you respond Like hey, what you working on?
Speaker 1: I just did this thing.
Speaker 0: Well, what you're working on that gives me something to work with.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then I you respond like I'm working on this and they say nice and then nothing else.
Speaker 0: This is even one step beyond that.
Speaker 0: this is they don't even ask a question.
Speaker 0: you can answer like what you're working on.
Speaker 0: It's just sort of like hey there.
Speaker 0: Hey there.
Speaker 0: Hi You know the end.
Speaker 1: maybe we can blame Facebook and the fact that there is this sort of culture in social media of the poke or the prod or the.
Speaker 1: Hey you there the sort of ping of yes, you still know who I am.
Speaker 1: or yes, we have contacted each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess the other one that's always bothered me I think I might have mentioned this many moons ago is can I ask you a question?
Speaker 0: never say that in your life?
Speaker 1: Well only if you have a question to go ahead and say that the answer is usually no.
Speaker 0: Sure, if you are about to say, can I ask you something?
Speaker 0: Can I ask you a question or anything similar to that instead?
Speaker 0: You should just ask your question.
Speaker 0: For example, if I want to know rim What is the brand of that mixer that you just bought Mackie?
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 0: See, I shouldn't have said rim can ask you a question.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: I Didn't know.
Speaker 1: I have asked a a variant on this.
Speaker 1: that I think is okay because I haven't you know the seat.
Speaker 0: Well, you can say are you busy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you have a second.
Speaker 1: or can I ask you an involved question?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, maybe as in if you concede the point of me asking you this question I'm about to ask a fucker of a question.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, like one that will require a preamble perhaps some supporting Documentation share whatever.
Speaker 0: anyway, let us continue with some news of gaming.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yes team box.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh team has been rumored off and on for the last decade.
Speaker 0: So you don't know.
Speaker 1: the box looks like there's pictures that are mock-ups.
Speaker 0: I guess I don't know people are talking about it.
Speaker 1: Like there's like.
Speaker 0: mostly it's the controller.
Speaker 0: is the news, right?
Speaker 0: No, that's the piston.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is the same box.
Speaker 1: In fact, this headline is this is an article about what is the steam box and at the bottom.
Speaker 1: is the piston the steam box?
Speaker 1: It's not I know but that's the question in the article.
Speaker 1: and their answer is sort of It's not not wall.
Speaker 1: The xi3 piston is not made by va valve.
Speaker 1: It is associated with valve Project shield.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, never mind this articles bullshit, right?
Speaker 0: No, see what valve is doing is they've?
Speaker 0: so it's part one steam OS which is a Linux distribution that when you boot it up We'll just boot up in steam big picture mode now Assuming it will play every single game on Steam without issue that has Linux support.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah useless.
Speaker 0: And as to his links See that's the trouble.
Speaker 1: the steam OS can't just be Linux that has to play every goddamn game or there's no goddamn point.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but that's cool Linux distribution.
Speaker 0: That's just open and free like all the old Linux distributions, but it runs steam right?
Speaker 0: That's cool.
Speaker 0: So part two is The controller really right?
Speaker 1: The controller is if you haven't seen people talking about it or trying it out because you can try it out like it.
Speaker 1: There's people who have had the ability to use it Instead of sticks.
Speaker 1: It's just two touch pads.
Speaker 0: You put your thumb on haptic touch pad So I can see what valve is going for here, right?
Speaker 0: What they were going for is like look we our games are all PC games and our library is all these games that already exist and were made for mouse keyboards But you want to play them from the couch Rather than try to make a mouse keyboard like the phantom that works on the couch.
Speaker 0: not gonna happen Right.
Speaker 0: Well, we're gonna try to do is make a gamepad.
Speaker 0: that is somehow You know good enough to do mouse keyboard.
Speaker 1: So there's only one way for that to work.
Speaker 0: It's got to have like a hundred buttons, of course, but the buttons they haven't been able to do.
Speaker 0: but the touch pads are Way better than analog sticks in terms of being able to do the things a mouse can do right?
Speaker 0: Maybe not.
Speaker 0: it's not quite as good as a mouse, but you know if it's a touch pad It's like.
Speaker 0: well you could use a one-fingered touchpad to play Like, you know a game that involves a mouse.
Speaker 0: so they can Better than using analog stick.
Speaker 1: a lot of the games I play on steam are also Xbox games that work just fine with someone Right, but that's what I'm saying is those games aren't PC like for example Super Meat Boy, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, sir.
Speaker 0: Meat Boy I have it.
Speaker 0: you can get it on Steam or you can get an Xbox.
Speaker 0: but that is a Console game.
Speaker 0: you play it, you know an analog stick and a button is the primary input mode.
Speaker 1: I don't know if that's the line I would make on console game.
Speaker 1: I think we could make a better line.
Speaker 1: I see your point.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying I don't think that is necessarily the best definitional line.
Speaker 0: I think that's the definition I'm using.
Speaker 0: xcom right is a game That is a PC game, but they have it's on the Xbox on the ps3 on the iPad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: Well, it's actually pretty good with a touchscreen better than better than with an analog stick and buttons Which is actually something I'm worried about in game design.
Speaker 1: in the long run I'm deathly afraid that games will start to have touchpad or tablet interfaces as their primary interfaces because that's God is sort of has that?
Speaker 1: yeah, and that shit is Fatiguing as fuck if you're the kind of person who's gonna sit down and play a game for 12 hours pretty good in my way.
Speaker 1: calm though I'm gonna try Emily's getting a new Wacom so I might take her old Wacom.
Speaker 0: Doesn't that one not work?
Speaker 1: I think it can be fixed.
Speaker 0: That one's also way big.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is way smaller than that.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna carry it with me anywhere.
Speaker 0: It's really I can't imagine playing it with the big one.
Speaker 1: Anyway, though they're the they haven't their little manga whatever.
Speaker 1: one is really small.
Speaker 1: It's only a hundred bucks.
Speaker 0: Oh that one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: I got I got.
Speaker 0: basically I got the smallest one of the better variety.
Speaker 0: That's not a screen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the pro whatever it's into a small I don't know.
Speaker 1: Emily is getting the.
Speaker 0: I mostly use it for photo editing in the Lightroom of That thing is I don't edit photos on that level.
Speaker 1: I pretty much just do develop.
Speaker 0: well once I learned how to do it I was like oh snap and it's awesome because I can just be like oh look that person's hair is making this photo look Ugly not anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh that person's got like a meds.
Speaker 0: it It's me up not anymore, and you just like whoosh.
Speaker 0: It's gone.
Speaker 0: instead of like sitting there with the mouse clicking on it 20 times I just don't even bother.
Speaker 1: Oh, I took a picture of you with this giant zit.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: Wow when you look at the picture right it just like looks nasty.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it you know like it stands out in the picture above other things.
Speaker 1: well You know to be fair really depends on what kind of picture I took.
Speaker 1: of course if I take a good picture Yes, I do that, but I can even do stuff like Oh background tourist whoosh.
Speaker 1: but if I take say Documentary pictures of just an event I don't bother because I take like a hundred pictures.
Speaker 0: Did you know?
Speaker 0: if you're taking photos the Olympics you're not allowed to do anything to them.
Speaker 1: I did not know that.
Speaker 0: yeah, you're basically allowed to do almost nothing to the photos.
Speaker 1: when you're if you're an Olympic photographer so Interesting I should get a drone fly it over the Olympics take a ton of pictures and beam them back right But you're right.
Speaker 0: so the original point is that with the haptics combined with the high precision touch pads Being superior to analog sticks for those kinds of games that are better with Mouse keyboard touch screen than they are with analog stick which is the kind of game that's mostly
Speaker 1: on It could be
Speaker 0: But also good enough for games like a super meat boy.
Speaker 1: It might be good enough for FPS's Depends on FPS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a hard to say you could play.
Speaker 0: Maybe Wolfenstein or doom with it.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you could play The trouble tribes - you don't have enough buttons you could probably play counter.
Speaker 1: Well, they gave us a picture that I see here of all the buttons and the default bindings for portal - yeah Well portal - I think they met a designer with portal - in mind.
Speaker 0: portal doesn't need a lot of buttons.
Speaker 1: Let's see the buttons.
Speaker 0: They remember the analog.
Speaker 0: The touch pads are buttons if you push them in.
Speaker 1: yeah, they use those for like scrolling and zooming the left ones for moving Communication and the four buttons in the middle are kind of weird push to talk toggle zoom crouch Gesture menu chat message.
Speaker 1: How the fuck am I gonna type a chat man voice?
Speaker 1: No, that's the typing chat message.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's not the character talk.
Speaker 1: No, they've got a separate button for voice communication.
Speaker 0: I don't fucking know.
Speaker 1: I don't know either.
Speaker 1: That's my.
Speaker 0: there is there is a screen in the middle of it Like a Dreamcast controller.
Speaker 0: who knows what they'll do with that.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna be a tiny keyboard.
Speaker 1: It could be a touchscreen though that I'm gonna type on.
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: No It could be like, you know There could be things that you touch in the middle of it to do.
Speaker 0: You know, like you press start on it and then the menu shows up and then you know, maybe we'll see.
Speaker 1: with that The problem is the gaming media is going nuts about this thing.
Speaker 1: We know fuck all about it.
Speaker 1: Yep, almost anything you hear anyone say is rumor.
Speaker 0: Mmm other than the guy other than the three announcements valve made themselves.
Speaker 1: Yes So three announcements, that's an auspicious number.
Speaker 1: I Wonder wonder if that means anything Because a troll face gave in.
Speaker 1: as you pointed out They also have the trademark for half-life 3 Control double trophy.
Speaker 1: if I were them I would just start trademarking.
Speaker 0: The troll meter is off the chart.
Speaker 1: most bullshit.
Speaker 1: I'd be like, yeah, I need a trademark for quarter life Full life half-life 2 squared.
Speaker 1: You have half-life 2.5 Breaking life half bad full life Consequences Consequences.
Speaker 1: So, we'll see.
Speaker 1: I've said for a long time that valve should make a steam box or something like it though What I suspected they were gonna do back then would be to work with other people to where they'll make the boxes.
Speaker 1: and if valve just put forward a set of like Hardware specs like a sort of minimum set of requirements for compatibility and you could get your things certified to be a steam box Instead they're actually going down the road of just making the hardware which is interesting.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm worried about the Linux part though Because as you said if it is a Linux OS and it doesn't somehow just play every game in this As far as I know it's just Linux.
Speaker 0: It can't play Windows games.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 1: so if that's true I think it's gonna be a ridiculous failure.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean making more games that work on Linux.
Speaker 0: You'd be actually be surprised if you went on Steam to Linux section.
Speaker 0: How many games are in there and how many more games will be in there?
Speaker 0: Nvidia actually was like, oh shit.
Speaker 0: They're making this team thing.
Speaker 0: Hey Linus.
Speaker 0: You want to make up with you?
Speaker 0: We know you hate us Right.
Speaker 0: Nvidia was like, oh snap the fact that we Linux people hate us matters.
Speaker 0: suddenly Let's make nice with them and they're being.
Speaker 0: they're making nice with Linux again.
Speaker 0: Yeah the kernel.
Speaker 1: so take that AMD.
Speaker 0: Well, actually AMD would be on top if this went through.
Speaker 0: AMD is also giving the chips to the two current consoles.
Speaker 0: You know that that is true.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 0: the X bone and the ps4.
Speaker 1: fine You know who's gonna take then, you know who's taking my that the.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: He's dead.
Speaker 1: This is this isn't the nail in the coffin of the you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is like oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: I was already dead.
Speaker 0: It's already buried.
Speaker 0: What are you talking about?
Speaker 1: This is the last bit of chiseling on the tombstone That replaces the Credit.
Speaker 0: this is someone visiting the oh, yeah long after its death and leaving a stone on the grave.
Speaker 1: No, this is not even.
Speaker 1: this is someone walking past the Uyas grave to leave a stone on the virtual boy's grave.
Speaker 1: That person is the oculus, right I Guess we got to do things of the day at some point.
Speaker 1: So things of the day we go.
Speaker 1: As far as I can tell this is every episode of the real Ghostbusters just on YouTube.
Speaker 1: So go nuts if you don't know what this is.
Speaker 0: We've talked about watches every day after school.
Speaker 1: I we were sitting here and I pulled up the clip just in the middle just to make sure it would play so I could remember That.
Speaker 1: oh, right.
Speaker 1: This is my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Scott was not looking at my screen and recognize the background music from this show.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: This show was so important to my life.
Speaker 1: I watched the real Ghostbusters and the bullshit Ghostbusters.
Speaker 0: I didn't watch the bullshit one.
Speaker 1: I watched the bullshit one only the real one because I was given a gift by a Far-off relative of some Ghostbusters toys.
Speaker 1: Nope And they didn't match up with the show and I was really confused.
Speaker 1: and then I found the other goes no internet in those days.
Speaker 0: I know I didn't actually know about the bullshit Ghostbusters until way until internet times Because it was never on where I lived or I never watched it even though Ghostbusters came first.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I never knew why the real Ghostbusters was called real or anything like that until way later.
Speaker 1: Yeah Fake Ghostbusters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, always better real Ghostbusters Dude is stay puffed in salty bed.
Speaker 1: So I present to you the real Ghostbusters season 6 episode 4 the haunting of heck house.
Speaker 0: Yes Riders for the show geniuses anyway, so my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Someone linked in Twitter to this music video that I just showed rim.
Speaker 0: The song is Delta by CDC.
Speaker 0: I watched that music video and I was like, holy Shit, you know what?
Speaker 1: This is a situation like to mix, right?
Speaker 0: So I went with that me right and I was like who the hell are these people?
Speaker 0: so I went to iTunes and I searched for the album and I found it.
Speaker 0: and then I click preview on all the songs and I was like, that's not even the best song on this album.
Speaker 0: So then I went to Amazon and I said shut up and take real money for this music.
Speaker 0: It is that good.
Speaker 0: Here's my real monies.
Speaker 0: put mp3s in my Amazon cloud player right now, and they did.
Speaker 1: are they on Spotify?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't not using Spotify any I pay for Spotify.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I stopped doing that and then I pretty much have listened this album Repeatedly at least twice a day every day.
Speaker 1: since then that music video reminds me of the two mix white Reminds me of see it.
Speaker 1: you think damn I really want to watch that show.
Speaker 0: the show is Maha.
Speaker 0: It's a kite Anyway, so who is c2c?
Speaker 0: it is a French turntable group created in 98 and consists of four members.
Speaker 0: Not gonna read their names.
Speaker 0: They're all from nonce Right.
Speaker 0: The group was formerly known as coups to cross Coups the number two cro SS.
Speaker 0: the group won the disco Mix Club world DJ Championship four times in a row from oh three to oh six.
Speaker 0: They're basically won all kinds of crazy awards.
Speaker 0: They released a bunch of like singles and EPs and whatever.
Speaker 0: but their first album was Tetra which is the one that I bought which is their only full album and it was released on September 3rd.
Speaker 0: So it's only been out for a month.
Speaker 0: Pay monies for this.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Oh My god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so in the meta moment, we're back as you can tell.
Speaker 1: check us out on the internet.
Speaker 1: Check out that tumblr that I started populating with old episodes of geek nights old classics.
Speaker 1: It is a curated collection.
Speaker 1: for the time being We got a ton of video online.
Speaker 1: Scott and I have both been streaming us playing games.
Speaker 1: now that we have some elgato's and We might be accelerating the video streaming live cool stuff that we do in the near future.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have been doing a lot of game streaming, but mostly now I'm working on Take.
Speaker 0: I take videos of like netrunner games at the meetup and then I commentate and upload them.
Speaker 0: So I've been doing more of that lately.
Speaker 0: people seem to enjoy it so I keep doing it.
Speaker 1: and Once we get all this stuff going don't forget that we're going to resume production of geek nights.
Speaker 1: presents Shoujo kakame utenna.
Speaker 0: when it's cold, we're gonna stay inside and do shit like that.
Speaker 1: It is it's been a hiatus solely because we flew to fucking Australia and then Seattle.
Speaker 0: someone two seconds ago emailed about it.
Speaker 0: Is that why you were bringing it up?
Speaker 1: Actually, no, I haven't checked my email someone literally a minute ago email Wow utenna.
Speaker 1: So yes, Ashlyn We are in fact going to do it again.
Speaker 0: Ashlyn, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Well, I shouldn't say her last name.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, you never know she signed it just Ashlyn.
Speaker 1: so I'm gonna go with that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she introduced the show to her so they're watching it together.
Speaker 0: She thinks our videos will help him answer questions without spoiling anything.
Speaker 1: Oh, that is a good idea because we in fact what this show is to end to be making more soon very soon In fact, I just ripped two episodes that we're pulling stuff together.
Speaker 0: All right You should also just check us out everywhere else on the internet that we exist like Twitter and Facebook and Google+.
Speaker 0: Remember to post the episode of Google+?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah by hand.
Speaker 0: We still can't do it on a magically.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep Yep and you know we have another tumblr that all it is is all our thing of the day links because a lot of people don't go to the Website and frankly our things are they're pretty fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: So I just want to make it easier for people to share.
Speaker 0: rim is doing all these manual tumbles and things He likes them tumbles.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna if this then that it once I figure out a good pipeline.
Speaker 1: All right I'm still tweaking right now.
Speaker 1: It's it's.
Speaker 1: it's both curated and artisanal Wanted.
Speaker 1: I wanted to just be curated sure.
Speaker 1: So enjoy your artisanal tumbles.
Speaker 0: and the next convention is mag fest.
Speaker 0: If you're not going to mag fest what the hell's wrong with you?
Speaker 1: Yeah, seriously packs mag fest.
Speaker 1: Anime Boston if you care about anime, yeah Not the New York Comic Con which is coming up in a couple weekends and we're done.
Speaker 0: We're done with it is not this weekend, but next weekend.
Speaker 1: We haven't gone in a couple years.
Speaker 1: It's right there Burning.
Speaker 0: it is October 18th through 20th the pentacle gone.
Speaker 1: I am running a new.
Speaker 1: well, I'm running an old scenario completely rerun making up a new scenario.
Speaker 0: I titled it.
Speaker 1: I titled it a title that has been the title of at least a few dozen Unrelated adventures and unrelated systems since the beginning of role-playing.
Speaker 0: this Saturday sleeping dogs.
Speaker 0: Saturday the 5th of October there is a Special netrunner tournament in Albany, right?
Speaker 0: It's like zombie planet store.
Speaker 0: Are you going into Albany?
Speaker 0: Yeah this weekend.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you want to go to Albany this weekend and play netrunner.
Speaker 1: I don't really want to go and play netrunner, but I'd go but it's unlikely.
Speaker 0: Anyway this Sunday there with that netrunner tournament in Albany is the special one the plugged in tour where the fantasy flight special prize.
Speaker 0: and right this Sunday There's a netrunner tournament at the 20-sided store in Brooklyn where I will probably go to.
Speaker 0: Then next week in New York comic-con.
Speaker 0: the weekend after that is burning con.
Speaker 0: but the Saturday of burning con the special netrunner tournament is gonna be at the strat in New York City Manhattan.
Speaker 0: and Sunday of burning con the 20th of October The special netrunner tournament with the plugged in fantasy flight people is going to be at Kings games in the middle of fuck nowhere.
Speaker 0: Brooklyn out in the who knows where gonna go to that one.
Speaker 0: Hell no.
Speaker 0: Then our book club book is Stasi land Stasi land, which I've read A few chapters up now.
Speaker 1: Okay, you'll you'll there's the best story.
Speaker 0: I read like a few chapters.
Speaker 0: You'll blow through it.
Speaker 0: I looked and I was like, oh, I'm like 15% done with this.
Speaker 0: It's a short it.
Speaker 0: There's a reason I could wait so long to read.
Speaker 1: it is because the best stories in a fast book that you haven't gotten to yet Are the guy who keeps that fucking plastic plate that he that is department one?
Speaker 0: No, yeah that one right.
Speaker 1: and the propaganda guy because he's just so crazy.
Speaker 0: Okay Let's do the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well can you the show so Pac-man ced-x is.
Speaker 1: it was literally.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure you've discussed it on the show before but I searched and we haven't dedicated.
Speaker 1: an entire episode is literally the only Game I had on my Xbox that I didn't also have on Steam.
Speaker 1: Thus it was the only reason I kept my Xbox.
Speaker 0: I now there's a rather reason for me to have the Xbox which is I bought that rock fan But I never use it.
Speaker 0: so I could just got to sell it and then I'm okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, does anyone want two Xboxes and a rock band?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have the real guitar controller the one that's also a real guitar.
Speaker 1: That really helped you learn the guitar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I would have used it every day would have why didn't you use it every day?
Speaker 0: Because I have no discipline.
Speaker 1: It's funny because I had the discipline to like I don't know do quake one Clan Practices multiple nights.
Speaker 0: I have discipline to play pac-man ced-x every goddamn day.
Speaker 1: You're way better than me at it.
Speaker 0: I am according to steam according to Xbox.
Speaker 0: I'm not but on the steam ced-x leaderboards.
Speaker 0: I am 15th Overall.
Speaker 0: that includes all the different modes and all the different scores and all the different mazes, right?
Speaker 0: But there are a few people who have cheated on the leaderboards.
Speaker 0: So I'm probably in the top 10 of best at pac-man.
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess All my records and have to start over on steam.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I started over also, which is good because I lost a lot of my skills.
Speaker 0: I haven't played much doesn't matter because it's not like you get negative.
Speaker 0: It's just always your best of everything.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, even if your things reported over that would actually help you.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so pac-man ced-x plus or even ced-x is the best.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it is so good.
Speaker 1: Basically all it is is it took the Trappings of pac-man and the core can only say trapping of pac-man's.
Speaker 0: it is 90% pack.
Speaker 1: well, I said it take the trappings and the core conceits and It made a new game.
Speaker 1: That is true to the spirit of pac-man but suffers from none of the problems of old pac-man.
Speaker 1: because I will say this right now I like old pac-man.
Speaker 1: It was an important game.
Speaker 1: It was a good game.
Speaker 1: It is still a pretty good game, but Competitive pac-man is one of the most boring and pointless things in the world.
Speaker 0: even competitive miss pac-man is pretty dumb.
Speaker 1: It is no way better than competitive pac-man because once you're good, it's just an endurance contest.
Speaker 1: I hate arcade classic records because they're the worst to watch.
Speaker 1: There's zero spectator component It's true.
Speaker 0: I mean There are some games that have a spectator.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but like like Rob Root beer bubbles or beer rock ice cold beer ice cold beer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's got a spectator component, but asteroids Yeah, I want to watch the guy walk away from the machine because he has so many lives.
Speaker 0: I can't even like get a few lives and this guy's got like infinity.
Speaker 1: Anyway, well, I had that problem.
Speaker 1: You know I recognized this when I was very young in the Atari days because I was playing dig-dug on the Atari 2600 or kaboom and I never would really Lose like it was rare that I would die and the game was over.
Speaker 1: It was always that my parents made me stop playing.
Speaker 1: or I got bored or I wanted to go outside or I wanted juice.
Speaker 1: I paused it and when I you died.
Speaker 0: dig-dug we play every time we played dig do we played?
Speaker 1: Yeah, everyone's they played on the arcade dig-dug.
Speaker 1: I'm talking Atari 2600 dig-dug 200 not 7800.
Speaker 0: you will never die unless you are not 2600 dig-dug but 7800 you will.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure there was only the 2600 dig-dug.
Speaker 0: Well, I know There's definitely a 7800 one that looks like a real dig-dug.
Speaker 0: the 2600 one is mad ghetto.
Speaker 0: Yes, you are correct.
Speaker 1: So it's the 7800 one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the 7800 one is basically the same as the arcade in any s1 because I got a 7800 before I got an NES.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah the product.
Speaker 1: but as a result, I have trouble remembering which games are on which system because it played every Atari game.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I played.
Speaker 1: one day I was like, I'm gonna be awesome and I'm gonna play this game and get the highest possible score.
Speaker 1: And then like six hours later, I turned it off because I just couldn't deal with it.
Speaker 0: Alright, so here's so pac-man CEDX.
Speaker 0: What is it about?
Speaker 0: Well, it's the same exact rules of pac-man.
Speaker 0: your pac-man You can move up down left.
Speaker 0: right in a maze There are ghosts that chase you.
Speaker 0: if they touch you you die.
Speaker 0: If you eat a power pill the ghost turn blue for a while.
Speaker 0: you eat them.
Speaker 0: It's the same as pac-man you eat the pills.
Speaker 0: you want to eat all the pills.
Speaker 0: Here are the rules.
Speaker 0: changes from original pac-man to championship edition DX.
Speaker 0: pac-man.
Speaker 0: Every maze is split into two halves the left and the right At the start of the game if you eat all the regular pellets on one side of the map The fruit appears on the other side of the map in a pattern.
Speaker 0: in somewhere It appears where it appears when you eat a fruit the other side of the map will regenerate into a new map.
Speaker 0: So let's say I eat all the pellets on the left.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: The left board is empty.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to go there.
Speaker 0: the fruit appeared on the right.
Speaker 0: I eat the fruit on the right.
Speaker 0: the left side of the board now turns into a brand new maze full of pellets and All kinds of stuff.
Speaker 0: so then I eat the fruit and all the pellets on the right.
Speaker 0: Then the fruit appears on the left.
Speaker 0: I eat the fruit on the left.
Speaker 0: the right regenerates.
Speaker 0: I eat the fruit and all the pellets on the left.
Speaker 0: and so back and forth you go Right and eating all the pellets and all the fruits.
Speaker 0: That's rule change number one.
Speaker 0: Rule change number two there are sleeping ghosts.
Speaker 0: They're just chilling out sleeping.
Speaker 0: if you go past a sleeping ghost it will wake up.
Speaker 0: It will then decide whether to chase you or not chase you if there are currently no chasing ghosts on the map.
Speaker 0: it will chase you if There are chasing ghosts on the map But they're far away right now like they're on the other side.
Speaker 0: somewhere like the chase train is not near you the ghost will go Back to sleep.
Speaker 0: if the chase train is right on your ass Which it is most of the time it will wake up and join the chase train.
Speaker 0: So there's these chasing ghosts that are always chasing you in addition to the normal one through four free-roaming Ghosts that are in pac-man.
Speaker 0: right those are just out there.
Speaker 0: those aren't chasing you in the train.
Speaker 0: They're just pac-maning normal ghosts.
Speaker 0: What other are those?
Speaker 0: the only rule changes I?
Speaker 0: Think those might.
Speaker 0: oh this bombs you have bombs.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I never think to use the bomb.
Speaker 0: You should use the bombs all the night except on those puzzle ones okay?
Speaker 0: So when you push the any button besides the arrows a bomb will go off that will take every ghost that is awake.
Speaker 0: So no sleeping ghosts But chasing ghosts and free-roaming ghosts And it will put them back in the middle of the map where ghosts in the ghost house And then they will immediately start pouring out of the ghost house again.
Speaker 0: So if you're in say surrounded by ghosts you push the bomb.
Speaker 0: it clears out.
Speaker 0: Another way to use the bomb is offensive bomb usage.
Speaker 0: So let's say you're running around the map and the ghosts are chasing you But you're about to eat a power pill.
Speaker 0: that means you have to turn around eat all the ghosts chasing you Then turn back around again and eat all the other ghosts that were sort of sleeping right.
Speaker 0: What you can do is let's say you go up the left side of the map Grab a power pill.
Speaker 0: if you use the bomb early enough in advance The ghosts will be coming out of the ghost house at that time And you can eat them as they come out of the goat house ghost house and not have to backtrack And you'll save like five to ten seconds of backtracking and forward tracking.
Speaker 1: Because remember this is a game that has many different modes.
Speaker 1: But it's it's either a game of time trial like down to the millisecond right.
Speaker 0: There's score mode time trial mode and ghost combo mode which sucks.
Speaker 1: Ghost combo mode is the worst mode right?
Speaker 0: It's all about time trial mode and score mode and score mode is Sort of like you still are in a hurry in score mode because the faster you go the more fruits you eat The more ghosts you know the more chances you have to eat ghosts.
Speaker 0: speed is really important in score mode.
Speaker 0: in time trial mode Though score time is speed is the only thing that's important, so you will skip past ghosts.
Speaker 0: You're not trying to eat a lot of ghosts.
Speaker 0: You're trying to avoid eating ghosts, right?
Speaker 0: Because that takes a lot of time and in time trial mode you just want to eat the pellets and the fruits.
Speaker 0: It's all about just how fast can you eat X number of fruits go?
Speaker 0: Alright, so you want to avoid the ghosts with the bomb?
Speaker 0: So a lot of times if there's a part of the map where you can't avoid hitting a ghost you'll bomb in advance Because whenever you get near a ghost you don't just die immediately.
Speaker 0: you go into like matrix pac-man mode But the timer still keeps going.
Speaker 0: like a timer is real time.
Speaker 0: So you don't want to go into matrix mode you want to get those goes bombed?
Speaker 0: Right before you get close to them, so you don't slow down and use the matrix speed.
Speaker 0: Also when you're in that matrix mode right the ghosts depending on the kind of ghost it is a free-roaming ghost or Chasing ghost it may actually just not come at you.
Speaker 0: like if you're at an intersection And there's a ghost coming right at you you can usually just turn and get out of its way or more often than not It will just turn and get out of your way, and you can keep going straight
Speaker 1: Just like in regular pack.
Speaker 0: you just have to be aware Is that a chasing ghost or is it a free-roaming ghost?
Speaker 0: if it's a chasing ghost?
Speaker 0: Like if the chasing ghost line is right in front of you.
Speaker 0: It's gonna come right at you right.
Speaker 0: it wants to chase you.
Speaker 0: That's all it will do is chase you wherever you are.
Speaker 0: come straight at you.
Speaker 0: It'll never turn away kind of like if you play snakes right.
Speaker 0: a free-roaming ghost Will turn out of the way if you come straight at it face to face most of the time unless There's no sort of intersection right there like if you meet it sort of in the middle of an alley And there's nowhere for it to turn yeah Then it's gonna come right at you and you can either die or use a bomb.
Speaker 0: And if you run it you can get bombs by eating ghosts that have bombs in their bellies.
Speaker 0: Or you can also get power pellets.
Speaker 0: There's some ghosts with power pellets in them.
Speaker 0: So if you get the power pill you can then eat a ghost with a power pill and replenish the power pill and basically Keep the game in a perpetual state of always being able to eat ghosts.
Speaker 1: But then the game becomes almost a challenge of how long can you keep that up right?
Speaker 0: basically what you.
Speaker 0: the reason you would use That mode is if you would just eat in a megaton of ghosts in a ghost chain.
Speaker 0: Then you keep going through the map really quickly But you keep the chain going to add more and more ghosts to your ghost combo Because the first ghost you eat is worth like a piddly amount of points.
Speaker 0: But like eventually it gets up to a maximum.
Speaker 0: as thing is this is 32,000 per go something like that.
Speaker 0: And if you every additional ghost you eat will give you big big points.
Speaker 0: right, but if you're going for score Unless you can eat every sleeping ghost.
Speaker 0: you probably want the power pill to run out so that you can wake up the ghost get To chase.
Speaker 0: you form the chain and then eat them all at once when you get a power pill.
Speaker 1: But the the fun of this game.
Speaker 1: the reason I like it so much is that the music rate the same reason hot Something so great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's definitely as good as hotline Miami music same level of oh my god I am in this and it's almost the sort of same genre as hotline Miami.
Speaker 0: right how perfect can you do this thing?
Speaker 1: Well, that's what I was getting at.
Speaker 1: This is not a game.
Speaker 1: if you want to play this game kind of casually It's not actually that fun.
Speaker 1: the game is only fun if you are trying to beat your own time and you get to within a Millisecond and failed.
Speaker 0: yesterday I played a map and I had a new technique for improving my time and I ended up with the exact same high score that I had previously to the second to the hundredth of a.
Speaker 1: Playing this game reminds me of a lot of those days when you me and Pete would hang around in beacon With the ultra hard mode event zero.
Speaker 1: Yeah, same thing and just you'd start a race and then restart.
Speaker 1: because you know, you fucked up.
Speaker 1: restart restart restart.
Speaker 0: I mean they make it really.
Speaker 0: you just press select twice and you restart.
Speaker 0: so it's really easy.
Speaker 0: Just restart.
Speaker 0: if you mess up like I'll do a time trial and if I take a wrong turn I'll just press select twice and start from the beginning.
Speaker 1: It's just immediately just BAM.
Speaker 0: Yep, and It lets you restart pretty much instantly.
Speaker 1: But this is a game of.
Speaker 1: it's not really multiplayer either other than comparing your scores in the leaderboard.
Speaker 1: It is purely a game of.
Speaker 1: do you want to master this Incredibly specific little thing?
Speaker 1: and it'll probably I mean it'll increase your reaction times and everything and sure like the game Scientific evidence for that.
Speaker 1: Well, like the game will go crazy sometimes and you just have to wing it like if you've bombed in certain situations avoid the ghost and kind of get back on track, but Really a big part of the game is memorization of patterns and then memorization of how to respond to those patterns.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much you have to learn each maze and how it works, right and Different mazes have different things going on.
Speaker 0: right like the junction maze is all about Basically going in these tight loops and then the ghost chain is too long and you're gonna bump into its ass like in snake.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right and you have to instead take different paths that go, you know Use the warping from the bottom to the top of the map to make to get the ghost chain longer So you don't bump into it.
Speaker 0: But then the highway one is like these long Highway is long and straight from left to right, right You have the new mountain course is really cool.
Speaker 0: Basically what you do is you go from bottom to top on them.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I guess they're gonna go bottom to top on the right and it's like you feel like you're climbing a mountain Pass going from left to right.
Speaker 1: Oh Ashland says rofl badass.
Speaker 1: Thanks for getting back to me so quickly.
Speaker 1: break a leg.
Speaker 1: Okay It was an arm and that was in Australia.
Speaker 0: Yeah but pretty much every different map has like a. you know half half is my favorite.
Speaker 0: actually I think cuz a half.
Speaker 0: what you do is Half.
Speaker 0: the map is loaded up with these ghosts and these pells and you really get to clear the sleeping ghosts out of the way.
Speaker 0: So you can get to the pills and like layer by layer you peel away and then when you finish clearing it out You eat the last pill on that side of the map.
Speaker 0: you go through the tunnel.
Speaker 0: You come out the right side of the map where the fruit is just waiting all on its own because it's only the left half Of the map matters.
Speaker 0: the right half of the map is just grab the fruit then go back into the left side again Which is now replenish the hats in particular.
Speaker 1: That's it's a test of Memorization and puzzle-solving while reacting in real time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well the memorization one is really darkness Which is where you have to basically time trial each other map in the dark to remember where to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right you can see the pills and the pellets but you can't really see the maze except for the immediate area around pac-man and you can See obviously the path the pills are making and you can see the ghosts.
Speaker 0: So you just are at to remember from the other modes what the optimal path is to take and like where the exit where the turns So you can anticipate them in advance.
Speaker 0: The darkness is time trial only it doesn't have a score mode.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it's a super fun game and you guys should play it so we can compare in the leaderboard on steam.
Speaker 0: I challenge anyone.
Speaker 0: I am probably top 10 in the world at this game except maybe I don't know if they had the weird You know, obviously this price and not to be all racist, but I'm gonna be racist.
Speaker 0: This is racist.
Speaker 0: There is definitely Japanese people who are way better than this than me and they're probably just not on our leaderboard.
Speaker 1: You should enter a tournament if there's one at like a PAX.
Speaker 0: They've had them at PAX every year for a while now You should enter one.
Speaker 0: I haven't been able to enter one due to difficulties scheduling.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, I would have.
Speaker 0: but yeah, they've had pac-man CE tournaments at PAX every year for a few years, so Because this was also a gaming news roundup.
Speaker 1: There's one last little thing here I want to talk about because I just saw this in Zelda a link between worlds.
Speaker 1: They made a big point That you can play the dungeons in any order, uh-huh.
Speaker 1: now One could argue maybe that could be like Zelda 1 where you can get to a lot of them But not all of them.
Speaker 1: That would be a good thing But you'd have to fight your way through like you could just go to level 8 and go and get that fucking book.
Speaker 0: if it's Like Megaman, I don't know about that.
Speaker 1: Here's what worries me.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna read from this article on joystick.
Speaker 0: Oh during the latest forward to this game during
Speaker 1: the latest Nintendo Direct presentation Nintendo president revealed that the game will arrive on the 3ds on November 22nd in Europe,
Speaker 0: okay,
Speaker 1: and He revealed that the game will dramatically alter the traditional Zelda formula allowing players to tackle dungeons in whatever order they choose.
Speaker 1: Here's the problem.
Speaker 1: This will be possible Thanks to a special shop where link can rent and purchase items that would normally only be found in dungeons Including the hookshot boomerang and hammer.
Speaker 0: So you go into a shop with your rupees and you rent a hook shot.
Speaker 0: You rent a hook shot to do the hook shot dungeon you couldn't normally do To get and then you get something in that right to do the dungeons out of order.
Speaker 0: I'll just do them in order and fuck that shop and not spend a rupee rupees on that shit.
Speaker 1: Yep No, I don't know.
Speaker 0: wait so if I but I guess you still need all the pieces of the Triforce.
Speaker 0: that's not a big deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess it's so.
Speaker 0: you know what it is.
Speaker 1: It's more that the the games have gone more and more toward this road of hard Barriers like well, here's the area you can't get through until you get the hookshot later and while that's exist.
Speaker 0: So the one had that walls.
Speaker 1: I'll hear that raft the primary thing preventing you from getting to a lot of areas Which is that you are not fucking good at that game.
Speaker 1: and then link was way we go.
Speaker 0: watch the stream of Zelda 1.
Speaker 0: It's two parts.
Speaker 0: The second part is mostly just the last level.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I think the second part starts at level 7 Maybe whatever.
Speaker 0: But yet that you can watch the early part of it where I go to get the white sword and there's the blue Centaur guy with who shoots swords at you guarding the white sword room.
Speaker 1: Wait, let me guess.
Speaker 1: Did you do the up?
Speaker 1: He's facing me.
Speaker 1: fuck leave the screen come back up.
Speaker 0: I did that like 20 times until I could finally sneak past him because when you have nothing but the sword and The tiny shield you can't deal with that guy, right?
Speaker 0: It's not like you can't go there.
Speaker 0: It lets you go wherever you want in the overworld map.
Speaker 0: It's just that guy will fucking kill you if you are not powerful enough.
Speaker 0: That is what's keeping you out and I wish you know more games did stuff like that.
Speaker 1: I wish more Zelda games did things like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, I mean, I guess Dark Souls does that right but it's they keep you out of everything with every guy because they're all hard.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I've been less and less enjoying Zelda games of time has gone on Always the newer ones, um, one more thing is the mighty number nine If you don't know what we're like number nine.
Speaker 0: How have you been?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's Megaman.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Kickstarter ends already by the time we're listening to this.
Speaker 0: Let me let me go check the exact timing on that.
Speaker 1: I backed it.
Speaker 0: who didn't back it?
Speaker 0: fools fools did not back.
Speaker 1: I think this is gonna be One of those games that's gonna come out and I'm gonna actually play it for real.
Speaker 0: As of this moment recording it has 47 minutes to go.
Speaker 0: Can you get the podcast up and if someone listened this lot this as the podcast been more than 47 minutes already?
Speaker 0: 4510. if we upload it right now somehow and you listen to the whole thing.
Speaker 0: You'll get to this part.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, 46 minutes to go is too late.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: Yeah They are at over like four million dollars here.
Speaker 0: They have added the stretch goal of 3ds version.
Speaker 0: I think that's the version I'm gonna play.
Speaker 1: Whoa, like I just went to Kickstarter to look at that and I found this other project right here.
Speaker 1: It's a you know bread baking machines.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like the ones that bread man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is a beer making machine.
Speaker 0: Why do you need a machine to make beer?
Speaker 0: Don't you need just a bucket?
Speaker 1: You have to do some other things.
Speaker 1: It's not just a bucket.
Speaker 0: So you just put all the ingredients in different apartments and it makes it seems to be it's an automatic micro brewing machine.
Speaker 0: Okay, interesting.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, just put the hops in the hop hopper and I'm pretty.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty excited for mighty number nine.
Speaker 0: Actually, yeah, I'm playing the hell out of that.
Speaker 1: I'm also Thinking about going five because it's gonna be cold soon.
Speaker 1: We have all those expansions.
Speaker 1: We're gonna play some multiplayer said five Let's do it.
Speaker 0: I'm any time anyone's to start to sit five.
Speaker 1: I basically it's got to get a little bit colder cuz I'm still going outside.
Speaker 0: I've basically figured out my sieve five strategy already.
Speaker 0: I know exactly what I'm gonna do.
Speaker 1: What's your strategy?
Speaker 0: I should I tell you right now.
Speaker 1: I have my strategy.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be the Greeks have horsemen.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna fuck people up in the early stages.
Speaker 0: That's definitely.
Speaker 0: you get definitely have Killing like one dude early, right?
Speaker 0: It's sort of like having losing a doubloon early in Puerto Rico, right?
Speaker 0: It just has his ripple effect through the whole game.
Speaker 1: The thing is if you just kill someone else early, you don't get that much out of it But they lose a lot.
Speaker 0: you just have to ruin the other people early and then defend your shit.
Speaker 0: You don't killing someone out.
Speaker 0: It's attacking the cities early and sieve five We'll just fuck you because the cities are so dangerous.
Speaker 1: But no, you said just kill like that one settler.
Speaker 0: You can kill his one settler per worker or you can just ruin his.
Speaker 1: like the thing is worker just worked or just go Over there and then he'll be afraid.
Speaker 1: So his guy hides in the city and then isn't working anything.
Speaker 0: It's also a good idea Things like that.
Speaker 0: you got his head the harassment going on.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Also the defense that you're not the harassed guy.
Speaker 1: I'm also a kind of confident in my advanced wars and skills to see me through.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my strategy actually minimizes the advanced wars that is.
Speaker 1: but some of the people who I know will be playing even playing a lot More said five than me.
Speaker 1: So I gotta play a lot more said five couldn't play so much on the plane.
Speaker 0: So I'm playing a lot of pac-man.
Speaker 1: It's gotta get colder before I do this and p-cross.
Speaker 1: So yeah, we're back.
Speaker 1: That's what happens.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.