Speaker 1: It's Thursday, February 7th, 2013.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, the fake geek.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Warm today.
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't.
Speaker 1: It's actually pretty warm compared to previous days.
Speaker 0: It's not particularly warm or cold.
Speaker 0: I mean, today's colder than it is warm.
Speaker 0: But anyway, there's a blizzard coming.
Speaker 0: Oh, shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got the- Enough of a blizzard to make our phones go.
Speaker 0: eh, eh, eh.
Speaker 1: Well, I had the moment where everyone in my office got the emergency alert over the cell network, except one dude who has not updated iOS in forever.
Speaker 1: So he was like, "How come you guys all got this warning and I
Speaker 1: didn't?".
Speaker 1: And then Modern Seinfeld tweeted basically the plot where that's Kramer.
Speaker 1: So on the way home, you know, there's a typical thing that happens in New York City.
Speaker 1: Subway train's about to close its doors and some jackass tries to like get in and fails and he's trapped in the door.
Speaker 1: He could just back out and the train could move, but no.
Speaker 1: He tries to hold the door open and like squeeze his way in.
Speaker 0: That asshole.
Speaker 1: So usually, there's only one recourse that the conductor has.
Speaker 0: Kick his ass out of the train.
Speaker 1: Which is, he can open and close the doors really quick to try to hurt the person.
Speaker 1: Which, if you're ever on a subway train and the doors go like open, close, open, close, open, close, the conductor is probably manually trying to hurt some asshole.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: In this case, he does that a few times and then he just starts talking.
Speaker 1: He says, "Sir, please do not stand blocking the door.
Speaker 1: It is a criminal offense to...".
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess you got on the train.
Speaker 1: And then the train goes and while we're in the Steinway Tunnel going on our way to Queens, conductor speaks up again and says, "Ladies and gentlemen," I'm paraphrasing obviously, "I know we say this often, but I'm going to have a little personal moment with all of you.
Speaker 1: You see, when you hold the doors open, you're a jerk.
Speaker 1: You're delaying everybody, you're making me unhappy, you're probably damaging the doors, you're lucky you don't get
Speaker 1: hurt.".
Speaker 1: Now this goes on for like five minutes.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: He just keeps talking.
Speaker 1: We get to a station, you know, Vernon Jackson, he's like, "I've got to let some passengers off the train.
Speaker 1: You who held the door open, you know who you are, so don't hold the door open now.
Speaker 1: And I hope everyone's given you dirty looks and we'll continue this conversation after I let these nice people
Speaker 1: off.".
Speaker 1: And then the doors open and close, we start moving again, it's quiet and everyone's silent, everyone's just kind of waiting.
Speaker 1: Whoever it was was not in my car, obviously.
Speaker 1: And then he's like, "So where was
Speaker 1: I?".
Speaker 1: "Right, that
Speaker 1: jerk.".
Speaker 1: He keeps going.
Speaker 1: I thought that was brilliant and the guy had such a stereotypical kind of Brooklyn-y accent that that sealed the deal.
Speaker 1: If I had thought I would have recorded it with my phone, I was kind of too busy laughing.
Speaker 0: Maybe someone did, maybe we'll see it on Reddit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so keep an eye out on YouTube.
Speaker 1: for conductor berates someone on a seven train going to Queens.
Speaker 0: Let's check the NYC Reddit, let's see.
Speaker 0: Bloomberg moved to North Korea, if you can't handle something, Blizzard morning.
Speaker 1: I don't think it'll be there yet because I just took that train.
Speaker 0: Please help.
Speaker 0: a radio station, goat chased in Bed-Stuy.
Speaker 1: I saw that goat thing, you know why that was notable?
Speaker 1: You know who caught the goat?
Speaker 1: A guy who apparently used to live in a country where his job was goat herder.
Speaker 1: For real.
Speaker 1: According to a comment on the Gothamist.
Speaker 1: That was verified by another comment.
Speaker 0: Alright, so check this out.
Speaker 0: This is just a tiny news.
Speaker 0: Google Hangout, which everyone uses all the time now.
Speaker 0: Which really put a hurting on Skype pretty quickly.
Speaker 1: The thing is, I use Google Hangout unless I just use Google Voice straight up.
Speaker 0: But anyway, they added a feature which allows you to adjust the bandwidth manually with a slider.
Speaker 0: And also an audio only mode.
Speaker 1: I did not notice that.
Speaker 0: They just added it like, there's an article about it right here.
Speaker 0: I don't even know if it's actually added yet or it's just going to be there soon, like you're rolling it out.
Speaker 0: You know, but it's super new, like today new.
Speaker 0: So this is kind of crazy because, you know, how come more things?
Speaker 0: don't do this?
Speaker 0: Just have the direct bandwidth adjuster.
Speaker 1: Because people who are clever UI designers think, which it's not, I can't say that it's a bad thought.
Speaker 1: I don't want to bother my users with this fiddly bandwidth thing.
Speaker 1: I'll have an algorithm that just kind of automatically does it.
Speaker 1: The problem is, those algorithms are never really that great.
Speaker 0: There's no way to do it.
Speaker 0: that's really good enough, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, okay we're going to do it for a game.
Speaker 0: So you see how fast your internet is, but the game server is far away.
Speaker 0: So we ping, ping doesn't tell the whole story.
Speaker 1: Well in the old days, so I used to manually tweak my settings in Quake 2 for like the look ahead.
Speaker 0: Exactly, but they don't give you control over those settings, you can't adjust them.
Speaker 1: The reason they don't in games is because you could trivially cheat by setting those in certain ways.
Speaker 1: If you had a little ping and you turned up certain kinds of interpolation, you could basically be Neo and go into a room and shoot and leave and people with high pings would never see you, they would just die.
Speaker 0: It's also annoying how YouTube, it used to be when you paused a video, you could eventually load the whole video.
Speaker 0: And now it doesn't really work that way.
Speaker 1: A lot of people, I've noticed the Daily Show and a lot of like apps that are purpose built for like a particular show or a particular thing, they only let you buffer like 12 seconds.
Speaker 1: Like dude, I probably have 24 gigs of RAM, just download the whole fucking thing.
Speaker 0: Exactly, I think what they're trying to do is, I think they've realized that a lot of people would basically buffer a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: Then not watch, and so they're actually saving a bunch of money on bandwidth on their end by not sending you a bunch of video you're not going to watch.
Speaker 1: Or, I have a theory, this would almost be a conspiracy theory.
Speaker 0: But they could solve that by giving you, again, control that says press here to buffer entire video.
Speaker 0: Or gasp, let me just download the video as a fucking file.
Speaker 1: Ah, so this would almost be a conspiracy theory.
Speaker 1: I would wager that at least some of the companies that have content like this make the experience suboptimal on purpose because they want the buzz of having it online, but they still want you to pay for cable to see it some other way normally.
Speaker 1: They don't want you to be that guy who only ever watches the Daily Show online, and has Adblock, and only watches it at hours where there aren't ads anyway.
Speaker 0: But at least for a hangout, this could be pretty cool, right?
Speaker 0: Because you can just turn on the audio only mode and be really good for podcast talking where you don't need the video.
Speaker 0: And if you got the video and someone's far away, they can just turn their bandwidth down and things will still be super smooth in general for everyone.
Speaker 0: Instead of like, someone's cutting out, that won't happen anymore.
Speaker 0: It'll still be there.
Speaker 1: We should try this out.
Speaker 1: I'm feeling the itch to get a guest on Geek Nights again.
Speaker 1: And I got a couple of guests lined up, possibly, who are not that close to us physically.
Speaker 0: Physically?
Speaker 1: Physically.
Speaker 1: Sorry, that's an inside joke that doesn't involve you.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like that song from two days ago.
Speaker 0: Yep, that song.
Speaker 0: I can't even remember it.
Speaker 1: So I got an aside.
Speaker 1: Total aside.
Speaker 1: I haven't had a primary care practitioner as a main doctor for a long time because I've basically been in perfect health.
Speaker 0: I think I said on the show how I found one using my insurance's website of list of doctors.
Speaker 0: And I went there a few years ago and it was an awesome doctor.
Speaker 0: I was like, yes, lucky, awesome doctor.
Speaker 0: The best doctor probably ever.
Speaker 0: And then before I could even see the guy a second time, he went to Florida to become a director because he was such a good doctor.
Speaker 0: He's like now a hospital director.
Speaker 0: So the last time... And I haven't been to a doctor since.
Speaker 1: It's the last time I had a primary care practitioner as in the generic doctor you go to for like your physicals and all your normal stuff.
Speaker 1: The one who writes all your referrals and everything.
Speaker 1: I never needed one because I was basically in perfect health.
Speaker 1: I would like go to a clinic.
Speaker 1: And now you're dying.
Speaker 1: So basically I'm over 30 and it's been a few years since I've had even like basic blood work.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, you know what?
Speaker 1: I should just get a legit doctor.
Speaker 1: I recently got new insurance.
Speaker 1: You know, not that long ago.
Speaker 1: Let's do it.
Speaker 1: So I've never had this experience before of.
Speaker 1: I called easily, not exaggerating, 11 doctors on the list from my insurance.
Speaker 0: And you say, hey, are you accepting new patients?
Speaker 1: All of them said, no, they're not.
Speaker 0: Well, well, that's a problem.
Speaker 1: Every doctor I called was like, either I'm not accepting new patients or I am accepting patients, but not patients where I'm the PCP.
Speaker 1: Like I will see you, but I will not be your doctor.
Speaker 1: And the few who would see me could give me an appointment for a physical in like three months.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it takes a while.
Speaker 0: I can tell you the office where the awesome doctor I went to was, and I'm sure there are other doctors there.
Speaker 0: You can attempt it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I have particular insurance, but anyway.
Speaker 0: You can check to see if any of the doctors in that nice office are on your insurance.
Speaker 0: I think that's what I'm going to do as well.
Speaker 1: So after two weeks of this last week, I finally called this one doctor's office.
Speaker 1: And here's the other thing.
Speaker 1: Most of the people who answered the phone were really surly and really weird.
Speaker 1: And most of them would just take a message like, oh, I'll talk to the doctor, whatever.
Speaker 1: No one ever called me back from those places when I called back.
Speaker 1: No idea who I was, nor any idea that I had ever called or anything.
Speaker 0: Here's something I've noticed right in New York.
Speaker 0: People when shopping for doctors are fucking racist.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And knowing that people out there are racist.
Speaker 0: You can basically just assume if you've got a doctor with like a white person's name or a Jewish name or something like that, that the doctor is probably full of patients.
Speaker 0: So you want to go and pick a doctor with an Indian name or something like that?
Speaker 1: There's one exception to that.
Speaker 0: Because you're being anti-racist.
Speaker 1: I called two doctors with traditional Chinese names who had noted, because my insurance says what languages the doctor speaks.
Speaker 0: You had to make sure they speak English and it's not the Chinese doctor in Chinatown who only speaks Chinese.
Speaker 1: Oh, so they all speak English guaranteed.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: In my insurance.
Speaker 1: But it's additional languages.
Speaker 1: So I called two doctors who spoke Cantonese and Mandarin because I work kind of near Chinatown.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 1: They were also full because all the people who speak Chinese Mandarin go to them in Chinatown.
Speaker 0: Try to find a Long Island City Astoria Queens.
Speaker 0: doctor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not so many.
Speaker 1: They're mostly Manhattan or Queens.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch near me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're not my insurance.
Speaker 1: So anyway, last week I finally called this one office and I was like, you know, I'm expecting nothing.
Speaker 1: And the nicest lady who actually sounded kind of cute answered and she was like, all right, he can see you Tuesday and we'll sort everything out.
Speaker 0: This might be.
Speaker 0: here's the thing where you start to worry, right?
Speaker 0: If the doctor is so open to new patients, maybe it's a shit doctor.
Speaker 0: Everyone left.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: You don't know.
Speaker 1: Or maybe he's just actually efficient and nice.
Speaker 0: That's possible as well.
Speaker 1: So we'll see.
Speaker 1: We'll see how this goes.
Speaker 1: First time I've had a doctor that I'm going to in a long time.
Speaker 0: If the doctor is good and not Randy, let me know and I'll go there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I will let you know.
Speaker 1: In fact, it's funny because when I finally got it, I came back.
Speaker 0: If that doctor that I went to that other time didn't go to Florida, I would have told you.
Speaker 1: So I come back into my desk and I sit down and I'm like, ah, finally found a doctor.
Speaker 1: Two of my coworkers like, who is he?
Speaker 1: Cause I've been trying to find a doctor like off and on for the last six months.
Speaker 0: You know what doctors, they make a lot of money.
Speaker 0: You could have been a doctor.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I'm not a doctor.
Speaker 0: I'm also glad I'm not a doctor because the first time I saw something gross, I would have been like, blah.
Speaker 1: That is not the reason I'm glad I'm not a doctor.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I'm not a doctor because if I had wanted to be a doctor, I would have had to do work in college and that would have ruined everything.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: But there are literally only two things that kept me from being a doctor.
Speaker 0: And that is number one, blargh guts.
Speaker 0: And number two, doctors don't work fucking nine to five.
Speaker 0: They got to do that shit in the hospital residency, stay in there all day.
Speaker 1: You can work nine to five if you run a private practice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you got to get to private practice.
Speaker 0: You got to go through all that other bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I wasn't going to go through any bullshit.
Speaker 0: If to become a doctor, I just went to regular college like everyone else and just learned doctoring and didn't have to look at guts.
Speaker 0: And then could just go straight to being a regular doctor who plays golf most of the time.
Speaker 1: We had two separate people.
Speaker 1: There's the one dude on the panel who was like, I can't deal with fake violence, but I can deal with doctor stuff.
Speaker 1: And you're like, I can deal with fake violence, but I can't deal with doctor stuff.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So I got, I got a news.
Speaker 1: It's Thursday.
Speaker 1: It's the lounge here on geek nights.
Speaker 1: So there was a paper and I read this paper actually.
Speaker 1: And I've been thinking a lot about this paper.
Speaker 1: They gave you the full text.
Speaker 1: I got it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So the paper is published recursive fury, conspiracist ideation in the blogosphere in response to research on conspiracist ideation.
Speaker 0: Where was this published?
Speaker 1: Uh, this one is on, I just read the PDF.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It was published in a journal, right?
Speaker 0: It's not a bunch of bullshit, right?
Speaker 0: So I'm referencing two articles just because it has a non bullshit name.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 1: So this is an article that is referencing a bunch of other articles.
Speaker 1: And basically the gist of all this is that the original research, the original article that I read a long time ago, and there's a bunch of related studies to it, was talking about that sort of Rumsfeld sort of remember the crazy guy at open everything, those kinds of people and how certain kinds of people are sort of prone to so-called conspiratorial thinking.
Speaker 1: And they will assume that things that are clearly not conspiracies are obviously conspiracies.
Speaker 1: Those kinds of people tend to have certain similar thought patterns and similar discussion and speech patterns.
Speaker 0: That's kind of obvious.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You think, yeah, things like that are common sense and kind of obvious, but it's one thing to say that it's another thing to actually document the specific detailed similarities between those people.
Speaker 0: What are those detailed similarities besides bad graphic design?
Speaker 1: It's not bad graphic design.
Speaker 1: It's particular kinds of graphic design.
Speaker 1: For example, one of the common signs.
Speaker 0: None of those kinds are good kinds.
Speaker 1: It's not just that they'll have bad graphic design, but that they will show you a piece of evidence linked to a result.
Speaker 1: And then they will show you like the link, like why that is the link.
Speaker 1: And they will have the assumption that the link itself is a revelation that the link, when they tell it to you, is something so self-evident and so obvious that the fact that no one has seen it until they saw it is mind boggling.
Speaker 1: But if you show that link to a normal person, they literally see no connection.
Speaker 1: But conspiratorial people, if they show it to another person who has similar thought patterns, sees the link.
Speaker 1: And basically conspiracy nut bags are all kind of the same.
Speaker 1: If a dude believes in chemtrails, he's likely to believe in similar kinds of crazy BS.
Speaker 0: If someone told it to him, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: So obvious known thing.
Speaker 1: So this paper, the separate one talks about how that research has built an entire community of denier skeptics saying that that research on conspiratorial thinking is a conspiracy to discredit the people who are uncovering conspiracies.
Speaker 1: I am amazed at the recursive fury.
Speaker 0: I'm amazed at the conspiracy.
Speaker 0: people found legitimate research because usually they don't read that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: No, they find legitimate research all the time.
Speaker 1: And it's, you know, in my eyes, the way to detect these people is pretty simple.
Speaker 0: If you find a look at one of their PowerPoints, if it looks like time cube, they're crazy.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So say you don't see the PowerPoint.
Speaker 1: Say you have a friend.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: If a friend ever show them time cube, ask him what they think.
Speaker 1: If you have a friend who denies anything that is actually pretty obvious, like, I don't know, climate change research or the 9/11, you know, inside job kind of people or chemtrails or lizard people or any of that.
Speaker 0: Well, you hope that you hope they deny chemtrails.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah.
Speaker 1: The moon landing hoax or guys, the birthers, the truthers, the Sandy Hook truthers.
Speaker 1: So any of those people will never actually offer a specific theory on why they think there is a conspiracy or what the end goal is.
Speaker 1: They will simply say that the official story is wrong and here is proof of that.
Speaker 1: And you can disprove every individual piece of evidence they have that the official story is untrue, but they will always retreat to further increasingly made up evidence.
Speaker 1: And there is no bottom to that.
Speaker 1: That's all.
Speaker 1: I just think this is an interesting set of links and articles.
Speaker 1: You should all read it.
Speaker 1: It's the lounge.
Speaker 1: It's not news.
Speaker 1: Click at all these links and read it all.
Speaker 1: And if you know someone who doesn't, who rejects climate science and don't talk to that person, just read and all these things.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Pretty much you should just stop talking.
Speaker 0: Get rid of that person from your life.
Speaker 0: Don't talk to them.
Speaker 0: Don't be with them and just ignore them because if you spend time on them, you're just wasting your own life.
Speaker 0: You're allowing them to do damage.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The thing is we have a friend who had friends like this who seemed to be coming around.
Speaker 1: He'd been like trying to like really not give up on them and really logic them until they have to admit basic science is true.
Speaker 1: And I'm pretty sure most of those people have regressed and or still believe in crazy shit to this day.
Speaker 1: And it's been many years.
Speaker 0: The thing is, to be honest, when I was in high school, I didn't know better.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I used to think there were aliens and some crazy shit.
Speaker 1: If you were a kid, if you were 10 years old and you watched Unsolved Mysteries, you were 100 percent sure that aliens come down and Lincoln's ghost will tell you where the gold is.
Speaker 0: That was me for quite a few years.
Speaker 1: That's every 10 year old.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So but how come I'm not 10 years old anymore?
Speaker 1: Either there's something that flips someone from normal person to conspiratorial person.
Speaker 0: You know, but like if I would have met one of those crazy old conspiracy kooks when I was a kid, I would have been like, fuck yeah, man.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 1: Because you watched Unsolved Mysteries.
Speaker 0: I watched similar shows.
Speaker 0: Doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 0: That's the wrong show.
Speaker 0: Doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Wrong show.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day you got for me.
Speaker 0: So check this out.
Speaker 0: I'm checking.
Speaker 0: A game I haven't thought about in a long time, but I actually own every iteration of is Super Smash Brothers Melee Brawl.
Speaker 0: I don't even know which I know one of them's GameCube.
Speaker 0: One of them's Wii.
Speaker 0: I don't know which one is Brawl and which one's Melee.
Speaker 1: Brawl is new, Melee's old.
Speaker 0: Okay, I don't even know that anymore because it's been so fucking long.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I could play that game again.
Speaker 1: Let's play that game.
Speaker 0: We suck so bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we suck even worse than a street fight.
Speaker 1: You and me and our friends playing that game is fine, but Fox only whatever.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so here's a video of a brawl snake verse Meta Knight, two characters that are not often used exclusively play peach or Meta Knight.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway, not by us used often.
Speaker 0: So they're fighting one on one.
Speaker 0: It looks like on a map with no items.
Speaker 0: And what ends up happening is an epic, epic battle.
Speaker 0: I don't know if this is two people with insane, insane skills or if it was computer assisted or whatever.
Speaker 1: Does anyone make computer assisted like versus street fighters?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Is that we can have a contest, right?
Speaker 0: A street fighter AI.
Speaker 0: Basically you take an Arduino, you plug it, you, the Arduino has one or the four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 14 inputs, right?
Speaker 0: The all the joystick and the six buttons and the start button.
Speaker 0: So 15, you have 15 outputs from your Arduino.
Speaker 0: The ticket, basically it is a programmable joystick.
Speaker 0: And then you have, how would it know what was going on on the screen?
Speaker 1: I was thinking more the way they do it with any S ones where they just frame by frame the input in an emulator.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess you have.
Speaker 0: the video output comes into your computer and then your computer sends a serial output to the Arduino, which is a joystick.
Speaker 0: And that goes into the joystick port.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, there's super Nintendo.
Speaker 0: And then we can have a competition where you program the program that takes the video input and outputs the joystick output and has to beat the other guy at street fighter.
Speaker 0: And he is versus his pro.
Speaker 1: You know, it'd be more interesting.
Speaker 0: I would just write one that does flow chart can exactly flow chart.
Speaker 1: I was going to say, why not just make one where you simply make a series of input for the game and then you put series of inputs together and just watch the tournament unfold.
Speaker 0: So you just, you don't know.
Speaker 0: You just try to pre inputted a loop basically because it has to loop at some point.
Speaker 0: There's no decisions it can make versus the other guy's loop of street fighter moves.
Speaker 1: Every, every round of a match, you start the same loop.
Speaker 1: That would be interesting to watch.
Speaker 0: I would hold down and crouch back and kick at basically random intervals, right?
Speaker 1: That's how I fight in real life.
Speaker 1: Kick, kick, kick, kick, kick, kick, hold back and crouch kicking random.
Speaker 0: And hopefully I would eventually do enough damage and avert enough damage that I would win.
Speaker 1: You know what I would do?
Speaker 1: Hadoken hadoken, hadoken, hadoken, hadoken, hadoken, hadoken, hadoken, hadoken, hadoken, hadoken.
Speaker 0: So the other guy does the same thing.
Speaker 0: And now that you have two hadoken infinite loops, the fireballs keep canceling each other out until time runs out.
Speaker 1: Did I input the hadoken in a way that would overlap them faster than the other guy?
Speaker 0: Uh, you, you have to figure out the timing of fastest hadoken.
Speaker 1: I think the fireballs, I have a theory.
Speaker 0: It would start moving closer and closer to the other guy.
Speaker 1: Here's a blast from the past.
Speaker 1: What is your theory of fastest hadoken?
Speaker 0: Uh, down, down, forward, forward button, down, down, forward, forward button.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: This is a pretty epic fight.
Speaker 0: Whether this fight is real or not, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Just watch it.
Speaker 0: Pretend two real people had this battle in Smash Brothers and it's epic.
Speaker 0: So worth watching.
Speaker 1: It is in fact quite epic.
Speaker 1: So I'm a big fan of the super cut.
Speaker 1: You know, every time someone says whatever in a movie, every time, you know, anything like that, every time a gun is fired, every time a guy says, well, it's the nineties.
Speaker 1: This one was false advertising, but it was enjoyable to watch nonetheless primarily because it's so long and so many of the scenes involving this thing are the same scene.
Speaker 0: It also includes many TV shows, which I think is cheating to go movies and TV shows.
Speaker 1: They did not say it is a movie super cut.
Speaker 1: They said it is a super I guess, but it's still, you know, anyway, this is a super cut.
Speaker 1: It claims to be of people being hit by buses.
Speaker 0: Some of them were hit by cars, vans, ambulances and non buses.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But it is enjoyable on the left and it is left less and it is super long.
Speaker 1: And also really I think hit by a bus is the right thing to call this video because the manner in which all these people are hit in this video, if I were going to call that a trope in a movie, I would call it hit by a bus.
Speaker 1: It's always like someone's talking to someone and someone's walking away.
Speaker 0: This video is a super cut of people hit by a literal and or figurative bus.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Because someone's hit by a car in a movie.
Speaker 0: That's different.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's not this kind of scene.
Speaker 1: It's a very different kind of thing.
Speaker 1: This is like dudes backing up into the street, yelling at a girl and then ironically is hit by a bus at a funny moment or serious moment or like I'm going to tell the cops what you'd bus.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's that kind of scene.
Speaker 1: So maybe they meant hit by a bus.
Speaker 1: in that sense in the meta moment Pax East is coming up.
Speaker 1: We're doing two panels.
Speaker 0: I feel like there's a whole bunch of conventions and things like looming on me and I haven't done anything for any of them.
Speaker 1: Pax East, Pax Aus, Kineticon, Anime, Boston.
Speaker 0: I haven't done anything for any of those.
Speaker 0: What should I do first?
Speaker 1: Pax East is coming first.
Speaker 1: Kineticon requires a lot of planning on our part, way more than the other ones.
Speaker 0: I feel like there's a whole bunch of shit I'm supposed to do that I haven't done.
Speaker 0: Should I just bail on all of it?
Speaker 1: Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: We have to write the one.
Speaker 1: All our panels in Anime Boston are really easy except the really complicated one that we decided to do.
Speaker 1: We need to get a lot of clips.
Speaker 0: We was your idea.
Speaker 0: Decided we would do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I said, Scott, this will be a lot of work.
Speaker 1: I remember this conversation.
Speaker 1: We had it like three months ago.
Speaker 1: Scott, this is a great idea, but it'll take a lot of work.
Speaker 1: Are you sure you want to do it?
Speaker 1: You said, yes, we have got plenty of time.
Speaker 1: Let's just make sure we start on it soon and don't wait until a month before Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: When we did that, we had a lot of time.
Speaker 1: We have at least two months before Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: Let's get on.
Speaker 0: Let's do it the week in advance.
Speaker 1: The Book Club book was The Great Gatsby.
Speaker 1: We read it.
Speaker 1: We're doing a show on it soon.
Speaker 1: You should have read it if you haven't already.
Speaker 0: You probably have two weeks to read it.
Speaker 1: You could easily finish it before we do the show.
Speaker 1: It's a very short book.
Speaker 0: It takes like a day or two to read it.
Speaker 1: We got a bunch of videos up, forum, all that stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And there's a blizzard coming.
Speaker 1: So if New York City disappears off the radar, there won't be a show on Monday.
Speaker 0: Also, uh, I've been going to this Android net runner meetup in the city.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: Just go to one soon.
Speaker 0: If I can, if you just go to Google and search for net runner NYC, you'll find a, probably the top link will be a meetup.com link.
Speaker 0: And they apparently they go to this cafe every Tuesday and Friday.
Speaker 0: And there's also tournaments.
Speaker 0: The 16th, which is not this Saturday, but the next Saturday, the non blizzard Saturday, a basically the way the tournament work last time is you show up with a deck of each, you pay five bucks, you play according to the official tournament rules and everyone just sort of had plays net runner all day.
Speaker 0: and that's it.
Speaker 1: Is there a prize?
Speaker 0: A very small prize.
Speaker 1: Is it more than $5?
Speaker 1: Uh, yes.
Speaker 0: It's more than $5 worth because I think the prize last time was that you get the next data pack for nothing from the strat.
Speaker 0: And also I think the top prize winner got like some action tokens.
Speaker 1: When I was in middle school, I had a friend who actually would run kind of for middle schoolers, high stakes, like invite only magic tournaments.
Speaker 1: Everyone would buy in with 20 or 30 bucks and the winner took all the twenties.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: He would take a 10% cut because he ran it in his house and his mom provided snacks.
Speaker 0: All these dollars I think go to Strad.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: I like the Strad.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Uh, so that's all the meta moment.
Speaker 0: Let's get to the main man.
Speaker 1: Now I want to preface this entire conversation by something that is very important.
Speaker 1: We're talking about the fake nerd girl thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Don't get it.
Speaker 1: We are talking about that.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Because it's something, the reason we're talking about it is because number one, it's something the whole internet of nerdery is raging about.
Speaker 0: So hopefully this will be controversial and generate lots of discussions and also lots of hits.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Two, we have an opinion on the issue and that is different from everyone else's opinion and therefore, right.
Speaker 0: Three, it'll be a really good episode.
Speaker 0: We hope.
Speaker 1: I think it'll be a pretty good episode, but no, I have another three that there is legitimate rage about this issue.
Speaker 1: Like it's not like there are, yeah, there are people out there not going to be our typical, why are you people talking about this?
Speaker 1: No, this is a legit thing that we need to talk about.
Speaker 0: Okay, so let's, let's roll all the way to the backist backstory.
Speaker 0: So the backist back story is.
Speaker 0: there are, as we know, sexist piece of shit people in the nerd community, especially nerd conventions of all kinds.
Speaker 1: Disagree with this.
Speaker 0: I take umbrage sir with your opinion.
Speaker 0: And of course also the internet.
Speaker 0: There are many sexist piece of shit people.
Speaker 0: and these sexist piece of shit people, what they have done is they're one of the things that they do.
Speaker 0: is they believe in a crazy conspiracy theory, much like the people in rims news.
Speaker 0: and the crazy conspiracy theory they believe is that when cute girls go to conventions, cosplaying or doing nerdery that many, if not all of them don't actually like those nerdy things that they are simply using their feminine wiles to infiltrate and pose or up to no good something.
Speaker 0: And they're not actually geeks.
Speaker 0: They are fake nerd girls because what girl needs to put on airs to attract geeky guys who have never seen a vagina in their lives?
Speaker 1: That is not the because they will say, but that's the because that they know in their hearts.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Now, before we go any further, those people, irrespective of everything we're about to say, are sexist assholes and you should Brooke them.
Speaker 1: No sympathy.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So of course, the second part of the story in opposition to these piece of shit people, the good people of the internet come back and point the finger at them and say, you piece of shit people.
Speaker 0: And they get mad, indignant and angry as per the incredibly accurate Penny Arcade comic, which I will now, which I will now read to you.
Speaker 1: That was all of the most recent Penny Arcades.
Speaker 0: I'd like this has been the best Penny Arcade in months.
Speaker 1: I laughed out loud.
Speaker 0: So in panel one, Gabe and Tyco, you can see this for yourself.
Speaker 1: Well, reading of a Penny Arcade, of course.
Speaker 0: So in panel one, Gabe and Tyco are sitting in a diner eating some fries and ketchup and shakes.
Speaker 0: And Gabe says, I think Cheetos girlfriend is one of those fake geek girls.
Speaker 0: And Tyco says, all right, so Gabe in this comic, always being the bad guy is playing the part of the sexist piece of shit.
Speaker 0: And Tyco is playing the part of the good people of the internet.
Speaker 0: And he said, Tyco says, I'm going to use some words now that you might not be familiar with, but I want you to promise me that you'll look them up when I'm done.
Speaker 0: And then the second panel Tyco continues.
Speaker 0: Listen up, Satan, who are you to assess her credentials as a woman or a gamer.
Speaker 0: There is no gate.
Speaker 0: You're not the gatekeeper.
Speaker 0: So go drink some bad poison and shit out your life.
Speaker 0: And then in the third panel, the punchline Cheeto is standing there with his fake geek girlfriend, who is a literal person made of straw with some glasses, lipstick, you know what she is?
Speaker 0: Scarf and Batman.
Speaker 1: I think this is a crossover with the bracken from Ogloff.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The point here being there is no such thing as the fake geek girl, right?
Speaker 0: It is this imaginary thing.
Speaker 0: And yes.
Speaker 0: Who are you to assess?
Speaker 0: Who is anyone to assess another person's credentials?
Speaker 0: as a woman gamer, you know, even bring race into it, bring anything you want, right?
Speaker 0: Who is any person to assess someone else's credentials in anything except maybe a scientist judging someone's credentials as a sign.
Speaker 1: Now, case in point, do football fans complain about the fake football girls who put on a jersey for the Super Bowl?
Speaker 1: No, they don't out and watch.
Speaker 0: No, they do not.
Speaker 1: Do they turn to the girl who's hanging out with them to watch the Super Bowl, who may not be a huge fan of football, but is, you know, where?
Speaker 0: these people who are watching the football may indeed be also sexist assholes, possibly, but not always, but they keep it on the inside.
Speaker 0: They don't say to some girl wearing a football jersey.
Speaker 1: Well, what's a two point conversion?
Speaker 1: When does the safety happen?
Speaker 0: Instead, they want to teach them.
Speaker 0: They say, hey, let me tell you what a two point conversion is, baby, which is also sexist, but assuming she doesn't know.
Speaker 0: But still, they don't have this thing.
Speaker 0: This is a unique thing to the nerdery sector.
Speaker 1: Now, I think that there's already.
Speaker 1: the fake geek girl or fake nerd girl argument already has too many preassumptions.
Speaker 1: Preassumption number one, why are we calling them fake nerd or geek girls?
Speaker 1: I'm going to use geek as the word for the rest of this discussion.
Speaker 1: So I have to keep saying geek or nerd.
Speaker 1: So why is it a fake geek girl as opposed to a fake anime fan?
Speaker 0: Well, some people, some people say that they'll say fake gamer, fake, you know, you know, fake gamer girl.
Speaker 0: I've heard being said.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's not just girl.
Speaker 0: It's it could be anything.
Speaker 1: I've never seen it actually be not a girl in the recent conversations that people are doing this.
Speaker 1: I, I've literally never seen someone call someone else a fake gamer if they were a dude.
Speaker 0: So, yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the point here, right, that the good people are making on this side, the well-intentioned, well-meaning people who, if you have not foreseen, you know, we still disagree with on some sense.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Is that, look, if somebody says that they like something, someone says they like Final Fantasy and they're not saying it in a sarcastic or sly way, who is anyone to disbelieve them?
Speaker 0: You can't know what the person feels or thinks when they see Final Fantasy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: If they say they like it, you know, it's.
Speaker 0: it's not an objective thing you can argue.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Like you could say, no, Final Fantasy six was called Final Fantasy three in the US.
Speaker 0: That's an objective fact that you can discuss.
Speaker 0: And there really is no argument.
Speaker 0: It's just a fact.
Speaker 0: But if someone says they like Final Fantasy, you can't argue with it.
Speaker 1: Now, if you disagree, everyone likes different things.
Speaker 0: They express their taste.
Speaker 0: That is their taste.
Speaker 0: There's no dispute.
Speaker 0: If someone says they like games and if that means that that the label of gamer is an appropriate application, as in someone who likes games is a gamer, then someone who says they like games is a gamer, whether you, you know, whatever they know or whatever you want to challenge them on or what, you know, now that's all there is to it.
Speaker 1: This is why I really want to talk about the idea of the fake nerd specifically, because in this case, all right, so someone could say I, you know, you said someone likes something.
Speaker 1: you cannot impinge upon someone saying they like something.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: I like cosplay.
Speaker 1: I like anime.
Speaker 1: I like games.
Speaker 0: I like cowboy Viva.
Speaker 1: Since when does liking in any way imply geek?
Speaker 0: Uh huh.
Speaker 1: Liking implies fan.
Speaker 1: If I say I am a fan of games, it doesn't matter at all if I know almost nothing about games.
Speaker 1: I like games.
Speaker 1: I like the idea of games.
Speaker 1: That's what the word fan is to be used for.
Speaker 1: We have a word for this.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, right, I think what's happening here is that there are many people in the world, many, many who are fans of things and the things that they are fans of are traditionally domains of geekery.
Speaker 0: For example, a fan of Star Trek, right?
Speaker 0: That most people put a fan of Star Trek as a geek, right?
Speaker 0: Because that is a geeky thing to like, right?
Speaker 0: Star Trek.
Speaker 0: It's pretty nerdy and geeky.
Speaker 0: So therefore, if you like it, that makes you a geek.
Speaker 0: So because we can't dispute you liking it and you do like it, you say you like it, that makes you an automatic geek because you like Star Trek.
Speaker 1: So what you're saying and what I'm saying, what we're saying here is that things that are traditionally the purview of nerdy basement dudes and, you know, nerdy geeky, sort of colloquial like things that those kinds of people are into that quote unquote normal people are not into.
Speaker 1: If someone is into one of those things, then they are therefore one of those kinds of people.
Speaker 0: Ah, and here's the thing is that kind of person, that basement dweller, when he sees someone who is a fan of the same thing he is a fan of, right?
Speaker 0: Yet that person, you know, is trying to label themselves the same labels he labels himself with and be in the same group, the same, you know, community as him, but yet is not actually the same as him.
Speaker 0: He is feeling threatened or infringed upon or that the other person is an opposer or fake in some way.
Speaker 1: Now I've run into this firsthand and it still really seems to only affect nerds because if you are a fan of something and you are deeply into it and you're a stereotypical nerd because that seems to be the kind of...
Speaker 0: Who does exist.
Speaker 0: We've met that person many times.
Speaker 1: And those kinds of stereotypical nerdy people tend to also be kind of sexist.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Partly due to the fact that their hobbies, there is a sexist society, obviously, that, you know, there's no physical reason why more guys are into, say, comic books from the beginning than girls.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: There's social and cultural and all these...
Speaker 0: It just so happens that most comic books are cheesecake superhero nonsense that no girl would want to read.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And a few girls would want to read.
Speaker 0: But so there are many who do.
Speaker 1: The people who were traditionally stereotypically in popular culture into those things and were socially awkward would have to sort of band together like you'd find the one other comic fan in your neighborhood and you knew that they were just like you because they like the same thing as you because no normal person would like that thing.
Speaker 1: And that ridiculous mentality has somehow survived into the year 2013.
Speaker 1: Somehow.
Speaker 1: So those people who are super... And you see this, like look at the Street Fighter guys who are like super into the tournament scene.
Speaker 1: There's a deep and surprising and really open sexist bent to the community of semi-professional Street Fighter tournament types.
Speaker 1: Professional gaming in general, you know, has a but they're also really hostile toward people who want to learn their hobby but aren't good at it.
Speaker 1: And somehow that culture maintains...
Speaker 0: Obviously all these generalizations aren't 100% true, right?
Speaker 0: But it's big enough, it's true enough of enough people of a great enough percentage that it is a problem in the community that is worthy of discussing and combating.
Speaker 1: Well, like let's put it this way.
Speaker 1: I've been to nightclubs.
Speaker 1: I've been to dances and raves and things.
Speaker 1: I've been to many conventions, professional, non-professional, fan, whatever.
Speaker 1: How come anime cons smell like shit way more than any other con?
Speaker 0: That is a fact.
Speaker 1: The reasons behind it, but there is a correlation to an anime cons and smelly people.
Speaker 0: There is no question about that.
Speaker 1: So to get back to the definition of geek or nerd, I'm a geek/nerd.
Speaker 1: I'm a geek.
Speaker 0: There is no disputing that.
Speaker 0: I care about...
Speaker 1: I have deep interests in a relatively narrow set of areas and as a result, I have a lot of knowledge about those areas.
Speaker 1: I also... One of the things that I'm a geek or nerd about... I guess I said I was going to not say geek or nerd.
Speaker 1: I keep saying geek or nerd.
Speaker 0: XCOM?
Speaker 1: No, I was going to say language.
Speaker 0: Marching bands?
Speaker 1: I'm really into grammar, like for real.
Speaker 1: Like I really care about style and writing and things like this.
Speaker 0: Eats, shoots, and leaves.
Speaker 1: So the lively art of writing is the book that I would ascribe to.
Speaker 1: So as a result, I care also about nomenclature, which comes in from science.
Speaker 1: You know, binomial nomenclature, how we classify animals.
Speaker 1: We say Pluto is no longer a planet because if we call Pluto a planet, the word planet means fucking nothing.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: If you have a word, it needs to have a clear definition that differs it from other words, otherwise the word kind of becomes useless.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, the word game means so many things that it's not useful for argument or debate or intellectual discussions anymore because the meaning is so broad.
Speaker 1: So we'll say orthogame or casual game.
Speaker 0: We'll come up with a new term or we'll define our terms beforehand, you know, so that people are clear about what we're discussing.
Speaker 1: But like, for example, the word punch, hit, strike, kick, they're all... They all mean similar things, but yet they have nuance and they have specific sort of differences.
Speaker 1: If they actually literally meant the same thing, then we wouldn't have different words.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And there's no one claiming like, was that a punch or was it not a punch?
Speaker 1: Well, sometimes... His fist was kind of half closed?
Speaker 1: In law, we have that distinction between an open-handed and closed-handed strike.
Speaker 0: What if it's half opened?
Speaker 0: What if my pinky finger's out?
Speaker 1: Well, then the judge has to decide if there's ambiguity.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Usually they'll define one type and then everything else is the other type.
Speaker 0: What if I make a fist, but I swing it sideways like a slap?
Speaker 1: Ah, but at the same time, what if we have a definition of a closed fist and we have higher punishments for closed fist?
Speaker 1: Because that implies probably more intent to harm than an open fist slap.
Speaker 1: But in many martial arts, an open-handed strike is actually more powerful.
Speaker 0: Quite possibly.
Speaker 1: Now, what we just had is a stereotypically nerdy conversation.
Speaker 0: Because we are those people.
Speaker 0: We do a podcast called Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: We've been doing it for six years, if not seven years.
Speaker 1: We've been doing it since Halloween 2005.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: We used to do that shit four nights a week.
Speaker 0: So actually seven or eight, seven going on eight years.
Speaker 1: I've been doing Geek Nights longer than I've been doing anything else in my entire life except masturbating.
Speaker 0: Except adding all the elementary, middle, and high school together.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 0: Any one of those schools I spent less time in than I spent doing Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: So what I'm getting at here is that if we already have... It's going to sound like I'm justifying the people who are saying there are fake geeks.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: I'm not.
Speaker 1: Hear me out.
Speaker 1: The problem with complex opinions is they don't travel well meme-wise.
Speaker 0: No, they don't.
Speaker 0: Because again, people will misconstrue what you're saying due to definitions of words.
Speaker 1: And again, to reiterate, the people who talk about fake nerd girls, 99.9% of the time are sexist douchebags.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: So if we have a word fan that already means someone likes something.
Speaker 1: I like cosplay.
Speaker 1: I like anime.
Speaker 1: You cannot in any way impinge upon that opinion unless you have objective evidence that that person has literally never seen or has literally no understanding of what the word they say they like actually means.
Speaker 1: If I say I like charmed quarks, and I literally don't know what a quark is.
Speaker 0: What is a charmed quark?
Speaker 0: And then I look at I'm winning a video and you don't know what it is, then sure, you're not a fan of charmed quarks.
Speaker 1: That situation really doesn't exist.
Speaker 0: If you say you like Star Wars and you know you can recognize Jabba the Hutt, you can pick him out of a lineup.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: We're pretty sure you're a fan of Star Wars.
Speaker 0: Who are we to challenge you?
Speaker 1: Hell, if you don't know the name of any character in Star Wars, but you saw it once and liked it, or you just like the idea of space opera and you know Star Wars that and you say, yeah, I like things like Star Wars.
Speaker 1: Still, you really can't impinge too deeply upon that opinion.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: There's nothing you can say to challenge that.
Speaker 0: And if you do try to challenge someone who says they like something, honestly, even if maybe they are lying and who knows why anyone would do that, because I have never met anyone who's ever done that ever.
Speaker 0: Why are you doing that?
Speaker 0: You're just a jerk, right?
Speaker 0: If someone comes up to me and says they like Star Trek and I say, you've never seen Star Trek.
Speaker 0: I'm just an asshole, whether they've seen Star Trek or not.
Speaker 1: I don't think any of our listeners look at that reference.
Speaker 0: That is why it is there to weed out the true nerds from the fans in the games.
Speaker 1: So we have a word for that already.
Speaker 1: If I dress up as a character and go to a convention, I'm clearly a fan of either that character or costuming of some kind or acting or something.
Speaker 0: If you didn't like doing it, why would you do it?
Speaker 1: Maybe I'm doing.
Speaker 0: it is even more evidence than saying you like doing it.
Speaker 1: I guess we could say there are fake nerd girls, like fake cosplayers.
Speaker 1: If a company that was trying to promote an anime hired girls to dress up to basically be booth babes and cosplay and wander around a convention that don't know about it, would be by definition a fake.
Speaker 0: I guess it wouldn't necessarily.
Speaker 0: I mean, it depends what your definition of the word fake is, but yes, that would be a person who is in some way physically appearing to be a fan or geek about a intellectual property.
Speaker 0: that is not actually.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I would suggest.
Speaker 0: A lot of people do get paid to do it when they do like it.
Speaker 1: Do you believe in your heart that there, that anyone who has ever complained about a fake nerd girl has ever complained about a booth, babe?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: So that would be a very few people.
Speaker 0: So that would be almost zero people.
Speaker 1: If there's even one, if we say that the word fan is unimpingable, I label myself as a fan of something.
Speaker 1: There's really no way to argue against that.
Speaker 1: You could argue that that thing is not good, but that's a totally separate conversation that nerds have all the time.
Speaker 1: We love talking about why we hate the thing you like, but what then Scott does nerd or geek mean?
Speaker 1: If I say I am a geek, what does that mean?
Speaker 0: Well, we discussed this in a very long episode ago and we discuss it not as often because it's sort of a sealed deal, right?
Speaker 0: And, but surprisingly many people, even though this deal has been sealed, sort of are still confused.
Speaker 0: So let us go over this same topic again because the internet needs to get the records straight.
Speaker 0: It's not going to matter though.
Speaker 0: This isn't going to set anyone straight except maybe two listeners.
Speaker 1: The definition we kind of use, but really it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Nerd and geek are synonyms.
Speaker 1: We distinguish them just because we're nerds.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: So, so what a nerd is, at least by our definition, is somebody who has a deep, deep knowledge of one or extremely few number of areas.
Speaker 0: For example, that guy who knows everything there is to know about Star Trek, but doesn't know anything else.
Speaker 0: He's typically so not even, regardless, right?
Speaker 0: Socially awkward, usually of high intellectual knowledge, like very good at school or maths or science, right?
Speaker 1: See, already we disagree a little bit.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: That is, that is the nerd person.
Speaker 1: I think of geeks nerd as being a hyper-focused geek, a geek to me.
Speaker 0: That's sort of what that is.
Speaker 1: But I don't attach to nerd socially awkward or any of that stuff.
Speaker 1: That is a separate application of the word dork.
Speaker 0: You want to move that over to dork?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You can be dorky nerd or a cool nerd or dweebus.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the difference is.
Speaker 1: I know what a doofus is, but I don't know the difference between a dork and a dweeb.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but you know, a geek is someone who does have deep knowledge of one or more areas, but compared to a nerd, they're usually into more areas, shallower in all of those areas, still deep relative to most people.
Speaker 1: Scott and I are game theory geeks.
Speaker 1: Dr.
Speaker 1: Hazard is a game theory nerd.
Speaker 0: That is right.
Speaker 0: His knowledge of game theory pretty much goes as deep as anyone's.
Speaker 0: Our knowledge is deeper than most people.
Speaker 0: The fact that we even know it exists is deeper than most people, but it goes kind of deeper than most people.
Speaker 0: But do we really know about it?
Speaker 1: Fuck no.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, Dr.
Speaker 1: Hazard doesn't know a whole lot about anime, nor would I expect him to.
Speaker 0: He's probably not even an anime fan.
Speaker 0: I have no idea how much anime he's seen.
Speaker 1: In fact, Hint, if you have a doctorate in anything, you're probably a nerd and whatever it is, you've got to doctor it in.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Geekery and nerdery applies to different topical areas, right?
Speaker 0: You know, you can be like a cream, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, it's like, yeah, it's like you're an ex villain, the ex nerd or ex geek, right?
Speaker 0: You can actually be a nerd and a geek simultaneously.
Speaker 1: Simultaneously.
Speaker 1: I mean, only recently would I say that we have transitioned like in the last four or five years from anime nerds to anime geeks, primarily because we don't watch nearly as much anime as we used to and don't pay nearly as much attention to the background of it as we used to.
Speaker 1: We know our focus has shifted.
Speaker 1: I'm, I'm rapidly going down the road of being like game design, game nerd, not game theory nerd, but game nerd.
Speaker 1: But anyway, digression.
Speaker 1: So we, so geeks and nerds are just people who not only are a fan of a thing, but have sign of deep knowledge about that thing and deep interest in continuing to further their knowledge of said thing.
Speaker 1: The fan of Lord of the Rings really likes the Lord of the Rings.
Speaker 1: The nerd of Lord of the Rings can name all the dwarves and remembers their histories from the Hobbit and ties them into references in the Lord of the Rings and can quote the Simarillion at you.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So Lord of the Rings geek can tell you the entire plot and name most of the characters, but doesn't remember Radagast.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So for example, let us take something we are both familiar with, right?
Speaker 0: Uh, Neon Genesis Evangelion, right?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I've seen that a bunch of times.
Speaker 1: I've seen that entire show five times.
Speaker 0: I'm a huge fan of it.
Speaker 0: I enjoy it very much.
Speaker 0: I am a geek of that show.
Speaker 0: I know many things about it.
Speaker 0: Uh, mostly because I've watched it so many times, but I've also read many Wikipedia and internets.
Speaker 1: I would say you're on the deeper end of geek because you also know about the people who made Evangelion.
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 0: I know the name of the director is Hideaki Anno.
Speaker 0: I know that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, but rim, how many angels are there?
Speaker 1: 13.
Speaker 0: I think it's 12 or 13, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm not even that sure.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: So it's like any one piece of trivia.
Speaker 0: you might ask, even someone
Speaker 1: like us, I'm glad you said the word trivia because I was going to say that one of the biggest ways to say if someone is a nerd geek and our definition is if they are good at trivia on their thing,
Speaker 0: right now, any single piece of trivia, right?
Speaker 0: Is not going to determine whether someone truly has a deep or extremely deep knowledge in an area to determine if they are truly a geek or nerd of that area.
Speaker 0: But enough trivia, especially the easy trivia, like, can you name three characters from the on Genesis Evangelion?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: I was going to try to think of like the most obscure three characters.
Speaker 1: Like what's the name of the guitar playing guy?
Speaker 0: Guitar playing guy.
Speaker 1: He works in the nerve operation center and he plays the guitar.
Speaker 0: You're making shit up.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: What about the glasses guy who has the crush on Masato who also works in the nerve data center?
Speaker 0: Oh, I know the guy, but I don't know his name because I'm only a geek and not a nerd.
Speaker 0: That's obscure trivia.
Speaker 0: I'm saying, you know, name any three and yeah, you've proved that you're probably a geek because a fan, you know, actually I didn't name three, so I guess, I don't know, Masato, Ray, there you go.
Speaker 0: I'll do three different ones.
Speaker 0: I'll do, uh, Kaoru, uh, Asuka and, uh, it's Genda.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: I point out our delays where we were trying to think of names to say that would be funny or reflective or
Speaker 0: whatever, the kind of thing that geeks do, but here's the controversial thing that people might get mad at us for saying the
Speaker 1: whole reason we're doing the show?
Speaker 1: because Scott has been on about this for a while lately for three days.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Is you have this guy, this girl, here's the scene.
Speaker 0: I sort of read a, I read something online that was a, an anecdote from a girl and I'm paraphrasing and or modifying that story because I don't remember it exactly because my memory sucks.
Speaker 1: So we're going to construct the straw man for our point.
Speaker 0: That's correct.
Speaker 0: So this is based on a true story.
Speaker 0: Construct the bracken wife girls at a convention.
Speaker 0: She sees a table at the convention, sexist assholes sitting behind the table.
Speaker 0: She doesn't know he's a sexist asshole yet.
Speaker 0: She sees a merchandise on the table related to an intellectual property that she enjoys.
Speaker 0: She says, yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's from that.
Speaker 0: I really like that.
Speaker 0: Sexist asshole says, oh, you really like that, huh?
Speaker 0: Well, do you know piece of trivia?
Speaker 0: And she says, no, it's been a while since I played it.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're just a sexist asshole who is testing me to see if I was fake geek girl or not.
Speaker 0: And he says, yes, I was.
Speaker 0: And you failed.
Speaker 0: fake geek girl.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That is a exaggerated paraphrase.
Speaker 1: That is exactly how those kinds of people talk.
Speaker 0: So here are the thing.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Dude behind table is sexist asshole.
Speaker 0: Why are you challenging people based?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And first, and even if it's okay to challenge people like that, which it isn't one piece of trivia determines the whole thing, even if it's not an easy trivia.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: However, the real question I have is girl or guy or whatever you are, black, purple, white, yellow person.
Speaker 0: You said you were a fan of intellectual property.
Speaker 1: So I started with black and then a made up one.
Speaker 1: that isn't real.
Speaker 1: And then back to any species.
Speaker 0: If you're a dolphin and you say that you like Reagan, you know, secret of mana.
Speaker 1: I was really curious to see what you were going to say.
Speaker 0: Picking something, whatever.
Speaker 0: First thing that came to mind.
Speaker 1: One way to tell a nerd is that they really worry about what social currency they reference in a situation like this.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You're a dolphin and you say you like secret of mana.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: If I ask you a random trivia, what's the name of that weird praying men is boss in the beginning.
Speaker 0: And you don't know that.
Speaker 0: So K not to know that.
Speaker 0: But if you say you're a fan of secret of mana and you don't know what mana sword is.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: What the fuck now?
Speaker 1: Now, at the same time, you are a fan.
Speaker 1: We're not saying you're not.
Speaker 1: You're not.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know the word secret of mana.
Speaker 0: You said you liked it.
Speaker 0: You probably must have played it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But you're not a secret of mana geek.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: I mean, if you can't get the basic trivia, if you really know nothing about it, then you really doesn't matter whether it's, you know, what sex, gender, race, whatever you are, you're not a geek.
Speaker 0: You don't know anything about it.
Speaker 0: A geeky person learns a lot about the things that they're interested.
Speaker 0: They take their fandoms and learn things.
Speaker 0: If you like playing D and D and you play it often, but you don't know any of the rules because you just don't remember them.
Speaker 0: You're a D and D fan, D and D player, D and D gamer, not a D and D geek geek.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to say you're a fake D and D geek or you're pretending you might just be using the wrong label on yourself.
Speaker 1: Labels.
Speaker 1: That's where we got to get into it.
Speaker 1: Cause here's the crux of the problem.
Speaker 1: There are, if nerds and geeks like to use prescriptive language for things like this.
Speaker 1: So for example, a prescriptive label of geek means we have a definition of geek.
Speaker 1: Thereby semi objectively, people are geeks are not geeks.
Speaker 1: If you are a fan of Star Wars, but you couldn't name any planet from Star Wars, don't know anything about Star Wars, never heard of George Lucas, you're pretty objectively not a Star Wars geek.
Speaker 0: If I make a joke about Alderaan and you don't laugh, right?
Speaker 1: Well, maybe the joke wasn't funny.
Speaker 0: That's possibly true.
Speaker 0: But if you see someone wearing the Alderaan weather thread t-shirt and I don't think it's threadless one and you don't get the joke, you're not a Star Wars geek.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's true.
Speaker 0: It's only one trivia, but it's like, or, you know, here's another example.
Speaker 0: If you've never heard of George Lucas and you don't know who George Lucas is, you just know what Star Wars is.
Speaker 1: Then you're probably not a Star Wars geek.
Speaker 0: Probably not.
Speaker 1: You might be the biggest Star Wars fan ever, but Scott's question is more subtle.
Speaker 0: If you can't tell an X-wing from a TIE fighter, not a Star Wars geek.
Speaker 1: Well, before I get back to Scott's question, the other way to look at labels is that they're self-descriptive.
Speaker 1: If I want to label myself as X, who is anyone else to say that I am wrong because I am the one choosing the label for myself?
Speaker 0: Nobody.
Speaker 0: Nobody can tell you you're wrong.
Speaker 1: Because I'm black.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: You decided that black means white.
Speaker 1: So yeah, by your definition, I am literally African-American.
Speaker 1: I have dark skin.
Speaker 0: No, you don't.
Speaker 1: Who are you?
Speaker 0: Because those are objective labels.
Speaker 1: Colloquially, the words geek and nerd have come to mean anyone who likes things from a list of social currencies and properties and genres of things that in the seventies and eighties were considered nerdy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: If someone says, you know, they're a fan of American Idol, no one calls that a geek, but I do.
Speaker 0: I say, man, if you're deep into it, like, you know, who's won every season and shit, and you really study it and watch every episode and read about it online all the time.
Speaker 0: I call you an American Idol geek.
Speaker 0: That's what I do.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So, so here's, I guess the question Scott's getting at and correct me if I'm wrong is the kind of an aside from the whole fake nerd girl debate, which is pretty nicely one sided debate.
Speaker 1: Luckily those people are assholes.
Speaker 1: I can't reiterate that.
Speaker 0: I hate you guys is why don't you know about the thing you like?
Speaker 1: If you're into something, like you're really into something, why aren't you a geek about that thing?
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: You, you, you're super, you're a fan of something enough to cosplay as it, to buy merchandise for it, to watch it, to read it, to, to, to play it all the time, to talk about it.
Speaker 0: But you haven't even read the Wikipedia page for it.
Speaker 0: And you don't.
Speaker 0: And I mean, I don't even know advanced trivia about lots of things, but you can't get any basic trivia questions.
Speaker 0: Even with many, many chances, you have shown you have almost no knowledge of the thing.
Speaker 0: Now, maybe you're not.
Speaker 0: Why don't you?
Speaker 1: Now, maybe you're not that interested in it.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: But the question becomes, if you're the kind of person who was a fan of a lot of things, like you really like Sherlock and you really like doctor who, and you're really like, I don't know the old slayers anime, but you don't know anything about any of those things you consume.
Speaker 1: What do you know a lot about?
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Like, are you into something?
Speaker 1: Cause I don't want to exaggerate, but I've met a lot of people in my life who don't have really any substantially deep interests.
Speaker 0: And now I will point out to you, right?
Speaker 0: The reason that this is important, even if you disagree with our definitions of geek and nerd, which is fine, right?
Speaker 0: Here is something that it's, this is the reason I have set the definitions in that way is to better describe this very real problem that I don't think is disputable.
Speaker 0: Even if we can eliminate sexism, racism, and all the isms, right?
Speaker 0: We have a situation now.
Speaker 0: Let us, let us imagine a gaming convention.
Speaker 0: At this gaming convention, many people will come together.
Speaker 0: Some of those people by our definitions will be fans of a particular game.
Speaker 0: Let's call it world of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: Some people who come to this convention will be geeks of world of Warcraft and they have come together because it is a convention.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's Blizzcon.
Speaker 0: World of Warcraft is pretty big there, right?
Speaker 0: And these people come together thinking that they are of the same community, right?
Speaker 0: That they are, they are of one people.
Speaker 0: They should get along.
Speaker 0: They all love world of Warcraft and play it great deal.
Speaker 0: However, some of those people are by our definition geeks and some are fans.
Speaker 0: And the fact is those people, even though they unite and come together on this single intellectual property, it should be happy times.
Speaker 0: They are actually of incredibly different psychologies.
Speaker 0: One of these people enjoys things.
Speaker 0: One group of them enjoys things on the surface level.
Speaker 0: The other person enjoys the thing in a different way.
Speaker 0: They enjoy the same property in a different way.
Speaker 0: They don't actually get along that well.
Speaker 0: The same reason me and rim don't game well with people who aren't serious about games, even though we're playing the exact same goddamn board game.
Speaker 1: Now don't get us wrong.
Speaker 1: There is nothing wrong with, I mean, for example, I really like kung fu movies.
Speaker 1: I do not know a lot about kung fu movies, but here's what bothers me.
Speaker 1: I know very little about kung fu movies.
Speaker 1: I mean, Daryl Sarad, his pinky finger knows more about kung fu movies than I ever know in my life.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 1: I enjoy kung fu movies.
Speaker 0: I watch them often.
Speaker 1: How come whenever I talk about kung fu movies with just random people I meet in the street or like coworkers or anything, they also will profess to like kung fu movies or might even be really into kung fu movies.
Speaker 1: And yet somehow no less about kung fu movies than I do.
Speaker 1: And I know almost nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, I know the only actor I can name in a kung fu movie is Bruce Lee.
Speaker 0: And I know that there was some fake ones like Bruce Lee and Bruce lie.
Speaker 1: And that's all I learned about that from that thing.
Speaker 1: We bought it.
Speaker 0: I can't name a kung fu movie director.
Speaker 0: I can name a few movie titles.
Speaker 0: I can't even remember the names of ones I've seen.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But that's still more than people who claim to be right.
Speaker 0: So people who have the deep interest, right.
Speaker 0: And people who have the light interest in the same property are often these days coming together into the same physical community space.
Speaker 0: But they do not get along regardless of gender, race, whatever.
Speaker 0: They're not actually of the same community.
Speaker 0: They're groups of Star Trek people who are surface level into Star Trek.
Speaker 0: And there are people into it who are Trekkie, Trekker, whatever word you want to use.
Speaker 0: And those two groups don't go well together.
Speaker 0: And this is a conflict we are going to see happen.
Speaker 0: It currently mostly exhibits itself in, you know, between these conventions and between the males of the deep interest group and the females of the fan group.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And this sex, you know, sexism allows the.
Speaker 1: I think it is existing and being a problem everywhere and has been for a while as convention culture is growing because, you know, the Internet is basically connecting all these people and convention culture is going to be a huge thing in the next 20 years.
Speaker 0: And it started huge.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, you think now is huge.
Speaker 1: I think now is such a bare beginning of that.
Speaker 0: I also think.
Speaker 1: But the problem is that the sexist dudes are really going out of their way to get it all out there in the open.
Speaker 1: That is there.
Speaker 1: Basically, those guys stand out and I'm sick of them.
Speaker 0: Who isn't sick of them?
Speaker 1: Them.
Speaker 0: That's about it.
Speaker 1: Now, I wonder if it's because they want their thing to be exclusive.
Speaker 1: Do they feel threatened?
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: I think what it is and this is just a guess, right, is that because they're sexist, they see a girl and they assume that that is a person who doesn't know.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That that is a person of the other community.
Speaker 0: So they attack.
Speaker 0: And if they weren't sexist.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They would perhaps look at dudes and recognize that as someone of the other.
Speaker 0: Or maybe when there were no girls there, they would, for example, see a dude wearing his Star Trek logo pin on the wrong side of his uniform and challenge that person in the same way.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like they'll challenge anyone who is merely a fan and not a geek, who is of the other, of the not same community that they don't go well with together.
Speaker 0: But because they are sexist, they see a girl and immediately assume that that person is in the other side and challenges them straight out.
Speaker 0: And that is the sexism aspect.
Speaker 1: Now, it's interesting if you think about it, the desire of these sort of specialist communities to have only people of their type at a gathering, at a convention, for example, is directly opposed by the fact that every convention, as soon as it gets beyond off the radar, immediately attracts every type of.
Speaker 1: basically the social currency is the beacon, not the level of engagement.
Speaker 1: So thus, while at the same time, there's an increased balkanization of specialization, there is simultaneously an increased merging of the communities to where the majority of the people at anime cons have seen less than 10 anime ever in their lives.
Speaker 1: And I'm not exaggerating.
Speaker 1: I mean, you go to the Star Trek convention.
Speaker 1: There's only like, you know, not Star Trek celebration because that's Star Wars celebration.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Star Wars celebration.
Speaker 1: You go to like a local, like sci fi Star Wars convention, for example, it's the 40 dudes from that area who are super into Star Wars.
Speaker 0: And 501st people.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You go to the Star Trek convention and a few kids and a few families heard about it on the radio, but you go to Star Wars celebration and you're really into Star Wars.
Speaker 1: It's more like the New York comic con.
Speaker 1: It's really, there's a lot of casual fans.
Speaker 0: There's people there who just sort of know Star Wars and like it because really even people who don't self identify as nerds and geeks fucking like Star Wars.
Speaker 0: It's rare to find a Star Wars not liker.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: But you go to an anime convention and you know, literally half the people in the audience of a panel who I can't believe they even went to a panel have never seen, I don't know, really any anime notable I'd ever can ever think of.
Speaker 1: listing and a list of notable anime.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And in, so basically the conclusion is right.
Speaker 0: We have this conflict of the deep interest geek nerd people and the shallow interest fan people of the same intellectual properties or topics or hobbies coming together and a conflict is brewing that currently mostly exhibits itself across sexist borders,
Speaker 1: but will
Speaker 0: over time reveal itself, I believe, across all borders.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And look at what's happening now.
Speaker 1: Look at magfest.
Speaker 1: Magfest is half people who are playing games the entire time.
Speaker 1: And half people are going to concerts the entire time, but there is a huge undercurrent of people who are from the internet, not super into games or concerts, super into drinking and internet bullshit and running around making a ruckus.
Speaker 1: Anime cons are primarily people who aren't super into anime.
Speaker 1: Every convention that grows at all is becoming an internet convention that is loosely tied to the intellectual property that spawned it.
Speaker 1: And that's it.
Speaker 1: And there's no way around that.
Speaker 1: The attempts to make hardcore anime conventions fail or they're tiny.
Speaker 1: And I don't even really.
Speaker 1: it's sad that I'm super into anime.
Speaker 1: And as much as I complain about the fact that I go to an anime con and no one knows or cares about anime, the anime only cons are even sadder.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So here is the things that you need to do, right?
Speaker 0: Number one, do not be a jerk and challenge people who are on the other side, right?
Speaker 0: You know, because there's nothing wrong with being a fan or there's nothing wrong with being a geek.
Speaker 0: We're not, you know, it's not bad or right or wrong to be on either side.
Speaker 0: We simply have to recognize that even though two peoples or two groups of peoples may like the same thing, they are actually not people.
Speaker 0: They approach it differently, enjoy it differently and don't actually get along, you know, and don't mesh as well together as you may think they should.
Speaker 0: So just keep it civil and recognize that you aren't really the same, even though you should be.
Speaker 0: And don't start fighting and getting into bullshit drama.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's not bad or right or wrong to be either one.
Speaker 0: And number two, don't go around fucking challenging people, you know, saying, ah, you're on the other side.
Speaker 0: You're bad pointing it out.
Speaker 0: It's like it's not wrong to be on the other side.
Speaker 0: And two, you're being a jerk and an asshole, right?
Speaker 0: Don't assume that just because someone may have boobs or have different colored skin or whatnot, that which side they are on.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That's fucking ist of any asterisk you want to put in front of it.
Speaker 0: And we also finally would encourage all people to come to the side that we are on because whatever side you're on, that's the side you want more people to be on.
Speaker 1: You don't have to be a nerd.
Speaker 1: At least be a geek.
Speaker 1: At least be into something.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like if you like something, if you're that fan person, nothing wrong with it.
Speaker 0: That's totally cool.
Speaker 0: Good for you.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: Like we said, why don't you know more about the thing?
Speaker 1: Like we said, I'm a fan of Kung Fu movies.
Speaker 1: My knowledge is not going to get much deeper than it already is.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I met a guy who's super into metal gear.
Speaker 0: Metal gear is number one thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, you do.
Speaker 1: this anecdote is sad.
Speaker 0: I've never beaten a metal gear game in my life.
Speaker 1: Scott, you've played less than half of the metal gear games that ever existed at all.
Speaker 0: I've got through like the second room of metal gear solid.
Speaker 0: I can get to the trucks in metal gear.
Speaker 0: one on the NES.
Speaker 0: Did you play snakes revenge?
Speaker 0: I don't know if that, I think maybe I turned it on once and then couldn't get anywhere and died and then turn it off.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But I know the original metal gear came out in Japan.
Speaker 0: What didn't suck like the NES one that it came out for the MSX too.
Speaker 0: I know that now all the metal gears are on the PlayStation.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure there's four of them.
Speaker 0: And there's, I knew there's a new one coming out soon.
Speaker 1: What's the main character in metal gear?
Speaker 0: Solid snake, right?
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: I know this is one other character.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Gray Fox.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 1: I gray Fox.
Speaker 0: I know some things about, uh, metal gear, big boss.
Speaker 0: I was about to say, I know the metal gear is a big Mac.
Speaker 0: I know a lot of things about metal gear.
Speaker 1: Interestingly, there's no way to know the metal gear is a big Mac.
Speaker 0: If you just play the NES metal gear one, I met a person who was a super metal gear fan.
Speaker 0: That was their literal number one thing.
Speaker 0: They did not know about the fact that the original metal gear was Japan.
Speaker 0: Only MSX two wasn't the same as the NES one.
Speaker 0: They thought any S one was the original metal gear.
Speaker 0: They had never played the original NES metal gear at all.
Speaker 0: The oldest metal gear that they had played was solid one.
Speaker 0: And the only metal gear knowledge they had was metal gear knowledge from the games themselves.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And they knew the name of Hideo Kojima, which is more than nothing, but they literally had no other metal gear knowledge beyond that at all.
Speaker 1: And you like if your favorite four movies were the lady vanishes psycho vertigo and rear window, and you'd heard of Alfred Hitchcock, but you didn't know we made any other movies.
Speaker 0: It's like, why don't you know more?
Speaker 0: You should, if you're listening to this, whatever thing you are into at least read the Wikipedia about it.
Speaker 0: I mean, you need to know about the things that you're a fan of.
Speaker 0: that you're.
Speaker 0: you're nerdy and geeky enough to listen to a podcast called geek nights.
Speaker 1: I don't think the people who were talking to were listening to this.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Probably not.
Speaker 0: People who need to hear it are not the ones here, but you, but whether you need to hear this message or not, you know, someone else who needs to hear this message.
Speaker 1: Here's a kind of a side, take the words geek and nerd back in the sense that use them to mean something along the lines of deeper than average interest in a narrower field of things, rather than just being a descriptor for things that happen to be associated with socially awkward smart people in the seventies.
Speaker 0: Is there any more to say on this?
Speaker 0: I feel like we've iterated many points and emphasize them.
Speaker 1: a lot of points there.
Speaker 1: We've gone this the longest episode in a while.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: We needed something like this.
Speaker 1: We're done.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We're out.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.