Speaker 0: It's Thursday, May 30th, 2013.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Fart Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we're talking about farts.
Speaker 1: Terrific.
Speaker 0: Farting.
Speaker 0: Your mom.
Speaker 0: Why Jake is in Finn's pocket.
Speaker 0: Hey bro.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So a little while ago we were talking about how small talk's kind of dumb and boring and we realized that we had actually just engaged in small talk about the weather.
Speaker 1: We talked about the weather a lot.
Speaker 0: Our conversation was, hey, warm today.
Speaker 1: That's sort of what we do.
Speaker 0: I don't think you guys realize that in real life we say warm today pretty much every time we meet each other.
Speaker 1: If it was warm.
Speaker 0: If it's warm.
Speaker 0: Or ironically, I think I say it equally often when it's woman out.
Speaker 0: If it's woman, I might say woman, I might say warm today.
Speaker 0: If I say warm today or woman, I pretty much just mean that the temperature is above or below 70 degrees.
Speaker 1: Uh huh.
Speaker 0: But yeah.
Speaker 0: Today, I don't know if it was the heat or what it was, but I was around my work downtown by City Hall and I saw a man.
Speaker 0: The man was fat.
Speaker 0: Like, in New York there aren't that many people who aren't tourists in tourist places who are like fat fat.
Speaker 0: Like notably fat.
Speaker 1: It's like freakin' fat Albert fat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like this guy was fat Albert fat.
Speaker 0: He obviously had a custom suit on.
Speaker 0: I'm not ragging on fat people.
Speaker 0: That's not what I'm doing here.
Speaker 0: The guy was reeling behind him a briefcase on a stick.
Speaker 1: Not like a wheelie bag.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like a full bag.
Speaker 0: You know my messenger bag?
Speaker 1: It was like an attache case.
Speaker 0: It was a quarter the size of my messenger bag.
Speaker 0: In fact, I think attache case is what I would call it.
Speaker 0: There is no way.
Speaker 0: that thing weighed more than his hand.
Speaker 1: But maybe he couldn't get his hand in the handle because he was so fat.
Speaker 0: That is a possibility, but the fact that the fattest man I've seen in person in a long time was reeling behind him a briefcase so small that it was almost comical.
Speaker 0: He looked like the kind of thing you see in one of those comedy sketches where they put something ridiculous on the street and see how people react to it.
Speaker 0: Maybe it was.
Speaker 0: I actually stopped and was like, "Whoa, dude.
Speaker 0: Really?".
Speaker 1: Maybe that's what it was.
Speaker 0: In my brain I didn't say that to him.
Speaker 0: I wasn't like, "Whoa, dude.
Speaker 0: Can't pick that up?
Speaker 0: Can't just carry
Speaker 0: that?".
Speaker 0: It only weighs like maybe a quarter of a pound.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've eaten hamburgers.
Speaker 1: He might lose some weight if he carried it.
Speaker 0: I've eaten hamburgers that probably weigh more.
Speaker 0: The handle probably weighs more than your briefcase, dude.
Speaker 0: Also, you can't fit on the subway.
Speaker 0: I didn't take a picture because while it was hilarious, I would have felt a little bit awkward standing behind a guy like that, obviously taking a picture of him.
Speaker 0: But if I had Google Glass, video would have already been up and it would have been my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I'm on Amazon right now buying some water bottles and some bike water bottle cages because I lost another water bottle to the streets.
Speaker 0: So did you lose your water bottle cage too?
Speaker 1: No, but the cage clearly is not good.
Speaker 0: What water bottle cage do you have?
Speaker 1: The same metal-y one I've had forever.
Speaker 0: You've got to get a better one than that.
Speaker 1: I guess so.
Speaker 0: Did it come with your bike or did you buy it?
Speaker 1: I bought it.
Speaker 1: I bought the cheapest one a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I bought the cheapest one.
Speaker 1: I'm getting this new one that's the highest rated one on Amazon.
Speaker 1: In fact, I'm getting two of them.
Speaker 0: Why two?
Speaker 1: Because I can have two water bottles.
Speaker 0: Why do you need two?
Speaker 0: If you're doing that, just go Camelbak.
Speaker 1: I have a Camelbak also.
Speaker 0: You need two water bottles and a Camelbak?
Speaker 1: I can go real far.
Speaker 0: I guess you could.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: And if it's not a Camelbak trip, like a trip to work, I can have extra water.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: It was like a freaking bike down the road, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like bump and you're like, and it sort of sounded like I was like, Oh shit.
Speaker 1: And I stopped and I checked my tire out and it was just fine.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, Oh, what happened there?
Speaker 1: And it sort of sounded like maybe I ran over a soda bottle and dragged it or something like a flat one.
Speaker 0: Well, you did run over a bottle apparently.
Speaker 1: Well, apparently no, that was just the sound of my water bottle was scraping on the road and I actually went back for it.
Speaker 1: And of course, yeah, it was run over by a car and it could have been sort of salvaged except for the fact that like the mechanism and the nozzle was also smashed.
Speaker 0: And that mechanism is very important.
Speaker 0: It's why you buy the good water bottle instead of the cheap one.
Speaker 1: So meanwhile though, right?
Speaker 1: My cheapo do nothing water bottle, cheapo cage combination.
Speaker 1: I've never lost that one.
Speaker 1: But both times I've bought a fancy insulated water bottle.
Speaker 1: I've lost them.
Speaker 1: So we're going to fix the situation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have a policy.
Speaker 0: I bought another of the fancy, fancy umbrella.
Speaker 0: So to not use it, not lose it like, Oh, let me add an umbrella to this order.
Speaker 0: I got it in a ridiculous pinkish purple color.
Speaker 0: So I'm hoping that I will never leave it behind anywhere again.
Speaker 0: If I leave this one anywhere, then fuck it.
Speaker 0: I don't deserve to own a nice umbrella.
Speaker 0: I'm going to buy the $5 umbrella.
Speaker 0: That'll last five rainstorms.
Speaker 1: Let me buy a, uh, let's see average customer review.
Speaker 1: The best umbrella.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so while you're buying that, I was an Amazon.
Speaker 0: I bought up going to step up the production values.
Speaker 0: a little bit of our video.
Speaker 0: I bought a much better led light panel than anything we own to date.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: Thanks.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Apparently makes the shit tier of led panels.
Speaker 0: So I'm buying one of those instead of the sub shit tier.
Speaker 1: Like the place that has the pastries.
Speaker 0: No fancy like fancier.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: They just, they, it seems like they just take commodity led panels, slap some basic electronics on them and sell them at a markup.
Speaker 0: But the markup is less than the annoyance of building one myself from scratch.
Speaker 1: So in between the time I added the water bottle to my car and trying to add the umbrella to my cart, Amazon updated their add to cart button area with better graphics.
Speaker 0: Oh, all right.
Speaker 1: Interesting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I kind of cheated.
Speaker 0: I saw, I saw this led panel at anime Boston.
Speaker 0: Someone was using it to light up their display in the dealer's room.
Speaker 0: So I walk over to their table.
Speaker 0: I get all excited.
Speaker 0: Like, Ooh, this guy might buy something.
Speaker 0: And I go over and I'm like, yeah, this is the light I want to buy.
Speaker 0: And I just like ask him questions about the light and I check it out.
Speaker 0: Then I buy it on Amazon.
Speaker 0: I think they were selling like little sculptures of fairies that I didn't really care about.
Speaker 0: That's got to feel bad when you've like got a thing.
Speaker 0: Like I'm exhibiting X and someone comes over.
Speaker 0: It's like, man, what do you print those posters on?
Speaker 0: Like what company did you use?
Speaker 0: So I'm poking around on the internet and I notice because I'm doing some YouTube stuff, basically continuously filing all of the filings I need to file to get Yamato SRL to lose their claims to every goddamn episode of geek nights presents.
Speaker 0: I win every time, but they dispute me every time and I have to do the double dispute.
Speaker 1: I think they're just doing it automatically.
Speaker 0: No, they, yeah, they, they ping me automatically.
Speaker 0: I dispute with a copy paste because it's the same dispute every time.
Speaker 0: So a human being on their side rejects my dispute and maintains the claim.
Speaker 0: So then I have to go and say, look, fucking sue me or GTFO.
Speaker 0: And they have yet to actually sue me.
Speaker 0: So YouTube's like, yeah, whatevs, but I got to keep doing it.
Speaker 0: And I noticed that one of our videos got linked somewhere.
Speaker 0: I love how I can see these analytics.
Speaker 0: But Neo gaff linked again, or maybe the old thread about it came up again to our old ballot of dude, bro.
Speaker 0: And that's how I discovered that our ballot of dude, bro.
Speaker 0: video seems to be the primary citation for the know your mean page.
Speaker 1: As opposed to the original dude, both thread itself on dude, bro.
Speaker 0: It's basically in order our video, which I guess aggregates the, the story of that thread, the thread itself and Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Those are the three sources.
Speaker 0: So we are like the source on dude, bro.
Speaker 1: You want to see one of the most highly shit is fucked up.
Speaker 0: So I got to shoot slash slice you too.
Speaker 0: It's straight up dog time.
Speaker 1: This is one of the most highly rated umbrellas on Amazon.
Speaker 0: That's I can see why that's a highly rated umbrella.
Speaker 0: Do you want it?
Speaker 0: I kind of do, but I already have an umbrella.
Speaker 0: My umbrella is Twilight Sparkle colored as opposed to as opposed to actual literal Twilight Sparkle umbrella.
Speaker 0: I really want, you know what I want?
Speaker 0: I want like a rainbow dash cutie mark umbrella.
Speaker 0: That's in the shape of my fancy sense of umbrella.
Speaker 0: Cause fuck those uniform umbrellas.
Speaker 0: I want umbrellas that are oblique, that are asymmetrical because otherwise you're just an asshole with a golf umbrella or you got an umbrella is too small.
Speaker 0: So yeah, that's what I got.
Speaker 0: Neo Gaff rediscovered that we did the research, the minimal research to talk about dude, bro, a meme that seems to disappear and then is perennially remembered by the internet.
Speaker 1: That's your news?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's Thursday.
Speaker 1: I thought we were going to talk about.
Speaker 1: pecs is a hour change.
Speaker 0: I was going to talk about that too, but I wondered if you had anything.
Speaker 0: It's the lounge.
Speaker 1: It's your mom.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there isn't really too much news.
Speaker 1: The only news really going around is pecs of course is four days, but now we know the hours and windows 8.1 I guess, which is we can save that for Monday.
Speaker 0: We should save that for Monday.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: So cause I got a lot to say about it.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about the pecs hours.
Speaker 1: So as people may or may not know pecs prime 2013 is going to be four days.
Speaker 1: So it's actually going to be during labor day, which means you have to go home Tuesday morning, not Monday morning.
Speaker 0: Now I point out that in the past we would talk about how the difference between mag vest and pecs was that having that extra day being a full four days really changes the feel of a convention.
Speaker 0: Because you, cause.
Speaker 1: normally you have the Friday night where you stay out late, but you have an entry day and an exit day and then the real day in the middle.
Speaker 1: If you have two real full days in the middle there, which means you have three stay up late nights.
Speaker 0: That is the key, but they backed off on the hours.
Speaker 0: pecs closes at midnight now.
Speaker 1: What are we going to do?
Speaker 0: Our pecs modus operandi is walk out of pecs when they kick us the fuck out at 2 AM.
Speaker 1: Well pecs is still 14 hours longer than it used to be.
Speaker 1: So we'll either get more sleep or we'll have to find some way to game ourselves without pecs until 2 AM.
Speaker 0: Now what this might do, which won't be bad for prime.
Speaker 0: I don't do this at east because there's nowhere to do it.
Speaker 0: that makes sense, but at prime I will go to people's parties and I'll go hang out like in a hotel bar somewhere with someone at night.
Speaker 0: I feel like maybe more of that's going to happen, which you know what it might have.
Speaker 0: the side effect that I'm thinking about just now.
Speaker 0: You know how when we're in pecs in the tabletop area like hanging out, half of us are playing games and half of us are just kind of sitting there dicking around.
Speaker 0: I think everyone will play games because they know that at midnight when we get kicked out, we're all going to go somewhere and just stick around.
Speaker 0: So it'll raise the quality of the gaming by reducing the hours.
Speaker 1: I think it will, because it's four days, I think it will enable bigger games, right, than otherwise, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like, yeah, okay, we can't game until 2 AM, but we have this whole extra day here on Sunday.
Speaker 0: Let's play eclipse.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's play like eclipse, like, you know, be like magfest, like, hey, let's play eclipse.
Speaker 1: Let's play, you know, fucking big ass games.
Speaker 1: Let's play some tabletop RPG that takes five hours.
Speaker 0: So before, all right, it's 11 o'clock.
Speaker 0: We can't start playing eclipse because we'll get kicked out at two.
Speaker 0: But if we're kicked out at midnight, I don't feel bad about starting a game of eclipse at midnight somewhere else.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: But I can't start a game of eclipse at two.
Speaker 1: I think I'm going to dedicate this Pax Prime to more tabletop RPGing.
Speaker 0: I think what I'm going to do is pick two of the days.
Speaker 0: I'm going to dedicate one day to nothing but tabletop RPGs.
Speaker 0: I'm going to dedicate one day to nothing but hardcore board games.
Speaker 1: I figure, you know, I got Paxes.
Speaker 1: I'll, you know, I'll switch it up Pax by Pax as opposed to...
Speaker 0: I do want to run one off torch bearers at Pax Prime.
Speaker 1: We got to have some torch bearers by then.
Speaker 0: I'm confident I can trick them into giving us ours early if they can't get it to us by Pax.
Speaker 1: They'll probably be there.
Speaker 0: I know they will.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to get them to be on our Pax dev panel.
Speaker 1: Anyway, let's see.
Speaker 1: What else?
Speaker 1: I guess that's it.
Speaker 1: It'll be interesting to see the different Pax hours and how that affects the show and whatnot.
Speaker 1: I think it's mostly just for enforcers, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, enforcers have to work the pony shift that many times.
Speaker 1: It's like, it's not going to work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 0: I, someday I want to enforce Prime, but this will not be that time.
Speaker 1: No, it will not.
Speaker 0: Because I'm already, if we go to Pax dev and the four day Pax, we're going to fly out on fucking Tuesday and fly back on Tuesday.
Speaker 0: And that's if we have no days in Seattle, just ah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a whole lot of hotel and food monies.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, it's dev and Pax, so we're going to be in the expensive hotel the whole time.
Speaker 0: We can't like shift to the cheaper hotel at any point.
Speaker 1: Like we're going to do in Australia.
Speaker 0: Like we're going to do in Australia.
Speaker 0: We're only going to be in the Pax hotel for Pax.
Speaker 1: And the Pax hotel in Australia is like a hundred something a night.
Speaker 0: I know, whatevs.
Speaker 0: Whatevs.
Speaker 0: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: You got a thing of the day?
Speaker 1: I feel like I used this as a thing of the day before, but that happens a lot and often I'm wrong.
Speaker 1: So what the hell?
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: This is a video from 2011.
Speaker 1: Apparently there's a race, a bike race in Pittsburgh called the Dirty Dozen Race, which includes, it's a bike race.
Speaker 1: And it includes the 13 steepest hills in Pittsburgh.
Speaker 1: So it's the Dirty Dozen, right?
Speaker 1: So it's a baker's dozen, I guess, of hills.
Speaker 1: And it includes one hill, Canton Avenue, which is quote the steepest road on earth.
Speaker 1: It's really freaking steep.
Speaker 1: It's like almost 40 degrees incline, something ridiculous.
Speaker 1: And in this video, you see people trying to bike up that hill.
Speaker 1: Some people managed to make it.
Speaker 1: They just get their low gear and they stand up and they go and they get up the hill because it's really not that long a hill.
Speaker 1: It's just really steep.
Speaker 1: But other people fall down hilariously.
Speaker 1: And it is like, oh my God, look at that guy fall into the other guy.
Speaker 1: There's a big collapse.
Speaker 0: I can see falling down if you're going up and then the guy in front of you derps.
Speaker 1: That happens once in this video.
Speaker 0: I actually watched a pretty crazy derp accident that I think someone broke a bone on the Williamsburg bridge the other day.
Speaker 1: Was the bone sticking out of her body?
Speaker 0: Basically, I'm biking and there's a wobbly girl in front of me.
Speaker 1: She's got to turn that gear down.
Speaker 1: Did she even have gear?
Speaker 0: No, her gear was down.
Speaker 0: She's just wobbly girl.
Speaker 0: Wobbly girl is a thing that I see every day somewhere on my bike commute.
Speaker 0: They're just kind of meandering around the road like, wobble, wobble, wobble, wobble, going super slow.
Speaker 0: And she was just wobbling and this guy goes around her and gives her a wide berth to pass.
Speaker 0: And she just wobbles like strafe, like three feet to the left, right into him and shoulder checks him.
Speaker 0: And they both go flying and flipping and rolling in a mess.
Speaker 1: How fast are they going?
Speaker 1: Wobbly person's probably not going too fast.
Speaker 1: How fast is this dude going?
Speaker 0: Well, the dude was coming.
Speaker 0: Well, so it's a little more complicated.
Speaker 1: Was he going downhill?
Speaker 0: The guy was going super fast.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: And coming up behind her.
Speaker 1: Downhill or uphill?
Speaker 0: We were kind of like just over the crest of the hill.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: And the girl was going to wobbly, wobbly, wobbly, not fast.
Speaker 0: But the other guy was so fast that he was like, buh buh buh buh.
Speaker 0: But she was the one who got hurt.
Speaker 1: Okay, good.
Speaker 0: I guess good.
Speaker 1: Whoever's wobbly deserves it.
Speaker 1: When you're riding a bike, you should be going straight without veering, just like in a car.
Speaker 1: If a car is going like, you think the person driving it is drunk, maybe she was drunk.
Speaker 1: But yeah, do not wobble on the bike.
Speaker 1: You should keep everything straight in the line.
Speaker 0: If you're wobbling, you're probably in too high a gear.
Speaker 1: Probably, yeah.
Speaker 1: Or you don't have gears.
Speaker 0: Even the city bikes have gears.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Someone told me it's an automatic transmission.
Speaker 1: I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: I have not used one yet, so I can't say.
Speaker 1: There is some sort of weird mechanism, though, attached to the rear axle.
Speaker 0: Well, that is to power the LED blinky lights that are always on when you're biking.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 0: And there might be other functions.
Speaker 1: There might also be an odometer.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I have not investigated city bikes closely yet.
Speaker 1: But yeah, they're heavy as fuck, apparently.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're like, in Japan, the term is Mama Charlie for that just shit-tier bike that is perfectly fine to kind of get around the city, but is not pleasant to ride.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, my thing of the day is pretty straightforward.
Speaker 0: There's a movie that I realize a lot of you probably haven't seen called Maximum Overdrive.
Speaker 1: Now, Maximum Overdrive is a title that sounds like something that is famous, that you know.
Speaker 1: But I really -- you tell me the name, Maximum Overdrive, and I'm like, "That sounds like the name of something pretty
Speaker 1: significant.".
Speaker 1: I cannot tell you what the fuck it is.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: So, Maximum Overdrive is an '80s movie based on a Stephen King novel directed by Stephen King.
Speaker 1: He knows about film?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a bunch of Stephen King stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know, but usually other people make the movies, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, he directed it, he wrote the screenplay, he based it on one of his books.
Speaker 0: I never actually read the book.
Speaker 0: The plot of Maximum Overdrive is that one day, technology tries to kill all humans.
Speaker 0: But it was made in the '80s, so it's not -- like, in the modern day, it'd be like, "My smartphone empties my bank account and tries to shock
Speaker 0: me.".
Speaker 1: So, it's not the Terminator?
Speaker 0: No, so it's basically low-level mechanical stuff, so trucks and steam rollers.
Speaker 1: But then how could even, like, a truck frickin' come to life?
Speaker 1: It makes no sense.
Speaker 0: I guess spirits take 'em over or something, I don't know.
Speaker 0: But this movie -- It's not gonna work, dude.
Speaker 0: We recently did a panel in Anime Boston, a lecture, where we talked about how people recommend stuff and they're usually bad at it, and one of the points we made is that there is an art to recommending the bad movie.
Speaker 0: 'Cause if a movie's bad, but it sucks to watch, it is not fun to say, "Hey, let's all get drunk and watch the bad
Speaker 0: movie.".
Speaker 0: No, no one has a good time.
Speaker 0: Maximum Overdrive is one of the movies that's bad in the way that you can enjoy how bad it is while watching it.
Speaker 0: It also stars Emilio Estevez.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Your favorite guy?
Speaker 0: Do you know who Emilio Estevez is?
Speaker 1: The coach in The Mighty Ducks?
Speaker 0: That is correct.
Speaker 0: Can you name any other thing he's ever done?
Speaker 1: The coach in Mighty Ducks 2?
Speaker 0: I don't know if he actually did that or not.
Speaker 0: Yes, he did.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: Gordon Bombay.
Speaker 0: He played it in 2.
Speaker 0: I pulled up his filmography.
Speaker 1: The cheap answer.
Speaker 0: So, this movie has a moment where a steamroller comes out of nowhere and kills some kid.
Speaker 0: And the whole movie is like this.
Speaker 0: So, this is my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: It's really this entire movie.
Speaker 0: The scene is just typical of it.
Speaker 0: There's a scene where they're all like holed up in this truck stop or something.
Speaker 0: And the trucks start honking their horns.
Speaker 0: And someone in the cast knows Morse code.
Speaker 0: And he's like, "Oh my god!
Speaker 0: It's Morse
Speaker 0: code!".
Speaker 0: They're saying, "Someone has to pump the gas.
Speaker 0: Do not kill all of
Speaker 0: them.".
Speaker 0: And the movie is just great in that really shit-tier way.
Speaker 0: Shit-tier has been my term lately.
Speaker 0: For stuff.
Speaker 0: Meta Moment book club book is Player of Games, Ian M. Banks.
Speaker 0: I'm going to read it really soon.
Speaker 0: We'll do a show on it.
Speaker 0: Scott already read it.
Speaker 1: Are you really?
Speaker 1: I finished like weeks ago already.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: I've been busy with shit.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Me too, but I read it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I've been more busy with more shit.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I've been editing video.
Speaker 1: Me too.
Speaker 0: I've been editing video of a higher caliber than you've been editing.
Speaker 0: What video?
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: You did edit video.
Speaker 1: Biking videos, Netrunner videos, and a panel for Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: Are your biking videos anything other than you biking to work?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: I mean, what else am I supposed to do?
Speaker 0: We were at Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: We will post video as I have time.
Speaker 0: Our next convention is Connecticon, where we run the panels and workshops department.
Speaker 0: We're doing a bunch of our own stuff.
Speaker 1: And the week after that is?
Speaker 0: PAX Australia.
Speaker 0: Fuck me.
Speaker 0: Where we're doing?
Speaker 0: Beyond Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: But a new updated version of it.
Speaker 0: We're adding Torchbearer.
Speaker 0: And I'm going to let you all in on a secret.
Speaker 0: We're adding Dungeons and Dragons to it.
Speaker 1: Oh no.
Speaker 0: Because most people who think of D&D only know like fourth ed.
Speaker 0: Maybe three point fifth ed.
Speaker 1: Fifth ed.
Speaker 0: Because that's not out yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is sort of.
Speaker 1: They were playing it.
Speaker 1: What do you think I was managing lines for as an enforcer at fricking PAX East?
Speaker 1: People were waiting in fuck line to play like these fifth ed demos.
Speaker 1: Or I guess D&D next or whatever it's called.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a work in progress still as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people were playing it.
Speaker 1: They were lining the fuck up and the line filled like instantly.
Speaker 0: All I have to say about it is that it has mutually exclusive goals according to the things they've said about it.
Speaker 0: So I have zero faith in fifth edition.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like if I said, all right guys, we're going to set this new software project.
Speaker 1: Our goals is to make it cheap, fast and awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like we want a data processing engine that has very low latency and very high throughput.
Speaker 0: You really only get to pick one of those unless you have money for hardware.
Speaker 1: I want to have a lot of money and I want the money to be really valuable money.
Speaker 1: I don't want it to be invaluable inflated money.
Speaker 1: I want a lot of it.
Speaker 0: I want to drink a whole bunch of beer.
Speaker 1: I want so much of it.
Speaker 0: I like drinking beer, but I don't want to have to pee.
Speaker 1: I want to print this money.
Speaker 1: That's how much I want.
Speaker 1: I want so much that I print it, but I don't want the value to decrease as I print it.
Speaker 0: I want to mine silver from the Americas in vast quantities and use it as my currency, yet not devalue my own currency.
Speaker 0: In Spain, I'm looking at you.
Speaker 0: So we're talking about farts, but first the meta moment.
Speaker 1: We already did the meta moment.
Speaker 0: Is there anything else to say in the meta moment?
Speaker 0: Join our forum, like our videos.
Speaker 1: Yeah, do all our internet stuff.
Speaker 1: Come see us on the internets and all the places.
Speaker 1: If there is a place on the internet that you frequent, we are there.
Speaker 0: If you like our videos, actually like them and post them in your forums, because the more people watch our videos, the faster we will produce Geek Nights Presents.
Speaker 0: And beyond all that, if you want Geek Nights t-shirts to come back, indicate that to me in some way.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to figure out if it's worth my effort to set up a new store now that Google has completely discontinued checkout.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we can set up a new store.
Speaker 1: We can reprint the old t-shirt if people still want it and then maybe make a new one.
Speaker 0: I got some good ideas for new shirt designs too.
Speaker 1: She's getting artists to do that.
Speaker 0: And I might see if Dave and Joel want to go in with us on something as well.
Speaker 1: A crossover shirt?
Speaker 1: I mean, their shirt sells way better than ours.
Speaker 1: Every Geek Nights listener I ever meet at a convention is wearing the Dave and Joel shirt.
Speaker 0: So I have a message for one Dave Riley and Joel White who never go to conventions.
Speaker 0: Ahem.
Speaker 0: Your fans, who often are also fans of us, but not always, seek us out at conventions to tell us how awesome you are because you are never there.
Speaker 0: If you come to the conventions, your fans will love you and say hi to you in person.
Speaker 0: If you want us to continue being your proxies for fan love, we might start making things up about you.
Speaker 1: Every time someone comes up to me at a convention, right?
Speaker 1: To talk to me.
Speaker 1: Even if they're a fan of us.
Speaker 1: I have never once seen anyone wearing a Geek Nights shirt.
Speaker 1: They are always wearing the Dave and Joel shirt.
Speaker 0: I have.
Speaker 0: Pax East.
Speaker 0: There's a guy wearing a Geek Nights shirt.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Which is, the reason it's rare is because we only sold a small number of them before I stopped bothering to run the store.
Speaker 0: I still have a box of them.
Speaker 0: we could just sell.
Speaker 0: I just don't.
Speaker 0: But yeah, pretty much the Geek Nights official shirt is the Fast Karate Hanabi shirt at this point.
Speaker 0: So yeah, Dave and Joel, come to a con.
Speaker 0: Oh wait, they are.
Speaker 0: Dave's going to be a Kineticon.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's on.
Speaker 0: It's a fart.
Speaker 1: I make them a lot.
Speaker 0: I will say this.
Speaker 0: The role of a fart in human evolution in this day and age is very simple.
Speaker 1: It is- To keep your guts from exploding?
Speaker 0: Without exception, the best possible way to punctuate any point you ever make in an argument.
Speaker 0: If you say something like, "And that is why the Assyrians
Speaker 0: fell!"
Speaker 0: And then you pause and then you immediately fart.
Speaker 0: There is literally no better way to win an argument.
Speaker 1: Drop can fart?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I fart kind of loudly and often.
Speaker 0: And I actually do.
Speaker 0: Emily will be mad now that she knows that this is true and that it's not just a joke.
Speaker 0: And that she's always suspected that I do this.
Speaker 0: If I have a fart built up, I actually will try to hold it in until there's a funny moment where I can fart.
Speaker 0: Especially during a silence.
Speaker 0: Like if I'm up on stage, if I'm like, "Can anyone name an anime that's worse than Desert
Speaker 0: Punk?"
Speaker 0: And then I just fart like right after that.
Speaker 0: That is comedy gold right there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I usually just let the farts out as soon as the pressure's building.
Speaker 1: It's like, "Why should I hurt myself by inflating my stomach with painful
Speaker 1: gases?".
Speaker 0: See, that I agree with 100%.
Speaker 0: I dislike people who say... Anyone who thinks you should go to the bathroom if you have to fart or walk away and fart.
Speaker 0: It's like, no, you only walk away and fart if you're walking out of an elevator.
Speaker 0: In which case you want to fart before you walk away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't fart in an elevator.
Speaker 1: That's crossing a line there.
Speaker 0: What do you do though?
Speaker 0: So wait, so Scott, if you have to fart and you're in an elevator, you actually wait?
Speaker 0: You hold it in?
Speaker 1: As soon as the doors open, I step out and fart.
Speaker 0: You don't fart, then step out?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: 'Cause there's a line, right?
Speaker 0: So what's the line?
Speaker 0: Is the line human decency?
Speaker 1: It's somewhat related to that.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you fart, right, it's gonna do some damage, right?
Speaker 1: In terms of people are gonna smell that shit and get your poop in their nose.
Speaker 0: So I do have a theory I'm gonna get back to, so remind me about the damage.
Speaker 1: But, you know, it's actually, most of my farts are non-smelly.
Speaker 1: They just make noise and I don't really smell them.
Speaker 1: And other people don't really smell them either most of the time.
Speaker 0: What I notice about you is your farts contain a sort of hidden power.
Speaker 0: They're very sudden and forceful.
Speaker 0: Like if I fart, sometimes it's like that *fart noise* you know, the kind of long fart.
Speaker 0: You'll just be like BAM!
Speaker 0: It's like a soap wafer that just has one beat played.
Speaker 1: Got some powerful ass.
Speaker 0: Mine are often more the like *fart noise*.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's called diarrhea.
Speaker 1: Go to the bathroom.
Speaker 1: Nah.
Speaker 0: What I can't pull off, maybe only fat people can do this, but there's that particular comedic fart.
Speaker 0: Where you have the normal fart and then the pause and then there's that kind of like high pitched squeal at the end.
Speaker 0: That like, I can't really do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's like that Austin Powers fat bastard nonsense.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: I wish I could make that fart happen.
Speaker 1: I could do it with my mouth and my hands or my armpit or whatever.
Speaker 0: The only good fart I can do, the secret, kids who try to make the fart noise always try to go like *fart noise* or something.
Speaker 0: Nah, you gotta get the lip up there.
Speaker 1: We used to always do the one where you put the heels of your palms like sort of against each other.
Speaker 0: Up against your face?
Speaker 1: Up against your face and then you *fart noise*.
Speaker 1: Nah, that's not how it is.
Speaker 0: I can't really do it anymore.
Speaker 1: *fart noise*.
Speaker 1: I can't do it anymore either.
Speaker 0: As a little kid I was obsessed.
Speaker 1: It's all about making your cheeks flap against your hands.
Speaker 0: With that vaudeville style armpit one, but it actually doesn't make that good of a fart noise.
Speaker 0: And then your hand smells like armpit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it can be used to great effect though in certain situations.
Speaker 1: Usually musical uses.
Speaker 0: Well you only do the armpit fart if you need fine control over the fart or you're doing a visual gag where you need it to be clear that you're making a fake fart noise.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying, if you're playing music, right?
Speaker 1: The armpit fart is good because you don't need to get the breaths in there, right?
Speaker 1: So you can just get something going on like a funky beat going with the armpit, right?
Speaker 1: Without any breaks in it or something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So for a musical instrument purposes, the armpit or the two hand squeeze that you usually use to squeeze water at people, but can also make fart noises if it's dry.
Speaker 1: You know, some people use that method.
Speaker 1: That's good for like *fart noise*.
Speaker 0: So I have a theory in terms of farts.
Speaker 0: I believe that the damage of a fart is inversely proportional to the loudness of the fart.
Speaker 0: I've never really experienced the loud fart that was also damaging.
Speaker 1: No, I think it simply has to do with how clean someone's ass is, right?
Speaker 0: No, that's not where the smell comes from.
Speaker 0: Unless you were putting toilet paper inside your ass and wiping around in there or like animating deep inside, that has no bearing on the smell of a fart.
Speaker 0: That has bearing on the smell of you smell like someone who doesn't wipe his ass.
Speaker 0: That smell doesn't go away.
Speaker 1: It also has to do with what you eat, right?
Speaker 1: If the poop that's inside your guts is more liquidy right now and the gas comes from, you know, past that and pushes, right?
Speaker 1: Versus maybe you got some really hard poops coming through, right?
Speaker 1: They're really dry.
Speaker 1: You didn't drink enough water.
Speaker 0: But then the gas serves an important purpose.
Speaker 0: If you got the hard poop like up against the end, you could have the single shot clean delivery.
Speaker 0: But we're not talking about poop, so.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: What I'm saying is that that's the relation between poop and farts, right?
Speaker 0: But why the sound?
Speaker 0: How come whenever I fart and it's silent, it's the worst?
Speaker 0: But if I fart and it's loud, it doesn't smell like anything.
Speaker 0: That seems to be a common trend.
Speaker 0: Silent but deadly.
Speaker 0: In middle school, we knew this to be truth, but why?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I can test that it's true to begin with.
Speaker 0: Why are silent farts so smelly, so deadly, more deadly?
Speaker 0: Okay, Google.
Speaker 1: See, I can test that this is actually true.
Speaker 1: But let's assume that it's true.
Speaker 1: Let us surmise why it could be, right?
Speaker 1: I think it might have to be a relation between the position.
Speaker 0: Someone has a really good theory.
Speaker 1: Positions of the gas and the poop in the intestinal tract.
Speaker 0: Google.
Speaker 0: Yahoo answers.
Speaker 0: Question.
Speaker 0: Why do tiny silent farts smell worse than big, loud farts?
Speaker 0: This was asked six years ago by Roller Coaster of Love.
Speaker 0: The accepted answer was a long one.
Speaker 0: that actually kind of makes sense when you're really flatulent with huge ripping farts.
Speaker 0: The main gas is mostly carbon dioxide, since the big ones are some sugar fermenting in your intestines, et cetera.
Speaker 0: Carbon dioxide is odorless, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 0: If you have a small fart, it's methane and sulfides from different kinds of fermentation.
Speaker 1: The sulfides are definitely where the odors come from, that's for sure.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Methane doesn't smell like anything.
Speaker 0: But I'm going to admit something.
Speaker 1: Wait, but does that mean... We see a lot of people on YouTube making asses of themselves trying to set their farts on fire and actually setting their assholes on fire.
Speaker 1: If they used a big carbon dioxide fart, they would actually put the fart fire out and not start it.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So I think you need a large quantity of the smelly fart to make that happen.
Speaker 0: Also, guys, never try to light your fart.
Speaker 0: You're going to set something on fire, probably your junk.
Speaker 1: Do light a cow's fart on fire, because I want to see that shit on YouTube.
Speaker 0: I kind of don't.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: Why not just make a flamethrower with hairspray?
Speaker 1: Also awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we did that at band camp.
Speaker 1: But I've seen that before.
Speaker 0: And then my hairspray got taken away.
Speaker 1: But how funny would it be to stand next to a cow with like a lighter and then boom, you light your hick friend on fire.
Speaker 0: Or you light yourself on fire because you're the one right next to it.
Speaker 1: Or use that to light bottle rockets, which then fire off.
Speaker 1: That is like the combo there.
Speaker 0: Are the bottle rockets themselves positioned in someone's butt?
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: You remember that video.
Speaker 1: So there's a guy who's got a bottle rocket coming out of his butt and he's butt to butt with the cows.
Speaker 1: He's butt rape.
Speaker 1: Fucking the cow butts together.
Speaker 0: Butts together is not necessarily rape.
Speaker 0: The butts are fucking.
Speaker 0: It's just butts.
Speaker 1: His butt and the cow's butt are pretty close.
Speaker 1: You pull the match near the cow's butt.
Speaker 1: It farts.
Speaker 1: It sets the bottle rocket on fire.
Speaker 1: The bottle rocket shoots into the air and explodes.
Speaker 0: It's like the best or the worst Rube Goldberg machine ever.
Speaker 0: So you remember that video.
Speaker 0: This is from the old Blumpy.org.
Speaker 0: Like the videos you keep around before YouTube of the guy who tries to launch a bottle rocket out of his butt.
Speaker 0: Which apparently seems to be a common tradition among.
Speaker 1: Bad fucking idea again.
Speaker 0: You realize guys, when you do that, you're going to clench up as soon as they light it.
Speaker 0: Because you're going to, because you're getting sparks.
Speaker 1: And that splintery wooden stick that consists of the shaft of the bottle rocket will leave its splinters all along your record.
Speaker 0: More importantly, you clench up because the sparks are hitting your butt and it hurts a little bit.
Speaker 0: As a result, the bottle rocket does not leave.
Speaker 0: It just flame throwers your butt for three seconds and then explodes.
Speaker 1: Splinters your rectum from the rod of the bottle rocket.
Speaker 0: Having seen many videos, no one ever successfully does this.
Speaker 1: I don't want any wooden splinters in my rectum.
Speaker 0: I'm more worried about the stream of fire followed by the explosion.
Speaker 1: Alright, you have two choices.
Speaker 1: Choice number one.
Speaker 1: I will take a fire and blow it on your butt for a little bit.
Speaker 1: Choice number two.
Speaker 0: It's not a fire, it's a rocket propellant directed directly at your taint.
Speaker 0: Or your genitals.
Speaker 1: Choice number one, I blast some sparks at your taint for like a few seconds.
Speaker 1: Choice number two, I take a splintery piece of wood, shove it in your ass and pull it out.
Speaker 0: It's so thin, it's not that bad I don't think.
Speaker 1: Splintery piece of wood.
Speaker 0: Because it's so thin you wouldn't even notice.
Speaker 1: Urethra.
Speaker 0: Thanks for that.
Speaker 0: But I'm going to admit something.
Speaker 0: I actually enjoy the moments where I have to fart and I can't hold it in.
Speaker 0: There's no way I could hold it in.
Speaker 1: And you let it out and go ahh.
Speaker 0: But I'm on the subway.
Speaker 0: And it's an express train.
Speaker 0: And once I fart, because it's always silent, no one ever suspects that I'm the one who farted.
Speaker 0: I'm always like the businessman, I'm skinny, I'm wearing like a fashionable jeans and a blazer or something.
Speaker 0: I always see this, I fart, everyone in the subway cars are like going.
Speaker 0: And they have to look and they look around to guess who.
Speaker 0: And I will always see everyone else in the subway car basically stare at the fattest person on the car.
Speaker 1: I never see anyone on the subway even care if anyone farts, this is interesting.
Speaker 0: Well it's only if, so it doesn't happen that often.
Speaker 0: It's if I fart on the subway and it's a dangerous one.
Speaker 1: Everyone just moves to the next car.
Speaker 0: No one moves for a fart, you move for the hobo.
Speaker 0: Because the hobo doesn't disperse.
Speaker 1: He's a walking fart.
Speaker 0: If you fart, the fart goes away.
Speaker 0: But if you're hobo, the hobo does not disperse.
Speaker 0: It doesn't diffuse into the car and go away until the cops come.
Speaker 0: But I enjoy that moment and it's a bad thing to enjoy.
Speaker 0: where everyone smells the fart, they're angry about the fart, and they all assume the fat guy did it.
Speaker 0: And no one ever suspects that it was me who farted.
Speaker 1: You know what bothers me a lot?
Speaker 1: It's these people who act like.
Speaker 1: they never fart.
Speaker 1: Like my mom.
Speaker 1: My mom will be like, she'll deny that she farts.
Speaker 1: But one time we were in the kitchen in grandma's house in Florida and it was just me and my mom.
Speaker 1: And there was a fart noise and it wasn't me.
Speaker 1: There was only one other person in that room.
Speaker 0: There's a Bill Cosby bit.
Speaker 0: that's basically exactly that.
Speaker 0: The mom's like, "I never
Speaker 0: fart."
Speaker 0: And she tries to fart while she's laughing.
Speaker 0: And they call her on it.
Speaker 0: And she hits them all because that's how Bill Cosby humor works.
Speaker 1: But yeah, stop denying farting.
Speaker 1: Embrace that farting.
Speaker 0: Well, farting's important.
Speaker 0: If you don't fart, that sucks.
Speaker 0: Just fart.
Speaker 0: Just go for it.
Speaker 1: I had a wise bus driver in my public school days.
Speaker 1: You know what the wise bus driver said?
Speaker 0: Everybody farts.
Speaker 1: Everybody shits the same.
Speaker 1: It all smells the same.
Speaker 0: People with Crohn's disease don't shit the same.
Speaker 1: Everybody shits and it all smells like shit.
Speaker 1: That's the point.
Speaker 1: Crohn's people still shit, do they not?
Speaker 0: So Scott, I'm going to ask you a question.
Speaker 0: I'm going to ask you a personal question that I will also answer truthfully.
Speaker 0: If you ever farted and it actually kind of smelled good.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Never?
Speaker 0: You've never experienced that.
Speaker 1: It either smells like nothing or it smells like poop, which doesn't smell good.
Speaker 1: I mean, there are things that smell, I will sell you, there are things, there are things that smell worse than poop.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So I typed, "Why do my,".
Speaker 0: and I was about to type, "farts smell
Speaker 0: good."
Speaker 0: And Google recommended, "Feet smell, nipples hurt, nipples
Speaker 0: itch.".
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: But the point is I'm making here is that there are things like, I would rather smell a fart than like a secondhand smoke.
Speaker 0: Why do my farts smell so bad, smell so good?
Speaker 0: Burn.
Speaker 1: Well, burning is bad.
Speaker 1: That's the doctor's situation right there.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: It seems like it's equal quantities.
Speaker 0: My farts smell bad, my farts smell good.
Speaker 1: Did you eat flowers?
Speaker 1: That would help your farts smell good.
Speaker 1: Did you shove flowers in your ass?
Speaker 1: That would probably work as well.
Speaker 1: Did you...
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Is there soap remnants in your butt crack?
Speaker 1: that would probably make it smell like soap?
Speaker 0: So I have learned the answer, and the answer is, Yahoo Answers is a treasure trove of some of the saddest people in the world.
Speaker 1: How is baby formed?
Speaker 1: How is fart smell good?
Speaker 1: Way insane, mother.
Speaker 1: Way insane.
Speaker 1: rectum, fart blasting, I don't know.
Speaker 1: What is the answer?
Speaker 0: It was long and I stopped reading it.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: I'm back to why do tiny silent farts smell worse than big loud farts?
Speaker 1: Did you ever get an answer on that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was the carbon monoxide, or carbon dioxide thing seems to be the common answer.
Speaker 1: Do you ever, do you think, right, people always say beans, the musical fruit, the more you eat, the more you do?
Speaker 0: I have never farted more or less after eating any particular food in my entire life.
Speaker 1: I have not tracked it, right, mathematically speaking.
Speaker 0: People say the food I ate led to farting unless it was McDonald's breakfast.
Speaker 1: But I think what really contributes to my personal farting, right, is a problem I have of eating too fast and not chewing enough, right, because when you eat fast and don't chew enough.
Speaker 0: You do basically just shovel food in your mouth and swallow it immediately.
Speaker 0: I've watched you eat.
Speaker 1: You have big chunks of food with air in between.
Speaker 1: You end up swallowing air.
Speaker 0: So I think that- No, you don't end up swallowing air if you're a normal human being.
Speaker 0: You end up swallowing air.
Speaker 0: The direct, literal you, not the royal you.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: So I'm saying- You eating is like, oh, no, you're just like swallowing gallons of air next to your food.
Speaker 1: The air just goes in your esophagus and the big chunks of food sort of trap it in there.
Speaker 0: But usually that doesn't cause farting.
Speaker 0: It causes gas.
Speaker 1: Your esophagus pushes it down.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It causes burping if the air actually makes it back up the esophagus past the food.
Speaker 0: How fast are you eating to force that air into your intestine before you burp it out?
Speaker 0: Jesus Christ.
Speaker 1: And that is a contributor to non-smelly farts because it's just air coming out and not say nasty sulfates or methane or who knows what.
Speaker 1: And it's bad for my stomach.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Does swallowing air make you fart?
Speaker 0: There's an Ask Men article about this.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: If you swallow a burp, does it turn into a fart?
Speaker 0: There's Yahoo answers coming to the table.
Speaker 1: There's not one answer from a gastroenterologist.
Speaker 0: Resolved question.
Speaker 0: The answer is a joke about farting with bad grammar.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: This guy just said no, but his name is Jalapeno Baby Canada.
Speaker 1: Okay, fine.
Speaker 1: How about these fart jokes?
Speaker 1: Why are fart jokes funny for children and still funny for adults?
Speaker 0: Because everyone does fart.
Speaker 0: So no matter how stoic and noble and Mitt Romney and just perfect history you are, if you're standing there and someone farts, you think back to all the times you farted.
Speaker 1: Why is that funny?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: The same reason poop is funny.
Speaker 0: There's a certain ... Monkeys seem to find these things enjoyable too.
Speaker 1: Why have we evolved?
Speaker 1: Why have the monkeys that thought poop was funny and were not afraid to fling poo better at surviving and evolving than the monkeys who are perhaps afraid of poo or did not like poo?
Speaker 0: Farting.
Speaker 1: How did the humor of poo add to survival?
Speaker 0: Swallowing air in the usual ...
Speaker 1: Get a Yahoo answer for that.
Speaker 0: So supposedly swallowing air can cause flatulence to ... All right.
Speaker 0: These answers are way too complicated.
Speaker 1: At least that means maybe they're true or not.
Speaker 0: Or not.
Speaker 1: Do you have anything else to say about farting?
Speaker 0: One last thing.
Speaker 0: Because I have an Aeron chair, farting in my chair is no longer an issue because the farts just go through it instead of lingering forever.
Speaker 1: I don't think farts really ... In the fabric.
Speaker 1: Farks don't linger in my chair.
Speaker 0: If you fart in a chair that is fabric, the smell lingers in the chair for a while, not You smell my ...
Speaker 1: My chair doesn't smell like poop.
Speaker 0: How often do you fart into it?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I fart whenever I fart.
Speaker 0: Plus when you fart into a chair, don't you usually raise the cheek a little bit to get a sort of freer delivery?
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: When you fart in bed, do you lift the sheet and kind of go flaf flaf, parachute to get it out of there?
Speaker 1: You know what I do do?
Speaker 1: Do you?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: The worst is if you're in the shower because the curtain and the humidity will keep the fart.
Speaker 1: So what I do is I have to fart in the shower, which actually happens rather often.
Speaker 0: I will stick my butt out of the shower and fart into the room.
Speaker 1: I will crack the edge of the curtain and stick my butt out and fart into the main bathroom.
Speaker 0: I do the same thing.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Same thing.
Speaker 0: I do like the resonance of the fart in the room.
Speaker 1: I've noticed there's a lot of things like that where it's like you do them and it's like you think it's a weird thing, but really everyone does it.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 0: that's why the humor is funny.
Speaker 0: Like, you know what?
Speaker 1: Like one time I asked a group of people, I was like, yeah, am I the only one who shampoos my you know, pubes.
Speaker 1: and they're like, no fucking everyone shampoos their pubes.
Speaker 0: I shampoo them.
Speaker 0: I condition them and I comb them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like fucking everyone does that.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, I'm not alone.
Speaker 0: Scott.
Speaker 0: Everyone has to wash the inside of their ass when they're showering.
Speaker 1: there was so I thought other people just soaked it and I was the only one shampoo in it.
Speaker 0: I used to condition and shampoo.
Speaker 0: My mustache.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: It's a little weird, but you never had a mustache.
Speaker 1: I have one right now.
Speaker 0: That is barely a mustache.
Speaker 0: I've get one like I had at RIT and you're going to, yeah, cause you didn't condition it.
Speaker 1: It's also hot out right now.
Speaker 1: So I'm going to probably reduce a lot.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking about, you know, maybe I'll do another reset just cause my face, I actually tried a new facial hair that I posted a picture of the look pretty okay on me, but it made me look silly and possibly communist.
Speaker 1: The problem is I feel like there've been enough men in the history of the world.
Speaker 1: They've already tried every possible facial hair.
Speaker 0: That's why you have names.
Speaker 0: Pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Pretty much anything I can possibly try is either going to be, you know, normal hipster evil doofy or like, you know, what make me look like some, you know, every time
Speaker 0: you get a beard going on, cause I get beards going on kind of off and just cause I don't, I don't shave for whatever reason.
Speaker 0: Once it's long enough and I got to get rid of it, I will shave it down into like five different possible facial hairstyles.
Speaker 0: as I shave down and I'm slowly building a lexicon of facial hair configurations that if I wanted to have them would look okay on me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's not too many there.
Speaker 0: I got, I tried one that looked pretty good cause it, it highlights my eyebrows if I want to do good, funny faces like in YouTube videos or while I'm describing anecdotes, we've moved from farts to beards.
Speaker 1: So I think it's time.
Speaker 1: I think it's time to go biking.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, geek nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative comments attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: Down in the country where I was born.