Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, May 8th, 2013.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: What time is it?
Speaker 1: I guess Scott doesn't want to play along.
Speaker 1: It's adventure time.
Speaker 0: It could be many other times.
Speaker 0: Text time.
Speaker 1: Right now, adventure time.
Speaker 0: Game time.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So Scott really hasn't watched it or isn't really a fan of it, but I'm really big into adventure brothers and season 5 is coming up way soon.
Speaker 0: I don't understand seasons anymore.
Speaker 0: It's like all the TV seasons.
Speaker 1: Because that's how production schedules work.
Speaker 0: There used to be that TV seasons started a certain time and ended and all the seasons started and ended at the same time of every show.
Speaker 0: And then there would be a time where there was just 100% reruns for months and then all new TV shows.
Speaker 1: So Scott, one, the reason you perceive that is that there was a time in your life when you paid attention to that and watched TV.
Speaker 1: And nowadays, you don't pay attention anymore.
Speaker 0: TV shows start all different times.
Speaker 1: Part of that too is that TV has changed.
Speaker 1: Cable has changed.
Speaker 1: I mean, when we were kids, there really wasn't cable.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: But cable came out.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying it's good or bad.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying there's been a change here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's been a lot of changes.
Speaker 1: These changes have been going on for a long time and I think part of it is just that you don't watch normal TV anymore because normal TV follows the more standard schedules.
Speaker 1: People still talk about summer reruns if they watch network bullshit sitcoms.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter though.
Speaker 1: It's all internet now.
Speaker 1: But yeah, Venture Brothers season five took for fucking... I can't believe how old Venture Brothers is until I looked at when season one came out.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, I remember, I think the first Kineticon we went to...
Speaker 1: You sure it wasn't Anime Boston?
Speaker 0: We went into this little tiny room where we got our folders with our itineraries and they had a tiny TV in that conference room and Venture Brothers is on that TV.
Speaker 1: I remember that happening at an Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: It was not Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: There was a PAX where we were going to perform in a room and it was at night and they were just showing clips from Venture Brothers in the room to the audience before we showed up, just like hanging out.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: So the thing is, it's funny because it's a show that I remember.
Speaker 1: I watched a few episodes because I was in India just waiting for a flight and I had it on my laptop.
Speaker 1: So I watched like the first four episodes and much like ponies, I was like, you know what?
Speaker 1: It's an okay show.
Speaker 1: Not great, but it's okay.
Speaker 1: But I get a long flight.
Speaker 1: so I watched the entire first season and the show just got better and better and better and better.
Speaker 1: I got Emily to start watching the show by skipping a lot of that first season stuff and just starting with the really good stuff and then backpedaling and seeing the original episodes once she kind of had seen stuff.
Speaker 1: So she's pretty much caught up now and I'll be able to watch the new season going forward with someone instead of by myself.
Speaker 1: Goddamn, I love that show.
Speaker 1: You'll get into it.
Speaker 1: I mean, you've resisted Adventure Time for the longest time.
Speaker 0: I didn't resist it.
Speaker 0: You seem to think I resist things because I delay.
Speaker 0: There was a delay in resisting, right?
Speaker 0: So adventure adventure time.
Speaker 0: I was delaying venture brothers resisting because I've seen it and it's not the kind of, it's, it's like one of those shows like Archer or C lab where I don't think it's funny.
Speaker 1: I still don't understand how you don't find Archer funny considering the other things you find funny.
Speaker 0: It's just sort of ridiculous and not humorous.
Speaker 1: So adventure time is clearly a no way ridiculous adventure time.
Speaker 0: Well, why don't we wait to the second half of the show for me to discuss that?
Speaker 1: So there was a Twitter discussion.
Speaker 1: Mike tool was involved and I threw my sense in and it came down to the fact that apparently episode 11 kids on the slope with its Bure release was either missing the left audio channel on the Japanese track or there was some other problem with it.
Speaker 0: And I'm sure it was actually missing the left.
Speaker 0: or was it the balance all to the right?
Speaker 0: It's either not there or on some there's like 100% of the track is mixed to the right side of mono.
Speaker 1: So it was missing.
Speaker 1: or it was so low volume, but it wasn't in the right track, which is gone.
Speaker 1: But there's more to it than that because when I was trying to find a succinct explanation of the problem just now to be able to talk about it, I discovered that anime DVD, well, anime DVD, anime boo rays have a history of fucked up audio and video issues and sampling issues and all these people complaining.
Speaker 1: But the people complaining usually don't know enough about audio or surround sound or Dolby or Bure to succinctly describe what their problems are.
Speaker 1: And many people don't believe those problems exist.
Speaker 1: But then I find people who find problems that are clearly real, but then there are fanboys who don't believe the problems exist because they're surround sound set up wrong in the first place.
Speaker 1: So I've been watching this whole thing and I think I have a more meta point to make.
Speaker 1: Physical media is dead except to collectors.
Speaker 0: Physical media has been head for a long time.
Speaker 0: I don't understand how blue Ray is still alive or why anyone ever buys them ever.
Speaker 0: It makes no sense to me.
Speaker 1: I could say, well, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: I would buy physical media for a show.
Speaker 1: that one, I don't have a reliably existent forever stream of two.
Speaker 1: I regularly show to other people in my house, you know, a physical media is.
Speaker 0: I get a digital copy onto a hard drive.
Speaker 0: Now it's a physical media that, uh, yeah, well, lately I'm really rip.
Speaker 1: I basically only watch streaming stuff now and things I actually care about.
Speaker 1: I will rip and I'm kind of planning to rip every DVD I own and they get rid of them all.
Speaker 0: I already did a lot of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, already did a lot of that.
Speaker 1: In fact, I'm in the process of ripping all of utenna as we ramp up production of geek nights presents already did that.
Speaker 1: Uh, the trouble is depending on ripping formats and everything, sometimes subtitles, there's.
Speaker 1: every like old anime release has its own particular bullshit.
Speaker 0: You got to know what you're doing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, you got to put some manual effort into figuring out the particular problems with each individual anime series and publisher.
Speaker 0: But the point is, is that, you know, regardless of the problems of physical media in general, particularly right, the less professional releases, right.
Speaker 0: And anime companies are less big time than, say, Hollywood movies.
Speaker 0: Good God.
Speaker 1: It is clearly amateur hour.
Speaker 0: It's amateur hour when it comes to mastering their DVDs and buries.
Speaker 0: And it always has been, except there are a few right companies that even though they are amateur, it's not amateur hour.
Speaker 0: For example, say anime ego back in the day or disco tech now.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They put in they're the people who actually care about the stuff they're doing and they're putting in the full effort, but say a fundamentally or a band is just like whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I'd, but what's funny is I was reading all these Twitter conversations and forum conversations about this and I noticed something kind of an anecdote.
Speaker 1: There were three classes of people, the people who weren't involved because they just stream everything and don't care about physical media.
Speaker 1: People like me who are busybodies and complain and the people who were defending the anime companies who make mistakes because you got to support them.
Speaker 0: See previous geek nights episode.
Speaker 0: This is not a charity.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is there is a way to make it a charity by using a combination of Kickstarter and donations and whatever, but that's a whole separate thing.
Speaker 1: My anecdotal evidence is something much more subtle.
Speaker 1: The people who were saying these mistakes are common in other industries and we shouldn't hold the anime industry to that high of standard because they're so small and whatever.
Speaker 1: We're almost universally very poorly spelled and with bad grammar.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: And the people who are saying things like the release is ruined or this is bullshit amateur hour use proper punctuation and good word order and spelling.
Speaker 0: So just, just pointing that out in a somewhat related news, right?
Speaker 0: No Zomi, another anime company is releasing princess night on DVD in the U S.
Speaker 1: oh shit son.
Speaker 0: And they're doing some crazy remaster and you can see this link that is provided for you a video comparison showing you the kind of remaster they're doing.
Speaker 1: Wait, is this a good remaster?
Speaker 1: or is this the Utena one, which is good.
Speaker 1: This is like.
Speaker 0: this is like the anime ego Macross one where it's just all the color is correct, right?
Speaker 0: However, there is a flaw.
Speaker 1: The flaw is a fatal.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Well kind of because it does it clearly given clue the final episode because of the materials that they have to work with.
Speaker 0: They do not have Japanese audio that they can include.
Speaker 0: So it is dove only.
Speaker 1: Ah, but that modern Astro boy had the same problems.
Speaker 1: The reason I didn't watch it because that was the worst.
Speaker 0: So this, they, to their credit though, right?
Speaker 0: The top comment on YouTube is I would get this.
Speaker 0: If only there was an option for the original Japanese audio with English subtitles, they themselves officially replied with their account saying, sorry, frowny face.
Speaker 0: We've been pretty open about the reasons we can't include.
Speaker 0: the Japanese audio is just not possible with the source materials provided to us.
Speaker 0: We still think this will be a very impressive addition for all the PK fans out there.
Speaker 0: Smiley face.
Speaker 1: So is it because I haven't followed this news at all.
Speaker 1: Is it that the Japanese company won't give it to them or that it's gone?
Speaker 0: I have a feeling that it's just, it sounds right.
Speaker 1: My gone can happen and that sucks.
Speaker 1: There are gone situations in the world, but I doubt this is a gone.
Speaker 0: My interpretation is that given whatever audio masters they have received, the quality or completeness of those is lacking.
Speaker 0: Like the, you know, there might be like just completely missing or, or the sound is like you can't hear it or full of noise, like, you know, something like that, that kind of issue, right?
Speaker 0: It doesn't seem like it's an issue where the material doesn't exist.
Speaker 0: It's an issue where the material that they received from saying they received.
Speaker 1: That's why I'm wondering what the Japanese company has to say about this.
Speaker 1: They, they, who knows what they might have like something better or they might not.
Speaker 1: And I say, or they might've let it fall because I don't know who owns whatever rights and I don't know, but do they, do they have the masters?
Speaker 0: Maybe that is the master they had.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's, I don't know, but whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: This is a problem in general that we need to be better about archiving stuff that wasn't already digital before.
Speaker 1: it's too late and we lose it all.
Speaker 1: But I worry that this was not necessarily a situation of.
Speaker 1: it wasn't available, but a situation of.
Speaker 1: there was some BS with whatever company has rights and copyright disputes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I think that, you know, that stuff seems to happen way more often currently than it literally does not actually exist anymore.
Speaker 0: It could also be that they got their source material.
Speaker 0: They couldn't get the source materials from Japan.
Speaker 0: They could only get them from the U S right.
Speaker 0: Something like that.
Speaker 1: But again, if it's something like that, that usually also means there's some IP dispute.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I hate the fact that there's no way to get the fullness of what happens in these situations.
Speaker 0: It's it's like, why not tell everybody things?
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: I've discussed that before.
Speaker 1: We talked about that, but anyway, things of the day, way back we had this video, I forget if it was me or Scott, but it was a, uh, a cat singing about how he can't find his keys in the morning.
Speaker 1: Something that even now, not owning a car happens to me on a semi regular basis.
Speaker 1: Heavens to me, never, but a situation we've all used.
Speaker 1: You've never experienced that.
Speaker 1: You've never been out to go.
Speaker 0: I have in the past, but I have a system that has been working for many years of perfectness.
Speaker 1: Well, my system now is I have a drawer.
Speaker 1: My keys always are.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Got my wallet.
Speaker 0: The problem will be I use the ropey thing inside of my Timbuktu bag and go click.
Speaker 1: I don't carry my bag anymore.
Speaker 1: Ever.
Speaker 0: I carry my bag, carry my bag bag is important.
Speaker 1: I don't carry my laptop with me cause I don't need it anymore.
Speaker 0: I carry a lot of stuff with me.
Speaker 1: I carry, I basically carry nothing with me.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: What happens when you're outside and then that's the apocalypse and you don't have any equipment.
Speaker 1: I'll break into paragraph sports and get it all because I just got, when the apocalypse happens, your net runner cards and your laptop are not going to be that.
Speaker 0: And those are the most important things.
Speaker 0: What are you talking about?
Speaker 1: Anyway, it was a funny video.
Speaker 0: We're going to pass the time in the fallout shelter without net runner cards.
Speaker 1: So, uh, the people behind that funny video did in fact continue to make funny videos and they have a youtube series that is basically just the odd couple.
Speaker 1: But if they're worse people, it's actually really funny and I've watched every episode of it.
Speaker 1: It is crude.
Speaker 1: It is mean black humor and it is great.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Is that it?
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So, uh, you know, on my wall, I have that awesome, uh, woodblock print.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, you do.
Speaker 0: It depicts, uh, what's his face?
Speaker 1: Uh, you already forgot.
Speaker 0: I forgot.
Speaker 0: All I remember is that it's, it's, oh, it's, is it Yoshitsune I think.
Speaker 0: And the, and, uh, Bankade the warrior monk and they're both, and they just killed the whole Tyra clan.
Speaker 0: Like they're evil enemies, right?
Speaker 0: Well, they're enemies.
Speaker 0: They're like, it's like half fields and McCoys.
Speaker 0: The half fields just killed all the fucking McCoys.
Speaker 0: I don't even actually know what happened with that in reality.
Speaker 0: But anyway, and they get in a boat and they're going back home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think this is the woodblock you have, right?
Speaker 0: This one now, but that's right.
Speaker 0: Not it.
Speaker 0: And, uh, the, uh, all of the ghosts of all the dead Tyra clan people come up or all around the boat.
Speaker 0: Like, Ooh, you just killed us all.
Speaker 0: Ooh, assholes.
Speaker 0: We're going to, right.
Speaker 0: So anyway, uh, so here's a website I found ukiyo a.org.
Speaker 0: It is a Japanese woodblock print search.
Speaker 0: Oh, it has pretty much every woodblock print ever.
Speaker 0: As far as I can tell, I have not, there is none that I know of.
Speaker 0: And I know of quite a few that I was not able to find on this site, including the one I have my wall and it separates them too by like, you know, time.
Speaker 0: So it goes all the way from early to mid 17 hundreds all the way up to like 19 fifties to now.
Speaker 0: And they had some fricking modern ones on here that are really brightly colored because fucking modern.
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 0: Look at this one with the mountain.
Speaker 1: Not bad.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: In the meta moment, we're going to be at anime Boston doing five events.
Speaker 1: We're also going to be a kinetic on packs, Australia packs, dev packs, prime magfest, et cetera.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: Uh, we got a forum book club book, player of games in a banks forum, YouTube, uh, Twitter.
Speaker 1: Grand Prix is currently Galaga Galaga.
Speaker 0: Shoot them bugs.
Speaker 1: It's got, what if I do not not get points forever, but I just take my sweet time.
Speaker 0: Eventually, you know, you're, you're using my time cause I have to watch you play.
Speaker 0: It's a one chance.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And if I have to, if you take up your whole, you know, whatever, whatever watch.
Speaker 1: So what's the rule?
Speaker 1: The rule is there a time limit?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: When I have to fucking go because I have a higher priority.
Speaker 0: Like besides watching you fucking is, is completely invalid.
Speaker 1: Cause what if someone's on the Epic?
Speaker 1: Like they're just going and going and going, but you got to pay.
Speaker 1: What are you going to do?
Speaker 0: Listen, you schedule a time for this shit with me, right?
Speaker 0: You're going to have enough time.
Speaker 0: Most people are going to die within a few minutes.
Speaker 0: No one's going to play for hours and hours and hours.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: And if they do, right, it's like they win.
Speaker 0: Who else is going to go that long?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So what if three people were going to go, one guy is going to go hours and hours and hours and some guys going that you cut him off.
Speaker 0: If some guys go in that long, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We're talking world record situation.
Speaker 0: So it becomes suddenly becomes bigger than the grand Prix.
Speaker 0: It becomes super important unless he's just really slow.
Speaker 0: You can't be slow at Galaga.
Speaker 1: He gets down to one bug each time and then takes a sweet ass time.
Speaker 1: Relaxing, recuperating, avoiding that one bug over and over again, does the no shootie glitch.
Speaker 0: It's not easy to avoid.
Speaker 1: the people do the no shootie glitch.
Speaker 0: We, we, uh, I was going to let people do no shootie because I was going to do the no shootie glitch.
Speaker 0: I'm assuming that no one can actually pull it off.
Speaker 1: I pulled it off like five times.
Speaker 1: I tried it.
Speaker 0: I'm going to go try it and see if I can do it and that will, then I will determine if I had to ban it or not.
Speaker 1: It's really easy to pull off.
Speaker 0: I'm going to try it anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So long, long time ago.
Speaker 1: I remember Scott and I watch.
Speaker 1: It was like 2007, maybe late 2006.
Speaker 1: We watched we're in beacon, a youtube video that was just this kid and his dog who had powers and booties and it was just crazy.
Speaker 1: It was one of those awesome internet things in an era before crazy internet things were that common.
Speaker 1: yet.
Speaker 1: They were still pretty common, not as common as they are now to where something crazy like this was notable among all the other crazy things that we remembered.
Speaker 0: It was moderately notable.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then somehow many years later it turned into a show and that show just kept going and still go and it was interesting.
Speaker 1: All these different waves of us encountering adventure time.
Speaker 1: I remember going to like New York anime festivals.
Speaker 0: I remember going to New York comic con and there was a giant inflatable Jake.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Huge.
Speaker 0: And I was like, Oh, I guess that's that thing.
Speaker 0: I guess that thing got pretty big.
Speaker 0: All right, go, go you people who liked that thing.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And then I remember seeing tons of people wearing the fin hat and I was like, Oh, I wonder if that's going to be a thing like at cons, like ponies thing now.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: And it and ponies and homestuck seem to be in this cluster of things that are continually appearing on the internet and at conventions, even anime conventions.
Speaker 1: So I resolved at some point to watch a bunch of it, but late to the game, cause a bunch of our friends like you go in enough and all these other people we know had already watched adventure time and we're just watching it as it came out and we're super into it and I just kind of ignored it.
Speaker 1: Scott had kind of ignored it.
Speaker 1: So finally me and Emily are like, let's just watch it because this lemon grab thing, I got to know what the fuck that is.
Speaker 0: I saw that video of the guy going with the lemon coming out of his mouth and I was like, what the fuck is that to me?
Speaker 1: Like what the fuck was that?
Speaker 1: It's some adventure time lemon guy and I watch it and I still don't know what the fuck's up with that video, but it's an officially posted video from Cartoon Network.
Speaker 1: But basically voice actor of lemon grass started watching adventure time and I liked it for the first, I don't know, 10 episodes.
Speaker 1: I was like, this is really great.
Speaker 1: But then from that point on, I loved it.
Speaker 1: I went through the same progression of ponies of.
Speaker 1: this is pretty good.
Speaker 1: And then halfway through the first season, this is great.
Speaker 1: And then by the end of the first season, this is one of the best things.
Speaker 0: You know, I like adventure time a lot and it has a lot of greatness to it.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to say it's one of the best things there is.
Speaker 1: Well, let's see of current, of current and recent things as in TV show of any kind, what's better than adventure time right now?
Speaker 0: Oh, it's better.
Speaker 1: That's ongoing or recent show.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean recent, nothing really.
Speaker 1: I mean recent at all.
Speaker 1: Let's go back even three years.
Speaker 1: I mean, Monica, I guess was really good.
Speaker 0: I'd say Monica's right.
Speaker 1: Better in venture time probably a while ago and ended.
Speaker 0: It just shows you what kind of drought we're in.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's a venture brothers, which I love, but you don't like.
Speaker 1: There's a Archer, which I love, but you don't like.
Speaker 1: There's ponies, which I love and you love, but I'm not going to pretend that season three is as good as season one and two.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: So with ponies, right?
Speaker 0: I'm going to say artistically speaking, adventure time is way ahead of ponies.
Speaker 1: I will agree.
Speaker 0: Like a whole category up a whole level beyond, but in terms of, you know, which one would I rather watch?
Speaker 0: I give those a new ponies and a new adventure time at the same time.
Speaker 0: Which one do I watch first?
Speaker 1: Before the third episode of season three of ponies, I probably would have still said pony.
Speaker 0: I say like coin toss.
Speaker 1: I think I want because ponies, I in season three, I started waiting a day or two and I watched the episode like Sunday or Monday, but adventure time, Emily and I pretty much download like the, the jankiest ass cap.
Speaker 1: you can get from Bittorrent every Monday when it's out and watch it that night.
Speaker 0: I mean, when I started, you know, when I started watching the adventure time, I burned through it like, you know, fire on some dry as leaves.
Speaker 0: I think by now that I've finished it all, it's like a new episode came out.
Speaker 0: what a Monday.
Speaker 0: I haven't watched it yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you've watched every episode up to that point.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I remember just pointedly, you were like, I'm only going to watch full seasons that are out.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to download these individual episodes.
Speaker 1: And then I think it was three or four days later.
Speaker 1: you just innocently asked.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So potluck princess, that's the last one, right?
Speaker 0: Just saying, I thought it was going to be more difficult to get all the one shot.
Speaker 1: I think also what happened was, cause you know, we're not gonna, I'm not spoilers, not really, but uh, the fourth season of adventure time actually does kind of end on a pretty big eska flow in a style cliffhanger.
Speaker 1: I wasn't really that hung, but it was not, did you not agree to not spoil eska flow in a, that was an eska flow in a style cliffhanger style.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I don't know level, but style.
Speaker 1: I mean it was the same.
Speaker 1: The only reason it wasn't the same level is because adventure times plot that ended in that was only a few episodes long as opposed to 22 episodes long.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The thing with here is, um, let's get to this.
Speaker 1: Adventure time has a number of aspects to it.
Speaker 0: That's what I was going for.
Speaker 1: It has the sort of, it is crazy and every episode is just way different and you never really like it surprises you and goes into really interesting places all over the place all the time.
Speaker 1: Two, it has a core set of extremely iconic, well done characters that are very strong and independently interesting.
Speaker 1: And three, it also has the nerd Gandalf girth world building all there in the background the whole time.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 0: So I see, I see that definitely Gandalf girth aspect, right?
Speaker 0: But here's is the way I see adventure time, right?
Speaker 0: On the one hand, you've got sort of the, you know, the world building Gandalf.
Speaker 0: on the second hand, you have this dialogue that the characters have this way of talking.
Speaker 0: That's really the highlight and where at the one hand they talk really funny, but also sort of the way friends would talk, but also a little way more exaggerated than the way and clever.
Speaker 1: It's, uh, it's interesting.
Speaker 0: you say that because it's almost like if you took, right, you know, those fast talking, funny vaudeville types from the olden days, like a Groucho Marx of modern times talking to his friend, who's also a Groucho Marx.
Speaker 0: And at the one hand it's, it's, it's, they talk funny, but no characters are really stupid, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, there's no straight man Abbott Costello situation.
Speaker 0: Everyone is totally smart.
Speaker 1: Sometimes, sometimes it's like sometimes Jake just does really stupid things.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: People do dumb things and maybe they're weird or eccentric, but nobody's dumb.
Speaker 0: Even the ice King's not dumb, right?
Speaker 0: It's just, he has a weird motivations and such one person.
Speaker 1: There's one dumb character who is cinnamon bun.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Cinnamon bun is dumb, but cinnamon buns barely in the show.
Speaker 1: I like cinnamon bun.
Speaker 0: I don't like cinnamon bun.
Speaker 0: Um, yeah, everyone.
Speaker 0: I mean, and you know, even some of the characters are super smart, right?
Speaker 0: Princess Volgum.
Speaker 1: You at Marceline too, I think.
Speaker 1: But anyway, you
Speaker 0: hit on
Speaker 1: something because Emily and I were watching venture brothers and there's a scene in season four where two characters are flying a fighter jet and that show does the sort of, it always juxtaposes friends having one of those banter style conversations with like they're in a fighter jet doing something crazy.
Speaker 1: Like when you see Spiderman just had like talking normal.
Speaker 1: Well, I know what you're talking about.
Speaker 1: I love that.
Speaker 1: But we realized that sort of banter in adventure time and venture brothers is stylized banter because friends, like if you and I have our banter just in person, it feels clever and fun in this certain way because we're, it's like our own personal inside baseball, but someone else just seeing that would not find it terribly witty or terribly apt or apropos.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't have that professional polish, but if you take natural banter and put it in a show, it also loses that and seems kind of lackluster and cheap.
Speaker 1: If you stylize that banter to go one step beyond what normal people banter like, it feels emotionally the way real banter feels.
Speaker 1: So it simulates the experience of having the banter with a friend by stylizing it with people who aren't actually real.
Speaker 1: So I think that's why they do it.
Speaker 1: And that scene in venture brothers is this multi-minute conversation about a hooker they met and how horrifyingly depressing her breasts were.
Speaker 1: And it's, I was laughing out loud and almost crying by the end of it.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: But the other aspect right is not quite with the world building, right?
Speaker 0: But with the, uh, the fact that every episode, right?
Speaker 0: There's, it's, everything is fresh, right?
Speaker 0: There's no like stock footage situation or reuse situation.
Speaker 0: It's a constant discovery of like, always new creatures.
Speaker 0: He goes in the forest.
Speaker 0: You don't see the same thing again.
Speaker 0: It's a new thing, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, Oh, in the background, new things.
Speaker 0: It's like, you're constantly exploring the world without stopping.
Speaker 0: It's not like they built the world and then living in it.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: It's, it's, they just keep going out and out and out without stopping to new places in the world, but simultaneously they support the world building by being consistent with the things that they do show.
Speaker 1: Like once they show something, it is always pretty surprisingly consistent with the rest of everything that's going on.
Speaker 1: But I think the right way they're able to do that is that they're constantly shredding new ground.
Speaker 1: So the things they revisit are the few core things that they can spend all the time to make sure Marceline is consistent with the history and the timeline and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But they'll, they'll never just like redo something they already did.
Speaker 0: If there's like a character that appeared in like one episode and they bring it back, it's doing something new.
Speaker 0: Like spanking guy comes back and he's doing something totally different with these birds and they don't cheap out on the animation.
Speaker 0: They're always drawing new creatures and new backgrounds and new places.
Speaker 1: Even stuff that's only in an episode for like a couple minutes and then it's gone.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like other shows like don't have that kind of shit.
Speaker 1: Even Ren and Stimpy had a lot of low rent parts and re reuse crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Or like the same characters over and over again.
Speaker 0: It's like, come on guys, you know, do something new.
Speaker 0: I was like another mojo Jojo episode and powerpuff girls.
Speaker 0: Why don't you come up with some new bad guy?
Speaker 0: Why don't you use him more than three times?
Speaker 1: Part of this is also, you know, I said the characters are really strong.
Speaker 1: I really liked the characters and it's not just because they're really well characterized and really sort of strong and iconic, both in the Matt Groening like silhouette way and just like the way they interact with each other and the way they, you know, their motivations and their histories and all that are just really consistent and well done.
Speaker 1: The characters themselves also often surprise me and I think it's because like you said, none of them are dumb.
Speaker 1: So they react like that.
Speaker 1: One of my favorite episodes in the whole show is Marceline's closet.
Speaker 1: That is just one of the funniest.
Speaker 1: That spider pushes that laugh off the dresser and they're just like, what?
Speaker 1: And then at the end where the spider bites him, I just, I, that's one of my favorite episodes.
Speaker 1: But the fact that the very end of the episode, Marceline is just like, okay, whatever.
Speaker 1: I hide in your house all the time.
Speaker 1: No biggie.
Speaker 1: Like just the, that kind of stuff doesn't happen in other shows that otherwise could be like adventure time.
Speaker 1: They'll always fall back on a trope.
Speaker 1: Adventure time ends with the abrupt weird shit.
Speaker 1: Almost every episode.
Speaker 0: The number one abrupt is you're going to say when Jake's in his pocket.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: He's smart.
Speaker 0: He's in my pocket the whole time.
Speaker 0: Hey, the final thing, right?
Speaker 0: Is that adventure time is very bonus, right?
Speaker 0: And the way that it has sort of these cute characters in a fantasy world, it looks like it's going to be sort of a silly kind of situation
Speaker 1: most of the time, but
Speaker 0: it's actually, they go on this huge expansive adventure to find out the terrible secret of fantasy world as opposed to space.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But actually it is a terrible secret to space.
Speaker 1: That kind of is.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But like the Lich was actually like.
Speaker 1: there's scary and serious sort of real plot mixed in with the crazy adventure time stuff.
Speaker 1: And I liked the fact that all those elements are in the same show.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I also liked the fact that it uses music.
Speaker 1: That's one thing that ponies did very well too is having music integrated with the show.
Speaker 1: I think Scott at least now understands why I keep singing these fucking songs just all the time.
Speaker 0: Even like, it's not even like ponies or winter wrap up is like a musical number.
Speaker 1: It's just like on a tropical.
Speaker 0: Jake is just things that there's barely like a fraction of a song, right?
Speaker 0: But it's just whoever came up with that.
Speaker 0: It's so good and catchy.
Speaker 1: And also I like tropical islands to begin with and I'll just look at suck in my head for like a week.
Speaker 1: I'll just be like, like I think what bothered Emily is the part that I like to say the most is rubbing it on my body or rubbing it on my body.
Speaker 0: You see the top comment on youtube is someone make a video, rub it on my body on loop for 10 hours, please.
Speaker 1: Well, like there's, there's one song that I found again recently.
Speaker 1: I was looking for an unrelated thing and it's just, they're kind of singing to each other and he's like, I'll stick my stick into your eye and you'll say, wow, wow, wow, wow.
Speaker 1: And that's been stuck in my head for a day and a half now.
Speaker 0: I don't remember that one.
Speaker 0: Randomly.
Speaker 1: They're just singing about how they'll stick a stick in your eye.
Speaker 1: And then there's all these cute scenes for Finna, like pick Jacob all sweet and they'll like sing at each other.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, and Jake is a musical dude.
Speaker 0: He has a little violin.
Speaker 0: He's always playing it and shit, but see, that's the thing.
Speaker 1: He's like, he's got all these, the characters have all this stuff going on.
Speaker 1: They're approaching the complexity of a real character in a real serious thing or a for real like big production thing, but yet it's just all these short little vignettes and then that character stuff is just kind of there
Speaker 0: and you never, and it's, it's, you know, cool how usually when you have a character in a cartoon, you know, it'll be like that character will have an aspect and they'll just, you know, explode that one aspect and character characterize it, you know, over and over again.
Speaker 0: It was an adventure time.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay, yeah, Finn's really great at adventuring and dungeons, but you know what?
Speaker 0: Every, most of the episodes, only two episodes where he dungeons and those are really good, but most of the episodes, it's like, he's actually doing something else and you're seeing some other aspect of him.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But he's still, he's still in character when he's teaching flame princess, how to dungeon that episode.
Speaker 1: Cause I just started thinking about dungeons and I like how the dungeons and everything, it's got that sort of trope of the trope aware character and that Finn's power seems to be that he just gets dungeons and gets it.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's the one episode that's pretty much just dungeon.
Speaker 0: He jumps into the dungeon.
Speaker 0: He's like, I'm my element.
Speaker 1: I quote that line.
Speaker 0: And then it to shows the smartness and the competence he does.
Speaker 0: He fucking tears that dungeon up.
Speaker 0: It's not like, you know, oops, you know, up some other show.
Speaker 0: It'd be like, I'm awesome.
Speaker 0: I actually know I just got caught right away.
Speaker 0: It's like, no, he's a total bad-ass.
Speaker 0: He cuts up the dungeon cause that's his thing.
Speaker 1: I think that's most evident in the monsters.
Speaker 0: He grabs treasures.
Speaker 0: He gets an awesome.
Speaker 1: So the episode with the fight King where they go in and he's trying to tempt them.
Speaker 1: They're like, yeah, we walked through there.
Speaker 0: That guy is going to kind of a lake.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: You did the giant dude.
Speaker 1: No, no.
Speaker 1: That guy was great.
Speaker 0: But it's like, no one beats that guy.
Speaker 1: But no, I'm talking about the fight.
Speaker 0: The farm that I'm thinking about the farm.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking about the fight King where he's just, they're like, it's totally a trap.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: If we'd walked in there, the doors would have closed and he would have been like gladiators fighting ghosts.
Speaker 1: and then they're like, eh, and then they run back in and they get trapped because that's going to be fun.
Speaker 0: It was a trap, but now you have to fight my gladiator ghost.
Speaker 1: We knew that I do like the serious parts of adventure time as much as I like the funny parts though.
Speaker 1: Like some of my favorite episodes are like the fact that the show will do.
Speaker 1: I think the example I'll use is that Dexter's lab episode.
Speaker 1: That's just ha ha ha ha ha ha.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: That kind of experimental arthouse sort of fun stuff like adventure time as the episode where it's just the snow golem and that awesome little firewolf dude.
Speaker 0: Same thing.
Speaker 1: Exact same thing.
Speaker 1: The high concept episode, but they'll also have the series episode, like the doorlords episode with the, you know, them singing their songs is actually really kind of sweet and serious and poignant and it's kind of funny, but it's also kind of sad.
Speaker 0: and there the relationship between fan and princess bubble gum is actually, yeah, that's another, they always, you know, sort of explore new combinations of the existing characters, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, well, Finn and Jake.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but how, you know, or one of the earliest episodes is like, well, how do Finn and uh, the rainbow, whatever, what's her name?
Speaker 1: Lady Raina corn.
Speaker 0: How did they get along?
Speaker 1: I love how they got about that because then later in the, in the episode where magic man doesn't come back with the little mini people that when Jake's like, why is little Jake so sad?
Speaker 1: and things like, Oh, lady Raina corn dumped him.
Speaker 1: She's dating someone better now and she's just making out with Finn that he like all that stuff.
Speaker 1: And the fact that these little subtle callbacks and everything, I love adventure time.
Speaker 1: The thing, the one thing I got to say hard to not make the show just be, let's tell all our favorite anecdotes from the show.
Speaker 0: No, I don't do that.
Speaker 0: Is that actually?
Speaker 0: don't think adventure time is really that funny.
Speaker 0: Like laughing out loud, hysterically rolling on the floor.
Speaker 0: Funny.
Speaker 0: It's like there are some funny parts, right?
Speaker 0: But more of it is, is a lot like bone or it's just like this.
Speaker 0: It's like just awesome.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah.
Speaker 0: As opposed to, you know, Oh my God, low.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But it has, it has hilarious moments, but they're interspersed with just baseline levels of entertaining and interesting or moderately funny.
Speaker 1: Like when there's the voice they use for a couple of different characters, like the demon with the bananas, when they're locked up in the nanosphere is like, sorry, I had to lock in there with the stuff.
Speaker 1: The fact that that guy was just so deadpan in hell, that kind of humor isn't, you're not going to just laugh out loud when there's just like a deadpan straight man in the middle of crazy demon hell, but it's amusing in and of itself.
Speaker 1: And that amusement just kind of all builds up and builds up.
Speaker 1: And then later there'll be an unrelated.
Speaker 1: Jake farts in the pocket joke and they just crack up.
Speaker 0: What else is there to say about the times of adventure?
Speaker 1: Well, we could, we're not going to do it because we've got too much on our plate, but adventure time could easily have the radio free.
Speaker 1: equestria geek nights presents treatment.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: I would love to do it.
Speaker 1: I would love to do it.
Speaker 1: I would do it, but I don't have time for that shit.
Speaker 0: It's all.
Speaker 1: you notice how one point Jake puts on the ice.
Speaker 1: King's fucking crown doesn't go crazy and nothing happens.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, Finn puts on that crown and pretty much immediately turns into a wizard.
Speaker 0: Probably only works on humans.
Speaker 0: Maybe or people who aren't already magic.
Speaker 0: It's basically already wizard stretchiness.
Speaker 0: He's basically luffy.
Speaker 1: I love how he basically is.
Speaker 1: nothing without his powers.
Speaker 1: He's just.
Speaker 1: basically, it's the same as what became a human.
Speaker 1: He just doesn't want to do anything anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Though I think I no longer hear benders voice when I see Jake.
Speaker 1: Now I think of Jake when I watch Futurama, partly because Futurama is dead to me.
Speaker 1: It hasn't been funny for a long time.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of glad it's being canceled.
Speaker 0: He does do a slightly different voice.
Speaker 0: The voice is mostly the same, but it is crooks slightly.
Speaker 1: So it's going on, watch season one of adventure time again.
Speaker 1: And it's just like, Hey bender.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I see you're in the body of a dog now.
Speaker 0: And you're actually, your character is somewhat similar and that it is sort of the main character, but also sort of the side kick to the human main character, but also very main and also the sort of silly, you know, supporting person who provides more humor than seriousness, but also some amount of seriousness, you know, he's feeling the same role as bender in many ways with the same voice.
Speaker 0: And I think that's sort of just adds onto it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I think all these elements combined, kind of like how we talked about ponies is so remixed because it has this particular set of elements together.
Speaker 1: I think adventure time is one of the freshest shows on TV or at least one of the freshest animated shows because it's just got so many elements that freshen it up.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's just modern, it's appropriate for this current, you know, the year 2013, right?
Speaker 0: It's for the time that it is made.
Speaker 0: It's not like you watch something old and it's like, Oh man, that's so old.
Speaker 0: This is actually, you know, appeals to a modern sensibility made by modern young people, not something made by old people.
Speaker 0: So trying to guess what the kids like.
Speaker 1: Who's your favorite princess?
Speaker 0: Oh, favorite princess.
Speaker 0: Because it's interesting because you, everyone has the same reaction.
Speaker 1: I'll say this, everyone hates lumpy space princess and doesn't even want her to be on screen until they realize it's hilarious to have her on screen.
Speaker 0: So the question is, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, are you talking about the favorite princess to be on screen?
Speaker 0: or like the princess that I would date or the princess that is.
Speaker 1: We did all of them with ponies because I, so all right, princess on screen and then princess date, a princess on screen is probably love his face.
Speaker 1: You know, you want these lobs that, that bit where they think they're invisible and they're fucking with her.
Speaker 1: and she's just like, you guys, how about the princess?
Speaker 0: You don't want to be on screen.
Speaker 1: You know, turtle princess is just kind of boring, boring and slow, but one could argue that that's the point.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, at least I can't say that that, that being the point would be bad because I argue that that being the point is good when an oshi movie is super slow and boring on purpose.
Speaker 0: I can tell you the princess.
Speaker 0: I don't want to see again raspberry or a wildberry princess.
Speaker 0: No is bouncy castle princess.
Speaker 0: Cause that joke is only funny once.
Speaker 0: And it's like, what are you going to do with that again?
Speaker 1: Really notice how Finn didn't actually go inside her when everyone else did at the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I noticed that.
Speaker 0: Um, but yeah, princess today, it's tough because you know, bubble gum princess is totally the best nerdy and sciency and awesome, but she's also kind of crazy, but she's kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: You know what she is?
Speaker 1: She's a cross of Twilight sparkle and our friend Lisa.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I think if I'm going to go out with a princess, dr princess, dr princess is pretty good.
Speaker 0: It's totally normal person.
Speaker 0: Like, Hey, what's up?
Speaker 1: See, it's tricky.
Speaker 1: Is Marceline allowed to be on the list because she's not a princess.
Speaker 1: She's not a princess because I prefer the vampire queen to any of the princess side that I've seen.
Speaker 0: She's okay.
Speaker 1: Slime princess.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen enough of.
Speaker 1: She's funny though.
Speaker 1: The few times she's there.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Hotdog prince is just sort of like, Hey, what's up too?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I like how they all are kind of vaguely obsessed with Finn.
Speaker 0: Well, you got to remember that one episode where you know, the nice King and all the princesses show their true craziness.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They're all kind of crazy, but I think lumpy space princess wins out for being the most dangerously crazy.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, is like lumpy space princess, the only one with parents and they do have crowns.
Speaker 0: So it's like, are they the lumpy space King queen?
Speaker 0: I assume they are, but they never say that.
Speaker 1: Well, we don't know a lot about the Kings and Queens because Marceline just calls herself the vampire queen.
Speaker 1: I think she's actually a queen.
Speaker 0: No, she doesn't.
Speaker 0: There's no King.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And the ice King is the only King we've really interacted with.
Speaker 0: He's not even really a King.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: He just has a crown and is crazy and made a kingdom out of ice.
Speaker 1: I love the episodes.
Speaker 1: We get flashback.
Speaker 1: The fact that his backstory is kind of, there's a few characters who are pre apocalypse and that whole storyline is just great.
Speaker 0: It is interesting that his, you know, that they made that storyline.
Speaker 0: Uh, but it doesn't make me like the ice King.
Speaker 0: I still think he's sort of annoying.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: But think about this.
Speaker 1: Here's a meta here.
Speaker 1: Think about that guy or the crazy uncle with Alzheimer's.
Speaker 1: You don't want to be around that guy.
Speaker 1: You don't want to deal with like.
Speaker 1: the guy, you know, who like is actually autistic and just, it's really hard to deal with them socially, but at the same time you can't hate him and you sympathize and empathize.
Speaker 0: I don't sympathize the ice King at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Guy who sacrificed his sanity to save a little girl in a post apocalyptic world.
Speaker 0: Spoilers, I guess he's just an annoying dude.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But that dude who sacrificed his life was a different dude.
Speaker 0: That dude is dead.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, that episode where Marceline is just hanging out with him and he's just being crazy and she's singing his notes back at him and he doesn't even realize anymore is so sad.
Speaker 1: So sad.
Speaker 1: I get a little choked up every time I see that episode.
Speaker 0: To me, the ice King is like the annoying, not as good as the other bad guys.
Speaker 0: Bad guy.
Speaker 0: He hires a hit man.
Speaker 1: I thought that one was pretty good.
Speaker 1: I liked him on screen and that hit man was pretty good.
Speaker 0: The scorching, but it's like, come on.
Speaker 0: You know, there's real bad guys out there, right?
Speaker 0: Like I'm watching powerpuff girls and it's like, I don't want to see this mojo Jojo every other episode.
Speaker 0: I want him.
Speaker 0: I want amoeba boy.
Speaker 1: Him is the only one I want.
Speaker 1: Him is the Lich.
Speaker 1: Him is better than every other girls.
Speaker 0: Him is better than the Lich.
Speaker 1: I think the thing is I like the Lich because the Lich, you know, this is just a smart and straightforward, actually bad guy.
Speaker 0: Him is a straight and as a smart and straightforward, actually bad guy.
Speaker 0: He also has style and the Lich does not have style.
Speaker 1: The Lich reminds me of rezo of, Oh, you're here.
Speaker 1: Time for me to immediately
Speaker 0: has styled also not as much as him, but more than fricking the Lich style, but rezo or attitude
Speaker 1: and all these, a lot of other villains have a sympathetic side, but the, the Lich is kind of the only thing in the adventure time world that is pure, absolute unquestioning evil with no possibility of redemption.
Speaker 0: Uh, playing princess is dead flame King.
Speaker 1: I think he's, he is evil in that evil is doing its job way.
Speaker 1: Like he's the flame King.
Speaker 1: Of course he's evil though.
Speaker 1: I think flambo is one of my favorite characters.
Speaker 0: Flambo is pretty good.
Speaker 1: He's like, I cast flame shield on you and I spit son.
Speaker 0: You know, all right.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: You know which characters this all right.
Speaker 0: Best side character that appears in only a few episodes, only a few lady rain accords, not in enough episodes.
Speaker 0: I want to say her, but you know, who's better than that.
Speaker 1: Uh, I like me now.
Speaker 1: Oh, you want to do the one, two, three choose goose.
Speaker 1: Aha.
Speaker 1: The choose goose is often forgotten.
Speaker 0: Choose is so good.
Speaker 0: That actually the juice goose actually brings out the laughs because he, cause he's totally weird and wacky, but he's not stupid either.
Speaker 1: But in any other show they would overuse that character in that voice.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: And he would be, it would get, you know, and they would make it a dumb character.
Speaker 0: It's like, no, choose goose is smart.
Speaker 0: He told you whatever he tells you was true and he gives you really good equipments.
Speaker 0: He also, when he's making fun of it, he's just the best.
Speaker 0: He's not fooling you.
Speaker 1: He's making fun of Finn when Finn wants the armor.
Speaker 0: That's so I love, that's one of my favorite episodes.
Speaker 0: One where he's got the armor that is.
Speaker 1: Well, the, you know, even inside of the show when magic man gives him the little miniature people and he's like, Oh, you know, these are, I left all the C listers in the bag.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Like he's only got the A-list characters out.
Speaker 0: So meta, but so true, but so meta.
Speaker 1: I like how Peppermint Butler has a fucking dark streak.
Speaker 1: You know, that's coming back.
Speaker 0: Well, it's already, you know, it already came back once in one episode.
Speaker 0: It's like Peppermint Butler, you know, death.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, Oh no, death is like, Oh, you know, Peppermint Butler.
Speaker 0: Why did you say so?
Speaker 1: He's like, you'll owe me a favor.
Speaker 0: And then there's another episode where it's like, Oh, this will show you the aura.
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: Peppermint Butler's like, let's not look at my aura.
Speaker 1: And, but all those things carry through like this very subtle thing.
Speaker 1: in one of the flashback episodes with Simon noticed how the candy goop was kind of interacting a little bit like the precursors, the candy people are evolving.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You're feeling we should do radio for you, but here's the question, right?
Speaker 0: So did bubblegum princess make all the candy people?
Speaker 1: I think she is the, she and her bloodline.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess bubblegum line sugar line, sugar line, but she's only 18.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Cause she, we know a little bit.
Speaker 1: She has her, uh, you know, she had a mother and a father.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: That was, that came up in the show.
Speaker 1: We know their names even.
Speaker 0: All right, cool.
Speaker 1: So the question is she, her bloodline sugar line is the manifestation of that evolved semi-sentient thing.
Speaker 1: And that family over time created candy people from that elemental life essence of sugar.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So how did peppermint Butler who came out of that become all evil and shit?
Speaker 1: Cause they all have free will and agency.
Speaker 1: He went off and hung out with death.
Speaker 0: I guess so.
Speaker 0: What's the story with that shit?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Actually the episode did that happen?
Speaker 1: So you want to forget all that.
Speaker 1: There's only one episode that actually kind of creep me out when Finn gets knocked out and wakes up and Jake's just fucking crazy and everyone else is gone.
Speaker 1: That episode was actually pretty creepy.
Speaker 0: Which one was it?
Speaker 1: where Jake's got a head injury and is living like a hobo and everyone's missing and the deer has kidnapped everyone.
Speaker 1: That episode was kind of creepy because Jake always acts flibbity flobbity.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm crazy Hamlet style.
Speaker 1: But in that, that episode he was Ophelia crazy.
Speaker 1: There aren't that many Ophelia crazy episodes.
Speaker 0: No, you can't overuse that.
Speaker 0: It would get old.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You guys can't tell adventure time super good.
Speaker 1: We really like it.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure everyone who's listening to this already knows people are not watching adventure time because they're stupid.
Speaker 0: You know how many people told us to do a show in adventure time this week?
Speaker 1: Guys, the show, it's like.
Speaker 1: the episodes are so short.
Speaker 1: You can just watch one like while you're brushing your teeth.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If you also floss, even though this over in the fifth season, season, every season, you can watch the whole thing faster than you can watch like a whole anime.
Speaker 0: Almost the problem I had is that I think it is still, I think there are, I think there may still be less seconds of adventure time than there are seconds of Utena.
Speaker 0: It's close.
Speaker 1: I think there's more seconds of adventure time because we tend to only 39 full length episodes.
Speaker 0: 39 times two is 78.
Speaker 0: How many adventure times are there?
Speaker 1: 26 per season, five seasons.
Speaker 0: So if you divide that in half because the episodes are only a little bit more adventure time than there is Utena.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but adventure time is just great.
Speaker 1: My only problem was we started watching it and after a few episodes we just would burn through like 10 episodes.
Speaker 1: then it go and then we ran out.
Speaker 0: That's the only way I watch things these days.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And if I don't have an urge to watch something and burn through it, then I don't watch it at all.
Speaker 1: Which is why House of Cards was great because they released the whole thing at once.
Speaker 1: So when I was like, I'm going to watch that show, I just watched the whole thing at my own pace.
Speaker 1: I had no point had to deal with Escaflowne bullshit cliffhangers.
Speaker 0: Now the thing I don't see, I like that method, right?
Speaker 0: But the method I like better than that, that no one has done yet, as far as I can tell, is don't have like some sort of schedule, right?
Speaker 0: Just make the show and as soon as an episode is done, put it up.
Speaker 0: And as soon as the episode is done, put it up.
Speaker 0: So if one episode is real easy to do and it took you an hour, you put it up an hour after the previous episode.
Speaker 0: As soon as you have the thing mastered and ready to upload, upload it.
Speaker 1: My only regret is not as you go, not watching the show closer to when it was coming out meant that much like when all our friends read the Prince of Nothing before we did, I missed out on that wave.
Speaker 1: Everyone's talking about it now.
Speaker 1: I'm the guy late to the party.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 1: Luckily, Scott watched it.
Speaker 1: So now we have a little party going again, which is fine.
Speaker 1: And what I was getting at is that even with Prince of Nothing, every time new people read it, we would have a wave of everyone talking about it again.
Speaker 1: And the wave just gets bigger every time.
Speaker 1: One of my coworkers is reading the Prince of Nothing right now.
Speaker 1: He just, he was like, yeah, he just left the guy behind in the woods.
Speaker 0: Is it a smart person who knows how to read?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The guy knows the guys into that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Okay, good.
Speaker 1: So he basically, he was like, yeah, Kelly, that's way early.
Speaker 1: Kelly's just left that guy behind.
Speaker 1: He just started reading it in the woods.
Speaker 1: He's like, I just met the spy who's also a wizard.
Speaker 1: And I was like, and his friend, the, and I was like, yeah, I like the friend, the priest.
Speaker 1: And he was like, yeah, well let's see what happens.
Speaker 1: He's just, he's like, I got past the proper noun bullshit.
Speaker 1: I think I see what's going on here.
Speaker 1: And I know he's smart cause he's like, you know, when he left the guy behind in the woods, that said a lot about what's going on.
Speaker 1: I was like, yep, that said a lot indeed.
Speaker 1: All right, we're done.
Speaker 1: I think venture time.
Speaker 0: It's not a veggie time anymore.
Speaker 1: Well, I just, I'm one episode ahead of you.
Speaker 0: Oh no.
Speaker 0: So I don't have a story to go.
Speaker 1: Favorite.
Speaker 1: Not that commonly recurring character is magic man.
Speaker 0: He's such a jerk.
Speaker 1: The fact that the moral was how much of a jerk I am and how the whole thing in Mars and all that stuff just reinforces.
Speaker 1: And I wonder, I wonder if he ever will actually come back because that I'm not coming back is the kind of crap that the show does that I love.
Speaker 1: And I wonder if he will come back because notice how he was just talking about that episode.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Cause notice how the show implied that he has a backstory much like Simon's.
Speaker 0: It didn't imply it.
Speaker 1: They showed the whole thing, but they didn't actually tell you what actually happened.
Speaker 1: They just showed you enough evidence to surmise that.
Speaker 1: there's a similarly tragic backstory.
Speaker 1: and we still don't know how Marceline became a vampire yet.
Speaker 1: We just know about what age had happened to her and we know that she was a half demon already, which would make her super long lived, but not immortal.
Speaker 1: She's only immortal because of the vampire.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure she was always a vampire.
Speaker 1: No, we know.
Speaker 1: Absolutely.
Speaker 1: She wasn't one.
Speaker 1: No bite marks.
Speaker 1: when she's a kid to vampires don't age.
Speaker 1: She aged up to a point and stopped aging three in the alternate reality where she didn't get bit by a vampire because all the other bullshit didn't happen.
Speaker 1: She got way old by the point where she would have met Finn in the normal universe where she is not old.
Speaker 1: This is why maybe I need to get someone else to do radio for you with me.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to do it now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: What exactly are the borders of the land?
Speaker 1: Ooh, that's what we got to figure out.
Speaker 1: I mean, we get that panic.
Speaker 0: It's already not adventure time anymore.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, geek nights is not one but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.