Speaker 1: It's Thursday, August 8th, 2013.
Speaker 1: I'm Rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Skun.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights Tonight, Australia!
Speaker 0: It's down under today.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so like we said last week, we're back from Australia.
Speaker 1: We didn't talk much about Australia because we mostly talked about the semi-related things that happened at, I don't know, PAX.
Speaker 0: We gotta save up our load so that we can have a Thursday show idea because you know what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: the next time is a Thursday episode is gonna be like, "I want you to do the show about...".
Speaker 1: There's a lot of things I would like to do the show on.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All bad ideas.
Speaker 1: Lots of good ideas.
Speaker 0: Bad ideas.
Speaker 1: I bet if I brought it up and I mentioned one or two ideas ahead...
Speaker 0: You could say any idea and the listener would say that it's a great idea.
Speaker 1: I think the listener is usually on my side.
Speaker 0: There is no idea you could say no matter how bad it was.
Speaker 0: Like, talk about Starfish.
Speaker 0: The listener would be like, "Fuck
Speaker 0: yeah!".
Speaker 1: I could talk about Starfish for about four minutes and I'd be out of Starfish talk.
Speaker 0: They're cute.
Speaker 0: The legs grow back.
Speaker 0: There's big ones and small ones.
Speaker 0: I like them.
Speaker 1: It's kind of funny the way they move around.
Speaker 1: The way they eat is cool.
Speaker 0: They can get stuck on things.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Their little beak is kind of cute.
Speaker 0: I'd say they're cute already.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the beak is particularly cute.
Speaker 0: The star part is cuter than the beak part.
Speaker 1: They have a different kind of symmetry from what we have in many ways.
Speaker 1: I think we can pad that out a little bit with some banter back and forth.
Speaker 0: I don't think you have nineteen and a half minutes remaining of Starfish stuff.
Speaker 1: I get the feeling that the listener is usually on my side and I think you're correct in that sentiment.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: We keep stealing that listener joke.
Speaker 1: Points to anyone who knows what we stole it from.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 1: So, yeah.
Speaker 1: Not going to talk much about news, but we got some Australian news since we were just in Australia.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically there's nothing going on in this country.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's no NSA scandal.
Speaker 1: A man named Wiener didn't show his dick to people again.
Speaker 0: That's not news either.
Speaker 0: It's the same old, same old.
Speaker 0: At least to us because we live in this country.
Speaker 0: So we hear about that stuff.
Speaker 1: There was a mass shooting right before we left.
Speaker 1: There was a mass shooting while we were gone.
Speaker 1: There's a mass shooting like yesterday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not news either.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: So we're going to talk about Australian news.
Speaker 0: The only Australian news I noticed when I was there that wasn't sports was this news about a refugee boat or two.
Speaker 1: Now it was interesting.
Speaker 0: It wasn't clear how many there were because I was paying attention to other things and I only saw this news in passing.
Speaker 1: But what I noticed was that all the places I saw news around, like newspaper headlines on TV, it was pretty much almost entirely about this with a secondary thing about how some states are going to in Australia are going to legalize gay marriage ahead of the federal government doing it.
Speaker 1: But it's interesting that because it was very, it's rare that the news in the US would have an issue like that that held the forefront.
Speaker 1: Is it just because we have more scandalous kind of news that makes national attention?
Speaker 1: Is it that we have more international connections so more stuff makes it to be news?
Speaker 1: It was weird to see a single narrative lasting for weeks.
Speaker 0: We weren't.
Speaker 0: No, you don't know.
Speaker 1: It was basically in the news the entire time we were there, which was just about two weeks.
Speaker 1: We know we were there for weeks.
Speaker 0: No, you weren't.
Speaker 0: We were there.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Under two weeks.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: More than one week.
Speaker 1: Therefore plural.
Speaker 0: No for it to be weeks.
Speaker 0: Plural.
Speaker 1: It must be at least two total and it was one full week and then portions of another week.
Speaker 0: So that doesn't make weeks.
Speaker 0: It involved two weeks and makes over a week.
Speaker 1: It involved two individual week.
Speaker 0: This is the rim strategy of exaggeration.
Speaker 1: My point is simple.
Speaker 0: If you're going to exaggerate, you should just do what I do and do extreme hyperbole be like in the news for like a fucking 10 years.
Speaker 1: I don't think that was much of an exaggeration also because I noticed that news before we went and then it's still in the news now.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I had some boat full of people who came from a country I forget.
Speaker 1: You don't remember any of the details.
Speaker 1: So there's a wider problem in that Australia seems to have very liberal refugee laws compared to other countries.
Speaker 1: And those laws appear to be fairly popular and the government seems to have been trying to not exactly follow the spirit of those laws because they don't want all these refugees being resettled inside of mainland Australia.
Speaker 1: So they're trying to resettle refugees that are coming in and other places.
Speaker 1: Like they tried to make a deal.
Speaker 1: I think they did make a deal with a pop on New Guinea to have him go there instead.
Speaker 1: And that seems to be what is generating the liberal outrage in Australia right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like we went to the fucking immigration museum in Australia, which is all about, look, Australia, you know, forgetting the aboriginal situation, right?
Speaker 0: Is a, it's like, look, this is a place that's pretty much all immigrants.
Speaker 0: We all came here.
Speaker 0: We let people in.
Speaker 0: Look how awesome it is to let people in from all over the place.
Speaker 1: Glad we went to.
Speaker 1: that museum is the kind of, it was not a museum for people like us because we were foreigners.
Speaker 1: We're not Australians.
Speaker 1: And that was really, it'd be like if of someone who had no ties to the?
Speaker 1: u s whatsoever in any part of their family came to the?
Speaker 1: u s and went to Ellis Island.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But seeing what Australia presents to its own people on that issue was great because the whole museum was pretty much, yeah, look how fucking racist we were.
Speaker 1: and yeah, we're still pretty racist.
Speaker 0: Let people fucking in.
Speaker 0: Jesus Christ.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Or at least don't be really.
Speaker 1: It wasn't that long ago that major political parties in Australia had a, they called it the white Australia policy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Pretty much means exactly what it sounds like it means.
Speaker 1: So this is a big issue, but it seems like at least from the media, there's a lot of popular support for the refugees and for the sort of more liberal ideas around it and the government's all fighting about it.
Speaker 1: And this was different nuances on this story.
Speaker 1: We're in the forefront of the news for pretty much the entire time we were there.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: If you're a modern country and someone wants to move to your country, just say yes, just say yes every time.
Speaker 0: What's the fucking problem?
Speaker 0: I don't get it.
Speaker 0: If someone like Mexicans wants to come to the?
Speaker 0: u s just let them in.
Speaker 1: Uh, so you say we should have 100% open borders.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: When I wouldn't cause any problem whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Criminal.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So already you have to have a system to not let anyone in and vet them if you want that.
Speaker 0: But you don't like set some number or something, right?
Speaker 0: And if there's like,
Speaker 1: you know, actually you kind of do to a degree, especially because people who immigrate fresh to a country tend to not go very far from where they came in and tend to settle in a very small number of places, which would put extreme load on local infrastructure and services coupled with the fact that u s uh, places don't really have very good social services for people who don't speak the language very well and don't have a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Those people moved here.
Speaker 0: They do just moving from one piece of land to another piece of land.
Speaker 0: If there's no infrastructure there.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You're the person who lives there.
Speaker 1: What if more people than can comfortably and safely live in Finland want to go to Finland?
Speaker 1: It's a small place.
Speaker 1: Now watch these.
Speaker 1: Let one, one person in and it literally pushes another person out into the water to those people that live there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, to take care of New York used to not be able to handle that many people, but you know what?
Speaker 0: Millions of people moved here and they built really big buildings.
Speaker 1: There were decades of misery in here as a result.
Speaker 1: This is earth.
Speaker 1: Everywhere is miserable in this right now is only slightly miserable.
Speaker 0: Basically say, okay, someone else is miserable and I'm happy, so I should keep that person miserable to maintain my happiness.
Speaker 0: No, I'm saying that spread the misery more.
Speaker 1: I'm saying that ridiculous idealism really falls flat in the face of basic pragmatism.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, this is a boat full of people.
Speaker 0: There's no reason not to let this boat full of people move.
Speaker 1: But that's not what the arguments were all about.
Speaker 1: That boat was sort of a catalyst.
Speaker 1: They're saying in general, what should the policy be?
Speaker 1: Because there has been a fairly long standing flood of boat people, which is kind of what we've been calling people who came here from Cuba in the past.
Speaker 0: Someone comes in Cuba, we should also let them in.
Speaker 0: They voted all the way across the Caribbean.
Speaker 1: What if everyone in all of Europe simultaneously decided to come here?
Speaker 0: Sweet.
Speaker 1: That wouldn't work.
Speaker 1: There'd be mass starvation along the coasts.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: That's okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would.
Speaker 0: People would come here and be like, oh, why did we come here?
Speaker 0: And then they would move.
Speaker 1: Where would they move?
Speaker 1: They'd die of starvation before they could move.
Speaker 1: There wouldn't be that much food along the coast anymore.
Speaker 0: The point of people are moving away from a place is because they didn't like that place and had problems.
Speaker 0: So they moved to a place that doesn't have problems.
Speaker 0: If that place starts to have problems, people aren't going to be attracted to that place anymore.
Speaker 1: And yet you did not want to do a Thursday show on immigration, but seemed to have a lot of opinions on immigration.
Speaker 1: This is when the news.
Speaker 1: Listener, should we do a show on immigration and continue this argument?
Speaker 0: You could say any idea and people say yes.
Speaker 0: So do you want to do us to do a show on X?
Speaker 0: The answer is yes.
Speaker 1: Well, the letter X is not that it's not up to the listeners.
Speaker 0: What should we do?
Speaker 1: I say it should be.
Speaker 0: No, let's do it.
Speaker 1: Why shouldn't we just do whatever other people say.
Speaker 1: Why deny them happiness?
Speaker 1: Why say you don't get to have any input?
Speaker 1: You individual person.
Speaker 0: It's not your show.
Speaker 1: It's see what I did there.
Speaker 1: Let's move on.
Speaker 1: What really struck me about the news in Australia was that this was in the news and the other item that I saw at the top of my national news and I was poking around every morning was a single gun murder.
Speaker 1: I cannot imagine a situation in the U S where a single gun murder that doesn't have multiple political situations tied to it would make national news because there's a local gun murder.
Speaker 1: That's single gun murder pretty much everywhere in the U S pretty much every day.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not as crazy gun shooting is like you would think from say Japanese people seem to think that everyone in the U S has guns for some reason.
Speaker 1: A lot of us do have guns,
Speaker 0: but yeah, it's like, yeah, that's a local news and not a national news,
Speaker 1: but the fact that the national news had an article about the kind of shooting that would not even be the regional news in the U S says a lot about how effective gun control was at reducing gun violence in Australia.
Speaker 0: Well, who knows about violence in general, but yeah, gun violence.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it worked.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Regular violence is pretty low as well as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: Probably there's, uh, there's been an uptick according to the media in hooliganism and sort of bar fights and things like that among young white people.
Speaker 0: Oh, well that's common everywhere.
Speaker 1: And there was a bunch of racial tensions in the Western, Eastern part, Western part.
Speaker 1: I forget what part already of Melbourne, the part of Melbourne.
Speaker 0: There was some racial, racial tension across the tracks.
Speaker 1: I also learned that Melbourne very recently ended what was called, I think the gangland war where there were decades of gangland mafia murders and there's a huge, crazy history of mafia bullshit in Australia that I heard.
Speaker 0: New York recently ended decade long history of gangland wars.
Speaker 0: We didn't have a name recently entered the same way.
Speaker 1: the Australian one was.
Speaker 1: action was much more interesting because it was a sort of defined set of, it was kind of like a look back in history, the story of who was being murdered and why red like stories in America from the twenties.
Speaker 0: I heard that LA recently sort of mostly ended a long decade, multi-decade history of gangland wars.
Speaker 1: Actually, no, they didn't for one and two.
Speaker 1: that's different kind of gang from the kind of gangs I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, I'm just saying they're two completely unrelated things, but anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So I found this video of a machine that makes the day are the only things in this episode that aren't Australian.
Speaker 1: I could have found an Australian one if I tried hard enough.
Speaker 1: I didn't even think to, and I haven't uploaded any pictures from the trip yet.
Speaker 1: This is a machine that constructs the paper airplane from a single sheet of paper and then launches it and it appears to be able to do this in rapid fashion and I thought that was really cool.
Speaker 0: It's awesome.
Speaker 1: But then there was a love related video and that related video was actually pretty great.
Speaker 1: Basically by this related video, I stumbled upon the community of people who is dedicated to making crazy origami paper airplanes out of single sheets of paper using no tools other than a single pencil or pen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I knew these people existed.
Speaker 0: I knew, I assume they never searched for them on YouTube.
Speaker 1: In fact, I interacted with them because when I was a kid, I did science Olympiad and one of the events had to do with making paper airplanes under similar constraints that would either go for distance or airtime.
Speaker 0: In the paper airplane contest, I almost won for most flips, but I was short by one.
Speaker 0: Mine went up and it went, and they hit the ground.
Speaker 1: I made a pretty good paper airplane to compete that it was going for airtime.
Speaker 1: It would go up in the air and it basically kind of circle very slowly for a long time and eventually come down.
Speaker 1: But the kid who beat me, I still don't know exactly what he made, but the airplane went up and just went across and up and then flipped over and went across the other way and up and flipped over and it did that basically forever.
Speaker 1: It was up so long.
Speaker 1: It was up more than double the time of any other airplane in the competition.
Speaker 1: It was ridiculous.
Speaker 1: And as soon as it ended, he walked over and he tore it up so no one could look at it.
Speaker 0: We should YouTube the world record for that shit.
Speaker 0: Oh wait, he tore it up so no one could look at it.
Speaker 0: Cheating.
Speaker 0: He was definitely cheating.
Speaker 0: He might had a paper clip on that motherfucker or something.
Speaker 1: No judges inspected them ahead of time.
Speaker 1: They didn't want any.
Speaker 0: He could have modified it after the inspection.
Speaker 0: You got it.
Speaker 0: That's why F1.
Speaker 0: they inspect your car before and after the race.
Speaker 1: They inspect it and they hand it back to you and you have to immediately launch it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, uh, slate a hand.
Speaker 1: So here is someone making the 12 a BAC TSR two out of paper and it's pretty off the hook.
Speaker 1: However, warning motherfucker doesn't throw it.
Speaker 1: So go to this video.
Speaker 1: and if you ever doubted that there isn't a community for pretty much everything on the internet, go to this video and sometimes, you know, you'll get into the situation, you're poking around on YouTube and you hit that one video that is tied to a ghetto of the internet where from that point onward, every related video will just be related to that one thing and it's a loop from which you can never escape.
Speaker 0: So here's a video that is super funny and awesome.
Speaker 0: It is an MMA fight of some variety.
Speaker 0: I can't tell which one and on one corner we have a small Japanese MMA guy, maybe 160 something pounds.
Speaker 1: I like those kind of scrappy guys.
Speaker 0: You know, he's lighter.
Speaker 0: He weighs less than me, but he could definitely beat me up cause I have no strength whatsoever and my arm is broken.
Speaker 0: And in the other corner we have Emmanuel Yarbrough who weighs over 600 pounds.
Speaker 0: A basically monster.
Speaker 0: Not as tall as Andre the giant, but I think he weighs more than Andre the giant did.
Speaker 1: I think that was, that's what that mediocre commentator said at one point.
Speaker 0: I think one of the commentators is Bas Rutten.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure, but Bas Rutten is not mediocre person, but the commentary was mediocre.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: I've heard better kind of pretty average anyway, but yeah, you got to watch this.
Speaker 0: This is crazy.
Speaker 0: It's like, it's like rigging King Hippo or it looks like a boss fight.
Speaker 1: Attack on Titan.
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: Attack a ton.
Speaker 1: I got to take that video and just add the attack on Titan theme to and re upload it.
Speaker 0: It might already have been.
Speaker 1: If it hasn't, I'm going to do that before we go to Wildwood.
Speaker 1: I'll.
Speaker 1: it's like a boss fight from one of those walk around and hit people.
Speaker 1: Games are like a resident evil where there's the lumbering monster in the middle.
Speaker 1: That's huge.
Speaker 1: That is slowly coming at you and you got to keep kiting it because as soon as you stop cutting it, it just punches you and say hiding.
Speaker 0: How are you playing?
Speaker 1: the mob is now with that term has been around for a while.
Speaker 0: Uh huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Now I'm, I have tried the mobas.
Speaker 1: Don't like the mobas still.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about the mobas at some point in the future.
Speaker 1: Might talk about them in our bad games, panel of packs.
Speaker 0: Anyway, man met a moment in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: We're back from Australia and we're about to go to packs.
Speaker 1: We're on Monday at noon.
Speaker 1: We're going to be presenting bad games in the theater.
Speaker 0: You should probably, instead of going to bad games, there's like a Robert coup interviewing Mike and Jerry panel, which was originally scheduled as mystery panel, but then they revealed it.
Speaker 1: You know what mystery panel, you know what they're doing?
Speaker 1: They're doing the same shit.
Speaker 1: We used to do a kinetic on with the crab people panel.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: The, well, we can't fill this hole now.
Speaker 1: Let's assume we'll have something good to put there and we're competing with that.
Speaker 1: So that's fine.
Speaker 1: Uh, I think we'll be fine because one, you guys all know what we're going to say in a bad games panel.
Speaker 1: I kind of want people who don't know who we are to show up to this thing.
Speaker 1: They're unlikely to cause they'll be at the anyway now cause that thing can only hold so many people.
Speaker 0: It's also Monday at noon.
Speaker 0: I don't know what Monday is going to be like.
Speaker 1: I think the whole con is sold out.
Speaker 0: So I know anyway, what else is in the meta moment?
Speaker 1: The book club book is very apropos to what is going on in the U S right now.
Speaker 1: And while we always assume that this shit was going down in the U S now there's evidence of it kind of mad that people aren't mad about it.
Speaker 1: So I hope that you guys read this and get mad.
Speaker 0: They weren't mad before.
Speaker 0: Why would they be mad now?
Speaker 1: Maybe because they lack the imagination to really think about what, where this road goes.
Speaker 1: Cause it's not nowhere.
Speaker 1: Uh, other than that, after packs, there's going to be kind of a calm down period.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we'll go to the New York comic con.
Speaker 1: We skipped it last year.
Speaker 1: Kind of done with the New York comic con.
Speaker 0: There's nothing really there that I need to say, but there will be mad.
Speaker 1: I'm doing it quiet.
Speaker 1: Like it's too soon.
Speaker 0: You can hear the mag fest in the distance.
Speaker 0: It's out there.
Speaker 0: It's a few months down the road.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to make a YouTube video on how to do the mag fest.
Speaker 1: Roar at mag fest.
Speaker 1: Do it like video, other people doing it and make the thing because mag fest is going to be off the hook and crazy.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 1: Like it always is.
Speaker 1: We will be there doing our usual thing.
Speaker 0: And so will so well.
Speaker 1: Oh right.
Speaker 1: Machine supremacy or you may incorrectly know them as mock and I supremacy.
Speaker 0: You may, but they have never before in the history of the universe performed music in the United States of America.
Speaker 1: If I had to say one thing to convince you to go to mag fest, it would be this.
Speaker 1: I love packs.
Speaker 1: If you can't tell Scott packs is a big part of every pack since away.
Speaker 1: We flew to fucking Australia to go to packs Australia.
Speaker 0: If mag fest was at the same time as packs Australia with machine supremacy being there, I probably would not have gone to Austria.
Speaker 1: Pax aside, mag fest is the best gaming convention in the Western hemisphere and two packs Australia packs.
Speaker 0: You've never even been to Gen Con.
Speaker 1: Oh, mag fest has a better arcade than packs.
Speaker 1: true to a degree that is painful to behold.
Speaker 1: True.
Speaker 1: Pax has a tiny little room with some arcade machines in it.
Speaker 1: Mag fest has a football field of arcade machines and Scott will tell you, I am not exaggerating at all.
Speaker 0: It's true.
Speaker 1: It is a football field.
Speaker 0: 100% true.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: It is ridiculous.
Speaker 1: Last year they had one of those VR machines that used to be in malls in the nineties.
Speaker 1: Just hanging out.
Speaker 1: It was just hanging out.
Speaker 1: You just fucking walk up and be like, Hey, I want to play this and be like, okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Mag fest is awesome.
Speaker 0: You should check us.
Speaker 0: If you're listening to this podcast, you should know that we're all over the internets and all the places that are on the internets.
Speaker 0: So go to all your favorite internet places, all your social networks and our websites and all those things.
Speaker 0: And if you go to front row crew.com, you can have help finding those places.
Speaker 1: Also, we're slowly uploading videos from Connecticut and packs.
Speaker 0: Australia is one of those places.
Speaker 1: Lots of our old lectures are on YouTube and, and, and, and we're actually doing another show called a geek nights presents shoujo kakame Utena, where we're going through a 39 episode anime and talking about each episode for longer than the episode runs, seems to be moderately popular.
Speaker 1: And if you guys spread it around, the more views it gets, the more likely we are to do it faster.
Speaker 0: Well, we're likely to do it faster after packs prime.
Speaker 1: We're going to try to at least record some episodes before packs prime.
Speaker 1: So we'll see where that goes.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So back to Australia, the land down under.
Speaker 0: There were no poison things, not anywhere near us.
Speaker 0: I didn't even see a big spider.
Speaker 1: The flight in my opinion was easier and better and more pleasant than when I fly to Mumbai.
Speaker 0: Oh, I didn't fly to Mumbai so I can't compare because my flight to Mumbai is one shot.
Speaker 1: There's no layover.
Speaker 1: The layover in LA before I get on the flight to Melbourne actually really helped.
Speaker 0: It didn't help me that one.
Speaker 1: It gave me an accused to walk around a whole very annoying on the way back.
Speaker 0: That layover going through customs, getting my bags and putting them back.
Speaker 0: That was a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: That was a, that was a super pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But two because the time zone change is pretty much the other side of the world.
Speaker 1: Zero jet lag.
Speaker 1: Well, literally I woke up, you know, on the plane and had breakfast and then we got out of the airport and it was like late morning, early afternoon in Melbourne on Thursday and I was fine around 10 o'clock.
Speaker 1: I was like, let's go to bed, went to sleep, woke up the next morning and I was in Australia time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, I set my watch when I got on the plane to Australia time and then the plane seemed to be operating on Australia time cause they gave us dinner like right away when it was dinner time in Australia.
Speaker 1: That's the secret.
Speaker 1: And I tweeted this in a bunch of people.
Speaker 0: I even tweeted and then they gave us breakfast during his breakfast time in Australia.
Speaker 1: All of you who experienced jet lag, I have so simple advice that will save you.
Speaker 1: Do whatever the plane is telling you to do.
Speaker 1: The airlines have this shit figured out.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And then like after dinner I did some stuff for a little bit and then I went to bed and then I woke up and it was breakfast.
Speaker 1: You're on a plane and they serve dinner.
Speaker 1: Eat it.
Speaker 1: No matter what, if they bring you food, eat all of it.
Speaker 1: If they ask you if you want water, you say yes, you drink that goddamn water.
Speaker 1: If the lights are on, you stay awake.
Speaker 1: If the lights are off, you go to sleep.
Speaker 0: They made everyone close all the windows.
Speaker 0: They didn't let you control your little plane window.
Speaker 1: If the lights go off and you can't sleep, close your eyes.
Speaker 1: Just lay there anyway.
Speaker 0: That's what I did.
Speaker 0: I was because even though I could sleep, I was tired.
Speaker 0: I basically have trouble sleeping, sitting up, even reclining the stupid.
Speaker 1: I have no trouble with that reclining chair.
Speaker 0: Thank glob.
Speaker 0: So I was just sort of, you know, uncomfortably drifting in and out, but that was, you know, it was shitty sleep, but it was sleep and I was rested when we landed and I did the same thing on the way back.
Speaker 1: So Melbourne airport, whatever, all normal.
Speaker 0: It's the first time for their gigantic duty free.
Speaker 1: Uh, that was not a gigantic duty.
Speaker 0: That's the biggest duty free I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: That was an average size duty free.
Speaker 0: It was like they make you, as you're walking to the gate, you have to go through this incredible duty free like Wonderland.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Fly through a Tokyo or something sometime or go to Istanbul.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: But it's like, why would anyone buy this full priced garbage?
Speaker 1: So we landed and we got a bunch of Australian money from an ATM.
Speaker 0: Australian money is awesome.
Speaker 1: Australian money is the best one.
Speaker 1: The default bill is the 50 not the 20 to.
Speaker 0: the bills are different colors and different sizes for blind people.
Speaker 1: Three.
Speaker 1: They have a really cool, clear part on them and every vending machine and everything takes cash and it just works every time.
Speaker 1: The coins are great because they don't have pennies and while they're not having pennies is great, but the coins are flawed.
Speaker 1: I don't think they're flawed.
Speaker 0: They're okay.
Speaker 0: So here's the one thing, right?
Speaker 1: I think they're in fact the opposite.
Speaker 0: It's good that the gold money is worth something and the silver money isn't right.
Speaker 0: So you can easily separate worthwhile money from unworthwhile money.
Speaker 0: But why is the $2 coins smaller than the $1?
Speaker 0: easily?
Speaker 1: Because you're going to carry a lot more one and $2 coins around because they're useful.
Speaker 1: I need any big coins that you get by accident.
Speaker 1: You leave his tip the next chance you get.
Speaker 0: But I'm saying, why were the twos smaller than the one?
Speaker 1: Because you're going to carry more of them than you are ones because that they're, that the smallest bill is a five and they don't even seem to ever give you fives and change.
Speaker 1: They just give you a pile of those coins and you know what?
Speaker 1: I did an audit of my pockets because this is an issue that really bothers me.
Speaker 1: The fact that the?
Speaker 1: u s still has pennies.
Speaker 1: One, I noted that pretty much because tax is already included and everything, prices are proud into the nearest dollar pretty much everywhere.
Speaker 1: Maybe the nearest 50 cents.
Speaker 0: There was one or two times or something.
Speaker 0: It was like nine 95 and I was seriously 95.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen that in this country anywhere.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: I almost never saw, I got maybe three or four nickels.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, the tax is built in.
Speaker 0: So I got a nickel and change and I was like, really?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Those are the only times they got nickels.
Speaker 1: But my car, my pockets had fewer coins in them on average that were annoying than I have in the u s.
Speaker 0: I had a lot of coins in my pockets that were annoying, but I then I would just dump them all out because they were these worthless silver coins.
Speaker 1: I didn't get a lot of those silver coins because I left them for tips everywhere.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the $2 coin, the u s should get rid of the one and $2 bill, replace them in one and $2 coins, get rid of the quarter and replace it with the much superior 20 cent coin.
Speaker 1: That 20 cent coin was so much better.
Speaker 0: I didn't use any, any silver coin at any point to pay for anything.
Speaker 1: I use my 50 cent coins a lot too.
Speaker 0: I took a stack of 50 cent coins and use them to buy.
Speaker 0: Uh, they came out to a bunch of dollars when I was at the base.
Speaker 0: I put all those useless coins in a bag and I took them with me home.
Speaker 0: And when I was at the airport about to leave, I took all the big 50 cent coins and bought like two candy bars.
Speaker 0: And I was like, Oh, got rid of those big fuckers.
Speaker 1: So we got out of the airport, we check in our hotel, we wander around Melbourne and we decide that we want to get some food and we walk around.
Speaker 1: And the of meat raft in pastry bread.
Speaker 0: That was most of the food.
Speaker 0: That was the default food.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The secondary default food was the sandwich.
Speaker 1: And I got to tell you, we live in New York, which is while not the king of submarine sandwiches, cause we don't have them.
Speaker 0: The king of other sandwiches, normal sandwiches.
Speaker 1: New York was until this point, the king, but Australia or at least Melbourne, my hat is off to you.
Speaker 0: Well, okay.
Speaker 0: So if you're talking like Carnegie deli, it's like, no, my hat is not off to you.
Speaker 0: You didn't have a competition for that.
Speaker 0: But if you're talking about the average place, right, you just walk into a deli or a cafe and they have that little refer display case refrigerator that has sandwiches in it.
Speaker 0: Usually in New York, when you go to one of those places that has a display case refrigerator with sandwiches in it, it's all the same paninis, the same wraps, the same sandwiches.
Speaker 0: They all look really bland and mediocre.
Speaker 0: Like, yeah, I could eat that.
Speaker 0: It won't poison me.
Speaker 0: It will taste fine, but it is not something I want or would actively seek out.
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: I ate way.
Speaker 1: I had a lot of sandwiches just because they look so good.
Speaker 0: Almost every place I saw with the display case, refrigerator had sandwiches that were obviously made at that place.
Speaker 0: They were using a high quality bread and high quality ingredients and a clever and interesting flavorful combination.
Speaker 1: Those sandwiches were so good, but they got nothing.
Speaker 1: They looked like restaurant presentable, but I didn't eat as many of them as I wanted to because I kept getting meat pies instead.
Speaker 0: I ate, tried to eat a nice mix of things.
Speaker 1: But I got different kinds of meat pies and I was amazed.
Speaker 0: I had a curry one and I had a lamb.
Speaker 1: There were pasties.
Speaker 1: I vote the pasties seem to exist in a small number of places in the world, a small number of places in the United Kingdom, Albion, the Northern upper peninsula of Michigan, and apparently all of Eastern Australia.
Speaker 1: pasties.
Speaker 1: Look them up.
Speaker 1: They're delicious.
Speaker 1: You might've heard of them in Neil Gaiman's, uh, American gods.
Speaker 1: That's where most people seem to learn.
Speaker 1: the pasties exist.
Speaker 1: But, uh, all that food stuff aside, we decided to eat at this pub.
Speaker 1: They're like, Oh, we'll get some pub food.
Speaker 1: And there was this prefix.
Speaker 1: that looked pretty good.
Speaker 1: And this is when our adventure began.
Speaker 1: This was the first point where we ran into culture that was different from our own.
Speaker 1: There was a surreal experience.
Speaker 1: We only had one other surreal experience the whole time we were in this country.
Speaker 1: So we go into this pub and we walk in and it's not really clear where to go.
Speaker 1: There's like a bar area and there's some people hanging out.
Speaker 0: Well, it's sort of a weird in between lunch and dinner time.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But there was a prefix thing like advertised outside.
Speaker 1: It was pretty cheap and it looked good.
Speaker 1: It was like pub food, like bangers and mash and that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: And we kind of look around and go, there's one bartender.
Speaker 1: So like, yeah, how do we get food?
Speaker 1: And she's like, Oh, you can sit up here or you can sit downstairs.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay, so go to the middle floor where it seems like there's an actual restaurant and it's basically dark and closed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we go even lower and it's a basically, it's really a bar.
Speaker 1: There's just a bar down there and there's a bunch of guys hanging out with the bartender.
Speaker 0: It was so stereotypical, like a thing you would see on TV, like people hanging out behind around the bar, talking wise.
Speaker 1: This is a weekday during the day after lunchtime, but long before anyone gets off work.
Speaker 1: And there's a bunch of guys like 10 of them just hanging out, doing basically reenacting a scene from a movie that would be going on in the background.
Speaker 1: So kind of walk in and they all stop and look at us like, and then they go back to their business.
Speaker 1: We sit down for a while.
Speaker 1: It's not obvious how to order food.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They asked us like, you know, we're like, should we go upstairs?
Speaker 0: Like, well, you shouldn't go to the middle cause that's closed.
Speaker 0: They're like, all right.
Speaker 0: So you sit down at a table and no one really talks to us or anything and North tries to serve us.
Speaker 0: So like, Oh yes, this isn't how you get food.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: There were no menus or anything.
Speaker 1: So eventually we just kind of walk back upstairs and go to the regular part and we'd go to the bartender and ask for food.
Speaker 0: Cause no one came to ask us.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: And then after that it was fine.
Speaker 1: So we get our good food, we're eating it.
Speaker 1: There's people hanging out and there's a mix of people in this bar, like a surprising panoply of people.
Speaker 1: And then a panoply, a gentleman, not a panoply, a gentleman, an elderly gentleman where dressed in that sort of shabby but fine way.
Speaker 1: Like he was wearing fine clothes that just looked like they were kind of old and worn out.
Speaker 1: And you're wearing like a jacket and he walks in and he bows to everyone and sits down at the piano.
Speaker 1: that's there and just starts singing the kind of song.
Speaker 0: Well he asked the bartender if he could play the piano, if it would be all right.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And she was like, you know, no worries.
Speaker 1: Go for it.
Speaker 1: And he just starts playing at the piano and then he sings what I can only describe as a British pub song.
Speaker 0: I don't even remember the song, but it was weird.
Speaker 1: It was one of those songs that like you'd expect someone to sing and a bunch of people are singing along with them around a piano in a movie from the twenties.
Speaker 1: And then he stops playing and he gets up, bows to everyone and just walks out.
Speaker 0: He said something to us about like, you know, he was like a performer and his stage is the street or something like that.
Speaker 1: He kind of sounded like James Mason.
Speaker 0: He was, you know, a weird eccentric kind of guy.
Speaker 1: And all this just kind of happened while we were trying to get lunch in this pub.
Speaker 1: And then we get our meal, we leave like a $20 tip and we go to walk out and the bartender's like, Whoa, what are you guys doing?
Speaker 0: Come back here.
Speaker 0: We're like, what?
Speaker 1: There's no tipping in this country.
Speaker 1: I am paid very well.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Apparently ever the minimum wage is really good there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: For service people it's like 20, 25 bucks an hour.
Speaker 0: Well, it's a bit, you know, it varies.
Speaker 1: service like, like that kind of hospitality.
Speaker 0: It's some number.
Speaker 0: Apparently it goes, it can be like, if you're a high school kid, it can be way low, like $8.
Speaker 0: And if you're, you know, have, you know, as if you have more and more years of working, it goes up and up and it can be like, I think it's around 16, $18, something like that.
Speaker 1: But it seems like all the bartenders and waiters and people make 20, 25 bucks an hour.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: People are getting paid real money there, so they don't need your tip.
Speaker 0: And there's also things like reward wages, which I still can't figure out what those are.
Speaker 1: And also they were almost as complicated as the Mikey card.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There's also concessions, which is like, if you, I guess if you're old or infirm or concessions, I figured out pretty quick were oldenings.
Speaker 0: It's, you know, social security or something, but it's like, they would always be on everything, but have concession prices.
Speaker 0: It'd be like, Oh, you want to buy this?
Speaker 0: It costs 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: concessions, six bucks.
Speaker 0: And it's like, what old people just, you know, seniors, it's like senior citizen discount, social security, et cetera.
Speaker 1: This is why I said the money is fine.
Speaker 1: Cause what did she say?
Speaker 1: She said, you leave a tip of pretty much all your silver money.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So all your 50 cent and 20 cent coins, you just leave them.
Speaker 1: And that's, that's the tip you leave.
Speaker 1: And while we're standing there, this old gentleman at the bar is like, Americans, eh?
Speaker 1: And we're like, you couldn't tell from our accent.
Speaker 0: He was like, you'll give yourself away.
Speaker 0: tipping like that is for tourists tipping like that.
Speaker 0: I'm like, Oh, our accents won't give us away.
Speaker 1: And then we were like, so what's the, what's the only thing we could do to offend people here?
Speaker 1: And there were, and the guy was basically like, try to do an Australian accent.
Speaker 0: That's not how it was.
Speaker 0: I said, what should I do?
Speaker 0: Should I fake an Australian accent?
Speaker 0: And he was like, no, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: Good day.
Speaker 1: Good day.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Good on you.
Speaker 0: You know, whatever.
Speaker 0: I never heard anyone say that.
Speaker 1: I heard several people say it.
Speaker 1: Enforcers seem to be saying it a lot.
Speaker 0: They would say no worries.
Speaker 1: That's got to be like, Oh, don't worry.
Speaker 1: I got this up.
Speaker 1: And they gotta be like it on you.
Speaker 1: I helped, uh, I helped coo move a chair at one point just cause he was trying to move a chair and he couldn't get it unlocked.
Speaker 1: And some enforcer came over and like was trying to help too.
Speaker 1: And he saw me and he was like, Oh, good on you.
Speaker 1: And then he walked away.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so yeah, then we went to packs, then we went to bags, bags, bags, bags, bags, well, no way you missed a very important part.
Speaker 0: So we spent the other part of that day walking around, just walking around the city, walking around, looking around.
Speaker 1: Scott almost got hit by a car immediately because he looked right instead of left to jaywalk.
Speaker 0: That happens.
Speaker 1: Also, people don't really jaywalk in Melbourne.
Speaker 1: And the reason for this is because cars are actually going pretty fucking fast there because traffic's not that bad.
Speaker 0: And also the street lights does super help for the blind there.
Speaker 0: So like if I'm blind, I'm moving there.
Speaker 0: Cause every street, like the buttons to tell you when to cross and the lights and the Tokyo's like that.
Speaker 1: So is Istanbul.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: The bumps on the sidewalk.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Way better than in New York.
Speaker 1: So is fucking Mumbai.
Speaker 0: But I got way used to it because I was busy using the noise to tell me when to cross the street and not the lights.
Speaker 0: And I was worried that I would get messed up when I came back to New York.
Speaker 1: I realized the reason I wouldn't mess this up is because we don't look at the lights in the U S either.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: But yeah, you can't, it's actually kind of dangerous to jaywalk.
Speaker 0: Also there's trams like actual trends, all these pictures everywhere that you're like rhinoceroses.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: That rhino picture was the best.
Speaker 0: And it's basically trying to say like, look, the tram weighs as much as like a bunch of rhinos.
Speaker 0: Don't get hit by it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So mass transit in Melbourne, they don't have a subway, which kind of sort of did.
Speaker 1: The subway has five stations.
Speaker 0: It's basically, from what I could tell, it wasn't used because they're building it right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's supposed, it's going to connect all the major transit centers inside of the city, apparently.
Speaker 1: And they've got light rail and they've got trams.
Speaker 1: The trams do not replace subways of New York.
Speaker 1: had these trams into the subways to have those trams.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Those trams, each tram in a fully loaded situation holds fewer people than one subway car.
Speaker 0: Correct.
Speaker 1: But they run pretty much constantly and they're really good.
Speaker 1: My take on these trams is that they do not replace real mass transit.
Speaker 1: New York needs the subway, but they augment mass transit because they replace walking.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So a lot of times, so for example, the S subway that could be replaced by a tram, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's the, you can just cross town walking.
Speaker 0: So it's like if you're walking and you have to walk three blocks from the subway station to a place, well you would start walking.
Speaker 0: And if a tram happened to pass, you would get on it and then it would take you the rest of the way.
Speaker 0: And I think, you know, based on another piece of evidence, everyone there walked really slow.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: You people walk slower than Tennesseans.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So the fact that they walk so slow, I think is because the tram is augmenting their walking or as New Yorkers walk fast because we don't have a train.
Speaker 1: Just about anything.
Speaker 1: If New York city implemented trams going cross town in Manhattan only just back and forth 24 seven and in that nebulous area between Queens and Brooklyn, like that area, if there were trams just going up and down every street there, that would make New York city the best ever beyond
Speaker 0: what it already is.
Speaker 0: You know what would be so great about that is they see all the slow people would get on those and I would walk and the sidewalk could be empty.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I could get there even faster just by walking.
Speaker 1: So we wanted to use the tram and we'd been warned ahead of time that you can't like, it's not like New York where there's a thing to buy a Metro card in every subway station.
Speaker 1: You can't buy Mikey cards basically anywhere you could get on a tram or a train.
Speaker 0: There were a couple of tram stations that had the machine, but not many in seven 11.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You buy them in seven 11 or you buy them at like the huge stations.
Speaker 1: Now I thought, because I have an anecdote from our friend Adam where, you know, he had a friend from New York that has a real subway system and that friend was visiting him in DC and he told him, take the red line to station named X. And the friend was like, what do you mean?
Speaker 1: red line, like uptown downtown?
Speaker 1: What, like, what?
Speaker 1: And I was like, are you seriously?
Speaker 1: You're from New York.
Speaker 1: If you look at a map at any station in DC, it will look like the New York subway map drawn with crayons.
Speaker 1: You'll figure it out.
Speaker 0: The DC Metro is Fisher Price first subway.
Speaker 1: Baby's first subway.
Speaker 1: So I figured, and Scott also figured we're New Yorkers.
Speaker 1: I'm looking at my Metro card right now.
Speaker 1: How hard can this other modern urban centers transit system be to figure out?
Speaker 1: And we stood there.
Speaker 0: I still don't 100% know all the rules of it.
Speaker 1: I feel like sometimes I should touch off, but not always.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So here's the deal with it, right?
Speaker 0: Is they've sort of done something that the New York didn't do in New York.
Speaker 0: A Metro card will only get you on a bus or a subway.
Speaker 1: It won't get you on Metro North, the light rail.
Speaker 1: It won't get you on special express bus.
Speaker 0: It won't get you on the path.
Speaker 0: It won't get you on air train.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't.
Speaker 0: Well, it will get you on air train, but only if you have dollars, not if you have infinite swipes.
Speaker 1: Now they gave you a way to put dollars on an infinite swipe card.
Speaker 0: Did they?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I didn't know.
Speaker 1: that's putting an infinite swipe card and you can add cash to it.
Speaker 0: Oh, nice.
Speaker 0: I didn't know that.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So, but anyway, uh, but yeah, in New York, you don't use the Metro card for everything.
Speaker 0: You just use it for a certain set of things.
Speaker 0: And because you only use it for a certain set of things, it's really simple.
Speaker 0: You swipe it and you're in the system.
Speaker 0: You can now ride as much as you want until you leave the system.
Speaker 0: If you want to get back into the subway, you swipe, and it's always the same price to swipe.
Speaker 0: And no matter how far you go, no matter where you go, it's just pay to get in.
Speaker 0: And when you leave, you pay to get back in.
Speaker 1: Now I'm reasonably okay with the alternate system.
Speaker 1: Some cities have a, you put your card in, you go in and then you swipe again on your way out.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Like DC Metro, you put a ticket in the thing.
Speaker 0: It lets you in.
Speaker 0: then on your way out, you can't get out.
Speaker 0: You put your ticket in the thing.
Speaker 0: It sucks it in and it lets you out.
Speaker 0: So it's, it's, you can't not figure out how it works.
Speaker 0: You buy a ticket to where you're going and the turnstiles force you to obey the system.
Speaker 1: So we stare at this thing.
Speaker 1: We can't figure it out for the life of us.
Speaker 0: So finally is Mikey pass and Mikey cash.
Speaker 1: I know when I go to a machine, I'm like, all right.
Speaker 1: And it gave me two options.
Speaker 1: Top up my Mikey card.
Speaker 1: I didn't have a Mikey card yet or buy a Mikey pass.
Speaker 1: And it was obvious I didn't want the Mikey pass, but I hit.
Speaker 1: top up, but I didn't have a Mikey card to put in.
Speaker 1: So we went to this hub in the main train station.
Speaker 1: We were staying right across from a Southern cross.
Speaker 1: I was thinking about a dimension century Southern cross.
Speaker 1: I was thinking of that every time we walked past entered or exited that station or so 10, no Ken.
Speaker 1: So we go into this PT hub, which is like the place where tourists and people can get help.
Speaker 1: And one, there were other people in there.
Speaker 1: Some of whom were native Melburnians, or at least Australians there for packs who themselves could not figure out the fucking Mikey card.
Speaker 1: Apparently it's relatively new.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Here's how it works is?
Speaker 0: it's basically, it's a card you use to go anywhere, any kind of the transportation, the trams, the trains, the trains that go really far, the trains that don't go so far.
Speaker 0: They all use the Mikey card, fucking everything uses it.
Speaker 0: So because everything uses it, but not everything is the same price, right?
Speaker 0: They have to actually sort of gauge it differently.
Speaker 0: So from what I could tell is we never left zone one, zone one is the city.
Speaker 1: It was possible to leave zone one because there's like three tram stops that are outside of.
Speaker 0: zone two is commuting, right?
Speaker 0: So we weren't going anywhere.
Speaker 0: Commuters are from in the suburbs.
Speaker 0: So we were in zone one.
Speaker 0: So in zone one, we paid three 50 to the Australian dollars to, to go around for a two hour time limit.
Speaker 0: We could do as much as we wanted.
Speaker 0: And then it would automatically sort of undo us after two hours.
Speaker 0: And then we would pay three 50 for another two hours, but there was a limit of $7 a day.
Speaker 0: So once we paid $7 a day, we could go around in zone one, unlimitedly on pretty much anything.
Speaker 1: Now you can touch on, which is like swiping to get on a swipe.
Speaker 0: You just sort of hold it near the thing and you can touch off when you get off.
Speaker 1: But people we talked to kept giving us different advice on when you should and should not touch off.
Speaker 0: I saw Australia.
Speaker 0: It's it's an honor system.
Speaker 0: It wasn't a turnstile.
Speaker 0: So I saw people getting on and getting off without doing anything.
Speaker 0: I saw people religiously tapping, touching on and off at every single, I saw most people touched on, but did not touch off.
Speaker 0: I saw a lot of people doing that, but someone else told me, yeah, you should touch off because if you don't, then it assumes you went the farthest you could possibly go.
Speaker 1: I had another person tell me that you shouldn't always touch off.
Speaker 1: And he tried to give me all these examples of times when touching off costs you more money.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And like, I went to refill my Mikey card at one point and it showed that I was still touched on somewhere, I guess.
Speaker 1: I really never quite understood it.
Speaker 1: And, uh, by the end of the trip, because I'd been using it sub optimally, I ran out my money and I kinda just kept riding for the rest of the day without paying money without paying more money.
Speaker 0: I think I had like $3 left.
Speaker 1: I didn't balance of negative $3 on mine.
Speaker 0: I didn't know you can get to negative.
Speaker 1: It appears that once you go over the first time, it says, instead of like touched on, it says like top up your Mikey card.
Speaker 1: So I guess they give you a credit.
Speaker 0: So then if you try to fill that card, you would have to put in the money and even more money.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And it costs money for the Mikey cards.
Speaker 0: Cards are anonymous.
Speaker 1: So why not just throw the card out because it costs $6 to get a new card.
Speaker 0: So just go for credit.
Speaker 0: Oh, blower than $6.
Speaker 1: I think the maximum credit you could get is like $3 and change because you touched on once.
Speaker 0: So you're better off refilling it than buying a new one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Clever girl.
Speaker 0: So yeah, we steal someone else's card from the ground.
Speaker 0: Point is we couldn't figure it out and neither could most of the Australians we talked to, but they did tell us that apparently even the Mikey system as messed up as it was, was still better than other cities.
Speaker 0: Like they told me that in Sydney, you have to buy a paper ticket for everything to go from point a to point B con like everything is Metro North or whatever.
Speaker 0: And that's not good.
Speaker 1: Istanbul is plastic tokens.
Speaker 0: That's cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I like that.
Speaker 1: That's because you buy tokens.
Speaker 1: They were super cheap.
Speaker 0: It's like, that's like the old New York city tolls used to have tone.
Speaker 1: I kept a couple of them.
Speaker 1: It basically costs like a quarter to ride the subway in Istanbul.
Speaker 0: The thing with the toll tokens is like, if you had a token, it'd be like easy pass.
Speaker 0: You drive up, you throw one token and you drive, you keep going forward.
Speaker 0: You don't have to make change.
Speaker 0: But if you needed to buy tokens, you basically stop at the toll hand, the guy at 20, he would give you like a fistful of tokens in a role, and then you would drive away.
Speaker 0: And that would be cause long lines of the tolls.
Speaker 0: Easy passes way better.
Speaker 0: They had an easy pass kind of system there.
Speaker 0: It was just called something else like E tag.
Speaker 0: It worked.
Speaker 0: I think it made a little noise whenever it charged you money and they didn't actually have like booths.
Speaker 0: It just sort of charged you money as you went down the highway.
Speaker 1: So the trams worked fine as like local mass transit.
Speaker 1: We used them the whole time and they were pretty much great.
Speaker 1: It was nice being in a modern city.
Speaker 1: I skip around a bit food.
Speaker 1: It was interesting that food, so Asian food, there is a Chinatown in Melbourne, which was about one third Japanese, one third Chinese, one third Korean, but then interspersed around all of those zones was pretty much every other Asian nation.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's a lot of Asian stuff there cause it's really close to Asia and there's a lot of Asian people there.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And we noticed that there were teppanyaki and hibachi restaurants and they were actually called teppanyaki and hibachi appropriately as opposed to the U S where everything is called hibachi, even if it is teppanyaki.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So we decided one night that we haven't had teppanyaki in a long as we Googled for the best teppanyaki in the city of Melbourne and we went to it and it was really expensive.
Speaker 0: It was really good and really good.
Speaker 0: And what I thought, but it wasn't as expensive as it appeared because remember the, between the built-in tax and the no tipping in restaurants, cause they're getting paid well, but it raises the, obviously that causes the prices of menu items to be raised.
Speaker 0: Like it says $70 on a menu for like some of the things, but really that's the equivalent of like a 45 $50 meal in the U S right.
Speaker 0: So expensive.
Speaker 0: Yes, but not as crazy expensive, like a $70 meal in the U S. I would've been like, hell no.
Speaker 1: So we had a pack shirt on and the girl who's seated is like, Oh, you went to packs.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: I was there to packs is the best.
Speaker 1: And that, that played out many times throughout our trip around the city.
Speaker 1: People went to packs and new packs and we're totally chill.
Speaker 1: And we kept meeting packs, people all around the city and like gaming shops and on the street.
Speaker 1: And even someone we met at the con and hung out with, we tweeted like, Hey, we're going to go eat here.
Speaker 1: He just showed up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Cool guy.
Speaker 0: Hang out with us.
Speaker 0: I think it's Paul, right?
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Cool guy.
Speaker 0: Cool guy.
Speaker 1: And uh, yeah.
Speaker 1: The other thing I noticed kind of generally, he's not good at hive though.
Speaker 0: He's got to improve his hive skills.
Speaker 1: All the Australians we talked to, even people who didn't have great jobs had a lot more disposable income than the average American.
Speaker 0: Well, things are more expensive, so I hope they did.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But in terms of their purchasing power, like people who, if the equivalent socioeconomic class in the U S at a con would go eat McDonald's because they could literally cannot afford to eat out fancy every night.
Speaker 1: Those equivalent people with equivalent jobs in Australia appeared to be able to eat out at nice restaurants in a downtown fancy city.
Speaker 0: So, you know, we didn't really go to areas where poor people live.
Speaker 1: Oh, I did run in and I just kind of kept an eye out and the restaurants everywhere were nicer than the equivalent restaurant would be in the U S nice.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: That was my experience.
Speaker 1: I have a ton of pictures from a lot of the kind of like normal residential, like the equivalent of far out Queens places.
Speaker 0: Something else that really surprised me in Australia was how big the queen is.
Speaker 0: She is kind of a big deal.
Speaker 1: We're walking around the botanical garden on Thursday and Scott keeps seeing this building.
Speaker 0: Well, we saw, okay, so in the distance we see this castle basically tower with a flag and I'm like, whatever that is, it looks touristy.
Speaker 0: It looks the kind of place that Australians won't go.
Speaker 0: It also looks like a castle.
Speaker 0: I definitely want to check that the fuck out cause castle.
Speaker 1: So we kind of keep it as a vague.
Speaker 0: I know that whatever's there isn't very old cause it's Australia, but I know that it looks like a cast.
Speaker 1: So we basically wander all these gardens with the idea that let's slowly try to edge your way toward this thing.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of stuff between us and that that looks cool.
Speaker 0: We saw giant amphitheater that was pretty sweet and awesome pictures of birds and flowers and all kinds of cool stuff in the park.
Speaker 1: People hanging out actually get closer to this thing.
Speaker 0: There's a fence in the way and it's like, huh, why, why is this closed?
Speaker 0: That looks like a thing we should be able to get into.
Speaker 0: The entrance must be on the other side.
Speaker 0: So I see an Australian guy walking around in the park.
Speaker 0: It was pretty quiet cause it was a Thursday weekday during the day in a giant park.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, Hey, uh, do you know if I can get in there?
Speaker 0: How I can get in here?
Speaker 0: He's like, Oh no, the governor, that's the governor's house.
Speaker 0: You can't get in there.
Speaker 0: Maybe twice a year.
Speaker 0: They open it for like one day for people to go.
Speaker 1: I believe at this point you were thinking what elected governor.
Speaker 0: I was thinking the governor of Victoria, the person who was elected by the people to be the governor of Victoria, sort of like Gracie mansion, the mayor lives in, in New York.
Speaker 1: Then we realized this is governor in the Sid Myers pirates.
Speaker 0: Governor governor, as in like, please, sir, may I have a letter of Mark and go privateering to bring back riches for you governor.
Speaker 0: And I was like, now I really fucking want to go in there and you can't, can't go in there.
Speaker 0: I'm going to go in there.
Speaker 0: I don't care what kind of international incident is going to happen.
Speaker 0: Well, later, later we went into the, I'm going to figure out like the day it's open and that's when I'm going to go to Australia.
Speaker 1: So we went to the tallest building in Melbourne, you know, God, we got to do the touristy stuff and see those things.
Speaker 1: because you like in New York city, you say, Oh, the Eureka tower is touristy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's touristy.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: It's also a fucking amazing view.
Speaker 1: All the big tall buildings in New York have great views of the city and it is kind of worth it.
Speaker 1: So we went and we got a great view of the whole city.
Speaker 1: They had this thing called the edge, the edge.
Speaker 1: You could pay extra money to stand in a glass cube that moved like 10 feet out and back in.
Speaker 0: It was really, really late.
Speaker 0: They didn't let you take cameras in there.
Speaker 0: We didn't do it.
Speaker 0: Obviously.
Speaker 0: It was really stupid.
Speaker 1: Like we're out there, like on this balcony, hanging out with Aaron C and a bunch of enforcers.
Speaker 1: And then we look and we see the edge just kind of popped out next to us.
Speaker 1: A bunch of kind of bored looking people were standing in there.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: They paid 12 bucks for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Each.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: And we could see the governor's house and I think we could have hang glided their base jumped there.
Speaker 0: Something like that.
Speaker 0: Apparently the previous tallest building in Melbourne, they told us a story that the someone put a restaurant at the top and then some people went to that restaurant, got drinks at the bar and then base jumped off the balcony, which is awesome.
Speaker 1: Oh, here's the story for daredevils.
Speaker 1: Do a base jump from Rialto towers after cocktails.
Speaker 1: I knew of this story because it's one of those things that was on FARC and you just knew about it a long time ago, but like it was in a collection of like crazy cool things people have done.
Speaker 1: And I didn't realize it was in Melbourne.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And that it was right there that it happened.
Speaker 1: And I did not realize the full extent of what these awesome dudes did.
Speaker 0: Awesome people, heroes.
Speaker 1: This is the awesomest thing.
Speaker 1: I encourage more people to do things like this.
Speaker 0: I do as well.
Speaker 0: Even if it gets you arrested, which it probably will in the U S it would probably get you really arrested.
Speaker 1: If you get arrested after successfully base jumping, that is a badge of honor.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's like an achievement.
Speaker 0: Got arrested, did a base jump that got you arrested.
Speaker 1: I would put that on my resume.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, it was arrested.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Base jumping off the empire state building.
Speaker 0: I would also put that on my resume.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of thing.
Speaker 1: It's one of those situations where the judge should, yes, it was illegal.
Speaker 1: Here's your punishment.
Speaker 1: I'm also going to high five you before they put the handcuffs on.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Uh, trying to think.
Speaker 1: So, uh, we'll jump around.
Speaker 1: We went to an Aussie rules football guy.
Speaker 1: I almost want to do it.
Speaker 0: That was on Friday.
Speaker 1: I feel like we should do a Tuesday show on Aussie rules football.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Let's just say that it was sort of a combination of professional sports and college sports in the way the fans reacted, the way the game is played.
Speaker 0: I like certain aspects of the game and I also dislike certain aspects of the game.
Speaker 1: I enjoyed it a thousand times more than any soccer game I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: That's your, I would be a fan of this sport.
Speaker 0: Were it on, uh, you know, TV in the U S in Jersey, because I love, did you actually buy one?
Speaker 1: They're hard as bucks.
Speaker 1: So I got it.
Speaker 0: That was a lot.
Speaker 0: I didn't buy one because it's too much money, dude.
Speaker 1: I spent like Essendon.
Speaker 0: I was for that.
Speaker 0: They got their asses kicked.
Speaker 1: It's got, I spent like a hundred and I spent like $200 in my red wings.
Speaker 1: Jersey.
Speaker 0: So seven bucks for I was, I was for them simply for the fact that a, they seem to be the home team and B their logo is way awesome.
Speaker 0: It's just like a fucking stealth bomber.
Speaker 0: It's like, Oh fuck.
Speaker 1: I will say this about AFL and about footy fans.
Speaker 1: The game is called footy.
Speaker 1: I used to kind of think when people said footy, they meant soccer.
Speaker 1: No footy is AFL specifically.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's way easier to say footy than say to AFL or Aussie football.
Speaker 1: We went to pretty much the craziest game that like would happen ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Basically there were three, we knew we wanted to go to a game and there were three games happening during the time we were there.
Speaker 0: And we asked around and people said, well, look, those two games, one of them's at one stadium.
Speaker 0: One's at the other, but those are the shit games.
Speaker 0: That's like Mets versus crappy other crappy team, right?
Speaker 0: You don't want to see those games like all right.
Speaker 1: Lions Brown.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: One of the games was at the Melbourne cricket grounds, which is this huge hundred thousand seat stadium, but that was one of the crappy ones.
Speaker 0: There was also a soccer game.
Speaker 0: Liverpool was in town to play Melbourne in soccer, every hotel in the entire goddamn city.
Speaker 0: So we left town that day because once he found out about that was happening, the concierge was like, yo dog.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There's going to be no hotels in the cities.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Get out.
Speaker 0: So that was also the Melbourne cricket grounds.
Speaker 0: So I kind of wanted to go to the Melbourne cricket grounds because that was the superior arena, the superior field stadium.
Speaker 0: But we ended up going to Eddie hot stadium where the superior game was happening, which is Hawks Essendon, which are the two top teams.
Speaker 0: So that's like fricking seeing, you know, the super bowl, but it wasn't, it was a regular, it was a regular season game between the number one team and the number two team.
Speaker 0: So we went to that one.
Speaker 1: It was great.
Speaker 1: I want to make the one cultural thing, even though it was a blowout, the cultural observation.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We rooted for the wrong goddamn team.
Speaker 1: That's for the cultural observations I want to make about it.
Speaker 1: in this show, as opposed to the separate show we'll do on footy one, you can bet on fucking everything.
Speaker 1: Gambling is just totally legal.
Speaker 0: Gambling was legal everywhere in Melbourne.
Speaker 1: So Scott and I were at the game.
Speaker 1: I was like, Hey, I'm going to go see if I can place a bet on the game.
Speaker 1: And I go to the kiosk.
Speaker 1: You can bet on everything.
Speaker 1: It was like first team to 20 points, first team to 30 points, first team to this spread point spread in either direction, number of behinds.
Speaker 1: Like you could bet on anything.
Speaker 1: It was crazy.
Speaker 0: I would not bet on that.
Speaker 0: and horse racing.
Speaker 0: I saw horse racing everywhere with betting everywhere.
Speaker 0: It's like we used to have OTV and it's gone.
Speaker 0: Now they have, what was it called?
Speaker 0: It was like you, Oh, Tats.
Speaker 0: No, Tats was the lottery, the private lottery, private lottery.
Speaker 0: I think it was UBT or something that was like the, the way to bet on sports from pretty much anywhere.
Speaker 0: And it was like, Whoa, there is betting all over the place.
Speaker 1: They rolled up a truck that just had a horse racing betting outside the stadium for Eddie out of stadium for the footy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So the other thing I want to point out is that at first, if I had stayed for the first quarter of this game and then left, I would have told you that fans of footy are surprisingly genteel because they are the, a lot of the people were old ladies route that they've been rooting for this team their entire lives.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: And it was a very interesting anti hooliganism culture.
Speaker 1: Like footy fans seem to take pride in the fact that there's very little hooliganism and they really look down on it and they really pride themselves in not being soccer fans with all their bullshit too.
Speaker 1: The, uh, the people were shouting things like, come on bombers.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like these very sort of like.
Speaker 1: the ref is a joke.
Speaker 1: That was a joke call ref.
Speaker 1: Like it felt just very quaint and very pleasant to genteel.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: After the second half, a man next to us put his hands up to his mouth and yelled immortal words, shit down his throat, shit in his fucking mouth, shit in his fucking mouth and then rip off his head.
Speaker 1: And it was so beautiful because that was the same man who had been saying the ref is a joke.
Speaker 1: Not 10 minutes prior.
Speaker 0: He was one, that was the yelling guy pretty much that was standing behind us.
Speaker 1: But he was the w. so we showed up, right?
Speaker 1: And the game like where is?
Speaker 1: hours before the game, we were some of the first people and there's a guy sitting in the seat and he yells footy.
Speaker 1: I was never more proud of a man that I've met who was a stranger than at that moment because all my mind, I was like, did he just say hockey?
Speaker 0: That's what they say.
Speaker 1: I almost yelled.
Speaker 1: That's what this is.
Speaker 1: But I didn't want to engage because I was in a foreign land and a foreign sport.
Speaker 1: I didn't know all the protocols yet.
Speaker 1: I wondered if someone else was going to yell a call back to him.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we'll talk more about footy in another show.
Speaker 0: So the big thing we did while we were there is we went to the penguin Island, also known as Phillip Island.
Speaker 1: So Phillip Island to give you a very brief history, penguins everywhere and seals and awesome nature.
Speaker 1: Australians ruined it by moving onto it and building houses.
Speaker 0: They all moved there and built crazy vacation places like holy crap, vacation land.
Speaker 1: So the Australian government was like, look, you fuckers.
Speaker 1: So they picked, they took a big chunk of the Island.
Speaker 1: They eminent domain, everybody off of that chunk.
Speaker 1: And now they're reintroducing the penguin populations.
Speaker 0: Most of the Island seems to be nature or touristy.
Speaker 0: And there is a town called cows, C?
Speaker 0: O W E S where people live and there's hotels and restaurants and houses.
Speaker 0: And it's sort of vacation beach town, right?
Speaker 0: But a large chunk of the Island is just like, yeah, this is penguin land.
Speaker 0: And then there's other chunks where it's like this, please buy this land and build a housing development and move to it.
Speaker 1: But what's interesting is that a lot like we went to the penguin thing, you know, the, the parade of penguins, you can look up what the parade of penguins is.
Speaker 1: It is exactly what it sounds like.
Speaker 1: And Scott and I, we figured, you know, everyone on the internet, even people who are cynical jaded travelers, like we are said the penguin thing, it's touristy, but you must see the penguin thing.
Speaker 1: So we paid for the ultimate penguin experience.
Speaker 0: So the regular penguin experience, you sit in these bleachers on the beach, the sun goes down, the moon comes up, they turn on lights so you can see.
Speaker 0: And these penguins come out of the water and go to their houses at night.
Speaker 1: It is adorable.
Speaker 1: The ultimate penguin experience is you go privately with like there was me, Scott and three other people and the ranger and a park ranger, right?
Speaker 0: Took us into a private, take you to a different beach while the private room first to tell you what's going on.
Speaker 1: And then you give, they give you night vision and shrouds and things to sit on.
Speaker 0: And they take you to a private beach where you watch different penguins come on and go to their homes in the dark.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's, it's a long experience.
Speaker 0: Usually like she explained, you sit there for like an hour in the sand and you learn it.
Speaker 1: She really knew her stuff.
Speaker 1: She told us everything about the penguins and what's her job is to know about penguins.
Speaker 1: And then this tiny group, we walk out into the beach that we'd been hiking on during the day, but now it was closed and we just huddle up on the beach in our black with our night vision and we wait with radios.
Speaker 1: And then the baby penguins, well, they're not baby.
Speaker 1: They're just tiny.
Speaker 0: They're called, they're called the little penguin.
Speaker 0: They're like a foot.
Speaker 0: They're also known as the fairy penguin, but the official name, I guess, is the little penguin and the little penguins just form rafts in the ocean.
Speaker 1: Apparently they didn't have babies on the land in penguin town.
Speaker 0: It wasn't the time yet in this time of year because it was winter.
Speaker 1: So they don't have to come in.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Basically the penguins live in the water and they also have houses on land, but they can stay in the water for fucking ever if they want to.
Speaker 0: They don't have to come back home.
Speaker 1: They come home to socialize.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Basically, it's like going to work and go into the city.
Speaker 0: It's like they can stay at work for a long time and they can stay at home for a long time and they sleep during, they seem to be nocturnal.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Now they're pretty safe in penguin town and we keep saying penguin town.
Speaker 1: No, there was a penguin.
Speaker 0: That was basically fucking penguin New York right there.
Speaker 1: The penguins all make their own little houses.
Speaker 0: It's like we're in this place during the day and you don't see or hear any penguins, but they stay signs everywhere.
Speaker 0: Like watch out.
Speaker 0: Penguins live here in holes in the ground.
Speaker 0: Don't step on this shit.
Speaker 0: And then at night they basically all come out and go, they're so loud.
Speaker 1: They're just like walking around talking to each other.
Speaker 1: Like one penguin goes to someone else's house and that guy's like, get the fuck away from my house.
Speaker 1: The females are like, find a mate and hang out or go to their mate's house or whatever.
Speaker 1: And they socialize and they're super loud and just walking around all night and interspersed among them are just rabbits everywhere and wallabies everywhere.
Speaker 1: Just hanging out animal gooses.
Speaker 1: They are so loud.
Speaker 0: They're loud at night when they work.
Speaker 1: They're not loud on the beach because the beach is where predators might get them.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: See when they're hanging out in the grass area, they can just go into their house.
Speaker 1: Imagine if you work in New York city and you commute back to beacon, you know, upstate New York on the train.
Speaker 1: So in New York, New York's awesome.
Speaker 1: You can just stay in New York forever, but occasionally you got to go home.
Speaker 1: So every day you kind of meet with all the other workers like near a subway train.
Speaker 1: You're like, should we go home?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Well, that's all.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Let's get on the train.
Speaker 1: So we all get on the train and then the train gets to beacon roll.
Speaker 1: Like you want to get out.
Speaker 1: And then there's wolves at the train station.
Speaker 1: We're not this time.
Speaker 1: Takes the train back to New York.
Speaker 0: They basically, they group up so that they're safe.
Speaker 1: They cross the beach in a group up and decide if they're even going to come in.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So they'll see them like the come out of the water.
Speaker 0: The first they'll be in the water and they'll form a group in the water where it's safe.
Speaker 0: Then they come out onto the beach where they basically have no camo and they have to run across the beach really fast.
Speaker 0: So they'll be in a group on the edge of the water and they'd be like, is there any wolves or foxes on this beach?
Speaker 0: And they'd be like, oh shit danger.
Speaker 0: And they'll run back in the water and then they'll come back on the beach and be like, I think we can go for it guys.
Speaker 0: Let's go for it.
Speaker 0: All right, let's go.
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 0: And they go and they run across the beach really fast.
Speaker 1: So fast and so quiet, but they're also kind of derpy.
Speaker 1: They keep tripping over stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But they climb big.
Speaker 0: It's like you think these little floppy fins, like they're meant for swimming, not for walking, but they climb right up that hill.
Speaker 0: Like whoop.
Speaker 1: What was funny is that there's always a whole bunch of penguins and then that penguin.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The brave guy.
Speaker 1: Well, there's the, there's the brave guy who goes first, all the normal guys.
Speaker 1: And then I can only assume that it's the, that guy of penguins that no one wants to talk to.
Speaker 1: He's always last by himself.
Speaker 1: And I think everyone just hoping the Fox will get him.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We saw signs everywhere that like, Hey, we're trying to get the Foxes off the Island.
Speaker 0: If you see one, call us.
Speaker 0: We never saw one.
Speaker 1: The ranger said that they have through a combination of poisoning and trapping gotten rid of all but 11 Foxes on this entire Island.
Speaker 1: And the ranger was like, yeah, those last 11 Foxes are the good God, bad-ass Foxes.
Speaker 1: We can't get them to the smartest of the Fox rabbit in the lion's den because apparently you know, penguin city, there really weren't predators like Fox in the human's den.
Speaker 0: That's a bad-ass Fox.
Speaker 1: So if a Fox goes to penguin town, he'll kill like 400 penguins.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 1: So yeah, they're trying to get rid of all the Foxes.
Speaker 1: Apparently what's sad is I'll be.
Speaker 1: another big problem for the penguins is feral cats and humans who have cats that they let wander around, but due to public sentiment, they don't poison the cats.
Speaker 1: They trap them and release them on other places and they still let people own cat.
Speaker 1: So the cats are pretty much always going to be a problem.
Speaker 1: I say if you're going to poison the Foxes, you poison the cats too.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: Because they're, they're.
Speaker 1: similarly, uh, there's similar threat levels to those amazingly adorable.
Speaker 0: We don't have a cat shortage.
Speaker 0: We have a penguin shortage.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But yeah, having the night vision was kind of cool because the penguins couldn't see at first.
Speaker 0: I'm like, Oh, they gave us the night vision.
Speaker 0: I just want to see the penguins.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to use it.
Speaker 0: I can see them without it.
Speaker 0: No, you can't.
Speaker 1: It is so dark.
Speaker 1: It is dark until you see all this other stuff.
Speaker 0: And it was nice to have some darkness after living in New York city.
Speaker 0: That was the first time in a while I've seen like fucking stars and shit, but the wallabies could see the IR splash.
Speaker 1: So I'd be like scanning and I'd see a wallaby and the wallaby would see me looking at him like, what the fuck dude?
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: Cause he could see it like a flashlight aimed at him.
Speaker 1: But the penguins couldn't see that.
Speaker 1: The rabbits couldn't see that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Other things on that Island.
Speaker 0: Uh, another surreal experience at a restaurant.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: So we went to this great restaurant that has this great dog and got some great food, but it was like this beer place, but we run by a guy who was clearly a beer nerd of Australia.
Speaker 1: That guy is such a beer nerd.
Speaker 1: It was one of the only places in Australia that you had his horsey beer, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I did have a source.
Speaker 0: It was really good.
Speaker 1: Most of the beer I had in Australia was mediocre.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No fosters in Australia.
Speaker 1: You narrow shit.
Speaker 1: Beer is Carlton, Carlton dress mediocre.
Speaker 0: It's basically, isn't it?
Speaker 0: sort of like, uh, no, what's it called?
Speaker 0: What's that shit that people drink in New York?
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 1: Uh, Emily's yelling suggestions.
Speaker 0: It's not that one.
Speaker 0: It's a mediocre beer.
Speaker 1: It's a step below Stella in terms of goodness.
Speaker 0: Just man.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Stella.
Speaker 0: That's the one.
Speaker 1: It's not the same kind of beer really, but it's mediocre beer.
Speaker 0: But it's the same.
Speaker 1: It feels the same as niche and there's this local blonde that's like the other local beer also kind of meh.
Speaker 1: But uh, we went to this Mexican restaurant, a family Mexican cantina because it was late at night.
Speaker 0: There was only two other people there.
Speaker 1: Not a lot of Mexican food in Australia.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: So we're like, well, let's check this out.
Speaker 1: So we go to this place.
Speaker 1: It's like 45 minutes before the place is supposed to close.
Speaker 1: There's one girl up front.
Speaker 1: There's some people finishing a meal and about to leave.
Speaker 1: So we're like, yeah, table for two.
Speaker 1: And it was just quiet and empty and surreal and weird.
Speaker 0: So we are.
Speaker 0: So we order and super hungry.
Speaker 0: Every plate.
Speaker 0: We're so far has had normal size portions, not American portions.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So we ordered a big nacho and just an entree each.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So we wait in like 40 minutes go by and now it's like five minutes before the place closes and we get our nachos at some point and they're gigantic.
Speaker 1: They're, they're more food that we can eat.
Speaker 1: So we're picking at him like assuming we're going to eat a bunch and take a bunch home and our main dishes never come.
Speaker 0: It's meanwhile, eventually we sit there.
Speaker 0: It's quiet and eerie and surreal.
Speaker 0: I think they refilled our water once or twice.
Speaker 1: And the lady comes over a few times and never bring, I think she was waiting for us to finish those fucking nachos before she was going to even start cooking our main dishes.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But then eventually after a super long time, it's way past closing time, they bring our actual meals.
Speaker 0: Now gigantic.
Speaker 1: I'm full.
Speaker 0: We can barely eat it.
Speaker 0: I had, I got, it was like, mine was like a taco and an enchilada.
Speaker 1: Like something I normally would have been able to eat, but I kept picking those nachos of other mush.
Speaker 1: So we eat and even wasn't that good.
Speaker 1: So finally I go up to the front.
Speaker 1: I was like, yeah, can we get the check?
Speaker 1: I think we're done.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And I was like, you know, I just wanted to take mine back cause I so much foods.
Speaker 0: It's like a whole taco.
Speaker 1: Can we get a takeaway?
Speaker 1: And she's like, we don't allow takeaway.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, what do you mean?
Speaker 0: So we're like, what are you going to do with that taco?
Speaker 0: We look at this and I'm just like, I'm just like, fine, take, take my money.
Speaker 0: Getting out of this weird situation.
Speaker 1: So now we leave like almost two hours after we walked into this place.
Speaker 1: It's so late at night.
Speaker 1: I'm so tired.
Speaker 1: I'm so full.
Speaker 1: We left multiple pounds of food behind us and the lady paid for a story.
Speaker 1: And the lady, the reason it was so surreal is that it was quiet, like deathly quiet the whole time.
Speaker 1: The lady never said a non-functional word to us the entire time and never changed the completely blank expression on her face at any point.
Speaker 1: And when we were like, we left and she just kind of stood there.
Speaker 1: Like as we walked out, I looked back and she was just standing there behind the bar, like not doing anything, just kind of looking really weird.
Speaker 0: It was weird.
Speaker 1: We went back to our seahorsee hotel.
Speaker 1: That was pretty great.
Speaker 0: It was, it was a typical drive in motel.
Speaker 0: It was a beach, vacation kind of place.
Speaker 1: So that was kind of fun.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And at this beach motel in the winter, we were like some of the only people there were maybe a handful of people staying at this place and it was a great place.
Speaker 1: But the guy who checked us in was super nice, super friendly tourist, welcoming guy.
Speaker 1: He knew everything about this island.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: He lives there.
Speaker 1: And then he starts giving us advice like, well, you should do this.
Speaker 1: You should do this.
Speaker 1: Oh, you might be able to take a boat to go with these.
Speaker 1: The seals.
Speaker 0: He's like, he's like, he tells us about the seals.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, is there a boat that goes to the seals?
Speaker 0: He says, let me check.
Speaker 0: And he gets a computer printout of the boat status of that day.
Speaker 1: Not just the boat status, but the status of the seas, all the ferries, all the, everything that happens on the island, whether or not it's like how high tech is this little island.
Speaker 0: And this little motel is hooked up to the high tech island system.
Speaker 0: No place in the U S is like that.
Speaker 1: We want to see the koala preserve because koalas kind of got out.
Speaker 1: They kind of got out competed by the world.
Speaker 1: They're not the most efficient animal, so they need a lot of help to not be extinct.
Speaker 0: So we went to the preserve to see them and they're sleeping as they said they would be.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They're basically just balls of fur that hang out in trees, not moving.
Speaker 0: They move, not a lot.
Speaker 1: And one of them long enough to scratch his stomach for a little bit and then go back to sleep.
Speaker 1: It was kind of cute.
Speaker 0: That's what I would do.
Speaker 1: Have you ever koala?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I mostly, I was actually more impressed with all the birdies than the koalas.
Speaker 1: Oh, the bird photography and the birds.
Speaker 1: We're all took.
Speaker 1: My favorite bird is that little blue rain.
Speaker 0: You like the blue guy, little blue guy.
Speaker 0: I actually like the guy that we just saw even outside preserve areas.
Speaker 0: It's like in the city.
Speaker 0: He was sort of white and black.
Speaker 0: And it's like, Oh, that looks sort of like an interesting tropical bird, but he's just sort of everywhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There were a bunch of parrots on the, uh, the, uh, old racetrack that I went to.
Speaker 1: We might have to do multiple shows.
Speaker 1: We got on for a while.
Speaker 1: I got a lot of cool stuff to say still about Australia.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Australia is a lot going on there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We didn't even talk about how Scott broke his arm.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess we didn't.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We'll save that for it.
Speaker 1: We'll do another Australia show.
Speaker 1: Good.
Speaker 0: We'll get through another Thursday.
Speaker 0: This is what happens when you save your laser.
Speaker 0: So much more to laser, not fully uncharged.
Speaker 1: We've barely even scratched the surface of the cool shit that happened to us in Australia.
Speaker 0: All right, good.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative comments attribution.
Speaker 0: 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.