Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, February 5th, 2013.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 0: Point and click adventure games.
Speaker 0: I can't believe we've never talked about these on Geek Nights before.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: What's up, Scott?
Speaker 0: You've been tantalizing me.
Speaker 1: We should start the "can't believe we haven't talked about these on Geek Nights before" series.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much the only place we're going to get new ideas.
Speaker 0: Thing is, we've already talked about almost everything I can't believe we didn't talk about.
Speaker 0: The Simpsons didn't.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights did it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so, you know, there's an old saying, "The good things come to those who
Speaker 1: wait.".
Speaker 1: And I know there's a lot of nerds out there.
Speaker 1: They don't like waiting for things.
Speaker 1: It's like, "Oh my God, they got to see the thing as soon as it comes
Speaker 1: out.".
Speaker 1: Or, "They got to go to the midnight
Speaker 1: screening.".
Speaker 0: You got to wait in line at Hall H to see the thing.
Speaker 0: that's going to be on YouTube sooner than you can see it.
Speaker 1: Got to play Portal 2 at PAX because I can't play, "Oh wait, it's $5 now.
Speaker 1: Gee.".
Speaker 1: You know, "Oh my God, I have to wait for another season of
Speaker 1: Ponies.".
Speaker 1: Guess what?
Speaker 1: At this time, we've already done that twice.
Speaker 1: And the third one's almost over already.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, it's easy to forget that.
Speaker 1: The waiting is so short.
Speaker 0: It is easy to forget that because, you know, we were watching Ponies a long but then we had a lull.
Speaker 0: So Adventure Time has four whole seasons out and we marathoned through that shit like butter.
Speaker 0: I hit the end, it's like hitting a brick wall.
Speaker 0: Now I got to wait a week for a half episode?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, I got to tell you, there's something I've been waiting for since 2011.
Speaker 1: Okay, so Half Life 3 longer than that.
Speaker 0: And I have it right now.
Speaker 0: Oh, that was totally worth waiting two years for.
Speaker 0: Scott, I hate you so much.
Speaker 1: That was worth waiting two years for.
Speaker 0: I can't believe that exists.
Speaker 0: You have it in our house.
Speaker 0: You put it in my fucking eyeball.
Speaker 1: You see how bright that shit was?
Speaker 0: That was pretty fucking bright.
Speaker 1: That was worth waiting two years easily.
Speaker 1: See?
Speaker 1: It's like I didn't wait at all.
Speaker 1: I feel like I bought that on Kickstarter yesterday.
Speaker 0: But you have ruined one of my greatest go to sticks.
Speaker 0: Your eyeball.
Speaker 0: Also my eyeball.
Speaker 0: Anytime Kickstarter comes up, what I'll always be like, I'll always turn to Scott and be like, yeah, just like your Hexbrite.
Speaker 0: When did you kickstart that?
Speaker 1: 2011.
Speaker 1: I looked it up.
Speaker 1: That's how come I know.
Speaker 0: Why did I turn around?
Speaker 0: My brain was like, don't turn around, Rym.
Speaker 0: But it was too late.
Speaker 1: My body was like, are you seeing a nice spot in your eye?
Speaker 0: I actually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was actually on the highest setting.
Speaker 0: That's a pretty good flashlight and it has three settings.
Speaker 1: Also the blinking setting.
Speaker 0: So is it going to be in stores?
Speaker 0: Can I just go buy it?
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll show you all the details of it later without putting in your eye to turn around again.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 1: It's in my bag now.
Speaker 1: I still don't trust you.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to turn around.
Speaker 1: It overheats if you leave it in that setting too long.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Slightly.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It has an auto off in the heat feature.
Speaker 1: So if it gets too hot, like if you leave it in a bag on by accident, it'll turn itself off.
Speaker 1: It's pretty amazing.
Speaker 1: Uh, but yeah, so, and if you've kickstarted something and it's been a long time since you've received it, odds are you're not gonna, but it's still possible.
Speaker 1: Don't lose hope and don't become impatient with anything ever because there's a whole world of things, right?
Speaker 1: I mean that new ghost in the shell.
Speaker 1: go a show that'll be out tomorrow pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually it'll be out in about a week.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm not, you know, what's, what's the rush.
Speaker 0: So all I got is some, my office, right?
Speaker 0: You know, we talk about memes.
Speaker 0: Actually we haven't talked about memes a lot on the show, but Scott and I have talked about memes for a long time and you know, as a unit of information that spreads like a virus through humans, you know, all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: We're not, when I say meme, I don't mean a lolcat with impact font though.
Speaker 0: That is a meme.
Speaker 0: That is not what a meme means.
Speaker 0: But a meme made its way through my office and it's, I'm like watching it cultivate and grow.
Speaker 0: It's like a fish ball.
Speaker 0: So one day one of my coworkers just kind of whistles, you know, little thing.
Speaker 0: And unlike any other tune that has been whistled or anything like that or even Gangnam style, this just kind of got repeated around the office, kind of in a loop and there weren't that many people in.
Speaker 0: And every day as days go by, different people kind of just do it randomly and hum it.
Speaker 0: And people who weren't in the office before come in and they hear it, they replicate it out.
Speaker 0: Someone's doing it every five minutes now unconsciously.
Speaker 0: And it's just.
Speaker 1: That's from a song, but I can't exactly put my finger on it right now.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to keep tabs on this and I'm curious if it's going to make it from me to other people.
Speaker 1: It feels really familiar, like an old video game song or a portion of a song from something, a soundtrack.
Speaker 0: It might be some garbage pop song, we just don't know the name of it.
Speaker 1: No, I think it's either from a video game or it's a sound effect or it's from an OST, like a portion of a song from an OST.
Speaker 1: I feel like the part after that goes like, you know, doo
Speaker 0: doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo
Speaker 1: doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo
Speaker 0: doo
Speaker 1: doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo
Speaker 0: doo doo doo doo doo doo doo
Speaker 1: doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo
Speaker 0: doo doo doo doo doo
Speaker 1: doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 0: so that's a cool thing right?
Speaker 0: so i have my augmented reality glasses and that stuff just built in there right?
Speaker 0: so i can see heat signatures of things.
Speaker 0: so i can see which card you were holding most recently.
Speaker 0: if you just did something in a game of cards and the cards were shuffled is that cheating?
Speaker 0: maybe so i think there is going to be a problem in the board gaming world and only the tabletop board gaming world casinos can cover it.
Speaker 1: there's already all sorts of devices you can use to cheat in a casino and casinos already keep those out.
Speaker 1: well for now they'll just be like hey you can't wear that shit in the casino.
Speaker 0: so then when i have my cyber eyes no cyber eyes in the casino?
Speaker 1: exactly, people with cyber eyes can't gamble.
Speaker 1: wait a minute, the rich people who are willing to spend money on ridiculous extravagances stay out of our casino the rich people who are willing to go into this EMP area or they'll invent some sort of un-cheatable system where you don't have the physical cards.
Speaker 1: it's some digital thing you're not plugged in.
Speaker 1: they'll just use some other system.
Speaker 1: that doesn't.
Speaker 0: here's how casinos get around that they have a ton of money.
Speaker 0: craps has the best odds.
Speaker 0: there's a reason why in most casinos craps is so expensive per play that most people can't play it.
Speaker 1: you can play craps.
Speaker 1: you put whatever the minimum chip is on whatever the line.
Speaker 0: and the last several times i've been in a casino the minimum entry point on any craps table was 100 bucks up.
Speaker 1: oh i've seen like 10 dollar craps i have, but not often.
Speaker 0: it depends on the time of day.
Speaker 1: who's gonna pay 100 dollars on one roll of the dice?
Speaker 1: you insane.
Speaker 1: i'm like i don't wanna buy a 3ds cause there's not enough games out.
Speaker 1: dude if i'm willing to put 100 dollars on the roll of a dice i'll buy two 3ds before i do that shit.
Speaker 0: what i'm saying is that casinos will minimize games or eliminate games over time culturally that have good odds or that could be game by.
Speaker 0: systems like that, separate question.
Speaker 0: tabletop competitive games ortho games to use the richard garfield terminology are gonna have a big problem when augmented reality is ubiquitous.
Speaker 0: because while there's the social contract of don't cheat during games you can't bring in external shit, like if scott got a piece of paper and started writing down how many victory points people were taking during a game in puerto rico or flipping a coin to act randomly, no no no this is a social contract.
Speaker 0: but when all those interactions are invisible and indistinguishable from what if you just have a really good memory that's a problem.
Speaker 0: there's a solution that you're completely missing board game mode and my electronic eyeballs?
Speaker 1: that's exactly right.
Speaker 1: if you have these magic eyeballs that can change colors, well obviously they can project any image to your eyes, right?
Speaker 1: so you don't even have fucking cards that could have heat signatures on them, both just you and the other guy are playing a video game and the display is your electronic eyeballs and when you look at the table you see cards that aren't there and you touch them to move them around but they're not actually there.
Speaker 1: so you can't possibly cheat unless you hack which is the same exact problem that we already have with Counter Strike video game cheating which is gonna have the same solution.
Speaker 1: so you headed me off, which is good because it means we're kind of on the same page with all this stuff right, so as soon as I have electronic eyeballs we have to be the first people to make Puerto Rico Electronic Eyeball Edition.
Speaker 0: so here's why I said it's a problem for board games not because it makes-
Speaker 1: oh no, people will stop sending money so that China can print games on cardboard, oh no
Speaker 0: no, because now, right now if someone wants to design a board game they basically don't need anything except their brain and pieces of paper and you know, fiddly bits
Speaker 1: oh, they're gonna have to learn to code.
Speaker 1: all board games will become video games amongst people with electronic eyeballs.
Speaker 0: basically yes suddenly board game development just becomes an interface for video game development which is something nerds have wanted for a long time.
Speaker 0: but I foresee that being a hugely disruptive period, especially in tabletop tournament gaming and that whole industry is gonna get really fucked by this.
Speaker 0: now the nice result is, it's pretty much a win for the gamers and for the game designers.
Speaker 1: A, you can just pirate all the board games right, you don't have to have a tabletop library, you just need the other people and everyone has electronic eyes.
Speaker 1: everyone can play every game ever.
Speaker 0: but I'm even pumped.
Speaker 0: now about Augmented Reality in tabletop games,
Speaker 1: oh no, I won't have to set up Eclipse, I'll just blink and I'll take a look at Eclipse, oh Eclipse is on the table don't you see it, yeah I see it
Speaker 0: there it is, but once we get to that point where a tabletop game is really just a video game and the bits are just an interface and
Speaker 1: it'll be so much faster to play, you won't mess up any rules.
Speaker 0: thus, the problem with the kinds of tabletop games we like now and while this is not an insurmountable problem it is not a problem that's going to be easily surmountable by most people why do we always say that tabletop games are the best games to study in design when you're a novice designer and why they tend to be very elegant?
Speaker 1: because the limitations of the physical world can strain your design decision.
Speaker 0: so suddenly if the physical world is not a limitation again but is simply a manifestation of the interface we again no longer have that limitation and it lets the non-genius non-expert game designers basically, it ruins their ability to make a good game.
Speaker 1: no it doesn't, because they can still create the game physically, right forgetting all those, you know, the fact that people can cheat with using their magic eyes and then once they've designed that beautiful game, just translate it into a digital version as has been very successful for many a developer.
Speaker 0: but the people who will design faster and rise faster in the early days of this are the ones who are game designers and programmers leaving everyone else in the dust, thus making it the point where well.
Speaker 1: I think, you know, if they were public companies I would invest a bit in the companies that are, such as Big Daddy's Creations who have made a business of taking other people's games and turning them into iOS, iPad PC apps.
Speaker 0: That is an apt investment that I think I would agree with.
Speaker 1: Those companies are going to do very well and in fact I would not be surprised if some of those companies started hiring the board game designers instead of just you know, taking contracts from other game companies.
Speaker 0: Because I was thinking about this and I realized how rapidly all the strictures of tabletop break down, like, even forget the heat signatures, alright, I'm holding cards.
Speaker 1: well, if I have Google Glasses or something like it recording everything that's going on constantly You could rewind and play the shell game to see and you could find where the card was.
Speaker 0: No, better, I could rewind because everyone holds their cards, right?
Speaker 0: There's that moment where for a second you lean forward a little bit and the cards are visible for a second but no human could actually see what they were.
Speaker 1: And you rewind to that exact frame on your 60fps video.
Speaker 0: Yeah, suddenly my thing just shows me, like, here's the, it has an overlay of.
Speaker 0: here's our best guess as to what's in everyone's hands based on glances we've seen or reflections off of eyeballs with the 8K camera Yeah.
Speaker 1: So The 8K camera in my own eyeball I think is a ways off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but within our lifetime I think.
Speaker 1: We'll be old.
Speaker 0: If that's the best time, it means that when my body starts falling apart We're gonna need it.
Speaker 1: You'll be lucky if you can even see at all.
Speaker 0: When I'm old I'm gonna be a brain attached to artificial genitalia and and a USB interface for playing Counter Strike.
Speaker 1: We can only hope as the genitalia is for the Counter Strike So you can talk about it while you play Counter Strike.
Speaker 1: That's the only reason you need it.
Speaker 0: No, but then you also need a joint.
Speaker 1: It's not like it's gonna work.
Speaker 0: You also need a marijuana simulator so you can talk about how high you are.
Speaker 1: But no, actually you won't need it anymore But anyway Things of the day!
Speaker 0: I would normally make this a Wednesday geek night thing, but I'll make it a Tuesday thing to spread the love and the horrible judgement of the moon.
Speaker 0: There's a guy, he was thinking a long time ago, and he would recreate openers to anime.
Speaker 0: Like Fist of the North Star.
Speaker 0: But he would do it live action and play all the parts and basically dress up and then make himself be all the characters in all the scenes in the entire opener.
Speaker 0: It's hilarious.
Speaker 0: Different guy is doing something similar and this is something pretty fantastic.
Speaker 0: Basically he's doing that with surprisingly better cosplay skills than I exhibited at RIT.
Speaker 0: Which isn't saying much Making costumes out of construction paper and redoing all of the transformation sequences from Bishoujo Senshi Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: Your favorite Not my favorite, but you know what?
Speaker 0: I do not regret having watched that entire show.
Speaker 0: So you should watch this and I'm not sure what you'll think of it.
Speaker 1: Okay, so this dude is playing I guess paintball it looks like?
Speaker 1: It doesn't look like airsoft and he's playing apparently a game called I guess CQB.
Speaker 1: no, I think the place is CQB Tactical and they're playing a game called One Man Army and in the description it says "Game was based around one floor at a time.
Speaker 1: Attackers have unlimited lives, defenders one life, and are timed on how long it takes to clear the floor.
Speaker 1: Rest of my team got finished off as I came around and shot the last two guys.
Speaker 1: I stayed quiet in one of the side rooms and to my surprise not one single person decided to check that they were clear.
Speaker 1: This was the result of that.
Speaker 1: Full video of day to
Speaker 1: follow.".
Speaker 1: So this video is just a 1 minute 19 second video.
Speaker 1: so that's pretty short and a large portion of this video is spent with him in a room just quiet waiting in the dark but he basically pops
Speaker 0: out
Speaker 1: and nobody knew he was in there and they were all facing the other way and he takes out enough people to make a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: So when you started telling this story what I was going to say but I did not interrupt because I wanted to see if it was the story.
Speaker 1: He's got like a GoPro on his gun or something.
Speaker 0: That was a clutch moment.
Speaker 0: I am a connoisseur of clutch moment Counter Strike YouTube videos.
Speaker 1: Yeah well this isn't Counter Strike.
Speaker 1: this is the paintball for real.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So this is more clutch.
Speaker 1: I mean he takes out like 2 Counter Strike teams worth of people.
Speaker 0: Yeah because it's one thing in Counter Strike In Counter Strike when my guy runs across the entire map murdering everyone that's not as impressive as a human running and murdering everyone because fingers get hurt and people get tired.
Speaker 1: I especially like how at one point he says "whoop whoop whoop bitches" and the second top comment on YouTube is "whoop whoop whoop bitches".
Speaker 0: Are you sure he wasn't playing Counter Strike?
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm sure you can check it out yourself.
Speaker 1: So in the meantime PEX East coming up soon we're going to be there March right?
Speaker 0: Yes March.
Speaker 0: we are doing not one March 22nd through 24th possibly three but probably two panel.
Speaker 0: well actually lectures.
Speaker 0: we call them panels but they're lectures at PEX East.
Speaker 0: We are doing announced officially here.
Speaker 0: I'm delaying because I'm scrolling through the email to find the titles again.
Speaker 0: We are doing Mastering Game Mechanics at noon on Saturday March 23rd and we are doing Practical Game Theory at 1.30 on Saturday in the same room p.m.
Speaker 0: p.m These are both going to be two pretty cool lectures because the room might not have a stage and we tell you guys right now might not video them.
Speaker 0: it's way hard to video a lecture if the panelists aren't on a stage we'll see.
Speaker 0: Kineticon submissions are open and it's February so we're starting to schedule stuff.
Speaker 0: so if you want to present at Kineticon in Hartford Connecticut a convention about literally everything which is the week before PEX OSS in August submit your shit.
Speaker 0: and Scott myself and one other person are the sole deciders of whether or not you get to present and if you present enough we'll give you a free badge.
Speaker 1: Is there any other meta like the book club?
Speaker 0: The book club book was The Great Gatsby.
Speaker 0: we both finished it.
Speaker 0: we'll do the show as soon as we have a Thursday episode free to do it.
Speaker 0: if you didn't read it you're a bad person.
Speaker 0: if you read it and didn't like it you're a bad person.
Speaker 1: I'm going to pick another book soon.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what really?
Speaker 0: What's that book going to be?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Pressure's on.
Speaker 1: I should stick with my plan of pick book.
Speaker 1: I own physically but have not read yet.
Speaker 0: I'm just warning you the second you pick something I don't like it's all non-fiction.
Speaker 0: or The Count of Monte Cristo.
Speaker 0: you would like The Count of Monte Cristo a lot.
Speaker 0: it's so long.
Speaker 0: The thing is you'll read it so fast because it's so awesome.
Speaker 1: Anyway anyway let's forget about any other metas right now.
Speaker 0: yeah we got videos online.
Speaker 0: I uploaded the third and final of our presentations from magfest 11 and he immediately goes into more meta.
Speaker 0: well I won't tell people I got a thing out.
Speaker 1: okay good is that?
Speaker 1: it is that all?
Speaker 1: it's all.
Speaker 1: that is all all right.
Speaker 0: so I can't believe we didn't talk about this.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty.
Speaker 0: I searched the theme song.
Speaker 0: we may have talked about this.
Speaker 1: we may have talked about this but in searching our website extensively with many methods I have not found any links to it.
Speaker 1: therefore we've I don't think we've ever done an episode on the point and click adventure game genre.
Speaker 1: so let us do that now because it is a genre of games that is beloved by many is of historical significance and is a recent resurgence.
Speaker 0: now we can talk about like actual history and things later.
Speaker 1: you can read about that on Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: yeah we're just talking about our own experiences and our own thoughts on these things.
Speaker 0: you know back to classic geek nights.
Speaker 0: you know a little bit of Dave and Joel style a little less anime world order style.
Speaker 0: so the reason I thought of this and Scott thought of this and Scott hasn't heard of this game though I'm really interested in it is that Kentucky Route Zero is this indie game.
Speaker 0: that is a point and click adventure but it does.
Speaker 0: it's not like old point and click adventures.
Speaker 0: okay and it reminds me kind of if you look at the graphics of Out of This World.
Speaker 1: oh like Flashback.
Speaker 0: yeah well Flashback came way later.
Speaker 0: Out of This World was the first one right and they're not.
Speaker 0: they're not really in the same genre but they'll they're remnant.
Speaker 0: anyway I digress.
Speaker 0: so I'll get back to why I think Kentucky Route Zero might be different but it has to do with things James Portnow said.
Speaker 0: you might know him from Penny Arcade stuff in our video from Magfest anyway.
Speaker 0: so the only point and click adventures I've ever actually liked were Maniac Mansion.
Speaker 0: but that's because I've never played anything like that before Shadowgate.
Speaker 1: because I'm a moron I like Déjà Vu more than Shadowgate.
Speaker 0: I liked them both equally.
Speaker 1: I beat Déjà Vu without cheating or looking up any facts or anything like that as did I.
Speaker 0: I beat Shadowgate mostly on my own but I looked in not facts.
Speaker 0: but I had a Nintendo Power.
Speaker 1: I actually didn't play Shadowgate until the emulator era but I had a strategy guide of NES games I didn't own and Shadowgate was in there.
Speaker 0: so I rented Shadowgate and I didn't know what to expect.
Speaker 0: and I remember playing through it and I was like I thought it was the most awesome thing ever because I was dumb and didn't really realize what was going on mostly because of the crazy deaths.
Speaker 1: all I cared about was alright we've talked about enough about Shadowgate crazy deaths.
Speaker 1: I don't think we need to talk about it more.
Speaker 0: Déjà Vu it's all about punching that mugger three times but not four times.
Speaker 0: no don't punch that other mugger but don't shoot him either.
Speaker 1: if you punched him three times don't go in the alley anymore.
Speaker 1: you only have to go in the alley three times at most right.
Speaker 1: just don't go that way.
Speaker 0: the only problem is if that other asshole mugger shows up anyway.
Speaker 1: anyway if you run out of money for the taxi.
Speaker 1: that's why you have to win the lottery in the slot machine.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna admit something.
Speaker 0: I hated King's Quest King's Quest 1.
Speaker 0: I just I hated it.
Speaker 0: I wanted nothing to do with that fucking game.
Speaker 1: I didn't hate them but I didn't play them significantly long.
Speaker 0: enough amounts of time to start to hate them.
Speaker 1: but it's not like.
Speaker 1: I loved them where I was like.
Speaker 1: I couldn't play them and I couldn't stop.
Speaker 1: I just sort of played them a little bit and said oh that's what King's Quest is like.
Speaker 0: okay I played King's Quest 1, 4 I think 5.
Speaker 0: I know I never played 2.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at the list of King's Quest.
Speaker 0: yes I definitely played King's Quest and King's Quest 4 and King's Quest 5 was on a computer at my school but I never actually played it.
Speaker 1: most of the ones I played I played King's Quest 1.
Speaker 0: I played 5 because that's the one that was on the NES.
Speaker 1: I never played any on the NES.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know that there was one on there.
Speaker 0: King's Quest 5 was on the NES.
Speaker 0: it really sucks to play.
Speaker 1: I played King's Quest 1 a little bit just to learn historically what it was like and I also played one or two of the ones that were sort of Windows 3.1 era where you would right click to change the mouse cursor and single click to do that action on the thing.
Speaker 1: I see some screenshots of them here.
Speaker 1: let's see which one is this this is King's Quest 6.
Speaker 1: I think I might have played 6 a little bit.
Speaker 1: this is I Heart Chaos King's Quest 3.
Speaker 0: I might have played King's Quest 3 it's possible but basically I didn't enjoy them primarily because I was used to playing action games or puzzle-y games and I just didn't enjoy the kinds of puzzles in King's Quest games.
Speaker 0: they felt very arbitrary.
Speaker 1: well that's exactly the problem of most of these point and click adventure games in general.
Speaker 1: right I beat what was the one the one that everyone really likes the Skull Guy I beat it a long time ago.
Speaker 1: and Grim Fandango Grim Fandango yeah.
Speaker 1: so I beat that one.
Speaker 1: right is that so much of these games?
Speaker 1: is it's really?
Speaker 1: I hesitate?
Speaker 1: I guess it's more of a game than Dungeon Village but even so it's really just a story a cartoon.
Speaker 1: choose your own adventure in that there's branching but it's not.
Speaker 1: but it's not that you choose.
Speaker 0: there usually isn't actually branching.
Speaker 1: well that's exactly it.
Speaker 1: each branch is incredibly short and ends in a death or an end of game and then you just return to the main trunk.
Speaker 1: there's no thick branches that really go far away and have a different ending and most of these most of them is one big long trunk with the real ending at the end and very tiny branches.
Speaker 1: if you choose an incorrect action you will die or soon die but you want to do those most of them to see all those animations of funny jokes that result from them because a lot of them the different ways to die actually do a different way to die and there's something to see and this content.
Speaker 0: I think Quest for Glory was the best in terms of crazy deaths.
Speaker 1: right but then you just return back to the trunk and try to figure out the thing you're supposed to do to continue and not die.
Speaker 0: see you talk about the trunk.
Speaker 0: I do feel we were talking about this earlier that there are at least two sort of distinct within this genre a word I use very lightly these days that there's like full throttle and a lot of the scum.
Speaker 0: games were much more linear and they'd like be in an area and you'd interact with all the shit in that area and then you go to the next area exactly.
Speaker 0: meanwhile games like the King's Quest even though they do some Legend of Zelda can't get there from here till you got the hook shot.
Speaker 0: they'd still be a much more like they'd be a grid instead of a line of go around and go figure out.
Speaker 0: oh I got to go here with this thing and then back over to here and then there were games like just because they had more screens per area.
Speaker 1: doesn't really make it right.
Speaker 1: I mean.
Speaker 1: what about those ones that are like?
Speaker 0: no it does in one sense.
Speaker 1: what about those ones that like escape the room?
Speaker 1: they're no different it's just more or less complex.
Speaker 1: it doesn't make it a different kind of game.
Speaker 0: well no I didn't say it was like a different kind of game.
Speaker 0: I said they are distinct.
Speaker 0: in one sense the grid ones have an initial sort of long discovery phase where you're discovering this world and you're like making a map for yourself.
Speaker 1: oh because they're more complex they have an extra part to the game just in the geography.
Speaker 0: no other aspect the fact that it's a big two dimensional grid.
Speaker 0: you're thinking to yourself like where is that village?
Speaker 0: again you're taking notes like alright this place had this but in like full throttle you're walking back and forth.
Speaker 1: yeah the other ones do still have that but it's very short right?
Speaker 1: it's like okay there's three screens.
Speaker 1: you can go to look at all three of them right and figure out all the things you can interact with on all of them.
Speaker 0: King's Quest had discovery and exploration but full throttle really just had discovery.
Speaker 0: like here's the new area.
Speaker 0: see all the things in this area.
Speaker 0: move on King's Quest also.
Speaker 1: you had to actually explore right now what the thing is full throttle and others like it did have something that the others didn't have which is an action element.
Speaker 1: in fact they basically put in a mini game or another game where it's like.
Speaker 1: yeah not only do you have to do the usual point and click figure out the stupid logic bullshit but you also have to play this motorcycle racing game and be able to survive to the end of the motorcycle racing game.
Speaker 1: uh and then that's the only you know.
Speaker 1: so that would be like it's like okay enough puzzle solving.
Speaker 1: now do shooting you know and there's some I'm sure there's adventure games you have to shoot or you have to do platforming or you have to do other.
Speaker 1: skills are tested to progress in addition to just figuring out the puzzles.
Speaker 1: so a fact won't help you beat the entire game automatically like it would with say Maniac Mansion.
Speaker 0: now the ones that I liked.
Speaker 0: I really like Police Quest because the only problem with Police Quest is that the driving was the worst driving in any game ever.
Speaker 1: I just remember the elevator in Police Quest.
Speaker 0: oh my god up the elevator down.
Speaker 0: the thing is Police Quest I liked because it was so fucking boring and so fucking procedural and it's like alright go into the locker room, change your police uniform, get your keys, go upstairs, go to the briefing, back into the elevator, click the button, close the door go downstairs, put the hank up on the tube.
Speaker 0: you actually had to push the buttons in the elevator but as a result that game would take you through the minutia of police procedure in a way that was actually pretty interesting to a nerd like me who was into that stuff at the time.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to go play that now like I feel like going home and trying some Police Quest.
Speaker 0: the problem with Police Quest is that it's the driving is unbearable unbearable.
Speaker 0: and the other problem with it is that a lot of the it's not like.
Speaker 0: it's open in terms of like where you go and there's a lot of kind of random events and stuff.
Speaker 0: but really the plot.
Speaker 0: there's only one solution to every plot scenario like in the poker room.
Speaker 0: at the end it's like alright wait for the guy to leave go use the phone, if you do anything else you die.
Speaker 1: these aren't visual novels, they're adventure games, it's not the same thing at all.
Speaker 1: it's like on the surface.
Speaker 1: you would think that they were similar because they have the key, the primary thing to enjoy in both of those is not the play of the game but the art and the story and the music and the visuals, it's like an animation
Speaker 0: and also the give and take of the mechanics of you're sitting there with the guy and it gives you the option of do you handcuff him in the front?
Speaker 0: because he seems harmless, do you handcuff him in the back anyway?
Speaker 0: and then exploring the results of those two actions.
Speaker 1: but it's really just seeing.
Speaker 1: the entertainment comes not necessarily from the choice but from the fact that you do actually get to see two different things happen, it matters.
Speaker 1: and you see, oh, you did it in the front and he was evil and he stabbed you.
Speaker 1: you did it in the back, you safely bring him in the police car, and there's two different animations to see and two different stories.
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: there is, well, there's only, there's a one like we tell, you know, in our old losing should be fun lecture I want to do again sometime just to video it, there's the narrative structure where there's a straight line to the end and every branch ends in death or basically gives you a scene you wouldn't otherwise see and then returns to the main branch.
Speaker 0: so they're similar to visual novels in the same way that Choose Your Own Adventure is similar to just another book because the whole point of a visual novel, at least some visual novels, is that you can actually branch, there's different endings and the decisions affect things later down the road and
Speaker 1: they don't bullshit you by trying to, like, make you do, you know, solve or test your skills.
Speaker 0: some do, some do nine whatevers, nine whatevers, nine whatevers.
Speaker 1: that's not really a visual novel.
Speaker 0: it's arguably in the visual novel genre.
Speaker 1: it's more of a, it's more like it's a visual puzzler.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's more like Myst than it is with easier, not stupid puzzles.
Speaker 0: oh, Myst, alright I hated Myst.
Speaker 1: yeah, Myst is not the greatest.
Speaker 0: I like puzzles, I like crazy puzzles that don't.
Speaker 0: but the puzzles in Myst don't even fucking no, they do make sense, I just don't like them.
Speaker 0: they're not good, I don't agree that they're good puzzles, right well, they give you the explorer with so little content, you know what it is?
Speaker 0: you know what it is?
Speaker 0: Myst has fucking zero directional heuristics unless you were willing to take notes.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean, well that's why I give you a notebook with the box when you buy it.
Speaker 1: yeah, you know
Speaker 0: what, there's only one point in all of Shadowgate where you actually have to take notes, and that's to know how to do the order of the bullshit in the, in the, anyway
Speaker 1: right, cause in Myst you'll go up to a device and you'll learn how to interact with the device and see how it works and say, okay, this button does this, this lever does that?
Speaker 1: okay, this has something to do with that, and it controls something along those lines.
Speaker 1: okay, but what do I actually want to set it to to do something?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: so you go examine the rest of the game and maybe, maybe if you're lucky, you'll find something that looks like the thing you learned how to operate before and you'll learn that that goes with that.
Speaker 1: but most of the time, the thing that tells you you know, what to do with a particular device looks nothing like that device and has no indication that it goes with that device, you just sort of have to say well, if this was the thing that told me how to use this then that would mean that I would have to do this with it, and
Speaker 0: sort of try
Speaker 1: it out and you try everything on everything but trying everything and everything isn't as simple as it is in a LucasArts adventure game where you're like, hammer on that nope, screwdriver on that, nope bread on that, nope, in Myst it's like, okay, if I use this on that, that means one, five seven, ten, and if I use this on that, it means middle lever up, side lever down right, and it's like, come on yeah, but again,
Speaker 0: I'm not saying this is a bad game, I just fucking hated it.
Speaker 1: I say it is many, there are many bad things about Myst.
Speaker 1: it did bad things to the gaming industry that's for sure, it is a bad game in many ways.
Speaker 0: but actually, the games like this I like the most were the Quest for Glory games, I talk about them a lot because I love those games and unlike a lot of these other ones which I tried to replay in the last decade from my youth and just couldn't deal with them, like, I tried to play King's Quest again in like 2004, and I just couldn't.
Speaker 1: I just didn't get it, I agree completely.
Speaker 1: when I was a kid, I fucking loved these kind of games like, my memory, see,
Speaker 0: I didn't, when I was a kid the SCUMM games, I actually hated most of those, really
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: remember, because my brother was playing Full Throttle, and I was playing Quest for Glory, I think, four and, you know, I was like, alright I'll try your game, you try mine, and he liked mine, okay and I was like, Full Throttle, what is this?
Speaker 0: it was just like a straight line, there's like, nah there's nothing to this game, just click on everything just click, just fucking click.
Speaker 1: but anyway, it's like, when I was a kid pretty much any adventure game was awesome, right.
Speaker 1: but now, if I try to play one I might feel like, aw yeah, at the start of it like, when I'm about to start playing but then as soon as I get to screen two, I'm like oh right, fuck this, and maybe what I'll do is get a FAQ, and just play it straight through to see the story, or watch it on YouTube, to get that enjoyment from the story and all the endings, alright well, we've
Speaker 0: talked about that as a game piracy if you watch someone play through it on YouTube
Speaker 1: right, and because there's no enjoyment for me in solving puzzles that make no sense.
Speaker 1: and here's the other problem, I played a game called Stacking, the one with the Matrashka doll oh yeah, which is basically sort of a point and click adventure.
Speaker 1: it's basically, you go to a there's a bunch of levels, in each level you have to solve these different parts of the level, and you can walk around it mostly freely, in order to advance to the next part, right.
Speaker 1: so in many ways it is a point and click adventure in the solving your way out of the room, sort of, what do I use on what you know, which Matrashka container do I use on that, and even if you know which one to use on that, where can I go?
Speaker 1: get the one that I need, right, and there's a little bit of that going on, well I guess, you know, here's the distinction.
Speaker 0: but
Speaker 1: the point is, is in that game most of the things to do made sense, unlike a LucasArts adventure game, well, a lot of the things because they made sense, it was so easy as to not be challenging at all, but Scott, a lot
Speaker 0: of the things in LucasArts stuff did make sense like in Full Throttle, the asbestos suit like.
Speaker 0: what do you think that does, yeah,
Speaker 1: most a lot of things made sense, but they still had a lot of things that were Nintendo logic, right whereas the stacking game had almost no Nintendo logic, but
Speaker 0: the difference is in these scum games for example, because of the limited set of items and the limited interactivity, even an 8 year old in their head could map out every possible combination of things they could do in a given room,
Speaker 1: yeah we played these when we were little kids.
Speaker 0: so yeah, meanwhile Myst is the opposite of that, there's no way to map out every combination, you have to solve it via an entirely different mechanism, yep so I like the games that are in between the two and Quest for Glory.
Speaker 0: that series of games with the first one doesn't really do it so much, but after the first one they kind of figured out the deal, well Quest for Glory has the RPG element to it.
Speaker 0: yes, Quest for Glory is more like an RPG that looks like an adventure game but it doesn't do the RPG stuff of like, I don't know.
Speaker 1: player based combat, oh yeah it doesn't do that.
Speaker 0: but we'll get back because Quest for Glory I could talk about for hours.
Speaker 0: it's like my game from my childhood.
Speaker 1: it's your jam, everyone
Speaker 0: knows
Speaker 1: it's your jam,
Speaker 0: I can do a pretty good job of separating the sort of semi objective reasons why I rationally enjoy the game from the sort of, it was one of those games I played as a kid but I can't separate them 100% but I did play all those other games.
Speaker 0: as a kid as well, I hated most of them, Quest for Glory, here's the reasons that don't make sense for anyone but me, one the first like computer game that was for real like a triple A blockbuster that I bought in a store, didn't just pirate where I didn't have an instruction book or whatever, but I actually physically bought with dollars for a brand new computer was Quest for Glory 4 because 1, 2 and 3 are not a
Speaker 1: triple A blockbuster,
Speaker 0: in that era it was one of the A games, it was like on the shelf.
Speaker 1: let's see what year that came out.
Speaker 0: that was what, '94?
Speaker 1: it was a long fucking time ago, Shadow of Darkness?
Speaker 1: yes, '93, and '94 came with the CD version, did you buy the CD or the floppy version?
Speaker 1: floppy version of course, ok so that was '93 right?
Speaker 1: yeah, so looking with Quest for Glory 1 came out, well hold on, I'm gonna look up something else.
Speaker 1: oh ok, MechWarrior 2 came out in '95, so it was before MechWarrior 2, ok so here's the thing, Quest for Glory 1 2, 3 were ancient.
Speaker 1: yeah, Doom came out in '93.
Speaker 1: I think that was the blockbuster as opposed to the Quest for Glory.
Speaker 0: well Quest for Glory was on, if you went to a computer game store.
Speaker 0: Quest for Glory 4 was underneath the Doom shelf.
Speaker 0: well no, it was on the shelf with all the other.
Speaker 1: all the shelves had Doom.
Speaker 1: Doom was every shelf.
Speaker 0: actually.
Speaker 0: I bought Doom 2 with babbages.
Speaker 0: I think yeah, anyway.
Speaker 0: so Quest for Glory 4 was like a big, I bought it.
Speaker 0: it was awesome but I was like 4.
Speaker 0: I've been through this rigor role before Final Fantasy 6 like I knew about that stuff.
Speaker 0: so I was already mad, it was like 4. where's 1, 2 and 3?
Speaker 0: and the internet didn't really exist in the way it does today now.
Speaker 0: so I'd like ask older gamer dudes I knew like on chat boards and things.
Speaker 0: and eventually I discovered and I found it and I went to a game store and bought this, Quest for Glory 1 had been re-released as a VGA version updated with clicking instead of typing nice.
Speaker 0: so I bought that and I realized oh you can fucking export and import characters.
Speaker 1: oh my god that is a great thing that I wish.
Speaker 1: modern games only Golden Sun has that, what else has that?
Speaker 0: uh Halo, not Halo.
Speaker 0: Mass Effect does it?
Speaker 1: yeah, but the decisions you make carry through from Mass Effect 1 to 2 to 3?
Speaker 1: yeah there are too few games that do this.
Speaker 1: that's all I'm saying.
Speaker 0: when I was a kid many of you probably went through this you had Final Fantasy 1 on the NES you had Final Fantasy 2 and 3 on the SNES and then when Final Fantasy 7 came out you were like what?
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: and then when you learned yeah but then as soon as you knew something was up and you were burned and you were like oh there's all these NES.
Speaker 0: so I knew something was up with this.
Speaker 0: it bothered me.
Speaker 0: that drove me to get deep into gaming, that's why I knew who made Quest for Glory, I didn't know who made any other game that I ever made, but I knew about Laurie and Corey Cole.
Speaker 0: solely because I was so desperate to figure out how to get Quest for Glory 2 and 3, did you see they have a Kickstarter for something?
Speaker 1: yes did you kickstart it?
Speaker 0: I noticed it too late because Quest for Glory 5 was terrible and it was made way later.
Speaker 0: but I eventually acquired floppies and these were 700 whatever K floppies not 1.4 megabyte of Quest for Glory 2 which is the best one in my opinion.
Speaker 0: but those are all the reasons why I like these games that you don't want to care about, the reasons you should like these games like Scott said they're more like.
Speaker 0: they're more like an RPG, you have stats that level up and there are puzzles but they're not puzzles like.
Speaker 0: well first you have to lick the toad and then push the witch into the oven and then close the door and then type duck, they're not like that.
Speaker 0: they're more like alright you need an anvil because of a spell, you know you need an anvil.
Speaker 0: well there's a couple of different places you could steal one from or maybe you buy one I don't know.
Speaker 0: so like I go to the blacksmith and I'm like alright I'm just going to fucking steal his anvil.
Speaker 0: so I pick his lock and I go into his place and I'm like alright I sneak because I don't know.
Speaker 1: if he you can't lift the anvil.
Speaker 0: though yes I go to the anvil and I'm like take anvil.
Speaker 0: oh I'm not strong enough, now if I were strong enough I could have just lifted it.
Speaker 0: but I was a thief not a fighter.
Speaker 0: I didn't put anything to the strength, I couldn't lift that thing for shit.
Speaker 0: so I'm like oh what do I do?
Speaker 0: so I get some oil and I try to grease it up and then the guards appear in the doorway and I'm like what and I get arrested.
Speaker 0: so the next time I do it and I close the door behind me and I lock it again and then I make so much racket trying to get the fucking thing out there that I wake the guy up and he comes down and beats me to death.
Speaker 0: and the fact there's so many ways to solve that puzzle that it's ridiculous.
Speaker 0: and depending on your class there's all these different options.
Speaker 0: but it's not like one of those games where oh if you're a wizard you can solve it by doing this but if you're a thief do it by this, no there's just like four solutions based on the skills you have and the items you have and the things you can do.
Speaker 0: any class can do any of them and that aspect of it made it feel a lot more open and a lot more interesting that there were multiple solutions to pretty much every.
Speaker 0: they weren't puzzles they were problems.
Speaker 0: there were puzzles in those games but that's kind of a separate piece.
Speaker 1: yeah is there anything else to say about the point?
Speaker 1: oh there's a recent resurgence right cause it's sort of a genre that died.
Speaker 1: no one was making games in the genre anymore and more people sort of bemoaned this cause.
Speaker 1: they had nostalgia for them or they really liked them and just wanted there to be more of them.
Speaker 1: so more recently there have been quite a bunch of these remade.
Speaker 1: you can buy a lot of them on Steam like they redid Sam and Max.
Speaker 1: they made a whole bunch of them and there was the Back to the Future ones and some people like them.
Speaker 1: some people don't you know.
Speaker 1: I haven't really played all too many of them but I'm sure if you enjoy like the story animation acting video story part that you could check them out on YouTube or buy them and play them or buy them and play them with a fac and it would probably be pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: but you know not having played them I question the game part.
Speaker 1: I imagine that they're along the lines of try clicking on everything until you proceed to see the rest of the story.
Speaker 0: because for example my problem are the games that have the sort of Nintendo logic it's just a puzzle or the games where there isn't any consequence of failure.
Speaker 0: you literally just click on everything like the escape the room.
Speaker 0: games are usually just click on everything until you get out.
Speaker 1: there's no consequence to failure not even death sometimes the worst consequences you have to try to escape the room again from back from the beginning and re-click everything you already clicked and remember what you already clicked because you died.
Speaker 0: yup but then again if the Nintendo logic is full on Nintendo logic like Maniac Mansion I enjoyed Maniac Mansion because it was arbitrary and crazy.
Speaker 0: but you were trying to figure out the logic of the arbitrary crazy world which was itself pretty self consistent.
Speaker 0: so I did enjoy Maniac Mansion and Maniac Mansion also frustrated the ever living crap out of me primarily because I played it mostly on the NES where it's very difficult to control.
Speaker 0: but once I learned there were a few ways to die I was obsessed with trying to kill all the characters and I came up with a way to do it.
Speaker 0: and I got this crazy ending that I didn't know was there.
Speaker 0: I killed all three kids.
Speaker 0: you know how I did it?
Speaker 1: How would you do it?
Speaker 0: you remember that game enough?
Speaker 1: Not too much.
Speaker 1: is there where you can put something in the microwave and it explodes?
Speaker 0: uh yeah the hamster.
Speaker 1: and doesn't that kill you?
Speaker 0: No it just kills the hamster.
Speaker 0: so here's how you do it.
Speaker 0: there is a way where the I think that there's a botanical that can kill you or the meteor can kill you in one situation but if you drain the pool and you don't fill it back up within a certain amount of time the whole place goes nuclear and everyone dies.
Speaker 0: but that's not the way I did it.
Speaker 0: I emptied the pool.
Speaker 0: I then put two of the kids in there and then I had the third kid fill the pool up.
Speaker 0: they both drowned.
Speaker 0: gravestones appeared I thought that was cool in the front lawn.
Speaker 0: so then I had to kill the third kid.
Speaker 0: so I went back, I borrowed the hamster, I put it in the microwave, I killed it and then I went into the room with the guy whose hamster it was and I gave it to him and he murdered me.
Speaker 0: I put a lot of effort into figuring that out and I don't know.
Speaker 0: like you said, part of the enjoyment of these games really is the funny and weird crap that happens.
Speaker 0: you want to experience it, that's why I'm kind of interested in Kentucky Route Zero.
Speaker 1: ok, so you've been talking about this Kentucky Route Zero, so far you've said it's a point and click adventure that looks like out of this world.
Speaker 0: so as far as I can tell by reading around a little bit on the internet there aren't really puzzles.
Speaker 0: it has the interface and aesthetic of a point and click adventure.
Speaker 0: but it is just, see the interesting stuff that's happening and try to figure out the story of this place.
Speaker 0: there is no puzzle to solve.
Speaker 0: it's also episodic and it doesn't end apparently yet.
Speaker 1: I should wait for more of it then and buy the whole thing.
Speaker 0: well right now it's going to be on Steam soon.
Speaker 1: I'll wait for there to be a giant bundle like Kentucky Route Zero complete edition.
Speaker 0: right now it's $25 for the whole thing or $7 per act, there's only one act out.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's too much.
Speaker 0: I'm going to buy the act one because I want to see what the deal is.
Speaker 0: because in that Magfest panel, the point James Portnau made that was really interesting was that we talk a lot about genre in games.
Speaker 0: we always define it by game mechanics and he pointed out that pretty much every other medium except music, as we came up in the discussion talks a lot more about mood and feeling like Phil Noire is more about the atmosphere than it is about the black and white camera angle close-ups.
Speaker 0: but we talk more about horror movies, but yet when we say survival horror game, we usually mean action, you know third person shooter or tank controls or something this feels like this is in the style of an adventure game point and click, but it is a game that is defined by the feeling it gives you and the experiences you have.
Speaker 0: so I want to give that kind of game a big chance.
Speaker 1: I have nothing against that, I just think it's not really a game, it's closer to what a boogie is.
Speaker 0: this is the one point where we disagree with Garfield in his book, I think we can define what a game is very well if we use our three definitions.
Speaker 1: what skill is this testing, right?
Speaker 0: a game is a game if it satisfies any one of our three definitions.
Speaker 0: it's like three types of games, either a competitive test of one or more skills.
Speaker 1: so this is not that?
Speaker 0: No what is the second definition?
Speaker 0: Oh, a series of meaningful decisions or a consensual interactive amusement?
Speaker 1: yeah, it's an amusement.
Speaker 1: it's like a Nickelodeon, you put a nickel in you take a look, you have fun you click on things and you have fun the same thing as Dungeon Village, you click on it and you have fun.
Speaker 0: Yes, but it is distinct from a novel or a book in that you are interacting, you could miss things, your interaction might be different than someone else's interaction and consensual has to be in there.
Speaker 0: because of a good example that I thought of a couple days ago at the panel last year, people were like, it has to be consensual but no one really gave a good reason why.
Speaker 0: here's why let's say every day I break into your apartment and I piss in your Cheerios so I'm making your life worse.
Speaker 1: that's just vandalism.
Speaker 0: so maybe it's a game to me, I'm like, I wonder if I can get in and do this, how many days can I do this before I get caught?
Speaker 0: it's a game to me, for me, that is a game pissing Scott's Cheerios.
Speaker 0: it's not a game for Scott because it's not consensual, now if Scott consented to that of, alright, I will try to catch you pissing in my Cheerios and then, you know, whatever then it's a game for both of us.
Speaker 0: or a better example, bullying to a lot of bullies or trolls, it's a game but it is really missing the point to call it a game from the context of the person being bullied.
Speaker 1: some people will say, you know, you think this is a game right, that's what they're talking about exactly, it's like, you think this is a game but it's not, I'm not playing, only you're playing.
Speaker 0: but I think and actually it's kind of my challenge to you listeners is there something you think is a game that does not satisfy one of those three?
Speaker 0: I'm just curious because I really like our definitions and I really want to do something with those definitions other than have the slide in every panel.
Speaker 0: we do alright.
Speaker 1: I think we talked enough about these.
Speaker 1: I mean, really, I've talked about most of the ones that I've played extensively.
Speaker 1: I've played a lot of them, a little bit each so it's not like I have much to say about any specific ones.
Speaker 1: I remember playing the Indiana Jones one on the Mac, that one was pretty good.
Speaker 1: the Atlantis one.
Speaker 0: I played a bunch of the King's Quest, I played as many of the police quests as I could get.
Speaker 0: I didn't play any space quests ever, so I don't know anything about them me either, I know what it looks like.
Speaker 1: I could recognize it, like oh, that space quest.
Speaker 0: I played the SCUMM ones.
Speaker 0: I didn't like them even as a kid but yet I liked all the other kinds except for King's Quest.
Speaker 1: and you know, I played a lot as younger but my memory is more vague I did a more recent replay of a lot of SCUMM VMs, like a year or two ago of SCUMM games.
Speaker 1: and yeah, it's pretty much like, oh, I just want to fack, you know, fuck this bullshit.
Speaker 0: Oh, Quest for Glorious also have action-based combat.
Speaker 1: I guess we should say the words Monkey Island, so no one gets mad.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, Monkey Island games yes, they're funny.
Speaker 0: the comedy that happens in them is hilarious.
Speaker 1: That is the enjoyment pretty much comes 90% from the comedy and the rest of it, whatever.
Speaker 0: And yes, they wouldn't work as just cartoons because some of the jokes involve the mechanics.
Speaker 0: I can think of a bunch of examples where there's only one option to click on, but the fact that that is the option you have to click on it is hilarious.
Speaker 1: But, you could just watch someone play on YouTube and get 99% of the enjoyment from them, as long as the person explored all of the things.
Speaker 0: Yep, I don't need to play these games again for any reason except nostalgia.
Speaker 0: but, like I said, I'm gonna give Kentucky Route Zero a try and if it passes muster I will see that.
Speaker 0: Scott does the same and we'll talk about that.
Speaker 0: and before any of you haters start bitching about us, we didn't really say anything bad about your genre nor did we talk about the history of it or get anything wrong about.
Speaker 0: well, technically, you know, ScumVM came one year after this other emulator whatever.
Speaker 0: don't tell us about games we didn't talk about unless you think they'd be worth playing.
Speaker 0: In fact, if there's a game out there with this Light Quest for Glory that I didn't play I kinda wanna know, because Quest for Glory 2 I played again like a couple years ago and it really holds up.
Speaker 1: I hear us talking.
Speaker 0: That's because the Closer music was playing in the background very faintly.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's what it was.