Speaker 0: Hey, it's Tuesday, January 8th, I'm rim Scott and this is geek nuts back from magfest not yet in Istanbul.
Speaker 0: We're doing a show on viva, Java encore worlds and castles of Burgundy and magfest.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I think this year after two years of magfest we can do the Colossus roar without sounding like morons.
Speaker 0: No, we figured it out.
Speaker 0: There's these.
Speaker 0: there is actually a technique to.
Speaker 1: it is not is not pleasant to do it.
Speaker 0: It is that that I think.
Speaker 0: that is why it is self-limiting because if you want to do it you're Sacrificing some of your precious throat HP to make that roar come out.
Speaker 0: throat HP.
Speaker 1: Your throat has HP at a convention, you know I mean even Colossus can only do it like three times on a couple quarters.
Speaker 0: He needs more quarters I know and for me instead of quarters, it's a throat drops.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how many Rico laws does it cost?
Speaker 0: It's like half a Rico law per shout.
Speaker 0: Yeah But the key I realized you actually got to kind of bring your shoulders up like you're gonna make the movement and you got to Start like normal, but then you have to kind of go warbly at the end in a way.
Speaker 0: That isn't pleasant and I'm not going to replicate now on the show.
Speaker 1: No Well, like we can't until it's time to prepare for magfest again.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, that would be inappropriate.
Speaker 0: You know, we could be like those monks who will maintain a chant continuously forever, but they're like, oh Yeah, so what we need to do is get like a thousand people who will Colossus roar back and forth across like a state constantly.
Speaker 0: But yeah, we were at magfest and we don't really want to dedicate a whole show to reviewing magfest.
Speaker 0: So one if you want a detailed review of magfest check out our previous Reviews of magfest
Speaker 1: because much of that is still exactly the same relevant information to this magfest such as complaining about wristbands And what magfest is like and what the building is like and what the people are like?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so this magfest was awesome.
Speaker 0: It was great.
Speaker 0: I had a great time as expect it was as expected.
Speaker 0: Yep Thanks to all of you who hung out with us played games with us came to our panels and lectures Came to that weird thing that happened at 3 in the morning on Saturday.
Speaker 0: I don't know what to say about that except it was weird and enlightening but not in the way the people who were there think it was.
Speaker 0: I'll just leave that Alone.
Speaker 0: that was an interesting time.
Speaker 0: So I want to get complaints out of the way because I don't want to leave even the various hint of an impression that magfest Is a bad convention or I really have almost nothing to complain about magfest except for the existing Wristband complaint from the prior episode.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna leave that off.
Speaker 0: Well, I do want to bring it up again because we did something different this year.
Speaker 1: Oh, what do we do different?
Speaker 0: first, you know for those of you who aren't aware magfest gives everyone a wristband says it's required And it checks your ID.
Speaker 0: So basically you wear this thing that shows whether or not you're under 18 under 21 or over 21.
Speaker 1: No other convention I've ever been to does this ever no convention anywhere.
Speaker 1: and this year They did have the nerve.
Speaker 1: this year They said if you lose your wristband five bucks for a new one.
Speaker 1: that was new this year.
Speaker 0: now What's interesting is last year?
Speaker 0: They were like this wristband and this waiver and the waiver was bullshit and the wristband was bull.
Speaker 1: at least the waiver is gone.
Speaker 0: So at least I didn't have to sign the way they forced me to take the wristband.
Speaker 0: I ripped it off in front of them.
Speaker 0: They were mad but I didn't care and I took the waiver.
Speaker 0: I signed Rainbow Dash.
Speaker 1: I didn't do the waiver I did.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they didn't give me a waiver.
Speaker 0: Let note last year.
Speaker 0: Oh This year they got rid of the stupid waiver.
Speaker 1: Well, at least I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think I saw someone else signing a paper, but I don't think in our line we signed it But I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: yeah in our line There was no waiver given or mentioned and I busted not sign one.
Speaker 0: last year Rainbow Dash signed one on behalf of me.
Speaker 0: But yeah, not only did they have the audacity to say the wristband was required force you to get it they put it on you instead of just handing it to you and the sign said, you know five bucks or whatever, but Scott was like, well, I was like fine put it on me and the girl put it on really loose.
Speaker 0: I immediately took it off and put it in my pocket and never pulled it out again.
Speaker 0: Scott argued and I walked away and you were arguing there for like four minutes.
Speaker 1: I just you know was having a friendly conversation about it.
Speaker 0: Yes, you were friendly.
Speaker 1: to the guy's credit He saw my point when I said well, you know, don't you see?
Speaker 1: but if you put a wristband on someone you verify that They are over 21. and if this wristband were to go to someone who was under 21 or if their ID was fake or he gave someone the wrong wristband and maybe some 17 year old gets drunk wearing a 21 year old wristband.
Speaker 1: now that's on you.
Speaker 1: and he said I See your point so credit to that guy.
Speaker 0: However two staffers there after our follow-up argument said Specifically, they don't want to do the wristbands, but the venue forces them to know the same guy.
Speaker 1: I said who told I that was the same guy?
Speaker 1: I said who told you to do this?
Speaker 1: the same question I asked last year, but this is a different guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and he's like.
Speaker 1: I'm like.
Speaker 1: did a lawyer tell you to do this.
Speaker 1: I'm not a lawyer either.
Speaker 1: I'm just asking did a lawyer tell you to do this?
Speaker 1: and he said He said the hotel told us to do it Just been pulling that out of his derriere.
Speaker 0: Oh, perhaps he was because one no one wears fucking wristbands at katsu khan in the same venue with a similar demographic?
Speaker 1: Of course not and two.
Speaker 0: I won't name names, but I talked to staff Who were more.
Speaker 0: I guess not not just the reg guy and to quote one of these staff.
Speaker 0: I will not name.
Speaker 0: That is ridiculous.
Speaker 1: I think it's ridiculous.
Speaker 0: Also, so, you know what what but here's the thing is weird.
Speaker 0: This is why I really want to talk about the wristbands.
Speaker 0: Scott and I didn't wear ours.
Speaker 1: I think not once were we checked for wristbands.
Speaker 0: Not only that Everyone else at the con was wearing these grody ass barely hanging together wristbands.
Speaker 1: by Sunday for four days They showered with the wristband three times saying this shower.
Speaker 0: So seriously, we were the only ones without wristbands everyone.
Speaker 0: Everyone had a fucking wristband.
Speaker 0: half the guests had wristbands.
Speaker 0: I think dr.
Speaker 0: Hazard even had a wristband on.
Speaker 0: I didn't check him.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the hell's hands pocket a lot but a lot of people didn't have the wristbands.
Speaker 0: and what's even weirder is that Scott are the only people who think the wristbands are dumb or Even think to complain about how ridiculous it is.
Speaker 0: because if you look in the mag vest forum The only three posts about wristbands are one me complaining about them once last year me following up on my complaint Mm-hmm and someone complaining they didn't get one.
Speaker 0: I Know well, I've noticed.
Speaker 0: people generally accept the authority of Convention people in general and we're just dicks.
Speaker 0: Yeah granted if that Otakon woman screams at me ever again about no cameras allowed in the line I might cry.
Speaker 1: are you gonna cry?
Speaker 0: I don't want to hear anyone talk to me like that ever again in my life.
Speaker 1: Well, what if someone did?
Speaker 1: what would you do to them?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I might just cry as I'm reminded of because you're upset I'm reminded of the folly but you're not gonna just get in their face and be like screw you.
Speaker 1: Don't talk to me like that.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what?
Speaker 0: I might just put earplugs in.
Speaker 0: But you know, that's pretty much my biggest Complaint about mag fast and that's pretty minor.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: No rampart machine.
Speaker 0: I guess they only have initial d3 Six and they only had like five.
Speaker 1: d Arcade machines are all brought by private owners.
Speaker 1: people privately own these are Machines.
Speaker 0: the bunch of them were brought by that same group that we got a Connecticut right a private owner, right?
Speaker 1: So it's oh, yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So it's.
Speaker 1: there are people who own these machines and they bring them to mag fest on their own Volition and then they bring them away.
Speaker 0: I know what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: is that my biggest complaint?
Speaker 1: So you're complaining that the people who own initial d6 machines.
Speaker 1: don't bring them to mag.
Speaker 0: Yeah What I'm saying is the level of complaints I have for mag fest are so tiny and insignificant.
Speaker 1: the table top library is pathetic.
Speaker 0: yeah, the tabletop library is Worse than anime Boston's tabletop library.
Speaker 1: It's slightly better than that.
Speaker 0: Ah, well, okay last year's was worse.
Speaker 0: This year's was equivalent mmm.
Speaker 1: Animate Boston's tabletop library is a Dominion box and a munchkin box.
Speaker 0: They had other boxes, but I like the thing is we weren't.
Speaker 0: we didn't actually go there last year because we're packs the whole time.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know how it's changed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they may have changed it I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: so I heard it's gone Actually that I would.
Speaker 1: I would not be surprised or at least if it's that room pretty much only Existed for that one vendor who was in there selling his monster miniatures game.
Speaker 0: It also existed for you and me to have somewhere to go when we weren't running like it's something to do in the hotels Overnight.
Speaker 0: also, it was a place where all our friends in Boston would meet us because they didn't actually want to go to anime Boston and no one ever checked badges.
Speaker 0: Yep The food and drink policy in the main con also really annoying hotels problem Problem.
Speaker 0: what was interesting is that magfest, you know nominally enforced it and the enforcement was Spotty to the point of if you were asked to remove it Like some people would walk over you be like, dude You can't have that Red Bull in here, even though it's sealed and there's no way that could be alcohol.
Speaker 1: Here's here's my advice for magfest from that issue.
Speaker 0: Tell the hotel to enforce it exactly.
Speaker 1: Yes, look at kinetic on kinetic on.
Speaker 1: I tried to bring donuts in kinetic on staff Didn't give two shits about me bringing donuts.
Speaker 0: Look as you were.
Speaker 1: only the Convention Center staff gave a shit.
Speaker 1: if you sit on the you know Heaters on the side of the way, you know The Convention Center staff are the ones who tell you don't do that.
Speaker 1: kinetic on staff might be like hey guys You know, I do that too.
Speaker 1: I'll be like, hey if I if the Convention Center staff see you doing that they're gonna tell you to stop and I'll you know Just to help people out.
Speaker 1: funny if you're nice, but I don't actually make anyone not do it.
Speaker 1: That is the Convention Center's job.
Speaker 1: If the Convention Center does not want people bringing outside food or drink Magfest should say then you stop them.
Speaker 1: We don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: You can't make us do it.
Speaker 0: But like I had some coffee I bought at the convention and they were like you can't bring that in here While they were telling me that they let a dude walk by with a big gulp that he was just drinking out of.
Speaker 1: Well, I think number one is they were letting staff do it.
Speaker 0: They think it wasn't staff.
Speaker 0: who's just some right?
Speaker 1: number two It was pretty much like selective enforcement.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't be surprised if maybe because you did see Convention Center staff around it might have been a Convention Center staffer Telling the magfest staffers stop that guy.
Speaker 1: Stop that guy.
Speaker 1: Because I was the hotel.
Speaker 0: I was listening to the Actually caring.
Speaker 0: I was listening to the radios for magfest staff and basically there'd be a swarm of enforcement every time.
Speaker 0: They carded a crazy drunk having bombed it all over person away and there were a number of them.
Speaker 1: There were many back.
Speaker 1: there was.
Speaker 1: there was many.
Speaker 0: there was the Willy sawdust in the lobby Or in on the lobby in the landing of our best is a 24/7 drunken fest.
Speaker 1: Everyone knows this.
Speaker 0: It is not a I believe you mean a convention.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: It's 24/7 Drunkenness.
Speaker 1: everybody knows that's what it is.
Speaker 1: It's not a surprise to anybody.
Speaker 0: Yep About the drunks because they really don't get in my way and I actually find them hilarious and endearing.
Speaker 1: They have never once vomited on me near me or on my things or on an arcade machine as far as I know.
Speaker 0: so So for us our magfest the hit of the year was space war.
Speaker 1: Well space wars.
Speaker 1: I've done research on this.
Speaker 1: So everyone knows.
Speaker 1: the first video game for the pdp-1 Also the first video game ever the same way the asteroid is the first anime ever is space war Which is a game that's sort of like versus asteroids or two people try to asteroids each other, right?
Speaker 1: There is a game a vector based game with a vector display called space wars space space Wars and it is a arcade machine that was made by a guy at MIT.
Speaker 1: It was basically a better space war.
Speaker 1: right and One ship is like the enterprise and one ship is like a Star Destroyer and it has modifications.
Speaker 1: like you turn on gravity Make the gravity stronger.
Speaker 1: you can have a Sun.
Speaker 1: no Sun there is a Sun but you can't see it.
Speaker 1: It's a black hole.
Speaker 1: all these, you know variables And it is a very good direct versus one-on-one game of skill Extremely precise very much like star control 2 hyper melee with a lot less with no variation in ships.
Speaker 1: So it's.
Speaker 1: it's completely symmetrical in every way and it's just who gets the most Scores by killing the other guy before time runs out and time is how many quarters you put in.
Speaker 0: It's pretty great and I played more of that than pretty much any other arcade machine.
Speaker 0: That was multiplayer.
Speaker 1: Played it about the same.
Speaker 1: Oh multiplayer.
Speaker 1: Okay, cuz we played Dig Dug.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we played Dig Dug.
Speaker 1: who won Dig Dug?
Speaker 0: You did win Dig Dug Mario brothers.
Speaker 1: that were not super.
Speaker 0: What's going on?
Speaker 0: You wouldn't play nibbles or Wizard of War.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Well nibble.
Speaker 1: Well, I did play nibble.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't had a problem playing it, but there was someone at it when at the time we were gonna play it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Wizard of War.
Speaker 1: I had no problem playing.
Speaker 1: who wouldn't joust.
Speaker 1: I think I won joust also.
Speaker 0: Who won Eclipse?
Speaker 0: what rim and Scott won Eclipse?
Speaker 0: both Everybody.
Speaker 1: but meanwhile, I carried that Eclipse.
Speaker 0: I had 41 points.
Speaker 0: You had.
Speaker 1: I had 41 Scott.
Speaker 1: We have witnesses.
Speaker 1: I had 41 points.
Speaker 1: I counted 41 up.
Speaker 1: You had 40.
Speaker 1: I had 41.
Speaker 0: I had 41 did not have 40.
Speaker 0: Why do I need to go get Pete and Phil?
Speaker 1: I had 41 points.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm just saying there are multiple people.
Speaker 1: I counted two times and on my second counting.
Speaker 1: It was 41.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying there were multiple people there.
Speaker 1: Are you sure you think I'm a hundred percent?
Speaker 1: I counted the second time and it was 40. actually because there was one.
Speaker 0: That game would not have gone that way and it would not have been a coalition of rim.
Speaker 0: and Scott Pete and Phil coalitioned early a lot allied.
Speaker 1: It's not a coalition alliance.
Speaker 1: The
Speaker 0: problem is they did this before Scott and I had fought and I had set up a turn where the next turn I was gonna send my entire army in because I played the guys who start way powerful Mm-hmm, and I was just gonna fuck Scott up because I get money every time I kill someone.
Speaker 0: I was going to do it.
Speaker 0: It was a foregone conclusion and then Phil and Pete allied.
Speaker 0: So it comes to my turn and I'm not gonna fuck the chance of allying.
Speaker 0: nor am I gonna face a coalition?
Speaker 0: Yeah by myself.
Speaker 0: So they basically lost the game by allying one turn too soon.
Speaker 0: Had they waited I would have fucked Scott.
Speaker 0: they would have allied it would have been them versus me and Scott would have been just Like fighting off and I would have been done and we both lost.
Speaker 1: personally I think that the if I played Eclipse again, because this is the first time using the expansion, right?
Speaker 1: I would continue to use The extra sciency parts, right?
Speaker 1: Because basically those just come out there and they hurt you as much as they help you Right, so it sort of doesn't really hurt the game and it sort of makes it like fun and tricky if you happen to get One of those right and different to those.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like the more aliens more.
Speaker 1: I like the more aliens and I wish we brought in some more those space hexes and more discovery things.
Speaker 0: I wish we brought in the super dangerous ancients.
Speaker 1: Oh that too.
Speaker 1: That would have been awesome as well.
Speaker 1: But the Alliance's I don't really like.
Speaker 1: I kind of like this the regular Also, I would like I was the strongest and the most dangerous and the highest score.
Speaker 1: you were hardly and I was just regular old boring humans.
Speaker 0: You were hardly In fact, you would have been out of the game had I attacked you except for my incredibly powerful ships.
Speaker 1: I was in fact, I think was that warmly one.
Speaker 0: yet because I started with a bunch of stuff in I think I think I was the only one to bring dreadknots on the board period cuz I can't build dreadknots Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I didn't need to.
Speaker 0: I had free shields Anyway, and I could move four units for move action.
Speaker 1: I took the center.
Speaker 0: I demolished Pete you took the center baby because we agreed because we had to ally.
Speaker 1: It's not like you would have been able to take it from me.
Speaker 0: I could have taken it with two fucking interceptors because of my leveled up assholes.
Speaker 1: No wouldn't happen.
Speaker 0: Your memory is faulty.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna bring Pete on the show and we're gonna discuss what happened in this game.
Speaker 0: I was the devastating army of doom Anyway, uh But yeah, I mean the concerts we went to.
Speaker 0: two years of magfest.
Speaker 0: never been to a concert before.
Speaker 1: Well the first year like, you know, two years ago That's nine.
Speaker 0: fuck that two years ago is tiny smelly room smelled like the inside of the whole con smelled.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that room was like concentrated.
Speaker 1: ooh to but last year just didn't go for whatever reason it was too busy doing the other things.
Speaker 1: this year on the schedule was the you show Wasn't it?
Speaker 0: The streets of rage?
Speaker 0: I didn't know.
Speaker 0: he also did actor a sir.
Speaker 1: He did it also like shinobi and some other games but because he did the streets of rage music Which is in my eyes the second best video game music ever after the Megaman music, right?
Speaker 1: I was like, I'm going to see whatever music this guy is playing.
Speaker 0: So he ran an awesome DJ dance party and I was getting those Otacon o2 feels one.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of videos of it on YouTube with one with good audio.
Speaker 0: people were dancing - it was Actual dance music and not bullshit dance music.
Speaker 0: Yeah three It did not smell at all.
Speaker 1: It was oc remixes of video game music by the guy who originally made that music.
Speaker 0: There was zero Bo.
Speaker 0: it smelled like.
Speaker 0: It's not like an empty room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was amazing to me.
Speaker 0: I cannot stress this for most of the people in that room were around my age.
Speaker 0: I I think I can go back to dances at things again.
Speaker 1: Yep The the best part of it was what's that beeping noise?
Speaker 0: That was my Skype ringing.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess my Google boys.
Speaker 1: Oh, anyway, whatevs the best part was that you know Even though this guy he even said so that he clearly did not have a lot of live DJing skills or practice in the past Can just keep talking.
Speaker 0: I don't know why I keep distracting you over here.
Speaker 1: I don't know all these noises coming from your computer all over the place.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what the listener can't hear them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay listener anyway the What's it called?
Speaker 1: So even though his DJ skills were low and if you watch on YouTube, you know You can see he messes up a few times like once he accidentally mutes all and brings it all back.
Speaker 0: That was hilarious cuz he keeps going like this like he's like Ravens arms.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then there's no music and then he's like And then like a couple times like switches tracks and it gets all messed up during the transition.
Speaker 1: it's sort of just like.
Speaker 1: And the other song now, you know what though don't fucking care It didn't matter because the songs the music when it was going right was so good.
Speaker 0: I'll let you guys in on a secret unless I am at a like Exhibition of DJ skills.
Speaker 0: I literally do not care.
Speaker 1: Yeah The guys a composer music.
Speaker 1: I would have been much at it You know, why didn't he just bring a CD and play it and dance for us, right?
Speaker 1: I would have been just as happy.
Speaker 1: I really don't give a shit if it's mixed live.
Speaker 1: the only advantage I see to mixing live is if you can gauge the feels of the crowd and Then you could live mix, you know one part to last a little longer, you know one part to go a little harder.
Speaker 1: Right as you see how the people's are doing out there, but if you're not capable of doing that, you know And it's also not strictly necessary.
Speaker 1: Just play a CD of your music if it's electronic music.
Speaker 1: unless you are creating music live You know with like Ableton something that's different again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but so I want to point something out.
Speaker 0: the drunken gamer convention Known in the past for its horrible smell has no problem with this.
Speaker 0: in a large pretty intense dance party What the fuck?
Speaker 0: anime cons?
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: Why do you people smell so bad?
Speaker 1: There were some smelly people there was at least one time when I was sitting in a place and I smelled Oh, yes in the convention.
Speaker 0: There were occasional smelly people, but you've been to anime cons.
Speaker 0: got you walk.
Speaker 1: Did we play any rhythm games at magfest?
Speaker 1: Even though they had an excellent selection of B money I did and they didn't smell like anything.
Speaker 0: The only place that smelled bad was the PC gaming area.
Speaker 1: I didn't go there.
Speaker 0: I walked over there and it smelled somebody in the LAN party smelled like a butt.
Speaker 0: Mmm the entire time.
Speaker 0: I do not know who.
Speaker 1: there is also the factor of the PC game gaming area.
Speaker 1: Someone may have brought their smelly butt computer from their smelly butt house.
Speaker 1: No Blowing their smelly butt all over thing is.
Speaker 0: smelly butt from a computer usually just smells like stale cigarette smoke.
Speaker 0: This was the ode to fat fanboy.
Speaker 1: There have been cases of poop in computers in the past.
Speaker 1: It has happened.
Speaker 0: I will not deny that.
Speaker 1: Has happened anything else to say about magfest?
Speaker 0: Oh, they expanded the arcade and they expanded tabletop to her.
Speaker 0: tabletop was as big as the arcade and was in a room with windows.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it wasn't as big as the arcade.
Speaker 1: there was a significant area that was taken up by table flipping for charity.
Speaker 1: While it looked fun that area turned into tabletop when the tabletop flipping was not happening and it was for charity Which is always laudable.
Speaker 1: It was annoying to have it next to tabletop But you do your table flipping in a place where noise doesn't really matter like maybe near the video game.
Speaker 0: There was also a great moment where a guy paid a lot of money to stack three tables on each other.
Speaker 0: I'm really surprised.
Speaker 0: He didn't break his face.
Speaker 1: Yeah It was you know.
Speaker 1: No Very few people were able to flip the table in an elegant and awesome way.
Speaker 1: many just sort of flipped them like derp.
Speaker 0: it flipped Okay Interesting you can get charity money for letting people do something.
Speaker 0: They can easily do in their own homes, but You get some charity money, but again, just don't do it in tabletop.
Speaker 0: next year Do.
Speaker 1: tabletop needs to be more quiet than the other places.
Speaker 0: Yes, cuz we need to play games.
Speaker 0: Yes I'm not magnificent fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: Our panels went great.
Speaker 0: We had cool talks about stuff.
Speaker 1: How could you not go to mag fests if you're a gaming person anywhere nearby?
Speaker 0: And I'm gonna tell you guys this now though.
Speaker 0: It's not relevant yet I learned you know kinetic on.
Speaker 0: we schedule like 220 230 panels every year.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: We get submissions in the four digits.
Speaker 0: Yep Magfest gets submissions in the double digits and they have a very tiny number of panel rooms.
Speaker 0: I want them to get more panel rooms when they open up panels.
Speaker 1: They have a lot of panel rooms.
Speaker 1: They had like six panel rooms, but they most of them are just empty all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they really don't have a panel culture and the biggest complaint I saw is that there weren't enough panels grant.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot of feedback.
Speaker 1: the mag fest online community forum is very small.
Speaker 0: Yes, so if you want to go to mag fest submit a panel they kind of use some submissions.
Speaker 1: Well, they also need to accept more percentage to fill their really just every.
Speaker 1: if you have a panel room There should be something in that panel room with breaks in between all the time And they have.
Speaker 1: you know, their con goes overnight.
Speaker 1: So why aren't they using the rooms overnight for things?
Speaker 0: Well, they give it us.
Speaker 0: I mean we would have happily done another lecture.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we only did one lecture and two panels.
Speaker 0: We would have done more but they didn't want him but then there was empty space.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: The final thing about mag fest is mag fest next year.
Speaker 1: now We've already been encouraging you to go to mag fest as you should every year and multiple listeners came out to me and said Something to the effect of.
Speaker 0: I'm glad I finally listened to you guys and came to mag fest.
Speaker 1: you should listen to us and everything we say including don't listen to this podcast, but The listener might disagree.
Speaker 1: if you don't listen to this podcast It may be hard for you to get our other advice on things.
Speaker 1: You should do because that's right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, don't do it Donnie don't does Next year at mag fest the miracle I've been waiting for For?
Speaker 1: I think it's ten years if probably possibly more than ten years.
Speaker 0: There was a moment when I think Scott is definitely me to this band.
Speaker 1: No, I can definitely.
Speaker 1: I can tell you exactly how this happened.
Speaker 1: All right, we discovered it in the colony apartment of Alex and Greg.
Speaker 0: I know it was cut was it Alex?
Speaker 1: I think it was Greg slash Alex.
Speaker 1: They had already known about it and we discovered they had shared it to us by playing it there during D&D which means it was in the year of 2001 or 2 and But now in the year of 2014, so Twelve years later minimum.
Speaker 1: I don't know how they lasted that long.
Speaker 1: I guess they're just that awesome.
Speaker 1: finally Finally in the United States for the first time ever it is confirmed 100% unless something happens to the cancellation and I might have to hurt myself Machine supremacy is gonna be a mag fest.
Speaker 0: You may know them as mock and I supremacy and one.
Speaker 1: you're wrong because well We used to say that because you look at the name and that's what it fucking says.
Speaker 1: But in case you want don't want to get it wrong.
Speaker 1: if you watch concert video Nobody stands out in the audience going machine supremacy.
Speaker 1: Whoo?
Speaker 1: Everyone just says ma sue mas.
Speaker 1: so you can just say masu and it's the easy way out.
Speaker 0: You know, you can't get it wrong saying that I am the most excited about seeing them perform live that I've been for any live Performance of any music in my life.
Speaker 1: I am a hundred percent In a thousand percent agreement, so we're gonna be at that concert.
Speaker 0: We're probably gonna line up for that line up at least two hours in advance.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be next I don't know how long in advance you gotta line up.
Speaker 0: If someone if someone could give me the good hookup, which I very rarely ask for This is my wife.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna use a hookup.
Speaker 1: This is what I'm gonna use it.
Speaker 1: I better be in that room somewhere close To the front part and not the back part, but the front part and a little bit to the right for the entire time.
Speaker 1: Duration of the thing.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, and maybe they'll come play arcade games with us.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I learned this.
Speaker 0: I was at mag fest because I was supposed to go to Istanbul Sunday after mag.
Speaker 0: I learned it later.
Speaker 1: We only confirmation I have is a bunch of tweets of people I guess to assume went to closing ceremonies and heard it there.
Speaker 0: now I was going to go to closing ceremonies But instead I was trying to frantically figure out if I was going to Istanbul or not and ended up not.
Speaker 1: I did not Believe these tweets until one of said tweets was retweeted by machine supremacy's Twitter account itself Which is a hundred percent confirmation in the book of Scott.
Speaker 0: or they're mocking us or they're mocking us.
Speaker 1: in which case Good job guys you win.
Speaker 0: but I saw this tweet while I was pooping in my hotel room and the poop came out real fast and I was like I Should probably get a second source before I say anything.
Speaker 1: when I saw that I just Really hit retreat.
Speaker 0: I didn't even didn't even think about it.
Speaker 0: I was like if this is wrong that I don't want to be right about it being wrong.
Speaker 1: and this is now.
Speaker 1: Magfest is beating packs in two areas.
Speaker 1: now I think it may even be pulling closely to equal to packs the fact that it's arcade is vastly superior Yeah, and it's concerts are now Vastly superior.
Speaker 0: Alright, so what magfest doesn't have yet to bring it up to PAX level for us is one tabletop.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have a proper tabletop.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It does not have panels.
Speaker 0: Well, it doesn't.
Speaker 0: not only does not have panels really any expo holic did the.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 0: I'm saying it doesn't for us mean Scott, you know the best place for pinky.
Speaker 0: It does not have the sort of scope and scale of panels and lectures that I prefer.
Speaker 0: I mean, I like presenting at magfest is very intimate setting.
Speaker 0: It's very fun.
Speaker 0: I can say fuck a lot But I'm more enjoy the sort of polished.
Speaker 0: There is a giant audience who can't interact with me.
Speaker 1: Yes way of presenting, you know packs also is falling behind a magfest in only one other aspects Machine supremacist.
Speaker 1: No story already said that part the concerts.
Speaker 1: The super art fight is at magfest and not at packs.
Speaker 0: it is and that was a really good super art fight.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 0: I was a pretty good one team stomp it on really should have won that.
Speaker 1: That was the only time in a super art fight in which the team that I believed was worthy of winning Was not the winning team.
Speaker 0: I was actually kind of sad about that.
Speaker 0: I was like I'd never felt that Bowser in the top, right?
Speaker 1: It was all about that Venusaur with the two whips going and the look on his face.
Speaker 1: I know it was so.
Speaker 1: as soon as I saw the Venusaur I was like, that's a winner and the somehow they didn't win.
Speaker 1: What do they were up against like some Metroids and angry cloud, but they were up against the standbys.
Speaker 0: The people are basically usually only beaten by yuko.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's They.
Speaker 0: if anyone's gonna challenge yuko's undefeated throne, it's gonna be stomp it on.
Speaker 1: I really want to see.
Speaker 0: I want to see yuko versus stomp it on.
Speaker 1: well Yes But I really want to see like I had this vision while I was watching super art fight a vision super art fight The TV show.
Speaker 1: it's like once a week maybe maybe once a day Whatever right and it's a real tournament, which I think they do anyway, but it's sort, you know It would be like professional wrestling maybe, you know with because it's already going in that direction with the belt.
Speaker 0: All right I have a crazy idea.
Speaker 1: bring in lots of artists and big-name artists of all kind.
Speaker 0: I have a crazy crazy idea right like, you know, we're friends with them and they're gonna be a kinetic on.
Speaker 0: We always bring them back.
Speaker 0: We're gonna make sure they don't get fucked by the stupid cosplay kinetic on this year.
Speaker 0: But more importantly do you want to talk to them and We don't speak for them.
Speaker 0: This is just us being dumbasses.
Speaker 0: we could get a crew and film the entire thing with a bunch of cameras and Edit it together into a show for them to use as a pilot Which would also be a big marketing thing for kinetic on.
Speaker 1: We'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying they should really.
Speaker 1: they're going to the west coast.
Speaker 1: So they're already getting bigger.
Speaker 0: Right, let's try to pull strings to get them into packs.
Speaker 1: we got it.
Speaker 0: Let's try to get you know What.
Speaker 0: let's see if they'll let.
Speaker 0: if they won't let them headline for like a main event.
Speaker 0: see if they can headline for us Like super are fine.
Speaker 0: and then gig nights does their talk about that would be us mooching on them.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: It's no good Like that one lecture of ours where it's the video starts with crazy applause and it cuts out the part right before that run like Let's give the enforcers a round of applause.
Speaker 1: Anyway, let's move on to the rest of our show The things of the day.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be a little self-serving But I got a video I uploaded and I'm making this my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: You're not allowed to do that.
Speaker 0: I'm a nerd who's into my nerdy thing.
Speaker 0: And this is a nerdy thing.
Speaker 0: I'm really into that.
Speaker 0: a lot of you probably should nerd out about at least a little but - I went through great trouble to acquire these videos, so this is a Performing three songs in late 1996.
Speaker 0: You know, what's awesome about this video?
Speaker 0: I Still have a mustache in it, but you can't really see because this is just a video of one of the performance.
Speaker 1: You're a white stick.
Speaker 0: Yes, but there are other.
Speaker 0: I have video walking stick 97 98 99 as well.
Speaker 0: And in those later videos, there are close-ups of me doing solos and you can clearly see the mustache.
Speaker 0: I look older than than I do now.
Speaker 0: It's kind of amazing.
Speaker 0: But I was pretty proud of my high school marching band and this is my high school marching band doing its marching band thing.
Speaker 0: No one else has uploaded this on the internet.
Speaker 0: and it brought up another interesting thing because I was talking to my friend Ken Who is in this video?
Speaker 0: Also, he's a bass drummer and we went to high school together.
Speaker 0: He's in the forum.
Speaker 0: He's Ken Jura.
Speaker 0: So if he's still here, you guys can be like, oh, that's that dude the one guy who has evidence of pre RIT rim.
Speaker 1: great.
Speaker 0: That dude and I were in the marching band together and we started talking about how basically anything that happened before about 2003 or four really just isn't on the fucking internet.
Speaker 0: No, like there are so few videos of things before then like now a kid growing up you're in college You're like, hey, I wonder if there's a video of my.
Speaker 0: you know, the time I was in Middle school football and YouTube will have a million hits.
Speaker 0: So we're one of the last generations to grow up in an era where there is not an archive.
Speaker 1: there is it's just on VHS tapes that no one transferred to digital exactly and they're disappearing rapidly again.
Speaker 0: I went through such ridiculous trouble to get just this tape.
Speaker 1: What did you do?
Speaker 0: All right, so Three years ago.
Speaker 0: I Emailed the company that I knew had last had an archival copy of this Asking if I could buy one.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I got no response.
Speaker 0: All right Yeah, I tried other avenues of inquiry ranging from contacting the school Trying to contact people I knew in high school, which is basically impossible.
Speaker 0: as far as I know everyone I knew in high school is dead.
Speaker 0: Okay, I Basically tried to contact anyone I could who would have these videos.
Speaker 0: My younger brother has two of the videos because we overlapped in high school a little bit But he did not have the early videos because he was not yet in high school.
Speaker 0: One of my VHS tapes had been destroyed when I was in high school.
Speaker 0: Ken did not have it anymore.
Speaker 0: No one had them.
Speaker 0: Eventually a few months ago.
Speaker 0: I got an email from the guy I'd emailed years before Responding like nothing had happened.
Speaker 0: Just like he'd just seen the email was like hey, yeah 70 bucks a tape and I'll transcribe him to DVD.
Speaker 0: Okay, and I was like, I don't really want to pay a hundred and forty dollars But I'm not going to regret not having paid Because those won't be around forever.
Speaker 0: And I've got him.
Speaker 0: and then Oh God was it a pain in the ass to get the audio to even Vaguely match up with the video from a VHS tape.
Speaker 0: And it looks pretty good for a VHS tape and I'm proud of this.
Speaker 0: So that's my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: great What do you got?
Speaker 0: video of a cat.
Speaker 1: so this is I Can't research it that.
Speaker 1: well, you're doing the snuff film because Russian but this may be a sort of a snuff film.
Speaker 1: But what if a snuff film does not include the actual?
Speaker 1: Death right?
Speaker 1: Like what if I had a video of a guy shooting a gun and then right before the bullet hit the person.
Speaker 1: It was the end of the video.
Speaker 1: Would that be a snuff film?
Speaker 0: I'm not much of a connoisseur of snuff films But I think you should watch the film 8 millimeter.
Speaker 0: that might tell you a lot about the subculture around stuff films.
Speaker 0: Have you ever seen a millimeter?
Speaker 1: I'd never heard of it.
Speaker 0: All right Nicholas cage great, but it's good.
Speaker 0: This is a video and it's fucked up.
Speaker 1: like many internet videos This sort of falls into the owned category the Russian owned category, which is a large subsection of the own guy.
Speaker 1: Some guys are doing some ridiculous thing rolling down a snow hill at a ski mountain in a big inflatable ball Thing that they're on the inside of.
Speaker 0: so Scott showed me this video and the whole time.
Speaker 0: I'm like that looks fun.
Speaker 0: I would do that.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, look at it go.
Speaker 0: Oh, man Is he gonna hit that guy like?
Speaker 0: I'm waiting for what the funny part is.
Speaker 1: It's not just like wait Wait, eventually it just rolls off a steep cliff with jagged rocks and the guys are still inside.
Speaker 1: And then you just see it go over the edge and that's it down the mountain.
Speaker 1: It's just gone according to the comments like one person died and the other ones didn't do so well, but aren't dead.
Speaker 1: so who knows.
Speaker 0: but Oral is that this hobby is a terrible hobby.
Speaker 1: The moral is is that when you're watching the early part of the video like rim said it looks Mostly really kind of safe.
Speaker 0: It looks like the guy like I. doesn't happen.
Speaker 0: It does one guy like chasing it.
Speaker 0: I thought it was gonna like roll back and hit him or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't look dangerous at all.
Speaker 1: It looks totally chill and this is why I don't go skiing.
Speaker 1: because things like this even though I know they're not skiing in this But still got stuff like that doesn't happen.
Speaker 1: skiing unless you're in Russia and then okay, so in Phil mr Ski Patrol, I'm like, hey Phil skiing so dangerous and he says he's never been hurt skiing But everyone else gets her skiing.
Speaker 0: It's got Judith Natalie Emily all ski.
Speaker 0: Did they get hurt?
Speaker 0: One of those three got hurt minorly once and required no more than two or three stitches.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's all.
Speaker 0: I've only been knocked unconscious once and I didn't break my neck that time only been knocked unconscious.
Speaker 0: Yolo, that's all Yolo man.
Speaker 1: You know how many times I hurt myself playing ns2.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna laugh a little bit Ten years from now when you've got carpal tunnel from playing ns2 and you're crippled by it And then you get hit by a car on your bike.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: side story side story.
Speaker 1: It's open enrollment at work for the benefits.
Speaker 0: I was looking at a disability insurance and you thought about picking on it.
Speaker 1: They want to charge you fucking 15 bucks a paycheck.
Speaker 1: I'm like, fuck you.
Speaker 1: That's a dollar a day.
Speaker 1: I'm not betting $365 that I'm gonna get hurt this year.
Speaker 0: Can I buy it on your behalf if I get the money?
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: like?
Speaker 0: I'll pay for your disability insurance, but as you get disabled you have to give all the checks to me.
Speaker 1: I Would get all the checks and I wouldn't give them to you.
Speaker 0: Well, then I wouldn't pay for it.
Speaker 0: Would you agree to sign a contract where I will pay your disability insurance?
Speaker 0: I'll pay that $15 a paycheck for you, but then you have to give me you.
Speaker 1: just Don't put me into this.
Speaker 0: just go find an insurance company that will sell you reverse insurance because the insurance company will recognize the perverse Incentive that I am now basically incentivized to injure you severely.
Speaker 0: So whatever they're gonna charge you is what they're gonna charge you but the $15 is probably much better than that And we'll both make out.
Speaker 1: How am I gonna make out?
Speaker 0: I'll be to say You look at $15.
Speaker 0: No, I won't.
Speaker 1: that dollars would go to the insurance company.
Speaker 0: fine.
Speaker 0: I'll give you 10% of the disability.
Speaker 1: Are you gonna attack me and disable me?
Speaker 0: Uh Not directly.
Speaker 1: no Do things to put my life in danger so I may become disabled.
Speaker 0: Anyway in the meta moment the book club book is the great Gatsby by F Scott Fitzgerald.
Speaker 0: You should read it.
Speaker 0: I started reading it.
Speaker 0: I'll probably done with it really soon.
Speaker 0: I didn't start reading it because because I'm going to Istanbul and I got a bunch of long flights, uh We got stuff on the internet.
Speaker 0: We got a bunch of videos from magfest last year that I'm gonna link to.
Speaker 0: We're going to have a bunch of videos from magfest this year including hopefully video of the three panels and lectures.
Speaker 0: We were on Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I'm not doing a music video this year because you guys really don't fucking care about those things enough for me to bother.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna upload some photos and also super art.
Speaker 1: fight time-lapse.
Speaker 0: We're gonna try to resume a regular schedule of both radio free equestria and gig nights presents as soon as we can But they will come sooner if you guys get our videos more out there on the internet.
Speaker 0: They're not getting enough views for me to put any more effort into him than I'm already putting into it.
Speaker 1: I feel like this episode is getting long But that's okay cuz you haven't done one in a while and also there isn't gonna be one for a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there won't be any until for at least two weeks.
Speaker 1: Let's let's keep going here.
Speaker 1: All right, so Oh, yeah conventions.
Speaker 1: The next one is PAX East.
Speaker 1: That's all we got right.
Speaker 0: now We're gonna be there and then we're gonna be a pax awesome kinetic on right?
Speaker 0: Okay, so packs prime.
Speaker 1: Yep So let's talk.
Speaker 0: and then I fast.
Speaker 1: we've been playing some a lot of new tabletop games recently But we haven't played any of them enough to really give a full-on episode.
Speaker 1: So we're just gonna Briefly talk about three.
Speaker 1: We've played recently.
Speaker 0: The first one is castles of a burgundy.
Speaker 1: So castle burgundy, I consider these impressions not review.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I bought this because it was highly ranked on board game geek and I wanted to buy a new game.
Speaker 1: So I bought it and I learned it.
Speaker 1: we played it and playing it.
Speaker 1: It was a lot.
Speaker 1: it gave me that same feel.
Speaker 1: not saying the game feels like a curricula.
Speaker 1: Learning it felt like a curricula and we're going through the rules is a whole bunch of shit.
Speaker 1: But then once you actually play it's like oh This game is pretty straightforward.
Speaker 0: See for me.
Speaker 0: It felt like Attica.
Speaker 1: Oh With the hexes.
Speaker 0: Yes visually in that.
Speaker 0: no also in terms of the actions I'm taking Oh filling.
Speaker 0: any only difference between this and Attica On that level is that there's the meta mechanic of you're gathering the tiles from a shared place Rather than everyone has their own completely solitaire game.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So here's how ours our castle of burgundy works.
Speaker 1: You have a an estate which is a big plot of land.
Speaker 1: That's a hexagon with a lot of little hexes in it and there is a shared board from which you can acquire Hexetiles and other goods and resources.
Speaker 1: what you want to do is on your turn you roll some dice and those dice Determine what actions will be available to you.
Speaker 1: You can use some resources to sort of modify the dice.
Speaker 1: So it's not a complete luck fest like settlers But it does cost you more resources if you want to change your dice a lot.
Speaker 1: So you have to be efficient and sort of go with the flow instead of trying to fight.
Speaker 1: You know your way to do what you want and you gather hexes and place them on your board Whenever you when you basically you gather a hex with one action and you add the hex to your estate with a second action.
Speaker 1: When you add the hex to your estate the hex the tile you put does something.
Speaker 1: So if you add a castle to your estate, you get another action.
Speaker 1: If you add a building to your estate, it usually does a specific extra action.
Speaker 1: if you add Animals to your estate you get victory points based on the animals, you know.
Speaker 1: So you're trying to gather specific hexes to do specific things But everyone else is grabbing at him too.
Speaker 1: So you're looking at what the other people are doing.
Speaker 1: If another guy's got sheep, do you want to take sheep away from him?
Speaker 1: So he doesn't score a lot Yes, but then you have to put the sheep somewhere.
Speaker 1: So you want to go get cows which he's not getting so you can score big and then he takes a cow to stop you And so on and so forth.
Speaker 1: Is there anything else about this game?
Speaker 1: I think it's really good and I want to play it more.
Speaker 0: It's really fun.
Speaker 0: It's relatively light.
Speaker 0: I Think it's gonna break down for us relatively quickly and that the decisions are pretty obvious.
Speaker 1: once you figure out they do have Alternate boards we do we can really mix things up.
Speaker 1: Basically.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be like Attica.
Speaker 0: It's really fun until you figure out a few reasonably optimal pads and then it'll become pretty random And I don't know anyone who's going to be willing to put forth whatever effort it would take to step up the game.
Speaker 0: It's gonna have an endgame like Agricola in the sense that among skilled players of Agricola the game really just comes down to Whether or not you can cock other people out of certain resource things at key times.
Speaker 1: But cocking someone out of something also cocks yourself, right?
Speaker 0: So and yeah, but that matters more you want you want to play your optimal You know solo while simultaneously cocking the other players as much as you can.
Speaker 0: But that's a really kind of third or fourth order skill.
Speaker 0: Yeah I worry the game is gonna break down in that.
Speaker 1: for and I know but the other thing is right a lot of games out There tend to be when there were.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of different ways to get points a lot of different paths to victory.
Speaker 1: It tends to be the way to go is to pick one and min max it right.
Speaker 1: go all in on that and all Not in on any other things and each player Picks a different thing to go all in on.
Speaker 1: if two people go all in on the same thing They compete and thus bringing each other down below the players who go solo.
Speaker 1: So like one guy went all animals he'd win.
Speaker 1: But if two people went all animals they would lose and the guy who went all castle would win, right?
Speaker 1: So but in this game you sort in order to get enough victory points like Agricola.
Speaker 1: You need to get victory points from all the different areas.
Speaker 1: You can't min.
Speaker 1: You can't maximize one thing.
Speaker 1: That won't be enough points.
Speaker 1: So in that sense, it's sort of just like who does better Overall You know and there isn't really this sort of you know Picking a thing or any particular strategy user.
Speaker 1: roll your dice and figure out the way to get the most victory points with what you got to work with.
Speaker 0: So we played core worlds exactly once having learned it in its entirety with a big expansion attached to it.
Speaker 1: Well, apparently that expansion was like already planned when the original game was put out.
Speaker 1: Yeah Our board games have Included DLC right so much so that symbols that only meant something in the expansion were already on the cards.
Speaker 0: But this particular set of core will leave race for the galaxy had the same thing going.
Speaker 1: so maybe but this particular Set was one that you can buy Someone else.
Speaker 1: it wasn't ours.
Speaker 1: Someone else had it.
Speaker 1: that had the expansion and the original game together in one box.
Speaker 0: No, I realized after I played this that I had played core worlds once before at nerd NYC.
Speaker 0: but I played the base game and It's it's a Dominion like.
Speaker 0: but more people called it an ascension like and having played it twice It is basically just a complicated ascension in my opinion.
Speaker 1: Well, it's a little better than ascension because in ascension you just engine is not even a game.
Speaker 1: I said you just play your whole hand every turn and then pick the best card on the table and that's it.
Speaker 1: There isn't really anything.
Speaker 0: there's no way to do better at ascension really in this game.
Speaker 1: There were Some things that you could work on Distorting it but I think the number one thing going on in is a deck building game, right?
Speaker 1: And usually the thing in deck building games is it's hard to call your deck, right?
Speaker 1: Like in Dominion you want to trash so that you can get a really efficient deck in core worlds.
Speaker 1: Almost every turn you get to put cards underneath, you know your Your city is basically automatic and building and whenever you do a battle You can put your a guy who is in the battle under the city hall.
Speaker 1: So it's so easy to get rid of all these shitty guys under your deck.
Speaker 1: I actually Didn't?
Speaker 1: I played the game wrong?
Speaker 1: Remember?
Speaker 1: Yeah I had two extra basically an extra copper and an extra estate it to put in Dominion terms You know an extra star fighter and an extra column in my deck to begin with.
Speaker 1: so I had two extra cards to trash and I ended up doing super well And getting all these freaking colonies What's it called capital capital ships colony ships and I was super powerful and awesome and scored two core worlds at the end of the game With that because the trashing was so easy and I never forgot to do the trashing.
Speaker 1: So I think they should get rid of that and force you to have the shitty decks that you have to Optimize more.
Speaker 0: so my impression of this game.
Speaker 0: I'm a castle of burgundy.
Speaker 0: I would say if you're a board gamer at all Just buy it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's fine.
Speaker 0: It's fun.
Speaker 0: My impression of core worlds is that I would not recommend you buy it unless you really Really really fucking like ascension, but you want another game.
Speaker 1: That's like ascension because you just want to have every deck building game in the world Like you're a deck building nut and you're a little bored of Dominion expansions and things like that.
Speaker 1: then, you know core worlds You know, it's probably I think it's better than maybe Thunderstone which I played once Not really a fan of Thunderstone.
Speaker 1: No, so it's probably like you know of the one deck building games I've played.
Speaker 1: it's probably like, you know Dominion, you know, I guess there aren't really that many other ones Dominion's.
Speaker 0: What about Tanto Kure?
Speaker 1: I guess Tanto Kure is actually better than the other non-dominions because it's so similar to Dominion.
Speaker 0: So my impression of core worlds is to not get it because and I'm gonna throw out that book We keep talking about the terms from it characteristics of games by Richard Garfield.
Speaker 0: You really just fucking read it if you listen to geek nights.
Speaker 0: because I'm gonna I'm replacing my.
Speaker 1: We get to the point where every reader every list the listener has read it and yeah you saying that they'll be like rim.
Speaker 1: I read it already shut up already.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm gonna keep using these terms.
Speaker 0: this game has no Directional heuristics at all.
Speaker 0: There's no way to do better than playing your hand in the obvious optimal way.
Speaker 0: You have so few actual decisions to make that if you discount the bad decisions You're basically playing perfectly.
Speaker 0: there were only way to do better is to have memorized the entire deck.
Speaker 1: There were some decisions to make however They didn't actually end up having to be made because I would be sitting there on most of my turns and the big decision was There are a bunch of cards in the table.
Speaker 1: Which one do I want to take?
Speaker 1: And you look and it's obvious which one is best for you the deck you have already started making Alright, and you say that one's the best card for me.
Speaker 1: Someone takes it or they don't.
Speaker 1: if no one takes it I took it.
Speaker 1: if someone else took it I look for the second best card for me and took that one and that was pretty much what I did all game.
Speaker 0: So it was like ascension in the sense that every turn after that first card you get on the first turn.
Speaker 1: you just keep getting Cards similar to that card for the rest of the game, and that's it now simultaneously?
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 0: no there's a lot of calculations you have to do while playing Because not only are there two different currencies and every card has both of them, which is fine But almost every card has some crazy different modifier on it like discard up to two cards from your hand each one of which gives you plus two to ground strength or Fleet strength.
Speaker 0: so to calculate what you could or could not do on your turn is Actually really time-consuming even if you are really good at that sort of.
Speaker 1: that was my biggest problem with the game overall.
Speaker 1: Is that Dominion or any other ones right?
Speaker 1: a deck building game?
Speaker 1: you have like ten cards to work with or remember what they?
Speaker 1: Do maybe up to 20. they're all open.
Speaker 1: you can see all the possible cards.
Speaker 1: You know what they all do in this one.
Speaker 1: every turn all these new cards appeared.
Speaker 1: you had to learn and they're all unique cards.
Speaker 1: so your deck is getting to ends up getting full of all these cards that are all different from each other and in front of You have all these cards that are all different from each other and you basically need to read every single card You've got every time you do something that involves all of them to sort of add them all together Because they're most of them are not just straightforward cards that you don't have to read.
Speaker 1: so it's like every time I attacked I had To read every one of my planets to see if they modified the attack and every ship in the attack to see if it modified the attack and every tactics card in my hand to see if it could modify the attack and
Speaker 0: Turn.
Speaker 0: you have a Second dual currencies.
Speaker 0: you have a currency of fleet and ground.
Speaker 0: you have another currency of actions and energy But they're both basically limiting to the same degree.
Speaker 0: So the game is really unnecessarily complex because that complexity does not beget complex problem-solving abilities or no.
Speaker 1: It's just complex Computation busy work to do to figure out what your score if you have you can do what you want to do.
Speaker 0: now the expansion Makes this worse by adding this whole meta where some cards have a symbol on them And then you're adding tokens to this other board of symbols And then there's victory points based on whether or not you have the most tokens on one of those.
Speaker 0: But you can spend them for points or to get action.
Speaker 0: It just it gets to the point to where there's almost no positional heuristic at all.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 1: no the two positional heuristics you have how many how many victory points the other guy has showing on his table?
Speaker 0: No, I think it's simpler than how many tokens he has.
Speaker 0: Has the person taken?
Speaker 0: yeah, and how many tokens they have on that other?
Speaker 1: yeah The victory points on the planets ended up mattering a lot if I had a chance based on the turn order to get a planet that was worth six.
Speaker 1: instead I ended up with one that was worth three and That happened once or twice Simply based on turn order.
Speaker 1: I didn't get a planet I could have had if say the planets had come out differently or the turn order had been different.
Speaker 1: I would have had many more points.
Speaker 1: So the victory points on the planets do matter not just the number of them.
Speaker 0: yep, so don't buy it.
Speaker 0: It's actually not that good.
Speaker 1: I would have to be pretty Thoroughly to be a super deck building fanboy who really loved and who maybe even gets off on the sci-fi space fighting theme.
Speaker 1: Yeah to get this one.
Speaker 0: It's there to play it again.
Speaker 0: I would have to be pretty thoroughly convinced to do so.
Speaker 0: it also took a really long time.
Speaker 1: It did take a long time compared.
Speaker 1: You know Dominion.
Speaker 1: You can bust off a whole bunch of good look.
Speaker 0: It's obvious why it took a long time.
Speaker 0: all the cards are effectively unique, and you have to read everyone over and over and over again.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of sidetracks and fiddly rules and the calculation time it takes to figure out even basic heuristics is Ludicrous.
Speaker 1: yep all right, so the third game.
Speaker 1: We were talking about is Viva, Java, so we didn't even really play more than one turn of this game.
Speaker 1: We played in zero games of this zero turns of it properly.
Speaker 0: So this is just an impression based on a brief teaching and then an attempt to play two rounds.
Speaker 1: Yes, we screwed up a bunch of rules Big time.
Speaker 0: so my viva job is a guy like you bid on beans and you form correlate.
Speaker 0: I don't want to talk about the mechanics really because we'll talk about it again.
Speaker 1: It's been a game.
Speaker 1: They had a lot of hype.
Speaker 1: I've heard a lot about it.
Speaker 0: my Team is that it's too fiddly and my rationale is thus The way the game is written at least the way the rules were described the way you play them.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of things that kind of could happen simultaneously and people seem to just play this game doing them simultaneously But it was me and Scott and dr.
Speaker 0: Hazard and a bunch of other people in the front row crew are all pretty on these things so immediately Anytime something could be simultaneous the question was asked by someone wait wait wait.
Speaker 0: What order does this happen in?
Speaker 0: because I'm changing my action based on what other people do.
Speaker 1: exactly so?
Speaker 0: This would be fine except that there's so many little things that happen.
Speaker 0: They and there's a giant and the game takes nine players granted.
Speaker 1: Well it can take.
Speaker 1: it can take up to eight players.
Speaker 0: I think it's sort of weird as recommended with five six seven or eight.
Speaker 1: right because when you look the cool part about the Game is this coalition forming aspect where you play every turn you play your guys somewhere in the world and wherever you play him in The world determines three things it determines.
Speaker 1: actually determines four things.
Speaker 1: Number one which bonus you're gonna get?
Speaker 1: each place is a different bonus or penalty.
Speaker 1: number two you get a free bean wherever you go.
Speaker 1: Determines what beans.
Speaker 1: beans beans beans determines what bean you're gonna get.
Speaker 1: number three if you roast it Determines what kind what variety you're going to roast on that turn which matters.
Speaker 1: and number four Anyone who goes in the same continent as you is going to be in the same coalition as you.
Speaker 1: there are three co three teams Basically that are formed each turn.
Speaker 1: so you want to be on a team with the right people.
Speaker 0: right because then each turn each team Votes whether or not to do a or B, and then they play their turn right.
Speaker 1: so every turn every team You're on a different team of three people.
Speaker 1: that team is either going to brew or it is going to research.
Speaker 1: if it Researches you basically all just increase your powers right in a really not intuitive way.
Speaker 0: We had to clarify the rules on like ten times.
Speaker 1: Yes if it Reese if you brew you basically all create a Victory point coffee machine and you will all get those points.
Speaker 1: everyone on that team will get those points.
Speaker 0: the coffee machines are poker hands Of beans, but you draw randomly.
Speaker 0: so you have to play the odds, but it's an individual game.
Speaker 1: So you have to think okay if I'm gonna brew do I want to brew with those people right?
Speaker 1: It's like you know.
Speaker 1: those people are you know below me.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna catch up.
Speaker 1: so yes I do want to brew with them because we'll all get the same number of points from that brew.
Speaker 1: Thus I'll be hurting these people who are not on my team, but let's say I'm losing someone's ahead of me.
Speaker 1: Do I want to brew with them?
Speaker 1: No, I'd be helping them And I wouldn't really be catching up to them because we'd all be getting those points.
Speaker 1: But maybe then I could join their team and poison their brew Making it so they don't get as many victory points, but that will only help someone else catch up to them.
Speaker 1: So what I really want to do is brew with someone else and have someone else poison their brew for me And you see where this goes.
Speaker 0: so there's a lot of cool mechanics in this game, but at least on an initial play And the game is recommended seven and eight players with eight players and turn order matters so much this will take forever.
Speaker 0: this game.
Speaker 0: You're gonna have to cycle through eight players.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna do this.
Speaker 0: well I'm gonna do this in a loop like ten times per turn.
Speaker 0: yeah this game will take forever.
Speaker 1: So unless we read the rules way wrong their words like the voting is supposed to be simultaneous But then the action taking is like you know well who you know this team, okay?
Speaker 1: So we all vote simultaneously.
Speaker 1: every one of the whole table votes.
Speaker 1: research.
Speaker 1: Let's just say right.
Speaker 1: so who researches first?
Speaker 1: in the turn order we research first.
Speaker 1: So we do the turn order research.
Speaker 0: that isn't clockwise.
Speaker 0: you're jumping around the table.
Speaker 1: You're jumping around the table checking the turn order Which is based on these colored chits.
Speaker 0: the turn order changes every round based on victory point.
Speaker 1: that was something that was a huge problem.
Speaker 1: Was the victory point thing right?
Speaker 1: is early in the game at least it's victory points determine turn order.
Speaker 1: You have to move the victory point tokens in the precise order because when there's a tie Let's say two people are tied for three.
Speaker 1: whoever arrived at the three later goes first or Second.
Speaker 1: right it matters.
Speaker 1: so you have to move the victory point tokens in the proper sequence.
Speaker 1: You can't just sort of be like okay.
Speaker 1: How many points did everyone get?
Speaker 1: I got two I got three I got four.
Speaker 1: right you have to actually see.
Speaker 1: okay You move yours first because you just scored the point.
Speaker 0: so my worries.
Speaker 0: now You just have points a large amount of sort of.
Speaker 0: it's not really mechanical busy work.
Speaker 0: It's just that the procedure.
Speaker 1: It's not busy work because you're not calculating.
Speaker 1: It's just procedural time.
Speaker 0: it's a you.
Speaker 0: it ends up having the same effect as busy work because You have to go through this procedure in such precise order that you can't ever just kind of do something and as a result You have to be constantly on the ball and aware of all right who just did this action.
Speaker 0: now Let's do the next action.
Speaker 0: you need like a person to run the clock tick of the game.
Speaker 1: I think that if this was a computerized game It would actually be vastly superior because number one you would never fuck up something like the victory point tying anything, right?
Speaker 1: So you wouldn't it if no one had to think about that.
Speaker 1: and number two all the things like drawing things Randomly out of the bag and peeking knowing, but be you know all that kind of stuff wouldn't be an issue, right?
Speaker 1: It would all just sort of happen you know.
Speaker 1: so it'd be like you want to draw being out of the bag.
Speaker 1: Yes, poop this bean right you know do you know it would be?
Speaker 1: it would solve a whole lot of problems Mostly with you know organizing the physical pieces and all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: so and then if you could play it on the computer like that the coalition making aspect which is the interesting unique mechanic of this game would emerge and Most of your thought would be going towards that every turn and it could be really fun.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of rules clarification questions on the geek many of which are not answered But I did it.
Speaker 0: yeah, there's a lot and one guy says it's primarily a social game.
Speaker 0: That's why he likes it.
Speaker 1: It is very social with the bean sharing and the teaming up except
Speaker 0: No, it's not because look at who was playing that is a purely mathematical game
Speaker 1: It's so I could see how it's social if the P if not everyone is super serious right because you're brewing together
Speaker 0: Is
Speaker 1: a game where you cannot score victory points alone.
Speaker 1: It is impossible.
Speaker 1: you must join a team every turn of people and do something.
Speaker 0: It is a game where I worry that playing to win will make the game Interminable and unbearable.
Speaker 0: possibly now we have to play it again to be sure.
Speaker 0: so we are going to play it again.
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 1: I do want to play it again unlike core worlds only for like I said that team making mechanic.
Speaker 1: Yep, just cuz I want to see that go in another worries.
Speaker 0: Just that that those that coalition for me is gonna be so Procedural that it's just gonna drain all the energy, but I can see how a similar mechanic might make other games awesome.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes, I agree on that point.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: We'll see you guys in a couple weeks.
Speaker 0: We start up geek knives again.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our Website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.