Speaker 1: It's Thursday July 24th 2014.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight we're talking about - con because it is an example of Every bad con ever.
Speaker 1: let's do this and long openers really annoy Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna find the thing that noise.
Speaker 1: there's nothing you can do that annoys me more than annoys you.
Speaker 0: doing it I'll just do blatant destructive things like break all your shit.
Speaker 1: That's not annoying.
Speaker 0: That's in your bed.
Speaker 1: I'll just call the police.
Speaker 0: do They come home?
Speaker 0: this pee in your bed, and I'm not here.
Speaker 1: Oh doll Bob call the police anyway.
Speaker 1: genetic testing.
Speaker 1: I got money.
Speaker 1: I could actually make the police do stuff if I needed to.
Speaker 0: okay.
Speaker 0: This is water With urine in it yeah.
Speaker 1: Also, there's a camera in there.
Speaker 1: I'd have video of you peeing.
Speaker 0: It's aimed at your bed.
Speaker 1: It would get me enough evidence.
Speaker 1: You'd have to go disable that drop cam without it being obvious.
Speaker 1: you disabled it.
Speaker 1: oh So yeah, anyway, it's Thursday.
Speaker 1: It's the lounge.
Speaker 1: talk about whatever here on geek nights, so you got any news anything anything.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's kind of hard to do news right now because we're on like the cusp of news.
Speaker 1: Oh, what do you mean every time of geekery?
Speaker 1: We're on the edge of a new cold war.
Speaker 1: Multiple airliners full of people have disappeared crashed or been shot down in recent memory, and there's nothing to say about any of it.
Speaker 1: There's a lot to say about it.
Speaker 1: You just don't have anything to say about it.
Speaker 0: It happened.
Speaker 0: What is there to say?
Speaker 1: all right a game came out?
Speaker 1: What is there to say?
Speaker 0: That's right exactly.
Speaker 0: The point is to talk about things people don't know so that they learn.
Speaker 1: so I thought the point of geek nights was to talk About things people do know for commentary purposes.
Speaker 1: Opinions we're not.
Speaker 0: You can't have an opinion.
Speaker 0: It's like having it.
Speaker 0: having an opinion on something like that is having an opinion on the weather like ah This rain it's not good.
Speaker 1: No because you've won.
Speaker 1: if you're into weather That's a fascinating conversation and - if you're into geopolitics like me and scojo We there is nothing any human being listening to this show can do to act on the fact that planes were shot down.
Speaker 0: It matters not to their lives in any way whatsoever.
Speaker 0: That is not something you want to do.
Speaker 0: I recommend you do not do that.
Speaker 1: we could go and do some investigative journalism.
Speaker 0: I recommend you do not do this.
Speaker 0: anyone listening.
Speaker 1: That's a bad idea a while ago cause some of our friends got married.
Speaker 1: It was an awesome wedding.
Speaker 1: Scott took some really great pictures.
Speaker 1: I all my pictures are sitting on this SD car that I'm fondling right now that I haven't even put it in a lightroom.
Speaker 0: Why are you fondling things?
Speaker 0: stop fondling?
Speaker 1: That's what I but but black dynamite.
Speaker 1: But they last night we were at a bar and they were showing us all the pictures from their honeymoon in Germany.
Speaker 1: There's good pictures But I noticed something in a bunch of the pictures that they did not notice and this ended up being ridiculous.
Speaker 1: So there's a picture.
Speaker 1: they're sitting like in a restaurant and they're kind of hugging each other like oh We're a cute couple and their friend takes the picture.
Speaker 1: in the background There's a woman with a zoom lens and a fancy camera that looks like it's pointed right at them.
Speaker 1: Okay from from like back into the right.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: They took a bunch of pictures in a row there.
Speaker 1: the next frame like the next picture.
Speaker 1: She is lowered the camera a bit and is looking right at them and has a raised eyebrow.
Speaker 1: And then the next picture.
Speaker 1: she's just like looking at him like, uh-huh Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It is it is a hundred percent her Not realizing that she photobombed them and taking pictures of them doing their thing at a restaurant.
Speaker 1: Okay, I thought that was hilarious.
Speaker 0: It's not hilarious in any way.
Speaker 1: It's pretty hilarious.
Speaker 1: You should see the pictures.
Speaker 1: She's got the raised eye.
Speaker 1: It's it's the raised eyebrow of approval.
Speaker 1: It's the proceed.
Speaker 0: Okay Yeah, but no the cusp of nerdy news because the Comic Con is starting Wednesday.
Speaker 1: Oh, that was gonna.
Speaker 1: I was gonna talk about that as my real news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, there's nothing.
Speaker 0: I mean There's no reason to go to it because we're gonna find out all the news in the Internet's without having to go there.
Speaker 1: My news was gonna be that SDCC is happening now, and I think SDCC is actually one of the worst Never have never having been to it.
Speaker 0: I agree.
Speaker 1: Well watching Twitter and I noticed that a bunch of people are tweeting along the same lines and Daryl Surratt was leading this charge great that People all the news that comes out of SDCC not just the news but like all the tweets all the blog posts pretty much everything.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much focused entirely on The big reveals and the big like events and screenings and the expo.
Speaker 0: so there's no reason to go.
Speaker 0: if that's what you want There's no reason to be there and you got to be in the room when the guy makes the announcement Rather than finding out the internet five seconds later.
Speaker 1: It's interesting that no one talks Fucking anything about like the other events like the panels and workshops and stuff that happens like because any media is only going there To go report on things that they think will make people their media.
Speaker 0: I think it's big Hollywood things.
Speaker 1: I think the attendees who self-report also only go there for those things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, look at the biggest line is the miss the hall H. I'll be.
Speaker 0: yeah The well the infamous Hall H. That was the word I'm looking for.
Speaker 1: Yeah But and it was the same thing with the New York Comic Con all those kinds of cons.
Speaker 1: a lot of people don't seem to Realize that like all the media and all the people in the world who don't go to a lot of conventions.
Speaker 1: Look at those cons like the mecca of nerdery.
Speaker 0: and even people go to other nerd cons.
Speaker 0: All they see is cosplay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because they're not actually participating.
Speaker 0: They're just sort of standing on the outside.
Speaker 0: they don't really see what's going on and anything that is going on has Nothing that is good to report on in mainstream media and nothing good to take photos of So it basically doesn't get broadcast to anyone who's not in on it.
Speaker 1: So these cons basically all have the same thing.
Speaker 0: also a lot of people go to San Diego Comic Con don't know of or go To any other con.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 0: It's like the same way that band-aid is band-aid.
Speaker 0: comic-con is comic-con.
Speaker 0: There aren't any others granted.
Speaker 1: I found some people who call other conventions like kinetic on a comic-con.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so yeah But these cons You don't go to him to do anything there.
Speaker 1: you go to him to walk in walk around Pay for an autograph and then get the fuck out of there and then all the people that are worth seeing are at other Conventions.
Speaker 0: right Katie cook is some giant ass line.
Speaker 0: It's like you can just see her pretty much anywhere.
Speaker 0: You know many conventions she works a year.
Speaker 0: I remember she does a convention like every weekend.
Speaker 0: Why would you pay to go to San Diego Comic Con to see her when you can see her like in?
Speaker 1: Anywhere near where you say there was a time you could say the same thing about Gabe and Tycho because you go to penny arcade expo.
Speaker 1: really hard to see them.
Speaker 1: Like if you want to get the autograph you stand in that huge line That one time they're at the New York Comic Con there was like no line, and they're just sitting at a table like Yep, so yeah comic-con just kind of sucks.
Speaker 1: I mean it's telling that the New York Comic Con Which is the same damn thing there's no difference between these two for any.
Speaker 0: like actual a New York Comic Con is much smaller.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the size of both of them is deceiving because it's pretty much a churn turnstile mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I actually saw a numbers for Anime Expo that were posted that included both turnstile and unique.
Speaker 1: Oh, maybe we're fine.
Speaker 0: They said they said their unique was 80,000 and their turnstile was like 200,000 something.
Speaker 1: you know how you get a unique of 80,000 because they're still missing.
Speaker 1: the third metric the metric that I actually want is maximum simultaneous Because that's the measure of how big the con is.
Speaker 1: Otakon's 30,000 people at a time But uniques are and turnstile.
Speaker 1: actually both kind of count that churn.
Speaker 0: well Otakon's also maxed 30,000 people so I don't I don't know if it's actually 30,000 at a time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well max 30,000 means they sell 30,000 badges and all those people have the right to be in the convention center, right?
Speaker 0: So that isn't that what the unique of anime expos?
Speaker 1: No, so Pax is unique is way higher than his maximum simultaneous because single-day badges I Got through a Friday Saturday and Sunday badge are still three unique people.
Speaker 1: because there's no way.
Speaker 1: well There's no way they're going to count those as one person not gonna keep track of.
Speaker 1: well This person bought two single-day badges.
Speaker 1: So that actually counts as yeah.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: They sell single-day badges Nominally and not that not just packs but any con nominally so that more people can experience it But really because it gives them a better number for the people who pay for booths.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, so the one thing that the news that came out of comic-con is actually worth paying attention to right now Besides all you know, all that movie garbage and whatever and shit.
Speaker 0: You don't care about new Jeff Lemire comic.
Speaker 0: Always a winner, but this is interesting because under read the description Is positive and negative right?
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna read the description.
Speaker 0: It's only two paragraphs.
Speaker 1: All right I actually haven't read anything about this yet.
Speaker 0: So ten year it's it's by Jeff Lemire and artist is this other guy does on Ant Man is it?
Speaker 0: no It's from image gets independent.
Speaker 1: I type for I typed SDCC just now into Google and the top news is here's Marvel's Ant Man comic-con poster.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, ten years ago massive planetside robots called the harvesters materialized without warning and evaded the orbits of all the United Galactic Council's worlds wiping out entire planets and civilizations before Disappearing again.
Speaker 1: All right in culture world.
Speaker 1: That's a hegemon star control.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you know fear-fueled response to this machine Holocaust the galaxy blamed millions of robotic companions whom they suspected somehow spawning the harvesters.
Speaker 0: all robots and androids are immediately outlawed and ruthlessly ruthless bounty hunters called scrappers were charged with universe.
Speaker 0: Any surviving robots Astro Boy?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was about to say well one Scrappers the.
Speaker 1: when you introduce your own proper noun in your pitch of the thing That's usually one of the warning signs of a bad anime.
Speaker 0: Yep The incredibly like like artificial boy Astro Boy.
Speaker 0: Tim 21 may hold the secrets to the origin of the harvesters machine Machine apocalypse.
Speaker 0: so we get rid of all machines that are smart and as a result is the most wanted robot in the universe With only his small pet bot bandit and the lumbering mining droid driller at his side spaced in.
Speaker 0: Tim 21 goes on the run before long.
Speaker 0: The entire galaxy is looking for this ragtag group of unlikely Companions as they make their way from one exotic planet to the next with new foes advancing on them in every turn saga.
Speaker 1: I feel like the term ragtag is also a warning sign.
Speaker 0: I don't know who wrote the description, but it's It's like every cliche of awesomeness put together.
Speaker 0: So I don't know how to feel about it because Jeff Lemire has done almost no wrong.
Speaker 0: Yep, and these are all cliches, which is bad.
Speaker 1: But when you but they're all awesome cliches combined, which is good But at the same time when you tell someone that something is everything they like combined That's usually what a snake oil salesman tells you I know.
Speaker 1: So I've been burned by that before with certain media.
Speaker 0: It's not like I'm not gonna read it.
Speaker 0: I just have doubts that it's gonna somehow Come over the top of saga to become the best comic on the shelf, which probably won't be.
Speaker 1: So it could be good.
Speaker 0: so back in ant-man territory I just wanted to talk about comics on Thursday because I think some Thursday people probably aren't reading comics and they should.
Speaker 1: yeah What comic should they be reading?
Speaker 1: the saga?
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much pretty much Saga is the comic.
Speaker 1: or if you have any friend who is like I don't really into comics Just give him saga.
Speaker 0: That's the only comic you gotta read right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't worry about anything else Things of the day.
Speaker 1: so I got a preface this this video is a little special to me because it reminded me of something that Happened to us at a wonderful Otacon.
Speaker 1: Oh my god This was like two thousand four.
Speaker 1: I want to say okay.
Speaker 1: This was a long goddamn time ago.
Speaker 1: We're at nota con walking around and out of nowhere a dude just says everyone everyone everyone.
Speaker 1: Ladies and gentlemen, can I have your attention?
Speaker 0: So the show time?
Speaker 1: Show time I didn't.
Speaker 1: we didn't live in New York yet, so I wasn't used to show time.
Speaker 1: show time.
Speaker 1: So I look we all we both look our friends look and there's a guy and he's holding his hand up and in that hand Is a condom.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's out of its package.
Speaker 0: It might be show too much time.
Speaker 1: he proceeds to then pull the condom over his head and Then inflate it through his nose and mouth over his head into a space suit and then pop it.
Speaker 1: and then he took a bow.
Speaker 0: Classic parlor trick.
Speaker 1: it was.
Speaker 1: it was wonderful to behold.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So this gentleman on YouTube Has taken this to the next level.
Speaker 1: He put a hat on the condom first and then inflated it using only his nose.
Speaker 1: I Invite you all to watch this YouTube video.
Speaker 1: It is delightful.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I have two YouTube videos daddy to peepee.
Speaker 1: I can't complain because I have often done the two video thing as rim alluded to in the opening bit, right?
Speaker 0: I've been doing more photography, right and Photography sort of weird because it is both science and art at the same time.
Speaker 0: And it's like you open up Photoshop and it's like where do I put these noblies?
Speaker 0: It's like there is no right answer where to put the noblies.
Speaker 0: every answer is the right answer.
Speaker 1: The wrong answer is let's make that sky more dramatic Maybe.
Speaker 0: so here's two really interesting videos that helped me learn a lot and they're pretty short right?
Speaker 0: So in the one video The guy shows you the difference between raw versus JPEG.
Speaker 0: Right and basically, you know raw versus JPEG is all about.
Speaker 0: you know He's like how much day.
Speaker 0: it's like people talk about there's more data in the raw file Like what the fuck does that actually mean?
Speaker 0: There's more data in the raw file, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, it's the same resolution There's the same number of pixels.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: what does that actually mean?
Speaker 0: when there's more data in there?
Speaker 0: and he actually shows you What it means when there's more data in there you can make this guy's so much more dramatic?
Speaker 0: Not really, but it's like you watch this and it's like oh I get it right.
Speaker 0: and the other thing the other video is Realistic HDR photography.
Speaker 0: It's like only seven minutes long.
Speaker 0: All right, both of these are like less than ten minutes and Basically, you know you have a raw file.
Speaker 0: it has more data.
Speaker 0: if you do HDR you're basically taking multiple photos of the same exact thing and Combining them to have one file with a fuck ton of data like more data than any monitor You'll ever use could display.
Speaker 1: like you can't display all of it right one photo?
Speaker 1: Well, maybe but like you're like you got to export that shit, right?
Speaker 0: So for example, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say I take a photo in a room and the room has a window and the Sun is shining through the window, right?
Speaker 0: Well, if I want to see what's outside the window, I have to like ever, you know a lot less exposure.
Speaker 0: You know to get to.
Speaker 0: otherwise that sunlight shining through is just gonna be a big white spot on the on the.
Speaker 0: you know The photo.
Speaker 0: you're not able to see anything outside the window at all.
Speaker 0: Even with raw I won't be able to see what's outside the window really.
Speaker 0: But if I do that then the inside of the room is gonna be really dark.
Speaker 0: I like the shadows near the furniture.
Speaker 0: It's like you don't see anything, right?
Speaker 0: But if I expose the photo for the furniture so you can see the carpet and the flowers and whatever's in the room This is gonna be the big white spot.
Speaker 0: So what you do is take two pictures or more than two pictures and you combine them and then when you're photoshopping You can edit it in such a way that you can see outside the window and inside the room at the correct exposure Which is what it would look like if you were looking at the room with your eyeballs, right?
Speaker 0: So he shows you how that's done and how you can use the HDR techniques and whatever without you know Make.
Speaker 0: you could use them to make some things that look crazy unrealistic and like ridiculous high contrast.
Speaker 0: That's you know stupid and tacky.
Speaker 1: Yeah But you can also use it this way for reals Of course those high cut those like really like fake looking pictures or sometimes useful in a sense that like if you take a picture of a big cityscape or something.
Speaker 1: Those pictures are good.
Speaker 1: If you want to like use that picture to impress impress people.
Speaker 0: make desktop wallpapers Oh, yeah, or more like.
Speaker 1: if I wanted to like try to do something weird like how many people are in that picture?
Speaker 0: That's not gonna help you with that so much They would
Speaker 1: because I guess if there's a lot of different varied white like White levels and light levels all over the place in this giant picture I can just have all the data and a normalized view where I can see everything Even if it's pretty tacky.
Speaker 1: not because it doesn't look natural at all because everything is it like the same brightness.
Speaker 0: mmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're not gonna get any more detail really didn't that more detail like that?
Speaker 0: And you're now you're gonna.
Speaker 0: how does it help with counting people?
Speaker 0: I don't know you're talking about.
Speaker 1: So if there's people like in the shadow of a building or not in the shadow of a building You'll
Speaker 0: still be able to tell there's a person there
Speaker 1: Maybe and
Speaker 0: it would only help if you wanted to be able to like see all the details on the human being like.
Speaker 0: oh I want to really be able to see the details in their skin.
Speaker 0: Okay, whatever.
Speaker 1: You know what's funny because I got this drop cam and it's got a. it's got a real set of lenses in it so I can zoom in on the image right but Then I zoom in and it's gonna be all blurry and then I can hit the enhance button because then it'll like focus on that area.
Speaker 1: But if I do that then it messes up the stream because now the whole stream is focused on that area because there's only one Lens obviously and it's a live stream, so it basically has the effect that amounts to the CSI zoom and enhance.
Speaker 1: Okay, yeah Camera's actually pretty good though.
Speaker 1: I'm enjoying it so far.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment the booklet book is still a canticle for Liebowitz.
Speaker 1: I've read every culture book that was ever written.
Speaker 1: while waiting for Scott to read this book.
Speaker 0: I Just choose not to spend my time on reading when I thought the whole point of this was to read.
Speaker 0: it is when the Sun Is out.
Speaker 1: you shouldn't probably shouldn't read read up on the beach.
Speaker 0: When have I gone to the beach?
Speaker 1: You want to go to the beach the weekend before packs?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: if I can.
Speaker 1: we'll see what could you be doing that week?
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: Okay, we should go to the beach.
Speaker 0: We'll find out.
Speaker 1: go read on the beach.
Speaker 1: So yeah, the book is a canticle for Liebowitz.
Speaker 1: It's one of the first apocalypse books of the modern era.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: I hope you know a lot about Catholics or will make a lot of sense.
Speaker 0: I Know enough.
Speaker 1: I think you know enough.
Speaker 1: no one about Jews also helps.
Speaker 0: I know a lot about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though the e-book I had didn't actually show any of the characters Hebrew character.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that that was annoying just asterisks.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay Well, it's not like you could read them.
Speaker 1: No, but you could recognize them.
Speaker 1: It's pretty obvious what they say anyway Even when they're all disastrous.
Speaker 1: we were at Connecticut.
Speaker 1: It was awesome.
Speaker 1: Publish a bunch of data from Connecticut take that every other fucking convention and I'm gonna publish that data in a computer readable format Not just images for you guys.
Speaker 1: once I finished redacting it and hopefully enriching it with some information like what categories the panels are in like anime or writing or Whatever.
Speaker 1: So, uh, stay tuned for that.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I hope people do cool stuff with this data.
Speaker 1: I hope other cons start releasing this data.
Speaker 0: I don't think any kind of even thought of releasing data like this or even up.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty confident.
Speaker 1: most counts don't even gather that data possibly because I have asked conventions where we attended and I saw a Staffer with a clicker count the number of people in the room and then look months after the con.
Speaker 1: I'd asked the convention.
Speaker 1: Hey, how many people were actually in our panel and they have no convention has ever been able to answer that question ever As any.
Speaker 0: well, let's wait for someone to ask us that question to be able to answer it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I actually I had three panelists asked me and you know what I told them exactly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I did not give them the internal notes though because the notes are fair and honest honest and for Scott's and mine and Kristen's eyes only Unless you want it, uh, I don't know what I would.
Speaker 1: I'm so far.
Speaker 1: I'm denying it to everyone because here's the problem.
Speaker 0: Someone said I want to hear the feedback I'm like, I'm warning you.
Speaker 0: I don't haven't looked at the Panel, I considered but it may be horribly negative and you might not like it.
Speaker 0: Here's the I don't know If you still want to hear it.
Speaker 0: if that is the case
Speaker 1: Part of the problem is that if I just say no to everyone Then I don't have to deal with having to decide if I'll even engage on the next level with someone or I go and look It up and I see like really bad comments about them.
Speaker 1: But - let's say I only respond to people where the comments are good or at least like not bad bad.
Speaker 1: And then I just tell the other people.
Speaker 1: Sorry, we don't have any data.
Speaker 1: that That people will figure out rapidly.
Speaker 1: that we don't have any data is code for your panel was so bad that people wrote bad right.
Speaker 0: That's why if someone I say do you really want to hear it?
Speaker 0: and then if they really want to hear it and I warn Them and then I read it and it happens to be a bad one.
Speaker 0: I'll just read him the bad one.
Speaker 1: I also don't trust to be perfectly blunt that that accurate the kind of oh, no I trust our staff and seriously reading those comments.
Speaker 1: They're pretty spot-on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Were I to give someone the kind of person who would get the kind of feedback that would make a person like that cry?
Speaker 1: Is the kind of person who would then take the email that I sent them with that data and publish it on the internet?
Speaker 1: possibly out of context Thus causing drama.
Speaker 1: and what's the number one rule of running a convention club?
Speaker 0: Don't run it like - can.
Speaker 0: yep, so - can.
Speaker 1: We're not going to give you guys a play-by-play of everything that went wrong.
Speaker 0: you can read that on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yes, we also did the same thing But basically is the deal.
Speaker 0: somebody made a con and they were gonna Make it basically a tumblr convention a convention for the tumblr community and all these different sub communities.
Speaker 1: We talked about this previously Which is not a bad idea.
Speaker 0: pretty much any internet community get you know of any substantial size can have a successful Convention and probably needs one.
Speaker 0: It's not a bad idea to have one, but this is unofficial not run by tumblr or anything.
Speaker 0: and They had troubles all along the way that you can read about online and famous famous troubles right big-time troubles.
Speaker 0: They couldn't pay the guests.
Speaker 0: They couldn't pay the hotel.
Speaker 0: the things were disorganized.
Speaker 1: They like panels didn't show up.
Speaker 1: panel rooms were empty.
Speaker 0: People who paid to go to the convention didn't get to see what they wanted to see because didn't happen and they were upset.
Speaker 0: They told video game room had like one TV with one game system on it.
Speaker 1: They told the attendees that they needed seventeen thousand dollars or the con was gonna close.
Speaker 0: It's unknown if that was a lie, or if it was actually true.
Speaker 1: The generally just drama filled ridiculous bullshit all over the place.
Speaker 0: now this made news on the internet.
Speaker 1: But this the point of what we're about to say.
Speaker 1: the rest of this night of geek nights is that Dashcon was a disaster.
Speaker 1: Don't get us wrong.
Speaker 0: No question.
Speaker 1: Dashcon was.
Speaker 0: we weren't even there, but we could tell that's a hundred percent accurate.
Speaker 0: This is a convention.
Speaker 1: where had I attended and bought my badge with cash I probably would have sued them in small claims court.
Speaker 1: had I bought my badge with a credit card I would have charged back the credit card.
Speaker 1: Yep Had I donated money to their seventeen thousand dollar fund?
Speaker 1: well one I wouldn't have.
Speaker 0: meanwhile the guests that went to their can.
Speaker 0: It was the same weekend as kinetic on right.
Speaker 1: I had it so a co-worker.
Speaker 1: when I came back After kinetic on they were like so uh you were running a convention this weekend.
Speaker 1: It wasn't this one, and I was like yes I was.
Speaker 1: you probably read about a convention on the internet.
Speaker 0: that is not the one I ran But sure enough, but guess that went to Dashcon and did not perform and were not paid should have come to kinetic on instead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, seriously welcome to night Vale.
Speaker 1: I hope it is not my job to invite guest guests to kinetic on.
Speaker 1: however I've told all the people involved that if they I would like them to ask you to come to kinetic on.
Speaker 0: Please come to kinetic on.
Speaker 1: we will not do anything that - gone did also.
Speaker 0: I heard from someone in may or may not be true that you live in Brooklyn.
Speaker 0: kinetic on is a way close.
Speaker 0: We'll fucking drive you there in our zip car.
Speaker 1: I'm not even joking.
Speaker 0: I don't know how many of you people there are.
Speaker 1: I will rent the zip van.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we will rent the zip fan, and we will take you to kinetic on with us.
Speaker 1: Yes We'll make sure you can still stay in the Marriott with all.
Speaker 0: our staff will give you the biggest panel room At the best time which we now have data to figure out when that is.
Speaker 1: yep, oh One other interesting fact before we get into the rest of this.
Speaker 1: so a lot of attendees of conventions Like to complain about shit even when the convention is awesome.
Speaker 1: so I have evidence that these people straight-up lie.
Speaker 1: a Large number of the complaints that I personally received about kinetic on that we you know we were on the panel's department for that Were people saying that an event they attempted to go to the room was full and they were turned away They lined
Speaker 0: up,
Speaker 1: and then they couldn't get in.
Speaker 1: but I have the data on that and I and I investigated those cases Most of the times.
Speaker 1: most of the panels that people complained were full and they couldn't get into.
Speaker 0: We're not in fact full and had our staff had clickers and counted the number of people in that room.
Speaker 0: You know shortly after the panel started and there were seats open.
Speaker 1: so if that is a representative sample of people who attend conventions in general People just lie about things.
Speaker 1: However - con does not appear that there were too many lies about.
Speaker 0: well I'm sure you know the.
Speaker 0: the 100% precise truth is not what was written on the internet.
Speaker 0: right there are exaggerations and Exaggerations for example, but there's no question.
Speaker 0: It was a disaster.
Speaker 1: well So a lot of people were writing like tear downs of - con like as it was happening and what I found interesting was a lot of the things people were complaining about appeared made up or Just didn't make sense.
Speaker 1: like one guy wrote a big blog post talking about how - con was operating illegally because the company that runs it is Incorporated in one state, but then the event was in a different state.
Speaker 1: It's like no kid.
Speaker 0: That's perfectly legal.
Speaker 1: you have no idea how companies work at all.
Speaker 0: You don't know anything.
Speaker 1: It's like people.
Speaker 1: once they notice this was happening we're going out of their way to like try to write the biggest list of things they fucked up and things that went wrong and I Filtering through all that noise.
Speaker 1: It was still a disaster.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the reason we want to talk about this is not because anything with - con civilly wouldn't care about - con So I'm gonna bring up examples from - chair, but conventions fail like this a lot.
Speaker 0: I've seen many of them all the time Throughout history.
Speaker 0: when we show not a rare thing at all.
Speaker 0: a convention is hard to run But it's often run by fans who are not experts and don't know what they're doing but they manage to know enough to at least get the convention to start and get people to show up.
Speaker 0: and then Because people show up and they the people running it fail bad things go down.
Speaker 1: I mean, we've been staffed at a lot of conventions Kinetic Con for many years, but also Katsu Con.
Speaker 1: We were staffed for years Oda Con.
Speaker 1: We were staffed.
Speaker 0: Well some other smaller cons You've never heard of and will bother with and conventions their failures are not always total failures or the whole con collapses.
Speaker 0: often conventions Will have localized failures.
Speaker 0: that first Ohio Con we went to oh my god That was the first con we ever went to had localized failures in the video game area Yep, and the panel area people not showing up right.
Speaker 1: a lot of their panels just didn't show up.
Speaker 1: In fact, that's how we.
Speaker 1: that's kind of how geek guide started.
Speaker 0: But like the dealers room artists alley were small because it was a tiny con, but they didn't fail.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they worked.
Speaker 0: they happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know and and also some of the things that went wrong weren't their fault like the hookers like that wasn't Happened to be.
Speaker 0: the hotel they chose happened to have the you know, or like we went to.
Speaker 1: We went to penguin con in Novi, Michigan, which ended up being an awesome con, but probably the best Unreplaceable con ever.
Speaker 1: the badges weren't like ready and we couldn't like register or go in or anything.
Speaker 1: The con started like four hours late effectively.
Speaker 0: Yep, but the con happened.
Speaker 0: it did.
Speaker 1: it did in the end happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah but so - con.
Speaker 1: What happened here is very simple nerds and fans of things wanted to make an event happen and they vastly underestimated the amount of actual work it takes to make that happen and Simultaneously.
Speaker 1: the core group of people who made this convention happen Were not a stable group of people who are professional and able to trust each other.
Speaker 1: It was people who either didn't know every convention well or was one of those drama friend groups.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And if you ever get involved in the staffing or management of a convention and You go to their meetings and you see that the people involved are drama people quit Immediately.
Speaker 0: never staff for a convention that has drama unless you kick all those people out and you run it.
Speaker 0: Yes, and you're not and you're not those people, but you can't know if you're not those people just like that guy doesn't know He's that guy.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: You know, like other guys are that guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you might.
Speaker 1: Why is it so hard to run a convention but one?
Speaker 1: it's actually not that hard.
Speaker 1: as much as I said, it's hard.
Speaker 1: It's not hard.
Speaker 1: It's just hard for most people.
Speaker 1: It's hard if you were unable to act without drama.
Speaker 1: Read and respond to emails immediately.
Speaker 1: Yes, if all of them if someone asks you a question and you can't answer it You need to.
Speaker 1: you have to already know who could answer that question And be able to contact them and that person has to be able to then actually Do what we just said.
Speaker 1: you have to do read emails respond to questions you also.
Speaker 0: the main thing is if you're running a whole convention, there's a huge list of things you have to do and You no one's just hands you that list.
Speaker 0: You sort of have to know it.
Speaker 0: Like did you know that you need insurance?
Speaker 0: if you don't know that and you don't buy it you are fucked.
Speaker 0: I've been to many but that's a thing.
Speaker 0: No one tells you you need insurance.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you just decide you're gonna run a convention and call a hotel and say hey, I want to have a convention.
Speaker 0: Let's say okay.
Speaker 0: They expect you to just know all these things that you need.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they think that you're an event manager.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you have to just know.
Speaker 1: and there's another big example.
Speaker 1: I have asked certain conventions.
Speaker 1: We've gone to I'm not gonna name any names But they're large ones and my question was do you pay ASCAP?
Speaker 1: Yep, they had no idea.
Speaker 1: and then as a result, I did not ask my follow-up question Which was we're gonna play a bunch of clips of stuff like music in our panel.
Speaker 1: We're assuming that we're covered by that.
Speaker 0: I guess you could also pay BMI.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, or questions like.
Speaker 1: do you have permission to screen that thing that you're screening in that room?
Speaker 0: Did you know that you needed permission to show this movie to people in this room?
Speaker 0: Is that a thing that you knew you had to have?
Speaker 1: those are professional looking radios that your staff are using?
Speaker 1: Are you licensed to use that kind of radio in this state?
Speaker 1: That is a question that needs to be.
Speaker 1: or oh, you've got a nice wireless microphone system.
Speaker 1: What year did you buy that?
Speaker 1: that might be a felony?
Speaker 0: Did you rent that from a company?
Speaker 0: Did they have a union?
Speaker 0: Did you know that the unions gonna stop working?
Speaker 0: It's such an hour.
Speaker 0: Did you know you want to load things to the loading dock?
Speaker 0: Did you know that you had to pay a union to do that?
Speaker 1: Because it's a union building Do you know what a fire marshal looks like?
Speaker 1: Have you seen him yet?
Speaker 0: Do you know what the fire marshal is going to look for?
Speaker 1: Yes Do you know how to?
Speaker 1: do you know what to say to a fire marshal?
Speaker 0: And these are only the things that we know that you have to check for.
Speaker 0: some of the things that we know you have to Check for.
Speaker 0: there are many other things that you must do that We have not mentioned that you won't know and so if you fuck any of them up you risk fucking everything up.
Speaker 0: But really did you know that if you call your the tickets to the convention tickets that many states most in fact have ticket tax That you have to pay.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, if you don't pay the ticket tax you could go to jail Possibly.
Speaker 1: so that is what tax evasion.
Speaker 1: that's why most conventions you go to they sell you a membership into their nonprofit Organization.
Speaker 1: Yes Also, how is your convention run?
Speaker 1: Is there a company involved?
Speaker 1: Is there an LLC or a corporation?
Speaker 1: If it's just you and there's no corporation for a sole proprietorship Well, not even we're talking like you.
Speaker 1: just run the convention and do it all yourself.
Speaker 1: Well, guess what?
Speaker 1: You're the one who personally gets sued if something happens.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's a shame.
Speaker 1: Yeah Also, if you form a nonprofit like a 503c or whatever There's rules about what content you can and cannot have at your event.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Why do you think so many anime cons have such a bug up their butt about not having content that doesn't fit their charter?
Speaker 1: Well, because a they don't want to have not only made content Also, they have ramifications to going outside of their charter and it's hard to change that charter.
Speaker 1: That's why my advice to you is if you ever run a convention, you should run it from a map from it like an LLC I'm not a lawyer by the way, and you should run it for profit.
Speaker 1: Even if you are in effect a nonprofit.
Speaker 0: All right, so that's pretty much covers all.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 0: The other thing though is that you look at a failed convention like this, right and when a convention fails I know the people who attend who run it are claiming that it succeeded.
Speaker 1: by the way, whatever because they're already.
Speaker 1: they've announced 2015.
Speaker 1: They've announced the venue.
Speaker 0: it's sort of a miracle that even when a convention fails people can still manage to hold another one.
Speaker 1: well, what amazes me is that people go to these things and Don't realize what a disaster it was.
Speaker 1: It's like you've never been to another convention and the answer to that appears to be no.
Speaker 1: Yeah, most of the people who went to dashcon appear to have never been to a convention.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about conventions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then they feel like they can post on the internet like they know everything.
Speaker 1: Yep And we know the staff had not been to a lot of conventions either because one thing I've noticed among nerd cons.
Speaker 1: Is that for good or ill?
Speaker 1: the people who run them The ones that have succeeded and continue to exist like Otakons and katsu kans and mag fests and things like that.
Speaker 1: They went to a lot of nerd cons saw things that were staffed at other cons Yep.
Speaker 1: And then when they run like when they rise to the ranks and start running their own conventions or running bigger events They kind of just do things the way all the other cons do like.
Speaker 1: there's an unspoken rule of like.
Speaker 1: This is just kind of how you do.
Speaker 0: but you learn.
Speaker 0: working at one convention You take the things you learn and just repeat them at the other one.
Speaker 1: You know like submit a panel to pretty much any nerd con even like New York Comic Con.
Speaker 1: It's all pretty much the same process Submit a panel to dashcon.
Speaker 1: Well, we talked about that at length on geek nights.
Speaker 1: It's like the people who wrote this policy had literally never heard of a convention and came up with like their idea of how Should go out of convention.
Speaker 1: quote as a panelist.
Speaker 1: You'll be expected to think on your feet at that quickly.
Speaker 1: You will be expected to attend all required briefing sessions.
Speaker 1: Well, you might be needed briefing for along with one in-person briefing session held just before the actual start of the convention.
Speaker 1: You'll expected to attend all the panels to which you are assigned.
Speaker 1: The assigned Sun will be expected to act in a way that does not upset our guests or trying to the convention name.
Speaker 1: You'll respect the authority of the Dashcon staff.
Speaker 1: Oh, so long as you do not feel the direction of the staff endangers the mental, physical, emotional well-being of you, you'll be expected to understand that panel...
Speaker 0: That was written by people who were on top of Tumblr.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's for sure.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, this just keeps going.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: This thing's like 100... Basically, you would... They formed these committees of people for different types of content, and then those people, who were vetted by this ridiculous process, would then put together these panels, and then you only got reimbursed.
Speaker 1: If you ran a panel, you still had to pay for your badge.
Speaker 1: You got the badge for the day of the panel that you ran refunded to you if 100 people attended the panel.
Speaker 1: Whoa.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: People just coming up with stuff that sounds good.
Speaker 1: Well, it doesn't even sound good.
Speaker 0: Well, it sounds good to them.
Speaker 0: Knowing nothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this forum wants my birthday.
Speaker 1: The forum to submit a panel to this is longer than any forum I've ever submitted to any convention in my entire life.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is, when a convention fails...
Speaker 1: Have you ever been convicted of a felony?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: If so, please explain.
Speaker 0: When a convention fails like this, there's mega collateral damage.
Speaker 0: That one person sucking at running conventions hurts all these other people, the attendees, the guests, pretty much anyone involved gets hurt.
Speaker 0: Some people traveled a long way, took vacation days, bought, spent money, and went to a thing and had a subpar experience and waste all the time.
Speaker 0: They have a right to be upset and they are, yeah, they should be upset at the people who sold them a raw egg, but they should be slightly upset at themselves.
Speaker 0: I know that's victim blaming, but you should be able to tell that convention is shitty and not go to it.
Speaker 1: I buy raw eggs all the time.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's your fault if you get poisoned.
Speaker 1: Raw eggs are just an egg.
Speaker 1: If I bought an egg, why would I expect it to not be raw?
Speaker 1: I wouldn't buy an egg that was pre-cooked.
Speaker 0: I drank raw milk and I died, come on.
Speaker 0: But it's really not any different from all the other things people fail at, nerds and not nerds.
Speaker 0: People try to do things they don't know how to do all the time, self-included, right?
Speaker 0: How many people like, I don't know, try to write a video game and they don't know how to code and it just fails completely?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: How many people try to do a podcast?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: And it fails completely.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The only difference is when people do those things, it doesn't make the news because no one else suffers.
Speaker 0: If you listen.
Speaker 0: Maybe the person who did it doesn't even suffer.
Speaker 1: If you listen to those early episodes, the geek nights, like the beta episodes, the only person who was harmed by those was you.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And you can just stop listening.
Speaker 0: It's not like you traveled and took out a hotel, used vacation days and bought tickets to geek nights and then it sucked.
Speaker 0: It's like you turned it on, it sucked and you turned it off two seconds later and that's life.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's not a big deal.
Speaker 0: You know, so it's like when a convention fails, it makes the news, but it's really not any different from anyone failing at any other sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: But you know, if you, if you look at why these people fail to this convention, look at any of the things you fail at in your life and it's the same thing that happened to you when you tried to do something and sucked.
Speaker 1: Though with the convention, I think what really happened here with Dashcon was that the people involved were young, inexperienced, naive, and there was obviously drama because, uh, I'll link to this.
Speaker 1: Dashcon put out a couple of different versions of this and they seem to have like tried to remove bits over time, but they have this like giant explanation of separating fact from fiction and official statement.
Speaker 1: I read this whole thing.
Speaker 1: It, to summarize it, we're all fuckups and this is our attempt to try to make ourselves look a little less like fuckups.
Speaker 0: We know how to write.
Speaker 1: We are.
Speaker 1: This is, we don't know how to run a convention, but we know how to write like the five year old that you find in his bedroom with the pie that he stole from the kitchen, like smashed all over his bed.
Speaker 1: And he's trying to explain to you the series of events.
Speaker 1: I can explain this and how it was not his fault.
Speaker 0: It's really smooth talker, but that pie is still all over the place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I'm looking at the pie.
Speaker 1: He's like, well, there might've been a pie.
Speaker 1: Someone else was responsible for the pie.
Speaker 1: I'm just responsible for the room the pie ended up in.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about some other failed conventions from history.
Speaker 1: From history?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: What, what, what failed conventions can we think of?
Speaker 1: You know, the only convention I've been to that I would consider a failure was Setacon.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Because as a person who uses the internet, I saw Dashcon as a disaster coming from the day it was announced that they were accepting panel submissions.
Speaker 0: I didn't even know it was a thing until I read the stories about it failing and I was like, oh, I guess this thing happened.
Speaker 1: They emailed me asking if we were going to be at Dashcon.
Speaker 1: I thought, I assumed it was some My Little Pony thing.
Speaker 1: So I was like, yeah, no.
Speaker 0: Oh, cause Rainbow Dash.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I was like, no, we're not going to that.
Speaker 1: I didn't even like look up what it was.
Speaker 1: And then like Mike Tool, I think tweeted something about like, oh my God, look at this Dashcon panel submission thing.
Speaker 1: I clicked on this expecting to make fun of some cronies.
Speaker 0: So you knew about it before the convention happened.
Speaker 1: The best reading this page, which I'll also link to the page on panel submissions.
Speaker 1: If you as a human being read this page and do not see that this convention is going to be a disaster from that point, you're the kind of person who's going to get scammed into buying a stereo from a guy in a white van.
Speaker 1: Dashcon was a guy selling you a really expensive stereo system for way cheap out of the back of a white van in like the parking lot of a Sears.
Speaker 1: I have almost no sympathy for the people who attended this convention.
Speaker 1: So as a result, I have not experienced convention failures because I see them coming and avoid them.
Speaker 1: Cinecon, we were paid to go to.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: They didn't fuck up even close to the degree of Dashcon because we got our hotel room.
Speaker 1: We got everything was compensated.
Speaker 0: All that stuff worked.
Speaker 0: All the events happened?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: The geek nights meet and greet.
Speaker 1: We showed up to run it.
Speaker 1: Everything was fine.
Speaker 1: The room was there.
Speaker 1: Microphones were there.
Speaker 1: No attendees.
Speaker 0: Wasn't there one attendee?
Speaker 1: One attendee.
Speaker 1: It was one of our fellow guests who came in to see what was up because no one was at their panel.
Speaker 1: And then the three of us left the room and went to the fast karate room.
Speaker 1: We're like, "Hey, what are you guys up
Speaker 1: to?".
Speaker 1: And they're like hanging out in this empty panel room.
Speaker 1: And then we eventually all converged on the Happy House of Hentai meet and greet panel.
Speaker 0: That actually had people at it.
Speaker 1: Yes, all of us and a few other people.
Speaker 1: And then we hung out.
Speaker 0: But yeah, just no attendance caused the not so success of that convention.
Speaker 1: We pretty much sat in the room that was like the guest's room.
Speaker 1: Like imagine the hall where all the guests sit at their table and you get autographs.
Speaker 1: So all of us who were paid to be there just kind of sat in that room hanging out.
Speaker 1: No one came in at any point who wasn't one of us.
Speaker 1: I walked over to the dealer's room and there were like 10 or 15 people walking around.
Speaker 1: There were people who went to the cosplay thing at the end, but that was a disaster because they asked us to judge it.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about judging cosplay.
Speaker 0: I judge the one that looked best.
Speaker 1: I was looking at people stitching and I was like, "I don't know, four out of five stitchings?
Speaker 1: Sorry, kid.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you bought this from a store.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what character this is.
Speaker 1: I don't understand enough about costuming to look at your reference material.
Speaker 0: That one definitely looks better than the other one to me.
Speaker 0: If it was on the internet and it was hot or not, I would pick that one.
Speaker 1: There was that first New York Comic-Con.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, they failed because they sold out.
Speaker 0: They had people showed up who couldn't get in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was a professional event and they fucked it up big time.
Speaker 1: I mean, when guests can't get in to run their own panels because the fire marshal has shut you the fuck down, that's it though.
Speaker 1: I haven't really run afoul a lot of these conventions.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've heard a lot of tell of smallish gaming cons.
Speaker 0: How many Rude-A-Cons failed?
Speaker 0: Did they even count?
Speaker 0: Did it even technically happen?
Speaker 1: So actually, that's a good example because that was the first convention I ever staffed.
Speaker 1: I was asked, well, tricked by hook and crook, I joined the staff and I became the webmaster for this convention.
Speaker 1: And then I went to the first meeting and the meeting was about how we as a convention are going to apologize to the vendors from the previous year for straight embezzling their money and thanking them for not involving the police.
Speaker 0: And I was like- How could you embezzle- Nope, nope, nope, nope, nope.
Speaker 0: How could you possibly embezzle a vendor's money?
Speaker 1: Openly.
Speaker 0: So what they did- The vendors give you money for the space, they come in and they sell things and collect money for themselves.
Speaker 1: So there was a currency at the convention called, I think, Rude-A-Box, and you could win them at events.
Speaker 1: They counted as dollars in the dealer's room.
Speaker 1: The dealers would then get cash from the convention after it was done.
Speaker 0: They just didn't give them the cash for the Rude-A-Box?
Speaker 0: Pretty much.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: There were a lot of Rude-A-Bucks.
Speaker 1: So, yeah.
Speaker 0: They just handed them out like candy?
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: That was before we were even at RIT.
Speaker 0: If I was a vendor, I'd be like, "Fuck your
Speaker 0: Rude-A-Bucks.".
Speaker 0: They're basically the- "You're Jackson's face on that
Speaker 0: shit?".
Speaker 0: "No.".
Speaker 0: "Eh, you ain't getting nothing from
Speaker 0: me.".
Speaker 1: It's that currency in itchy and scratchy land.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Bits.
Speaker 0: Dogecoin.
Speaker 0: Not taking your dogecoin.
Speaker 1: But basically, seriously.
Speaker 1: When it comes to- I feel like we could do a separate- I don't want to do a Geek Nights on this.
Speaker 1: I almost want to do a separate YouTube series of every area of a convention.
Speaker 1: Dude, if you're seriously going to run it, here's the playbook on how to run this shit.
Speaker 1: Because if you read this Dashcon thing, most of their excuses come down to, "Well, Jenny McShavidoo was responsible for that, and she didn't respond to an email, so I wasn't able.
Speaker 0: The first thing we said about running a successful convention, reading and responding to emails immediately.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much just nothing but passing the bucks around, because these kids had no idea what they were doing.
Speaker 1: And it's really just summed up by that ball pit.
Speaker 0: Buck stops here.
Speaker 0: Who is the con chair?
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: But it appears- You read the con chair, and you email someone.
Speaker 0: They don't email you back.
Speaker 0: It's on you.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's it.
Speaker 1: In the old days, before we got Kristen and other people to help us, if something went wrong, I had a panelist come up to me, and they were like, "We were promised a hotel room, and we don't have one, and we need somewhere to sleep tonight, and there was no one I could go to above me to deal with that.
Speaker 1: That was my responsibility to figure out what the fuck happened there, and I had to deal with it.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: I dealt with it.
Speaker 1: People at Dashcon didn't deal with it.
Speaker 1: They just kind of let it all slowly collapse around themselves.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando Kay for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.