Speaker 0: It's Monday July 28th 2014.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about children and Technology and the future.
Speaker 0: it's all right Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So my office needed a Security camera just because someone walked into our office like during the day not that long ago went into what like we have a little conference room kind of by the front door and Like they just walked in and took someone's laptop and walked out.
Speaker 1: Awesome good.
Speaker 1: Yeah them.
Speaker 0: so we you know we dealt with that, but the CEO was like we need a security camera.
Speaker 0: And I'm started to learn over the years that in every job I've ever had whenever there's anything that isn't like in the direct purview of like everyone's specific job They call someone else to take.
Speaker 0: no they call me.
Speaker 0: Everywhere I've worked IBM my current company my previous company that hospital anything weird everyone's like hey And they come over to me, and they're like how do we get a security camera?
Speaker 0: And if someone else is tasked directly with one of those weird jobs that person will come over to me and ask me Like what do you know about security cameras?
Speaker 0: because they assume that I know something about it.
Speaker 1: Is you're the only one knows how to Google exactly so.
Speaker 0: little googling later I found actually that security systems are not that expensive like big ones with like for Night-vision cameras and loaded up with SD cards.
Speaker 1: probably just need one camera and a recorder, and that's it yeah.
Speaker 0: So I looked at all these systems, and they were not that expensive And they'd be really.
Speaker 0: you could probably install it yourself trivially like five or six hundred bucks tops for like a really good system That'll keep like a month's worth of HD video and all that stuff and ir splash.
Speaker 0: And then I looked at him, and I realized that if I buy that I'll have to install it.
Speaker 0: I'll have to maintain it.
Speaker 0: I'll be in charge of it for as long as I work here which Called like some security company to come do it.
Speaker 0: Oh That's how.
Speaker 0: I'm the phone administrator of this company.
Speaker 1: you're doing the phones - you didn't?
Speaker 1: you don't have a contract for that.
Speaker 0: I am the phone.
Speaker 0: I am the phone person.
Speaker 0: I in fact Am a phone person now.
Speaker 1: Did you set it up with?
Speaker 0: I set up everything power over ethernet up?
Speaker 1: No, it's not VoIP phones.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: It's not just regular.
Speaker 0: I suggested VoIP phones.
Speaker 0: They didn't want to pay for them, but they're just better in every concern.
Speaker 0: I know don't get me started.
Speaker 0: so Then I realized you know all that.
Speaker 0: so then I just ordered a drop cam and I told the person you know like our office manager like look you can set this up here because it's like you know.
Speaker 0: drop cam It's like they didn't set it up up, so they couldn't even though babies first wasn't their fault.
Speaker 0: So here's my problem with drop cam because I like drop you couldn't mount it.
Speaker 0: Oh, no none of that.
Speaker 0: I well one.
Speaker 0: I'm the only person in this company who drills into drywall.
Speaker 1: Okay Take a drill you aim it at the wall, and you push yeah Just I'm holding the trigger dad make sure it's plugged in.
Speaker 1: make sure that the screw the the drill bit is in tight.
Speaker 0: You know when I went into I feel bit key Was al Biles told me after he played his jazz trumpet and said you should join IT Toodly-toodly-toot you'll make a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Toodly-toodly-toot won't have to do a lot of work Toodly-toodly-toot, and he was a hundred percent accurate.
Speaker 1: and all that the guy told me the same thing.
Speaker 0: yep You chose a slightly harder job that pays slightly less But you get to do what you actually want.
Speaker 1: I could make much much more if I so decide I work for me.
Speaker 1: Well, I could work less than 40 hours a week.
Speaker 0: I could make that guarantee, but you'd have to do mostly like really boring Java development.
Speaker 1: Can I sit around and read reddit for most of those less than 40 hours long as you finish the tickets?
Speaker 0: I assigned to you and the code I give you.
Speaker 1: can I bike into work and bring them a bike in the office?
Speaker 0: That's what I do.
Speaker 1: Can I wear like shorts and a t-shirt?
Speaker 0: I've just been fucking wearing shorts to work.
Speaker 1: Can I have like 30 vacation days?
Speaker 0: no Anyway, so I get the drop cam and I have a drop cam.
Speaker 0: now like I use it That's our bunny camera or whatever and they're great like I like them.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna review the drop cam on this at work.
Speaker 0: I plug it in Doesn't work.
Speaker 0: It's a broken one, and it gives you zero Information.
Speaker 0: it has an LED that can show blue or orange With or without blinking.
Speaker 1: This is what people want Apple products.
Speaker 1: You can't think you did just work.
Speaker 0: so I plug it.
Speaker 0: so I plug it in and it's simple.
Speaker 1: So I look no help for you.
Speaker 0: And of course the office manager like she set it up a hundred percent correctly and when she plugs it in it Blinks yellow, which means connecting.
Speaker 0: then it shows blue like connected to Wi-Fi And then she gets an email like it turned on and it shows a picture that it took right then.
Speaker 0: but then if she clicks on the video it times out and eventually the light on the camera just turns off and nothing and There's no logs.
Speaker 0: I even like plug the device into a computer and poked around like there's no logs anywhere.
Speaker 0: The website just says your camera is not connected.
Speaker 0: long story short it needs a bunch of specific ports open out to the internet and That's not documented fucking anywhere.
Speaker 1: No, it probably just assumes you have like a UNP PNP or basic home router.
Speaker 0: Even with that like it doesn't work.
Speaker 0: It needs like 13 like the RTMP port open to the outside and port 80 And some other things and it just doesn't fucking say anything.
Speaker 0: gives no way to troubleshoot this.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it says if you google it, so I plugged it.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't.
Speaker 0: that's the problem.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's someone who wrote this.
Speaker 0: I found a few blogs of people but the official drop cam website Basically doesn't actually give you any as the kind of thing that would be in the drop cam forum on the support forum on their.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know how I found it.
Speaker 0: someone was complaining saying that they should be able to configure the ports They should but they didn't say what ports it starts on by default.
Speaker 0: I just had to assume it.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: So knowing what I know I got it all set up and got it working and then I had some other issues where occasionally It'll just turn off and not turn back on Mmm, so I opened a support ticket with drop cam.
Speaker 0: They have yet to respond.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: They They're not.
Speaker 0: I don't think they have that many employees.
Speaker 0: They're still not fully integrated into nest because nest bought them and Google bought nest.
Speaker 0: so the hard.
Speaker 0: it's like GoPro.
Speaker 0: the hardware is great But at the same time the interface to that hardware is kind of.
Speaker 1: but well It's.
Speaker 1: you know, that's what happens when you try to buy simple stuff and not pro stuff.
Speaker 1: Yes, we're too used to pro stuff and semi pro stuff.
Speaker 0: I know I mean, I'm looking right now at the Mackie We use for like geek nights.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking back to like what if we tried to do geek nights now with the not professional equipment We had before and I would just quit.
Speaker 0: I was like not do geek nights anymore.
Speaker 1: All right, so in somewhat tech news Alright, the only thing I could find anything to say about Amazon opened up a new store today.
Speaker 1: It's actually just part of Amazon.
Speaker 1: I don't know what they call it like a store, but it's really just a section of the amazon.com For 3d printing and it sells 3d printing supplies.
Speaker 1: books about 3d printing Smart move plastic that you can use.
Speaker 0: it's not the maker.
Speaker 0: ferret for 3d printing is big.
Speaker 0: I mean how many people are kick-starting.
Speaker 0: I'm making a 3d printer.
Speaker 0: That's the same as all the other 3d printers, but crooks slightly.
Speaker 1: so right you can actually buy 3d printers, too.
Speaker 1: But the one thing that they're selling that's interesting is actual things that are 3d printed now.
Speaker 1: They're not competing directly so much with shape ways where you send shape ways that your model and then you know Your digital file and then they print it and send it to you.
Speaker 1: What they're doing is they sort of have like these pre Done models.
Speaker 1: so for example Create your own 3d printed Mixi for 30 bucks and what you do is it's like it's almost like you make a me using this little interface in when you check out and like you can choose the hair and the color in the face and whatever and Then they print.
Speaker 1: so it's sort of like you can slightly customize this 3d printed model And then they print it out and send it to you.
Speaker 0: That's a pretty good idea.
Speaker 1: So you don't have to know any 3d modeling and you can get some personalization.
Speaker 0: Emily even had that idea like way back when ponies were things she was like.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna do this because you know shit talking But it'd be trivial to make like a bunch of pretty generic But very high quality pony models and then let people customize the parameters that are trivially customized and print their things for them.
Speaker 1: I mean this you know Hasbro just went to a partnership with shape ways.
Speaker 1: Right yeah, and they're actually.
Speaker 1: you can go to the take an official pony printing site and do similar thing.
Speaker 1: They're like.
Speaker 1: it's actually an official partnership.
Speaker 1: I think it's good.
Speaker 1: shape way saw how many people were printing ponies Yeah, and they must have contacted Hasbro.
Speaker 0: the deal Hasbro was way the fuck behind the curve on making merchandise And we talked about that on other shows.
Speaker 1: But well we love fine seems to be scooping up all the money on companies that are way behind on making merchandise.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we love vines a brilliant business model.
Speaker 1: It's almost like just don't like any of their products.
Speaker 1: They're tacky as fuck.
Speaker 0: You know what they are.
Speaker 0: they're the square print silkscreen red dragon shirt.
Speaker 0: That's what they are.
Speaker 0: square print Twilight Sparkle.
Speaker 0: yep But the ponies themselves at least like the model is a pretty simple model and doesn't have the kinds of things that Make it difficult to print like a lot of.
Speaker 0: like anime characters might have a unicorn horn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what's hard to print tall things with thin legs.
Speaker 0: You know it's easy to print squat things with big old blob legs.
Speaker 1: You could just print the thing the tall skinny thing really big yeah, but even then it's gonna have issues sure.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I mean Unless you put like polonium in the feet you can't make a Sailor Moon crystal model.
Speaker 0: It'll stand under its own power.
Speaker 0: I don't think crystal.
Speaker 1: no You can make a Luna model yeah, or you can make a But a wand.
Speaker 0: so I think this story a wand in quotes.
Speaker 0: So this story does tell us one thing that we've been saying a lot 3d tech like the 3d printing stuff like people kind of poo-poo.
Speaker 0: it is like this really like early hobby thing.
Speaker 0: once again It is moving way faster than almost everyone thinks it is a 3d printing.
Speaker 1: It's like you look at oculus rift, and I'm like.
Speaker 1: I don't think in any time soon It's gonna be small convenient or cheap enough for everyone to be using that Etc.
Speaker 0: yeah like people are into it will use it nerds for it will use it same with Google Glass.
Speaker 1: But the 3d printing that's already a thing right.
Speaker 1: I mean originally 2d printing was a thing that you couldn't do unless you went to A printing press and 3d.
Speaker 0: I remember when I'm binkos opened up near my house Jesus Christ and like some majorly rich person might have a printer I went to that.
Speaker 0: kinkos.
Speaker 0: like the week it opened with Machine was a big deal.
Speaker 1: you had to go.
Speaker 1: It's like the library, and they had one.
Speaker 1: you put quarters in it.
Speaker 0: I remember printing copy photocopies of pages from my Dungeons & Dragons books and that was goddamn magic.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: and now You can just print.
Speaker 1: I can rent fucking photos which the the for like 30 cents.
Speaker 0: Yeah, drug store used to have to do and Scott was 24 hours.
Speaker 0: I was printing ultra high-resolution glossy photos on photo paper at our booth at Connecticut with no, and I didn't even need power outlets though I used them because I can use them and you were just sending the photos to that thing wirelessly wireless.
Speaker 1: I took a photo in the camera wirelessly send it to the iPad where I Photoshopped it and then wirelessly sent it to a printer that could have been battery powered which then print.
Speaker 0: It's got.
Speaker 0: think about this when we were kids.
Speaker 0: You know what didn't exist wireless anything about CB radios.
Speaker 0: a computer powerful enough to do any of that.
Speaker 0: printing on paper printing in color Right.
Speaker 1: so 3d printing is gonna be just.
Speaker 1: you know it's gonna be just like 2d printing is.
Speaker 1: yeah I just think the thing is.
Speaker 1: 2d printing is something that died.
Speaker 1: No It's something that like a lot of people sort of generally needed.
Speaker 1: right like Everyone needed it.
Speaker 1: if you had a computer you sort of needed a printer.
Speaker 1: You know cuz like you would off with.
Speaker 1: you know especially pre-internet you would type a letter But then you couldn't internet it to anyone's.
Speaker 1: you had to print it and mail it or print it and hand it into the teacher.
Speaker 1: And even today, you know if you're in school or even in a business you still need to print out documents, right?
Speaker 1: I think people print way more documents than they really have to.
Speaker 0: oh my god Don't get me started by about any developer.
Speaker 1: probably like one in 50 documents actually needs to be printed.
Speaker 1: that's a conservative estimate, but There are occasions where you still need to print out documents.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anytime developers asked me a question about a spec and I walk over and they show me the section they have a question on because They print it out like the whole confluence page.
Speaker 0: I'm like guy.
Speaker 0: I've updated that page like 40 times in the last month.
Speaker 1: Yep Yep But yeah 3d printing is not every something everyone will need to have in their home.
Speaker 1: But you know cuz like a lot of people might just never need to print a 3d thing.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: at the same time I could argue that the same thing was said of printing on paper for a time.
Speaker 1: Mmm, I mean like what would my parents ever need to print in 3d?
Speaker 0: So imagine well, let's skip the far future.
Speaker 0: We're duh, like you're printing like everything right when you're printing food.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: We're skipping that.
Speaker 1: we're talking about the plastic.
Speaker 0: The next level is gonna be where every hobbyist who has a physical hobby will have one.
Speaker 0: Absolutely, because that's when you're like you're making a Gundam model and you break something like up better But another one for not a policeman partner exactly.
Speaker 0: So I think it'll just it'll pull it but almost everyone.
Speaker 0: Who's a human?
Speaker 1: Who is every?
Speaker 1: every nerd and art person will will need will want one even whether they can afford one or not.
Speaker 1: But it'll get cheaper - it'll be like 200 bucks like a desk yet.
Speaker 0: So my hope is that everyone in the industrialized world who's otherwise mostly achieved Maslow's pyramid like you have food.
Speaker 0: You're not living in a crippling poverty.
Speaker 0: You're gonna have some hobby that involves physical components of some kind and I think that will like that level.
Speaker 0: once printers get That reliable when there is reliable and probably still as expensive as an inkjet printer I think you're gonna see we're like 60 70 percent of internet at households will have one within 30 years.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'm really like.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure I'm not married to that I'm just.
Speaker 1: but I mean like how even if you have a use for one if you don't use it that often you're probably better Off just having someone else print your 3d
Speaker 0: things, but that's another interesting trend We're seeing is that like
Speaker 1: Amazon store this
Speaker 0: kind of an aside, but young people I mean all the car companies and they're still going crazy about this if you pay attention to like mainstream media They're like Millennials aren't buying cars.
Speaker 0: They're all trying to figure out like why Don't live in stupid suburbs like dumbasses.
Speaker 0: Yep But part of it too is that young people who live in cities in my opinion are way more willing to share Things that require a lot of capital investment with other people in their demographic or even just other people.
Speaker 0: I mean most people who live in New York can't afford to have their own rec room with a pool table in it.
Speaker 0: So guess what?
Speaker 0: There's a whole bunch of pool halls that you can play pool and instead it's just.
Speaker 1: that's just cities Period so but in the suburbs.
Speaker 0: So cars are the same way now in the sense that a lot of people are willing to share cars.
Speaker 0: Use their friends cars or use things like zipcon and taxis.
Speaker 1: But again, oh, he's drive that you don't go anywhere and you just stay home and internet.
Speaker 0: So 3d printers are again the same way.
Speaker 0: I know enough people who have 3d printers to where if I want to print anything 3d I can ask a whole bunch of different friends or go to this Amazon store or go shape ways.
Speaker 0: Yeah So, maybe we won't need them all in all of our houses because so enough of the people in this young tech demographic will have Them to where everyone has one.
Speaker 0: It's like even if you don't even if not everyone we know has a smartphone Everyone we know is almost always in the presence of someone they know who has a smartphone.
Speaker 0: So in other news, this is kind of amazing a New virus was discovered the kind that hurts people of now hurts computers.
Speaker 0: We're not sure what it does compete people people virus.
Speaker 0: It hurts individual cells arguably, but you know a lot of viruses are pretty benign.
Speaker 0: This one's the bacteriophage.
Speaker 0: Okay, you know your guy kills all the bacteria not necessarily, you know.
Speaker 0: You know the guy in every biology textbook in the world goes in the bacteria who multiplies.
Speaker 1: He looks like an octagon with a little bug behind him.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: He looks like the little bug Yeah with a little and then he explodes the bacteria in it or the cell and a million little viruses come out.
Speaker 0: So well, they don't always explode.
Speaker 0: There's other.
Speaker 0: they can all work in different ways.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: So I knew one of those was discovered and apparently it is infected possibly the vast majority of all humans and has been Present for a long time.
Speaker 0: Okay, and yet somehow we never noticed it.
Speaker 1: Well, it's really fucking small.
Speaker 0: So yeah So there's this whole story that and if it's not like a high quantity in your body.
Speaker 0: It's sort of a newly discovered virus has been found by a San Diego State University team to live inside more than half of all Human gut cells sampled.
Speaker 0: Yep There's a cool complicated story of how they found it.
Speaker 0: they're trying to figure out what it does all sorts of things about it.
Speaker 0: there's the article talks a lot about Why it was so hard to find it and it looks like every other kind of virus.
Speaker 1: you pass right over it when you're looking In the microscope.
Speaker 0: It's a little more complicated than that.
Speaker 1: We don't sample a lot of gut cells.
Speaker 0: people One.
Speaker 0: they sample gut cells via fecal matter primarily or as the scientists who wrote this article said poo.
Speaker 0: Sure He's like poo.
Speaker 0: He just calls it poo.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 0: So Remember things that we think about as common knowledge.
Speaker 0: a lot of those things were not discovered But relatively recently case in point vitamins go.
Speaker 0: look up when different vitamins were discovered.
Speaker 0: We have not known about vitamins for that long guys.
Speaker 1: Flintstones vitamins, right?
Speaker 1: You know why they're Flintstones vitamins?
Speaker 1: because we discovered that shit and we started selling them when the Flintstones were hot when Flintstones hot 70s 60s and 70s.
Speaker 0: This is the second time you've brought up Flintstones in a casual conversation by a tangent.
Speaker 0: It's the.
Speaker 1: it's what's it called if we ever done.
Speaker 0: is the bear shitting in the woods syndrome?
Speaker 1: No, that's what.
Speaker 1: no, that's what I call that thing where you see the same like word being used.
Speaker 0: Yes, I call that bear shitting in the woods.
Speaker 1: Why is it bear shitting in the woods in George Carlin?
Speaker 1: I'd ever heard that bit anyway, I'm gonna go find it on YouTube after this anyway.
Speaker 0: So, yeah vitamins were discovered relatively recently and The whole reason I'm bringing this up is one.
Speaker 0: It's real science news.
Speaker 0: It's interesting.
Speaker 0: Some research might come out of this but most importantly the virus has the best name I have ever heard for a virus ever.
Speaker 0: It is called the ass phage.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, cr.
Speaker 0: It's crass phage, but capital CR Lower case capital a s capital a s s ph a GE.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: It is the ass phage virus and this crass is also a great word the crass and crass phage.
Speaker 0: the ass phage Slash shot is mostly focusing on the name.
Speaker 1: Why wouldn't you?
Speaker 1: what else is there to focus on?
Speaker 0: and here's a comment I am the last author on the paper Mmm, and it was discovered by my bioinformatics lab in the CS department at SDS you it was named after our analysis software CR uppercase a SS cross assembly because they're Investigating poo.
Speaker 1: So that's why they named it that way because their software is about poo.
Speaker 0: So thus they decided to go all out on that kind of like out IBM.
Speaker 0: We had a huge server we were building.
Speaker 0: that was just a data store like hundreds of terrible ridiculous storage server.
Speaker 0: so we're like, what should we call it?
Speaker 0: and We came up on the BMFS which stood for officially big motherfucking server.
Speaker 0: But we came up with some other reason.
Speaker 0: that acronym was there so we wouldn't get in trouble.
Speaker 0: But I present for your consideration the ass phage.
Speaker 0: but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: You all may or may not be familiar with the music video to a song entitled turned down for what what what?
Speaker 0: The music video is pretty special in its own way.
Speaker 0: It's the most special but that's not my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I'll link to it because you really should see what it is.
Speaker 1: Possibly You can handle it if you can handle it.
Speaker 1: You should watch it.
Speaker 0: So it's it's.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 1: a lot of people can't handle it.
Speaker 0: It's pretty turned down pretty unhandleable.
Speaker 1: I don't know it for what but what?
Speaker 0: Our whole thing over the weekend with when we had friends over was the Skeletor?
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: So unrelated.
Speaker 0: Oh, I could mash those up pretty well turned down for what what what?
Speaker 0: So this is that music video but the music has been removed and they have foleyed in all the.
Speaker 1: What is this foley?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: you give using that word.
Speaker 1: I don't know where that word came from.
Speaker 0: really, okay.
Speaker 0: So, you know in a movie when like you see a dog run by like in a house Like just this dog in a house running by and you hear like their nails like running by on the hardwood.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm That doesn't get recorded When they're filming it obviously, but why would it be called foley?
Speaker 0: Oh Lee is what that's called foley.
Speaker 1: It's called dubbing.
Speaker 0: No, dubbing is the voices.
Speaker 0: foley is when you recreate in a sound studio Individual sounds or like sound effects to go along with a movie Sound effects.
Speaker 0: No, that's called foley.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Should I link to you to an article on foley?
Speaker 1: I don't disbelieve you I just I just didn't know there was a special word.
Speaker 0: Foley is the reproduction of everyday sound effects that are added to film video and other media in post-production to enhance audio quality.
Speaker 1: I didn't disbelieve you.
Speaker 1: I just said that's a word I hadn't heard You just say put in sound effects.
Speaker 0: putting in sound effects is where you take an existing sound effects library and add sound effects to Something.
Speaker 0: foley is when you take like a melon and then you put like a knife in your fist and you stab it And then you you and you stab it along with the movie to make the sound of stabbing.
Speaker 1: Just making sound effects.
Speaker 0: Yes making sound effects for movies Okay Especially adding in like the little background clicks and things like when people bump into each other someone gets hit someone drops a phone book Like the.
Speaker 0: did you ever read on how they made the lightsaber sounds in Star Wars?
Speaker 1: electric razor in a metal bowl?
Speaker 0: exactly That's foley.
Speaker 1: Okay Who doesn't know that tonight?
Speaker 1: if you didn't know that and you had to and you were surprised by my answer Well, you're not a real geek.
Speaker 1: Take that Regardless of gender it could have been.
Speaker 0: I was about to make a geeks.
Speaker 1: Listen to geek nice.
Speaker 0: I was about to make a really inside joke.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: He's good.
Speaker 0: Anyway This music video with no music and with just really well foley didn't sound effects is basically a horror movie.
Speaker 0: It is horrific to behold.
Speaker 1: That's it was a horror movie to begin with.
Speaker 0: trigger warning for what?
Speaker 1: Everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah So you got a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 1: it's actually Star Wars related.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Star Wars.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess it's Flintstones time right?
Speaker 1: This is an article on boing.
Speaker 1: boing the limits of animal life on Tatooine.
Speaker 1: Maggie Coerth Baker science writer and boing boing on why the megafauna of George Lucas parched desert world makes no sense.
Speaker 1: It's not the dry heat.
Speaker 1: That's the problem It's the food supply.
Speaker 1: big long awesome article.
Speaker 1: all this Gandalf girth thing plus science, but even better.
Speaker 1: at the bottom It says read the rest of the Tatooine science carnival.
Speaker 1: This post is part of a series spread over several blogs all about the animals climate oceans of Tatooine.
Speaker 1: Be sure to check out the rest of the stories.
Speaker 1: Tatooine is oceans news to me Even though I know how to make lightsaber noises.
Speaker 1: I did not know the desert world had water on it.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's underground or some shit Tatooine.
Speaker 0: What about Dantooine?
Speaker 1: totally different planet?
Speaker 1: only nerds know that those are Planets, but they're both in Star Wars and both mentioned in the original trilogy.
Speaker 0: off and or Hoffs forest moon Not hot and or or indoors forest moon.
Speaker 1: and or you mean yeah.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I Was always a big fan of the ice planet.
Speaker 0: ha they had all these Legos That were like ice planet dudes.
Speaker 1: my brother had ice planet Legos, but they were not hot ice planet.
Speaker 1: But now they actually have hot Legos.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: You know what they actually worked in the snow.
Speaker 0: Do you know how many Legos I'd lose every winter in the front yard and then find in the spring?
Speaker 1: I'll never bring it never have a pool and bring your boat Legos in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most of those ended up in the pool filter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they go and then they're all bleached out from the chlorine and disgusting.
Speaker 0: Yep, yep in the meta moment the book club book is a canticle for Liebowitz.
Speaker 0: I'm only on my fifth novel since I finished it waiting for Scott.
Speaker 1: When do you read these novels?
Speaker 0: I guess I read faster than you.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It just went like I read really fast.
Speaker 1: if I read on the subway I'm not on the subway.
Speaker 1: I'm biking every day occasionally.
Speaker 0: I subway like if it's raining.
Speaker 1: Okay, but if I occasional subway, I have to hack all the portals and I don't read on the most of my subways underground.
Speaker 0: So I don't hack any portals.
Speaker 1: most of my subways above ground.
Speaker 0: Let's read books.
Speaker 0: Also, I fly.
Speaker 1: the underground part is like five minutes.
Speaker 0: I also actually read when I'm laying in bed before I go to bed.
Speaker 0: I Read the internet and sometimes I read while I'm cooking Video game if it's fairly low impact cooking.
Speaker 0: I did not read during those times if it's not that interactive in the cooking.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, we got a bunch of videos up.
Speaker 0: We were streaming a lot more.
Speaker 0: so follow both of us on Twitch because now the kinetic ons passed.
Speaker 0: We have no conventions until packs.
Speaker 1: Mmm, speaking of packs Huge metamoment news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the biggest metamoment news we've ever had you've ever.
Speaker 1: so if you usually skip the metamoment You just fucked up.
Speaker 1: You fucked the fuck up.
Speaker 1: So fucked up just in case we were worried We might not get a panel at PAX Prime this year because that shit keeps getting bigger.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're not getting any bigger.
Speaker 1: We're sort of the same size.
Speaker 0: Yep, and wall packs have been very good to us.
Speaker 0: I mean we've performed it literally.
Speaker 0: love you packs without exception since 2008.
Speaker 1: I will continue to kiss your ass But because I want to not because I'm getting a reward out of it because your ass tastes so good.
Speaker 0: We flew to Australia to do a panel at a PAX on purpose because we wanted to.
Speaker 0: yes They didn't pay us to do that, right?
Speaker 1: Anyway, but I don't want to I don't want to assume but we were worried, you know Just in case maybe we wouldn't get a panel at.
Speaker 1: PAX is here because it's bigger and badder and awesomer.
Speaker 1: So I bought some tickets to PAX and cuz I'm good at internetting.
Speaker 1: I got four four weekend passes.
Speaker 0: now if you want to know how hard it is to get these passes I want to point out that Scott and I Noticed badges went on sale and entered the queue at roughly the silk within the same minute.
Speaker 0: Definitely Scott got four day badges the maximum you can get four for four day badge And it was sold out by the time I got through the queue.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: So I bought the four four day badges and our panel was accepted.
Speaker 1: so we don't need any of them But Emily needs one.
Speaker 1: So Emily gets one.
Speaker 1: Yes, and then they cost a lot of fucking money.
Speaker 1: They're like a hundred and ten dollars each.
Speaker 1: So I don't care if you hate me.
Speaker 1: I got to sell at least one of these fuckers to get some money back.
Speaker 1: cuz yeah, I have money.
Speaker 1: that's $440.
Speaker 1: that's a lot of fucking money I could have bought in a really fancy camera lens or all kinds of crazy shit with that money I don't buy but the other two We will sacrifice for you, maybe We're going to use them for self-promotion Advertising purposes because maybe you know, like I said geek nights isn't getting any bigger But maybe with the injection of packs badges it can be.
Speaker 1: so here's what we're gonna do.
Speaker 1: We need you people who listen to geek nights who want to go to packs, but don't have tickets.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do the same stupid thing.
Speaker 1: Everyone else does.
Speaker 1: we're gonna make a tweet, right and You can retweet it.
Speaker 1: or you can make a tweet to like your favorite geek nights episode.
Speaker 1: You know It has to link to us in some way to promote us and has to have hashtags of geek nights and also the hashtag of packs two hashtags Right.
Speaker 1: that way it'll get promoted when people search for packs related tweets And also people will know the name of geek nights and also be linked to our shit Though you could even just link till.
Speaker 1: it doesn't have to be a geek nights episode.
Speaker 1: You could link to one of our YouTube videos.
Speaker 1: It is the link to some of our content in some way even a pecs panel and have those two hashtags.
Speaker 1: Or you can even be like at geek nice hashtag packs.
Speaker 1: That's okay, too.
Speaker 0: Well, the I geek nice can't be at the beginning of it, obviously.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, we're not gonna guess and I don't know we might be able to add in G plus and Facebook.
Speaker 1: The issue there is.
Speaker 1: we have to be able to find your message when we do a search, right?
Speaker 0: That's all you.
Speaker 1: Twitter only I think for now Twitter only.
Speaker 1: if I figure out how to search for like everyone who did this You know G plus or Facebook.
Speaker 1: we can do it there also.
Speaker 1: but for now Twitter only.
Speaker 1: if you do that, we will randomly select someone and On the day, I receive the packs badges in the mail I don't know what day that's gonna be and Then I will immediately that day go to the post office and mail the two of them to that person if you
Speaker 0: wish if it
Speaker 1: Direct messaging them on
Speaker 0: Twitter
Speaker 1: and getting their address for whatever.
Speaker 1: if you fail to direct message me back within like the 24 hours, I can pick someone else and that's how it's gonna go.
Speaker 0: Yep on the off chance that for whatever reason we can't mail them to you because you're like you You know a person without an address or something weird we can give them to you at packs
Speaker 1: and I will swear That you know you if you meet us on the Thursday morning or Thursday pretty much any time after I land
Speaker 0: Well, I'm gonna be a fax dev the whole time.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll give them to you You can.
Speaker 0: there's anything?
Speaker 0: is these sky-high?
Speaker 1: There will be plenty of opportunities if you are a person who has your shit together to find us in Seattle and get the badges.
Speaker 1: I promise you that you know you paying for your airfare and hotel, which we are not contributing to in any way shape or form.
Speaker 1: It's just the two tickets.
Speaker 0: Oh, I was about to promote the prepack sky-high tabletop play benefiting food.
Speaker 0: Fuck out.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Well, there you go.
Speaker 1: So you're not going to that unless you already have tickets to it
Speaker 0: Yep,
Speaker 1: but yeah If you do not have packs tickets and that is the thing that is keeping you from packs prime I have to their
Speaker 0: badges to guys
Speaker 1: their four-day packs tickets, you know I'm not bullshitting.
Speaker 1: you can get them if you promote geek nights by Twitter in the correct way.
Speaker 0: Yes starting now stay.
Speaker 1: we're going to make a news post on our website with the full Instructions and rules.
Speaker 1: I hope we don't get in trouble with some like state law about contests and prizes or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Yep, basically for people listening.
Speaker 0: It'll be.
Speaker 0: you have to have hashtag.
Speaker 0: geek nights Hashtag packs, they're separate hashtags You can also have at geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yeah Can't be the first thing in your post because then no one will see it except us and it has to link to Something that we created.
Speaker 1: some of our content must be linked with a URL and it must be geek nights content.
Speaker 0: If you link to like my personal blog Yeah, you can't link to one of my netrunner videos But it's okay to link to my rims YouTube account because that's basically the official geek nights one and all our packs lectures are there.
Speaker 1: I guess you could link directly to the channel.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, you could link to a geek.
Speaker 1: nice presents you.
Speaker 1: Tana has to be some sort of geek nights content.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah, that's it.
Speaker 1: All
Speaker 0: right so Our friends had a baby and the babies a
Speaker 1: lot of friends who had babies Yep
Speaker 0: But the one of them had one a while ago and this one's formed up to the point where still kind of preverbal like Talk, but it's that kind of not making sense talk.
Speaker 0: But what I'm gonna go what we noticed that was interesting was watching this kid because I've been very rarely around young children.
Speaker 0: What I am.
Speaker 1: that is for the better.
Speaker 1: our society's rules are functioning as design.
Speaker 0: Hey kid You want to learn the words?
Speaker 0: They're gonna make your mom flip the fuck out.
Speaker 0: They got a bit a little older for that.
Speaker 1: So I told him hey if you want to know anything about the history of your parents or anything about them Yep, you just find anyone named Scott.
Speaker 1: There's like two or three of us.
Speaker 0: We all knew your parents before they were dating each other both of them.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: So, uh what I noticed?
Speaker 0: because you know, they came over and seen him forever.
Speaker 0: They're in our apartment The kids running around up.
Speaker 0: His middle name is danger, which is like double awesome, but that's all before the opposite of awesome.
Speaker 1: They'll find out when he goes to school whether that's awesome or not.
Speaker 0: I think it's pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: It's very much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're not some student in school who may be positively or negatively Appreciating that.
Speaker 0: so I noticed something when he was running around our apartment doing his kid thing.
Speaker 0: he was a kid by all normal ways, but He went around seeking out anything that looked like electronics and the first thing he would do is try to interact with a Touchscreen on it
Speaker 1: or push buttons
Speaker 0: if there was no
Speaker 1: wanted to push buttons and touch screens and look at screens.
Speaker 0: Yep, he would push the button and it wasn't just random.
Speaker 0: He if he was pushing buttons and it wasn't having any visible outward effect He'd figure out they were fake.
Speaker 0: Like I gave him my controller like my big arcade stick and it wasn't plugged in anything.
Speaker 0: So he messes with it.
Speaker 0: He loi why he immediately looks up the TV while he's messing with it realizes it's not actually plugged in and got mad at me.
Speaker 1: But then when he like if it got a reaction like once I gave him my GoPro and he pushed the button and he didn't Understand that it was a camera, but it beeped when you push the buttons.
Speaker 1: So he liked pushing those.
Speaker 0: But once he figured out how to turn off the TV He wanted nothing more than to make sure that TV was fucking off or on again.
Speaker 0: And the most beautiful thing though was we were you know, we had the Hgpc plugged in so we had it like a Windows desktop.
Speaker 0: on the TV There's a YouTube video that we had been playing.
Speaker 0: it was paused.
Speaker 0: The first thing he did when he saw the TV is ran over and hit the TV screen itself his finger.
Speaker 0: He hit the pause button Specifically to make it play again.
Speaker 0: Now my TV is not a touchscreen.
Speaker 0: that obviously didn't work.
Speaker 0: But think about this.
Speaker 0: a kid who's like a year old Already understands touchscreens more than most adult humans that I know.
Speaker 0: Kids growing up now are in some ways Fundamentally different from kids who grew up in earlier era.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I grew up with a keyboard and a gamepad So I fundamentally understand those things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I also know how to use a touchscreen Exactly, but I won.
Speaker 0: I'm starting to wonder more about what kids who were growing up now Like what they're gonna be like in terms of technology because I'm what I love is a technology issue.
Speaker 1: This is more like a child psychology issue.
Speaker 0: Ah, but the technology is allowing child interactions that in the history of humanity basically couldn't exist.
Speaker 0: Okay, like we're kids have access to the kinds of information environments that like it's almost unprecedented the interactivity that they can have.
Speaker 1: There's been something unprecedented in every era of child.
Speaker 1: No one has raised children that grew up similar conditions that they grew up in.
Speaker 0: arguably there were multi-hundred-year spans throughout many of the great empires of history where Multiple generations in a row grew up under effectively identical cultural and political regimes.
Speaker 0: Those were dark ages and they were dark for a reason up also like during non dark ages like ancient Greece and places like that.
Speaker 0: It's just a lot.
Speaker 0: of those societies were for long Like stretches in the micro were pretty static in terms of like child rearing.
Speaker 1: Okay, those are societies.
Speaker 1: No one living.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus what about that?
Speaker 0: I mean from Cro-Magnon to like the births of Civilizations and writing and agriculture and all that people raising kids.
Speaker 0: Nothing really changed much.
Speaker 0: the rate of change of technology Relation to the span of human lifetime is accelerating and the rate of acceleration is itself accelerating.
Speaker 0: that rate by the way is called jerk.
Speaker 1: Why don't we just call it rim?
Speaker 0: then I'm the acceleration of an acceleration that you're a jerk.
Speaker 0: So I realized - looking back at me as a kid I mean I grew up without computers.
Speaker 0: computers came After I was already like really sentient and already could do math and stuff Apple - in kindergarten and we didn't have our a 2600 and a video game before kindergarten and an NES in elementary school.
Speaker 0: I mean, I didn't have a cell phone until college.
Speaker 1: I didn't own one till college.
Speaker 1: My family had them when I was in high school.
Speaker 0: Yep, my family also had them when I was in high school.
Speaker 0: I would occasionally borrow it up smartphones.
Speaker 0: I didn't have until like 2009.
Speaker 1: smartphones Existed when we were in late college because Steve Pomeroy had them.
Speaker 1: But I didn't have one until the day the iPhone.
Speaker 1: I didn't personally own what I had blackberries from the job I got as soon as I graduated college or just counted.
Speaker 1: But I didn't personally own one until the day the iPhone 3g came out.
Speaker 1: I was in line about it.
Speaker 0: I was a functioning adult on my third for real career job when I first had in my possession a device That would show me a live map of where I was with GPS data.
Speaker 1: iPhone 3g do that.
Speaker 0: I didn't have an iPhone 3g.
Speaker 0: I Didn't say first thing that existed.
Speaker 0: I said I owned one.
Speaker 1: I mean you could have had the palm trio Yeah, I could have but I didn't or one of those windows CE phones.
Speaker 0: I bought a Symbian phone.
Speaker 0: I used my work blackberry for like six months and then I bought a palm pre.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 0: So I didn't grow up having a lot of like could directly always connected access to information.
Speaker 0: And when I think back at my life the way I interacted with the world was Fundamentally different from the way I interact with it now I mean I had to explore neighborhoods because there was no way for me to know what was around.
Speaker 0: What flipped through the yellow pages?
Speaker 0: Go through a road atlas.
Speaker 0: There's like 15 years out of date.
Speaker 1: use triple-a because we're driving to Florida What I bring out a triptych when I go home.
Speaker 0: I got through the highlighter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the guy would like print out maps and highlight your route for you And you know what.
Speaker 0: if something went wrong on that trip you were fucked.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm In fact, uh, I remember in the old days I used my triple-a card which was long expired But the triple-a website only checked to see if the number was valid.
Speaker 0: It didn't check to see if the account was active to let you log in.
Speaker 0: So throughout all of our IT I could go generate trip ticks and I stopped doing that once Map quest and Google Maps we use my best because Google Maps did not yet exist.
Speaker 1: I'm used Yahoo Maps when map quest is giving shitty directions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we kept using them because Google Maps version 1 was garbage.
Speaker 1: And then Google Maps became good and all the other maps died.
Speaker 0: But even then we would before a trip like someone's job was to figure out the route Print all the maps for the entire trip because we got on the road without those maps.
Speaker 0: Oh bad news at a convention.
Speaker 1: So we're mostly just talking about olden days now and not talking about kids at all.
Speaker 0: So think about kids now.
Speaker 0: It's a growing up one.
Speaker 0: So you agree they can look up Anything at any time all the time thus eliminating 90% of the conversations I had as a child.
Speaker 0: Like a kid like once it could get to the point where they start using technology.
Speaker 0: Why will the Kelvin's dad situation ever happen again?
Speaker 0: Will a kid ever ask their parents how something works when they know that they can just type it into the internet and they'll get An answer?
Speaker 1: well kids in elementary school ever be like in Mortal Kombat.
Speaker 1: There's a secret you can get boo boo ballad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know who's gonna say that?
Speaker 0: I have a theory about what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: the divide like we always talk about.
Speaker 0: the digital divide and how it's wide and how it's why than anyone realizes and way more important Than anyone realizes.
Speaker 0: I think it's even worse than that.
Speaker 0: I think because I've seen this already the children of People I have seen who themselves are not supercomputer are also not supercomputer Mm-hmm, but the children of people who are computer are so much more computer than even their parents already That I think that it's not like the computers and the internet and all this access is gonna democratize our culture.
Speaker 0: I think the divide between digital kids and not connected kids is gonna be so great that That is going to be the primary former of clicks in physical schools among young kids growing up.
Speaker 1: I'd see I mean I go to the mentoring and it's at a computer high school a public computer high school the Academy for software engineering.
Speaker 1: yeah, and I go and I see these high school kids right and There are a few who are.
Speaker 1: those nerdy kids are coding.
Speaker 1: They're gonna be Steve Pomeroy But most of them Don't computer right even though they're out of computer school.
Speaker 1: They can use a computer, but they don't understand how computer works.
Speaker 1: for reals They don't have.
Speaker 1: they did that instinct to Google everything, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they're still reading like video game magazines from GameStop, right?
Speaker 1: They don't read Polygon right.
Speaker 1: they don't know really what's going on.
Speaker 1: There's one kid.
Speaker 1: Metal Gear is his thing number one thing right of all his geekeries.
Speaker 1: for me Metal Gear is like man, right?
Speaker 1: Not into Metal Gear really.
Speaker 1: I like old Metal Gear, but I know Metal Gear, but I'm not super into it.
Speaker 1: I can't get past like two rooms in Metal Gear solid.
Speaker 0: Right, I didn't like Metal Gear solid.
Speaker 1: I knew more about Metal Gear than this kid because I internet.
Speaker 1: I Mean.
Speaker 1: he knew.
Speaker 1: he knew like all the Metal Gear games that existed He knew what you would know about Metal Gear if you went to GameStop and played every Metal Gear game and read video game Magazines.
Speaker 1: right, but I knew who Deo Kojima was and he doesn't.
Speaker 0: so that's my question are his parents internet?
Speaker 0: Do you have any way to know?
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: don't know
Speaker 0: because I'm starting to think I'm worrying that When we like when I see kids that tends to be kids of internet people and those kids seem like like I see them on A path that could not have existed in the world I grew up in like though they're gonna grow up to be so much more reliant upon and connected to technology than I ever was.
Speaker 0: But at the same time when I interact with other kids I feel like they're less internet than kids who grew up in the era of no internet.
Speaker 1: It's also, you know the computers, you know, it's like we had were.
Speaker 1: if we wanted to internet right we had to do the hard way right.
Speaker 1: They just like Facebook whatever true.
Speaker 1: No, so they end up not learning anything about actual computers.
Speaker 0: but at the same time not everyone has to learn about the core computers.
Speaker 0: because I see some kids who Like.
Speaker 0: they use computers effectively like if they don't know something they immediately google it.
Speaker 0: But most kids don't even do.
Speaker 1: that I'm saying is I think it's the percent.
Speaker 1: All right, so back in the day some percentage of kids are gonna be computer.
Speaker 1: I don't think the percentage is increased.
Speaker 1: It's the same percentage as it was when we were in school.
Speaker 1: Yeah right But of that percentage in our day a hundred percent of the kids who are gonna be computer II Had to learn everything for reals because there was no other way.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now same percentage of total kids will be computer internet II but a smaller percentage of that will actually learn anything about how Computers work.
Speaker 1: and the other person, you know of that small percent now just use computers and the same number of people don't know anything.
Speaker 0: Yep There's also this other factor that they just Facebook and Candy Crush.
Speaker 0: The other thing that they have that we didn't have is everyone else around them recording everything forever.
Speaker 0: I mean all of us posted embarrassing shit when we were in like elementary school and middle school on internet places.
Speaker 1: I wish there had been more that would see.
Speaker 1: here's the thing people complain about.
Speaker 1: they're like Oh no ruin your life.
Speaker 0: I would give anything to be able to go back with things that I owe much that there was more documentation.
Speaker 1: I can go back and just see You know pictures videos Recorded accounts of dates and times because I don't remember much.
Speaker 1: Yep, if I had things recorded back in the day.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I mean if I've been able to save my pokemons to the cloud in high school and my original pokemons I still have them now.
Speaker 0: the other day I found a single picture that I didn't know existed.
Speaker 0: That was a picture of the inside of our apartment at our IT.
Speaker 0: That wasn't that long ago.
Speaker 0: It was like finding the remnants of the Holy Grail Like I'm looking in the background like look at that CRT.
Speaker 0: who the fuck is that?
Speaker 0: Oh, right Scott on that Israeli flag.
Speaker 0: What are those huge speakers?
Speaker 0: What happened to those?
Speaker 0: Like huge speak.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we had these huge speakers just like laying on the floor next to my computer.
Speaker 1: They were like a foot and a half where those part of that like Set only a foot and a half.
Speaker 1: that was that black sound.
Speaker 0: right that awful sound system that you used as your speakers.
Speaker 0: Yeah uses my speakers and sorry.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I thought you meant huge speakers like, you know person tall.
Speaker 0: No not one foot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no those part of that sound system Yeah And it was the boombox I had and I look at the screen and I saw that I was playing Final Fantasy 4 on my Computer.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Just randomly and it looked like I was fighting as a Romans Paladin.
Speaker 0: Yeah but Kids now are growing up in a world where all everything they do is cataloged forever.
Speaker 0: if Their friends and or family are internet people Mm-hmm I think there's gonna be another digital divide between kids who have this documentation of their lives and kids who don't.
Speaker 1: Mmm, because if your parents have documentation of your life, right?
Speaker 1: I mean we want documentation of our lives.
Speaker 1: But what if your life was really shitty and you have documentation of it?
Speaker 1: And so it is everyone else.
Speaker 0: Yeah It could be bad it's good or bad.
Speaker 0: the thing is it's It's good and bad.
Speaker 0: it's fundamentally different and that's the only thing we can say about it.
Speaker 0: We can't say if it's good or bad.
Speaker 0: It's just different and inevitable good and bad.
Speaker 0: Ah And yeah, well, maybe maybe it's not bad, but there's a short-term bad and a long-term good anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you got a time machine, you'll go take back and take video of my life.
Speaker 1: Please do.
Speaker 1: I don't care what happened then.
Speaker 1: I want to see it.
Speaker 0: So I guess I Don't know what to do about the divide because I'm thinking about that more and more and I think it's it's gonna be like.
Speaker 0: I think the digital divide there's.
Speaker 0: the way different children grow up with different access to technology is More controlled by their parents and the culture of their family than it is by a lot of other factors.
Speaker 0: And I think a lot of kids who would otherwise be internet e and smart if their parents are not also pushing them toward internet They will not internet and they will just be completely left behind by their peers who internet.
Speaker 1: let's predict this horrible dystopia.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it'll be a dystopia where the the Technological elite rule and the people who don't understand computers are peasants.
Speaker 0: That is what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: I just don't know.
Speaker 1: That's just what you want to happen.
Speaker 0: No, I really don't.
Speaker 1: I I imagine I think it's gonna be more like ghost in the shell right where yeah, there are people who are super internet, but People are getting by and people aren't peasants, right?
Speaker 0: They're just getting by an internet world I guess I just I imagined a world where everyone I interact with on a daily basis Had the personal capability of googling things they didn't know And I realized that that is utopia for me.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm If the average person that I talked to Knew just I had a vague awareness that anytime they didn't know something they could just google it and they did that.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine the kinds of conversations I would have with strangers.
Speaker 1: people.
Speaker 1: What about people who?
Speaker 1: it seems like they just don't want to know things.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like people just have.
Speaker 1: they just do things right?
Speaker 1: It's like they watch TV.
Speaker 1: They go to work They get drunk.
Speaker 0: So, how do we go to sleep?
Speaker 1: They eat food They don't want to know things Hunger for knowledge because we didn't have internet.
Speaker 0: and then we did a group without internet.
Speaker 0: and then one day I got access to internet.
Speaker 0: And basically if you chart that my life and what I was doing with different percentages of my time The day I got access to the real internet ice the majority of my time Became that to the exclusion of almost everything else.
Speaker 0: Yeah It was like I was walking through the desert and then someone walked over and said Here's a spigot of infinite water.
Speaker 0: use it as much as you want for the rest of your life Drinking for the rest of my life mostly so.
Speaker 0: then I hand it to other people and they're like what the fuck is this?
Speaker 1: I prefer to be thirsty Or maybe they're just not there.
Speaker 1: Yes, they don't need water to live.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you spray them with it They're like practices.
Speaker 1: They don't need too much water.
Speaker 0: So it's the world of of geeks wearing camelbacks that are connected to a giant spigot in the sky and everyone else is a camel Eventually dying alone in the desert after breeding.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: I think we're taking it up.
Speaker 0: Someone just linked.
Speaker 0: someone just tweeted.
Speaker 0: Okay, they didn't have the hashtags, but they just tweeted to video of our panel.
Speaker 0: They don't know about the contest yet.
Speaker 0: Obviously doesn't count.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't have the hashtags, but I just they just tweeted it.
Speaker 0: now I found that funny.
Speaker 1: Okay doesn't count.
Speaker 0: Yep Alright, I think we're done.
Speaker 0: I'm hungry.
Speaker 0: It's nice.
Speaker 0: I don't want to go run.
Speaker 0: I'm hungrier for food right now than I am for information.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: It was the baby.
Speaker 0: I stole from Randle Princess Adora.
Speaker 0: Princess Adora.
Speaker 0: You remember the baby the baby?
Speaker 0: we broke into the palace that time.
Speaker 0: It was the only time me and you work together.
Speaker 0: Yes, I remember.
Speaker 0: Yes the baby.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes the baby.
Speaker 1: Yes What the baby skeleton you remember.
Speaker 0: you must remember it was that one time.
Speaker 0: Remember I was having a hard time with the vehicle couldn't get the jetpack flying on them on them.
Speaker 0: you remember.
Speaker 0: Oh Yes, the baby of course The baby What.