Speaker 0: It's Tuesday June 10th 2014.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: level editing and games.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Oh My god, it's e3.
Speaker 0: I've never cared about you know in my entire life as big of a gamer as I am And as much as I deeply cared about video games, I never cared about e3.
Speaker 0: I vaguely wanted to go back in like the you know, the that era when we would read like mega Tokyo.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, I only cared about e3 like I can't because I couldn't get into it.
Speaker 0: I wanted to be at it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like when I was in high school, you'd get like video game magazines.
Speaker 1: They'd be like check out all this stuff from e3.
Speaker 1: You'd be like, what's e3?
Speaker 1: I guess it's a place where they have all these great games and you can play like crazy.
Speaker 0: I forget e3 any conference like that.
Speaker 0: until the internet and until I went to like a lot of conventions I pretty much assumed that every time I heard about a video game conference of any type It was exactly like the Nintendo tournament at the end of the wizard.
Speaker 0: But I was really disappointed when it turned out.
Speaker 0: that can conventions are not like that at all.
Speaker 1: I'm still surprised e3 even exists because was there was a time it died completely.
Speaker 0: Well, it died as the show that was aimed originally, you know It had the problem where it was for the press.
Speaker 0: But fans wanted to go to and their paths were.
Speaker 0: they only had two possible pads.
Speaker 0: they could either go a hundred percent press only like for real and not just let like the guy who has a blog with one subscriber that's himself show up.
Speaker 1: or Well, it used to be the GameStop employee would show up because they're in the industry.
Speaker 0: Yeah Or they could go the other route and just try to become a shitty version of what became PAX.
Speaker 0: There's really no middle ground for a convention like that.
Speaker 0: Mmm, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I've just I've never been interested in e3 and actually I've never even been interested in the news or the announcements even as a journalist Because the announcements can be summarized by a list of bullet points of these games were announced.
Speaker 0: There was usually no reason to actually watch the press conferences.
Speaker 0: They usually show almost no actual gameplay.
Speaker 0: Sony actually is the only company that gets props in recent memory because they announced a game and Said it's already available for sale.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 0: That is that my head is off to you golf clap.
Speaker 0: However, the game Entwined looks beautiful looks like an amazing visual auditory sensory experience.
Speaker 0: It looks like the height of interactive amusement.
Speaker 0: Okay, I wouldn't necessarily say it meets any of the other definitions of game.
Speaker 1: I mean I might play it but I wouldn't pay money for it.
Speaker 1: And even if I got a free PlayStation and the game for free I might spend 20 minutes on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what it is watching it and oh my god I just looked at a trailer for it and the first comment was the same thing I was about to say.
Speaker 0: effectively.
Speaker 0: so they made journey to now withdraw fish and bird Except you can basically it's journey if you control both entities.
Speaker 0: It's just Viv ribbon it's just a rhythm game.
Speaker 0: I don't get why so many rhythm games have come out recently that Basically, how is it anything with the skin?
Speaker 1: It's like, uh, I played this game.
Speaker 1: now I will play this exact same game again only looks different now.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying there is not a place for aesthetics or style.
Speaker 0: I mean the game seriously is beautiful Other than the fact that apparently it also has dragon mode where the fish and the bird merge to become a dragon.
Speaker 1: Of course a dragon is just a fish bird.
Speaker 0: if your body knows that if your game has dragon mode Why the fuck is there a not dragon mode?
Speaker 1: But that makes the dragon mode that much more exciting.
Speaker 1: If it was just dragon mode from the start you'd be like, okay dragon mode, but it's like oh shit dragon mode time.
Speaker 0: I'll never forget my year with dragon mode.
Speaker 1: You had a whole year with dragon mode.
Speaker 1: It would get a little Who anyway.
Speaker 0: But there is.
Speaker 0: there is definitely a place for games that are these visual Experiences that are.
Speaker 0: you know rhythm games like this can be engrossing.
Speaker 1: They're an important part of gaming, but I see no reason to be excited about this game For this one, there's people out there who are just like so into video games and it's like, you know They actually like.
Speaker 1: these games are their thing like as much as we care about whatever we care about.
Speaker 1: They care about these games that were announced that much like they're so into it.
Speaker 1: but for me at this point I Really don't give a shit about any of these games at all.
Speaker 0: I give a few shits about some games.
Speaker 0: However, they're kind of out of my reach.
Speaker 0: I mean Nintendo is continuing to release its series of b-plus versions of its first-party games But not gonna buy a Wii U just to play the new Zelda game, especially because I didn't finish the last couple of Zelda games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean that's the main thing is like all these games that I had Twilight Princess like was really fun And then I really got tired of it way before I was done with it Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I mean look at the games that I have now.
Speaker 1: so on my 3ds Pokemon whatever unbeaten poke the pre Pokemon.
Speaker 0: really you haven't beaten Pokemon yet I haven't even.
Speaker 1: I guess I just stopped playing it.
Speaker 0: You didn't foil.
Speaker 0: I Sanders plot.
Speaker 0: It takes like 20 minutes.
Speaker 1: No Basically what happens to me lately right is I'll play a game and I'll be kind of into it and then I'll get to a Point in the game where it's just like it's just too much fucking work to continue.
Speaker 1: Fuck it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I was playing Fez.
Speaker 1: Fez is really good.
Speaker 1: I had these really interesting sort of puzzles.
Speaker 1: we'd flip the map around and you know It's really good puzzle platforming right and it was.
Speaker 1: it was fun Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then I got to a point in the game where in order to really make a lot of progress You had to learn to read the stupid fucking language or read a fact and I was just like, you know What fuck it.
Speaker 1: and I stopped playing.
Speaker 1: everybody picked it up again.
Speaker 0: Well, you know where it comes down Pokemon.
Speaker 1: I got to the town in the middle Right and the gym inside the Eiffel Tower was open and there was just so much stuff in that town Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: I didn't even go and look at any of that shit.
Speaker 0: You know what it is.
Speaker 0: It's a million cafes where three people tell you two sentences of dialogue, right?
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: But it's like I feel like wow, you just gave me way too much shit to do at once.
Speaker 1: Fuck this right Dragon Age.
Speaker 1: I got Dragon Age for like way cheaper.
Speaker 1: someone gifted it to me or something right a long time ago like months and months ago, maybe in a year ago and I'm playing it and I'm like, okay, this isn't really much of a game but you know there's something happening here and following the dwarfie story whatever just clicking through and eventually I get to a town and It's like oh you're in a town and inventory management.
Speaker 1: You have a zillion items and I'm like, fuck it never played it again.
Speaker 1: Well, there's two guy rim my same shit.
Speaker 0: I think there's a couple of different types of things.
Speaker 0: that'll cause people like us to Peter out on a game.
Speaker 0: A lot of the reason I'll play a new game is either because it's something truly novel.
Speaker 0: I'll play for the novelty like wow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got a mechanic that I have not.
Speaker 1: if there's something really new I gotta see what it is.
Speaker 0: Like for example, uh, a cron.
Speaker 0: Yeah time-traveling RTS.
Speaker 0: Holy fuck.
Speaker 0: Is that a novel idea?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but sorry, dr.
Speaker 1: Hazard.
Speaker 1: I couldn't get through the tutorial.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, that's because we're bad at RTS is it was just I couldn't Do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're.
Speaker 0: uh We're crippled when it comes to playing RTS, but you know what?
Speaker 1: Starcraft 2 on Easy slash normal mode.
Speaker 1: I beat the whole the single players.
Speaker 1: Yeah Even the expansion bit.
Speaker 0: but I get to a point.
Speaker 0: in games like that like any sort of single-player nominally an ortho game competitive game like that where I'm not going to engage heavily with the multiplayer community where the Single-player version of the game like the campaign or whatever it is Just kind of get samey.
Speaker 0: and I think that really happened.
Speaker 0: even look at castle crashers.
Speaker 0: The first couple of levels of castle crashers were really novel.
Speaker 0: The music was great They were really fun.
Speaker 0: Then the whole rest of the game was just the same fucking thing over and over again.
Speaker 0: No Slowly leveling up and unlocking a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: as soon as I have to unlock stuff I no longer care.
Speaker 1: as soon as I have to redo a part.
Speaker 1: I already did done.
Speaker 1: It's like it was.
Speaker 1: if your game is only fun once fuck it, right?
Speaker 0: But I said there is a place for games that are only fun once.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's that's.
Speaker 1: the point is if I have to ever redo a part I'll just give up on the whole game, right?
Speaker 0: You only if you've played Super Meat Boy you die and you're like fuck it.
Speaker 1: Super Meat Boy is actually good.
Speaker 1: But Super Meat Boy is another good example.
Speaker 1: It's like, okay, I beat Super Meat Boy I didn't do any hell levels.
Speaker 1: I didn't do anything.
Speaker 0: That's different.
Speaker 0: That's fine because I do like games that have a an ending point But then they have more for people for whom that game is their thing.
Speaker 0: I mean, I love the shit out of the challenge areas and bionic commando rearmed But I understand that most people want nothing to do with that.
Speaker 1: the game I'm playing most these days It's like my 3ds actually is where I'm playing the most video games.
Speaker 1: It's like I got games on there like the new Phoenix Wright or the relatively new Phoenix, right?
Speaker 0: I stopped caring about Phoenix Wright's a long time ago.
Speaker 0: They're all the same They're just you.
Speaker 0: you see a what would be an okay episode of an anime.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, you solve trivial logic puzzles.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Once I played the third like I was like, yeah, I no longer care about I have it.
Speaker 1: I haven't even opened.
Speaker 1: I haven't even launched it not even launched.
Speaker 1: It's been sitting there on my 3ds home screen, right?
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 0: Why'd you even buy it?
Speaker 1: I'll play it eventually maybe one day.
Speaker 1: I still haven't beaten.
Speaker 1: I have games for the DS that I have bought and did not beat right.
Speaker 1: I bought.
Speaker 1: I have a bunch of 3ds games on cartridges some that I bought when I got the 3ds Some of which I have not even put into the 3ds.
Speaker 0: I Bought the newest 3ds Zelda game and I have not actually played it yet.
Speaker 1: Which one's that?
Speaker 0: the Between worlds whatever.
Speaker 1: Oh, I beat that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the SNES Zelda remake.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I beat that.
Speaker 0: I'm going to play it but I'm powered through some fun parts towards the end of Pokemon.
Speaker 0: I gotta go victory road it up.
Speaker 1: if anyone wants that cartridge I will sell it to you because I will never put it in my 3ds ever again.
Speaker 0: But if I so because I have such a wide Panoply of games I can play Just every type of game.
Speaker 0: look at my Steam library But I could have.
Speaker 0: these games have never been installed.
Speaker 0: I can play anything.
Speaker 0: So a game either has to have a thriving current multiplayer multiverse for in which I can compete in which I wish to compete or It has to provide a novel experience or an enduring experience.
Speaker 0: Store interwoven FPS story games have not gotten too far past half-life 2 in terms of construction.
Speaker 0: All the like.
Speaker 0: you are military fighting military battle.
Speaker 0: I feel like I've played that game before.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no need.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you could do novel stuff.
Speaker 0: But until I see something really interesting and more novel than the other ones I've played I mean the new.
Speaker 0: you are military man.
Speaker 0: doing military thing is not that much different from the new Or the new man.
Speaker 1: you were even talking about how you're loving that day of sex.
Speaker 0: whatever human revolution was a fucking amazing game.
Speaker 1: I played that for like five minutes, and it's like oh fuck it.
Speaker 0: I don't care I don't understand why you didn't like that game.
Speaker 1: just walk around and shoot things game, and then there's not.
Speaker 1: I don't care about anything that's happening.
Speaker 0: It's walk around and not shoot things.
Speaker 0: the fuck were you doing anytime?
Speaker 1: I try to actually stealth.
Speaker 1: in any game that claims to be stealth I get seen immediately and get killed except bad at that Except for thief.
Speaker 1: thief is the only game where the stealth actually works seriously Scott metal.
Speaker 1: here stealth doesn't work.
Speaker 0: How in Deus Ex you just fucking.
Speaker 0: you see a guy.
Speaker 0: he turns his back you sneak up behind him and either knock him out Or crawl into the vent next to him.
Speaker 0: He'll never see you.
Speaker 0: I don't know how you.
Speaker 0: and then we get seen.
Speaker 1: you're on a map And it's like okay get from here to here and the only thing between you and there is a giant room with lights on everywhere And a million bad guys, that's never.
Speaker 0: there's no point in the game.
Speaker 0: That's like that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I just didn't care.
Speaker 0: You just don't play games anymore.
Speaker 0: I just don't.
Speaker 1: I really I just don't give a shit about Not almost any video game that comes out.
Speaker 1: I'm playing pie cross more than playing any other video game.
Speaker 0: So you're turning into one of those casual gamers.
Speaker 1: share pie cross.
Speaker 0: really pie cross isn't even a game.
Speaker 1: It's a puzzle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a puzzle.
Speaker 0: I noticed that you did not disagree.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 1: I don't disagree.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that's what you're just playing time wasters.
Speaker 1: It's an entertainment software puzzle.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm actually still the games I play the most right now our FTL.
Speaker 1: now that there's the expansion that game FTL I beat it and then I was done.
Speaker 0: you beat it on easy on baby mode.
Speaker 1: Yep, easy and baby mode You have no desire to play anymore.
Speaker 1: FTL ever.
Speaker 0: You didn't even play that game.
Speaker 0: That's like playing counter-strike once.
Speaker 1: I have no desire to play it ever again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know why you just don't like games anymore.
Speaker 0: I just don't.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, I'm playing a bunch of games.
Speaker 1: the point right.
Speaker 1: the point is e3 e3.
Speaker 1: However, everything they announced I don't care about even from the start.
Speaker 0: I would care about some of these things like for example, the new Zelda game looks pretty good.
Speaker 1: Okay, sure I would play the new Zelda game, but I'm not buying a Wii U for it.
Speaker 0: The new Mario Party looks pretty good.
Speaker 1: They actually I'll just play my old Mario Party.
Speaker 0: They added a mode that would be.
Speaker 1: I have that Mario game for the Wii new Super Mario Brothers.
Speaker 1: If four people can play it once.
Speaker 1: we never even played that.
Speaker 1: So why would I buy some Wii U Mario Party?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know why you bought that game because I knew we wouldn't play it.
Speaker 1: I'll play it at some point.
Speaker 0: No, you won't I'm gonna you're never gonna play it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna retire.
Speaker 0: probably lost it.
Speaker 1: I have it.
Speaker 0: I'm tired, but the new Mario Party actually does have an amazing mode.
Speaker 0: It has two ways to play the game normal Mario Party and Bowser Party.
Speaker 1: How does Bowser Party?
Speaker 0: Bowser Party is three people are playing Mario Party and one person.
Speaker 0: the entire game?
Speaker 0: Controls Bowser and the enemies in all the minigames.
Speaker 1: Let's just play Bomberman and then everyone have asshole revenge mode.
Speaker 0: Are you seriously saying that those are the same basic experience?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you get the same feeling from fucking.
Speaker 0: so Yeah, you know because Bomberman for one is a directly competitive ortho game Where the Mario Party so it's a party has a lot more random.
Speaker 0: no, because - it is basically take one type of game one minigame effectively the Bomberman game and Foster extreme mastery of that Mario Party is Foster competent mastery of a large number of disparate types of games.
Speaker 0: sure I mean, they're they're very different games.
Speaker 0: fundamentally I wouldn't really just brush them off the way you're brushing them off.
Speaker 0: But my problem with Mario Party 10 is this one?
Speaker 0: I don't trust Nintendo to make Bowser mode actually fun for Bowser Even win.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: they haven't announced enough details.
Speaker 0: They just I don't trust Nintendo to use the.
Speaker 0: we use capabilities at all and there is no way this mode is actually going to Be good.
Speaker 0: It's the.
Speaker 0: you know what this mode is gonna turn into.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be the mode where your friend Who doesn't like to play the competitive game?
Speaker 0: Well you get to be Bowser and they sit there and deal with it for like 20 minutes And then they get bored and now your game's fucked because you need Bowser for the whole rest of the game.
Speaker 0: That's what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: That's what this mode is Mmm.
Speaker 1: It's like that Zelda game.
Speaker 1: It's like okay I'd want to play that but I'm not gonna pay for it and I gonna buy a Wii U for it.
Speaker 0: I buy it and play it.
Speaker 0: if I didn't also have to buy a Wii U and there still are not enough games on the Wii U for me to buy it.
Speaker 1: one day They're gonna come out right like not the next thing after the Wii U like the Wii U plus or something right?
Speaker 1: They're gonna come out with like the Nintendo Revolution my foe from and like 20 years from now and on that the Nintendo console two generations from now.
Speaker 1: They're gonna have an e-shop where you can download digital games or I don't know absorb them into your consciousness, right?
Speaker 1: However, it works and they're gonna re-release.
Speaker 1: this old Zelda game will get re-released just like Wind Waker got re-released and Ocarina of Time got re-released.
Speaker 0: Ah, but when you care about it, I feel like with all the Zelda games that have come out in the last many years Many of them effectively replace others of them and that there is no reason for Anyone even people are into Zelda games to play all of them.
Speaker 0: There's a place you should probably skip.
Speaker 1: I've played every Zelda game pretty much.
Speaker 1: I think I had.
Speaker 1: I think I played every Zelda game.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, I didn't beat the train one on the DS.
Speaker 1: I played it a bunch and then stopped because it was awful, but every other zone.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, I didn't beat Majora's Mask either because it's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: But every other Zelda game I've beaten right?
Speaker 1: Yeah So I would play this why not?
Speaker 1: but I realized they keep coming up with like remakes.
Speaker 1: They came out like Wind Waker HD.
Speaker 1: So it's like I already played Wind Waker.
Speaker 1: I have no need for Wind Waker HD.
Speaker 1: But if I just wait two generations and don't play anything and they re-release everything I'll get a lot of value out of that new console.
Speaker 1: Right, like someone who never played Wind Waker Would get a lot of value out of a Wii U right now because Wind Waker HD is on it.
Speaker 1: So there's actually two games they want to play on it.
Speaker 1: That's old Zelda game remake and this new one.
Speaker 1: for me There's only one game on it.
Speaker 1: So it's not worth it.
Speaker 0: But also they announced the new Madden and I'm just what's the difference?
Speaker 0: do you even need to?
Speaker 0: well They make.
Speaker 0: they change things every year.
Speaker 0: They make players better fields the graphics I don't know.
Speaker 0: actually they made a lot of differences and there's a pretty long article about like the pretty specific Changes they made to how the game works.
Speaker 1: If I didn't buy the old Madden, why would I buy this Madden?
Speaker 1: I'll just play Tecmo Bowl.
Speaker 0: that they're very different experiences.
Speaker 0: There is a place in everyone's heart.
Speaker 0: So why?
Speaker 1: why is Madden an experience I would ever want to have?
Speaker 0: What's the last like football game you played?
Speaker 1: I Bought Madden for the first.
Speaker 1: we didn't played it once.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well that that Madden was like at a. that was an atrocity.
Speaker 0: against Madden games.
Speaker 1: I played Tecmo Bowl like the other day.
Speaker 1: I played ten yard fight like yesterday.
Speaker 1: Nah I was testing out an emulator and that's the first game.
Speaker 0: cuz it's not like blitz on the 64 begins with 10.
Speaker 1: So it's the first game Because it begins with one zero,
Speaker 0: but I guess this is where e3 just lacks my interest because I knew a new Madden game was going to come out and I knew that all the details about that Madden game were going to be released at some point.
Speaker 0: So the huge press conference and stuff about it Especially because they pretty much don't actually show gameplay in most of these e3 things Was completely useless except as a hype machine.
Speaker 0: and I noticed and this is just my personal opinion that a lot of the gaming journalists I know who I was following on Twitter their tweet streams reeked of forced enthusiasm and Attempting to say anything about the announcement.
Speaker 1: or they're actually legitimately enthusiastic because that's their only thing is video game?
Speaker 0: No Cuz I know these people and watching the tweet streams like you'd see the occasional tweet where it's obvious Like they're really into the new Civ game, which I'm pretty into the new Civ game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have Civ 5 I haven't played it and but then you see yeah, I don't know why Civ 5 is amazing.
Speaker 1: What am I supposed?
Speaker 1: I don't have time for this shit.
Speaker 0: I don't know what you do with your days that you don't have time to play video games at all.
Speaker 0: live Like I don't know what you do did.
Speaker 0: how long does it take you to do laundry?
Speaker 1: Actually been paying for someone else.
Speaker 0: do my laundry lately, then you should have plenty of time to live video games.
Speaker 1: I'm watching stuff and playing cooking food and biking and yeah, is that that bicycle show?
Speaker 0: You're just watching all this anime Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: Oh shit this new Sailor Moon, isn't there?
Speaker 1: It is sort of anime season right now, yeah it is.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, we'll continue on our March to mastering out since you tonic and leave you behind.
Speaker 0: Anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: So since we're talking about level editors as you may or may not know I was big into Editing levels and creating levels and modding shit in the doom days.
Speaker 0: You know back when no 3d knowledge was really required and the games were Just.
Speaker 0: they were simple to the point that I could know a great deal about the intricacies of the engine without having to spend months researching and reading books and learning this stuff, but It had their own editors to make it levels and to do stuff with the game, you know they use something to make the levels and There were a lot of other tools like win do.
Speaker 0: The tool that I used when I made these levels in doom primarily was something called wadded Like wadded as in wad editor because those files were called wad files.
Speaker 0: There's a whole history of wad files and why they were called that.
Speaker 0: it's kind of amazing.
Speaker 0: We'll skip all that.
Speaker 0: this is a YouTube thing that's got like 20 views and it's just a playlist of a bunch of video of the interface To wadded.
Speaker 0: this is the world I lived in and it's really interesting to look back at this interface and remember that I used to spend hours designing levels in this That are probably now gone.
Speaker 1: I've got them then no one will ever play.
Speaker 0: I could put if I put them on the forum.
Speaker 0: I'll bet people would play them.
Speaker 0: No, I don't have them.
Speaker 0: They're on that hard drive.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I could pay someone to fix that hard drive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the controller died.
Speaker 0: The platters are fine.
Speaker 1: Sure Yeah, so you ever seen you know that that foam that's shaped like egg crate, right?
Speaker 1: They call it egg crate I guess because you I guess if you put a bunch of eggs in it in the little cuppy parts, they would sort of right.
Speaker 0: Yep, I'm looking right now at a similar foam that's used to shield audio Surfaces and prevent echoes in a studio.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: Well, have you ever thought about how that foam was made?
Speaker 1: I mean we love videos showing me cool machines and factories that make stuff and work in a really interesting way and I thought just if you would have asked me how it was made, right?
Speaker 1: I would have said oh, they probably just squirt foam into a mold.
Speaker 1: That's the shape of an egg or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would have thought something similar.
Speaker 1: but well you did think something similar when I asked you that exactly we were both wrong.
Speaker 1: It's actually made in a much more clever way with this machine in this video.
Speaker 1: is the thing about this?
Speaker 1: is I had to watch this video and like actually look closely and think about it for a few seconds before I Really realized how it was working and then I was like, ah Genius clever girl.
Speaker 1: How about that?
Speaker 0: Hahaha Met a moment.
Speaker 0: The book club book is a canticle for Liebowitz.
Speaker 0: Scott has not updated the website yet.
Speaker 0: So let's send me.
Speaker 1: I got a. I don't do.
Speaker 1: I pretty much don't do anything unless I put a reminder in my.
Speaker 0: yeah Thingy, maybe that's what.
Speaker 0: so you get home You just don't.
Speaker 0: you just sit there doing nothing until like a timer goes off time to make dinner.
Speaker 1: No But like anything like that That's not something that I would think to do or naturally want to do.
Speaker 1: I won't remember to do unless I put a reminder.
Speaker 0: Yes I'm so glad meanwhile that you've remind me repeatedly and publicly on Twitter if I forget to do something like that Because you just don't do things even if you're reminded.
Speaker 1: If I have a reminder I get the reminder and then I do Don't do the thing ever.
Speaker 0: I guess the book club book is still wool.
Speaker 0: So I got already read that.
Speaker 1: no, it's not.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be a kinetic on in July 13th.
Speaker 0: it's a fucking amazing con and you should be there.
Speaker 0: We're also doing some of our own panels.
Speaker 0: They're gonna be a pecs prime.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be a pecs dev.
Speaker 0: I don't think Scott's gonna be a pecs dev.
Speaker 0: come say hi And go to pecs dev.
Speaker 1: probably not.
Speaker 1: No, you don't go to pecs dev unless someone else pays for it.
Speaker 0: Nah kickstart yourself going.
Speaker 0: no The Kickstarter will be.
Speaker 0: you'll make a game.
Speaker 1: No, I won't Listen, the only Kickstarter that I will ever do right that's gonna work is You give me enough money that I don't have to go to work and then I'll have time to fucking do something.
Speaker 1: If you guys want to pay my salary for like a whole year Then I will do something else that you want me to do.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, nothing's happening.
Speaker 0: So, yeah There was some news about level editors.
Speaker 0: that made us think to do this episode because I've actually been thinking a lot about level editors Independently of Scott saying hey, let's do a show on level editors.
Speaker 1: Well, I saw the e3.
Speaker 1: They announced this Mario level editor and I was like, oh, where was that?
Speaker 1: 25 years ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah 30 years ago at least 30 years ago while they could have had a level editor There was no way to monetize or community a fi that It didn't matter.
Speaker 1: a friggin excite bike had an editor.
Speaker 1: So why didn't Mario have one?
Speaker 0: Yeah, because that there probably wasn't enough space on the cartridge.
Speaker 1: Maybe no more copies of Mario 1 would have been sold but for like they could have on a Super Nintendo Right like a Mario all-stars.
Speaker 1: They could have had a level editor But again the cold calculus.
Speaker 0: would more of that have been sold?
Speaker 1: Listen had Mario paint even had the mouse.
Speaker 1: It would have been so easy.
Speaker 0: Yes, the mouse.
Speaker 0: who fucking owned that?
Speaker 0: a mouse other than you and me this other kid.
Speaker 1: I knew who is also named Scott.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: I dead mouse.
Speaker 0: I didn't amazing until I realized that games that needed Mouse did not support Mouse like Sim City.
Speaker 1: Only Mario Paint supported.
Speaker 0: no, no that King Arthur games supported it.
Speaker 1: I don't know what game you're talking about.
Speaker 0: Wow, really?
Speaker 1: My god, I'm gonna find only King Arthur game I know for Super Nintendo is like kid King Arthur or something or is it Merlin's son or something?
Speaker 0: What that game sucks.
Speaker 1: It was it was a garbage game.
Speaker 0: So you never played King Arthur's World never heard of it.
Speaker 0: Imagine lemmings.
Speaker 0: Okay, but you all the guys instead of being lemmings are troops that have different attack.
Speaker 1: So is this?
Speaker 1: how is this different from King Arthur's gold, which is that new game that we bought but didn't play vaguely similar?
Speaker 1: Okay, yeah How about that?
Speaker 0: I should live stream some fucking King Arthur's World because I can use the mouse.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 0: I'm so down with this.
Speaker 0: I'm doing it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so level editors right in tender should have released this level editor a long time ago.
Speaker 1: So it took them 30 years.
Speaker 1: So I guess the Pokemon MMO should have been released 10 years ago.
Speaker 1: So 20 years to go till the Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Can't count down.
Speaker 1: in 2034 when the Rangers are back in this and they got finals again because that happens every 20 years You'll also get the Pokemon MMO.
Speaker 1: finally put it in your calendar.
Speaker 1: Yeah level editors It used to be a lot of games came with a level editor that I'd usually just ignore and only occasionally use.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean now it seems very few.
Speaker 1: if no games come with it.
Speaker 1: It's like you can still mod some modern games But you sort of have to code and use your own tools and it's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: It's a launch game.
Speaker 1: They don't give you like the user user friendly level editors.
Speaker 0: So when I got my Super Nintendo for Christmas There was a game that I had on it because there weren't that many games out in 1992 91 RPM racing Radical psycho machine racing.
Speaker 0: Yep that game had a track editor Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Actually, it was a surprisingly full featured track editor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's see what it's a civilization - Right, yeah and Matt right.
Speaker 1: Sim City 2000.
Speaker 0: Well Sim City 2000 because the game is about editing a map.
Speaker 1: in a sense No, but they had the pre before you started playing the.
Speaker 0: yes, you could articulate your splines.
Speaker 1: I flattened the whole man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because we pancake because what a nice coastline and a nice river.
Speaker 1: to make it as easy as humanly possible.
Speaker 0: Yeah You're the same person who would play Civ to put all the other civilizations on one square islands in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 1: Not one square islands because then they could have boats.
Speaker 1: I made islands exactly the radius of a city and I put their city right in the middle So they couldn't possibly ever boat.
Speaker 1: and then I would make myself a nice beautiful large island fill it up with cities Boat over and shoot them one at a time with cruise missiles.
Speaker 0: Why would you do that?
Speaker 1: It was easy Because if I played the game normally, you know what happened I would get to the point where like I had way too many troops and I could win the game.
Speaker 1: But it's like oh, it's too much effort to sit here for another two hours.
Speaker 1: Fuck it.
Speaker 0: And yeah, I remember when I play the game with Ken.
Speaker 0: He was a really big fan of doing the fanatic stuff.
Speaker 1: So I did that too.
Speaker 1: Yeah when you've got Every single hex would have a fortress with full irrigation and a railroad and a fortified fanatic.
Speaker 1: Yep They didn't have any maintenance.
Speaker 1: so I could just make a million.
Speaker 1: I would just be pumping fanatics across the Trans-siberian railroad that I think someone would come over with like some real military units.
Speaker 1: I'm like, I don't care what unit you have.
Speaker 1: I have like a hundred fanatics stacked up in my city.
Speaker 1: It won't matter.
Speaker 0: But in RPM racing what I would do with the level editor is we would my brother and I would always make large open world maps by using the pluses because the game didn't.
Speaker 0: it only checked that the integrity of the map met these like Minimal requirements.
Speaker 0: so we'd make these giant like multi-directional maps and we never raised because the racing was not that fun.
Speaker 0: We play tag effectively or king of the hill or something like that.
Speaker 0: instead We'd always like hack together our own game on top of it man.
Speaker 0: Even stunts 4d racing had a level editor.
Speaker 0: Wow, a really advanced level editor, too.
Speaker 0: What if people still play that game?
Speaker 0: What if there's a speedrun community around that?
Speaker 0: But there when it comes to these level editors the embed there's three different types of level editors when you really think about it.
Speaker 0: There's the internal tool.
Speaker 0: like if I made a game engine or like I made a new Mario game What tool do I give to my designers who are making levels in that game?
Speaker 0: Like what do we use?
Speaker 0: We're not just gonna write raw code every time we make a level.
Speaker 0: There's more efficient ways to do that in most cases.
Speaker 0: But then there's the level of.
Speaker 0: do you make an editor like that for the users like Scott brought up those kinds of editors?
Speaker 0: Like hey make new levels in Mario.
Speaker 0: those need Radically different interfaces and affordances because you have to assume that the people making the games know a lot less about your engine.
Speaker 0: I mean, no one's going to be attaching scripts to objects in like a Mario editor that they release on the Wii U. Nope, nope, and then the third level are the fan Editors meaning there's a game that does not have an editor and fans make their own editors.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the Super Mario Super Mario World things.
Speaker 1: you see we're like some.
Speaker 1: they create some ridiculous combo right.
Speaker 1: that like does something crazy.
Speaker 1: We've done those this thing of the days before.
Speaker 1: yeah We have the results of using those level editors or like the Mario paint that you can just download Yep, or like.
Speaker 0: there was id software's editor for doom.
Speaker 0: but I would use all these fan created things that actually worked in fundamentally different ways and Some of them were kind of broken and some were kind of better than id's editor itself.
Speaker 0: but Each of these is like a totally different topic.
Speaker 0: you'd almost do a separate show on all of them.
Speaker 1: I mean, all right, so let's just let's just talk about some right.
Speaker 1: So what do you think is the best?
Speaker 1: Official editor that came with a game that you've ever seen.
Speaker 0: I can't get past stunts 40 racing right now.
Speaker 0: Actually, the advanced wars level editor was super good.
Speaker 1: Oh, that is a good one.
Speaker 0: It let you make really really crazily arbitrarily put together maps.
Speaker 1: You make any map you wanted pretty much pretty much.
Speaker 0: the only constraints really was just the sheer size of the maps Yep, but you can even put like weird units.
Speaker 0: you could do anything I would.
Speaker 0: I made some really I think amazing advanced wars maps that no one will ever play with me.
Speaker 0: So it won't matter My think.
Speaker 1: the one is the one that most people don't even know about which is on the n64.
Speaker 1: There was an f-zero game f-zero X which is pretty much just f-zero GX of shitty graphics And there was a level editor for you can make f-zero tracks the 3d kind with the loops and everything.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's you know, and it's like there's pretty much nothing like that.
Speaker 1: Right, and then you get to play basically real f-zero on it not some, you know gimpy racing game But f-zero for reals, you know.
Speaker 0: when I was in you know A young boy and I was playing stunts 40 racing because that editor was so complex.
Speaker 0: 40 racing was like the thing in my high school So people would pass around discs with their high scores and their maps and compete on each other's maps.
Speaker 0: I was really obsessed with making maps that had multiple ways to go and I was Particularly obsessed with making them such that they all took about the same amount of time no matter how good you were.
Speaker 0: And I was triply obsessed with designing those maps to where there was actually one way to go.
Speaker 0: That was a clever shortcut that catered to my skills so that I could make ridiculous times and beat all my friends Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's kind of a dick.
Speaker 1: when it came to that How is that any different from me making the sieve map with an island for each bad guy?
Speaker 0: Because I was at least doing this to cause other people to feel bad.
Speaker 0: You were making a rudimentary AI field nothing.
Speaker 1: if I played it multiplayer.
Speaker 1: Someone would have felt really bad starting on that.
Speaker 1: No boat possibilities plus mine revolve.
Speaker 0: one at least a level of subtlety And two it still required skill to pull it off and get that time.
Speaker 1: Listen, it required skill Skill of patience to sit there and so you can get boats and blow everyone up All right.
Speaker 1: So what game do you wish had an editor but does not?
Speaker 0: Well, I could almost cheat there because what about games where there is an editor?
Speaker 0: but it is beyond my ability to Use effectively or to where I could do something amazing with it But for the lack of time and energy willing to be.
Speaker 1: that's true for every editor.
Speaker 1: Even something that doesn't take too long to make like say Starcraft comes to the level editor.
Speaker 1: Right a Starcraft map doesn't take that long to make.
Speaker 1: it takes a long time to perfect it But not a long time to make it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But it's like you still had to put in a lot of time to make a good Starcraft map that anyone wants to play on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's more than games that had level editors.
Speaker 0: I wish they had used their level editors to more effectively let people compete with said levels.
Speaker 0: I want games to integrate level editors into the core game.
Speaker 0: Here's an example.
Speaker 0: Imagine a Mario game Where it has a multiplayer mode, here's the way the mode works.
Speaker 0: I design a level you design a level We then play our own level and the other person's level and then whoever has the highest score wins.
Speaker 1: See, it's play both maps.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: Castlevania on the DS.
Speaker 0: the the first one actually had a thing like that in it.
Speaker 1: Have you played Jason roars?
Speaker 1: castle doctrine?
Speaker 0: No, I have not.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that's a game where basically you make a house According to certain rules and then you put your stuffs in it and people try to break into your house and you try to break into other people's houses.
Speaker 1: So it's basically level editing the game and also navigating other people's levels the game.
Speaker 0: Yep You know what?
Speaker 0: It's you know what these all come down to.
Speaker 0: you know what.
Speaker 0: there's one type of game That is actually perfected that except that they usually don't do it with multiplayer.
Speaker 0: That is the tower defense game.
Speaker 0: You put the games are basically edit a map and make it as cheap and opportunistic as possible.
Speaker 1: There is a tower wars game, but it wasn't that good.
Speaker 1: I played it on Steam a few times and it's you basically simultaneously make a map and Send bad guys to attack the other guy.
Speaker 1: You're basically doing both at once Right, and he's and they're doing both at once to you, right?
Speaker 1: But you're like their bad guys interact with your map and your bad guys interact with their map, but that's about it.
Speaker 1: There's no other interaction going on.
Speaker 1: So it's really like you're just playing two games at once and who can play both games better?
Speaker 0: true I think they're.
Speaker 0: you know, we're kind of going down a road.
Speaker 0: I think there's a big distinction here because of an editor that's within the context of a competition or a game is Part of the game.
Speaker 0: But yet when we talk about editors We're usually talking about an external meta of a way to create levels within a game.
Speaker 0: I think they are actually fundamentally distinct.
Speaker 0: the most interesting thing that I'm surprised people haven't taken advantage of more yet is Straight up monetizing that and having community sharing map things which you see.
Speaker 0: Yes That's not widespread in other areas.
Speaker 0: A lot of games don't give you those capabilities or they don't use the community factors effectively.
Speaker 1: Well, these team workshop you can.
Speaker 1: there's the portal map editing right and some of those are really good.
Speaker 1: I've played a whole bunch of them the especially the co-op ones with some people, right?
Speaker 1: So like if you have a friend and you've played a whole bunch of portal and you just wish you're waiting for portal 3 to Come out like portals the kind of game where I'll actually beat it because it's that good But then I won't play it again.
Speaker 1: But hey, it's like if there was new portal I would play that right away.
Speaker 1: and there is new portals.
Speaker 1: people made it and a lot of it's not bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's even portal racing maps.
Speaker 1: Those are pretty fun, too If you have a friend to play them with.
Speaker 1: yep The way they work is basically you race around in a circle on a racetrack using portals.
Speaker 1: But you can also like with your portal skills, you know Like trigger obstacles that will you know harm the other players set them back and such, you know You know what those are like.
Speaker 0: gorge race pretty much.
Speaker 1: Yeah scored race.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to play old gorge race.
Speaker 1: now I'll play portal to co-op Race.
Speaker 0: man gorge race was only fun though because of how fucking broken it was Pretty much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if it wasn't broken.
Speaker 1: it would've been too easy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but At least ignoring the monetary aspects their Nintendo should have made things like this and made them available a long time ago Because that would have added a lot of long-term street cred Replayability to some of their games.
Speaker 0: they could have with the with the DS even Made ways for people to get maps and share maps and that could have been a whole like Nintendo community store thing.
Speaker 0: But we know they're afraid of communities.
Speaker 0: They're afraid of people talking to each other.
Speaker 0: They're basically afraid of anything innovative at this point.
Speaker 1: Well, they're gonna be forced into it, right?
Speaker 1: I think someone said desperate Nintendo is best Nintendo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz they'll start doing things they don't want to do.
Speaker 1: That we need them to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we'll see.
Speaker 0: because when was I mean when tenor was desperate before?
Speaker 0: were they even that desperate in the GameCube era?
Speaker 0: I mean GameCube was just the next iteration of Nintendo.
Speaker 1: the GameCube.
Speaker 1: I don't think was really Necessarily super amazing.
Speaker 1: It was just good.
Speaker 0: It was like solid Nintendo, right?
Speaker 1: But it was.
Speaker 1: it happened to be at the time when we had a bunch of people in the same place to play all those Four-player games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even then if GameCube came out now, we'd be like whatevs.
Speaker 0: I would have played a lot of those single-player games especially like.
Speaker 0: I mean that f-zero was amazing.
Speaker 0: If you want to just make yourself feel miserable Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: yeah, how can?
Speaker 1: there wasn't one on the Wii yeah, but this level editor?
Speaker 0: Yes, because at least from the screens we see it looks like it's ultra ultra Intuitive which is what a consumer fan facing editor needs to be.
Speaker 0: I mean I could make an editor for a game.
Speaker 0: Like if I made a game I could have an editor that a developer could use and that would be perfect for our internal use And it would also be perfect for like high-level fans Like.
Speaker 0: that's a way to engage the people who are really into your game Like the.
Speaker 0: the community of people who make maps for Counter-Strike Valve has a vested interest in keeping those people happy and giving those people the tools they need To make more levels to give their own game more replayability over time.
Speaker 0: But at the same time that tool the tools you use to make Counter-Strike maps are literally beyond the reach of 99.9% of humans like.
Speaker 1: I could learn it if I wanted to but I don't care.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it would take so much effort to learn that it would only be worth it if it was my job.
Speaker 0: They're expert tools.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, I don't enjoy doing it to the point where I would do it on my own on purpose And they're from a different perspective.
Speaker 0: those things are from the perspective of someone who knows how the engine works from from the inside and the outside and Knows how the game works like gameplay level design all those things.
Speaker 0: but because the game's so multifaceted There's so many aspects so many features.
Speaker 1: I think it's also because you know Counter-Strike is just like a full-on 3d game for reals.
Speaker 1: So just by the nature of technology, it's very complicated to make a map for it.
Speaker 1: It's very easy to make say a Starcraft map.
Speaker 1: It's just a grid, right?
Speaker 0: It's difficult to make a space an air and interesting Starcraft zero map isn't really any different than an excite bike map.
Speaker 1: There's a set number of components and you put them in a you know in a straight row together And then you eventually have to end where you started.
Speaker 0: yep, so but those games from a from a like interface perspective can still be really intuitive and Graspable by a normal person who was simply played the game super meat boy levels.
Speaker 0: really easy to make but it's really hard to make Those games that are well-designed?
Speaker 1: sure.
Speaker 1: Absolutely.
Speaker 1: I mean that's true for any game, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but technologically speaking right.
Speaker 1: the software to edit with a good user interface You know and the ability of a person to at least make a legal legitimate map made.
Speaker 1: Well, even if it's crappy it's possible with a you know, a two-dimensional grid based game.
Speaker 0: but meanwhile I remember like doom like I know the inside and out of doom and all the line deaths and side deaths and pegging textures to things and all that crap.
Speaker 0: But when quake one came out, I was like man.
Speaker 0: I'm really into this level making modding community for doom.
Speaker 0: I should get on board with quake and That lasted about an hour.
Speaker 1: I've had the half-life.
Speaker 1: What was it?
Speaker 1: I forget with the thing hammer tool, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah war hammer I don't know what remember they had some tool and the icon was a hammer and I basically I succeeded in making a map That was a big box room and for natural selection - same thing I made a map that was a room.
Speaker 1: that was a big box like a hallway sticking out of it.
Speaker 0: But a game like Mario is so perfect because the only people are gonna mess around with that level editor are people who already know how Mario works and Mario has a very simple set of User interfaces and things like mushrooms pop out.
Speaker 0: We know how mushrooms work.
Speaker 0: We know pipes working out piranha plants work.
Speaker 0: None of those things need to be configurable.
Speaker 0: You just are.
Speaker 0: it's almost like making a diorama and then playing around in the diorama And I can do stuff that other Mario games never dared to do.
Speaker 1: for example a hole so big.
Speaker 1: you can't jump over it But there are hidden blocks above the hole, but you can't step on them because they haven't been hit yet.
Speaker 1: So the only way to get across is to get the turtle shell Kick it over cross the hole so that it hits one of those blocks Making the coin come out making the block appear.
Speaker 1: then the shell bounces back at you.
Speaker 1: You better dodge that shit.
Speaker 1: and now you have created us a foothold By which to get over now.
Speaker 1: granted a lot of people have made things like that sure But that you know, it's just like an example of something that Nintendo would know like.
Speaker 0: look at this video.
Speaker 0: Look at this stack of piranha plants just hanging out here.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's a nice map.
Speaker 1: See that's Nintendo's basically saying.
Speaker 1: look Here's things that you could do with this editor that we have never dared to do.
Speaker 0: all it took for Nintendo to do This was have many years of history of fans doing it on their own.
Speaker 0: Yep But anyone can make a Mario map and they the level editor actually looks super good like it.
Speaker 1: Is this a Wii U thing or 3ds thing?
Speaker 0: Wii U looks like.
Speaker 1: Why can't it be a 3ds thing?
Speaker 1: There's no reason.
Speaker 0: There's no reason except they need you to buy Wii U.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: we're gonna buy like.
Speaker 0: look at this.
Speaker 0: They.
Speaker 0: they show you right up that you can edit the levels while you're playing them.
Speaker 0: So poke around in the level like test something change something while you're in the level and then keep playing it and the interface Not only looks exactly like Mario Paint, but it has the same icons as Mario Paint.
Speaker 0: It's got a Mario Paint theme going on.
Speaker 1: Can I put can I put a swan out in the map it though?
Speaker 0: Oh my god If only if only If only it had the Mario Paint music editor in it and you can put the music you made in the Mario Paint music editor in the Mario level.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of stuff that Nintendo never does but I would like them to do Even though again, no additional sales though.
Speaker 0: I might buy a Wii U if they did all that.
Speaker 0: I'm worried about how they're gonna Handle this on the community side.
Speaker 0: How easy will it actually be for me to share levels with people?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like can I just put a level on the internet?
Speaker 0: I think not.
Speaker 1: but here's the thing even if this is perfect in every way, right and I bought a Wii U And I got it.
Speaker 1: how much of my life would I devote to this really?
Speaker 0: Ah, well, that's the thing making a man.
Speaker 1: We already I know.
Speaker 1: that's the reason I talked about like, you know, yeah, I doesn't have time for this shit anymore Even if it's really good It's like.
Speaker 1: am I gonna give up some other?
Speaker 1: Hobby that I have to become to get into the Mario map editing community and make that my thing?
Speaker 0: Well, there are two.
Speaker 1: Then it's not worth it.
Speaker 0: two ways to be involved in a thing like that.
Speaker 0: The first way is if you're going to make levels for other people like and you had to have a twitch stream where I'm streaming Myself making the levels.
Speaker 0: but what like?
Speaker 0: I could have fun making levels for games like this and Making them because I know that my friends will play them like hey everybody.
Speaker 0: I made a new level play it I don't have.
Speaker 1: who do we?
Speaker 1: how many people do we know are gonna play and stick with the Mario level making?
Speaker 1: You know, we have a core of about ten people I think tops who would do and all of them are gonna do it and go all in on Mario Matt making and we're gonna Talk about Mario making all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Mario couldn't get to the castle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was a wall beyond the flag.
Speaker 0: Yep, so making it for your friends like having a local community where you and your friends occasionally make maps and fuck around with them Like you whip out the crazy map you made when people sure if we already had we use I'll be.
Speaker 1: you know I'd be perfectly willing to buy this game and do that, but it's not something to buy away you from.
Speaker 0: non It's definitely not something to buy away you for.
Speaker 0: But the other way 3ds's.
Speaker 1: it was on 3ds.
Speaker 1: I could see it happening.
Speaker 0: The other way to get into it is like you were saying if you're gonna double down on trying to make these for a wider audience like you're making them to flex your Fundamental game design skills.
Speaker 0: You're in the game industry.
Speaker 0: You're practicing like basic game design.
Speaker 0: those are the two reasons to have and use this and Only one of those warrants buying a Wii U.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I also think the editing tools are really the most useful For games that have some sort of competitive community right like I talked about the Starcraft map editor They make like the maps of Starcraft comes with are not good for Starcraft tournaments.
Speaker 0: No, they're not.
Speaker 1: they make the maps that are for the Starcraft tournaments.
Speaker 1: They didn't have that map editor.
Speaker 1: They wouldn't really be able to have you know fairly competitive maps that are also interesting and it would be kind of lame And they probably wouldn't competitive.
Speaker 1: Starcraft wouldn't be where it is today without that map editor.
Speaker 1: So, you know pretty much any competitive game wouldn't be where any video game really wouldn't make it without some sort of editing capabilities Right to sort of.
Speaker 1: you know craft the game, you know to fix problems with the rules that are unfair You know.
Speaker 1: yet Even every game always has that tournament mod of some kind that does the things that the base game does not do to make it Tournament viable right?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So it's like you don't really see Mario tournaments.
Speaker 1: You see Mario speedruns, but maybe with the Mario map editor that could open the door to real competitive Mario.
Speaker 0: in fact imagine this imagine at a place like magfest get some of those speedrun people and have a tournament where a Bunch of people at magfest ahead of time made maps that no one has ever seen before and they have a one-time Race on those maps.
Speaker 1: live with no prep Yeah, but all the people who basically had to be blindfolded and you unblindfold them one at a time as they play Yep, or you know, what I would do is just make it simultaneous.
Speaker 0: Oh One two three go.
Speaker 0: there's ten people with ten projectors Simultaneously running the same special map.
Speaker 1: go.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah ten projectors you do that.
Speaker 0: You could make that happen at a con like Paxer magfest.
Speaker 0: trivially Not trivially.
Speaker 1: ten projectors a lot to have in one place at one time where everyone can see them all.
Speaker 0: There's spaces for it.
Speaker 0: I sort of have to have everyone playing on a TV and then four projectors because you're not how many of those people in that Community who are good enough to even compete on that level.
Speaker 0: You're gonna get at the same time at any convention.
Speaker 0: I mean imagine if it was like you and me and a bunch of people we know in a tournament like that Like one of us would beat it like minutes before everybody else.
Speaker 0: probably It would be the worst.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's it's weird though that like you think a lot of the games that had editors Alright or have them now are some of like the top games of all time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well because let editors let a competitive game be interesting from multiple perspectives Effectively indefinitely unless the game is so simple that game literally explored every interesting thing You could do.
Speaker 1: games that have no capability to be edited or modded in any way are Much more likely to disappear or you know and are not remembered and are not as.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, no one remembers games like the Legend of Zelda.
Speaker 1: They're less likely to be remembered especially their multiplayer of some kind.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right like and you know, what games do you know that have an editor just sort of disappeared?
Speaker 1: No one cares.
Speaker 0: Well, a lot of single-player games have editors within themselves for like these kind of ghetto one-off half-assed Multiplayer competitive modes, but those don't really count.
Speaker 1: you're talking about something that really, you know, something significant.
Speaker 1: Right, like you can make a completely custom map.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean don't.
Speaker 0: who plays sieve - these days People play sieve though.
Speaker 0: Did you play sieve?
Speaker 0: Yeah, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and my comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: Yo, the beach is strong with the night.
Speaker 0: it long too strong.
Speaker 0: yo the beach is strong with a night.