Speaker 1: It's Monday August 11th 2014.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: IT Disasters will be done this show.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: we're about to find out.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: ah It was a good weekend had a good barbecue some hanging out.
Speaker 1: It was we.
Speaker 1: it's always weird to me though that it's that I'm not at Otacon despite having been so many years Since we last went to one like.
Speaker 1: but then again I think about it.
Speaker 1: most of the people I know who used to go with me don't go anymore.
Speaker 1: They either go to PAX or magfest.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like I enjoyed every Otacon I went to and I'm sure I would enjoy going to it even now Despite it still has some major flaws.
Speaker 0: well one one major flaw as more than one major flaw, but - it's in Baltimore.
Speaker 0: It has a lot of good.
Speaker 0: It has many many good points as well But when I look at like the big picture of like my year, it's like man my summer just fucked if I go to.
Speaker 1: Well true because this is like our one break between convention season and convention season.
Speaker 1: yeah In fact we pretty much every year like we used to be like Otacon was the end of the summer because we go to this Thing.
Speaker 1: and then we'd all road trip to like Wildwood, New Jersey and have this crazy week of doing fucking nothing on the beach.
Speaker 1: And now our year is our summer ends by flying to Seattle for like a week and going to PAX.
Speaker 0: Yep, that was a good upgrade.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll take it.
Speaker 1: Seattle's not as warm as I would like.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not really beach weather out there.
Speaker 1: It's only like Tops.
Speaker 0: oh no.
Speaker 1: Yeah got to go to the beach feeling Beach.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it's Monday news day tech day tech news.
Speaker 0: all right, so this is a news.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure what to make of it, but it's on the verge.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's.
Speaker 0: it says the headline is really curious.
Speaker 1: what you're about to talk about.
Speaker 0: Headline is scientists made a laser that can detect explosives from half a mile away.
Speaker 1: That's culture type stuff right there, right?
Speaker 0: So it says imagine a plane that can fly over large areas of land while identifying hidden stockpiles of drugs or explosives.
Speaker 0: They say there's a remote with stockpiles.
Speaker 1: so not like an explosion.
Speaker 0: No it can detect material.
Speaker 0: so apparently it's using something called Raymond scattering which is where light goes through something and the light Vibrate.
Speaker 1: Raymond like the name.
Speaker 0: no Raymond r.a.m.
Speaker 0: An ramen Like ramen, but you take out the E and replace it with an a and it's not noodles anymore.
Speaker 1: Alright, alright, so basically some stuff.
Speaker 0: you shoot a laser through something and the light hey look.
Speaker 1: What's on this page?
Speaker 1: Feynman diagram.
Speaker 0: right the light will scatter Based upon the material it hits and it'll scatter uniquely and you can identify molecules Based on this and you can make I guess in theory or perhaps in reality.
Speaker 0: They've made a device where you shoot a laser over an area in a burst of some kind and Over a kilometer away you can tell if certain you know Molecules are present.
Speaker 0: so they can be like oh yeah, there's um this TNT over there for sure somewhere in that area that we shot this laser this TNT 100% and It's like whoa.
Speaker 0: is this for reals or not for reals?
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know anything about this either.
Speaker 0: So let's discuss what if it was for reals if it's for real.
Speaker 1: That's really awesome.
Speaker 0: But what are the implications?
Speaker 1: oh you want over the implications for scientists and also Terrorists.
Speaker 1: well and normal people it allows Interesting at a distance analysis of things.
Speaker 0: right, but you could go for example To the airport and there won't be drug-sniffing dogs.
Speaker 0: They'll just go BAM with a laser and be like well this heroin in your bag.
Speaker 0: We know it.
Speaker 1: I would be a hundred percent okay with that if they use Technology to have actual security as opposed to security cop drives down the house.
Speaker 0: BAM this THC in that house.
Speaker 1: Well you know what my I. I'm gonna take a meta argument there.
Speaker 1: I'm of the mind
Speaker 0: cocaine in that house
Speaker 1: that if a society is going to have a law against anything That society
Speaker 0: not any search warrant whatsoever just driving down the street shooting lasers at your house
Speaker 1: that society Has to be comfortable with the idea that it would be theoretically possible to enforce that law.
Speaker 1: If you're not if you have a law that you would you that you realize would cause societal issues Or you wouldn't be happy if that law were able to be or could theoretically be or was Absolutely a hundred percent enforced by magic then that law should not exist.
Speaker 0: They're just lasers right.
Speaker 0: see it I guess it's safe to shoot a person with them.
Speaker 0: so as a result so I shoot rim.
Speaker 0: rim You said you're a vegetarian, but looks like you ate steak for dinner.
Speaker 1: Well we can already do that memetically.
Speaker 1: I mean there are already a lot of algorithms that can detect to a reasonably high degree gender identity and Orientation and political beliefs and all sorts of laser at rim.
Speaker 0: you just room.
Speaker 0: you go to apply for any of conversation.
Speaker 0: You go to apply for a new job.
Speaker 0: They shoot me with a laser.
Speaker 0: Why is your stomach full of semen rim?
Speaker 1: That's gattaca.
Speaker 1: Are you okay with gattaca?
Speaker 0: I'm just saying yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm saying that these Technologies if and when they do exist cannot be avoided and thus society has to adapt to them and not the other way around Mmm, so as a result The first most important application I could see is obviously the sort of military Application.
Speaker 0: I think the most basic application is you're a scientist in a science lab you have a little laser gun.
Speaker 0: you go pew like Oh, I have two white powders here, which one is wedge.
Speaker 1: But imagine a world where I walk into the airport and instead of the fake bullshit body scanners There's a real body scanner, and I walk through it and it detects if I have anything I'm not supposed to have and that's it.
Speaker 1: and as a result.
Speaker 1: I don't have to take my shoes off.
Speaker 1: That is the human dream one day.
Speaker 1: This is fascinating stuff, I mean actually there's a related new.
Speaker 1: It's not really news, but and I'm not gonna try to find the article right now, but a guy talked about a DIY thing he was working on.
Speaker 1: but basically you know the old spy thing where you point a laser at a window and You can record you can hear like the sound in that room by the vibrations in the window like that's real.
Speaker 1: that works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can make those devices Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so you know that other thing of the indirect photography where the very fast cameras you can take photos of Areas that might be around corners based on reflections and things mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so by combining those two technologies You could record sounds at a distance Without there being like a window to look at.
Speaker 1: Basically by doing high-speed video and looking at different sorts of anomalies like a fluttering piece of paper inside of a room somewhere that you can't hit directly with a laser if you can just get photos of it in any capacity.
Speaker 1: and High and high enough speed photos high enough resolution photos you can reconstruct the soundscape of the room Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so that kind of technology is pretty much the same ramifications of the technology we're talking about here and Society already has a way to deal with those things.
Speaker 1: I can as a police officer I can spy on people theoretically.
Speaker 1: You know tits just dejour dip.
Speaker 1: well not to George de facto as much as I want.
Speaker 1: There's no physical thing stopping me from doing that.
Speaker 1: But if I arrest someone and the judge says hey, how did you get this evidence?
Speaker 1: Then the guy could get off.
Speaker 1: and that's probably the best possible compromise with technology like this because you can't physically stop it from being used.
Speaker 1: There's just no way.
Speaker 1: in fact one of the culture books actually talks about that matter talks about that But there's no.
Speaker 0: there's no crime in the culture because the things a crime.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so what about other societies like primitive societies right?
Speaker 0: Just absorb them into the culture.
Speaker 1: Okay, you live in our society mm-hmm, and the cultures out there Yeah, so a higher level society might have a technology that has undetectable nanobots that diffuse throughout our entire planet and record Literally everything that ever happened.
Speaker 0: is a society like the culture exists even if we're not a member of that society?
Speaker 0: Our society effectively has the same laws of the culture.
Speaker 1: Yeah in a sense.
Speaker 1: But so what do you do like?
Speaker 1: what do you do if a technology exists in society like this?
Speaker 0: It's the same reason like so for example in to bring it to reality right?
Speaker 0: Oh copyright's a law in the u.s Yeah, but I can just go to like almost any other country, and it doesn't matter at all.
Speaker 0: So I don't have to obey it here either except then you have the the physicality of.
Speaker 1: well I'm physically in the u.s.. Right now.
Speaker 0: I'll be alright For now if there was no place to go, but if it's like the culture is just like.
Speaker 0: yeah, murdering people's.
Speaker 0: okay I can murder people.
Speaker 0: go the culture.
Speaker 1: But I guess it just comes down to when there's technology that you cannot defend against.
Speaker 1: like there's nothing you can do about it like a Laser that can tell whether or not you're a vegetarian.
Speaker 0: I can defend against it.
Speaker 1: Mirror you're gonna coat your entire body in a mirror.
Speaker 0: I'll be Miriam.
Speaker 0: It'll be so awesome.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: It's funny That's how armor works in the culture books.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you basically mirror the lasers off of you.
Speaker 0: All the ships just covered in mirror.
Speaker 1: well they have fields and one of the fields is like a reflective field.
Speaker 1: But then there's other kinds of weapons.
Speaker 1: Yeah They've got those.
Speaker 1: So Another interesting news kind of them.
Speaker 1: in the opposite side of this yahoo has announced their intention.
Speaker 1: Now yeah, who is it?
Speaker 1: and also ran dead player in the tech space.
Speaker 0: yeah, who's got some products though that aren't garbage liquor The weather apps.
Speaker 0: good Yahoo Games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, who sports?
Speaker 1: yeah Anyway name some more.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Yahoo is completely irrelevant in the email.
Speaker 0: Yeah, who owns tumblr?
Speaker 1: the only people.
Speaker 1: Yahoo is completely irrelevant.
Speaker 1: So Yahoo has a completely non-player Email system.
Speaker 1: there are people a lot of people use it a lot.
Speaker 1: I know in some countries.
Speaker 0: It's number one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that amazing isn't it?
Speaker 0: huge in Japan.
Speaker 1: I think it's huge in not India because India They seem to use like MSA is Microsoft country.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I know some people use Yahoo, but Yahoo I boycotted a long time ago because of some China stuff.
Speaker 1: But all that aside yeah I was announced their intention to allow and not just allow because all male systems effectively allow this But sort of assist in using end-to-end PGP encryption of all email.
Speaker 0: when you say end-to-end Meaning which ends browser to browser.
Speaker 0: So in my browser I type an email.
Speaker 0: yes the breath the JavaScript of the Yahoo web Client uses my local private key uses JavaScript to encrypt the email.
Speaker 0: yeah And it's a Yahoo.
Speaker 1: so it's stored encrypted on Yahoo's serve.
Speaker 0: right gets to Yahoo encrypted It's encrypted by my computer.
Speaker 0: it gets to.
Speaker 0: Then I'm sending an email to someone who's also at Yahoo, and that's it deep right.
Speaker 0: what have I sent an email to someone?
Speaker 0: Add another domain.
Speaker 1: it just sends the encrypted mail I have to have there and then that that person can't read the email.
Speaker 1: well That's the problem with all PGP.
Speaker 1: is that all these sort of trust network encryption mechanisms?
Speaker 1: Require me to have a trusted key of the person I want to talk to mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So the other thing they want to do which will only apply within Yahoo is have automatic key discovery handshaking sure Which exists.
Speaker 1: like you can do that.
Speaker 1: There's PGP key rings and PGP trust networks like you can do that.
Speaker 1: now Nobody, but the nerdiest of the crypto nerds will set that up.
Speaker 1: because yeah pain in the ass I mean even will Wheaton who uses this stuff like if you want to email him to this day He's like yo at least use PGP to sign that shit.
Speaker 1: Even he does not like.
Speaker 1: it's hard to interact with him via the public key Networks of trust because that just you know.
Speaker 1: nerds do that.
Speaker 1: so Yahoo is going to make that easy and automatic for people who are using Yahoo to email Yahoo people and Ideally that means that it'll work.
Speaker 1: if you email non Yahoo people, but you got to do the key exchange yourself.
Speaker 1: This is actually a big deal because no one has done this before.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not.
Speaker 0: what needs to be done to make this really happen is if like Google and Yahoo Team
Speaker 1: up and share
Speaker 0: team up so that it works together Automatically and there's a federated key exchange
Speaker 1: which again
Speaker 0: that just works without people having to do anything except click send email and by default The encryption is all on.
Speaker 0: no, no opt-ins just everything's on all the time.
Speaker 1: Yes This is a huge deal because also what they should do is to do this themselves.
Speaker 0: They should also make it by default out people who aren't Yahoo or Gmail.
Speaker 0: when you send them an email It should send them the encrypted mail by default and then Make them like be like what the hell just happened and you should like go through a hoop to send them a non encrypted one and then people who aren't using Yahoo or Gmail will have to figure out and like suddenly everyone will start developing, you know and Joining in on the club to make all the other males compatible.
Speaker 1: because that that that what you propose is exactly why this is actually Important news.
Speaker 0: It's like oh shit Everyone everyone hot males complaining because all the emails they receive are encrypted and Google's like tough shit.
Speaker 0: It's like suddenly Microsoft has to get on board.
Speaker 1: Otherwise all emails coming from Gmail or You can do this super nice Like you could have a system where it basically sends the person email that says yo This email came from a person.
Speaker 0: everyone Everyone with an exchange server has to suddenly add in all this stuff.
Speaker 1: but no the fact that no one's done this before and that a one of the One of the major players if you don't count Gmail is actually doing this it's a big deal because people might actually start using encryption and It's interesting to see why it's happening.
Speaker 1: Yahoo and Google both they need to have a good story on this stuff for their users because people are pretty mad about at least people who know a Little bit about the internet are mad about the current crypto spying issues, but to by doing this They Themselves do not have access to the email anymore and they can basically any time the governments of the world say hey Hey, hey, they can say not our problem.
Speaker 1: Nothing we can do math Yep.
Speaker 0: So they're basically because they're like always complaining like here's how many letters you get from the government asking for stuff all the time.
Speaker 0: We'll publish this, you know They're clearly mad about having to do all that work and spend all that money and develop systems to handle that Evil with purely self-interested is to give them no profits whatsoever.
Speaker 0: They would rather not do that.
Speaker 0: So it's easier for them to just be go We're just gonna encrypt all the emails.
Speaker 0: then we won't have to answer the government anymore when they ask for emails.
Speaker 1: It'll be us that old situation if Hitler saves a puppy.
Speaker 1: He's still Hitler, but he still did something good.
Speaker 1: You want to trick.
Speaker 1: the Hitler's of the world need to do good things even if they're doing them for the wrong reasons.
Speaker 1: So so as a result if they do this, we don't need to trust Yahoo anymore at all.
Speaker 0: You need to trust that encryption isn't bullshit.
Speaker 1: Well, if it's PGP It's just straight PGP with a key exchange.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have to look at it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, but that's the thing that the idea of encryption is that you don't have to trust the intermediaries.
Speaker 0: You have to trust the code you're running locally and you have which is written by Yahoo and you have to trust that the Endpoint you're sending the data to.
Speaker 1: is it self trustworthy?
Speaker 1: So the person I'm sending the email to I have to trust that they're not gonna just like forward it in ASCII to the NSA?
Speaker 1: Yeah so Google is also doing something interesting.
Speaker 1: This will probably take a lot longer because Google just takes forever to do anything.
Speaker 1: It amazes me that Yahoo is doing this encryption thing first But Google has announced that they intend to start using the fact that a website encrypts itself But with HTTPS as a signal in their algorithmic ranking engine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whenever they do this it's always so vague cuz SEO people right.
Speaker 1: fuck SEO people by the way and it's like do that It's like.
Speaker 0: yeah, this will affect a small percentage of you know searches in a very small way But it will matter and maybe you should you know.
Speaker 0: And basically they just try to say these things all the time to sort of make web developers and people who run websites Basically behave in the way Google wants and behaves.
Speaker 0: the Google basically says we want every website Should always use encryption.
Speaker 0: They're basically Google's like we want everyone to use HTTPS.
Speaker 1: Let's just say this and then everyone will have to yep, but you know what again if Hitler saves a puppy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the one thing that she does is it does make like websites that don't need it and don't have sensitive information.
Speaker 0: Turning on HTTPS eats up a lot of CPU resources makes your site slower You know, it's not a hundred percent just better and it's not turnkey either.
Speaker 0: You have to pay for it.
Speaker 0: SSL cert yeah into the SSL cartel, you know, and it's not you know, a hundred percent good Yeah, they're all there.
Speaker 1: I mean if you've ever tried to set up SSL certificates in like a standard just like I've got Apache running It's actually not that straightforward and you have to keep changing it all the time because you have to set like.
Speaker 0: certain configurations like turn on this cipher and turn off that cipher make this site for a higher priority than that one.
Speaker 0: and It keeps changing all the time as new vulnerabilities and different encryption mechanisms are discovered because it's symmetric encryption I gotta make sure you know about like chaining certificates.
Speaker 1: and yeah CAs are trust.
Speaker 0: It's not like a push-button thing.
Speaker 0: You can just do if you run a website.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, everyone would have done it already.
Speaker 1: So I want to make a meta point.
Speaker 1: It's also not 100% free all the time by Google saying this if Anything it might raise the bar.
Speaker 1: because imagine if one percent of the websites in the world that care about Google So that's already a pretty small percentage decide we should do this.
Speaker 1: the whatever IT guy works there is gonna have to learn a Little bit more than they already know to make that happen or they know it already and just didn't do it.
Speaker 1: I Get the impression that most IT guys don't actually know how to make SSL work and they're gonna go to like TLDP and Apache's documentation and Fumble around for a while pages already get mad hits.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they do.
Speaker 0: they can get mad hits for years about the TLDP is so out of date.
Speaker 1: It's almost a joke.
Speaker 1: Things of the day.
Speaker 1: It was kind of funny that Scott's news Involves Feynman diagrams because my thing of the day is the 60 symbols video.
Speaker 1: That's not so much about chemistry.
Speaker 1: It explains what a Feynman diagram is and how to read it.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: It's 10 minutes long.
Speaker 1: It's really well done and if you ever seen you know those.
Speaker 1: there's like two lines coming in and then a squiggle and then two lines coming out and like E's and Q's and lines all over the place in your physics test book in the in the Chapter that in high school you probably didn't get to.
Speaker 1: This explains what that shit is.
Speaker 1: It's actually really straightforward unless you try to understand what it means.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So check this out, you know, give a god free day.
Speaker 1: I was about to say something that he said once anyway, and then I didn't.
Speaker 1: it's kind of racist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and a lot of things.
Speaker 1: so I'm the pirate from Aladdin.
Speaker 0: No, he's the bird from Aladdin.
Speaker 0: I said the parrot.
Speaker 0: Oh Parrot if I said pirate no, no, it's hard to say words correctly while doing that voice.
Speaker 0: I don't think he's actually.
Speaker 0: is he actually a parrot Iago or is he some kind of other bird?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna look that up.
Speaker 0: All right while you're looking that up.
Speaker 0: So the people from cards against humanity Sent him some money and paid him to record some audio in an episode of some kind of mp3 Whatever.
Speaker 0: It's on SoundCloud.
Speaker 0: Just listen to it.
Speaker 0: That's where my link is sending you.
Speaker 0: They've paid him right - I guess number one advertise cards against humanity and - they made him read in a loud voice the speech from Independence Day.
Speaker 0: Hahaha That's all there.
Speaker 1: He is a red lorry a species of parrot in the.
Speaker 1: so not gonna say that word family.
Speaker 1: Okay sit talk coolie die Sure.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Oh, I could have one of those.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's that there is.
Speaker 0: how could you not listen to this?
Speaker 0: Therefore it's a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of things today today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was a lot of good stuff.
Speaker 1: I got a lot stocked up Met a Book that Scott will probably not we read until it starts snowing is I can't?
Speaker 0: I read it wits another chapter or two.
Speaker 1: Did you meet Levi wits yet?
Speaker 1: No, do you know who?
Speaker 1: Levi wits was?
Speaker 0: a Jew?
Speaker 1: you find a canticle.
Speaker 0: No, isn't the whole book the canticle?
Speaker 1: so you're still in.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of priests one of whom is kind of dumb but also kind of smart As the young guy who found the stuff underground.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who's both dumb and smart.
Speaker 0: and there's an old guy who tried to make him shut up But they gave up shut up.
Speaker 1: Shut up.
Speaker 1: Then there's a bunch of other random priests, okay Okay You haven't so, uh, no no like I don't know nuclear war has happened yet.
Speaker 0: No, okay Maybe in the past but not in the in the.
Speaker 0: you know, part of the book that I read In the moment, we're going to be at the penny arcade expo prime in a few weeks.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, we're doing a panel called how to win every game.
Speaker 1: We'll teach you how to win games like go and Football.
Speaker 1: we're not even joking.
Speaker 0: No, we're not.
Speaker 1: this might be the most well-prepared and greatest lecture that we have ever done.
Speaker 1: We're bringing some technology to assist us in doing this.
Speaker 1: It's on Monday at noon in the sand worm In other related news.
Speaker 0: We have two extra tickets two packs prime.
Speaker 0: I have them in my hands and It is too late for you to get them.
Speaker 0: As soon as I get home I'm gonna go through and find everyone who tweeted appropriately and use random org to select one of them To receive those two tickets in the mail.
Speaker 1: There is no way this episode will be uploaded by the time or before that is announced for free.
Speaker 0: So congratulations to winner that is yet to be named.
Speaker 0: I will direct message you on Twitter and you'll have a certain amount of time with which to message me back with your address.
Speaker 0: If you fail, I will make you very sad and give them to someone else.
Speaker 0: Yes also Person who made an account that only has one follower and made the Twitter account yesterday and the only tweets you have are trying to enter Free packs giveaways with us and other people.
Speaker 0: you're disqualified by complete arbitrary decision by me.
Speaker 1: Yep, if you don't like it sue us.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Come after me, bro Deal with it.
Speaker 0: Also if you win and you sell the tickets on eBay instead of going you will still get them because there's no way for me To know that but you will be on my shit list for all eternity.
Speaker 0: The end.
Speaker 0: You will not like that.
Speaker 0: I will make it unpleasant for you in some way possible.
Speaker 1: Hang out outside your house at night.
Speaker 0: I have your Twitter account and it's probably gonna be a real person on Twitter not a fake one because You know, I'm gonna filter out the bullshit ones like the one I just said.
Speaker 1: Emily and I are also going to be at pegs dev.
Speaker 1: So if any of you are going to be there and you want to hang out We're gonna be in Seattle for like three extra days before packs.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be chillin in New York having a good time.
Speaker 0: Come keep me company because I'll be lonely.
Speaker 1: Yeah All that aside up I booked my tickets so it's on.
Speaker 1: Scott is not coming But I am going to packs Australia in October the first packs.
Speaker 0: I will have missed since 2000.
Speaker 0: I've been to every single pack since the year 2008.
Speaker 1: Yes This is a problem because for that one that includes Australia and the problem is by going to this next packs Australia and then by going to pack south when the third packs Australia comes around.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna feel really shitty if I don't go.
Speaker 1: That's like when you've got a portal in ingress you've held on to for 19 days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least by just going to the one be like, alright, I did it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Cuz your streak is still.
Speaker 1: you've been to the first packs of.
Speaker 1: I didn't go to the first time Since you started going to pack.
Speaker 0: I didn't go to the first packs prime.
Speaker 0: I should I said since my greatest regret in life I didn't go to every packs and I could have if I would have sacrificed everything else in my life.
Speaker 1: You know, our lives are pretty good considering that literally are too big.
Speaker 0: What did I miss at packs four five six and seven?
Speaker 0: there were four packs is there?
Speaker 1: yeah, what happened?
Speaker 1: Do you regret not going to neck for a Wamba con?
Speaker 1: No I wonder how many people listening now even know what that is.
Speaker 1: Some people know but there are people who go to packs and don't know what penny arcade is.
Speaker 1: Sure So all that aside IT and technology disasters because there was a high-profile Technology disaster this past weekend.
Speaker 0: Well, was it so?
Speaker 1: Otakon convention we were talking about?
Speaker 0: this is not high-profile.
Speaker 1: It's high-profile because this is an example of an IT fuck-up that was trivially avoided.
Speaker 1: had people known better It was still not high-profile.
Speaker 1: Well by high-profile, what do you mean by high-profile?
Speaker 0: Amazon's down for a long time people can't buy anything That wouldn't be high-profile.
Speaker 1: That would be Mad Max.
Speaker 0: Amazon's ordering system got screwed up.
Speaker 0: everyone received the wrong package like millions of people thousands.
Speaker 1: That would just be hilarious.
Speaker 1: that keep whatever they mailed me and then I demand that they send me whatever I ordered.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because there's laws around all Google searches returned wrong results for a day.
Speaker 1: I'd use Bing for that day.
Speaker 1: So Otakon an anime convention that we joined the staff at one point and we've been basically since we went to packs Prime.
Speaker 1: oh wait We have told them every year they should mail the badges because handing out 30,000 physical badges the Thursday before convention This is stupid like that stupid beyond stupid.
Speaker 1: So we're going to skip The.
Speaker 1: the real solution to this problem, which was mail the badges.
Speaker 1: Jesus Christ sound of it.
Speaker 0: We've said that enough.
Speaker 0: We don't have to say it enough.
Speaker 0: Well, no, it can't be said enough.
Speaker 0: now the fucking badges.
Speaker 1: But that does that a sort of core moral to our lesson right now.
Speaker 1: If you have a technology problem and the problem seems insurmountable You need to examine your first principles.
Speaker 1: You need to decide whether or not your fundamental approach is correct or not.
Speaker 1: If your problem is something like my database can't handle 12 billion queries per second What the fuck is generating 12 billion queries per second?
Speaker 1: Yep, like that's your problem.
Speaker 1: Not the database.
Speaker 1: So Otakon's problem was they're attempting to even do this in the first place.
Speaker 1: Yes, but assuming You know taking that first principle we have to do it physically at the convention.
Speaker 1: pass out 30,000 badges What they did and this is based on just me trying to piece it together from things They've said and other people have said because they haven't given a very good official explanation Something like 10 to 15 thousand of those 30,000 people lined up Thursday night and they had a number of computers Onside.
Speaker 0: and they need those computers because they need to.
Speaker 0: when you go up to the booth and say I am so-and-so Here's my ID proving.
Speaker 0: I'm so and so please give me my badge.
Speaker 0: They use the computer to look up if you are indeed so-and-so how many badges you are have paid for.
Speaker 0: and you know If you even are a person who paid for badges, yep, and there's no way you could look that up by paper.
Speaker 0: That would be the worst.
Speaker 1: So they have a number of those and those computers all have I assume a physical network cable Connecting them to a network on site.
Speaker 1: Yep So what from what I gather what happened was those computers to authenticate whether or not you were the person We're connecting to a database Now that database containing the list of names and numbers of badges of all the people who registered for Otacon.
Speaker 1: that database as far As I can tell was not physically on site, but it was hosted wherever their website is hosted.
Speaker 0: So every time someone tried to get a badge Well, obviously you need to have the database or the website is hosted because you register on the website And then it needs to insert you into that database.
Speaker 0: So it needs to be accessible by the website application for wherever the websites hosted most likely Yep, so logically that is a pretty like it seems but then more right.
Speaker 0: but then when the convention happens You are going to have a you know, your computers at the registration booths.
Speaker 0: Are they going to connect to the internet to attach to query that database?
Speaker 0: Or are you going to make a copy of that database and bring it with you to the convention on a computer?
Speaker 1: so what I think happened what their architecture was these computers connected over the private internal network of Otacon of Otacon of the Convention Center and then out the Internet connection the real internet head.
Speaker 1: Yep to the website and that connection failed, of course.
Speaker 1: now supposedly their backup plan was to switch to the Wi-Fi at the Convention Center which apparently had a separate egress route maybe Which but it also is not going to work.
Speaker 1: But it was super slow and overwhelmed by all the other people connecting to it and also didn't work very well And as a result thousands and thousands of people were unable to pick up their badges that night independent of terrible Mismanagement of the situation.
Speaker 1: like they didn't send anyone to go out and tell people to get out of line They like didn't have.
Speaker 1: they obviously had no plan whatsoever for what to do if the system failed.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So as a technologist then before we did this show I checked to make sure that conventions we work with do not have this vulnerability Because I would have felt really shitty if I said you should do it like X and then a convention where I have some say Didn't do it like X. Why didn't they have a backup plan that involved connecting to a server rather than just giving up?
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean even I of course packs right but not just packs as a whole.
Speaker 0: the packs Tabletop checkout library system, which is a tiny database of just barcodes and a few hundred board games Even that system which is like two laptops and a server.
Speaker 0: They bring the database physically with them to packs on that server.
Speaker 0: There is no internet connection required whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Yes now sure you need the database to be as up-to-date as possible But at the same time you need a local copy of that database.
Speaker 1: because let's say a change was made on the master database Like I don't know an hour into when you're doing registration and then your internet connection goes down.
Speaker 1: You're missing that one change.
Speaker 1: 99% of the people trying to pick up badges could still pick up badges if you had a local replicated copy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I mean it does give people the ability to register for the convention like the day of on the website.
Speaker 0: You can pre-reg BAM right away on the website and you'll be in there, right?
Speaker 0: That's a good thing I guess.
Speaker 0: but is it really that necessary when you can just buy badges on-site?
Speaker 1: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 1: So what they could have done is just a much shorter line the day or two before the database before the convention.
Speaker 1: Just lock the database.
Speaker 0: lock all the tables say registration is closed.
Speaker 1: Yep dump a copy of it to a server and then drive that server to the site and Plug it directly into the local network.
Speaker 0: done.
Speaker 1: That would have solved this problem 100% unless the local network failed.
Speaker 0: so it's very unlikely much more unlikely than the internet failing.
Speaker 0: so
Speaker 1: I would actually because I've done this when I've run events in the past if I were them I would have with me a backup local network meaning a bunch of consumer grade switches one or two professional grade switches a Bunch of Ethernet cables and a bunch and a spool of cable that I could crimp off if I fucking needed to Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I have an even better idea.
Speaker 0: So this database is not really that complicated.
Speaker 0: You don't even need the whole database.
Speaker 0: All you really need is this one table that has names.
Speaker 0: Right, maybe the state to verify it's the right person because you have duplicate names and stuff like right, you know registration number.
Speaker 1: Why not just replicate it to all the individual PC and number number of badges?
Speaker 0: Yeah, just copy that frickin database because it's like SQL lite table on every single one of those computers.
Speaker 0: It's a standalone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, thingy, especially because no Worst case scenario.
Speaker 0: So let's put it on a USB stick.
Speaker 0: Give a fistful USB sticks like here everybody and you just make sure none of them.
Speaker 0: You know, there's a little security risk.
Speaker 0: is someone take so great who?
Speaker 0: someone has a list of names that people went to Otakon?
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not like credit card numbers are on there.
Speaker 1: physical security could be done for email addresses Because obviously if the network fails these computers are not on the network anyway, right but to Physical security gets around.
Speaker 1: the issue like let's because let's say the master database server locally fails But I've got the replicated copy on all the local machines.
Speaker 1: in that case sure, a person could theoretically go to machine one and Then somehow go to machine two and get double their badge allocation, but the way the physical security works Once you walk into that place you go up to a table.
Speaker 1: they take care of you.
Speaker 1: There's no path from a table to another table.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm That's trivially solved by one person watching the line.
Speaker 0: Also, who is going to do that?
Speaker 1: who would know that you had a problem and that that would work?
Speaker 1: How ballsy would it be to try that not knowing that they had a failure?
Speaker 1: Yeah, or even then say the master database goes around down Even if you don't have local replicated copies and all the pcs all those pcs could still be networked to each other.
Speaker 1: I mean the odds of your backup switch going down.
Speaker 1: these pcs are at most a few hundred feet away from each other.
Speaker 1: Like this is not rocket science.
Speaker 1: No, this these kinds of problems are trivially solved by even the most Basic of IT procedure and back.
Speaker 0: Well, the fundamental problem is a problem made by many people who not only run conventions but go to them and not just conventions But pretty much anywhere.
Speaker 0: is that?
Speaker 0: Assuming there is going to be internet somewhere.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I can't tell you how many panelists I can.
Speaker 1: like 11 came up to me a kinetic on in a panic and they're like Yeah The panel staff told me to talk to you.
Speaker 1: I our panel needs internet because we're gonna show YouTube videos and we can't connect to the Wi-Fi.
Speaker 1: and Also, our tablet doesn't have a video output so we can't connect it to the projector.
Speaker 1: It's like really kid you ever been to a convention before?
Speaker 0: it's not just by me conventions, especially but like anywhere you go If you go to another person's office for a meeting to sell them something is you're a salesperson.
Speaker 0: Your entire demo.
Speaker 1: better run on that local laptop.
Speaker 0: You know we cannot assume that that business is going to have Wi-Fi for you to connect to the internet Let alone Wi-Fi that opens weird ports or any.
Speaker 0: if you go to a coffee shop to work You cannot assume the internet there is going to be working and will be fast and reliable.
Speaker 1: You can also not assume that your local wireless tether will work because again like say you go to a convention There's 30,000 people there.
Speaker 1: at least half of them have smartphones.
Speaker 0: If you it's like you can go someplace and assume there's gonna be electricity and water.
Speaker 1: Yes Because if electricity and what basically I said no one's gonna go to that place you can leave Assume that everything short of Mad Max will not be available.
Speaker 1: if the convention center doesn't have water Pools closed like it doesn't matter right but Wi-Fi is gonna go down.
Speaker 1: there's gonna be no Wi-Fi and this applies to your daily life.
Speaker 1: if I travel somewhere and Like we're driving long-distance, and I get like directions on my Google Glass or my phone I At least have a cash local copy of those directions.
Speaker 0: in case internet fails Yeah I'm going to drive anywhere as soon as you drive out of Wi-Fi range of your house you need to be able to get where You're going.
Speaker 0: if there is no internet whatsoever Between the end of your driveway and your destination which also will not have internet
Speaker 1: yup I even if the fucking map if I have to
Speaker 0: the only way you can guarantee that internet in your destination is It's also your beach house where you paid for Wi-Fi and internet, and you know it's work.
Speaker 0: Maybe then it'll be trustworthy.
Speaker 1: Maybe yup, so I can't imagine having a dependency for 30,000 people picking up badges on an internet connection from a convention center in Baltimore.
Speaker 1: So have you ever run into Scott an IT?
Speaker 1: Disaster or an IT mess caused by someone who didn't quite think their architecture through?
Speaker 0: not really because I don't work on a lot Of things that other people fucked up and I've been in one place for a long time.
Speaker 0: When I showed up there was some fuck-ups, but then once I was put in charge I made everything legit, and it's been legit for years with no problems now like the AWS like you finally getting control of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so when I got there basically we were you know there was an existing system We were replacing completely But the replacement was already written by these people and these people were like the design firm And they wrote the back-end also But they had never written a back-end before.
Speaker 0: so their back-end was garbage and the home page made like a thousand queries.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so first job was okay.
Speaker 0: We can't fix their code right now, but make it run.
Speaker 0: so Apparently that the IT guy had to do.
Speaker 0: you know I could.
Speaker 0: I basically just was working on fixing the code and the IT guy Was making it run, but the IT guy was a Windows guy.
Speaker 0: you couldn't set up Linux web servers for shit.
Speaker 0: He even though we gave him instructions and drew diagrams like how to set it up He had like this server with Apache Proxying another server with Apache to serve the static files through like three different like you know things before it actually made And it's like oh my god No Wow
Speaker 1: That's like when you visited
Speaker 0: the home page like images would load halfway And then there'd be black on the bottom half because the proxy like timed out halfway On each request.
Speaker 0: and it's like oh my god.
Speaker 0: What did you do so?
Speaker 0: but yeah eventually I fixed that and then we rewrote like.
Speaker 0: it took a year, so we rewrote all the code to not be garbage and Now everything just works forever.
Speaker 1: I think AWS is a commonplace.
Speaker 1: people run into this especially and servers in general.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I set up the AWS from scratch.
Speaker 0: there wasn't anything bad there to begin with.
Speaker 1: I've had jobs before where I've been you know There's issues and eventually I say something to the effect of look let me log into your AWS And I'll take a look.
Speaker 1: and usually when I see that dashboard, and I see what they do UM play God Why why do you have a hundred instances and a hundred security groups?
Speaker 1: It's like what are you doing?
Speaker 0: They're all the default security group.
Speaker 1: I'll be not even default.
Speaker 1: They're all just like open to everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah size here I Ran into one a while like.
Speaker 1: I guess it's.
Speaker 1: I run into these a lot more often.
Speaker 0: one because I'm IT Instead of you know CS, so I deal like Scott dealing with servers, and I mean if you're a programmer And you go to a lot of different places and you work at places that have existing code you're gonna see disastrous code.
Speaker 0: But if you you know work at a place where there's like just one code base, and it actually got to be good and That you're not gonna see that you know if you're a contractor or something where the people hire you for little you're gonna see a Lot of bad you know for anything.
Speaker 0: Maybe you're.
Speaker 0: it's not just programming.
Speaker 0: What if you're?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: You install a you're an electrician right?
Speaker 0: so You get called out to a house to fix something.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Look at the wiring on.
Speaker 0: this is the horrific.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: But if you wire up a new house, it's gonna be great if you don't suck.
Speaker 1: So my jobs though before like before my current job like there was the time when I was basically like a project manager Like assisting kind of person for a hospital.
Speaker 1: so my job basically became go-around like they give me a folder and the folder would be like here's a project that has failed or stalled or Like we don't know the status of it or like the guy in charge of it died or like something weird.
Speaker 1: And my job would always be Physically go to wherever this project was supposed to have been happening and figure out what the fuck happened to it And what to do to make it happen.
Speaker 0: and every single one of them was hard.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, there's some.
Speaker 1: well some of these things were pretty straightforward like I show up And it's just like oh no one ever actually ordered these servers or the printers aren't hooked up because no one ordered network drops And there's no power in that room.
Speaker 1: but some of them would get down to the point like.
Speaker 1: I think the two most interesting ones is There was the set of like really expensive like $30,000 printers.
Speaker 1: I don't know why this department needed these printers But they needed them.
Speaker 1: and I go to see what's going on and I see like oh, there's network drops There's power outlets there are other printers The power outlets are rated for the appropriate wattage is for these ridiculous printers are there?
Speaker 0: printers are there they have toner.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they have paper.
Speaker 1: That's all fine.
Speaker 1: All right, so they're like, yeah, we tried to plug him in.
Speaker 1: it doesn't work cables.
Speaker 1: So I see the crossover cables, I see these network jacks and the first thing I noticed that they're not labeled Mm-hmm, so don't go anywhere.
Speaker 1: So I Ask around where the server closet is or the wiring closet.
Speaker 1: No one knows because it's like a contract.
Speaker 0: You just start opening every door.
Speaker 1: So I basically eventually get a security guy with a master key and I just start fucking open.
Speaker 1: and all these doors.
Speaker 0: You see scary things behind each one.
Speaker 1: So I found a wiring closet and in that wiring closet was a bunch of switches.
Speaker 1: They were active and a lot of stuff was labeled.
Speaker 1: So I think all right This must be it.
Speaker 1: So I could take my toners and my flukes and I start trying to figure out like where this Jack terminates this closet.
Speaker 1: After about an hour I determined that there is no physical way that Jack terminates in that closet Every single port coming into the room.
Speaker 1: it did not wherever it.
Speaker 1: so to this day I do not know where those terminated in the end.
Speaker 1: I just fucking cut them out Put new jacks in those walls over them with real cable runs that I had running to the proper server closet Never figured out where those other ones went.
Speaker 1: When I tried to chase trace it like through the wall with like a sort of like the induction device robot No, like an induction device where you put a thing up against the wall So I put a toner thing on the cable.
Speaker 0: So it's like basically the cable turns to a giant antenna just broadcasting noise And then you rub a thing up against the wall and it beeps and you're next to it Like one of those stud finders.
Speaker 1: Yeah And then I lost the signal and even like I opened the wall and I still couldn't figure out what the fuck it went.
Speaker 1: We just gave up.
Speaker 0: So those cables are probably still in that wall in that hold on the cables where they attach to something at the other end.
Speaker 1: That well they were in the sense that I wasn't gonna just start yanking at him.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: because what if they unplug something else that's actually being used?
Speaker 1: I mean, this is a hospital like for all I know there might be like an old token bus running like an OR machine.
Speaker 1: Okay, like I can't just fuck around in these places.
Speaker 1: No, the other the other interesting one was more of a project management thing.
Speaker 1: a classroom was supposed to be built.
Speaker 1: I'm supposed to have like 30 computers in it.
Speaker 1: I go to the site and There's a cement building with no interior and no doors and no roof and I go in and I see a server rack with nothing in it in this exposed to the environment area and Nothing else.
Speaker 1: it is an unfinished building.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and all I did was take a picture of it and I wrote my report and my report basically said Classroom wiring not complete because building not complete see appended.
Speaker 1: and then there's a picture.
Speaker 1: And I faxed that back and that was the end of it.
Speaker 1: Okay, I never found out what happened to that.
Speaker 1: No one responded and said, oh there was just nothing.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh See the most recent one I dealt with was kind of interesting.
Speaker 1: Someone asked me why the time wasn't synchronized.
Speaker 1: That's your job on these three sir.
Speaker 0: That's your jam.
Speaker 0: Yeah So I mean if it's like if there's a person falling off a building Superman comes.
Speaker 0: if the clock isn't correct rim just comes.
Speaker 0: You can hear it from like 10 miles away.
Speaker 1: So so I go in.
Speaker 0: someone's clock is wrong.
Speaker 1: The first thing I see my two milliseconds is that one of the servers has a cron job That's calling like NTP date and an IP address every five minutes.
Speaker 0: How do people end up with that solution?
Speaker 1: so often that solution is recommended by a lot of really bad websites.
Speaker 1: That's why that solution exists because people don't know what NTP does even came up with.
Speaker 1: that solution is spread around to begin with I don't even know but I even better as I see people who have updated that advice.
Speaker 1: So instead of NTP date, it's it's like NTP d - I think you like the one-off NTP command.
Speaker 0: Why do they even have that command to begin with?
Speaker 0: Oh When would you legitimately use it correctly?
Speaker 0: I might use it with some other options to on boots Mmm-hmm to like with a different if there is no if there is no internal clock on the computer Maybe or maybe if I for the battery in the computer, right?
Speaker 1: I might use that if I'm like starting a virtual machine Mmm, but even then if you do it and you don't understand what you're doing like if someone thinks oh I'll have that run it boot.
Speaker 1: So it'll force the clock to at least be close and then I'll synchronize normally.
Speaker 1: There's a big problem there.
Speaker 1: If you just run NTP like that It'll detect that the clocks too far off and crash without setting the clock just like the demon does.
Speaker 1: So it won't actually do what they think it'll do.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 1: So then the other two servers have an NTP configuration.
Speaker 1: They're synchronizing to each other and they're synchronizing to their local like fake time device.
Speaker 1: so they're basically synchronizing to their own local clocks and each other and NTP had crashed anyway.
Speaker 1: So I set it up and I said, yes, it's fixed now.
Speaker 1: and then Four months later in an email and the email asked me and I quote Why are these three?
Speaker 1: Why do these three servers have different NTP D configurations?
Speaker 1: So I'm like what I think I vaguely remember these servers.
Speaker 1: So I go in and sure enough.
Speaker 1: They're the servers I set up.
Speaker 1: they have they're perfectly synchronized everything's perfect everything is wonderful and The quite that.
Speaker 1: basically the people just didn't really understand NTP and they wanted to know why the servers didn't have identical NTP comps.
Speaker 1: And I was like, well, they're pairing with each other.
Speaker 1: So they have to have each other's IP addresses the end.
Speaker 1: But It seems like those sorts of server things are what I run into the most with service like.
Speaker 1: people learn How to set up a server by reading other people's blogs or by example.
Speaker 1: So if you have a one bad server That's the only server in a company every new hire looks at that server and takes it as their examples.
Speaker 0: Well, that's you know.
Speaker 0: It's a fundamental problem with people learning.
Speaker 0: when they learn a process on how to do something They follow the process without actually understanding what it is that they are doing.
Speaker 0: so any variation from that, right?
Speaker 0: So you have people who for example learn how to use Microsoft Word?
Speaker 0: To do a mail merge and they remember click on this menu then click this then type this then click Okay, and there's a procedure and they remember that procedure Precisely.
Speaker 0: and if Microsoft Word changes or if for some reason that exact procedure doesn't do the thing that they need done.
Speaker 0: They're clueless because they don't actually understand or read or know anything about what they're doing.
Speaker 0: Yeah applies to every kind of education whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Someone learns how to pump gas They go to pump gas lift this lever and they go to a different gas station where the pump isn't exactly the same And now they don't know what the fuck to do because they don't understand the fundamental concept of pumping gas.
Speaker 0: They simply remembered these steps and don't actually think about what the hell it is They're doing or incapable of understanding what it is that they're doing.
Speaker 1: So I think there's a more subtle thing that happens here Because this is another option because that's the option of me when I would show up at a place and I'd see a server and Servers really badly configured rather than looking at and going.
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess that's how I should set up servers.
Speaker 1: I would loudly go who the fuck set this up and what the fuck is wrong with this because
Speaker 0: you can tell that it's bad because you actually understand it as opposed to just assuming that there's this procedure you follow at the end and not know what being able to judge or You know, you don't have a comprehension of the system.
Speaker 1: But I think the places that have bad IT in general will find it very difficult to hire good IT because good IT will either want a lot of money or Good IT will come and then immediately try to redo everything from scratch Because the path to building a new server from scratch as opposed to taking an old server and fixing it
Speaker 0: You're shorter.
Speaker 0: It's much much shorter.
Speaker 1: It's not only shorter, but I think the latter is actually impossible.
Speaker 1: But also like today I found this old server and they were like, yeah, you got to fix the some vulnerabilities.
Speaker 1: I log into it like oh, this is Susie 10.
Speaker 0: All right, so I googled What how old is that?
Speaker 1: So I googled.
Speaker 0: What year is that from?
Speaker 1: So so I go on Google to figure out what the fuck package managers Susie uses.
Speaker 0: just cuz I don't even but I forget the Name of it.
Speaker 1: There's like this Zephyr.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 1: And there's a couple other ones, too.
Speaker 1: So there's like this Yast tool that also does.
Speaker 1: So I type yes, it's like yes starts but it's like not configured and can't connect to the outside like whatever.
Speaker 1: So then I type the name of the other thing is like command not found.
Speaker 1: I'm like, ah So I responded I was like, yeah, there's no way to fix this server.
Speaker 0: build from source, yep Build new server.
Speaker 1: just install like fucking sent OS at this point like I don't even care copy Whatever this server is doing to a new server.
Speaker 1: Yep Don't copy your opt directory or whatever it is that you do stuff in over gonna pull that shit from scratch.
Speaker 1: - guys I can't tell you how many servers I've seen they're messed up because like someone copied like user has been or Like opt just across.
Speaker 1: a lot of people just put everything that matters to their business in opt and their procedure for building a new Server is something like install the server Copy opt from this particular server and then do a whole bunch of chones on it.
Speaker 0: No Nothing.
Speaker 0: any server that I have, you know, how many files are in opt?
Speaker 0: None.
Speaker 0: No files are in opt ever.
Speaker 1: I have a lot of shit in op, but that's cuz.
Speaker 1: I'm always everywhere.
Speaker 1: I've worked.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of like third-party software that's usually Monolithically packaged because people can't deal with dependencies and fucking nobody in the world seems to know how to package software.
Speaker 1: Mmm, like everywhere I've ever worked.
Speaker 1: Hey, can you make that as an RPM?
Speaker 1: The.
Speaker 1: the response to that question ranges from no to what's an RPM?
Speaker 0: But I think I'll make you all the devs Any devs you want.
Speaker 1: I think the biggest thing I've ever run into and I want to give some specific advice to you kids if you work anywhere and The any procedure you ever look at for setting up a server says disable IP tables.
Speaker 1: What and at no point does that procedure say?
Speaker 1: Re-enable IP tables.
Speaker 0: Why would you disable IV tables?
Speaker 0: The majority have no IP tables.
Speaker 1: rules I think.
Speaker 0: leave it on anyway, it doesn't do anything if you just leave it on.
Speaker 0: Ah, but a lot of times there's a rule that they don't understand I'm sure and the thing is there's probably gonna be rules in there.
Speaker 0: It's probably not no rules.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would say that the majority of the servers I have ever touched in my life that were not built by me had IP tables disabled When I logged in what?
Speaker 1: People don't understand.
Speaker 0: the majority of servers.
Speaker 0: I touch have IP tables enabled with no rules, which is bad.
Speaker 1: Well, usually it's like they just never at least have the one rule that blocks all local broadcast traffic and blocks all local Traffic.
Speaker 1: that's not directed at you in case some bullshit happens on your network.
Speaker 1: Mmm Because I've seen so many.
Speaker 1: here's the situation.
Speaker 1: You've got a computer on a switch like all computers should be.
Speaker 1: So as a result, you never see any traffic except traffic that's directed at your computer.
Speaker 1: That's fine, but switches will usually send you also anything that at the low level is broadcast traffic 99% of the time.
Speaker 1: broadcast traffic is malicious or useless.
Speaker 1: Might as well.
Speaker 1: just have a line at the top IP tables.
Speaker 1: It says like drop not log.
Speaker 1: just drop that shit.
Speaker 1: Just get it out of your hair.
Speaker 1: If you're not doing anything with multicast you just drop multicast too.
Speaker 1: because why even send that up the stack?
Speaker 0: Why don't you write a little tutorial on that?
Speaker 1: Mmm, there's a lot of tutorials out there that tell this advice.
Speaker 1: I don't need to write a better one But do people like?
Speaker 1: people will install stuff and then it doesn't work And then the first thing they do is disable IP tables because they assume that it's blocking something They just like.
Speaker 0: why don't you just open the one thing that's being blocked?
Speaker 1: Why don't you just look at far log IP tables and see if that's actually what the problem is a good idea I think a lot of people.
Speaker 1: You don't want to know what the problem is.
Speaker 1: They disable IP tables because that's like part of their standard troubleshooting procedure.
Speaker 0: How did they get that?
Speaker 0: I've never had that as part of my procedure ever.
Speaker 1: not because you're smart because once in their life Something was blocked by IP tables.
Speaker 1: It was fixed by blocking IP tables.
Speaker 1: So they added to their script of reboot the computer disable se Linux disable IP tables.
Speaker 0: Important things granted.
Speaker 1: You should disable se Linux.
Speaker 1: I've never used it effectively.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean se Linux is just as a professional.
Speaker 1: Have you ever had a production environment running a configured se Linux in a capacity where it did something you could say specific?
Speaker 1: That it did.
Speaker 1: Yes, that's my point.
Speaker 0: But if I was in a serious thing where security mattered a ton Yeah, like the financial world.
Speaker 1: I don't think anyone in the financial world has ever enabled se Linux on purpose.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's just it's on by default in certain distributions.
Speaker 1: Yes, and the first thing they do is disable it.
Speaker 0: No The first thing you do is basically as you're setting up or they set it to like permissive mode.
Speaker 0: Well, no as you said what happens usually nowadays is as you're setting up the machine.
Speaker 0: if it's a distribution with se Linux by default You're gonna bump into it where it's gonna stop you from doing things and you're saying you have to be smart and you have to Know oh is the thing that I'm doing actually the right thing to do?
Speaker 0: I've been doing something wrong my whole life and you google it and make sure the thing you're doing is Indeed the thing you're supposed to be doing and then you make a specific exception.
Speaker 0: you say, okay, I see Linux I'm gonna do this thing.
Speaker 0: Let me do this.
Speaker 0: I'm root I swear to God.
Speaker 0: and then it lets you do one thing and it continues to do all its other protections that you don't even Know about.
Speaker 1: yep So it's funny.
Speaker 1: you bring that up because that's the.
Speaker 1: that's the way smart or at least competent IT people should do their job.
Speaker 1: If you're gonna break a rule, you should understand why you're breaking it.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing in music theory.
Speaker 1: So if a Program is blocked because the IP tables is blocking a port I look in the log first to see if that's the problem and if it is then I make an exception for that problem.
Speaker 1: I don't just assume that IP tables will get in my way because reasons.
Speaker 1: So with se Linux you want to know why I think most people disable se Linux.
Speaker 0: It stops you from doing anything because they copy Opt from some other fucking computer and the date says the Linux is not gonna let you run that shit.
Speaker 1: Well, even if it will the reason it won't.
Speaker 1: usually that I've seen is because some bit, you know, like a you idea whatever is wrong or because the time that those files was created ends up being in a time in the future because NTP was also not set up right.
Speaker 0: they can't.
Speaker 0: just you can just wait ten minutes and then suddenly it'll work.
Speaker 1: so the problem is that usually that time in the future is some like made-up number or the time is.
Speaker 0: That's the problem.
Speaker 1: so the the perfect storm of NTP is set up wrong IP tables is set up wrong possibly causing NTP to not work and Some directory like opt or s bin was stupidly copied from another server.
Speaker 1: That is the perfect storm of se Linux just giving you errors You don't understand.
Speaker 0: if you had just used like our sync with like - M time or something I forget the flag you would have the right times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I want to point out Scott I don't really.
Speaker 1: you don't remember.
Speaker 1: you'd have to look up like the exact options in our.
Speaker 0: I know how to type man our sync.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why I love one of my developers.
Speaker 1: the other day.
Speaker 0: We were looking up some stuff and And also I wouldn't I would not only would I not be copying up from one computer to the other but if I was I'd be using our saying.
Speaker 1: we see a file format.
Speaker 1: We're like what the fuck is this and the developers like he.
Speaker 1: I am just like.
Speaker 1: here's the command that I use to generate that And it's like t shark.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just remembers that command copies and paste.
Speaker 0: it has no idea what it does.
Speaker 1: This isn't that problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we look at the command and Like I used I do packet capture a lot But every time I do I type man t shark.
Speaker 1: cuz I don't fucking remember all those filter details.
Speaker 1: No one does unless your job is just that.
Speaker 1: so I we both look at this command.
Speaker 1: Another one of us says anything and he just types man t shark.
Speaker 1: Yep, and I gave him the silent bro fist from behind Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So what's the moral of this?
Speaker 1: I guess don't you learn from the mistakes of others Monday.
Speaker 0: show ideas?
Speaker 0: We need more of them.
Speaker 1: Yes learn from the mistakes of others.
Speaker 1: Think about what you're doing.
Speaker 0: If you're if you're copying pasting commands Just typing them in doing it wrong.
Speaker 0: If you don't understand every single thing that you are doing fully 100% you have failed even if in the end it works.
Speaker 0: you fucked up.
Speaker 1: when I installed That fucking Linux from source gen 2 back when we were at our IT I understood about 40 or 50 percent of what I was copy pasting to bootstrap that thing.
Speaker 1: But also kind of an aside if you're setting up a system of any kind writing code anything Think about the things that could go wrong even if you don't do anything about them.
Speaker 1: if Something if you like deploy a system and then like a week later something goes wrong And you didn't at least anticipate the possibility of that going wrong.
Speaker 1: You're a failure that You've got to think like.
Speaker 1: think like the most horrible pessimists in the world like it like the Otacon example.
Speaker 1: If I were in charge of that apartment, I'd be I'd be thinking so what if the internet goes down?
Speaker 1: What are we gonna do?
Speaker 1: fine?
Speaker 1: What if the power goes out?
Speaker 1: What are we gonna do?
Speaker 1: Fine and the answers to some of those questions might be we shut the fuck down and don't give out badges or we break out the paper copies.
Speaker 1: the fact is even if you don't have a Contingency plan that actually solves the problem of the ridiculous failure you have to at least have a plan.
Speaker 1: The plan might be give up and go home.
Speaker 0: It might be it's like oh, we actually have to tell these people Don't wait in line anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like a you know in the fit like some crazy Financial thing like you might have a plan.
Speaker 1: like even when I worked in like a broker-dealer We had plans that said things like if the trading system cannot be brought up within X minutes after whatever outage like multiple site failure The business the continuity plan after that was a business plan.
Speaker 1: That was like call our customers and tell them we're down Update our website to tell people we're down.
Speaker 1: Disconnect all of their fixed sessions because we're down.
Speaker 1: It's okay to have a plan that says we're fucked.
Speaker 1: This is what we do.
Speaker 0: once we're fucked you can't just do nothing.
Speaker 0: Yes Or maybe the you know, maybe do nothing's the right answer But at least you know, you need to know why do nothing's the right answer?
Speaker 1: I can imagine conditions he found that says if the backup fails leave the office change your name never show up to work again cash that check.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brand-okay for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: Launching the largest aerial battle in the history of mankind Should have new meaning for all of us.
Speaker 1: today We can be consumed.