Speaker 1: It's Monday, February 10th, 2014.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights Tonight, technology in sports.
Speaker 1: Sports technology.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: I've been just skiing a lot this winter.
Speaker 1: And finally, I have someone else to ski with.
Speaker 1: Emily's been skiing with me and she's gotten to the point to where she can go on the big mountain.
Speaker 1: She has progressed from beginner skier to competent skier.
Speaker 0: Alright, next step.
Speaker 0: Graveyard.
Speaker 1: I think it means she can go in the-- Perhaps hospital.
Speaker 1: So last time we went skiing, actually, she took-- I got her a private lesson.
Speaker 1: And I gotta say, in terms of learning a nuanced physical skill, nothing really beats a private lesson with someone who's an expert at teaching that thing.
Speaker 0: It's so weird, 'cause when I was a kid, I had plenty of lessons in all kinds of things.
Speaker 1: Probably from people who weren't actually professionals at it.
Speaker 1: There were people who were way better than I was, but the thing is-- Professional instructor.
Speaker 0: The point is, as a kid, it's just like, it didn't matter what the instructor was.
Speaker 0: I didn't fucking pay attention and follow instructions properly.
Speaker 0: But now that I'm an adult, it's like, I feel like, aha, if someone tells me what to do, I can do exactly what they tell me to do.
Speaker 1: See, maybe you were just dumb, 'cause when I was a kid and I got, like, swimming lessons, like, I paid a lot of attention to what the instructor was saying and I tried to do it.
Speaker 0: I think I got bored with things like swimming lessons because it's like, I already sort of knew how to swim and they were like,
Speaker 0: "Kick.".
Speaker 0: And I was like, "Yeah, I've been kicking in a pool for like ten
Speaker 0: years.".
Speaker 1: Well, obviously you weren't kicking right if they were telling you to kick.
Speaker 0: All they said was,
Speaker 0: "Kick.".
Speaker 0: And it's like, "Yeah, look at
Speaker 0: me.".
Speaker 1: See, I think there's a very simple issue here.
Speaker 1: There's a fundamental issue.
Speaker 1: If you're a kid and you clearly know more or feel like you know more than an instructor, you won't listen to anything they say and you won't respect them.
Speaker 1: And I think this is complemented by the fact that most people who are paid money to teach kids things outside of a school and oftentimes into school, not actually good at teaching that thing and often not that good at that thing.
Speaker 0: I think another aspect is that when you're a kid, you're not paying that person.
Speaker 0: As an adult, if I get a lesson, I'm paying that person for the lesson.
Speaker 1: I was paying, yeah, college.
Speaker 1: I was paying that professor to teach the class that I skipped.
Speaker 1: I was paying a lot of money for that.
Speaker 1: I would think about how much money that credit hour cost when I walked out of that class.
Speaker 1: The money is not the factor.
Speaker 0: I mean, if you pay for a specific thing, as opposed to just college, right?
Speaker 0: If you had paid for one class, I want to learn this thing.
Speaker 1: But I could break down.
Speaker 1: I was paying for that one class.
Speaker 1: I could have taken a different class.
Speaker 1: In fact, I was paying the same no matter how many credit hours I took over 12.
Speaker 1: So if I didn't take that extra four credit hours, I was just pissing away money.
Speaker 1: But yeah, instructors, what I've also noticed is that the group lessons for things like this, if you go to a place where you're going to learn a skill, like a ski lodge is a great example, because they have usually group lessons, where you go to a group based on your ability and then they teach.
Speaker 1: Other than at the top levels, the lessons are almost garbage, usually, because the other people are just really extra bad or extra not paying attention.
Speaker 0: It's the same feeling you get when you have to play a board game and someone playing the board game is really dumb or slow or doesn't understand the rules.
Speaker 0: It's the same idea when you're in a group lesson and the other people are holding back the whole group.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the moral is get private lessons and get private board game time with people like us.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should do that at a con.
Speaker 0: No, because you're the dumb person who's going to fuck it up.
Speaker 1: Scott, at a con, let's charge people to play games with us.
Speaker 0: So we sit at a table and we say, "If you want to play with us,
Speaker 0: bye-bye.".
Speaker 1: Here's a list of games we know.
Speaker 1: We will play good, fast, skilled games for $80 an hour.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: What if the person who plays sucks?
Speaker 1: Then it's going to take four fucking hours.
Speaker 0: That's going to reduce our income.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this would only work if we... It'd basically be our equivalent of wasting our day at Artist Alley.
Speaker 0: We need to get more games in for more money.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It depends.
Speaker 1: Do you want to make money or do you want to have fun?
Speaker 1: Seems like a lot of people who are Artist Allying it up tend to want to make money rather than have fun.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I digress.
Speaker 1: That was my opening bit.
Speaker 1: Now we can move on to the news bit.
Speaker 0: Just the tiny news because there isn't really much news going on.
Speaker 1: It's fine.
Speaker 1: I got a shit ton of news.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So apparently, if you look at the biggest websites in the world, not in terms of the number of users or the number of visitors or the number of web visits or any shit like that.
Speaker 0: If you look in terms of which company is using the most internet bandwidth, number one, at least in the United States, I don't know if it's U.S.
Speaker 0: or World, but Netflix, 32%.
Speaker 1: I would easily believe that.
Speaker 0: Google, 22%.
Speaker 0: Apple, 4.3.
Speaker 0: And I guess that's including like all the stuff iPhones are doing, right?
Speaker 0: Because they always have to talk to Apple.
Speaker 0: They can't talk directly to who they're talking to.
Speaker 0: Number four, above Facebook, above Hulu, above Valve, above Amazon, above Pandora and Tumblr, right?
Speaker 0: In terms of how much percentage of U.S.
Speaker 0: peak internet traffic produced by companies networks, number four is Twitch.
Speaker 1: Not bad.
Speaker 0: There is that much game streaming now going on.
Speaker 1: There is a big culture of share what you're doing with the three people who care.
Speaker 0: I think it was pushed on by the fact the Xbone and the PS4 can just stream to Twitch, right?
Speaker 0: That helped it out a lot, but it's awesome.
Speaker 0: It's good stuff.
Speaker 1: It's awesome, but at the same time, I find watching these things to be usually awful.
Speaker 0: That's why you got to find the good ones, like Fast Karate Channel.
Speaker 1: Or perhaps Rim and Scott playing Nidhogg, even though apparently that disappeared.
Speaker 1: Thanks, Twitch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Twitch is supposed to... They said we're not automatically archiving your things anymore, but go to your settings and turn this thing on so they auto-archive.
Speaker 0: And I did that, and I guess I just discovered right now they're not auto-archiving?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so sorry guys, you don't get to watch the awesome Nidhogg stream we did.
Speaker 0: Where I won a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: So, Rim couldn't even defeat me even once.
Speaker 0: His swords just got dodged and blocked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in fact, you're so good that we should play live at a convention and show everyone how good you are.
Speaker 0: Screw you, Twitch, for lying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see what's up.
Speaker 1: We'll figure it out.
Speaker 1: So, actually, another meta bit.
Speaker 1: It arrived today.
Speaker 1: I got my titanium lens frames to put my prescription lenses in for Google Glass.
Speaker 0: But there's no lenses in them?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I gotta go to an optician to get lenses in.
Speaker 1: They come with lenses that don't do anything.
Speaker 0: Oh, I could wear those.
Speaker 1: You could, if you want to have the aesthetic of wearing glasses.
Speaker 1: All the pain in the ass of glasses with none of the benefits, then that's your option.
Speaker 1: So, in the news, it was leaked that the New York Police Department is evaluating using Google Glass for its investigative and/or patrol officers.
Speaker 0: How is that gonna help?
Speaker 1: I think it'd help pretty well.
Speaker 1: One, it doesn't replace.
Speaker 1: The thing is, everyone expects this to be used to video everything the cops do.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Glass is terrible at that.
Speaker 1: Stop.
Speaker 0: Everyone thinks Glass can do that.
Speaker 0: They're all morons.
Speaker 1: Well, it could if you hack it together with a fucking battery plugged into it.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have enough storage.
Speaker 1: It has enough storage for an entire day.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: It compresses the video to shit.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying.
Speaker 0: I have investigated.
Speaker 0: You got all the other shit on your glass, too, filling up storage space.
Speaker 1: The only thing taking up any space is pictures.
Speaker 1: That's 99% of the space.
Speaker 1: Pictures and videos.
Speaker 1: Anyway, there is already technology that exists to be a dashcam for a cop.
Speaker 1: That's not what Glass would be good for.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a separate technology, anyway.
Speaker 1: But, basically, all they're doing, they're not saying they're gonna use it.
Speaker 1: What they're doing is they're saying, "We're gonna look at it to see if anything it does now could be useful for law enforcement.
Speaker 1: And simultaneously, we're gonna see if there's anything we could come up with after officers use it and see what it's like.
Speaker 1: if we could write software that would be
Speaker 1: useful.".
Speaker 1: So they're doing exactly what everyone should do when there's technology like this.
Speaker 1: Evaluate it to see if there's use cases that are worth pursuing.
Speaker 0: Why is that in news?
Speaker 0: Someone is evaluating a technology.
Speaker 1: Well, partly because it was leaked.
Speaker 0: It was a secret that they were evaluating a technology.
Speaker 1: And partly because a lot of people seem to be really mad about it.
Speaker 1: They're like, "Now the cops are gonna have video of what I
Speaker 1: do.".
Speaker 1: Yes, I want the cops to have video of everything they do.
Speaker 1: That way, when they beat someone up, there's video of it.
Speaker 1: Cops.
Speaker 1: Bad boys, bad boys.
Speaker 1: Or the cops might look me up and investigate and be like, "Yeah, if I'm getting arrested, I'd like them to be able to easily, on the fly, figure out if I'm armed and dangerous or
Speaker 1: not.".
Speaker 0: Glass cops, glass cops.
Speaker 1: I could come up with a lot of really good things that you could do if you wrote good software for cops to use with glass.
Speaker 1: I don't think that good software will ever be written.
Speaker 0: If there's an emergency, immediately they see an alert on the glass and the map shows up telling them where to go.
Speaker 0: So imagine this.
Speaker 0: Shows them a picture of the suspect and then...
Speaker 1: Yeah, or imagine this.
Speaker 1: Let's say you are driving to the scene.
Speaker 0: A cop's driving around town, a convenience store alarm goes off.
Speaker 0: Immediately, he sees, you know, convenience store robbery, in progress, address, map, and then he sees the live footage from the cameras.
Speaker 0: From the helicopter.
Speaker 0: From the helicopter or the cameras in the convenience store.
Speaker 1: But think about that.
Speaker 1: If you had Glass on showing you the live feed from the IR helicopter while you're walking through the woods chasing a guy, that's some Ghost in the Shell shit right there.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: Or imagine, here's my dream app.
Speaker 1: I'll share my dream app with you.
Speaker 1: I've been thinking a lot about how to make Glass useful.
Speaker 1: Imagine if a cop could be like, "Okay, Glass.
Speaker 1: What are the laws about possession,
Speaker 1: marijuana?".
Speaker 1: And then it just shows the current law right there while he's like, handcuffing the person.
Speaker 0: The cop is like, "Google, is it legal to take pictures of the
Speaker 0: subway?".
Speaker 0: "No.".
Speaker 0: Just like, "Well,
Speaker 0: fuck.".
Speaker 1: Of course, then he'll just get no connection to Google Cloud.
Speaker 0: "Oh, I'm in a train.
Speaker 0: That's a
Speaker 0: problem.".
Speaker 1: But the biggest one is if they finally do the facial recognition.
Speaker 1: Imagine if you're arresting someone, right?
Speaker 1: Or you're talking to someone.
Speaker 1: You pull someone over, you detain a suspicious individual.
Speaker 0: Three warrants, crazy drug dealer, crazy murderer.
Speaker 1: It's the Schmod's computer.
Speaker 0: "Watch out for this
Speaker 0: dude."
Speaker 0: From the Blues Brothers.
Speaker 0: Even if you approach someone who's not illegal or anything like, "Oh, there's a guy walking around town with a
Speaker 0: gun.".
Speaker 0: Just walk past him and it says, "Joe Blow has..." Outstanding warrants.
Speaker 0: "Has permit.
Speaker 0: Is totally cool.
Speaker 0: Ignore this guy.
Speaker 0: Don't even bother
Speaker 0: him.".
Speaker 0: Just say, "Hey, Joe.
Speaker 0: What's going
Speaker 0: on?"
Speaker 0: And keep going.
Speaker 0: Don't even have to stop him and question him.
Speaker 0: Because he's a crazy libertarian.
Speaker 0: He's legally right and you're just going to make a fight with him, so just don't do anything.
Speaker 1: You could do really cool stuff with this technology, but guys, I bring this up because everyone's making this mistake.
Speaker 1: Focus on the screen, not the fucking camera.
Speaker 1: Jesus.
Speaker 1: If you're going to talk about future sci-fi awesome stuff, at least focus on actual cool awesome sci-fi future stuff.
Speaker 1: Wearing a camera that always records everything has been possible for a decade.
Speaker 1: Nothing new is happening there, at least in regards to Google Glass.
Speaker 0: We've said this about a hundred times.
Speaker 1: Also, I think this is cool.
Speaker 1: I want to see if they actually come up with something.
Speaker 0: How about all the things I just said?
Speaker 1: I am 100% convinced that they will not come up with anything interesting and that if they do, they will spend a ton of money to develop software that doesn't work and then it'll be called a failure years later.
Speaker 1: Because that's how government contracts work with that stuff.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: A co-worker pointed this out to me.
Speaker 1: Are you familiar with Yeshivish?
Speaker 0: I know what a Yeshiva is.
Speaker 0: It's a school where the Orthodox Jew kids go.
Speaker 1: Yeshivish is a sort of dialect, or according to Wikipedia, a sociolect of Yiddish and English that's spoken basically in the Yeshivas.
Speaker 0: So it's how Yeshiva kids talk to each other in school.
Speaker 0: Basically, yeah.
Speaker 1: The Yeshiva kids and their dads in the more farther Orthodox communities will speak in this sort of dialect.
Speaker 1: that's kind of like Franglais.
Speaker 1: It's halfway between Yiddish and English.
Speaker 1: And it's an interesting dialect.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of cool stuff you can learn about sociolects.
Speaker 1: I mean, me and Scott and the Front Row Crew effectively have a sociolect around caveman talk and doujing and things.
Speaker 1: So there's a whole sea of Wikipedia that I'm going to point you in the direction of.
Speaker 1: that you might find fascinating.
Speaker 1: But this here is a pretty famous document in Yeshivish.
Speaker 1: It's the Gettysburg Address translated into Yeshivish.
Speaker 1: And it's delightful to read.
Speaker 1: I almost want to read it because it's funny and cool.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, I do not pronounce Yiddish words well at all.
Speaker 1: But it's just, let's see.
Speaker 1: The Gettysburg Address.
Speaker 1: "Barek, a yoival, and a half ago, the mishadim sheld vekthis makam anaya malkas with the
Speaker 1: kapana.".
Speaker 0: That's so bad.
Speaker 1: How do you want it?
Speaker 0: Can you at least try?
Speaker 1: I am trying.
Speaker 0: No, you're not.
Speaker 1: I have a genetic undisposition toward this.
Speaker 1: There's a funny part at the end.
Speaker 1: That Hashim should give the Gansi oilim anaya brana cheris that the nation that shams buy the oilim, buy the oilim, buy the oilim will blodfest ad oilim.
Speaker 1: Because Yiddish is kind of Germanic.
Speaker 1: So, of the people, by the people, for the people basically becomes buy the oilim, buy the oilim, buy the oilim.
Speaker 1: This is funny and you should read it.
Speaker 1: And then learn all about this cool stuff.
Speaker 0: So we're talking about sports technologies.
Speaker 1: Also, Captain, I should send you this and we'll record you reading it.
Speaker 0: Alright, that'll sound right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe it will.
Speaker 0: Speaking of sports technologies, this guy bought a 3D printer.
Speaker 0: Or at least he bought 3D printer parts.
Speaker 0: But he didn't make a 3D printer.
Speaker 1: He made an air hockey robot.
Speaker 0: Can't beat it at air hockey.
Speaker 0: So good.
Speaker 0: Sports technology.
Speaker 0: Air hockey's the best.
Speaker 0: I'm a guy at air hockey.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is pretty great.
Speaker 0: The end.
Speaker 1: I don't think a human could beat this, but at the same time, he was not attempting to get much velocity out of that puck there.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It moves pretty fast.
Speaker 1: One, he was not using a tournament grip.
Speaker 1: He was using that hold the joystick.
Speaker 1: He was using the dick grip instead of the finger grip.
Speaker 0: Let's go get a full photon table, make a big one of these things, and see what happens.
Speaker 1: The thing is, I'm pretty sure...
Speaker 0: You've got really powerful motors to it too, so we can go whoosh whoosh whoosh whoosh whoosh.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure even this project, just built with hardier materials on a real table, no human could beat it.
Speaker 1: At best you could get a draw, I would suspect.
Speaker 0: Well, you came up with your strategy of, instead of detecting where the puck is and moving to block it.
Speaker 0: Just vibrate.
Speaker 0: Just stand it completely in front of the goal and move back and forth ridiculously fast so that there is no time window period in which a puck could get through without being touched and deflected.
Speaker 1: And basically always do that unless I have a clear firing solution and then suddenly strike the puck with such speed that it will just immediately go into the goal and the human can't do anything about it.
Speaker 0: Faster than a human can possibly react to stop it.
Speaker 1: I guess you could hit it hard enough to make it like a bullet so it goes through the player's.
Speaker 0: What if you have two of such robots play against each other?
Speaker 1: I would watch that like an Olympic sport.
Speaker 0: And they're both set to have perfect defense no matter what and also attack as violently as possible whenever possible without sacrificing your ultimate defense strategy.
Speaker 1: You know what that's like, Scott?
Speaker 1: Because I've been reading all these culture books.
Speaker 1: That's like two equiv tech civilizations having a war.
Speaker 1: I'd love to watch it.
Speaker 1: It's like watching the ping pong championships.
Speaker 0: Remember that rock paper scissors robot that would cheat?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: What if we had it play against itself?
Speaker 1: You know, I wondered that.
Speaker 1: I think I even posited that question when we talked about that robot.
Speaker 1: It'd come down to who's the faster processor.
Speaker 0: Metamoments.
Speaker 0: Conventions are actually coming up really soon.
Speaker 0: Did you know Anime Boston was next month?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we gotta get on our fucking panels.
Speaker 0: What is our panels?
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: We're doing a bunch of panels in Anime Boston, guys.
Speaker 0: Uh-oh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think we wrote a new one, though.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, we wrote one.
Speaker 1: It's the one anime that aren't what they seem.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Like, Trigun seems silly, but oh, it's actually about pacifism.
Speaker 0: All right, well, you're taking care of that.
Speaker 1: I'll take care of that one.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: PAX East.
Speaker 1: We got a panel ad.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 1: I don't think it was announced yet.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be there.
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 1: We're enforcing.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be there doing stuff.
Speaker 1: It's PAX East.
Speaker 1: No one we know is going, except fellow enforcers and speakers, because no one we know could get badges.
Speaker 1: That's a shame.
Speaker 1: So, our entire friend group, except for the people who are enforcing, or our guests alongside us, is not going to PAX East, possibly ever again.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's their problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Their loss.
Speaker 1: It's hard to get badges.
Speaker 1: Know what you do about it.
Speaker 1: Uh, we're gonna be at MagFest, but that's a ways from now.
Speaker 0: Kineticon, while it's still a ways off, there is much preparation for it.
Speaker 1: We're already scheduling panels.
Speaker 1: If you want to do a panel, submit it fucking now.
Speaker 1: Time slots are disappearing, kids.
Speaker 0: Other non-convention meta stuff.
Speaker 1: ZenkaiCon we're going to.
Speaker 1: I forget what we're doing at that con.
Speaker 1: Who cares?
Speaker 0: Don't go to that.
Speaker 1: Someone might care.
Speaker 0: Dude.
Speaker 0: Unless you're super desperate.
Speaker 1: If you go to ZenkaiCon, you're a Geek Nights listener, so I want you to go, because we're gonna do all our panels, and the rest of the time, we're gonna go hide in a corner and play German board games.
Speaker 1: So we want listeners to come play German board games with us.
Speaker 0: Hockey at some bar.
Speaker 1: We'll go watch hockey at a bar, but we'll also play German board games.
Speaker 0: Um, not be able to get breakfast because Panera is the only thing.
Speaker 1: You know, if we'd gotten up before like 11am, we probably could have gotten a fake bagel.
Speaker 0: Why would we do that?
Speaker 1: Seriously, I don't think you guys understand how cranky Scott gets if he can't get a bagel and some cream cheese in the morning.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: you don't have bagels?
Speaker 1: The fuck?
Speaker 1: New York?
Speaker 1: I could have gotten a bagel.
Speaker 1: Seriously.
Speaker 1: Jesus.
Speaker 1: Fuck this place.
Speaker 1: Fuck this town.
Speaker 0: Listen, a vampire can't go too far from his coffin.
Speaker 0: A New Yorker coffins like New York.
Speaker 0: You can't go too far away.
Speaker 0: It's bad news.
Speaker 1: Vampires.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, rice.
Speaker 1: How many grains are there?
Speaker 1: The Book Club book is Wool by Hugh Howie.
Speaker 0: Like the shit you take off of lambs and make sweaters out of.
Speaker 1: I know almost nothing about it except that so many people recommended it to me that I either want to read this really good book- And we got a pile of free copies from who the fuck knows where.
Speaker 1: I have at least three copies of this book.
Speaker 0: None of which you have paid or asked for.
Speaker 1: One of them is signed by the author.
Speaker 0: Okay, give me one of them.
Speaker 1: So I gotta find them.
Speaker 0: I might even actually still have one.
Speaker 1: You might.
Speaker 0: I should check before I take another one because I know I'll never be able to give it back.
Speaker 1: Either it's gonna be great or I'm gonna piss all over someone's parade.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: As this happened in the past.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Oh!
Speaker 1: What else we got?
Speaker 1: YouTube.
Speaker 1: We got stuff.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights Presents Utena has resumed.
Speaker 0: We have YouTube channels.
Speaker 0: We have fucking tumbles and twits and face boxes and G pluses and pretty much every possible imaginable thing.
Speaker 0: Go to all those places and do the things at those places on the internet.
Speaker 1: Yes, and link to those things.
Speaker 0: If you're not on the internet, how the hell are you listening to this right now?
Speaker 1: And link to those things on whatever Reddit cave you hide in.
Speaker 1: because I found that I link.
Speaker 1: if I post a new thing about gaming and I go to a gaming subreddit and post a thing, I get down mod like, "Yeah, don't promote your own
Speaker 1: shit.".
Speaker 1: But if someone else who isn't me posts the same thing, it gets upvoted and everyone's like, "Oh, that's
Speaker 1: amazing.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, people have been, a few people have been occasionally posting links to our stuff on Reddit and other places and when they do, we get some traffic.
Speaker 0: So go to all the places on the internet that you go and promote us for free for absolutely no compensation whatsoever and just be a shameless and dirty shill for our benefit.
Speaker 1: One, it'll warm the cockles of your heart by doing that for us.
Speaker 0: And two, you might get some karmas if it gets upvoted, but based on our content, you'll be leeching off of us to get pointless internet smiley points.
Speaker 1: But if you do this and our stuff gets more popular, we'll do more stuff faster.
Speaker 1: We could be done with that.
Speaker 0: It's possible if everyone promotes us enough that we would get so ridiculously popular that someone would pay us to do stuff and we could quit and do stuff all day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, guys, you realize if I- You're holding us back for not promoting us enough, not because we suck.
Speaker 0: If this was my job- Not because our shit's not good enough.
Speaker 0: We'd have an episode- You are not giving us free advertising and social karmas.
Speaker 1: We do an episode of that Utena show like every two days.
Speaker 1: We would make a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: But no, instead- I have to go to work every day.
Speaker 1: You guys can watch PewDiePie or whatever.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So, sports technology.
Speaker 0: There is so much sports technology.
Speaker 1: The conversation Scott and I had was basically, "What do we do this show
Speaker 1: on?".
Speaker 1: I was like, "I don't know.
Speaker 1: What about sports
Speaker 1: technology?".
Speaker 1: Okay, I guess that's our crowd, people.
Speaker 0: I felt like we had done it already, and I know we've talked about some topics in the past, perhaps as newses.
Speaker 0: I feel like we talked about those Olympic super-baiting suits before, at least once.
Speaker 0: We have, but we've always talked about them.
Speaker 0: And we've talked about soccer replay and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: But we always talk about it from the game perspective.
Speaker 1: How does it affect the game, the game theory, the game, the game, the game, the game?
Speaker 0: You're going to talk about that.
Speaker 0: You're going to talk about that, I guarantee, within the next 10 minutes.
Speaker 1: I will, but we're going to focus- You're not even denying.
Speaker 1: We're going to focus more on the tech, because basically, then we stopped chatting, and then we both were like, "Okay, I got a lot to
Speaker 1: say."
Speaker 1: Because I realized pretty immediately that sports are literally made by their limitations in such a fundamental way that a sport that does not have arbitrary limitations on the aids and technologies that can be used becomes a meaningless sport immediately.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, I kind of want to see a sport sometimes where it's like, you can do whatever the hell you want, right?
Speaker 1: It's like- So I murder the team the night before in their bus.
Speaker 1: I mean, like- You got to have a limitation.
Speaker 0: Like, you can use any equipment you want, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like- The batter comes up, just shoots the pitcher, and then runs after he dropped the ball.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know, imagine F1.
Speaker 0: F1 has a ridiculous number of rules about how the car has to be designed.
Speaker 0: Imagine if the rule was, it has to be a car, right?
Speaker 0: Imagine if the rule was- Suddenly, driving no longer matters, and engineering is the only thing that matters.
Speaker 0: And already, it's out of state, even with all the restrictions where engineering matters perhaps more than driving, right?
Speaker 1: Well, engineering definitely matters more than driving, because as skilled as these drivers are, it's the teams that win with their better management and technology.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: I mean, if you look at something like baseball, it's like, okay, baseball, technology matters, I guess, some amount greater than zero, but mostly it's the person, right?
Speaker 1: Why is that the case?
Speaker 0: Because it is so restricted on what technology you can use.
Speaker 0: It's like, you can't do anything to the ball.
Speaker 0: Everyone has to use the same goddamn ball.
Speaker 0: The limitations on bats are extremely strict.
Speaker 1: Yeah, imagine if I could just use an aluminum bat.
Speaker 0: Boom.
Speaker 1: Like, what?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You could just use any bat you wanted, like some ridiculous carbon fiber titanium, who knows what bat, with springs in it, and you could use any ball you wanted, like a tennis ball.
Speaker 1: What if I wear shoes that are just so big that after I hit the ball, I just lean my toe forward and I hit first base?
Speaker 0: Clown shoes?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The end of the shoes are in the dugout, and you just sort of tilt your shoe to the right, and suddenly- I'm on first base.
Speaker 1: I'm on first.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to make it to second.
Speaker 0: It springs in your shoes, so as soon as you hit the ball, you jump and you launch in the air like a trampoline- And just land on first base.
Speaker 0: And then you go boingy, and you land on second base, boingy, third base, boingy, home plate.
Speaker 1: What if I just wear armor with spikes and just charge the guy at first base?
Speaker 1: Well, I guess no, because if he catches it, I'm out no matter what.
Speaker 1: It would only work charging second or third base.
Speaker 0: Sure, but there are other sports where the technology doesn't dominate the physical ability, but it matters.
Speaker 0: Something like golf, right?
Speaker 0: In golf, for me, it doesn't matter what the fuck golf clubs I use, I suck, right?
Speaker 0: I could take Tiger Woods' own golf bag and I'm not going to win shit.
Speaker 0: Tiger Woods is even winning shit with his golf bag lately, right?
Speaker 0: But if you're good enough at golf to where your skill is really high, suddenly the changing clubs can actually make a difference.
Speaker 0: Getting a lighter club or one with a better head or something is going to maybe give you an extra 10 yards on the drive or whatever, and that can make a difference in winning and losing.
Speaker 0: It'll save you a stroke here, a stroke there, right?
Speaker 0: Bowling, it's like changing.
Speaker 0: which ball you're using could matter significantly.
Speaker 0: If you're already good at bowling, changing your ball starts to matter.
Speaker 0: It's not like I can take the champion's bowling ball and win, because human ability matters more, but it's not.
Speaker 0: the technology doesn't matter whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Olympic bathing suits, you already talked about those long ago, right?
Speaker 1: Some sports, every sport is different, so some sports are really restricting the technology to focus on the human competition, but then the human competition becomes almost the technology of training and engineering humans, which is also technology.
Speaker 1: I mean, look at the monsters we breed to compete in highly specialized professional sports.
Speaker 1: Now, we don't breed them in vats yet, but that will happen probably in our lifetime.
Speaker 1: If not in vats, then at least through positive eugenics programs.
Speaker 1: I say positive as opposed to negative, positive meaning encouraging certain breeding patterns as opposed to negative of kill the babies Sparta style.
Speaker 0: I mean, basically, I mean for football, I know a lot of football players like Samoans, I think there's still, I think it was documentary about how they basically breed football players in Samoa.
Speaker 1: Or look at biking, no amount of training, if you get equivalent training, the only determining factors in bicycle races, long distance races are either luck, as in equipment failure.
Speaker 1: or someone hits you or something crazy, or your legs are this slightly longer or your lungs are slightly bigger or you have a freakish amount of red blood cells or you dope or you do steroids.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone talks about Lance Armstrong's cheating, right?
Speaker 0: But think about it, he cheated and won when everyone else also cheated.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like he was the only cheater, right?
Speaker 0: And he won every single goddamn time.
Speaker 0: If no one cheated, he probably also would have won every single time because his body is freakish like that.
Speaker 1: Yep, so the technology of sports is also the technology of training humans.
Speaker 1: I mean, Olympic athletes, the intervals for some of these events have come down to random chance as to who wins.
Speaker 1: It's the start of a lot of these short foot races matter more than any amount of training or skill.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess the training and skill of being able to anticipate and do the start without fouling it.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, Usain Bolt is just freakishly large, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, he's had the same training as everyone else, right?
Speaker 0: But he wins every time.
Speaker 0: Well, he wins almost every time just because genetics are mattered more.
Speaker 1: So what will happen, like technology-wise, we limit these sports from external chemicals and we limit them from technology and equipment outside of the bounds of a very limited set.
Speaker 1: It's sort of a prescriptive designation like in baseball.
Speaker 1: A baseball bat is defined by X and you may not deviate from it by more than Y and Z, but there are no rules about the genetic side of it or scouting people who have freakish qualities.
Speaker 1: that would make them better at the sport fundamentally, but that is also technology of being able to find and train those people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there's also no rules about breeding the people.
Speaker 0: It's just you can't use certain chemicals on your body after you're born, but it didn't say anything about like, hey, let's get, you know, they do it for horses, right?
Speaker 0: They already do it for horses.
Speaker 0: There's no rule against doing it for people, but just people don't, or at least haven't yet.
Speaker 1: You know, I think a lot of people would have ethical concerns about it, but if you wanted to make money, you should probably make a company that finds people who are good at football or have the physical attributes that make them predisposed toward being good at football, and come up with the programs to get them to marry, form couples, have babies, and then train those babies basically their entire lives for a shot at being in major league football.
Speaker 0: No, what they should do is you should basically get them to sign a bunch of papers giving you that, you know, you basically make the baby in a test tube by borrowing genetics from those people.
Speaker 1: I think there's laws against that right now.
Speaker 0: And they sign the baby over to your company.
Speaker 1: It's now, you are now.
Speaker 1: I was trying to come up with a business model that wouldn't immediately get crucified in the media.
Speaker 0: Your company is now the, you know, legal guardian of these babies, and then you raise them in football school, and your company is this football school, and then they, you know, the babies, while they're still, you know, when they make money, you take a percentage of the money they make because you're their agent.
Speaker 1: Now there's also, there's a subtle thing that, it's subtle in some sports, that people seem to forget how goddamn dangerous most sports were even as recently as 40 and 50 years ago.
Speaker 1: Like football is probably more dangerous now, but that's a separate thing.
Speaker 0: Safety in sports is actually relatively recent.
Speaker 0: Like there's been concern for safety perhaps my whole life, you know, even when I was in school playing sports, but most sports, even in the 80s and 90s were ridiculously dangerous.
Speaker 1: Look at old timey car racing.
Speaker 0: When I watched NASCAR in the 90s, people were getting killed, right, in ridiculous crazy crashes.
Speaker 1: What about the ground effects era in F1?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's just, every, they just, you know, they went for winning for the sake of safety.
Speaker 0: Hockey, people in my lifetime played ice hockey with no helmets.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No helmets.
Speaker 1: Not like no face masks, which was later, but that was also true.
Speaker 1: Like a lot, when I saw hockey games, almost no one wore face masks when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like helmets.
Speaker 0: Except the goalie.
Speaker 0: Helmets were added to hockey within my life.
Speaker 1: Face masks were added to goalies not that long ago.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And the old face masks didn't work so well.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: There was a time.
Speaker 0: The Jason style, I dare you to wear that and play hockey.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: You would, if a modern hockey player wore the Jason mask in a modern hockey game.
Speaker 0: And a puck hit him in the face.
Speaker 1: They would spend most of their time dodging pucks rather than trying to stop them.
Speaker 0: Did you know that one of the rules of Olympic hockey that differs from regular NHL hockey is that if the puck hits the goalie in the face mask that you stop play?
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That's, I almost want to say that's BS, but at the same time that's probably better.
Speaker 0: There's an interesting thing that lists all the differences between Olympic hockey and NHL hockey.
Speaker 0: And Olympic hockey is pretty much just better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in almost every way.
Speaker 0: In almost every way.
Speaker 1: Is it still, I remember there was a point where I think it was actually a wider hockey.
Speaker 0: It is wider.
Speaker 0: It's still wider.
Speaker 1: It's bigger, yeah.
Speaker 1: Because I remember during the trap era of hockey, watching games and being so frustrated, then thinking about Olympic hockey and realizing that that kind of fixed that problem.
Speaker 0: Olympic hockey is just bigger ice.
Speaker 1: Wider ice.
Speaker 1: Longer ice would not make for a more interesting game, but wider ice certainly does.
Speaker 0: But yeah, bicycling we talked about a bit already, but the technology in bicycling actually is pretty significant.
Speaker 1: Well, remember the famous story of before modern bikes, I mean you had penny fire things which were just death traps.
Speaker 1: Just bicycling used to have a reputation for being one of the more deadly and ridiculously stupid things a young man could ever do.
Speaker 1: And when the modern bicycle was invented, people scoffed at it.
Speaker 1: And then a woman beat the best bicyclist in the world trivially with a modern bicycle.
Speaker 1: Having gears literally made her the best bicyclist in the entire world.
Speaker 0: But yeah, so they keep developing technology of bikes, but they don't allow all those technologies in say the Tour de France, they have minimum weights and stuff, even though we could make some lighter bike that was like 100% carbon fiber ridiculousness.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well like tennis has that.
Speaker 1: I for a long time used a tennis racket.
Speaker 1: that would not be legal for tournaments.
Speaker 1: Wouldn't be legal in a real competition, but they sold it.
Speaker 0: Was it actually superior?
Speaker 0: Because a lot of times you go to the store, right?
Speaker 1: Yes, it was actually superior.
Speaker 1: It had that weird weave.
Speaker 0: It's like a lot of times you'll go to like the sporting goods store and they'll be like buy this tennis racket and they'll be like look at how much fancy shit it is.
Speaker 0: It's so expensive.
Speaker 0: It must be better.
Speaker 0: And it's like, no, actually it's just a bunch of gimmicky nonsense they're using to trick you into spending a lot more money on a tennis racket.
Speaker 1: So I had a racquetball racket that was just too big to be legal.
Speaker 1: It was just bigger.
Speaker 0: Well, just bigger is just better, right?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's no question about that.
Speaker 1: But then my dad was like, oh, no, no, no, no, no, and then he made me play with like an old school racquetball racket.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the ones that are like that big.
Speaker 1: And I was like, oh, oh.
Speaker 1: Granted, even with my cheating racket, he could still beat me trivially even if he had the shit racket.
Speaker 0: Listen, the older you are, you don't even have to know what racquetball is.
Speaker 0: If you just get old, your racquetball skill increases exponentially.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: If you're a man and you're over 50, you'll stand in the middle of a racquetball tournament and just beat people even if you don't realize you're there.
Speaker 1: Like you'll wake up in a racquetball tournament like, what?
Speaker 1: Where am I?
Speaker 1: And you're at the top of the ladder.
Speaker 0: And next thing you know, you're standing in the shower room completely naked with all the other old men.
Speaker 0: You got one leg up on the bench.
Speaker 1: Oh, the one leg.
Speaker 0: Airing out the junk, chatting up about, hey, did you see that?
Speaker 0: And that's where it goes.
Speaker 1: That's the life.
Speaker 1: I'm looking forward to those days.
Speaker 1: Those are going to be good days.
Speaker 0: You can enjoy those days alone.
Speaker 1: But seriously, like skiing, because I ski a lot.
Speaker 1: Skiing is a big part of my life and the technology of skiing has literally changed the sport in a way to where skiing 20 years ago is unrecognizable to skiing today.
Speaker 1: If you took someone from today, put them in skis from 20 years ago and said, ski, they would probably die.
Speaker 0: Well, it's the same.
Speaker 0: You know, they always.
Speaker 0: it keeps coming back on the Internet over and over again, the one comparing the Olympic vault from a long time ago to today.
Speaker 0: It's like in the old vault, it's like the lady runs, jumps, flips once over the vault and lands.
Speaker 0: And now it's like this land, right?
Speaker 0: It's the same level of development.
Speaker 0: That's such an easy visualization to show how much development there has been in that sport.
Speaker 0: But pretty much every other sport has developed just as much in that same time period.
Speaker 1: Well, I think think of this.
Speaker 1: There's a there's a turn called a stem Christie and there's all these turns and skiing, which basically involve like skidding and like twisting and throwing the back end of your skis out.
Speaker 1: But there's a turn called the carving turn, which you can really only do the way that people do it today with modern skis that have a special shape that no one made skis like that a long time ago.
Speaker 1: So I can turn in ways that were literally impossible when I was learning how to ski when I was young.
Speaker 1: And also the binding technology has changed so much that I mean, look at the old stereotype of skiing.
Speaker 1: It's ridiculously dangerous.
Speaker 0: It still is.
Speaker 1: Well, now it really isn't.
Speaker 1: I actually found some statistics.
Speaker 0: Skiing deaths per thousand skiers are pretty low and comparable to going to the hospital in critical condition, but not dying.
Speaker 1: That counts as a casualty.
Speaker 0: How about breaking a leg?
Speaker 1: Actually, not super common.
Speaker 0: Breaking anything.
Speaker 1: I broke a nail once.
Speaker 0: Breaking a bone.
Speaker 1: I'll put it this way.
Speaker 1: In the old days, skiing was so dangerous.
Speaker 1: And what was the stare to watch any movie about skiing?
Speaker 1: There's always the guy in like a full leg cast sitting in the lodge by the fire.
Speaker 1: That's like.
Speaker 1: that's like every ski movie had that thing.
Speaker 0: Not going to go skiing.
Speaker 1: That doesn't happen nearly as much anymore.
Speaker 0: You're telling me that when you were at the ski lodge last, there was not a guy there in traction.
Speaker 1: There was not.
Speaker 0: You sure?
Speaker 1: I am 100 percent sure.
Speaker 0: Maybe he was taking a nap.
Speaker 1: And one way I was talking to an old timer like this.
Speaker 1: guy's been skiing at this mountain for like 40 years and he was talking about how there's a run on the back mountain that in the old days, only the most expert pro in the world could even get down it because it's just this icy, cliffy bullshit.
Speaker 1: But today with modern skis, I can ski down that thing.
Speaker 1: And he was like, yeah, the modern skis opened up all these trails in the old days, like only super pros could go on.
Speaker 1: the technology literally made trails that used to be considered expert trails become like a normal trail that a good skier would ski on.
Speaker 0: So it's, you know, when you tend to think about technology improving like sports, right, you tend to think about the equipment you use for the sport, things you've been talking about, rackets, skis, uniforms, you know, bathing suits, golf clubs, right?
Speaker 0: There's a lot of technology you can use to improve at a sport that doesn't actually get used on the field.
Speaker 0: I just read an article about how some of the skiers were using wind tunnels, right, to optimize their skiing before going to the Olympics.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's like, oh, footballs, right, American footballs.
Speaker 0: They used to in the olden days take pictures of the field with a photo camera, develop the photo, right, with chemicals, put it on a, you know, a clothespin on a rope with pulleys and wheel it down this giant clothesline from the top of the stadium to the coach at the at the sideline.
Speaker 0: Nowadays, they take the picture and it's digital and then the coach can see it on a, you know, print it out and look at it right to see what's going on.
Speaker 1: Now, imagine how much sports change if you have access to that kind of technology.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: People are talking about how, you know, basketball, they might let him have tablets or something on this.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: There's a big talk about changing basketball.
Speaker 1: They might have already done it.
Speaker 1: I don't follow too closely to give the coaches access to a lot more data.
Speaker 1: live at the game.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it's theoretically possible.
Speaker 0: you could develop a technology to where I mean, when you shoot in basketball.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's in the air for about a second or so.
Speaker 0: You know, it doesn't, you know, fly through the air like bam.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's going like it goes up and then down and then in the back in the hoop.
Speaker 0: You could have a camera set up that would be looking at the basketball.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Figure out its trajectory.
Speaker 0: And the camera plus a computer would know immediately after the ball was released from a player's hands whether that was going to be a swoosh, bounce off the rim and rebound, be an airball or whatever.
Speaker 1: And if rebound, what direction?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So the coach sitting there looking at his tablet, as soon as someone takes a shot, he could look and it would tell him with enough time to yell out like rebound.
Speaker 0: And then the players would know how to react to that.
Speaker 1: But both coaches would have access to the same technology.
Speaker 0: The only way to communicate that to the players would be to yell it out.
Speaker 1: Now, what if you let the players have displays somehow Google Glass?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like some equivalent of that to where you just get hurt using that.
Speaker 1: Well, what if they design one that wouldn't hurt?
Speaker 1: Imagine if every time you shot, it's like as you're shooting, like you're put, you're going up, it shows the projected trajectory and you make subtle movements to your wrist.
Speaker 1: It changes the projection so you know if it's going to go in or even forget that.
Speaker 1: not in the game and training.
Speaker 1: What if in tennis you have a device on your arm and a camera and all these things that every time you serve, it makes noises and gives you immediate feedback as to how effective your serve was to allow you to train your body's muscle memory to always give a perfect serve.
Speaker 0: You toss the ball up in the air and it beeps.
Speaker 0: at the moment you should have made contact with the ball.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or it makes a noise like like to kind of give you the motion and the timing and everything.
Speaker 1: So two things.
Speaker 1: One, having that technology to train will make you a very effective player.
Speaker 1: Two, what if you could use that technology during the game?
Speaker 1: That's like the in drag racing, which I think is a stupid sport.
Speaker 1: I think it's a great competition for engineers.
Speaker 1: But as a sport with a human in the car, I think it's dumb.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But because basically a computer just says shift, shift, shift, shift, shift, shift, shift.
Speaker 1: It tells you when to shift.
Speaker 1: The human just goes.
Speaker 0: That's what it is.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Is that the more, you know, if you use technology to like figure out what to do beforehand, like NFL film study.
Speaker 0: That's just figuring out strategies and stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean, I even do that for now runner.
Speaker 0: I'm like studying, you know, watching people's games and people chess.
Speaker 0: People do it right.
Speaker 0: But the more you use that during the game, basically what ends up happening is it's less and less a battle of humans and a battle of computers.
Speaker 0: It's all right.
Speaker 0: My computer is really doing all the work, but it's controlling this human.
Speaker 0: So we need humans that are really good at being controlled by computers, which is not hard DDR.
Speaker 0: And then it becomes which computer is better.
Speaker 0: and maybe a tiny fraction of it is which human is better at being controlled by the computer, which is making all the decisions because it's better at making those decisions than a human can and faster.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So like eventually, like if you had an athlete with the computer was making all the decisions and the computer was just better and perfect, it's not you and you would.
Speaker 0: basically it's going faster than your reaction time.
Speaker 0: So you basically have to not react and you sort of be able to like give up your will and allow the computer to control you.
Speaker 1: But at that point, now you're relying upon the failings of that individual human.
Speaker 1: So breeding technology and genetics become important again.
Speaker 1: Or fuck it.
Speaker 1: Why even have the human involved?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just robot battle.
Speaker 0: That's really, you know, and it's like we've had battle bots, which isn't that exciting.
Speaker 1: Battle bots is actually kind of shit.
Speaker 1: Like I've always.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the idea is cool, but battle bots is always implemented with so many restrictions and the contests are always so lame.
Speaker 1: I want to see a battle bot.
Speaker 0: that's basically you make any bot you want and you make any bot you want.
Speaker 1: You want you want to put guns in there.
Speaker 1: Fine.
Speaker 1: How much ammo do you carry?
Speaker 1: Go fucking nuts.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You want to, you know, it's like just do it.
Speaker 1: My bot is just a whole bunch of bombs.
Speaker 0: Your bot has to survive those bombs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it just rolls bombs out.
Speaker 1: It can.
Speaker 1: it can deal with up to 10 bots.
Speaker 0: Bowling ball.
Speaker 1: It's got 10 bowling ball candle bombs.
Speaker 0: It's a 20 round turn.
Speaker 1: I have n bomb and plus one bombs and being the number of rounds.
Speaker 0: Yeah, good luck.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you know, I want to see.
Speaker 0: it's like I kind of want to see computer versus computer.
Speaker 1: I want to see F1 races like those same cars drive themselves.
Speaker 1: Yeah, self-driving cars, same size cars, same tracks and maybe even some.
Speaker 0: But if it's a self-driving car, you don't care about safety anymore.
Speaker 0: So just make the cars no rules.
Speaker 0: It has to be a four wheeled motorized vehicle with some sort of.
Speaker 1: I would like a restriction that they have to be above a certain size just so they're big and interesting.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it has to be above a certain size.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, I have this tiny little rocket car.
Speaker 1: There's.
Speaker 0: Well, I think you can have a weight limit.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It has to weigh at least X.
Speaker 1: Maybe even do something cool like have a fake human that you put in there.
Speaker 1: And there is a secondary rule of that fake human can't get destroyed by the end, like protect the egg.
Speaker 1: That could make it more interesting.
Speaker 1: Maybe you just have this.
Speaker 0: But imagine how lame it would be.
Speaker 0: You're watching the sport on TV and it's like, oh, the red car lost.
Speaker 0: The fake human thing inside got hurt.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, because you get the video of the fake human thing like exploding in the shower of it would like its head would shake back and forth.
Speaker 0: You know, he's got whiplash.
Speaker 0: Technically, the sensor says he would be in a coma right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, fine.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: Then trigger it.
Speaker 1: If you kill the human, your car blows up.
Speaker 0: There we go.
Speaker 0: Now we're talking explosions.
Speaker 1: Even with technology, competition is only fun if there are arbitrary constraints of some kind.
Speaker 1: I mean, otherwise, I kidnap your robot engineer the night before and make him put a virus in.
Speaker 1: I mean, you've got to have some constraints.
Speaker 0: I mean, really, what this all comes down to is the old nerd versus jock battle.
Speaker 0: And if we can turn every sport into actually something where the engineers are what matters and not the athletes.
Speaker 1: And football is already real close to that.
Speaker 0: Then we can just eliminate all jocks and there's rule everything.
Speaker 0: because you'll be like high school football, right?
Speaker 0: We'll be a robot battle.
Speaker 0: So it'll be all programmers in the high school football team, right?
Speaker 0: High school basketball team also full of programmers.
Speaker 0: We won't need to separate men's and women's sports at all because it's just engineers.
Speaker 1: Now, what's interesting is that in non-competitive sports or non-professional sports like skiing for me, like ski races left some arbitrary rules about things.
Speaker 1: But me as a skier, I will use the level of technology that makes my experience the most enjoyable.
Speaker 1: Maybe I want a challenge and I use like not as good as skis and I try to ski like particular courses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, get killed.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or maybe I use things that wouldn't be allowed in the tournament because it makes skiing more pleasant for me.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's biking too.
Speaker 1: Like I could get a bike that would not be allowed in the Tour de France.
Speaker 0: I see people with them all the goddamn time in the city.
Speaker 1: And it'd be really fucking awesome for certain kinds of biking.
Speaker 1: Like if I wanted to bike, I don't know, to Florida, I'd probably get one of those cheating goddamn bikes.
Speaker 0: You couldn't really carry anything on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I biked to Florida, I would do the stop at a hotel every night bike.
Speaker 0: You would do the someone drives behind you in a car situation?
Speaker 1: Or I would do the stop at a hotel every night.
Speaker 0: Where are you keeping your clothing?
Speaker 1: I'd wash it in the hotel that night.
Speaker 0: And you'd be naked.
Speaker 1: OK, fine.
Speaker 1: I carry one extra set of clothing.
Speaker 1: Scott, it'd be all like lycra.
Speaker 1: So I just roll it up and put it into my jacket.
Speaker 0: Oh, like, OK.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All everything you have is in those three pouches in the back of the jersey.
Speaker 1: Clothes that would pass the legal definition of clothing in those pockets, along with my wallet, keys and cell phone.
Speaker 0: It would be like those, what's it called, the T-shirts at Muji.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: They come in a tiny cube.
Speaker 0: Come in a tiny cube.
Speaker 1: I like how those things are so wrinkled from the cube that you can never unwrinkle them.
Speaker 0: You can.
Speaker 0: A lot of hard work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you're not supposed to.
Speaker 1: That's the style.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: But that's why I bought all those heat tech and those lycra.
Speaker 1: Like, compression shirts.
Speaker 0: They're so tiny.
Speaker 1: I could fit like four hundred of them in my suitcase if I wanted to.
Speaker 0: Don't do that.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: It doesn't affect you.
Speaker 1: I should make Ignite shirts like that.
Speaker 0: Do whatever you can do.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Do we have anything else?
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't know.
Speaker 1: You guys have any questions about this stuff?
Speaker 0: I'm just really hungry.
Speaker 1: I'm also really hungry.
Speaker 0: And it's getting seven o'clock.
Speaker 1: Oh, now they know when we do the show.
Speaker 0: In what time zone?
Speaker 1: Oh, this has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.