Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, June 4th, 2014.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem, and this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, Ghost in the Shell Arise.
Speaker 0: Or at least the first two episodes.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So we got to see Takashi Murakami's jellyfish eyes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so basically it was really weird.
Speaker 1: So if you don't know, there's two Murakamis and people get them confused.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's the 1Q84.
Speaker 1: The author Haruki Murakami.
Speaker 0: But no, we're talking about super flat Murakami.
Speaker 1: Right, the guy we went to see his art exhibit in Brooklyn some years ago.
Speaker 0: Yep, that was when we learned that most of the people in the world that we know were slow walkers.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so he was coming to the city because he made a movie, and I was like, "Well, I don't care what that movie is, he made it and he's going to be there, so I want to go to
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 1: I tried to buy tickets and their website basically didn't work because I said, "Oh well, I guess I didn't get
Speaker 1: tickets.".
Speaker 1: And then I checked my credit card statement at the end of the month and they charged me money, and I was like, "Hey, what the
Speaker 1: hell?".
Speaker 1: So I called the box office and was like, "You charged me money for a thing I didn't get tickets
Speaker 1: to.".
Speaker 1: They said, "You did get
Speaker 1: tickets.".
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Oh shit, this thing is in like two days.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I checked with
Speaker 1: you.".
Speaker 1: So we went to see it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was crazy sold out.
Speaker 0: There were like a hundred people hanging around hoping to get in on standby, and he was there.
Speaker 0: Like we walk in, Scott and our friends Phil and James do.
Speaker 1: I mostly wanted to go because I knew the movie Good or Bad was going to look crazy because he made it.
Speaker 0: And it did.
Speaker 1: And I knew that I wanted to see what this guy was like because his art is crazy.
Speaker 0: So we're not going to do too much of an in-depth review just because a movie like this, just go see it.
Speaker 1: Well, how are you going to see it?
Speaker 0: I'm sure there will be a way to see it at some point.
Speaker 1: It's going to be a while before you have a chance to see it.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't think it's on the internet yet.
Speaker 0: But it is beautiful.
Speaker 0: I will say that.
Speaker 0: It is absolutely beautiful the way it's filmed.
Speaker 0: The compositing is really good except for some of the weird fights at the end.
Speaker 0: The characters are actually really cute and weird except the one guy who just looks like a dude in a costume.
Speaker 1: You don't like Luxor?
Speaker 0: Well, Luxor's size is proportionate to the sadness and the heart of that little girl.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: I think Luxor might actually be the best one in my book.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: The jellyfish dude was pretty cool because he was the most badass.
Speaker 0: What about Coco?
Speaker 1: The monkey?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Coco was the fighting game girl.
Speaker 0: Oh, well that's- Co to the second power, Coco.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no.
Speaker 0: I guess that kid was sadder than the girl who had Luxor because he had like a million Pokemon.
Speaker 0: He was the hikikomori.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: This movie, it started out like it was going to be ET.
Speaker 0: You know, kid finds a weird thing, hiding it from his parents, but then it immediately turns into Pokemon.
Speaker 1: And then it turns into Godzilla.
Speaker 0: Yup, pretty much.
Speaker 0: And the good things I can say about it, it was beautiful and weird and I actually was surprised by it at a number of points.
Speaker 0: The bad things I can say about it, the child actors were kind of bad.
Speaker 0: The story was pretty dumb in the end.
Speaker 1: It was like a typical live action Japanese kids movie.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: It reminded me a lot of actually Juvenile.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty similar.
Speaker 1: Except without the, this also had the Godzilla listening to this knows what the fuck Juvenile.
Speaker 0: Oh my God, Juvenile.
Speaker 0: We should do a show on that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'd have to watch it again.
Speaker 0: How'd we even fucking get that?
Speaker 1: It was on some random tape.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: In the anime club or some shit.
Speaker 0: We just saw this VHS tape and it was labeled Juvenile.
Speaker 0: We're like, what the fuck is that?
Speaker 0: It's actually just Japanese ET.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: Basically.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this thing was just, it has kind of this ham fisted Fukushima sort of metaphor allegory about you have to have optimism and there's sadness and coming of age and there's a lot of ideas sort of just mishmash together into it.
Speaker 0: So I can't say that it was good, but it was definitely enjoyable, but you got to enjoy some parts of it from the perspective of why is that cultist so angry?
Speaker 0: He got what he wanted.
Speaker 0: None of the other cultists are angry.
Speaker 1: Uh, I guess in other news, there's other news.
Speaker 0: Not really.
Speaker 1: There is.
Speaker 1: There's hardly any news, but I just wanted to remind people number one, saga volume three should be out now, right?
Speaker 1: And two, uh, at this as of like some days ago, maybe even a week ago, the last episode of Gundam UC unicorn is out.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So this is pretty chill.
Speaker 0: This is basically one of those things where it's two cultures that aren't United States slash English speaking Western world and commentary on each other, which is the kind of thing I always like.
Speaker 0: So it's the guy who's Malaysian, speaks Malaysian, speaks Japanese, and he's explaining mostly for the benefit of other people who aren't necessarily us about Japanese phrases and Japanese sayings.
Speaker 0: and Japanese people do like this.
Speaker 0: That's, this is, it's very different from how Malaysian people do.
Speaker 0: And the best of his videos, I'll link to both of them cause they're pretty great is how does, how to use high like a Japanese.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: And the four levels of the Japanese.
Speaker 0: Hey, Hey, Hey, it's really good.
Speaker 0: It's really good.
Speaker 0: Especially if you don't speak Japanese.
Speaker 0: that well, but you watch a lot of anime.
Speaker 0: If you watch these videos, you'll be like, ah, I get it.
Speaker 1: I think you sort of naturally get it.
Speaker 1: I feel like I already know the four levels of A.
Speaker 0: You'd think so.
Speaker 0: The more, uh, important or dangerous ones are actually shorter.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Hey has a profound theory.
Speaker 1: So you remember retro game master.
Speaker 0: Do I ever game center CX?
Speaker 1: Did you know that it was a retro game challenge too for the Nintendo DS?
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: Why don't I own that?
Speaker 1: Because it never was and probably never will be released in English.
Speaker 0: Fuck.
Speaker 0: I'll just play it in Japanese.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 1: Well, you might be excited to know some fans just came out a few days ago with a translation patch.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: Get your DS emulators or DS piracy cards all fixed up.
Speaker 1: Patch that ROM and play the game center.
Speaker 0: That takes me back.
Speaker 0: It takes me back to a day when I discovered final fantasy five and I had a ROM of it, but it was in Japanese.
Speaker 0: Then I found a patch that made that ROM in English and oh fuck did I play that game.
Speaker 0: and also fuck did the translation not just sort of Peter out about two thirds of the way through.
Speaker 0: It just that all the words got replaced with like sword icons and gibberish.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So as a result, I never beat that game.
Speaker 0: Also fuck the shield dragon.
Speaker 1: Meta moments.
Speaker 0: Book Club book is identical for Lebowitz.
Speaker 1: I read like a chapter and then stop.
Speaker 0: precursor book, the proto culture book to all the like.
Speaker 0: post apocalypse survival in a place with a color system books we've read.
Speaker 1: If anyone knows an earlier store instance of that story, please tell it to us.
Speaker 0: Wikipedia lists a few, but I think this one is the beginning of the modern era of post apocalypse survival.
Speaker 1: Well, something I realized is even the idea of a manmade apocalypse, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, it's Noah's arc, right?
Speaker 1: But the idea wasn't made by man.
Speaker 1: No, as I'm saying is that apocalypse is in general Noah's arc, right?
Speaker 1: Or maybe even older than that, but right.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The idea of a manmade apocalypse, right?
Speaker 1: Didn't even, it wasn't even conceivable to people because we didn't have any things that could possibly do that.
Speaker 0: Well, imagine you're Roman.
Speaker 0: You're like, all right, what do we do?
Speaker 0: Just start stabbing the earth and keep stabbing it until it dies.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: It's like other than something that comes from God or nature or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: I got a God or nature, whatever.
Speaker 1: the only, we couldn't even conceive of a manmade apocalypse until we invented nuclear weapons, right?
Speaker 1: So this kind of story didn't really exist until we invented nuclear weapons, which was less than a century ago.
Speaker 0: And funnily enough, most of the post-apocalypses in these stores are caused by nuclear weapons.
Speaker 0: You don't say occasionally get the biological weapon, the zombie, right?
Speaker 1: Well, the only, the only stories that are otherwise are stuff like cat's cradle where someone makes up something fictional, right?
Speaker 1: Like ice nine.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: In other news, you should join us at Connecticut.
Speaker 0: Second week of June and the weekend, I think it's the 10th, 11th, 12th, 13th.
Speaker 0: Uh, Connecticut con is not better than packs prime.
Speaker 0: No, it's not better than magfest unless you're into anything other than gaming.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it's a better gaming con than almost every gaming con in the United States.
Speaker 0: All rolled into one.
Speaker 0: So as we've said before, you know, we, we run the panels and workshops department.
Speaker 0: So we scheduled a, I think a pretty bad ass schedule of panels and lectures and workshops and stuff.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: It might be the best panels and lectures period at any con.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it might be actually, I think, I think we pretty much, you know, our department, you know, not to be all self aggrandizing, but I think about the panels and lectures departments of other cons and their schedules.
Speaker 1: and it's like the big cons, mostly of industry panels, which are boring as hell.
Speaker 1: And the small cons just, you know, either they have rain bro dash, right?
Speaker 1: And then the other cons like anime Boston, like it's really good, but it's anime only Connecticut con.
Speaker 1: We got panels on everything of the highest quality.
Speaker 0: Absolutely everything except we don't have anything on the demo scenes.
Speaker 1: So email us, uh, other meta things you should go and find us on the internet.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you're listening to this, you probably already have, but we have many places on the internet, Twitter, IRC, newsletter, forum, Facebook's got pluses.
Speaker 1: We have everything.
Speaker 0: I feel like we should put that part at the end and the closer as opposed to in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: No people probably turn off the podcast by then.
Speaker 0: So somebody listens for the first time though.
Speaker 0: might listen to that cause it's explained some stuff.
Speaker 1: Maybe I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know guys.
Speaker 0: I'll say this.
Speaker 0: I'm going to highlight one thing.
Speaker 0: If you're going to interact with us in any way, the best way to do that right now is to share our shit on Reddit because Reddit won't let you put your own stuff up and people are really weird about that on Reddit.
Speaker 0: So it's up to you.
Speaker 0: The more popular you make our videos, the more videos we'll do.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Go.
Speaker 1: We need a people who like us to go and promote us because at least on Reddit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's hard to do otherwise.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should use our project wonderful money to buy some ads.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We just need someone to pay someone else to post our stuff on Reddit.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: Make a new account, fake account, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Gig nights.
Speaker 0: Fuck.
Speaker 0: I already fucked it up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: So pretty much since standalone complex second gig and then the, uh, pretty okay.
Speaker 0: Solid state society OAV came out.
Speaker 0: Uh, I've modicum magic.
Speaker 0: It was great.
Speaker 0: I really enjoyed Kill La Kill, but all I really want out of anime is more ghost in the shell standalone complex.
Speaker 1: Well, they're not going to get more of that, but you will get more ghosts in the shell.
Speaker 1: In fact, we just did.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And it's the closest thing to standalone complex that has come out since standalone complex.
Speaker 1: It's the only ghost in the shell that's come out.
Speaker 0: Yes, but there have been no other anime that scratched that itch at all.
Speaker 0: This is the only anime that scratches that.
Speaker 1: Some people would make some animes or mangas in a ghost in the shell ish cyberpunk genre.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's not a dystopia ghost in the show.
Speaker 0: It's not a utopia.
Speaker 0: It's just kind of a realistic future of cyber tech and cyberspace and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, procedural police drama.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So not going to spoil a million things.
Speaker 0: Let's spoil a few things because we didn't see all of a rise.
Speaker 1: It's not all out yet.
Speaker 1: Much like Gundam unicorn.
Speaker 1: I was originally going to wait until all of it was out and then watch it all at once.
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 1: They went and put episodes one and two, uh, in a theater in New York city and I'm like, well, might as well go see it.
Speaker 1: And I went to see it.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: I'm glad we watched it on the big screen because it was really loud.
Speaker 0: It wasn't that loud.
Speaker 0: I've been in louder theaters where the plot of a ghost in the shell standalone complex season would encompass, you know, a certain thing.
Speaker 0: Like there's a politician.
Speaker 0: We finally bring him down.
Speaker 1: Every episode of this has about the same amount of plots, but there's also this sort of a overarching plot to the whole thing, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Formation of section nine and whatnot.
Speaker 0: Well, of course we know pretty much the gist of it, at least from all the other ghosts in the shell media.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But you're getting all these details that may or may not conflict with previous camera.
Speaker 0: It already conflicts a couple of times in tone with a standalone complexes backstories.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And some of the characters are different.
Speaker 1: Like Saito is pretty excitable, but complex is super serious.
Speaker 0: Excitable is probably the best way to describe it, right?
Speaker 1: But he's super serious in standalone complex and other ghosts in the shells.
Speaker 1: It's like, why did they change his personality?
Speaker 1: Or maybe he's just going to show us his personality changing.
Speaker 1: But no, because there was a flashback in standalone complex that showed him in the past being super serious.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't make sense.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That's just one example.
Speaker 1: But other things are perfectly match of the canon.
Speaker 1: Like Toga is a detective and he's getting noticed.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And probably, you know, that's probably going to match up really well.
Speaker 1: And, you know, bottles is a ranger and he seems pretty similar to.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But everyone's definitely their younger self like they have more energy.
Speaker 0: They're they're surprisingly all kind of snarky with each other and they all mostly know who each other are.
Speaker 0: Like they're all kind of famous or infamous within their various spheres.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like, you know, say John Carmack's walking down the road.
Speaker 1: Most people are not going to know who he is.
Speaker 1: And if he opens his mouth, people are going to be like, oh, it's Professor Frank.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he talks.
Speaker 1: But if we see him walking down the road, I'd be like, whoa, it's a John Carmack over there in our industry.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So these people are all in, you know, the military, you know, law enforcement, you know, industry.
Speaker 1: So they know each other because they're all infamous badasses.
Speaker 0: So the interesting thing, though, is that at least because every episode is pretty much standalone as a movie, even though it kind of reveals the greater world, you can't just go watch an episode.
Speaker 0: I wasn't going to say watch them out of order.
Speaker 0: I'm saying you can watch one episode and be totally satisfied.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can do that.
Speaker 0: You don't need to wait for the next episode to come out.
Speaker 0: There are no cliffhangers.
Speaker 1: There's no cliffhangers.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It was each one is like a whole movie's worth.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It resolves.
Speaker 1: So, you know, there isn't.
Speaker 1: there isn't like, well, you know, continued in the next episode or anything like that.
Speaker 0: So if you're a fan of standalone complex, like the previous sets of Ghost in the Shell, what I would say is primarily different is that the world is much freer with crazy military technology.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that's to a greater point, like society is still a little lawless or there's still a lot of military hardware hanging around after the war.
Speaker 0: But I mean, in early episodes, bad guys have like military tanks and military shit and they're just blowing things up.
Speaker 0: Landmines everywhere.
Speaker 0: Oh, landmines look like prepubescent girls.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, maybe that could actually be a result of, you know, well, first of all, the political situation in the country at the time.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, they talk a bit about, you know, how things are kind of unstable.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, the military is getting reorganized, which is like the backdrop for everything.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Every military group is basically trying to protect itself.
Speaker 0: A lot of people committed war crimes.
Speaker 0: It's shady shit during the actual war.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And you could almost, you know, say that, you know, all the difference in the world here in Arise versus the difference in standalone conflicts and other Ghost in the Shells is, you know, the results of the work of Section 9.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like they did a good job.
Speaker 1: Therefore, things became this way because watching this only then the cyber crimes they have to deal with are, you know, the only ones that are left are like super high level, amazing people hidden deep in the net.
Speaker 1: And all the things on the service level have sort of cleaned up, you know, by the major and team.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But it's interesting how pointed all of that is like the backdrop really fits with the way this show is working.
Speaker 0: Violence is the answer much more readily.
Speaker 0: And the plots are actually pretty straightforward because everyone's corrupt.
Speaker 0: I mean, when the major tricks the one politician in the car to spill in the beans, his beans are the smallest of beans.
Speaker 0: And it seems like everybody has a lot of beans.
Speaker 0: Everybody.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Granted, all they had to do was find the other coffin.
Speaker 0: They would have been good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not easy to find.
Speaker 1: It was right there.
Speaker 0: I carried this coffin around with me.
Speaker 0: I'm working on a meme mashup with that guy from Cowboy Bebop and this episode.
Speaker 1: How about also some Trigun in there?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: I could get to Mid Valley, not Mid Valley Horn Freak, Legato Blue Summers and carrying that coffin.
Speaker 0: Man, the Trigun manga is pretty fun.
Speaker 1: And you could also put in, maybe you could mix in the grave in Fist of the North Star.
Speaker 1: He's like, I dug this grave.
Speaker 1: He's going to make him fit in it.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: I got to put that thing together.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The major is interesting in that she's still very recognizably her character, but she's a lot more openly surly and a lot more direct.
Speaker 0: She finds out a thing.
Speaker 0: She goes immediately straight at that thing.
Speaker 0: Also, she gets hacked.
Speaker 0: She's not 100% yet.
Speaker 0: She's not the goddess of hacking yet.
Speaker 1: Well, the body that she has here is not the body that she has for, I guess, the cyborg body that she has for most of the Ghost in the Shell story.
Speaker 0: Not the crazy military body.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: It's not like she doesn't have the guns coming out of her arms and shit or anything like that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's just sort of a really good cyborg body she got from when she was in the military.
Speaker 1: And at the start, the military still owns it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: In fact, the show makes a big deal about that too.
Speaker 0: They have all these nice subtle touches about how basically full body cyborgs are not really a thing outside of the military.
Speaker 0: People don't...
Speaker 1: Even in other Ghost in the Shells, it's like no one can afford that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Ultra rich people can.
Speaker 0: It's out there.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's why you have people like even someone who owns a company like Jameson.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: He's in a little tiny box because...
Speaker 0: Well, he prefers that body.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, but that's the why.
Speaker 1: If they do have a full body cyborg, they don't have a good one.
Speaker 1: It's not like the fact that the major is... That's true through all Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That she basically always has the best possible cyborg body.
Speaker 1: that's a full cyborg body.
Speaker 1: No one could even tell.
Speaker 1: They'd be like, "Whoa, that's a full cyborg body.
Speaker 1: Holy
Speaker 1: shit.".
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Because most full cyborg bodies are really crappy.
Speaker 0: But as a result, we get this interesting thing that actually fits with the old shows where they're really worried about personal freedom and personal attitude and the ability to fight for what they want and whatever and not being beholden to anyone except by consent.
Speaker 1: And control by being hacked because you have a computer.
Speaker 0: But in this one, there's all these characters want something and can't go after it because they work within an organization that's hobbled by bureaucracy.
Speaker 0: And basically, the story of Ghost in the Shell is, as it's always been, all the people who want justice and who are smart, band together to semi-legally pursue justice and do that via Batman.
Speaker 0: Cyber Batman.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: That is the plot of Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 0: But with a rise, it is open.
Speaker 0: It is out there.
Speaker 0: That is what they are doing.
Speaker 0: A hundred percent.
Speaker 0: The show is also ultra, ultra action.
Speaker 0: Very little.
Speaker 1: I think because it's an OAV, because you're getting so much time in there, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they got to fill it with awesome action scenes.
Speaker 1: You have a big budget.
Speaker 1: How do you blow it?
Speaker 0: And I think, apparently, in every episode, they're going to spend a lot of detail on one of the major's arms being blown off.
Speaker 1: That's how it goes.
Speaker 0: Two episodes in a row.
Speaker 0: Boom.
Speaker 0: But everyone's bodies get injured a lot.
Speaker 1: But when you have several bodies, that's something you can do that you couldn't do otherwise.
Speaker 1: So true.
Speaker 0: But in standalone complex, when someone needs to replace a part of their body, that's a big goddamn deal.
Speaker 0: And it kind of hobbles them for a while.
Speaker 0: And in this OAV, they pretty much are immediately fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the major difference between this and the other Ghost in the Shells is that the, you know, the original Ghost in the Shell movie and even standalone complex, right, sort of has this really mysterious kind of thing like, ooh, what's going on in the net?
Speaker 1: Who's the laughing man?
Speaker 1: And it's like you'll get to the end of an episode and it won't be fully explained like what really happened there.
Speaker 1: We know most of it, but not all the details.
Speaker 1: And, you know, you got sort of like that cyber eeriness going on, right, where not everything's explained in this.
Speaker 1: Everything is literally and in plain text explained to you, except for the higher level meta.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Of course, they pretty much explain everything.
Speaker 1: Someone just says right out everything that happened in a given episode at some point.
Speaker 1: So nothing.
Speaker 1: It's not like what really happened.
Speaker 1: No, you just saw everything literally just happen, right?
Speaker 1: There's no eerie ness of like, hmm, what's what's going on?
Speaker 1: What's that guy up to?
Speaker 1: You know, there's no mystery whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And coupled with the fact that there's no mystery, it doesn't read like it does a terrible secret of space either.
Speaker 0: Well, other than the ones we already know about from other Ghost in the Shells or the sort of open questions of like what is going to happen in the future with this society?
Speaker 1: There's also very little that like you can see foreshadowing of things in other Ghost in the Shells.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, OK, so there's these logic commas.
Speaker 1: Clearly they're touchy coma precursors.
Speaker 1: But it's only really blatant stuff like that.
Speaker 1: There's nothing else sort of like hinting at the laughing man or the puppeteer or any, you know, anything coming down the line.
Speaker 0: There's a little bit of reference to the puppeteer with a certain spy.
Speaker 1: I didn't notice any of the A.I.
Speaker 1: Maybe a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't know that.
Speaker 0: That was definitely.
Speaker 0: But notice how that was inconceivable to them at that point.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But it's interesting to watch the show.
Speaker 0: I like it a lot.
Speaker 0: I don't like it as much as I liked actual standalone complex because it's missing a lot of the key elements that make standalone complex a standalone complex.
Speaker 0: It's not directed by Kenji Kamiyama, the new one, and the music in the new one is not the same kind of music as every other Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The music's not that exciting.
Speaker 1: The music is very a lot like the Akira soundtrack where it's sort of like boom, boom, boom.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Which has its place.
Speaker 1: Chanting and some noises.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Mostly it's the opener is just really kind of milk toast.
Speaker 0: The opener to both standalone complexes just drives you crazy.
Speaker 0: Like you are pumped up and ready to jump off of buildings backwards.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But then you watch this opener and you're like, can we just cyber butt past this opener and get back to the fighting in the show?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Really like to get back to that.
Speaker 0: So I don't know much about the guy who directs this new one.
Speaker 0: I haven't really done much research on this yet because we're going to do a real review after we see the whole thing.
Speaker 0: I mean, if we reviewed standalone complex after a couple episodes, it's just a completely standalone procedural police drama.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Which is awesome.
Speaker 1: You know, another seat, right?
Speaker 1: Stuff happens.
Speaker 1: So who knows?
Speaker 1: Maybe like the next episode will say to be continued or something like that.
Speaker 1: You don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We don't know at all.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I mean, if you like Ghost in the Shell, you'll still like this and want to watch it after you've watched all the other Ghost in the Shells.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But now I really just want to go back and watch standalone complex.
Speaker 0: I have this real urge to just watch.
Speaker 0: In fact, I watched an episode.
Speaker 0: Most of it's on YouTube for free legally, as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: How about that?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Maybe this will be one day.
Speaker 0: If you're a fan of Ghost in the Shell, watch this however you can.
Speaker 0: It's up.
Speaker 0: It's in your wheelhouse.
Speaker 0: There's no other anime for you to watch.
Speaker 0: Kill La Kill is done.
Speaker 0: Monica was done a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Attack on Titan has got a long time before.
Speaker 0: anything new is coming out with that.
Speaker 1: Sailor Moon will be there for a long time.
Speaker 1: It's not going anywhere.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Of course, if you don't watch it as it's trickling out, it might be hard to bite down on that 200 episode monster.
Speaker 1: I watched all of Fist of the North Star after it was all out.
Speaker 0: True.
Speaker 0: And then there's the new Sailor Moon, which that I'm going to watch as it comes out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.