Speaker 1: It's Thursday September 4th 2014.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Judith and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: Judith is on the spot.
Speaker 1: This is the part where I usually talk way too long and Scott gets really mad.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh Scott apparently and I shit you not Forgot to come over to the studio to do the show.
Speaker 1: He was.
Speaker 1: we were talking about it right before I was at work.
Speaker 1: I was like, hey, we're gonna do a show and he was like, oh, yeah We'll do the show on this.
Speaker 1: and I was like we're gonna get Judith on and put her on the spot.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be hilarious.
Speaker 1: And he was like, yeah, that'll be pretty good.
Speaker 1: And if she doesn't show up, we'll just talk about gamer gate because that's pretty stupid.
Speaker 1: and I'm like, yeah.
Speaker 1: and then Scott didn't come home and After like an hour and a half.
Speaker 1: I've wondered if he was dead, you know bike accident or whatever.
Speaker 1: So I messaged him and the response I get was basically I'm gonna read his exact response.
Speaker 1: Also Judith, you can say something at any time.
Speaker 0: You were planning to put me on the spot the whole time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was waiting for you to say something and yes I was planning.
Speaker 1: I decided to call this Judith on the spot.
Speaker 1: the second you asked if you could come over and watch us.
Speaker 1: do geek nights class.
Speaker 1: I Am nothing but class.
Speaker 1: All right, let's see.
Speaker 1: so Are you dead or just not coming over?
Speaker 1: emoticon of a B is what I sent to Scott?
Speaker 1: law he paused.
Speaker 1: there's like five minutes of no response followed by.
Speaker 1: Oh I Just forgot there was a show and went home.
Speaker 0: Does he usually reply to you within a few seconds?
Speaker 0: Is it weird to have a five-minute pause?
Speaker 1: It's weird to have a pause.
Speaker 1: That's why I wondered if he was dead.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's so cute.
Speaker 1: So I said lol a whole bunch of times and he's like, so, uh, yeah I guess forgetting once in this many years is actually pretty good.
Speaker 1: So yeah, Scott's not dead.
Speaker 1: he's just bad at remembering things.
Speaker 1: so I guess he's just stop going senile early.
Speaker 0: It's going on his permanent record.
Speaker 1: So instead what I'm doing here is I'm putting Judith on the spot because we've changed the production process of geek nights a lot over The years.
Speaker 1: the last time we did a show on this we talked about how we had this like fucking compressor in line.
Speaker 1: we had all this analog mixer stuff and we really don't do any of that anymore and none of you guys seem to know how we do the show and Judith wants to do a podcast.
Speaker 1: now the whole internet knows she wants to do a podcast.
Speaker 1: if she doesn't do a podcast People are gonna be like, hey, where's my podcast?
Speaker 0: except the whole internet doesn't know who I am.
Speaker 1: I think some people know who you are.
Speaker 1: Do you want them to know who you are?
Speaker 1: You're just gonna be Judith.
Speaker 0: I'll just be Judith.
Speaker 1: Can do you want me to link to anything in the in the show notes?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: so okay, you can give him my Twitter cuz I don't have much else at the moment.
Speaker 0: Oh Twitter.
Speaker 1: So in the old days show notes were called schnoz by horrifying people who luckily no longer podcast.
Speaker 1: So bear that in mind.
Speaker 1: It's a terrible word.
Speaker 1: It is a terrible word.
Speaker 1: You know what a lot of people we used to podcast with hated us because we thought podcasting was stupid.
Speaker 0: And why did you do it?
Speaker 1: because it's really stupid.
Speaker 1: All right, okay we're into this but a lot of people tried to make money off of podcasting and There was like this whole cottage interest.
Speaker 1: There's a point where a radio producer invited us and Emily came with us to come to the radio station in New York and then Scott and I explained to this celebrity and all these people like what podcasting is and how to do it and We started to build a professional relationship.
Speaker 1: and then podcasting died and that person left New York and radio died and podcasting died again.
Speaker 1: in fact There used to be awards and we won one of them.
Speaker 1: We're the best anime podcast.
Speaker 0: Who gave you that?
Speaker 1: This is the parsec Awards.
Speaker 0: These are awards for like Exemplary short fiction that looks like something from a garage sale.
Speaker 1: In fact, this is why a lot of people hated us because we won this the first one ever and we didn't even fucking go to the award ceremony and Everyone else who was nominated did so.
Speaker 1: they announced us We weren't there.
Speaker 1: a friend of ours went up to the stage was like, yeah, I'll just take that for them I know them.
Speaker 1: and then we didn't even like announce that we won it once we found out that is ultra typical for you.
Speaker 1: Well, it is.
Speaker 1: and then we got nominated again the next year and we didn't even fill out the form we had to fill out.
Speaker 1: So lesson one Learn how to do patter and how to constantly talk and generate content because dead air sucks But the only thing that sucks more than dead air is editing.
Speaker 0: I Did that on purpose just now?
Speaker 1: And point number two because if you're gonna do this podcast with another person the way Scott and I have been able to do this and panels so easily is Honestly that we never have ever looked at each other while we were doing the show.
Speaker 1: We face away from each other so that when we're in a panel, we don't have to look at each other.
Speaker 1: We can take completely Psychic cues.
Speaker 0: you guys just do that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, though, even when you're just talking Yeah, but it was fostered over a long time and we kind of refined it by doing the show this way.
Speaker 0: Okay, I always assumed that's just how you met looking away from each other.
Speaker 0: What could be wrong with this guy?
Speaker 0: Let's room together.
Speaker 1: Actually, the story was we wanted to get a four-person apartment.
Speaker 1: the last one ended.
Speaker 1: We thought we were gonna live in River Hole with all the rats and as we're walking Dejectedly over there to sign up for the non internet apartment.
Speaker 1: They announced that there were two one-bedroom two-person apartments available in colony and We said yes and we start to run over and Greg holds up his hand and says wait and he turns around and he looks at all of us and he says and I quote who is going to live with Scott and There was a long pause and I said I will.
Speaker 0: of course you did.
Speaker 1: of course I did masochist and then Great Scott is a great guy.
Speaker 1: I remember how you guys met.
Speaker 0: I Kind of yeah, we were at a wedding.
Speaker 1: Uh Was it the wedding or was it that Otacon or was it both?
Speaker 0: It was the wedding.
Speaker 0: I might have been at the same Otacon as you but I didn't take any note of you.
Speaker 0: That's how I am with strangers.
Speaker 1: I Must have been quiet.
Speaker 1: maybe I hurt my throat or something.
Speaker 0: I can't even imagine.
Speaker 1: So, uh, it's Thursday, it's the lounge and you're not.
Speaker 1: Scott usually gets mad when I call it the lounge But I can see why what we do.
Speaker 1: Well, you don't like the lounge.
Speaker 0: That's kind of corny as hell.
Speaker 1: Well, the original concept was that instead of doing our normal format on Thursday We'd have a different format and just talk for like an hour with no Like boundaries or format or anything and we said we'd do it and then we never actually did it.
Speaker 0: Okay, then you couldn't come up with like a free for all.
Speaker 0: there's three for all Thursday.
Speaker 0: No, that doesn't work.
Speaker 1: We should have called it three for all Thursday and still only had two people.
Speaker 0: So have your third be Moogy or Theo Away, they weren't born yet.
Speaker 1: No, they were not even born.
Speaker 1: The thing you have to think about too when doing a podcast is content is king.
Speaker 1: So in addition to being able to do the pattern to just talk and to not have to edit and to already know what you're gonna Say and talk about you have to decide day one if you're going to have a format or not And I suggest having a format.
Speaker 1: So what are you doing your podcast on?
Speaker 0: Just being thrown in here and not knowing what I'm saying?
Speaker 1: pretty much yeah pretty much Yeah, is that way gonna be what your main show is?
Speaker 0: Is this you trying to teach me some kind of lesson?
Speaker 1: No, I'm just curious like what's your show gonna be about?
Speaker 0: I'm not entirely sure yet Just like we're gonna do podcast Maybe some of the things that we've covered in panels because we've done a variety of panels at different cons so far.
Speaker 1: So you're not gonna make a topical one.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna be like adventure time and every episode is about adventure time.
Speaker 0: I might do that only not so specific You got.
Speaker 1: I think the format you guys want to use is the fast karate for the gentleman format.
Speaker 1: go on their format is as such They start talking about how they're setting up the podcast like alright, dude.
Speaker 1: I got the Skype going you ready and Then they talk about something for like 10 minutes, and then they talk about their topic which is either an anime they watched video game they played or 24.
Speaker 0: we're probably gonna wind up doing shit like that minus the 24.
Speaker 1: So maybe adventure time is your 24.
Speaker 0: it could be so.
Speaker 1: you do your normal thing once a week And then whenever there's a new adventure time you just talk about that.
Speaker 1: instead until adventure time ends I wonder if it will end.
Speaker 0: of course it'll end.
Speaker 1: I wonder well it all things.
Speaker 1: then I wonder if Imagine if they just keep letting Finn age and then 20 years from now He's just an adult and the show just keeps going and it's radically different.
Speaker 0: I'd be okay with that.
Speaker 0: even that would be better than what happened to spongebob.
Speaker 1: Spongebob started bad.
Speaker 0: No it was good for kids.
Speaker 0: I think back.
Speaker 0: was it really?
Speaker 1: was it?
Speaker 1: really?
Speaker 1: did that not foster a generation of kids who run around going?
Speaker 0: it was plain and slim simple slapstick and now it's just stupid.
Speaker 1: I much prefer the Vaguely horrifying slapstick of like a ren and Stimpy or Rocco's modern life.
Speaker 0: Yes, those were far superior shows.
Speaker 0: There's still one episode of spongebob call an old one called band geeks that makes me laugh every time I watch it.
Speaker 0: I still recommend that one But that could just be me could be.
Speaker 1: I've never seen it, but I do like some dumb things.
Speaker 1: I can't really cast aspersions here.
Speaker 0: I'm getting a look of approval from someone else in the room.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah We have a studio audience, too.
Speaker 1: So the other important thing is are you gonna do this on a schedule or not?
Speaker 0: I would prefer a schedule vastly because Neither of us works well without one.
Speaker 1: So how rapidly do you want the show to go from horrible to listenable to good?
Speaker 1: um Cuz it's got to be horrible.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I know that I mean Scott and I recorded geek nights for a couple of months before we even put that shit on the Internet.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you I listened to some of those episodes this prep for this But I pray to the gods that no one ever actually finds those though they are still on the Internet.
Speaker 0: There's a reason I never went into your old archives and bothered.
Speaker 1: I Assumed the thing is our old archives start months after we actually started.
Speaker 0: Oh, I thought I would just feel all this secondhand proxy embarrassment for you, too And I wouldn't be able to bear it now.
Speaker 1: the old episodes were not great But they were at least listenable.
Speaker 1: the beta episodes We're listened to by maybe five or six people and most of the feedback was really This is what you're doing.
Speaker 1: This is this is what happens when you leave college.
Speaker 0: That's kind of what I've been anticipating.
Speaker 0: only when you leave college is replaced with when you turn 30.
Speaker 1: You know, I was hanging out of packs with a bunch of cool people but we hung out with something who was someone who was cool, but in their early 20s and People who are in the early 20s look the same as us mostly But they exhibit an exuberance that I think has gone from my brittle old man bones.
Speaker 0: I know that feeling a Little too well, yeah, we're old.
Speaker 1: listen kids tone down the exuberance.
Speaker 0: Stop it.
Speaker 0: You're making us feel bad.
Speaker 1: You make us feel bad.
Speaker 1: one because I go to bed while you're still Exuberating and two you fucking hit me in the face with your elbow when you're exuberating.
Speaker 0: Also, I enjoy going to bed while you're still exuberating and that makes me feel bad.
Speaker 1: Poor Scott at PAX.
Speaker 1: It was like 1045 and he were playing pen Dante.
Speaker 1: He just lays down at the table.
Speaker 1: He's like, I think I need to go to bed.
Speaker 1: I think I'm fading.
Speaker 0: 1045 Jesus.
Speaker 1: That was pretty much the reaction I was going for there, okay good.
Speaker 1: so the way we got at least reasonably competent at this the less the listener will agree is that we set a schedule that was Way way more than we could possibly reasonably expect to achieve and we forced ourselves to do it no matter fucking what?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've heard that four nights a week every week for Four and a half years.
Speaker 0: That's pretty crazy.
Speaker 1: And uh, you know what we did the show no matter what.
Speaker 1: there were nights Where I didn't sleep.
Speaker 1: I stayed up all night editing and then we went to work the next day.
Speaker 0: and that is how you not Suck.
Speaker 1: that is how you not suck.
Speaker 1: pick your schedule never ever skip an episode for anything not even packs.
Speaker 1: Well, if you're at a convention, that's fine.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay thing is conventions didn't get in our way too much because conventions We'd always leave on Thursday.
Speaker 1: So we just time it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we used to record ahead when we were gone for Otacon for the week we would record four fucking extra episodes.
Speaker 0: The illusion is broken.
Speaker 1: We would record so far ahead.
Speaker 1: It was ridiculous.
Speaker 0: so much for that actually recorded at night thing.
Speaker 1: Well, we were to record at night just at night ahead.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah sure.
Speaker 1: That's what we do.
Speaker 0: last time I was here.
Speaker 0: It was daylight.
Speaker 1: Just want to say that It was daylight, but it was still like seven something o'clock.
Speaker 0: That's not night.
Speaker 0: That's not evening.
Speaker 0: It was evening.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: We're old now.
Speaker 1: night is when you feel night.
Speaker 1: So, uh, do you have any news to bring to the table or are we doing the lounge?
Speaker 1: the lounge we can talk about whatever But if we do the normal geek nights format, we each have to bring one item of interest to the table for discussion.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I've got some gay news.
Speaker 0: Gay news sad gay news, but gay news.
Speaker 1: Oh, there was some good news.
Speaker 1: today I think two or three more states.
Speaker 1: gay marriage got on overturned.
Speaker 0: Well, I always I always preferred the bad news first.
Speaker 0: cuz then I leave a feeling happier when I've gotten the good news Rules against gay marriage bans in two states.
Speaker 1: Yeah Louisiana sucks though, Louisiana quote the US appeals court issued a scathing unequivocal ruling.
Speaker 1: yes Alright, so what Louisiana do to ruin all this?
Speaker 0: they upheld their their matter Meh, their marriage ban in their federal court with this chromogeny old judge who basically recycled every horrible thing that's ever been said about the gay quote-unquote lifestyle and Summed everything up by quoting the dissension from the Supreme Court's.
Speaker 1: Wow That's like copying off of the dumb kid in class.
Speaker 0: Yes saying that was the precedent not the actual case, but the dissension.
Speaker 0: He finished everything saying every other judge before me was wrong.
Speaker 0: I am right gay people are like Polygamous or whatever.
Speaker 1: the other thing I don't like is so maybe there's there's a couple ways to go.
Speaker 1: maybe Somehow he is actually on the right side and he is trying to force the Supreme Court into the final corner.
Speaker 1: There's a tiny possibility of that.
Speaker 0: I sometimes worry about that because the Supreme Court is ultra fucked up right now.
Speaker 1: Maybe he wants to go down in history as the last judge to stand against this.
Speaker 0: Maybe he's old and shitty and from Louisiana.
Speaker 1: But I repeat myself, ooh, I didn't get the dirty look I was expecting.
Speaker 0: sorry, I wasn't looking at you not you.
Speaker 1: No, I'm getting approval for the statement.
Speaker 1: I stand by it.
Speaker 1: then So, yeah, I got some news.
Speaker 1: apparently nerds in their basements tried to stage a gamer gate protest at PAX because as far as I can tell and it took me a While to figure out what gamer gate was.
Speaker 0: Did they try to state it from their basements?
Speaker 1: I think they did because there wasn't actually a protest.
Speaker 1: I saw all these tweets and then this one guy posted is like there's gonna be a false flag.
Speaker 1: Zoe Quinn is gonna be at PAX and then she's gonna stage an assault in a hallway And then they're gonna set it up to where she's gonna come out on stage at the closing ceremonies and Gabe and Tycho are gonna agree with her and unify and say that gamer is now a bad word and they're gonna drop the names of prominent youtubers who were collaborating and blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: and I Think what's beautiful is that even reddit was like, yeah, that's a bit much and that shit got deleted.
Speaker 1: It's like when even reddit backs off from you, I think you got trouble.
Speaker 0: reddit is just swimming and swill though They don't get a pass for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah thing is reddit.
Speaker 1: What does someone say?
Speaker 1: reddit is like 4chan, but it doesn't realize it's the bad guy, of course not.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, I'm a hundred percent advocate of free speech even really shitty speech.
Speaker 1: So I kind of am glad that reddit exists.
Speaker 1: as horrifying as it is I am not in favor of some of the threats that they've supported Well supported or well like who which they the people in subreddits or reddit itself as an organization.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm sure that some people who frequent reddit have taken have partaken in making those threads while people on subreddits Ah, the people who have used the seven train have then threatened people.
Speaker 0: That's not what I'm trying to say.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't support the threat.
Speaker 1: Well, welcome to the lion's den.
Speaker 0: Judith on the spot Beauty I'm gonna throw this iPhone at you.
Speaker 0: I Know it's your iPhone.
Speaker 0: That's why it's okay.
Speaker 1: Ah Remember they can't hear our studio audience.
Speaker 0: I know they can't.
Speaker 1: so you know how to use a microphone.
Speaker 0: I'm talking into it.
Speaker 1: Yep Do you know?
Speaker 1: do you know why?
Speaker 1: like why you have to point it directly at your face?
Speaker 0: Cuz it doesn't pick up all this other shit.
Speaker 0: cuz why would I want anyone want to hear that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, most of the microphones you use don't have that power.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know that this is like a good microphone.
Speaker 1: It is a really good.
Speaker 1: Well, there are good microphones that also don't have that power.
Speaker 0: Wouldn't everybody want that power?
Speaker 1: No, because that power causes other problems too.
Speaker 1: For example, it allows me to have the smooth radio voice and adds a ton of bass to my voice Which can be good or bad on the circumstances.
Speaker 1: It causes some other distortion and if I move my head around at all, I'll suddenly get really quiet.
Speaker 0: There's bass in your voice ever.
Speaker 1: If I do this there is Listeners out there can hear.
Speaker 1: the thing is when you have a microphone like this It will.
Speaker 1: actually there's something called the proximity effect.
Speaker 1: So the closer you get the deeper it gets.
Speaker 1: That's why Howard Stern.
Speaker 1: So it sounds so much more amazing and manly on the radio than he ever has in real life.
Speaker 0: I just listened to your dash con episode.
Speaker 1: No, yeah, cuz I'm not doing it all the way.
Speaker 1: I stay back to have a more naturalistic tone.
Speaker 1: But if I eat this microphone, you'll see you have to do a whole show like that sometime, you know I've tried.
Speaker 1: the problem is that if I get loud when I'm this close, I'll blow it out.
Speaker 0: I'll be too loud and don't get loud and make Scott be the loud one.
Speaker 1: So I did.
Speaker 1: the problem is we yell you don't look at these waveforms You've got I know I've been watching them tiny little Judith tiny little Judith And I'm just fucking yelling into the microphone.
Speaker 1: In fact, I've got compressors like holding my voice back from its full fucking loudness here.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: It's my diminutive feminine And The compressor that is applied here because this is Scott's voice profile is just the patriarchy holding you back.
Speaker 0: So that's what it looks like.
Speaker 1: That's what it looks like.
Speaker 1: It's a dynamic processor right there.
Speaker 1: I wonder if I can show you.
Speaker 1: I can show you what it's doing.
Speaker 1: So you kids at home won't be able to learn this.
Speaker 1: but here's what's going on.
Speaker 1: There is a path in our voices in it.
Speaker 1: in the old days when we did geek nights It was actually way harder because we didn't have good multi-track editing software.
Speaker 1: So we record like a stereo waveform and then I would manually like run all these filters and ran a script.
Speaker 1: But you with the power of audition need to learn all this stuff works and basically make a filter that will work kind of live.
Speaker 1: So you don't have to ever like after the show like listen to it and go.
Speaker 1: Oh, maybe I should make that part louder that part quieter.
Speaker 1: You have a thing that just does it all automatically.
Speaker 1: So you can do the same process that the Daily Show does.
Speaker 1: Daily Show records live Mixings live and they go right quote to tape meaning what they recorded is pretty much as what goes on the air, right?
Speaker 0: Okay, so you can do the same thing with audio and you have one tailored to each of your voices exactly.
Speaker 1: So basically each one of these tracks I can apply different effects to and effects generally take effect live.
Speaker 1: So for example, if I click here These are the effects applied to my voice The top line is the actual volume of my voice just as I'm talking as it's recorded.
Speaker 1: if it turns right here I got too loud and I clipped it.
Speaker 1: I wasn't able to clip it because I set it up.
Speaker 1: So awesomely.
Speaker 0: Anyway, don't try again.
Speaker 1: And down here is the end result.
Speaker 1: see how it's louder and more uniform.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm the filters make that happen.
Speaker 1: So if someone's listening like that, you got that waveform there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I see it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it looks like vomit.
Speaker 1: So the first thing I got going on here you want to learn about noise gates.
Speaker 1: So what this is doing is this it's a graph showing like as the volume increases by one decibel In the actual signal.
Speaker 1: Well, how much will it increase in the output signal?
Speaker 1: Like what's actually being recorded?
Speaker 1: So you see it's doing nothing up here, but down here it gets quieter faster as it gets quiet.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm that removes you in the background from my channel.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I won't pick up you in the background like making extra noise or whatever.
Speaker 1: Like all this extra stuff is getting rid of like it also gets rid of like Little weird noises that I make with my mouth when I lean back.
Speaker 0: Like that those are the worst noises.
Speaker 1: stop and I like those noises.
Speaker 1: So the second filter that we got going on here which takes place after that That is called a compressor.
Speaker 1: So above 20 decibels the louder I get if I get too louder The wave only gets one louder.
Speaker 1: So I'm basically cutting my volume down at half the rate from what it normally would get to.
Speaker 1: In general compressors just even the sound out and make you sound awesome when in doubt.
Speaker 1: Compress more because while it'll sound maybe a little artificial and a little kind of radio II That's why radio sounds so consistent.
Speaker 1: You just compress the ever-living fuck out of it.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 1: And the other thing you need to use is mastering.
Speaker 1: this will just make shit easy.
Speaker 1: just drag this stuff around and listen to like a recording your voice and find the parts that are Loud or weird or like.
Speaker 1: there's probably one area of your voice that sounds annoying When you're listening to it Like you're listening to it in headphones.
Speaker 1: Find that part and get rid of it like here.
Speaker 1: I raised that part because that's the one good part of my voice right there.
Speaker 1: that little bit.
Speaker 1: that little bit is good rim And that is a bit like bass at the top there.
Speaker 0: Where's that whole missing singing range?
Speaker 1: Well, I could.
Speaker 1: I could you want to add autotune.
Speaker 1: I Could auto tune this episode right the fuck now And actually make yourself sing a tune.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is it'll only get me close.
Speaker 1: It'll get me out of the nearest note.
Speaker 1: That might not work out so well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, please don't try.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: in music theory class I sang in falsetto because there's only way I could hit notes.
Speaker 0: you sang.
Speaker 1: I had to.
Speaker 1: I had to sing my thesis.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're poor teacher.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got to whistle after I was told by the teacher that I in fact I'm not one of the people who can say and by the people he meant everyone can sing.
Speaker 1: Hummed it and I harmonica did.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, so we have these filters that are applied live.
Speaker 1: So normally if we have a guest on the show, I'll just make like an extra template.
Speaker 1: So I have this whole template already saved.
Speaker 1: so I cue it up.
Speaker 1: Look it even says like rim Scott bumpers sound effects Microphone three.
Speaker 1: for if you use one of the weird microphones in my nickname be bumpers next time you want to be on bumpers?
Speaker 1: Bumpers has no effect.
Speaker 1: sounded though.
Speaker 1: That's the trouble.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just like the word and we do more complicated stuff but you can learn that later.
Speaker 1: the gist is right.
Speaker 1: record yourself talking and Get the levels right to where you don't clip the microphone in the mixer themselves Like you never clip here and then you're gonna have to do something that's gonna feel really awful.
Speaker 1: You have to listen to your own voice on a loop like a few sentences and just listen to it on a loop for hours Fiddling with all these knobs.
Speaker 0: I was afraid you were gonna say something like that.
Speaker 1: That is the only way to make a thing sound good.
Speaker 0: Well, that's one way to desensitize Desensitize yourself to how stupid you sound.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: Everyone sounds both stupid and awesome on the radio.
Speaker 1: You sound stupid because you're not used to hearing your own voice and you sound awesome because actually most people sound awesome.
Speaker 0: Most people really.
Speaker 1: yeah, most people sound just great if you put it.
Speaker 1: if you record into a little bit of processing this sound Awesome.
Speaker 0: All right Audition is magic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll just an audition like friendship is magic.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: so things of the day Notice how.
Speaker 1: what happened there is that we stopped recording and then we started again.
Speaker 1: Yeah for a split second Yeah, so in the old we do this mostly now just because it's easier to edit.
Speaker 1: but in the old days We would try to record the whole show in one go and that's good.
Speaker 1: But if you're gonna have a format where you switch between topics It's good to have a pause there so you can like get your shit together Like pull up the web page that talks about the thing that you're gonna talk about.
Speaker 0: make sense Yeah, except I didn't know I was gonna be here.
Speaker 0: So I don't have a thing exactly.
Speaker 1: but if you want to sound smart on a podcast the best thing to do if you're talking about a thing have the Wikipedia of that thing just up in front of you so you can say things like like Scott will be like, oh Yeah, it was in like 1993 94 and you can be like.
Speaker 1: actually it was in 1991.
Speaker 0: I knew that's what you guys were doing.
Speaker 1: That is that is how everyone does it.
Speaker 1: everyone who's smart on the radio or a podcast just has Wikipedia in front of them And if they're doing a video they have a teleprompter.
Speaker 0: Words from the wise.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course right now.
Speaker 1: I'm just looking at Twitter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: It might as well be.
Speaker 1: oh, they're looking at a phone now.
Speaker 1: We've broke the magic's broken shows derailing rapidly.
Speaker 0: I don't get a computer like you do.
Speaker 0: All I saw on that phone just then was the word rapist.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I want if I want to talk about Whatever that is What?
Speaker 0: You guys that's the word I saw.
Speaker 1: there's trouble going on in the studio here.
Speaker 1: so I recommend you find some songs that either Don't have copyright encumbrance or get someone to write them for you or steal something that no one will ever recognize.
Speaker 0: I think I'm more comfortable with the first two.
Speaker 1: Yeah We have permission for our opening song and I will not tell you where the other songs came from.
Speaker 1: Luckily no, I don't think anyone's ever actually figured it out.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: This is our bit OC do not steal.
Speaker 1: Okay, so you know about our things of the day, right?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Can you think of a thing?
Speaker 1: What's the most awesome thing you've seen in the last 24 hours?
Speaker 0: Oh Jesus I don't know the last 24 hours.
Speaker 1: Oh originally it was didn't have to be a link It would just be like yeah totally saw a guy pass out on the train and mrs.
Speaker 1: Stop and that was hilarious.
Speaker 0: Saw a baby bird being fed by its mom went to the US Open last night for the first time ever despite the fact that I Live in Flushing.
Speaker 1: Oh, dude.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that sounds awesome.
Speaker 1: I really like tennis.
Speaker 0: Serena Williams just kind of ate her opponent.
Speaker 1: Yeah literally I Was making a vore joke not a sex joke.
Speaker 0: you you happen to be talking to a gay thing over here So I thought you were being derogatory.
Speaker 1: No, I was not being derogatory.
Speaker 1: She's fucking amazing.
Speaker 0: Yes, she is.
Speaker 1: I love tennis.
Speaker 1: I love tennis a lot.
Speaker 1: Well, we have to segregate Actual sexes because testosterone is literally just like hacks mode in tennis is it so is?
Speaker 1: I love the fact that women's tennis is Just as awesome as men's tennis just as beastly.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: There was no mercy.
Speaker 1: I Also love how there was a heat wave going on.
Speaker 1: Some of the matches I watched on the internet Got pretty sad toward the end.
Speaker 1: and is it bad if my bad person for the fact that I like watching tennis matches that start Strong and get increasingly sad as people wear out into a long deuce?
Speaker 0: Isn't that every long tennis match ever?
Speaker 1: But by the end like I forget who I was watching.
Speaker 1: but I saw this highlight clip where the serve was made.
Speaker 1: It was returned derpally like burp and the receiver of the return just stood there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it just went by and he totally could have just if he just like run a little bit He could have gotten it.
Speaker 0: that happened a few times last night.
Speaker 0: It was like really frustrating to watch.
Speaker 1: I love watching that because he knew it too.
Speaker 1: Like I saw like you see him turn to turn and look at the ball and then he's like He does a Daria.
Speaker 0: He just stands there puts his hand out a little bit.
Speaker 0: No, we were watching a jokovich vs.
Speaker 0: Murray, which is a really big match and it was going on for ever.
Speaker 0: They were constantly tying and we eventually left because it was midnight and we chalked it up to whoever feels old first We'll be losing tonight.
Speaker 1: one of my co-workers was apparently also at that game and they watched it to the end and When asked if that was worth it The answer was no, but I'm gonna say yes to anyone else who asks me that.
Speaker 0: Oh the secrets out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think he knows.
Speaker 1: I do geek nights.
Speaker 1: So my thing of the day if you follow me on Twitter you might have seen this.
Speaker 1: We we went to a secret restaurant in Seattle after Pax two years in a row and Apparently no one who goes to Pax knows about this place.
Speaker 0: That's where you took the pictures of the ice cream.
Speaker 1: Yes So the internet might be able to figure it out.
Speaker 1: Scott ate so much that he sounded like he was dying when he was laying In bed.
Speaker 0: how much food can Scott fit in him?
Speaker 1: Scott cannot eat as much food as the rest of us and as Scott is said an old geek nights.
Speaker 1: if he eats too much Food the food comes out in every direction and every path.
Speaker 1: He laid in bed and he was just made all night.
Speaker 1: he was like.
Speaker 0: Just have the worst image now of Scott bleeding ice cream from his eyeballs.
Speaker 0: So what a terrible.
Speaker 1: do the bathroom and he comes back he's like guys that bathroom.
Speaker 1: And then I remembered that the previous year we had the bathroom had also been awesome.
Speaker 1: So I go in there and I made two vines of this.
Speaker 1: what's going on in the men's bathroom?
Speaker 1: Is there?
Speaker 1: is there are two old analog TVs or like one one like old LCD and one like really old CRT and they're playing a loop of footage of like fire hoses and waterfalls and kids playing in sprinklers and Like geysers and meanwhile ride of the Valkyries is just looping.
Speaker 0: That is awesome.
Speaker 1: Never again.
Speaker 0: a shy bladder Is that before you make it to the urinal or the stall or so it's there on the TVs Behind the urinals.
Speaker 1: there is a mirror in front of each urinal.
Speaker 1: So you are guaranteed to be able to see that TV.
Speaker 0: So it's not like a test like as soon as you walk in you have to run because all of a sudden it's been made.
Speaker 1: There's a thing.
Speaker 1: I don't know you probably haven't ever experienced this but a lot of guys Can't pee if there's another guy in the room that they're in any way intimidated by and
Speaker 0: say I've ever Experienced
Speaker 1: men experience this shy bladder thing like it like ask people on the internet and like a lot of people Will often just like clam up and they can't pee if someone's nearby.
Speaker 0: We don't have the whole urinal thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what urinals are amazing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they look pretty easy.
Speaker 1: In fact, you know what is better than urinal just a trough in bars.
Speaker 1: We'll just have like a trough.
Speaker 1: It's just like this long tub And you know what it means.
Speaker 1: there is never a line.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know people like to make that joke about ladies all going to the bathroom together But really it's not cuz.
Speaker 1: the line is like four years long.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that shit sucks.
Speaker 1: Maybe if we had gender-neutral bathrooms, we could fix that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why don't we just have the urinal bathroom and the non urinal bathroom?
Speaker 1: That will work.
Speaker 1: and then the baby bathroom in case anyone has a baby.
Speaker 0: Yes, please.
Speaker 0: Can we have those?
Speaker 1: I got to listen to a side a father and his like Just starting to talk.
Speaker 1: daughter doing their like doing their like.
Speaker 1: kids can't deal with the bathroom.
Speaker 1: yet in the stall next to me.
Speaker 1: well, I was pooping at packs and they were really loud and He was like being funny and like okay, dude.
Speaker 1: But basically I got to experience this whole thing auditorily while I was sitting in the cell next to them and it was just really weird and awkward because he's like All right.
Speaker 1: Now you get to flush it.
Speaker 1: She's like, yeah That's how you get a kid pumped and then you hear flush flush.
Speaker 1: No only flush once but dad flush once.
Speaker 1: Otherwise you'll fall in and it'll suck.
Speaker 1: He was like it'll suck you away And she's like really he's like really.
Speaker 1: and then she got stone silence.
Speaker 1: Like, you know that moment when a kid like is told something that you think is funny, but they're taking seriously.
Speaker 1: Yes, like like when a kid watches Beetlejuice for the first time and they don't realize there's a comedy.
Speaker 0: That was me on an airplane at age five Terrified.
Speaker 1: that was also me watching Beetlejuice and project eco.
Speaker 0: Apparently I freaked out so hard that they had to subdue me.
Speaker 0: I was five years old and on my way to Vegas Wow, you started young.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I just picture five-year-old you with like a cigar and just a pile of poker chips.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and this little stuffed animal of Roger Rabbit in the seat next to me Living it up, you know when I was really when I first saw Roger Rabbit, like I really liked it But I also took it way serious.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep that part with this with the shoe.
Speaker 1: Yep that part with the shoe, which actually was just a straight-up murder.
Speaker 0: Forget that part man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and at the end when the crazy eyes come out, I about flipped a brick.
Speaker 0: It's Doc Brown.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment the book club book is a canticle for Liebowitz.
Speaker 1: Scott read part of it because he was on a plane.
Speaker 1: I got to read it again because I forgot most of the allegory at this point.
Speaker 1: So thanks Scott.
Speaker 1: I read five fucking novels the time it took you to get two-thirds of the way through Liebowitz.
Speaker 0: You're just a better person.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Also, you should read a canticle for Liebowitz.
Speaker 1: Why do you know what it's about?
Speaker 1: Nope, it's arguably the first or the second modern apocalypse story.
Speaker 1: Okay, as in an apocalypse caused by technology like, you know post-apocalyptic Wool style silo paranoia all those things.
Speaker 1: All right Those novels really didn't exist until nuclear Armageddon was a possibility.
Speaker 1: This is probably the first one.
Speaker 1: What year was this written in during the Cold War like the early part of the Cold War?
Speaker 0: and what makes it not suck?
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: it's not that it doesn't suck.
Speaker 1: I'm not But it's basically roughly about a guy named Liebowitz who's not in the book, he's long dead and he was just like this engineer and Because after the world got destroyed by an apocalypse his writings and like stuff about him Sort of became Legend and he was sainted by like the church that sort of picked up the ashes of the post-apocalyptic world.
Speaker 1: So st.
Speaker 1: Liebowitz and the holy artifacts like here's his box of resistors.
Speaker 1: They don't know what resistors are anymore.
Speaker 0: So this was a normal dude.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: This is a normal day now st.
Speaker 1: Liebowitz and it takes place after the apocalypse and It's the first book like that other than me.
Speaker 1: There's arguably one earlier book, but that's about zombies About zombies.
Speaker 1: Yeah zombies.
Speaker 1: That's an apocalypse story sort of like zombies and people dying and stuff zombies in before.
Speaker 1: Yeah, possibly.
Speaker 1: It's arguable.
Speaker 1: It's debatable.
Speaker 1: Okay, pretty good book.
Speaker 1: You got to know a lot about Jews and a lot about Catholics or it's really hard to understand what this is talking about.
Speaker 1: define a lot, um You would get most of the Jewish references and I think as a result you could parse the Catholicism like inside baseball.
Speaker 0: Okay, yeah, it's the Catholicism I worry about in the same way that I'm not.
Speaker 1: I'm not the most Deep person when it comes to Jewish stuff, but I remember a lot of weird Catholic inside baseball.
Speaker 1: So I was able to parse the Jewish stuff by juxtaposing it with the Catholic stuff that was happening.
Speaker 0: All right, then it's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't want to be studying any more Catholicism.
Speaker 0: I already took in our history course We were a Pax.
Speaker 1: Pax is done a bunch of videos from Pax.
Speaker 1: We coming up online as soon as I can get to it for all of you saws at Pax.
Speaker 1: That was awesome.
Speaker 1: Stay tuned for next week when we'll return with our usual hosts and I will see you kids in Singapore.
Speaker 1: if you're at the FPL show, I doubt you will be and then I will be at Pax Australia lecturing without Scott.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's gonna be me talking for an hour about like losing I guess or possibly about winning.
Speaker 1: Actually, I realized I've submitted the panel called losing in a panel called winning.
Speaker 1: So Which one they pick?
Speaker 0: I won't be there though.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna be there.
Speaker 1: You don't come to Australia.
Speaker 0: I do want to come to Australia.
Speaker 0: Can I?
Speaker 1: do you want to come to Australia to go to a gaming con and then basically fly right back?
Speaker 1: Yes Well, you know what you should try to get yourself to be a guest of Pax and then Murder someone.
Speaker 1: Okay, they're playing ticket.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Go on.
Speaker 1: I'm only going cuz I tricked my work into flying me out.
Speaker 1: I Can't afford that shit.
Speaker 0: I'm doing my part.
Speaker 0: might do it by doing art for the Australian Pokemon League for Pax this year.
Speaker 1: Oh I saw they put a call out for some stuff.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I already drew a Kangaskhan for them.
Speaker 1: Judith is apparently the most devastating gym leader in recent history.
Speaker 0: I am NOT the most devastating in recent history I am just very good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so when are you gonna?
Speaker 1: What are you gonna beat the elite four or whatever?
Speaker 0: I I will be on the elite four hopefully soon hope so.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you're gonna be the elite four.
Speaker 1: That means there's only one person better than you and that's the nine-year-old ash or whatever.
Speaker 0: No, they had some pretty awesome people.
Speaker 0: last time one of them just kind of disappeared.
Speaker 0: Not really mysteriously.
Speaker 1: He came back after it was all I was gonna say.
Speaker 1: you must have gone down victory road Like what happens to ash after that?
Speaker 0: No, our champion at PAX East last year was dressed as Lysander.
Speaker 0: Wow Yeah, you know the guy.
Speaker 1: I know the guy.
Speaker 0: I'm a little girl play with my Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Hello child.
Speaker 1: What would it mean to be immortal?
Speaker 1: I'm going to muse on this while talking to you and then give you my phone number because that's what 40 year olds do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you had to beat him.
Speaker 0: He was wearing Kanye glasses.
Speaker 1: I love out right and be like I'm walking around the game and then I'll just get a call from him like hey So about immortality, what does it mean to be alive?
Speaker 0: By the way, the professor gave me your number.
Speaker 0: I hope you don't mind.
Speaker 1: Yes, I'll be calling again.
Speaker 1: Hey little girl, you should come to my club in whatever city someday.
Speaker 1: We totally don't serve alcohol because it's a Pokemon game.
Speaker 0: All the walls are red and the floors are also red and the chairs are red.
Speaker 1: Oh and my secret base is hidden in here and all you have to do is talk to the obviously team flare person That's hanging out here.
Speaker 0: They'll send us do bat out to fight you.
Speaker 1: Sometimes they also have that dog Pokemon Whichever one is in this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what at least in the earliest Pokemon's Team Rocket would have like three Pokemon sometimes Yeah, but they're always throwing shit, yeah, but at least there's three of them.
Speaker 1: it's not just like one zoo bad It's like really team flare.
Speaker 1: You guys are the worst.
Speaker 0: if there ever can be a zoo bat there will be a zoo bat.
Speaker 1: They'll be like eight zoo bats.
Speaker 1: Oh the flock of zoo bats.
Speaker 0: But anyway, yeah packs Pokemon League will be at packs East and packs Australia.
Speaker 0: I think they're working on pack South.
Speaker 0: anyone who plays should go challenge them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, seriously packs Pokemon League and Scott will back this up is legit super legit.
Speaker 0: It's the most fun.
Speaker 0: Anyone can have playing the game.
Speaker 1: Seriously, you know, what else is legit?
Speaker 1: Pokemon rusty.
Speaker 0: That is also legit.
Speaker 1: So, yeah now that's the part where we do the main show but if we kind of already did it.
Speaker 1: So you have any questions about like what you should do podcasting that I can answer an audio form That you can answer an audio form.
Speaker 1: Yeah as opposed to like showing screens of things.
Speaker 0: Hmm, you mean like technical questions anything and what questions would you ask?
Speaker 1: This is your moments.
Speaker 0: How do you get past the whole idea of?
Speaker 0: Every other podcaster talks about this stuff like anime or games or something like those podcasts all fucking suck.
Speaker 1: Okay, that's how I got past it.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 1: Well, we originally got past it by.
Speaker 1: there really aren't podcasts.
Speaker 1: Let's do one Like the podcast weren't much of a thing yet.
Speaker 0: Wasn't that like 25 years ago or something?
Speaker 1: Scott actually arguably did the first podcast the first podcast so podcasting was not yet a term.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: We were at RIT.
Speaker 1: Scott was like I should just record audio of me talking and put it online and kind of syndicate it.
Speaker 1: and he did it.
Speaker 1: There's an episode of proto geek nights.
Speaker 1: and when Scott and I were in RIT and then he was like, that was really hard.
Speaker 1: I'm never doing that again.
Speaker 1: And then podcasting became a word.
Speaker 1: 25 years later, but seriously nowadays Listen to a pie.
Speaker 1: if you listen to any podcast not very many.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're awful.
Speaker 1: I listen to anime world order fast karate for the gentleman pseudopod and Most other podcasts are either awful or stopped.
Speaker 1: Okay I don't find most podcasts good and I think that you could do better than the vast majority of podcasts on these topics.
Speaker 0: So just bolstering yourself by telling yourself everyone else sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what.
Speaker 1: if you want it If you need to believe that go listen to some podcasts.
Speaker 0: Oh, I do that all the time.
Speaker 1: I can do that Yeah, just like find a podcast about the thing you're gonna talk about and just listen to it.
Speaker 0: Then you get angry enough fuel your show with rage.
Speaker 1: the other thing too is either differentiate yourself like do something different or get by solely on your Personalities and banters such that it doesn't matter what you're talking about.
Speaker 1: That's the fast karate style.
Speaker 0: That's something I can do too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just be funny.
Speaker 1: get it get a shit going to get a routine.
Speaker 0: I'm super funny.
Speaker 0: I mean you people have been listening to me, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Judith is a laugh riot.
Speaker 0: They've all turned it off by now.
Speaker 0: Last person just hit the X button.
Speaker 0: Screw this bitch.
Speaker 1: the self-deprecating joke.
Speaker 1: We always use is whenever we talk about the listeners.
Speaker 1: We always say well the listener will agree But we did.
Speaker 1: I just stole that from NPR.
Speaker 1: it's all politics, but they stopped.
Speaker 1: so I guess Where was the joke from The Simpsons?
Speaker 1: if you're anyone other than NPR, it's all politics.
Speaker 1: You're stealing my joke.
Speaker 0: Don't ask me Simpsons questions.
Speaker 0: What I was denied Simpsons as a child never got into it.
Speaker 1: both.
Speaker 0: I was forbidden from watching it.
Speaker 1: It is amazing to me and it should be amazing to all you young fucks out there that When The Simpsons aired on TV, a lot of parents wouldn't let their kids watch it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like that shit was controversial.
Speaker 1: You were not allowed to wear a Bart Simpson shirt to school.
Speaker 0: I watched some episodes of it now and I'm thinking What I want.
Speaker 1: your point made me turn my Bart Simpson t-shirt inside out or they would not let me in.
Speaker 0: Was he a controversial character?
Speaker 0: Is that why?
Speaker 1: Well, the shirt had the word hell on it and tiny print.
Speaker 1: Oh It was a shirt.
Speaker 1: There was Bart Simpson with a speech bubble and it said I'm Bart Simpson.
Speaker 1: Who the hell are you?
Speaker 0: I guess Who the he double hockey sticks are you?
Speaker 0: That's all it said.
Speaker 1: Also Bart said bitchin' once Those early seasons.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I think pretty much that show was controversial until South Park came out And then everything after that was just the flushing of a toilet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: Thing is Simpsons was good for at least 11 seasons and honestly New Simpsons is pretty good again.
Speaker 0: I never did get into it though, but you can.
Speaker 0: you can blame my parents for that.
Speaker 1: You know what you should do?
Speaker 1: Just take season 5 just pirate it and just watch it.
Speaker 1: It's really really funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pirating stuff is how you show your support for it, right?
Speaker 1: I don't think the Simpsons need my support.
Speaker 1: I think the Simpsons is going to run for the rest of my life probably Hopefully Adventure Time will too.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: No, I don't want to say something like that.
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 1: I want it to.
Speaker 1: I want Adventure Time to be like that comic in the newspaper Where the characters just all aged in real time and it went on for fucking ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah But American TV for better or for worse has this way of pile driving shows into the ground once they reach a certain age until They're just not the same.
Speaker 1: Adventure Time has gotten way past the point where that usually happens and has only gotten better.
Speaker 0: It's gotten much more mature.
Speaker 1: Yes It's changed and not gotten worse.
Speaker 1: name another show that has changed for the better or at least changed for the same level of quality But being different pleading the fifth at the moment.
Speaker 1: Yeah name any show Show.
Speaker 1: I bet a show on American TV that changed and the change was for the good.
Speaker 1: I could probably come up with something I can name after this show is over.
Speaker 1: I can name one.
Speaker 1: Whoa?
Speaker 1: No, you have to say it out loud now.
Speaker 0: No No, I think I can come up with something when the pressure is not on.
Speaker 1: is what I thought you were meaning You were about to say something that would piss off tumblr or whatever.
Speaker 0: No, I love pissing off tumblr.
Speaker 1: Ah, that's a hobby.
Speaker 0: They forgive me cuz I'm probably gay.
Speaker 1: my one See in a way cishet white males are more oppressed Because don't even don't even start because if I say something racist and sexist the internet jumps all down my throat.
Speaker 1: But then if I get reverse racism or white slave then suddenly remember the iPhone I was gonna throw at you.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be a wheeling chair this time.
Speaker 1: But there's my.
Speaker 1: one example is South Park because the first like half of the first season was just little kids swearing and Then the show got good Like the first episode.
Speaker 1: I also like those episodes.
Speaker 1: but the show changed and got way better.
Speaker 0: in my opinion It got more political but in a good way, yeah, I love our.
Speaker 1: South Park Really does a good job of taking the piss out of any argument no matter how stupid it is.
Speaker 1: I Am hard-pressed to name any American show that changing got better.
Speaker 0: No, no, that's a big challenge.
Speaker 1: Seinfeld got incrementally better for a long time just as the craft got better.
Speaker 1: But that wasn't a change in the way the show was.
Speaker 0: Yes It wasn't like we're gonna go dark like Adventure Time did when you put the word American as a qualifier for that then I can't come up with anything.
Speaker 1: I'm trying what it was the anime Anime that changed for the better at any point.
Speaker 1: No, they all got worse.
Speaker 1: They all got destroyed.
Speaker 1: Sailor Moon I guess changing got better in s but that's because they brought out the good Sailor Senji and the show got fucked up about Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: You know, I promise Scott I wouldn't shit all over that show anymore on the show because every time I complain about it Like why are you even watching it?
Speaker 1: That shows awful.
Speaker 0: I've watched more of it than you have now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you have and you know what?
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna rewatch all the old Sailor Moon again.
Speaker 0: I'm doing both of those things.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'm a better fan.
Speaker 1: Tenchi muyo just got worse and then worse again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then somehow worse up to the third power and in between they brought out.
Speaker 1: Uh, gee But tenchi muyo gxp We didn't even have the characters.
Speaker 1: I liked and somehow was also awful.
Speaker 0: I gave up after worse again.
Speaker 1: Where's the guy?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was tenchi in Tokyo burned me the worst.
Speaker 0: I think that was the worst.
Speaker 1: that was the one where that was a put time in my life where I was also kind of Invested in tenchi.
Speaker 1: There's a thing same here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those are dark time.
Speaker 1: I felt betrayed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like wow.
Speaker 1: These are awesome characters.
Speaker 1: This is an awesome show and it's a little perverted but in that funny way that like Ron mo was a little pervert.
Speaker 1: Yep, the clothing like very few shows in that era animated clothing like that thing.
Speaker 1: Oh my goddess was the only other show.
Speaker 0: That's a good example.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then you know what notice tenchi in Tokyo.
Speaker 1: Everyone's wearing bicycle shorts because they just asked to animate that shit anymore and the animation style has been chopped not the style.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: This animation itself has been chopped to shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I said style because a long time ago I was still a high school student and I was complaining about the quality of the animation Descending into the pits of hell for tenchi in Tokyo and this Defensive guy was like that's just a style change.
Speaker 0: if you can't handle that kind of thing Then you shouldn't be complaining about it.
Speaker 1: I saw that same argument this morning about Sailor Moon crystal.
Speaker 1: They were like no the transformation sequences are CG.
Speaker 1: So they have to look worse.
Speaker 1: I was like wow, you're wrong on every point.
Speaker 0: Why did they choose a medium that has to look worse?
Speaker 0: then if that's your argument?
Speaker 1: Because it's a deconstruction is the latest argument.
Speaker 1: Everything everything ever is now a deconstruction.
Speaker 1: I think was Mike or someone who said that deconstruction.
Speaker 1: the definition of that is I swear.
Speaker 1: I'm not watching porn.
Speaker 0: Sailor Moon is just the construction.
Speaker 1: It's just the thing but it's like half finish.
Speaker 1: It's like they built one wall.
Speaker 1: They're like, yeah, fuck it good enough Just slap some eyes on it and in a gate mouth.
Speaker 1: I Still can't come up with any anime that it made a change and got better.
Speaker 0: No, you mentioned Ranma.
Speaker 0: I was a fan of a lot of Takahashi things and yeah, that's a terrible example.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those shows didn't get better.
Speaker 1: They just never change.
Speaker 1: That was the opposite problem.
Speaker 1: by never changing.
Speaker 1: They eventually ran out of shit to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they didn't get endings.
Speaker 1: I think Adventure Time would have ended if they had not continued to mature it and keep changing like the entire timber of the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it would have spongebobbed.
Speaker 1: I'm hard-pressed to agree with you because as far as I'm concerned spongebob spongebob the first sponging that ever Bob Like.
Speaker 1: I watched an episode of that show and I could summarize it as yeah.
Speaker 1: And then credits.
Speaker 0: there was some slightly more clever humor in those older ones.
Speaker 0: Maybe you and I have slightly different senses of humor.
Speaker 0: Maybe I was an animation student.
Speaker 0: I did like the anvils falling and all that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I got that from like Monty Python animation.
Speaker 0: I don't think that's a fair comparison.
Speaker 1: I think that is a fair compare.
Speaker 1: No, it's not fair because Monty Python when I was that age was the funniest thing in the world.
Speaker 1: You know what.
Speaker 1: watching it again today.
Speaker 1: It is still fucking hilarious.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only reason I don't laugh at is because I've seen everything they've ever done like a hundred times over the course of my life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have to usually wait about five years in between watching the Holy Grail.
Speaker 1: I remember the first time I watched the Holy Grail.
Speaker 1: I remember laughing so hard that I missed like entire scenes.
Speaker 0: Yes, it was the same for me.
Speaker 0: I was at Lisa's house on the couch as a high school student.
Speaker 0: She just put it on being like.
Speaker 0: this is going to be the funniest thing you've ever seen in your whole life Yep, for the longest time.
Speaker 1: I ignored it.
Speaker 1: My dad was like you should watch this movie.
Speaker 1: I was like whatever dad whatever.
Speaker 1: and Then yeah, like I was laughing so hard it hurts.
Speaker 0: It looks old and it looks British and it looks live-action.
Speaker 0: How could that be funny?
Speaker 1: Granted I've realized a lot of kids today like don't even like like I almost said new kids on the block Kids in the hall or all like like 90s stand-up comedians or anything.
Speaker 0: Are you so old?
Speaker 1: I am really old.
Speaker 1: I remember watching like a young Janine Garofalo and a young Steven Wright doing comedy on TV.
Speaker 0: I don't even know who those people are Wow.
Speaker 1: Sorry Wow Steven Wright, okay.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do a Steven Wright joke.
Speaker 1: This is what it.
Speaker 0: despite his best joke Did I just lose a seven-year listener?
Speaker 1: So Finally finished.
Speaker 1: the dictionary turns out.
Speaker 1: the zebra did it.
Speaker 1: That's Steven Wright.
Speaker 1: What was his other joke?
Speaker 1: one time I was walking through and he ended a night with this.
Speaker 1: one time so I walked out into an alley and I look up and I see two kittens and the kittens jumped out a window did a triple backflip and landed on a box and I looked at him.
Speaker 1: I said wow if that just happened I'm lost.
Speaker 0: Sorry.
Speaker 1: All of this is just like just we would talk like that completely deadpan.
Speaker 1: That might not even be the joke, but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: He would just say things like this.
Speaker 1: and that's the joke That works.
Speaker 1: That's the joke.
Speaker 0: that dictionary zebra thing almost sounded like a dad joke.
Speaker 1: You mean an uncle joke either one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, uncle joke is better.
Speaker 1: I prefer uncle joke mostly because of the Teen Titans go cache.
Speaker 1: I have another listener who just gets every time I mentioned two times ago Like he flips his shit about how bad and disrespectful that show it was better than the first one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: Everything is better than the first Teen Titans.
Speaker 1: That was such like animu wannabe crap like it had sweat drops.
Speaker 1: They were like, what are the kids into these days?
Speaker 1: I don't know anime.
Speaker 1: What's anime?
Speaker 1: So take our show draw it worse add sweat drops and we're good to go.
Speaker 0: Everybody's head randomly gets giant at a silly scene.
Speaker 1: It's called Cheebification.
Speaker 1: I learned that from the internet.
Speaker 1: So do you want you need to animate that shit?
Speaker 0: There was certainly an air of desperation to the Teen Titans art style at the very least.
Speaker 1: The worst thing was it would alternate between super bad comedy and super bad like ultra serial drama.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like they were kind of star fires drama with Beast Boy and everybody.
Speaker 1: They all love each other and Tara betrayed them.
Speaker 1: and oh my gosh.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it almost seemed like they were trying to go dark like Batman the animated series.
Speaker 0: ish.
Speaker 1: But then they would go chibi with sweat drops like the next scene.
Speaker 0: No, I tried I couldn't take it seriously.
Speaker 1: I couldn't even watch it.
Speaker 1: It was painful to watch.
Speaker 0: I can take Teen Titans go seriously.
Speaker 1: Teen Titans go has the bonus point that Raven has killed a lot of people And that is the primary reason I like that show.
Speaker 0: I Think she's my favorite.
Speaker 1: She is definitely my favorite but Beast Boy is my second favorite.
Speaker 1: Beast Boy Yeah, because Beast Boy is actually kind of adorable.
Speaker 0: he actually has like the cutest voice.
Speaker 0: I don't know who does his voice, but I haven't heard it anywhere else.
Speaker 0: I don't think he's also animated.
Speaker 1: really funny.
Speaker 1: Like there's one episode where the second the elevator and he really has to pee.
Speaker 1: The way they animate him having to pee is one of the funnier things I've seen in my life.
Speaker 0: Didn't he turn into animals?
Speaker 0: couldn't he just turn into a dog and piss in a corner?
Speaker 1: Well, so he just does piss in the corner, but he doesn't turn into anything.
Speaker 1: I thought why didn't he turn into like a bird?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then do what birds do?
Speaker 0: just shit on everything.
Speaker 1: Yes, let it go works that way.
Speaker 1: I think he has to pee like the people come with him.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: I like.
Speaker 0: I don't know because he doesn't transform He just pees he turned into a littler bird with the pee amount.
Speaker 0: stay the same.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that's the kind of question that keeps me up at night.
Speaker 0: And now I know all right.
Speaker 1: I think you can do a podcast just fine.
Speaker 0: So, thank you.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Monday's gaming Tuesday's anime comic Wednesday's and indiscriminate Thursday's.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: Wow that just happened.