Speaker 0: I feel like it's Tigress and Euphrates season suddenly.
Speaker 1: How is that a season?
Speaker 0: I feel like that's what happens.
Speaker 1: Spring, summer, fall, went to Tigress and Euphrates.
Speaker 0: You know, if those were the four seasons, I would have a pretty good life going on.
Speaker 0: I think what happened is just that because we taught some people how to play and we did a live stream the other weekend, and then the following weekend, more friends came out and we just played it because we all know how to play.
Speaker 0: I also kind of got hustled in that game.
Speaker 0: Emily beat me in a game that we played with Phil and Jay the other night.
Speaker 0: And basically what happened was, the first game that we played, I won the game and crushed everybody.
Speaker 0: It was partly because Jay attacked me and I just happened to have four green tiles in my hand.
Speaker 1: It just happened.
Speaker 0: Like they were there, I got attacked, I was like, "Well...".
Speaker 1: You didn't see the attack coming?
Speaker 0: I did not expect the attack at that time.
Speaker 1: See, that's the thing.
Speaker 1: When I play Tigress and Euphrates, I basically see the future.
Speaker 1: Because every...
Speaker 0: Well, if you can see the future, you didn't see the future of me winning.
Speaker 1: People only have two actions, right?
Speaker 1: So you can't really surprise anyone.
Speaker 1: It's pretty easy to see every possible conflict that could happen on your turn.
Speaker 0: Well, you should be clear.
Speaker 0: You can't necessarily predict what people will do, but you can narrow it down to.
Speaker 0: there's only a few things they can do.
Speaker 1: But at least in a four player game it's harder, but in a two player game it's ridiculously easy.
Speaker 0: It's more that in this attack, it was a strong, augmented attack from a hand that happened to be repulsed by an equally lucky strong defense from the hand.
Speaker 0: The kingdoms themselves were not that powerful in either direction.
Speaker 0: It was pretty even.
Speaker 0: But then the next game, I was winning hand over fist.
Speaker 0: Just hand over fist.
Speaker 0: And then I attack Emily.
Speaker 0: And if I won that conflict, I would have won the game mathematically.
Speaker 0: There was nothing anyone could have done to stop me.
Speaker 1: But she had six tiles.
Speaker 0: She just has a handful of black tiles.
Speaker 0: And just due to the way the game ended...
Speaker 1: You couldn't get your black guy back on the board.
Speaker 0: I had like 15, 15, 15, 4 at one point as the score.
Speaker 1: You couldn't get the black guy back on the board.
Speaker 0: Ah, so the next turn, because I was still winning and I had a chance, I internal conflicted with my black leader...
Speaker 1: That's the only way to get it back on.
Speaker 0: ...to get onto a spot that had two black monuments.
Speaker 0: And yeah, once again, Emily just happened to have a whole bunch of red tiles in her hand.
Speaker 1: See, here's the thing, right?
Speaker 1: So here's some basic T&E strategies.
Speaker 1: We're not going to do a whole show on this, right?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Well, we have done a whole show on it.
Speaker 0: I'll link to it.
Speaker 1: You can see what's coming and you can look at your tiles in your hand and you can tell, "Aha, a black conflict is coming.
Speaker 1: Am I going to win
Speaker 1: it?".
Speaker 1: If you're not going to win it, you can either A, abandon it or B, dump tiles to try to get black tiles.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Now...
Speaker 1: Other basic strategy.
Speaker 0: Well, what was I saying the other day?
Speaker 0: The two most powerful things you can likely do in that game are build a monument in someone else's kingdom.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: Or start a fight between two other people's kingdoms.
Speaker 1: You can also, the catastrophe can swing you.
Speaker 1: If you don't have the red tiles to get, if the kingdoms are big and are stable, then you can only use internal conflicts to get your guy back on the board, right?
Speaker 1: It's very hard to use external conflicts to get back on the board.
Speaker 1: Unless you go back on the board in a shitty location and just start taking two points, not the greatest.
Speaker 1: So, you need red tiles to get back on the board.
Speaker 1: You can dump to get red tiles or you can use catastrophes.
Speaker 1: That'll probably get you back on, but if you use your catastrophes first against someone to get back on the board, they still have their catastrophes.
Speaker 1: You don't want to be the first person to catastrophe.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: You want to be the last person to catastrophe.
Speaker 0: If you're building a snake tendril of a kingdom out to touch somebody and make some mischief, and that somebody doesn't have any catastrophes left.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you still have catastrophes and the other players have been forced to use them all, then what you can do is you can start using board positions that are normally weak to catastrophe with no fear.
Speaker 0: Like four leaders huddled around one un-treasured red.
Speaker 1: You can leave a leader next to one red tile.
Speaker 1: You can make a long snake of tiles to grab a treasure.
Speaker 1: You can do all this stuff that you normally cannot do when catastrophes are out, but if you can force the other player to use theirs to get back onto the board by kicking them off and maybe blocking a nice internal conflict, like if they try to internal their way back on and they lose, they have to catastrophe their way back on, catastrophe them off, take your position back.
Speaker 1: They're out of catastrophes and now they're done.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Seriously, you know, we talk a lot about board games.
Speaker 0: We play a lot of board games and, well, we played.
Speaker 0: Lately, Scott doesn't play as many.
Speaker 0: But Tigris and Euphrates has consistently remained my favorite tabletop board game.
Speaker 1: So good.
Speaker 0: There are a few games that I might argue are better.
Speaker 0: It really depends on what you mean by better, like.
Speaker 0: better at, you know, what's a good at.
Speaker 0: Like Puerto Rico is probably a more finely tuned test of skill in a general sense.
Speaker 1: There's no random tile grab.
Speaker 0: Eclipse, however, is better at like satisfying that big old war game intense feeling.
Speaker 0: But in terms of the average of all possible aspects of a game, Tigris and Euphrates is far and away my favorite tabletop game.
Speaker 0: And it's telling that after all these years, nothing has unseated it.
Speaker 0: Even games that I really like.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So in the news, there's a new board game coming out that was announced today.
Speaker 1: Look at how new this news is.
Speaker 1: Fantasy Flight Games, publishers of such games as Netrunner and others you may enjoy, Citadel's, I guess, are now going to publish X-Com, the board game.
Speaker 1: Oh my glob.
Speaker 1: So.
Speaker 0: Well, well, oh my glob.
Speaker 0: It's funny you say that because usually when there's property, I like game in that property.
Speaker 0: warning signs.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: But Fantasy Flight, not like Cryptozoic.
Speaker 1: So this is the thing people don't realize.
Speaker 1: is that X-Com, there's an interview I watched with the CEO of Fantasy Flight Games.
Speaker 0: You almost said the CEO of X-Com.
Speaker 1: No, the CEO of Fantasy Flight Games.
Speaker 1: So I guess is now possibly also the CEO of X-Com.
Speaker 1: And they asked him, how do you choose which properties to license and how do you get such good licensed properties?
Speaker 1: Because they do Star Wars.
Speaker 1: They're making X-Wing, right?
Speaker 1: Star Wars.
Speaker 1: What bigger licensed property is there than Star Wars?
Speaker 1: They're doing Warhammer and they're not games workshop.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: It's like, how are you getting these properties as Fantasy Flight?
Speaker 1: And he's basically like, look, we do such a good job.
Speaker 1: All the licensers are coming to us trying to get us to make games for them.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Take, take note of that.
Speaker 0: Anyone who goes to Cryptozoic and we turn most of them down.
Speaker 1: And then I guess they go to Cryptozoic and who always says yes and just make some piece of shit.
Speaker 1: So the fact that they said yes to X-Com, right, is a big deal.
Speaker 1: So is this game good?
Speaker 1: Well, let's see what we know about the game so far.
Speaker 0: It has an embed, like an app that goes with it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So here's the deal.
Speaker 1: All the descriptions of this game seem to suggest it's a combination of Pandemic, which sucks, and Space Alert, which is good.
Speaker 0: The board game is a hybrid digital game that requires a companion app.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So Space Alert uses like a CD or an MP3 or a cassette or whatever it uses.
Speaker 1: This uses an app.
Speaker 1: So it's basically it's more versatile and they could update the app to add more scenarios and things of that nature.
Speaker 1: So that can be pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Of course, you could also.
Speaker 0: it could also be Omega virus.
Speaker 1: It could also be Omega virus.
Speaker 1: But so basically you and your friends are co-op against the game, which is X-Com, the aliens.
Speaker 1: And each person does something different, right?
Speaker 1: You've got the chief scientist who manages the science, the commander who moves the interceptors around the central officer who basically pays attention to the app and also the satellites.
Speaker 1: The squad leader manages the units who come out of the sky ranger.
Speaker 1: And so each person has their own job.
Speaker 1: And it doesn't seem like the jobs are programming related, which fixes the Space Alert problem of some of the people you're playing with can't program even for instructions and are incompetent.
Speaker 1: So you can't actually play Space Alert properly by making it more pandemic like.
Speaker 1: And at the same time, each person has to concentrate on a completely different thing, not more pandemic.
Speaker 1: Everyone's doing the same thing.
Speaker 1: So you is going to be less quarterbacking because of that.
Speaker 1: And also because it's real time with this app telling you what's going on and having to react to the app in real time, there's less quarterbacking because one person can't handle all four jobs.
Speaker 0: You need four people.
Speaker 0: That's a big factor.
Speaker 0: The game now becomes much more reliant upon things like charisma, shouting ability.
Speaker 1: But you're all on the same team.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but even on the same team, you're not going to charisma the aliens into leaving.
Speaker 0: No, but you're going to charisma your friend into doing what you tell him at the critical moment.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you can even, you know, hopefully it looks like like there's so little information about the game, but looking at the board and the pieces, it looks like each player has so much going on that I don't know if you could really like even pay attention enough to what the other people are doing in order to manage more than one of these jobs at a time.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's some smart person out there going to handle two or three of the jobs.
Speaker 1: handling all four at the same time seems pretty difficult.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah, this looks like it'll be fun.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I'll pay for it, depending how much it is.
Speaker 1: I think I might sell a bunch of board games I don't play and buy this if I can't convince someone else to buy it.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: I wonder if we'll be able to.
Speaker 1: I really want to try it at PAX.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is a game that I don't know.
Speaker 0: It could be good.
Speaker 0: It could be bad.
Speaker 0: There's factors in both directions.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's just exciting to see the XCOM license used at all for something besides a video game.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, people forget the days of like XCOM Interceptor.
Speaker 1: Well, that's a video game.
Speaker 0: Yes, a bad video game.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: But I wish that, you know, the XCOM license were used more often on other things.
Speaker 0: Also, I was reminded why you should never read comments on articles.
Speaker 0: The comments on this polygon article about this are choice.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Here, I'm going to quote one of these guys.
Speaker 0: This is trinium 1029.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry, but no.
Speaker 0: XCOM is great as a video game because it allows for real tactical decisions without needing to worry about a bunch of numbers and fuzzy stuff.
Speaker 0: Board games aren't so good at.
Speaker 1: XCOM has no numbers.
Speaker 0: He says that board games are bad at being real tactical games.
Speaker 0: is what he's saying here.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: I agree.
Speaker 0: Converting the XCOM to a board game seems like a painful experience.
Speaker 0: The plot and theme would make for a great game.
Speaker 0: These people, it's like they have no idea how to evaluate.
Speaker 1: Well, also he's like, it would be a bunch of numbers and stuff.
Speaker 1: In other words, I'm dumb.
Speaker 1: No want to do hard thing.
Speaker 1: In other words, you're dumb.
Speaker 1: We should not consider anything you have to say.
Speaker 1: You admit ignorance and anti-intellectualism.
Speaker 1: If you are proud of being stupid, why don't we just kill you?
Speaker 1: You're worthless and you admitted it.
Speaker 0: You should go post there because you're right in the tone of this discussion.
Speaker 1: That's exactly what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Perfect internet comment.
Speaker 0: Plus five would read again.
Speaker 1: I'm even posting this comment to the internet in MP3 form.
Speaker 1: It's so fancy.
Speaker 0: I suspect if I have to guess, I think this is going to be a fun game.
Speaker 1: It could be good.
Speaker 1: It's worth it.
Speaker 1: It's going to be worth playing at least once to see how this app works.
Speaker 1: Now here's the thing.
Speaker 1: Requires this app.
Speaker 0: That's fine by me.
Speaker 1: Which you can use in a computer, a tablet, a phone, whatever.
Speaker 1: Even a desktop.
Speaker 1: But what about those people who don't have any computing device whatsoever?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm going to have to get four friends and they're each going to have to buy a Game Boy Advance and the Game Boy Advance link cable.
Speaker 1: You know people are going to say that?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: They're going to be like, "I can't play this game because I don't have the
Speaker 1: app.".
Speaker 1: Or, "The game's at a convention.
Speaker 1: Check it out of the library.
Speaker 1: You don't have the app on your phone and no one does either in the
Speaker 1: group.".
Speaker 0: And the wireless is too slow because you're at a convention.
Speaker 1: You can't get the game because you got to download this massive app over wireless.
Speaker 1: Is the convention going to put a tablet in the game box?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Well, I could see.
Speaker 0: so I could see like mag fest like having one person who just did that because they'd be pretty trusting of that.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: I don't see that happening at PAX.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, right, that's a problem for this game and convention libraries and other game libraries.
Speaker 0: What I would do is, you know what?
Speaker 1: It's also a problem for this game in the distant future.
Speaker 1: if you don't have some, you know, this app isn't going to be updated for all time, right?
Speaker 1: It'll probably stop working on iOS 12 or Android 20 something.
Speaker 1: It can go into the pile of such games as Tribes 2 and Quake 2.
Speaker 1: But it's a board game, so board games usually don't become unplayable.
Speaker 0: I have a WWF, that's how old it is, wrestling game that requires a VHS tape.
Speaker 0: I don't have a VHS player.
Speaker 1: No, but you can get a copy of that video in YouTube or something.
Speaker 0: I wonder if I can, actually.
Speaker 0: This is a piece of software.
Speaker 1: You would need like an iPhone emulator and a copy of it or something.
Speaker 1: It would not be as easy to play this game in the distant future when the software is no longer available.
Speaker 0: Playing Tribes 2.
Speaker 1: Well, there is a desktop version of this app, it appears, because it's a picture of a laptop.
Speaker 1: So whether I buy this game or not, I'm going to download the software and then keep it somewhere safe.
Speaker 0: So here's the thing, if this game is good enough to be remembered to the point that anyone would want to play it after it is sort of expired technologically, it'll be kept around.
Speaker 0: I mean, how many packs of every ROM from every console ever are available online?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, this is not, you know, it's not guaranteed.
Speaker 0: It's guaranteed because if it's forgotten, it was forgotten for a reason.
Speaker 1: There are things that are forgotten that shouldn't be.
Speaker 0: Very few.
Speaker 0: Some things.
Speaker 1: Nothing lasts forever.
Speaker 0: Some things ye mighty.
Speaker 0: So in other news, I want to bring this up briefly.
Speaker 0: We've been talking a lot and everyone's been talking a lot about Nintendo's not doing well.
Speaker 1: No, they're doing awful.
Speaker 0: You guys really need to pay attention to how poorly Nintendo is doing.
Speaker 1: Super awful.
Speaker 0: This isn't just like, I mean, like there were times in the past where they'd have like a weird, like, Oh my God, we were unprofitable.
Speaker 1: And then they came back and it was just like Apple came back.
Speaker 0: Well, a lot of those instances were due to things like currency fluctuations or cycles missing between like when Sony releases something, but Nintendo doesn't have something to release that quarter.
Speaker 0: Like all sorts of things.
Speaker 0: Nintendo lost $97 million in the quarter ending June 30th.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So Nintendo lost $97 million.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you some unrelated news just to give you some scope.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Bernie Ecclestone, the F1 guy basically was mad bribery corruption and he was going to go to jail.
Speaker 1: And in fact, the other guy who was involved is in jail and he paid the court a hundred million dollars to not go to jail.
Speaker 1: Basically.
Speaker 1: So Nintendo lost less money than that dude paid to not go to jail.
Speaker 1: That's how much money 1% has.
Speaker 1: But there you go.
Speaker 0: That's just sad.
Speaker 1: Think about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's why Luigi is so mad.
Speaker 1: If they just gave that money to Nintendo, Nintendo would be in the profit zone.
Speaker 0: So why is Nintendo not profitable?
Speaker 1: Well, no one's buying their shit.
Speaker 1: Wii U sucks.
Speaker 0: No one's buying the Wii U and no one bought a Wii U who didn't already own one to play Mario Kart 8.
Speaker 1: Why would I buy a Wii U just for Mario Kart when I already have 10 Mario Karts that are perfectly awesome?
Speaker 0: Just remember that there was a time in my life where GameCube, we had to own one because there's going to be a Mario Kart.
Speaker 0: We didn't buy GameCube.
Speaker 1: We didn't even buy GameCube for Mario Kart.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But we bought a big GameCube because you knew that there'd be one.
Speaker 1: I don't even own Double Dash and I've hardly played it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't even like Double Dash.
Speaker 1: It's one of the worser Mario Karts in my book.
Speaker 1: Worser.
Speaker 0: Not one of the worst though.
Speaker 1: No, it's not the worst.
Speaker 1: It's not a great Mario Kart.
Speaker 1: Take that.
Speaker 1: People are mad at me now.
Speaker 0: Of course they are.
Speaker 0: A lot of people I know think that's the best Mario Kart because usually it's the people who are bad at Mario Kart who like to be the partner in the back.
Speaker 1: Those are the people who can't play the real Mario Kart on the Game Boy Advance.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: What about the snaking Mario Kart on the DS?
Speaker 1: That's really bad.
Speaker 1: Actually, that could be the best one if it didn't have the snaking.
Speaker 0: But for snaking.
Speaker 0: Well, we're going to talk about snaking at our panel at PAX on how to win at games.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: On Monday at noon.
Speaker 0: But the problem is that Nintendo does not have a lot to bring to the table anymore and they've gotten to the point.
Speaker 0: They do.
Speaker 1: They're just not bringing it to the table.
Speaker 0: Well, as a result, they don't.
Speaker 1: Pokemon MMO.
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 1: How desperate do they have to be to make the Pokemon MMO?
Speaker 0: If they were going to make the Pokemon MMO, it would have to be on the PC and mobile devices, not on a Wii U.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Just fucking do it.
Speaker 0: The problem is Nintendo's gotten to the point now to where their first party games are no longer, oh shit, I need to own the console to play that game or the current generation of those games.
Speaker 1: Of course not, because those games aren't Super Metroid 2.
Speaker 0: They're also not getting better.
Speaker 0: Mario Kart 8 is, you know, it's got a lot going for it, but it's not.
Speaker 1: How is it any different from Wii Mario Kart?
Speaker 0: Minor improvements.
Speaker 0: The Luigi Death Stare.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The network works better.
Speaker 1: Probably the same as Wii Mario Kart.
Speaker 1: What do I need it for?
Speaker 1: I'm sure it's great, but it's not worth paying money for.
Speaker 1: when I can play Wii Mario Kart.
Speaker 0: I'm actually still really liking the 3DS Mario Kart.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's an okay Mario Kart.
Speaker 0: Also, look at the Mario Tennis.
Speaker 0: Recent Mario Tennises have gotten easier and worse.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Objectively worse.
Speaker 1: I got GameCube Mario Tennis.
Speaker 1: What do I need another Mario Tennis for?
Speaker 0: I think GameCube Mario Tennis was the peak of Mario Tennis and it's been a decline since then.
Speaker 1: Obviously.
Speaker 1: Well, did you ever play the GBA Mario Tennis?
Speaker 0: Yes, I have played it, but I never owned it.
Speaker 1: The GBA Mario Tennis is made by the people who made Golden Sun using the same engine and it's got like an RPG aspect to it.
Speaker 1: It's actually pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: I recommend checking it out.
Speaker 1: I don't recommend maybe playing the whole thing because it takes a while, but it's worth seeing for like, "Ooh, this
Speaker 1: happened.".
Speaker 0: I don't think Nintendo is going to recover.
Speaker 1: Maybe not.
Speaker 0: I don't foresee.
Speaker 1: I would just, I hope that they could recover so easily if they would just do what I tell them.
Speaker 0: Well, look at what happened.
Speaker 1: The thing about this, all right, so here's something someone pointed out the other day, right?
Speaker 1: We talk about, people are talking about like PS4 and Xbone.
Speaker 1: There's more 3DSs than PS4s and Xbone combined.
Speaker 0: Well, watch out.
Speaker 0: The PS4 is selling like crazy.
Speaker 0: The Xbone's not.
Speaker 1: It seems like the PS4 is winning, for sure.
Speaker 0: Winning, I think won.
Speaker 0: I think done.
Speaker 1: Probably, yeah.
Speaker 1: But still, 3DS is crushed both of them by a lot, right?
Speaker 0: Is that just because it's been a lot longer?
Speaker 1: Why doesn't Nintendo just abandon their Wii garbage and just go full-on 3DS and give the people what they want?
Speaker 1: Nintendo's main problem is not that they can't give the people what they want.
Speaker 1: They won't.
Speaker 1: If Nintendo would just do what we tell them, as we've been saying on this show, for as long as this show has existed.
Speaker 0: Well, in the GameCube era, they would make all the money.
Speaker 1: The profit would go whoop.
Speaker 0: In the GameCube era, they experimented and they went toward their like sort of core, invested in Nintendo demographic.
Speaker 0: But yet, they also had the infinitely profitable mobile platform at the time.
Speaker 0: Then, in the Wii era, because they weren't doing so well, they had a rapid gear shift and they went toward the Blue Ocean strategy.
Speaker 1: Which made them a lot of money on Wii Sports.
Speaker 0: Wii Bowling.
Speaker 0: Not even Wii Sports.
Speaker 0: It was pretty much just Wii Bowling.
Speaker 1: And then also Wii Fit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And then all those people didn't buy any other games.
Speaker 1: No, of course not.
Speaker 0: And certainly weren't going to buy a Wii U.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, all the people like us said, "Yeah, fuck you
Speaker 0: guys.".
Speaker 0: So we left.
Speaker 0: So now they're floating out in the Blue Ocean alone.
Speaker 1: But Nintendo could easily please us people.
Speaker 1: If they would just make what I tell them, all of us would suddenly have to go and buy whatever they were selling.
Speaker 1: If they made the right game for it.
Speaker 0: I've said this so many times.
Speaker 0: If Nintendo did even a quarter, an eighth, a twentieth of what the Wii U controller is capable of, I would have bought that console in a heartbeat.
Speaker 0: But they haven't.
Speaker 0: They've done nothing with it.
Speaker 0: Just like they did nothing with the waggle.
Speaker 0: The last time they did anything was Four Swords and Crystal Chronicles with the GBA link cable.
Speaker 0: I gotta reach back for glory.
Speaker 0: And the greatest achievement in terms of proving an interesting path forward?
Speaker 0: Most people consider those games a failure.
Speaker 0: I think those people are wrong and kind of dumb.
Speaker 0: Tiny side news too.
Speaker 0: There's an article on Polygon that caught my eye a minute ago.
Speaker 0: Zelda fans debate Sheik's gender.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: It's Princess Zelda in disguise.
Speaker 0: Yeah, guys.
Speaker 0: It's Zelda in disguise.
Speaker 1: Have you not played Zelda 64?
Speaker 1: I think that the title can't be true because if you don't know that Sheik is Zelda in disguise, you're not a Zelda fan.
Speaker 1: He's not a real Zelda quote.
Speaker 0: Sheik's gender is a surprisingly hot debate among Nintendo fans.
Speaker 1: Is Samus gender a debate as well?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: It was when I was a kid and there was no Internet.
Speaker 0: I remember when someone told me Samus Aaron was a girl and I said, "How do you
Speaker 0: know?".
Speaker 0: And the thing is they couldn't beat the game quickly enough to show me, so I didn't believe them until I went and found a picture of it.
Speaker 0: Is Sheik, the mysterious character first introduced in The Legend of Zelda, the Ocarina of Time, a man or a woman?
Speaker 0: The debate has begun again after Nintendo reveals that Sheik will be a playable character in the upcoming Hyrule Warriors.
Speaker 1: Have you played Smash Brothers?
Speaker 0: This article's amazing.
Speaker 1: You don't even have to have played Zelda 64 to know this.
Speaker 0: One person argues that, yes, it's Zelda, but it's Zelda dressing up as a man, therefore it's cross-dressing, blah, blah, blah, non-gender, binary, fluid, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, argument.
Speaker 0: Therefore, it's better if you argue that Sheik physically transformed into a man.
Speaker 0: So that's all fan garbage.
Speaker 0: At the bottom, the Polygon article.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna read this.
Speaker 0: This is "Sheik asked Nintendo if there was an official word on this, and they answered the call.
Speaker 0: Nintendo's official line quoted from Nintendo's senior product marketing manager, Bill Trinen, is
Speaker 0: this.".
Speaker 1: Nintendo of America, not Nintendo of Japan?
Speaker 0: Uh, Bill Trinen, so I think Nintendo of America.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I actually don't know which one he works for.
Speaker 1: He could have hired an English dude in Japan or vice versa.
Speaker 0: They could have, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know Bill Trinen.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: I've heard the name, but I haven't.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Quote, "The definitive answer is that Sheik is a woman, simply Zelda, in a different
Speaker 0: outfit.".
Speaker 0: You don't say.
Speaker 1: You don't say.
Speaker 0: So things of the day.
Speaker 0: You know the old game, high five?
Speaker 0: Where you give someone a high five, and then you mess with them?
Speaker 1: You mean slap me high?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Slap me low?
Speaker 0: Down low, too slow?
Speaker 1: Slap medium, slap me low, you too slow?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All those kinds of things.
Speaker 0: The interaction in middle school, or possibly elementary school, where the cool kid does this to the not cool kid, and the not cool kid gets flustered, and it's hilarious.
Speaker 0: You know, that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: This video, I don't know what to say about it, but Mr.
Speaker 0: Ligandarius has presented an 18-second drama recorded entirely in vines of that experience.
Speaker 0: This is amazing.
Speaker 1: This is, we'll have to compete with my equally amazing thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Three words, Russian duck farmer.
Speaker 1: That's all I'm going to say.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's a tough choice between mine and yours.
Speaker 1: Excellent things of the day.
Speaker 1: Today, perhaps of great vintage.
Speaker 0: Perhaps we're back into the, we might be coming into a vintage year.
Speaker 0: No longer do we just go to College Humor.
Speaker 1: Those days are long past us.
Speaker 1: I haven't stopped going to College Humor, which is part of the reason.
Speaker 0: Thing is, as a result, I've been going to College Humor, and it's still consistently the best source of great videos.
Speaker 1: Probably.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Other meta moments.
Speaker 0: The Book Club book is The Canticle for Leibowitz.
Speaker 0: I'm hoping Scott will read it on the flight to Seattle.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: It's too nice out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, too nice out on the plane flying to Seattle.
Speaker 1: I guess I recharged my Kindle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually just bought a, I found a book that purports to teach me Turkish.
Speaker 0: that's relatively new, so I bought it on the Kindle.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna try it out.
Speaker 1: We'll see how much Turkish you learn.
Speaker 0: I know more Turkish than most people in America who are not Turkish.
Speaker 1: You don't say.
Speaker 1: I know more Hebrew than most people in America.
Speaker 0: Those ducks know more Russian than any of us.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: We are giving away two fucking tickets, four-day tickets, fuckers, to PAX Prime 2014.
Speaker 0: Holy
Speaker 1: shit, if you want to go to PAX Prime 2014 and you can get there on your own, and you can find a place to stay on your
Speaker 0: own, and you can either give us your address or meet us at
Speaker 1: PAX, and for some reason you didn't get tickets because maybe you were lazy and didn't buy them, or you were just slow, or you're bad at internet, or whatever.
Speaker 1: You didn't listen to us.
Speaker 0: I can no longer blame people for being lazy or slow.
Speaker 1: I got them.
Speaker 1: How come you couldn't get them?
Speaker 0: Scott and I saw that it went up at the same, like within seconds of each other.
Speaker 0: We both jumped into the queue.
Speaker 0: Scott bought as many four-day badges as he could, and I could not buy any.
Speaker 0: However, I got the good hotel.
Speaker 1: To get these two tickets, here's what you must do.
Speaker 1: You must tweet on Twitter and shamelessly self-promote us Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: We need promotion, so here's how it works.
Speaker 1: You make a tweet.
Speaker 1: The tweet must contain the hashtag of PAX.
Speaker 1: That way people who are looking at that hashtag will see it.
Speaker 1: It must contain either the hashtag of Geek Nights or @GeekNights.
Speaker 1: If you use @GeekNights, do not make that the very first thing in the tweet, because then only we will see it, and other people who follow us and also follow you will see it, but no one else will see it.
Speaker 0: Thus defeating the purpose of shameless self-promotion.
Speaker 1: And it must contain a link to some sort of Geek Nights content.
Speaker 1: It could be one of our panel videos on YouTube.
Speaker 1: It could be Geek episode, right?
Speaker 1: It could be anything that is us to promote us, and you make that tweet sometime before the tickets arrive at my house, and then if you make more than one tweet, it won't help you.
Speaker 1: It won't disqualify you, but it won't help you.
Speaker 1: One tweet is enough.
Speaker 1: More tweets are welcome.
Speaker 1: Tweet all you want, but only one entry per person.
Speaker 0: Because the more popular we get, I mean, we just spent like a thousand dollars on new microphones to do some awesome stuff, but we'll do that awesome stuff faster if you guys get us around more.
Speaker 1: And then on that day, uh, sometime soon, I will search all those tweets and use random.org to pick one of the Twitter accounts, and those two tickets will go to that person.
Speaker 1: If that person sells the tickets for money, you're a fucker and an asshole and a jerk.
Speaker 1: I won't be able to stop you, but I'll be hella pissed, and I'll put your name on the shit list.
Speaker 0: It's a short list, so watch out.
Speaker 1: If I give you the tickets, I want to see you at PAX, like at our panel and go, "Hey, what's
Speaker 1: up?".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, in fact, if you come to our panel with those tickets, what panel would that be?
Speaker 0: That would be, oh, I gotta go to the older news, archive news.
Speaker 0: It is How to Win Every Game.
Speaker 1: Every game.
Speaker 0: The example games we list are games like Stratego, Settlers of Catan, or Football.
Speaker 0: We're not even joking.
Speaker 1: No, we're not.
Speaker 0: Noon Monday, Sandworm Theater.
Speaker 1: Sandworm Theater.
Speaker 0: So, if you get the badges and you come to that panel and say hi.
Speaker 1: Don't say the word Beetlejuice when you come.
Speaker 0: But bring spice, though.
Speaker 0: Can you think of a third Sandworm thing?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Tremors?
Speaker 0: No tremors?
Speaker 1: I don't know what the hell that is.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Scout doesn't know what tremors is.
Speaker 1: I don't know what you just said.
Speaker 0: What rock do you live on top of?
Speaker 0: Because if you lived under it, they would have gotten you by now.
Speaker 1: Long Island.
Speaker 0: So, beyond all that, oh, that's a bachelor party.
Speaker 0: Do I have any other stuff?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: We've started streaming and uploading videos of us playing tabletop games.
Speaker 0: So, a lot of you asked for that.
Speaker 0: We did it.
Speaker 0: If you liked it, spread it around, post it to Reddit, and we'll do more of it.
Speaker 0: That's a good way to get into the Geek Nights PAX Ticket Giveaway as well.
Speaker 0: So, Curse of the Necrodancer.
Speaker 1: So, this is a game I know has been coming for a long time.
Speaker 0: Played it at a PAX.
Speaker 1: I played it at a PAX like a minute, so it barely counts.
Speaker 0: They had, and I feel like, well, we'll talk about it.
Speaker 0: I feel like it was a little bit of disingenuous advertising, but they had it at PAX, and they had a dance pad set up, and there'd be people standing there dancing in front of the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, this game, on paper, is a rhythm roguelike.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: DDR plus roguelike.
Speaker 0: You know, not just us, but people in general are big fans of the "What if you took Mega Man and mashed it up with
Speaker 0: football?".
Speaker 1: But, I mean, that particular combination is just so, well, there's Mega Man soccer.
Speaker 0: That's what I was about to make a joke about.
Speaker 1: That particular combination of roguelike and rhythm is just so, you can just imagine how amazing this game is going to be.
Speaker 1: Walking through a dungeon, equipping items, fighting really hard bad guys, but also funky music, excellent soundtrack, moving around, up, down, left, right.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: This has got to be the greatest.
Speaker 1: You play it for like a minute, and you're like, "Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: I can't believe
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: Finally, the pre-release of the game is on the Steam.
Speaker 0: Pre, pre, pre, pre-release, alpha, nowhere near done.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: It's nowhere near done, but it's actually more done than you would think.
Speaker 1: I think, like, the only thing that's missing is, like, final bosses and ending levels.
Speaker 0: It's got plenty of levels and there's tons- It's missing UI stuff and polish and a few tweaks to the core conceit.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know if it's ever going to get this.
Speaker 0: I don't think it will.
Speaker 1: But, regardless, we both played it, and let's talk about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Crypt of the NecroDancer is pretty fun.
Speaker 1: Great name.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Great music.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling- I mean, the music isn't the greatest rhythm music, but it's still great.
Speaker 0: The music reminds me so much of Super Hexagon's music.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a little bit.
Speaker 0: It's a little bit less- I don't know, but listen to it again without playing the game.
Speaker 0: But someone told me, and I haven't tried to do this, that you can just put any song in there.
Speaker 1: But it has to be the right rhythms.
Speaker 0: Hellorb.
Speaker 0: It'll figure out the beat, supposedly.
Speaker 0: So much Hellorb.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Hellorb.
Speaker 0: I'm not Hellorb.
Speaker 0: You are.
Speaker 0: So, basically, what it is, is it's a row-like where you play it in a rhythm.
Speaker 0: So, it's almost like a row-like where instead of just you move and then, like, the world's turn happens because you took your turn.
Speaker 0: Instead, turns happen every beat.
Speaker 1: So, if you stand still, bad guys keep moving on the beat.
Speaker 1: And you move on the beat.
Speaker 1: You don't have to move on the beat.
Speaker 1: You can't really move faster than the beat, right?
Speaker 1: So, ideally, you move on the beats.
Speaker 1: If you miss the beat, you don't really move.
Speaker 1: It's like, oops.
Speaker 0: Now, the game rewards you for continuing to move on the beat exactly.
Speaker 1: You get a coin multiplier.
Speaker 1: So, the coin multiplier basically means that when you kill guys, you're getting more and more monies, right?
Speaker 1: So, when you go to the shop, you can buy pretty much everything if you have your coin multiplier up.
Speaker 0: That's my problem.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to dwell on the bad stuff first.
Speaker 0: The problem with this game, fundamentally, is that the rhythm aspect of it matters very little.
Speaker 0: That coin multiplier is it.
Speaker 0: Except in a few rare cases.
Speaker 0: Like when there's a shrine that you can activate and then you get hurt every time you miss the beat.
Speaker 0: But you know what happens when that happens?
Speaker 0: You just die.
Speaker 0: I mean, most of the games... So, yes, the rhythm multiplier would be cool.
Speaker 0: Except it only really is triggering when you have a fight.
Speaker 0: A good chunk of all the play is walking around a mostly empty level exploring.
Speaker 0: Staying on the rhythm during that time is boring and you're just gonna fuck it up.
Speaker 1: And it's just a steady rhythm, right?
Speaker 1: And it's not like you have to follow a particular pattern or hit different beats.
Speaker 1: It's just keep pushing the arrows at this rhythm.
Speaker 1: And different levels are... Later levels get faster and the rhythm is faster.
Speaker 1: And this is kind of good because if the game was turn-based, the way you fight the bad guys, it would be trivial because you could sit there and think about each and every move and figure out the optimal move.
Speaker 1: Because it makes you move fast, that's what makes you screw up because you don't have time to think and the bad guys are coming.
Speaker 1: But in terms of it, it needs a little more DDR going on here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's why I said in the early time when you see it set up and people are showing it off.
Speaker 1: It seems amazing.
Speaker 0: Because they have the dance pad out and you imagine it being a certain kind of thing.
Speaker 0: The dance pad is an afterthought.
Speaker 0: The dance pad does not really add to the game.
Speaker 1: It's a different control aspect and it also makes the game a lot harder which is why they have dance pad mode which is basically easy mode.
Speaker 0: But for example, Dance Dance Revolution, you're walking around the mat doing patterns.
Speaker 0: This game, you're mostly going left, left, left, left, left, right, left, left, left.
Speaker 0: It's really fucking tedious.
Speaker 0: You can't even just leave your foot down to keep going left.
Speaker 0: You have to keep tap.
Speaker 0: So it's basically tap with your foot on a really inefficient bullshit controller.
Speaker 1: As opposed to DDR which is like up, down, jump, both, left, left, left, right.
Speaker 0: If the game had like combos like do a rhythm to cast a spell or a particular dance to do a thing.
Speaker 1: All the items that you cast are basically two buttons at once.
Speaker 1: So it'll tell you on the screen like for bomb, go down and left simultaneously.
Speaker 1: So if you're using a game pad, you can't use the D-pad or the analog stick.
Speaker 1: You have to use the four buttons on the right to control the game.
Speaker 0: Or bind a combo button.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which sucks.
Speaker 1: You don't want to do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now what I would have done is made the game more like eighth note patterns.
Speaker 0: So on the beats, you move and do the normal game.
Speaker 0: But if I want to use a potion, I should have to be like up left on an eighth note pattern to use the item instead.
Speaker 0: That would have been cool but they don't do anything like that.
Speaker 1: Now the other thing is the bad guys in this game, each bad guy has his own pattern of movement and attacking.
Speaker 1: So you can learn each bad guy in the way to approach them.
Speaker 1: For example, there's a green slime.
Speaker 1: All you got to do is walk up and bump into it to kill it.
Speaker 1: Pretty easy.
Speaker 1: There's a blue slime.
Speaker 1: The blue slime only moves up and down.
Speaker 1: To kill him, you have to hit him from the left or the right.
Speaker 1: If you approach him from the top or the bottom, he's probably going to hit you.
Speaker 1: Unless you get your timing really right.
Speaker 1: And then you know bosses and stuff come at you in even harder ways.
Speaker 1: So it's like when the dragon comes, it's like you have to step away from the dragon, then step back at it, then hit it, then step away and go at it and hit it and so on.
Speaker 1: It's like there's more complicated things you have to do.
Speaker 1: There's a ghost that's like boo and he follows you around invisible but then you turn it and you got to turn around right when he's just behind you to get him to appear and stab him, right?
Speaker 1: And you have to do this on the rhythm.
Speaker 1: So when there's a room full of a bunch of different bad guys and you have to keep moving, it's not the easiest to think of like the exact right patterns.
Speaker 1: Like you can focus on one guy and then another guy is going to come over and kill you like the big dragon or something.
Speaker 1: So you know the rhythm is good and then it forces you to, because if you could just sit there and think and assess all the bad guys and how they move, it would be trivially trivial and dumb.
Speaker 1: You would never get hit and never die because you'd always be able to make the right move.
Speaker 0: And I enjoy this that aspect of it a lot because it is not even analogous to DDR.
Speaker 0: It's not even the same realm.
Speaker 0: It's just a you don't have time to think roguelike.
Speaker 0: The other problem I have with the game is that it does a very poor job of Mega Man X-ing.
Speaker 0: It does not tell you fuck all about what things do.
Speaker 0: but in rogue and roguelikes that's fine because you sit there and think like I do a thing.
Speaker 0: What the fuck did that weird thing do?
Speaker 0: In this game because it's moving so fast, unless you read a fact, you will never know how the weapons actually work.
Speaker 1: The only way to learn anything is to learn the bad guy movements.
Speaker 1: They have a little training mode where you can go and practice against all the different bad guys.
Speaker 1: You have to unlock the guy who does that for you by playing.
Speaker 1: And there's another one where you can unlock bosses to practice against them.
Speaker 1: To unlock that you need to get diamonds and shit.
Speaker 1: So it's like you can't get the practice mode to learn the game for the different bad guys and their movements until you get kind of far in the game and have probably beaten those guys.
Speaker 0: And also a lot of the game is very unrhythmic in the sense that the patterns of the monsters are sort of mitigated by the fact that you can dig up pretty much any wall.
Speaker 0: So the game is very open and you spend a lot of time backtracking through empty areas which is super boring especially because you've got your coin combo going and you want to just keep it going.
Speaker 0: So you got to be like left, left and follow the rhythm perfectly and then you'll a lot of backtracking through boring empty areas even in harder higher levels.
Speaker 1: I think part of the game is sort of trying to be like spelunky in a way.
Speaker 0: Yeah it reminded me a lot of spelunky.
Speaker 1: Where it's like okay the stages are kind of small right.
Speaker 1: They're sort of randomly generated.
Speaker 1: They have a few areas and a few aspects in common.
Speaker 1: There's always a shop with some random items.
Speaker 1: There's always going to be certain numbers of rooms with bad guys and a treasure chest maybe and maybe a key and you know it's like okay do you just rush for the exit?
Speaker 1: Do you try to beat all the bad guys?
Speaker 1: Do you you know try to get certain items and things you know and it's like doesn't have as much stuff as spelunking but it has bombs which spelunky has and it also has the shop and whatever.
Speaker 1: So you know I think they're hoping that you know.
Speaker 1: people are going to try to do the same thing with this.
Speaker 1: they did with spelunky like trying to perfect it trying to unlock secret stuffs trying to do easter eggs speed runs all that sort of stuff which you could do that with this game but it wouldn't be as good as spelunky until a lot more is added.
Speaker 1: Spelunky is mad polished after being released on like a zillion different platforms.
Speaker 0: So I don't know this game like if I had to say in some.
Speaker 0: now it's not done yet.
Speaker 0: I don't think and I think you agreed when you hinted this earlier it's never going to get the the highest level of polish like.
Speaker 0: I don't see that happening.
Speaker 1: There's no way it's like.
Speaker 1: unless they keep working on this thing for years which I don't see happening it's not going to reach like the spelunky level but it's definitely going to be better than it is now.
Speaker 1: but I don't see them changing the core conceit and adding more rhythmness to it.
Speaker 0: So if I had my dream game it would be a game where you hold a controller to move around and you dance on a dance pad to do things like almost like robotron controls but it's moving with the hands and casting spells by doing complex combos with the feet.
Speaker 1: What I would actually like to make is a pure rhythm game where it's just ddr but the visualization of the game right you know like when you're playing regular ddr the visualization just the arrows yeah and the guy dancing in the right and and you can see him going through the dungeon.
Speaker 1: and as long as you keep hitting perfect the guy goes through the dungeon nicely and if you you know mess up playing ddr.
Speaker 1: the visualization is not so good.
Speaker 1: you get hit when you make a mistake.
Speaker 0: oh you don't even have to be a visualization.
Speaker 0: imagine going between the two.
Speaker 0: imagine if the the dungeon in one of these levels in this game was very linear and you're playing it and the enemy's patterns are all sort of.
Speaker 0: basically you have to the pattern.
Speaker 0: that's perfect.
Speaker 0: there's no like empty spaces.
Speaker 0: you're just going through stuff monsters and the dance pattern is always the same.
Speaker 0: don't make it randomly generated necessarily and you've got to just like play perfectly through it.
Speaker 0: but also you know what it doesn't do anything with you.
Speaker 0: either get the rhythm or you don't.
Speaker 0: there's no like gradation there.
Speaker 0: what if every day if you hit the rhythm so perfectly like the perfect in ddr you got like a 1.1 to x damage got a good.
Speaker 0: maybe it's 0.8 x damage like it doesn't do anything like that?
Speaker 0: i don't think it ever will.
Speaker 1: hmm that would be good.
Speaker 1: yeah there's a lot of this and the rhythm is always steady right on the beats.
Speaker 1: there's some things that'll speed it up and slow it down sure but within a single level the rhythm doesn't change unless you fall into a trap or something that messes with it.
Speaker 1: why not have the rhythm actually follow like the melody a bit right so it.
Speaker 1: you know the game would be like move move move move move move move move move instead of move move move move move move.
Speaker 1: you know it would be a lot more interesting that way because you know you had to sort of sit around in the opening part of the game get a feel for the song.
Speaker 1: you know there would be certain times like you'd be like all right.
Speaker 1: wait for the bunch of movement then approach the room full of bad guys on this beat.
Speaker 0: you might get caught by surprise when the suddenly you know there's a there's an awesome does have pretty good co-op in the sense that you just play together and it's actually really fun.
Speaker 1: but if you get to the edge of the map you're sort of stuck yep and it doesn't do any split screen or anything interesting.
Speaker 0: and if you die well fuck you just sit there and wait for your friend to beat the level or die and the game over because it's a roguelike you're dead you're dead.
Speaker 1: yep i'd say it has a bit of the rogue legacy though where when you die any diamonds you got other things don't matter but any diamonds you got can be used in the lobby to buy stuff but if you don't use them you lose them.
Speaker 1: so you can't build up diamonds over time sort of like rogue legacy.
Speaker 1: yeah uh and you can use that to buy things in the shops that either you know put items into chests in the dungeon to make the chest better or permanent upgrades like more heart containers just period stuff like that.
Speaker 0: so if i had to rate this game in terms of fun it's about the same level as the binding of isaac?
Speaker 1: yeah by the same level.
Speaker 0: it's the kind of idle game that i like playing my laptop with my fingers while i'm waiting for an airplane.
Speaker 1: it's not an ftl level.
Speaker 0: yeah uh speaking of which i've been playing a lot of ftl.
Speaker 1: still you don't say people were talking.
Speaker 1: i heard some rumblings right not of anything actually happening in terms of an official thing but just you know fan made.
Speaker 1: they were typing in fan made ftl board game.
Speaker 0: but also i've been talking about that.
Speaker 0: i've started prototyping an ftl board game.
Speaker 1: someone else is talking fan made ftl tabletop rpg using torchbearer ish kind of rules.
Speaker 0: yeah that would be.
Speaker 0: that would be the fucking bomb.
Speaker 0: that's what i'm saying especially because then you take those like the care.
Speaker 1: would it be the fire bomb?
Speaker 0: you take the character sheet inventory tetris.
Speaker 1: i'll be i'll be mantis man and you couple it.
Speaker 0: you can be stone man but you couple it with the ship's inventory tetris.
Speaker 0: yep oh my god there's so many possibilities there.
Speaker 1: i'm mantis man.
Speaker 1: that's all i'm saying.
Speaker 0: you really have to read more culture books scott.
Speaker 0: that's all i'm gonna say this mantis man.
Speaker 0: uh i'm just.
Speaker 0: there's so many things.
Speaker 1: i'm sure if you're in the culture you can just become a mantis man.
Speaker 0: who's gonna stop you?
Speaker 0: there's that guy who he's he?
Speaker 0: he's the ambassador to the species called the affront.
Speaker 1: they're mantises.
Speaker 0: no they're just the worst but he's like.
Speaker 0: he kind of likes them even though they're the worst and he's kind of like me.
Speaker 1: are they worse than azad?
Speaker 0: uh you have no idea.
Speaker 1: that's why i'm asking.
Speaker 0: that's pretty tame compared to the affront.
Speaker 0: are?
Speaker 0: i'll put it this way they were found by the like normal civilizations.
Speaker 0: the big guys and they were like you motherfuckers are an affront to existence and this civilization liked that name so much.
Speaker 0: they adopted it as their own name.
Speaker 0: awesome and this culture guy's like kind of want to become an affronter and everyone else is like what the fuck is wrong with you.
Speaker 0: but there's mantis men too.
Speaker 0: yeah mantis man they're not that they.
Speaker 1: uh they're not that great mantis men in ftl though are the best.
Speaker 0: i'm more a fan of a bunch of rock men to be honest.
Speaker 1: uh all right let's get in a fight.
Speaker 1: you're mantis man you're rock man.
Speaker 0: i just got my mantis man all right.
Speaker 0: fine you know what rock man mantis man.
Speaker 0: i'll just cut the oxygen in the room.
Speaker 0: that's fine.
Speaker 1: we're fighting inside my med bay on my ship.
Speaker 0: yeah you should play ftl advance because one thing you can start as is the mantis ship that doesn't really have a lot of weapons and you just teleport guys over and fuck shit up.
Speaker 0: yes the whole game is killing people.
Speaker 1: yes but then you get it's so much easier if you can board people because then you get to steal their ship and upgrade really fast.
Speaker 0: the game's an easy mode and then you get some anti-bio beams.
Speaker 0: you're also shooting deadly stuff at their ship but that doesn't hurt mantis.
Speaker 1: men it's good times.
Speaker 0: so uh yeah hopefully we'll keep doing shows right up until packs.
Speaker 0: but uh the week of packs there's gonna be no shows at all because if you don't live in the u.s.
Speaker 1: this is labor day weekend which is a holiday you don't know about but it's always the first weekend of september.
Speaker 1: so we're going to rim's gonna be going to packs like way earlier than me.
Speaker 0: me and emily are flying out to packs on tuesday because we're going to packs dev first then scott's joining us we're all going to the sky high tabletop charity as vips and then we're going not because we're actually vips but just because we paid for that.
Speaker 0: yes you realize most people who are vips paid for that or are friends with people who run whatever.
Speaker 0: that is.
Speaker 0: yeah in a general sense not this thing.
Speaker 0: just in general vip means money or nepotism.
Speaker 0: in this case money yes and then packs for four days and then we're flying back like the tuesday after pack.
Speaker 0: so we're gonna be gone for a is like tomorrow i think.
Speaker 0: uh-huh i'm going to pack sauce.
Speaker 1: okay i don't know if scott is so i don't think it's gonna happen like yeah i'm gonna go somewhere else.
Speaker 0: should we kick start you going?
Speaker 1: someone else gives me a whole pile of money.
Speaker 0: i'll just why did you just kick start like you going and doing the panels?
Speaker 1: because that's not a thing you can kick start.
Speaker 1: yes it is.
Speaker 1: you do it then i'm not doing it.
Speaker 0: the result of the kick start?
Speaker 0: well i i can just pay to go.
Speaker 1: you you kick start me going.
Speaker 0: why would i do that?
Speaker 0: i'll kick start me going and i'll just pocket that money.
Speaker 1: if anyone's just mad rich living in australia and you got money to burn send me some monies and maybe i'll go.
Speaker 0: the good news is as a result i submitted a panel that i've always.
Speaker 0: we did it.
Speaker 0: we never videoed it.
Speaker 0: i thought it was a great lecture so i rewrote it and i want to do it again.
Speaker 0: scott wants nothing to do with this.
Speaker 0: so that's what i'm hoping to do.
Speaker 0: a pack sauce.
Speaker 0: great it's.
Speaker 0: the losing should be fun.
Speaker 1: uh you and your losing should be fun.
Speaker 0: i think that was one of our better better lectures.
Speaker 0: i think it was way better than the other unvideoed one the egregiously unrealized potential.
Speaker 0: that one was not good that one was better than money-making games.
Speaker 0: i think maybe i like that one because it was basically the end was 20 minutes of us going contento.
Speaker 1: what the fuck the thing we just did just now.
Speaker 0: yes also that was the one where we got to talk a lot about how bionic commander rearmed was the true sequel and the actual sequel failed.
Speaker 1: everyone knows that.
Speaker 0: a lot of people don't seem to know what happened there.
Speaker 0: yeah i remember we pulled up the sales figures.
Speaker 0: the audience was like what.
Speaker 0: so yeah see you guys at packs.
Speaker 0: this has been geek nights with rim and scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music cat lee for web design and brand.
Speaker 1: ok for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech mondays gaming tuesdays anime comic wednesdays and indiscriminate thursdays.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.