Speaker 0: It's Monday, September 8th, 2014.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, upgrading computers.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Because somehow we never talked about that, at least not as a topic.
Speaker 1: Are you sure?
Speaker 0: I did a cursory search.
Speaker 1: That's about all we ever do.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Interestingly, I could not find an episode we'd ever done on hacking as a concept.
Speaker 1: Because it becomes a pedantic argument about, "Whoa, that's not hacking.
Speaker 1: Hacking is this.
Speaker 1: Hacking is
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 0: Scott, I believe that if you and I were to discuss hacking, we would not in fact get into a stupid and pedantic argument.
Speaker 1: No, but everyone listening would be, "Whatever we decided the definition of hacking was, people would be like, 'That's not
Speaker 1: hacking.'".
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: Fuck them.
Speaker 1: That's cracking.
Speaker 1: That's modding.
Speaker 1: That's a hack, but it's not hacking or a hacker.
Speaker 0: Fuck them.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We'd have to be more, you know, anyway.
Speaker 0: More what?
Speaker 1: More defensive.
Speaker 0: So we'd have to be hacking.
Speaker 0: colon the act of breaking into systems to which you do not have authorized access.
Speaker 1: You mean cracking?
Speaker 0: No, cracking is...
Speaker 1: This is why we're not doing that show.
Speaker 0: So you got any news?
Speaker 1: Well, there's a big Apple news tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Tomorrow's Apple Day.
Speaker 0: Oh no, there's gonna be another iPhone.
Speaker 1: Most of you are listening to this tomorrow, meaning today's Apple Day.
Speaker 0: iPhone.
Speaker 1: When I was driving home from a weekend getaway, we crossed midtown to get to the 59th Street Bridge and we passed by the Apple store and there were people waiting yesterday, which was the 7th.
Speaker 0: Guys, you just wait like a couple days and just walk into an Apple store.
Speaker 1: My contract doesn't run out.
Speaker 1: See, last year I waited a bit before getting the iPhone.
Speaker 1: Well, two years ago I waited a bit before getting an iPhone 5.
Speaker 1: So now my contract ends in October, so I can just chill out and pick it up in October.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm waiting because my phone works fine and I'd like a new phone.
Speaker 0: And I don't have to buy one right now.
Speaker 0: And last time I checked, the best phone I could get in terms of being relatively small and not shitty was the Moto X Developer Edition.
Speaker 0: Because that was actually cheaper than the regular Moto X. that was just worse in every possible way.
Speaker 1: Cool.
Speaker 1: So let's talk about some other hardware that is announced-ish.
Speaker 0: You sent me a picture of a Drobo looking thing.
Speaker 1: So I didn't know.
Speaker 1: TiVo was like still a thing, but apparently it is because people get DVRs that aren't the shitty ones that are attached to their cable plan.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: I imagine TiVo as being like Nectar and Adventure Time.
Speaker 1: So this is the TiVo's new product, the TiVo Mega.
Speaker 1: It's $5,000.
Speaker 1: It looks like 10 hard drives in it, which is about $1,000 worth.
Speaker 0: It's like a fucking 4U rack mount device.
Speaker 1: And then it's got a computer in it, so given the benefit of the doubt, that computer's $2,000.
Speaker 0: Who is this aimed at already?
Speaker 0: Rack mount!
Speaker 0: Who has a rack?
Speaker 1: And then I guess you're paying for TiVo software and stuff, so I'll give you a few hundred for that.
Speaker 1: So there's like a $1,500 markup on this thing, at least, if not more.
Speaker 0: The huge server-sized TiVo contains a whopping 24 terabytes of storage in a RAID 5 arrangement with hot, swappable drives.
Speaker 0: So it's just a SAN.
Speaker 1: Yes, but...
Speaker 0: That probably doesn't even have iSCSI.
Speaker 1: I think it can record more than one thing at a time, maybe.
Speaker 1: Better for $5,000.
Speaker 0: Anything could record more than one thing at a time.
Speaker 1: It better have at least two tuners.
Speaker 1: It better have at least two tuners, at least.
Speaker 1: But anyway, um, yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, it says six tuners.
Speaker 0: Who would ever need this for anything?
Speaker 1: So on the one hand, no one needs this for anything.
Speaker 1: On the other hand, no one needs this for anything.
Speaker 1: Seriously?
Speaker 1: You're gonna back up all of television for like the next day?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you watch one channel anyway, maybe two.
Speaker 1: If anyone who has this who's actually using all six tuners at once, right, prove to me that there's six things worth recording and keeping forever.
Speaker 1: If you're watching something and deleting it, you don't need this.
Speaker 1: You only need this if you have a legitimate reason to not only record six things at once, but to record so many things and to need to keep them around for all time.
Speaker 0: According to the article, if you keep high quality HD, I don't know if this is based on them speculating or based on the specs.
Speaker 1: 1080p.
Speaker 0: 4,000 hours total.
Speaker 0: That's not even that much content.
Speaker 1: Well, it's 10 a piece.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Most TV shows actually, even if you buy, let's say you buy the best cable package you can get, but the best dish package you can get.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do.
Speaker 1: It's called the internet and you have a four and you have a four K TV.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Almost nothing is in four K if nothing.
Speaker 1: And even tons of stuff is not even in 10 80 B. Lots of stuff is just 10 80 I or seven 20 peak because they don't want to use the bandwidth on the cable network for that or the satellite network.
Speaker 0: Also, the people who still watch broadcast TV largely can't tell.
Speaker 1: I wonder, here's the thing that's not mentioned, right?
Speaker 1: You're recording in HD, mostly video, but if TV shows are actually often in surround sound, if I record a TV show with this, no, you're not sounding so good there.
Speaker 1: Now is it, um, will it record, you know, 5.1 surround sound and play it back properly?
Speaker 0: That would actually be, all right, wait, I'm looking at the actual specs here because you seem to have just looked at the news.
Speaker 0: without 24 terabyte raid five, which already raid five.
Speaker 0: Really like raid technology is kind of, uh, I don't want to say obsolete, but there, there's better ways to do redundancy than raid in the modern era.
Speaker 1: Well, they've already said, right?
Speaker 0: Also raid five.
Speaker 0: If any one of those tendis dies, it is a race against the clock.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure it'll light up and you can take it out because there's, you know, on the front panel.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: It does a little bit more.
Speaker 0: So streaming live and recorded stuff so we can stream live stuff as you're watching it to smartphones and tablets.
Speaker 1: So it's also a sling box with built in stream transcoding also whistling box, multi-room.
Speaker 0: I don't know what that means.
Speaker 1: That means that, so normally a TiVo will have like one video out, right?
Speaker 1: So it's plugged into one TV.
Speaker 1: That's the TV you can watch recorded things on.
Speaker 1: So if you go upstairs to your bedroom, cause you have a house, not in a Newark apartment, you couldn't watch something from the TiVo upstairs because the TiVo is downstairs where this TiVo will stream to the other TV in the house.
Speaker 0: Universal search across the local stuff, cable listings, video on demand, Netflix.
Speaker 1: That's something that TiVo just does.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute and YouTube.
Speaker 0: Will it also record YouTube?
Speaker 1: I don't know if it'll record YouTube.
Speaker 1: That would be interesting.
Speaker 1: That would be, that would be interesting because one thing people don't know about TiVo is you have a TiVo, you can actually get the files off the TiVo pretty easily to use them, you know, for stuff on your computer.
Speaker 0: It's not what you watch.
Speaker 0: It does the same thing that I guess TiVo did or still does.
Speaker 0: It tells you what you should watch.
Speaker 1: But that's the, that's the thing that TiVo just does is if you have TiVo, you use that as your user interface for the whole TV.
Speaker 0: Use your smartphone or tablet as the remote control.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Something I can already do with just any cable.
Speaker 0: Slide Pro remote comes with it, including a full QWERTY keyboard to make fast text entry, RF, whatever.
Speaker 1: That's the TiVo remote control.
Speaker 0: Ethernet.
Speaker 1: That's the stream tour out the house.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: The YouTube and such also.
Speaker 0: There's really no other specs here.
Speaker 1: It's just a TiVo with a lot of space that's maxed out.
Speaker 0: I just, I can't imagine the person this is aimed at.
Speaker 0: The kind of person.
Speaker 1: I'm not even paying for cable.
Speaker 1: Do I really need to pay for a six X cable?
Speaker 0: The kind of person who this is aimed at is the kind of person who wouldn't be capable of using it.
Speaker 1: It's watch TV.
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: even then, that kind of person is better served by pirate bay and a net like by a fucking, you could
Speaker 1: almost justify using this at say some sort of media network where or like a news network where they're like, you know, getting clips from other, like if you work through the daily show, for example, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You could use this to record the daily show and the archive all your episodes forever, but yeah.
Speaker 1: Or you could record all the news programs, all six 24 hour news and then use the embedded built in search.
Speaker 1: I see where you're going with this, but if you are a pro like that, you're not using some consumer friendly as TiVo.
Speaker 1: You got that shit handled by the tech guys because you're a fucking TV network.
Speaker 1: You don't need this.
Speaker 0: Well, and I mean the, the more hours of television someone watches from broadcast, I imagine the less understanding of like having a homeland.
Speaker 1: they are really rich person who'd never home and gets home once a year and watches all the TV at once.
Speaker 0: If I were an overseas pirate who's providing illegal television to other people, this would be, this would be the best fucking thing in the world.
Speaker 0: Huh?
Speaker 1: Maybe that's not a good money deal.
Speaker 1: If you're smart enough for that, you can just build a computer to do that much better.
Speaker 0: And if you're the kind of person who's hobby is illegally redistributing American television broadcasts, I imagine you built your own crazy box with all the hard drives that people threw away.
Speaker 1: But one thing to point out though, if you build your own crazy box, it's probably a lot harder to get six TV tuners than it is to just buy this.
Speaker 1: TV tuners, good ones that just work like these ones.
Speaker 0: They exist.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but not easy.
Speaker 1: They're a little finicky.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but even then $5,000 that's a lot of money.
Speaker 0: $5,000.
Speaker 0: with $5,000 I could buy like three fully loaded out like Drobo five ends for less than $5,000 a year.
Speaker 0: I could buy the maximum cable satellite package, but then you wouldn't have everything you'd ever seen on it forever.
Speaker 1: I don't need that.
Speaker 0: Or for, you know, 4,000 hours worth of content.
Speaker 1: If I'm paying that much, I'm watching that shit live.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Huh?
Speaker 0: It's interesting.
Speaker 0: Really curious who decided this was a good idea.
Speaker 1: Who at TiVo came up with this thought it was a good idea, you know, actually went through with it and developed it and now decided to go ahead and sell it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I mean, they even make it big deal about how user swappable drives already trouble.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So in other, uh, interesting news, so people using drones for a lot of awesome stuff, pretty much only used for awesome stuff except for killing people.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends with some people just need killing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, it happens.
Speaker 0: We did a show on kill bots.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So the FAA has done something interesting.
Speaker 0: They've escalated the war because it's basically technically illegal to use drones for pretty much any commercial purpose, but tons of people are using them because they're so easy to use to like look for wells or like keep track of your cattle or just like all the stuff that you might want to use a drone for.
Speaker 0: Like people just doing this.
Speaker 0: The FAA has been going around the internet looking for anyone who's using drones for any useful purpose and sending them cnds.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Like if you post a youtube video of using a drone for something.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: They're literally a quote.
Speaker 0: Those who use UAS only for recreational enjoyment, operate in accordance with advisory circular 91 dash 57 cetera.
Speaker 0: Generally applies to remote.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: That's a really long paragraph.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to read, but basically they are trying to prevent people from using them for such example topics as tornado research, inspecting gas well stacks or aerial photography, journalism, education.
Speaker 1: I guess they want you to pay them now to get an FAA license.
Speaker 0: No, you can't really get licenses in most situations because there's no precedent for using drones for these sorts of things.
Speaker 0: Basically what's happened here is that the technology around drones like autonomous or like far remote drones has so rapidly eclipsed our ability to regulate it, but simultaneously our regulatory bodies are just competent enough to be able to trivially find all the people who are using this.
Speaker 1: It's not the regulator that is competent enough.
Speaker 1: It's the bureaucrat who's enforcing the existing regulations and the regulators are basically not making any new regulations or changing them.
Speaker 0: So I want to know what intern at FAA at the FAA ruined everything by telling their superior that you could just Google for this stuff.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling it was figured it out on their own feeling.
Speaker 1: A superior said, you know, Hey, you know, any, whoever enforces, you know, the most thingies gets bonuses and is, you know, surprise, something like that.
Speaker 1: Like, Hey, bureaucrats who enforce regulations, whoever can report the most violations gets prize maybe.
Speaker 0: And the prize.
Speaker 0: Well, so we'll see what happens because the real issue is simply that Congress, the United States Congress has literally zero capacity to deal with this issue.
Speaker 1: And he kind of any small issue.
Speaker 0: Well, this issue, I don't think is small.
Speaker 0: The problem is I think, and I'm going to make a really pessimistic and I think accurate prediction.
Speaker 0: It will be more than 20 years before Congress deals with this issue effectively.
Speaker 1: You know, in other countries, this is not a problem.
Speaker 0: Actually, this is a problem in a lot of other countries.
Speaker 1: I didn't say every other country.
Speaker 0: I say there are three.
Speaker 0: This is, well, I can name one Somalia.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: I've seen plenty of like TV shows from other countries and not just Korea, but that is one of them because that is the one I watch the most TV shows from.
Speaker 1: They're just using drones to film shit all the fucking time.
Speaker 0: So here's the question, because the same thing's happening in the U S major TV, the same thing's happening in the U S. So the question is, is it in these countries illegal?
Speaker 0: And how are the regulators just not even at the level of responding?
Speaker 0: Are they just ignoring old law?
Speaker 0: Like the problem is that the laws just don't have any way to deal with this stuff.
Speaker 1: If there's no law about something, at least in the U S that means it's legal.
Speaker 0: So here's an interesting example of how that's really starting to backfire.
Speaker 0: Someone made a really cool drone thing where say you're skiing, right?
Speaker 0: The drone will follow you circling at a predefined distance and following a pattern and just get awesome video of you skiing.
Speaker 0: Cool.
Speaker 0: Totally awesome.
Speaker 0: Uh, that is banned at ski resorts and there's some laws around it.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: However, there is a way there is a loophole to get around the law that is far more dangerous than breaking the law, which is attached the drone to a tether.
Speaker 0: If you do that, you now have a rotating neck catcher, but simultaneously you're not breaking that law anymore, but it will strangle you to death.
Speaker 0: Well, it'll probably strangle someone else or maybe get caught on it.
Speaker 1: If it goes around you 360 degrees all at once, then it will tie you up.
Speaker 0: Well, they could.
Speaker 0: Scott, I can imagine tethers where that is not.
Speaker 1: what would happen to like a screw on the top of your helmet and it just stays above you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think the problem will be if you run into anything.
Speaker 0: So I don't know what to do about this.
Speaker 0: It's a, the problem is that these tech issues are no longer tech issues.
Speaker 0: There are solely bureaucracy issues and we will likely not see in our youth any action taken by any major world government.
Speaker 0: I don't know what to do about this, but the problems are amazing and the technology is moving so quickly.
Speaker 0: Look at how, look at one funeral at a time.
Speaker 1: The next.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but look at in the last five years, how rapidly drones went from toys to extremely commercially useful.
Speaker 0: So things of the day, uh, I found this, it's an anime music video called night of the hunter and it is set to the Kirby anime and it seems to follow a meta night.
Speaker 0: The character.
Speaker 0: I make this my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: One, because it has as of now 318 views and 14 likes.
Speaker 0: So the internet has not seen this.
Speaker 0: and two, it is proof of a, of a new internet theory and anime music video to a thing can guaranteedly make that thing seem a thousand times more awesome than it is.
Speaker 1: I think I've seen this before.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: This, this AMV, not the, not the same view specifically, but like that shot of meta night.
Speaker 1: I feel like I've seen that somewhere.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 0: You know where you might've seen it is in that Evangelion opener to, uh, set to the animation from Kirby, the animation.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so Calcio Fiorentino also known as Calcio Storico historic football is an early form of football that originated in 16th century Italy.
Speaker 1: Once widely played.
Speaker 1: The sport is thought to originated in the Piazza Santa Croce in Florence.
Speaker 1: Here it became known as the G go Dell Italian word.
Speaker 1: This is excellent or simply Calcio, which is now also the name for football in the Italian language.
Speaker 1: Uh, so basically there's four sections of Italy, the blues, the reds, the whites and the greens.
Speaker 1: Oh, Florence, right?
Speaker 1: Each quarter of Florence, uh, is represented by a team.
Speaker 1: And once a year on June 24th, they play this game.
Speaker 1: Uh, it's pretty much football that doesn't stop.
Speaker 1: You can do whatever you want to get the ball and the net touchdown at the other end to get a point.
Speaker 1: And you have a zillion dudes and also some historic pomp and circumstance.
Speaker 0: Scott showed this to me and before it was explained what was going on.
Speaker 0: Here's how I would describe it.
Speaker 0: Not knowing there is a huge line of boxers facing off, beating the ever living fuck out of each other.
Speaker 1: Okay, so here we go.
Speaker 1: I'm going to read the rules from Wikipedia because why not?
Speaker 1: Matches last 50 minutes and are played 50 5 0. played in a field covered in sand twice as long as it is wide.
Speaker 1: A white line divides it in half.
Speaker 1: A goal runs the width of each end.
Speaker 1: Each team has 27 players with no substitutions.
Speaker 1: The teams are made of four goalkeepers, three fullbacks, five halfbacks and 15 forwards.
Speaker 1: Captain and standard bears tent sits at the center of the goal net.
Speaker 1: They do not actively participate, but can organize their teams.
Speaker 1: They act sometimes act as reps and mainly to calm down the players or to stop fights, stop fights.
Speaker 1: Uh, there's a ref and he has six lines.
Speaker 0: The only things you're not allowed to do are sucker punches and kicks to the head.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Head butting, punching, elbowing and choking are totally okay.
Speaker 1: Every anything else is okay.
Speaker 0: So it's, oh, more than one person can't attack another person at the same time.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, uh, players try by any means necessary to get the ball into the opponent's goal.
Speaker 0: Guys, any means necessary.
Speaker 1: I mean, it is important to shoot with precision because every time a player misses, the opposing team gets half a point.
Speaker 1: So basically no one goes for like the long throw that they lands in the score area.
Speaker 1: They fight until there's an opening and then run over and put it in very carefully or relatively carefully.
Speaker 0: Like at one point there was just this line of people and they have their fists up like old, uh, and then one guy he's looking at the other guy looking at each other in the eye.
Speaker 0: They got their fists up and then he just hauls back and kicks him in the nuts.
Speaker 1: I do really like this rule though of, you know, the, if you take a shot and the other team gets half a point, I feel like that mechanic could be used in other, not ridiculously violent games, soccer, even board games,
Speaker 0: soccer,
Speaker 1: even less shots and even more boring in games where, you know, shots are too much.
Speaker 1: It could help basketball a lot, right?
Speaker 1: You wouldn't take a shot.
Speaker 0: Well, that would just mean no one would ever go for it.
Speaker 0: It would only dunk.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, there are ways you could use this, you know, kind of rule, maybe in conjunction with other modifications to improve a lot of games or sports to basically when people are just shooting like crazy or just trying to score like crazy because there's no reason not to, right?
Speaker 1: You can force people to be much more careful, uh, in their attack strategies by basically awarding points to the other team for failed offense.
Speaker 1: Like what if in football, if you didn't get a field goal or a touchdown on your drive, the other team got a point.
Speaker 1: If they, if the defense gets a stop that you score points, so suddenly defense becomes way more important, right?
Speaker 0: This is amazing.
Speaker 0: And at least at one point in my life before I die, I want to be in live attendance of this game and go to Florence on June 24th.
Speaker 0: And also, uh, these guys get points because the uniforms they wear are basically, it's like a cross between a modern sports outfit and pantaloons.
Speaker 1: They somehow have not completely removed this.
Speaker 1: It's like this kind of reenactment aspect of the sport, which is great.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, I think this would be really popular if it were played in the United States, but it would also be illegal.
Speaker 1: It's basically football earliest, most primitive form of football that I've seen ever.
Speaker 0: It also illustrates something like it.
Speaker 0: I love this video because it's so primal and so fucked up, but at the same time, uh, watch this and then watch modern American football.
Speaker 0: And that is why there are rules in sports.
Speaker 1: That's why football has more rules than all the other sports in the meta moment.
Speaker 0: The book club book is a canticle for Liebowitz.
Speaker 1: I've read two thirds of it.
Speaker 0: Ah, did you get the spaceships?
Speaker 1: I am on the first page of spaceships.
Speaker 0: Oh, spaceships is by far the most depressing section of that book.
Speaker 1: The second section was rather depressing.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: You thought the second section was depressing?
Speaker 1: Slightly.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 0: Why do you read the third section?
Speaker 1: It was like silver lining depressing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The first section might be the most depressing depending on how you look at it.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: We've got to save our commentary for after we both read it all the way through.
Speaker 0: I might have to read it again.
Speaker 0: It's been so long.
Speaker 0: I don't remember many details at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I wonder why it took so long.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: We have no major conventions coming up until PAX Australia, which is coming up in like two months.
Speaker 1: I'm not going.
Speaker 0: I'm going.
Speaker 0: So I will see you all there.
Speaker 0: Happy.
Speaker 1: Fricking.
Speaker 1: Why does the grocery store have like Halloween shit already?
Speaker 0: Uh, I have not seen that.
Speaker 1: I saw Halloween candy.
Speaker 1: I even saw Hanukkah shit.
Speaker 0: Uh, I'm waiting to hear.
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess it was Rosh Hashanah shit, but yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm waiting.
Speaker 1: That's actually appropriate.
Speaker 1: That's like the first Christmas song.
Speaker 0: You will know because I will tweet a lot of obscenity the moment I hear a Christmas song.
Speaker 1: Five weeks.
Speaker 0: And any retail establishment.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be, it was before Halloween last year.
Speaker 1: So give it five weeks, five to six weeks.
Speaker 0: I suppose I could avoid going into stores, thus avoiding this.
Speaker 1: I can't avoid going to work.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: Why would you hear it at work?
Speaker 1: I'm at work at 49th and 7th.
Speaker 1: It might as well be fucking Santa's workshop.
Speaker 0: You might as well, you know, earplugs.
Speaker 1: Eye plugs.
Speaker 0: Practice being blind.
Speaker 0: Try to walk from the subway to your door without opening your eyes.
Speaker 1: They're replacing the, uh, you know, the billboards on my office building with digital signage.
Speaker 0: That won't be annoying.
Speaker 1: I'm glad it faces away from the building.
Speaker 1: So, and we don't, none of our windows are near it, but still it's there.
Speaker 0: So yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, the other day we, uh, you know, we're back from PAX and we recorded panels and a bunch of other content in glorious 4k.
Speaker 0: We're not uploading that shit in 4k.
Speaker 0: So, uh, that's awesome at all.
Speaker 0: Went to edit that shit.
Speaker 0: And the first thing I realized was that, uh, I built my computer, the one I'm using right now for geek nights in 2009.
Speaker 1: Oh, well five years.
Speaker 1: Time to upgrade.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I have not upgraded yet.
Speaker 1: Or buy a new one.
Speaker 0: And in fact, the only thing I've had to upgrade in the entire span of this computer was I bought a $0 now and I bought a better video card at one point.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Now I have to upgrade again.
Speaker 0: I just ordered a couple of, uh, 256 gigabyte SSDs.
Speaker 1: That's not really, it's kind of an upgrade.
Speaker 0: Well, it's an upgrade because when I first bought this computer, I put windows on a 32 gigabyte SSD that I paid like $300 for because it was 2009 when I did that.
Speaker 0: And that was awesome.
Speaker 0: Later I moved windows from that 32 gigabyte SSD to a spinning disk because windows outgrew it and there's no way to fix that.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: So that slowed the computer down to a degree, at least until it booted up because between 12 gigs of RAM and ready boost, pretty much it took forever to boot, but once it was booted, it was fine.
Speaker 0: But one panel recorded in 4k, plus the 1080p backup video from an alternate angle and the audio is like 80 gigabytes.
Speaker 0: I can't put the whole thing on an SSD.
Speaker 0: In fact, I interleaved the segments across two spinning disks and the SSD, but the moral is I can't really edit 4k video unless it's on an SSD.
Speaker 0: So I bought a couple of cheapo 256 gigabyte SSDs to add to this computer.
Speaker 0: I think I can get another two years out of it.
Speaker 0: Easily.
Speaker 1: Computers are lasting longer than they ever did.
Speaker 1: Mine, I don't know when I bought it, but it's lasting way long and needs no upgrades, but that's because I went all the fuck out.
Speaker 0: I did too.
Speaker 0: I spent like $3,800 on this computer.
Speaker 1: I have a GTX 680, 32 gigs of RAM, i7 ridiculousness, and it hasn't needed any upgrading ever.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I mean, I got a, I got an i7.
Speaker 1: I got this one.
Speaker 1: The 680 was new.
Speaker 1: So that's figured out when that was.
Speaker 0: I don't even have USB three.
Speaker 1: I have USB three.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Your computer is way newer than mine.
Speaker 1: So the, you know, the best thing about upgrading is something like a hard drive, which is not really a tech sort of an upgrade, whatever is keeping the old stuff.
Speaker 1: It's like, you upgrade your video card, your old video card.
Speaker 1: Goodbye.
Speaker 1: You know, my 800, my 8,800 GT is gone.
Speaker 1: Someone else has it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But, uh, you know, when I had the old previous computer, I had a 128 gig SSD in that, in that computer.
Speaker 1: I didn't buy it when I made that computer.
Speaker 1: I bought it later when I got the new computer, but a 256 gig SSD.
Speaker 1: And now I got two SSDs.
Speaker 1: Oh, and the 128 one is like, you know, my Adobe premiere Photoshop swap discy thing.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is, you know, if I tried it, it's hard because the advice I would give on how upgrading computers works is different every five years because technology has actually changed.
Speaker 0: Like consumer PC technology has changed a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Since like the nineties.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, the trend has been with a few exceptions up, you can upgrade computers pretty semi indefinitely at this point because CPU is pretty much never the bottleneck anymore.
Speaker 1: Well, it's sometimes isn't a better CPU to get.
Speaker 0: Well, like, well, I'll put it this way for what most of you listening use your computers for.
Speaker 0: Like, especially like anyone who uses like playing games or whatever, the video card matters more than everything else in your computer.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And if you're not using a video card, nothing else in your.
Speaker 1: nothing in the computer is holding you back.
Speaker 0: So, cause I, the reason I thought of this episode was I saw a friend who will remain nameless, who was saying that, Oh, GTA five is coming out.
Speaker 0: I guess I got to get a new PC.
Speaker 0: My gaming PC doesn't really hold up anymore.
Speaker 1: Just buy a new video card.
Speaker 0: I was like, what video card do you have?
Speaker 0: Just buy a new one.
Speaker 0: I don't upgrade computers.
Speaker 0: That's really hard.
Speaker 0: Not worth the effort.
Speaker 1: I'm anti intellectual and like spending a bunch of ridiculous, unnecessary money on things like dude, what you're going to buy?
Speaker 0: a thousand dollar new one.
Speaker 1: My car needs an oil change.
Speaker 1: Better buy a new car.
Speaker 0: If you buy like a thousand dollar new computer, the video card it comes with is probably shit.
Speaker 1: That's also true.
Speaker 0: If you buy a $400 video card, you can probably keep using the same computer for another two to four years.
Speaker 0: I mean, the greatest thing is I run, I ran one time I rendered a video in software mode.
Speaker 0: I haven't turned off the video card acceleration just to see.
Speaker 0: And I ran the windows performance profiler for the entire render just to see like what was being used.
Speaker 0: And sure I could, in that case, I maxed out my CPU a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: Whoa.
Speaker 1: All the cores.
Speaker 1: All eight.
Speaker 1: Whoa.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, disk IO was at like 80%.
Speaker 0: And Ram, I was using maybe half my Ram.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But then when I switched to a video card rendering, CPU is not maxed out.
Speaker 0: Disk IO is literally the hundred percent bottleneck.
Speaker 0: And if I render solely from an SSD, I can't actually tell.
Speaker 0: Like it kind of jumps around.
Speaker 0: Like at that point renders go so fast that it literally like is no longer concerned.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, even a video render, an HD video rendering, which is something that takes, unless it happens instantly, like you click export and it says done.
Speaker 1: There's some bottleneck somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But you're playing a video game and it's rendering one frame.
Speaker 1: every time your monitor refreshes the end.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: You're done.
Speaker 0: So if you got a hundred frame monitor, you need to render a hundred frames at that resolution.
Speaker 1: No one has a hundred frame monitor.
Speaker 1: You either have like a 60, a 75 or a 120.
Speaker 1: Probably a 60 or 120.
Speaker 0: Man, that's something that changed a lot.
Speaker 0: Remember CRTs?
Speaker 0: I ran my CRT at RIT at a hundred Hertz.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There were nineties and stuff like that too.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well, if I ran it under about 75, like I ran it at 60, it would make kind of a noise.
Speaker 1: So 60 by the way, 60 is enough for pretty much anything you're going to do.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: 120 is if you have 3d because it's basically doing two sixties left eye, right eye, left eye, right eye, left eye, right eye.
Speaker 0: 240 buys you nothing.
Speaker 0: Nothing.
Speaker 1: Waste.
Speaker 0: But seriously guys, if you're thinking, if your computer seems slow and it seems slow as a gamer, uh, just buy a video card.
Speaker 0: I highly doubt your video card is already the second fastest video card on Mi Pro silence.
Speaker 1: That's some other upgradey bullshit, right?
Speaker 1: So more RAM, a lot of people like, man, I buy more RAM.
Speaker 1: Number one, it could be when you don't have enough RAM that you're just really bad at computer.
Speaker 1: That's actually the most likely thing.
Speaker 1: I have computers that don't have much RAM in them, like four gigs, which is not a lot these days.
Speaker 1: And I had never used all that RAM ever.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: Because A on that computer, for example, my work computer, I'm not doing anything ridiculous.
Speaker 1: I actually am doing some things like virtual machines, but even that doesn't push the limits of four gigs.
Speaker 0: Most of the people who complain like, ah, I need more RAM.
Speaker 0: I'm using on my RAM.
Speaker 1: Why does your Chrome have 10,000 tabs open?
Speaker 0: But even then, if you look, they're still not swapping.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: Like they mistake, like, yeah, like.
Speaker 0: right now I'm looking at my computer.
Speaker 0: I've got 12 gigs of RAM.
Speaker 0: I've turned swapping off because I literally do not need it.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I've got four gigs of cash, eight gigs available, four gigs free.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It is very unlikely that you actually need more RAM or that it will do anything for you.
Speaker 1: And even if you are filling up your RAM, it's probably just your shitty behavior.
Speaker 1: Or you let a bunch of shit ruin your computer and it's all running in the background.
Speaker 1: Shit you don't need that.
Speaker 1: you should uninstall or clear out or viruses or who knows what.
Speaker 1: And you just fucked up your computer.
Speaker 1: And that's why your RAM is full.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I've pretty much never seen anyone using all the RAM unless either a piddly amount of RAM or they think they're using all the RAM because they don't know what all those metrics mean.
Speaker 1: If you are not swapping, which means your computer has literally used all of the RAM and is using hard drive as extra RAM because it has no choice.
Speaker 1: More RAM will do absolutely nothing for you whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Now, simultaneously, I've seen people suggest that you should have an SSD and put your swap on that.
Speaker 0: No, just buy more RAM.
Speaker 0: Yes, just buy more RAM.
Speaker 0: That's cheaper than SSDs.
Speaker 1: If your computer can't hold more RAM, then you should upgrade maybe your actual computer.
Speaker 1: But, you know, four gigs at work, just doing normal everyday stuff that, you know, and a virtual machine, which means more more so than people are just doing web browsing and shit is more than enough.
Speaker 1: So if you've got eight or if you've got more than four, you don't need more.
Speaker 0: So part of the reason I bought the computer I did, the motherboard I got actually was really expensive compared to other motherboards.
Speaker 0: You know what it's got going for it?
Speaker 0: One, it's got like a fuck ton of sados, like way more than I could ever use, which seemed like I would use it back then.
Speaker 0: And then I ended up not so much like I made some raids and I kind of didn't need them anymore.
Speaker 0: But because hard drive technology just got so much better, but it had six dim slots.
Speaker 0: So I've got, I just filled that thing up with two gigabyte sticks.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So
Speaker 0: there used to be a time when you'd buy cards to upgrade your computer like, well, there used to be a time when you would buy like a chip to put over your four eighty six or over your three eighty six or like you'd put a math coprocessor in there.
Speaker 1: Those were days.
Speaker 1: There were days where you just replace your CPU in the same motherboard.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I remember those days.
Speaker 0: Remember we went from sockets to slot or slot sockets to slots to sockets again.
Speaker 1: There were days when your motherboard only had S.A.T.
Speaker 1: at thirty three ribbon cable connectors.
Speaker 1: You bought an eighty sixty six controller for your PCI slot connected drives to the computer I'm using.
Speaker 0: now that I built in 2009 is the first computer I've ever built that didn't have at least one like legacy ISO or ISA slot hanging off on the back.
Speaker 1: I think mine might have an ISIS.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: This one doesn't even have PCI.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 0: It only has PCI X six.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't even know anymore.
Speaker 0: But seriously, anyone who says that buying a new computer periodically is more cost effective than building a slightly better computer yourself and then periodically upgrading it is flat out wrong.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Now, it's situations for the Mac people out there, right?
Speaker 1: Because in the Mac world, first of all, Apple, they're going to rip you off.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: When you buy a brand new Mac, everybody knows they're overcharging for the RAM.
Speaker 1: And if you buy an Apple device, they overcharge and for the storage, it's like, oh, you want to get a sixty four gig iPhone instead of a thirty two gig iPhone.
Speaker 1: That'll be one hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: Dude, I just paid one hundred dollars for one twenty eight gig as is SD card for my camera.
Speaker 1: You can't be charging me one hundred dollars for thirty two gigs.
Speaker 1: Fuck you.
Speaker 1: But in an iPad, what are you going to do?
Speaker 1: They don't let you open that shit up, which is why PCs are better than Macs.
Speaker 1: And in fact, most Macs these days, you can hardly open that shit up.
Speaker 1: I think they let you get to the RAM slots on some of them.
Speaker 1: I'm not even sure which ones anymore.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And the Mac Pro is that big black thing now.
Speaker 1: Like even that those video cards, it's like you can't just switch out those cards.
Speaker 1: You don't know the OS X as a driver for that.
Speaker 1: You don't know, you know, that it's going to work in that weird slot or something.
Speaker 1: And they're overcharging you by a lot.
Speaker 1: So it really sucks big time.
Speaker 1: You know, it not only do at max cost more, but upgrading them is like losing an option.
Speaker 1: So you do kind of need to buy a new computer when they start sucking, which is right away because the video cards they come with are garbage.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And you know what I do.
Speaker 0: as a result, every fall of the year old video cards in them, I just buy a new laptop.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I have every old laptop I've ever owned because they don't stop working now.
Speaker 1: The other thing with Apple is in terms of what we said about running out of RAM.
Speaker 1: OS X is just really shitty at using RAM compared to Windows, which is shitty compared to Linux.
Speaker 1: OS X is awful at managing memory.
Speaker 0: Can you back that up?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Everyone at my work, it's just like I'm running the same stuff.
Speaker 1: everyone else is running, you know, Chrome and the virtual machine and whatever.
Speaker 1: And you look at their Macs and they're just using way more RAM.
Speaker 0: Huh?
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I honestly don't know enough about Apple memory management.
Speaker 1: It's like they open up Photoshop.
Speaker 1: I open up Photoshop.
Speaker 1: My computer is four gigs of RAM.
Speaker 1: I'm just fine.
Speaker 1: They're like, shit, I'm almost running out.
Speaker 0: Huh?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's interesting, actually.
Speaker 1: So, and the thing is, Apple also be charging you so much for the extra RAM.
Speaker 1: So you have to do is when you buy a Mac, get the lowest amount of RAM, hope you get a Mac that allows you to change the RAM, then go online and buy a RAM from some third party and put it in there yourself.
Speaker 1: Don't let Apple store do it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So just skip all the Mac mini because I mean, every upgrade I could actually list every upgrade I've ever given to a computer in my entire life.
Speaker 0: That's, that's sort of telling it on how useful this is.
Speaker 0: My 486, SX2, it had four megabytes of RAM and I convinced my dad to spend $300 and we bought four more megabytes.
Speaker 1: Ours had eight and I upped it to 16.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you, when we got that, when we got up to eight.
Speaker 1: No more boot disks.
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: When we got the eight, I could play doom.
Speaker 0: I didn't even use a boot disk for doom.
Speaker 1: I'd hold F5 to boot into like, well I had eight, so I never used a boot disk for doom, but I didn't even have, once I had 16, I didn't even need a boot disk for Mac warrior two.
Speaker 0: I still used a boot disk for, oh, what did I use a boot disk for?
Speaker 0: Some quest for glory games and fantasy empires because they perform better.
Speaker 0: if I did it that way.
Speaker 1: My friends had dual speed CD roms.
Speaker 1: I had quad speed.
Speaker 1: I could install doom so fast.
Speaker 0: Man, you're like that kid with the Neo Geo.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: So yeah, that was my upgrade.
Speaker 0: And then, then the most important upgrade I ever did in my entire life to a computer.
Speaker 0: We had a built-in, like Fort 16 sound cars, piece of shit.
Speaker 0: I convinced my parents to buy me a sound blaster, all 32, my advanced wave effects.
Speaker 0: that when I installed that, then I would proceed to play tie fighter and X-wing.
Speaker 0: The music in those games was MIDI.
Speaker 0: And because the all 32 had it embedded, like real MIDI support and MIDI chips, uh, that music sounded amazing.
Speaker 1: We had a sound blaster 16 from the start in the 46.
Speaker 0: Oh, you didn't have advanced wave effects though.
Speaker 1: No, but that Pentium three, four 50 that I brought to RIT that I built myself in 1999 board.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That one had a sound blaster live.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I bought a sound blaster live with surround sound and I've had surround sound ever since.
Speaker 0: In fact, I remember I got the one that had that like front panel with all that stuff.
Speaker 1: because that, that I didn't have that ridiculous one.
Speaker 1: I had the cheap sound blaster live.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I had the full on one, the five 12, what?
Speaker 0: I don't, I even forget what they were called gold platinum.
Speaker 1: I don't remember the silver one or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But remember I was really into like music and audio and I thought I'd use that front panel and the SPDIF and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: No, you weren't.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That was only if you're a musician.
Speaker 0: I use the MIDI a lot.
Speaker 1: I use the midi and games that use the midi.
Speaker 0: I use the midi to compose too.
Speaker 0: I had a pirated copy of Cakewalk.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to copy Cakewalk, but didn't pirate one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Ken had it and he gave it to me and we, we did a lot of midi back in the day.
Speaker 1: Did not do midi.
Speaker 1: I did a video game.
Speaker 0: I was, you know, I was really into midi.
Speaker 0: Like I had a huge midi collection.
Speaker 0: It's hanging out in that hard drive right next to, uh, uh, Hey people.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So then we bought the Pentium 200 and I bought, I upgrade, I bought for that a video card.
Speaker 1: That Pentium 3450 was the first time I bought a video card when I built the thing and I had a TNT too the day it came out.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 0: I bought a creative graphics blaster extreme.
Speaker 0: That was when I could play GL quick.
Speaker 0: That was amazing.
Speaker 0: And I bought some more RAM for that thing at one point and I bought like an extra card on the back that gave me USBs and I didn't buy much else for it.
Speaker 0: After that I bought, I got that SCSI card so I could have my SCSI Plextor CDR.
Speaker 1: After that, there was just many, many years of various AMD mishmash because that shit was broken.
Speaker 0: But that was the era when you bought, you buy a motherboard and then you'd buy a processor and some RAM and video cards and stuff.
Speaker 0: And then like you'd periodically just swap out individual components during the college years, early two thousands.
Speaker 1: We kept, it was, you know, late, late nineties, early, just like buying stuff.
Speaker 1: The acceleration in hardware, you know, performance was just so much and prices kept going down and old stuff and new stuff could come out.
Speaker 1: That was actually way better.
Speaker 0: Like I bought an 800 megahertz processor and then six months later it was worth it to me to buy a gigahertz processor.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It was like golden age.
Speaker 1: Just kept buying stuff, buying stuff, switching CPU's in the same motherboard.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Slot A.
Speaker 1: Craziness was going on.
Speaker 1: Uh, Socket A mostly.
Speaker 1: These are all Socket A machines.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I had slot A until that motherboard exploded because I got hit by the, uh, bootleg Chinese industrial espionage, uh, capacitor problem on my a bit board.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But ever since the, you know, the overclocking era too, but ever since the I three, I five, I seven era is hardly any reason to upgrade computers last so much longer now.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Because I mean, you're limited pretty much by video card.
Speaker 0: And if you're not limited by that, you're limited by disc IO.
Speaker 0: I highly doubt anything else is limiting you.
Speaker 1: And video cards are the only thing that are getting better.
Speaker 1: And you might be like, well, how come video cards are getting better and CPU's aren't?
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: When they're making CPU's, especially these days, they're trying to make them faster, of course, but they don't want to make them less efficient, especially since they're mostly being used in laptops and things of that nature.
Speaker 1: They want them to use less energy and also their general purpose.
Speaker 1: Yes, they do all, they're not specific, you know, geared towards this one task.
Speaker 1: They need to be able to do anything.
Speaker 0: So CPU's aren't getting that much faster, but they're not, not only are they not getting faster, they're getting slower.
Speaker 0: Clock speeds are going down to accommodate more cores, different memories, stuff like if you look at server hardware, like Xeons, like crazy stuff, higher end servers have lower clock speeds than what you would put in your desktop PC.
Speaker 0: In fact, if you want high clock speeds, like really high clock speeds, a lot of the processors that have actually higher clock speeds have fewer cores or disabled cores or other trade-offs.
Speaker 1: But video cards is the land of we don't give a fuck.
Speaker 1: Why are they faster?
Speaker 1: Well, the chips aren't actually like ridiculously that much.
Speaker 1: It's like the same fabrication technologies we have for CPU's.
Speaker 1: It's not something special.
Speaker 1: It's that they just don't give a fuck.
Speaker 1: So like, oh, let's just put like four GPU's on here with hella fans and use 10 zillion electricities.
Speaker 0: Well, put it this way.
Speaker 0: If you have an SLI set up, like two video cards, that shit's bigger than my laptop.
Speaker 0: It's like my whole laptop.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, my car is slow.
Speaker 1: I should get a better engine.
Speaker 1: I already have a V12.
Speaker 1: I guess I'll just have two V12s then.
Speaker 1: That's a video card.
Speaker 1: Whereas, you know, the CPU is like, I've got a four cylinder turbo.
Speaker 1: How can I make this faster?
Speaker 1: It's really fucking hard without just button to V12 instead.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, for a lot of what, especially you guys, like listeners of GeekKnives are doing with your computers, the video card matters more than everything else.
Speaker 0: So it's optimized to do the few things you do that actually tax a computer, which is matrix math, rendering images and holding textures and memory, applying them to services.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, my video editing, I mean, it would take about 25 hours in software only mode to render the video of the panel with the 4K.
Speaker 0: But I started a test render to kind of scope it out and to test some stuff.
Speaker 0: Nine hours.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Nine hours with the CUDA cores doing their thing.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So yeah, if your computer is slow, video card.
Speaker 0: If the video card isn't the problem, replace whatever disk your applications run from with an SSD.
Speaker 0: If you're already on an SSD and you already have the second fastest video card, it's probably, you know, 90 percent of time.
Speaker 1: if you have a PC and it's running poorly or even a Mac is running poorly, it's because you put a bunch of shitty fucking crap on there.
Speaker 1: Clean up, reinstall your OS cleanly and don't fuck it up this time, because you still will every time because you're not me and everyone but me fucks it up.
Speaker 1: But try not to fuck it up as much as you did the last time.
Speaker 1: Don't install your ghetto ass software.
Speaker 1: If you're not sure if software is ghetto ass, ask me.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: To summarize it actually more simply, you don't need to upgrade your computer most likely except for the video card and everything else.
Speaker 1: And you definitely don't need to buy a new computer in the year 2014.
Speaker 1: You just need to upgrade it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: If you need to, which is unlikely.
Speaker 0: And if you're going to build a brand new computer now, like say you're running.
Speaker 1: Maybe your computer actually is mad old because you have bad money.
Speaker 1: Your computer is like 10 years old.
Speaker 0: You've got like an AMD K7.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: In that case, buy like a super fast, super awesome like core I5 or I7.
Speaker 0: Get a good extensible motherboard with a whole bunch of dims and sadies and whatever.
Speaker 0: Spend more money on the power supply than you think you should.
Speaker 0: In fact, spend double what you think you should.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Don't I don't know.
Speaker 0: Don't buy like a 10,000 watt like, oh my God, ridiculous power thing.
Speaker 1: But also don't get the twenty dollar going to explode and not work thing.
Speaker 0: Don't buy high wattage by high quality.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I usually get like the four hundred five hundred watt, like super efficient and viral friendly and tech ultra reliable power supply.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But seriously, don't skimp on the power supply because if you had a problem, don't get a twenty dollar one.
Speaker 0: I've noticed a lot of people are afraid of upgrading because they they hear horror stories.
Speaker 0: They've experienced things where like they try to upgrade the computer because they built their own computer.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: An incompetent person screwed something up.
Speaker 1: That is not a reason not to do the thing unless you are also incompetent, in which case you shouldn't not do the thing.
Speaker 1: You should become not incompetent.
Speaker 0: There was a time where computers would fail to boot due to no fault of your own.
Speaker 0: That time was the AMD case, K3 or K7, whatever era.
Speaker 0: Yes, we're past that.
Speaker 1: And even during that era, just get an RMA on the part that's not working.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well, back then, like there'd be weird incompatibilities like of course you shouldn't have bought up whatever Northbridge coupled with a whatever video card in that particular brand.
Speaker 1: You might say, well, I just don't want the hassle.
Speaker 1: I'd rather spend money than have the hassle.
Speaker 1: And that's called anti intellectual.
Speaker 0: Now there's the forget that I'm not going to try to insult the listener.
Speaker 1: I insult the listener.
Speaker 0: I'll put it this way.
Speaker 0: Buying the new computer will not get you a performance improvement compared to just buying the video card.
Speaker 0: And literally a child whose age is in the single digits could replace the video card given almost no instruction.
Speaker 0: You just pulled the old one out and put the new one where the old one was.
Speaker 1: And maybe upgrade the driver.
Speaker 0: Now I guess the worst thing that can happen is if you pull the old one out and it turns out that the slot it was plugged into you is like AGP.
Speaker 1: Buy a new computer if that's the case.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: If your computer does not have a PCI express x16 slot, you need a new computer.
Speaker 0: But a $400 video card will buy you more than almost anything else you can do to your computer.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.