Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, December 17th, 2014.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 1: The delightful Cucumber Quest.
Speaker 1: Cucu.
Speaker 1: It's a webcomic.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, I kind of realized that I'm watching a lot of animation lately.
Speaker 1: Like, a lot.
Speaker 1: But I'm not watching a lot of anime.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of off and on watching Yo-Yo Peddle.
Speaker 0: You can just watch Yo-Yo Peddle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sure.
Speaker 0: Every Monday, around afternoon, the new episode's up.
Speaker 0: And then when you get home, Crunchyroll, you can watch it.
Speaker 1: But I was also watching the old Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: Because now it's getting to the good stuff.
Speaker 1: And I'm rewatching Nutenna for obvious reasons.
Speaker 0: I ran out of animes.
Speaker 0: I might have to go back on that Sailor Moon train.
Speaker 0: Back when the long hair, I was a non-normal girl.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that one, Scott, basically if you have been skipping Sailor Moon, did you get up to Queen Beryl, like, getting killed?
Speaker 1: Spoilers and all that?
Speaker 0: No, I didn't watch any episodes since long hair guy was hitting on normal girl.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, so I guess, yeah, Queen Beryl loses.
Speaker 0: You don't say?
Speaker 1: So, it's probably worth it to watch.
Speaker 1: I didn't see that coming at all.
Speaker 0: That's a total surprise.
Speaker 0: A bad guy loses.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: It is worth it to watch Sailor Moon up until, like, all the way up until Queen Beryl loses, the end of, like, the first real season.
Speaker 1: But if you, you can pretty much skip everything after that up until the first episode of S, if you really want to.
Speaker 0: What happens in that period that Skipple is island episode?
Speaker 1: So, first.
Speaker 0: I want to see some island action.
Speaker 1: First, I watched, like, the Alan and Anne part.
Speaker 1: I'd never even watched that in Japanese.
Speaker 1: Two aliens come down in a tree, and it's card captures.
Speaker 1: It's like a lame-o card capture Sakura for a while.
Speaker 1: You don't care.
Speaker 1: Then, the, like, one of the noble families from the old Moon Kingdom, who are all evil and fucked up and are on the bad guys team, they come from, like, the Nega Moon and try to fuck shit up.
Speaker 0: The Nega Moon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like, Prince Diamond and all that.
Speaker 0: So, this Princess Nega Moon?
Speaker 1: Nah, it's just, it's more Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: Like, nothing really special happens.
Speaker 0: It's still Monster of the Week?
Speaker 0: There's just a different bad guy producing the Monsters of the Week?
Speaker 1: Yes, pretty much.
Speaker 1: Now, it gets into, like, the history and backstory a lot, which is cool.
Speaker 1: But otherwise, it's not, like, super different than the first bits of Sailor Moon, except the whole team's together the whole time.
Speaker 0: What about the circus part that's in that music video?
Speaker 1: That's way, way, way, way later.
Speaker 1: That's two seasons.
Speaker 1: So, after that R stuff is S. Start with it, just when S starts, just watch that.
Speaker 0: 'Cause that's when all the others... A completely different bad guy creates the Monsters of the Week, and that bad guy is better than the other one, somehow.
Speaker 1: Well, that bad guy's way better, 'cause it's a complicated bad guy.
Speaker 0: It's a bad guy who makes Monsters of the Week.
Speaker 0: What the fuck is the difference?
Speaker 1: So, you know, in the beginning Sailor Moon, it's like, new sailors come one by one.
Speaker 0: They get punished in the name of the moon, just like the ones that you think I should skip over.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know how new sailors come one by one, and then, like, the team's, like, being built out?
Speaker 1: Sailor Moon R is, we already got the team, some amnesia, and we reformed the same team again, and then it's just, like, the team.
Speaker 1: S is all the awesome Sailor Scouts coming in one by one from the outside.
Speaker 0: So, different good guys fighting the Monster of the Week.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: They're just way better sailors.
Speaker 1: Like, they're better at this shit.
Speaker 0: Their boat doesn't crash?
Speaker 0: They've been to the West Indies?
Speaker 1: Pretty much.
Speaker 1: Their boat... It's just, you know what it is?
Speaker 1: It's Horatio, and then, like, double Horatio, and then triple Horatio.
Speaker 1: Like, every sailor that comes after the first intersenshi is just better.
Speaker 1: But, so, I was also watching Sailor Moon Crystal.
Speaker 1: Because I wanted to review it.
Speaker 0: I don't know why you keep watching bad things.
Speaker 0: Have you watched every episode of Sailor Moon Crystal?
Speaker 1: No, I actually stopped, and I kind of want to talk about why.
Speaker 1: now, because there's...
Speaker 0: Have you watched more Yoah pedals?
Speaker 0: Or have you watched more...
Speaker 1: I've watched way more Yoah pedals than I've watched Crystals.
Speaker 1: So, here's the deal with Crystal.
Speaker 1: Crystal is bad.
Speaker 0: Don't say.
Speaker 0: It is poorly executed.
Speaker 0: We already discussed this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we have.
Speaker 1: So, I was saying, "Oh, I'll watch it anyway to
Speaker 1: review.".
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: Just so I can review it.
Speaker 0: You've got to have something better to be watching.
Speaker 1: Plus, it's not that long.
Speaker 0: There's a new Mushishi season.
Speaker 0: Why not watch that?
Speaker 1: Because it moves through the story of Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: Aside from the fact that it's technically poorly executed, it just moves through the manga Sailor Moon way fast.
Speaker 1: And that could be cool.
Speaker 1: The thing that is preventing me from ever watching this until maybe they finish it and it's on Blu-ray is that, you know how anime nowadays, when they make the show for TV, a lot of stuff is badly animated, and then they fix it in the Blu-ray release.
Speaker 1: That's totally a kill-a-kill.
Speaker 1: Every anime does that.
Speaker 0: Even if they fixed it, wouldn't it still be bad?
Speaker 1: See, you'd say that, but here's the fucked up thing.
Speaker 1: I'm going to link to this article that shows just a really wide collection of all the changes.
Speaker 1: And it's not just that they're cleaning up the animation and fixing... They redid the whole show?
Speaker 1: Basically, yeah.
Speaker 0: Cell by cell?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so basically, look at this shit.
Speaker 0: Why didn't they do that in the first place?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the left is what was aired on TV and what was aired on Crunchyroll.
Speaker 1: See all those fucked up faces, all things we're complaining about?
Speaker 1: The right doesn't just redo it.
Speaker 1: The right changes the style to look like the original anime.
Speaker 0: The right is... Look at that one at the bottom there.
Speaker 0: The right is a greater improvement over the original than any other show I've seen in the TV vs Blu-ray thing.
Speaker 0: But it's still not incredible.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: it looks exactly like the original anime now?
Speaker 0: It's still not so good that it's going to be worth watching.
Speaker 1: Well, the primary problems with Sailor Moon Crystal was that technically it was very poorly executed.
Speaker 1: Even though the story is fine.
Speaker 0: Even if they make the design correct, the poses and whatnot are still going to be the same.
Speaker 1: No, they're redoing the poses too.
Speaker 1: They're redoing fucking everything.
Speaker 1: It's like it's being reanimated.
Speaker 1: It's ridiculous.
Speaker 0: It's a big difference.
Speaker 0: I mean, I can't deny that it's a humongous difference.
Speaker 0: Bigger than any difference I've ever seen in TV vs DVD.
Speaker 0: It's still not good enough to be watching.
Speaker 1: I think it'll be worth watching on the Blu-ray because Sailor Moon's main problem is that it moves so fucking slow and it goes on forever.
Speaker 0: But you've got nothing better to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: If I'm going to watch The Slow Show, I'm watching L.O.G.H.
Speaker 0: I'm waiting till I'm an old man for that shit.
Speaker 0: I think Gerald...
Speaker 1: Gerald said it best.
Speaker 0: Delayed gratification.
Speaker 1: He said Legend of the Galactic Heroes is best watched alone.
Speaker 1: You can't watch that with someone else because you've just got to sit down and pay attention.
Speaker 0: You'll all be dead and then I'll need something to do while waiting to die.
Speaker 1: There is no way you're outliving me.
Speaker 0: There is many ways, like when you die skating next week.
Speaker 1: But independent of our divergent opinions on whether or not Sailor Moon Crystal on Blu-ray is going to be worth watching to review, here is my point.
Speaker 1: The fact that they released Sailor Moon Crystal to TV in Crunchyroll as it is.
Speaker 1: compared to what they're turning it into, I don't think they planned to clean it up this much because it's not just clean up.
Speaker 1: I think that they realized they fucked it up and the bad press was getting so bad that they actually are making a stylistic decision.
Speaker 0: No one in Japan is intelligent like that.
Speaker 1: No, explain why they did this.
Speaker 1: It's not intelligent.
Speaker 1: They already fucked up.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: All I can say though is that of those eight panels you're looking at, the second one on the left, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that one?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, with the lazy eye?
Speaker 0: While it's obviously so bad, but it's sort of like,
Speaker 0: "Hey.".
Speaker 1: Except that's not what she was saying at that scene.
Speaker 0: Obviously, but it's like,
Speaker 0: "Hey.".
Speaker 0: I kind of like that that exists.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Wait, you want bad still images from Sailor Moon?
Speaker 0: If it was the better one on the right to begin with, we might not have insulted the show to begin with, but we wouldn't have that amazing, "Hey," lazy eye frame to look at.
Speaker 1: The most stark one is the one at the bottom.
Speaker 0: The bottom one where there's no depth or face, or face is like a paper sheet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like skeleton face.
Speaker 0: It's like a paper sheet on a neck stick.
Speaker 1: But the fact that I think they originally intended to clean the show up, like every anime, like Kill La Kill did the same thing.
Speaker 1: And I think they have redirected to not just cleaning it up, but changing the style.
Speaker 0: Maybe someone who sucks got fired, and then they slave drove someone else for no money all night to fix it.
Speaker 0: But the moral is, if you care about the show at all- And that you're cracking that whip, you demanding quality animation.
Speaker 1: Do not watch this show on Crunchyroll.
Speaker 1: Do not watch it live.
Speaker 1: Do not watch it on TV.
Speaker 1: Fuck that business.
Speaker 1: If you're gonna watch it, there is literally no reason to not wait for and/or pirate the Blu-rays at this point.
Speaker 0: Or you could just not watch it at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could say that about any piece of media.
Speaker 0: I could say that about any bad piece of media.
Speaker 1: It's not that bad.
Speaker 1: It's just poorly executed in a way that somehow- You wouldn't give any shits.
Speaker 0: No, not necessarily, because the fact that- There are like 20 better animes you could be watching.
Speaker 1: Name 20 anime that I haven't already seen that are recent, that are worth watching more so.
Speaker 0: I picked a number that was too big.
Speaker 0: Name five.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a new Mushishi show.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: One.
Speaker 0: You haven't watched every episode of You Up, Have You?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that's two.
Speaker 0: Two.
Speaker 0: I can keep going.
Speaker 0: There's a super deformed, uh, Hokuto.
Speaker 0: no Ken.
Speaker 1: Those always suck, unless you can show me evidence that this one doesn't suck.
Speaker 1: I don't trust it.
Speaker 1: Is it really, Scott?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they just got licensed by, uh- Yeah, is it really actually good?
Speaker 1: Is it the one we already watched?
Speaker 0: It's better than Sailor Moon Crystal.
Speaker 1: Is it the one where they work in the convenience store?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Because that one kind of sucked.
Speaker 1: That one's good.
Speaker 1: No, you're still only named two.
Speaker 0: You haven't watched Space Brothers.
Speaker 0: There's a zillion episodes of that motherfucker.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so while- I haven't watched it either.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that's a wash.
Speaker 1: Because while arguably it is a better show- I don't have to have watched it.
Speaker 1: It's got the old Sailor Moon problem if there's a billion episodes.
Speaker 0: There's a billion episodes of, uh, fairy tales from Japan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 1: I've watched almost all of them because that show's amazing.
Speaker 1: I watch them, like, every time I'm mopping and sweeping and, like, doing shit in the apartment.
Speaker 1: I also watch them while I'm dead in Counter-Strike.
Speaker 0: You should make a mod for Counter-Strike where when you're dead, it would switch to VLC and then switch back when you come back to life.
Speaker 0: And automatically pause and unpause?
Speaker 1: That would be an amazing thing to make.
Speaker 0: Alright, so make it.
Speaker 1: Or even better, just have it show you a random YouTube video every time you're dead.
Speaker 0: There's that some show the listeners keep telling us to watch.
Speaker 0: that looks like a perverted show and I need you to confirm- Bakemonogatari?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Because that's the perverted one.
Speaker 0: Akame Ga Kill or something?
Speaker 1: I need you to confirm- Wait, who told us to watch that?
Speaker 1: Because I've read things that tell me that those people might be bad people.
Speaker 0: I did a Google image search and I'm pretty sure this show is garbage, harem, whatever, pervertedness.
Speaker 0: But people are saying we should watch it, so you go check it out first.
Speaker 1: Isn't this the show that people in the Animators Network Forum were, like, flipping out when people criticized it?
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about that because I've never been to the Animators Network Forum.
Speaker 1: I am going to use a term that I've been using.
Speaker 1: I've been saying this word a lot lately.
Speaker 1: Skep.
Speaker 1: I am skep about this show.
Speaker 0: You're too lazy to say skeptical?
Speaker 1: No, because skep implies this sort of, like, I am above this and I am skeptical of it.
Speaker 1: Ah.
Speaker 1: That's what skep means.
Speaker 0: Well, you still need to watch it to, uh, you know.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, so if I go, wait, if I have to watch the show to review it, why don't I watch the Blu-ray Sailor Moon Crystal?
Speaker 0: Because you know everything is known by Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: You need to go and do this for me.
Speaker 0: I don't care about Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: I need information about this show.
Speaker 1: Scott, you would care a lot more about Sailor Moon if you knew about Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: Also, uh, I can think of some old animes you haven't seen.
Speaker 0: Have you seen all of Pat LeVoir TV?
Speaker 1: Uh, no.
Speaker 0: You haven't.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 1: Alright, so already you've had to deviate into old-ass anime.
Speaker 0: Scott, I thought you said you've seen all the anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But apparently one of the greatest shows of all time you haven't seen.
Speaker 1: Alright, Scott, I'm going to cancel that out.
Speaker 1: Have you seen all of Kodocha?
Speaker 0: Uh, neither have you.
Speaker 1: I've seen more of it than you.
Speaker 1: All you've seen is half of that, like, movie compilation because you fell asleep during it.
Speaker 0: Listen, not everyone can watch anime at TYF.
Speaker 1: How much Project Aco have you seen?
Speaker 0: Uh, I saw all of it a zillion years ago.
Speaker 1: Have you actually seen all of it, Scott?
Speaker 0: It was on Syfy Channel.
Speaker 0: I remember nothing.
Speaker 1: Scott, not all of it.
Speaker 0: I was, like, who knows how old.
Speaker 1: Scott, there's way more Project Aco than was aired on the Syfy Channel.
Speaker 0: I saw everything that was on the Syfy Channel.
Speaker 1: So you saw, like, the first one, two episodes.
Speaker 0: And I remember nothing.
Speaker 1: Did you see the movie Battle Gray, Battle Blue?
Speaker 1: Well, the OAV.
Speaker 0: I didn't even know a thing like that existed.
Speaker 1: Well, okay.
Speaker 1: Well, alright.
Speaker 0: But I doubt that it is more important to watch than Battle Boy, the TV series.
Speaker 1: I'm betting that old Project Aco is way more important to watch than Agame Ga Kill.
Speaker 1: Which, funnily enough...
Speaker 0: I'm not defending Agame Ga Kill.
Speaker 0: When I typed Agame Ga Kill... I need you to see it so that I can know.
Speaker 1: It looks like a lot of people...
Speaker 0: Without suffering on my own.
Speaker 1: I tried to type Agame, and then Google was like Ga Kill and No Kill.
Speaker 1: So I think people don't actually know the title of this anime.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the difference is.
Speaker 1: It's about an assassin group, night raid, to encorrupt... What?
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: Is it like noir?
Speaker 1: Serialization of Square Enix's Ga... The more I read about this, the less likely it is that this is good.
Speaker 0: I didn't think it was good to begin with.
Speaker 1: It might be a dark... It might be a perverted darker than black.
Speaker 1: This might be darker than black plus Bakemonogatari.
Speaker 1: Anyway... Anyway...
Speaker 0: In news!
Speaker 0: If you're in New York, because you're an awesome person and not somewhere else, as a totally lame-o geographical location, every other place on the entire face of the earth, this is a good week to be in New York.
Speaker 1: Well, it's always a good week to be in New York.
Speaker 0: An even better week to be in New York, because an even more awesome person than you is in New York, named Brian K. Vaughan, perhaps one of the greatest comic book writers alive and working at the time.
Speaker 1: What's he doing here?
Speaker 1: It's not New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: He's just hanging out in town, and tomorrow, he's going to be at the Kinokuniya Bookstore.
Speaker 0: Huh?
Speaker 1: From...
Speaker 0: Which one?
Speaker 0: The one near Bryant Park.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: From 3 to 6.
Speaker 1: The one where we interviewed TM Revolution?
Speaker 1: That one.
Speaker 0: Yes, that one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, guys, we interviewed TM Revolution once.
Speaker 0: And the day after that, he's going to be in Midtown Comics downtown.
Speaker 0: So, it's like there isn't even a convention.
Speaker 0: But it's the only person you would need to see at a convention anyway.
Speaker 0: New York is living in New York.
Speaker 0: If there was a convention, he is the only person you would see.
Speaker 0: And anything you would buy at the convention, you can buy at either of these two stores.
Speaker 0: Living in New York is like being at a convention.
Speaker 0: You can see him twice.
Speaker 0: Go to Kinokuniya, go to Midtown.
Speaker 0: It won't even take you all day.
Speaker 0: You won't have to pay an entry fee.
Speaker 0: And yeah, dude wrote Saga, so... It's better than anyone else you're going to see in your town.
Speaker 0: And if you're in New York, go see him.
Speaker 0: I might try to see him tomorrow at Kinokuniya after work.
Speaker 0: He's going to be there from 3 to 6.
Speaker 0: So, I can leave work at 5 and just walk over there.
Speaker 0: It's really close.
Speaker 0: Maybe there won't be a huge line.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: Or maybe I'll just go home.
Speaker 1: So, I got a real quick Geek Byte here.
Speaker 1: So, a show that I just ignored for whatever reason for a long time.
Speaker 1: Enough people I trust told me to watch it.
Speaker 1: And one of them was like, I'm just putting on a... They pulled my trick of just put on an episode while they're hanging out.
Speaker 1: And then they'll watch it.
Speaker 1: So, they did that to me.
Speaker 1: And I watched an episode of Rick and Morty.
Speaker 1: And Rick and Morty is really, really, really good.
Speaker 1: And kind of like how I've recommended The Amazing World of Gumball.
Speaker 1: And Adventure Brothers, Archer, all those shows.
Speaker 1: Rick and Morty makes that vaunted list.
Speaker 1: Rick and Morty is basically... Imagine if Doctor Who was crossed with the Doc from Back to the Future.
Speaker 1: And was fucked up and kind of mean and possibly evil.
Speaker 1: And he was taking his grandson on Doctor Who style adventures through the universe.
Speaker 0: That doesn't make me want to watch that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because you hate animation.
Speaker 1: You don't watch anything.
Speaker 1: So, I didn't even expect you.
Speaker 0: Why are you watching this instead of Mamoru Oshin created Battle of War the TV series?
Speaker 1: Rick and Morty is pretty fucking hilarious.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: It's also, it's got that thing going on kind of like Adventure Brothers did.
Speaker 0: Even robot police cops going out to get Chinese food?
Speaker 1: That isn't hilarious so much as like sense of good-natured camaraderie.
Speaker 0: Well, you see that episode.
Speaker 0: It's actually one of those fucked up weirdo episodes.
Speaker 0: Where everything's dark and spooky.
Speaker 1: Rick and Morty has that same kind of thing going on that like Venture Brothers does.
Speaker 1: Where it's funny, it's mean-spirited, it is dark humor.
Speaker 1: But yet, the characters are deep and interesting enough.
Speaker 1: The stories are interesting enough.
Speaker 1: The whole world and everything they're setting up around them is such that you actually like really get into these characters.
Speaker 1: They can kind of grow and build on itself and do really fun stuff.
Speaker 1: So, I'll talk about it more in depth at some point later.
Speaker 1: Season 2 was supposed to air in 2015.
Speaker 1: They're running out of time on that.
Speaker 1: But season 1 is great and the entire thing is just totally free.
Speaker 1: And you can just watch it on the Cartoon Network website like right now.
Speaker 1: So, watch Rick and Morty.
Speaker 0: After you watch every other show, especially the most important animation that was made.
Speaker 0: We've talked about so many animes right now and so many cartoons right now.
Speaker 0: We have neglected to mention the greatest animation that has been created in the past few months is South Park.
Speaker 1: South Park's been hitting it out of the park lately.
Speaker 0: I think it's been hitting it right on the park.
Speaker 1: Well, no.
Speaker 1: It's hitting it out of the park like a home run.
Speaker 0: It's North Park now?
Speaker 1: If you hit it on the park, that's at best an RBI.
Speaker 0: It's South Park.
Speaker 0: If it had it out of the park, it wouldn't be good.
Speaker 1: That was a stretch.
Speaker 1: Anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So, we're going to be at Anime Boston and we're going to be at Zenkai Con doing our anime panels and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: Are we going to Zenkai Con?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay, maybe.
Speaker 1: Well, it's either Zenkai Con or Genericon.
Speaker 0: We can just not do either one.
Speaker 1: I really need the people.
Speaker 1: It's a toka kokan.
Speaker 1: We perform at Zenkai Con and in return, certain high quality people staff at Kinetic Con.
Speaker 0: Are they going to refuse to go to Kinetic Con?
Speaker 0: if we refuse to go to Zenkai Con?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Probably not.
Speaker 1: But also, you know what?
Speaker 0: Zenkai Con is kind of fun.
Speaker 0: Because Kinetic Con is actually, like, I would go to Kinetic Con if I wasn't working there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Kinetic Con is like one of... Kinetic Con...
Speaker 0: Some but not all packs is Magfest.
Speaker 0: Even though I'm working there, I still kind of don't want to go to Zenkai.
Speaker 1: But one, I'll go to Zenkai Con because we can take the train directly there and back.
Speaker 1: And two...
Speaker 0: Alright, there was that train that went back to the inn.
Speaker 1: We don't really do a lot of anime cons anymore, but yeah, we have a lot of good anime content.
Speaker 1: So in that con, I'm going to do a new version of anime openers around the world because I found some shit.
Speaker 0: You did find some shit indeed.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Good God.
Speaker 1: Lupin, Lupin, Lupin.
Speaker 1: That might be my favorite thing.
Speaker 1: So one of the parts of that panel is the Portuguese opener to Harlock.
Speaker 1: And I learned from both a fan and Lou that that was based... Two separate people.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I call Lou a fan.
Speaker 1: He's more friends.
Speaker 0: I thought he's a fan of Harlock.
Speaker 1: No, I'm not a boss.
Speaker 1: The fan of us told me this.
Speaker 1: Lou also told me this.
Speaker 1: So that song was the way it was because the Harlock opener is like melodramatic old Japanese music.
Speaker 1: Harlock is a melodramatic show.
Speaker 1: The opener in Portuguese... I've seen a bunch of it, but...
Speaker 0: Why are you watching?
Speaker 1: The Portuguese opener is that melodrama dialed up to like a million.
Speaker 1: Like it's amazing.
Speaker 1: And the reason for that is because it's based on a style of music that's basically known only to Portugal.
Speaker 1: Fado.
Speaker 1: Fado, F-A-D-O, is essentially the music that came from wives wailing at the ocean in sorrow and melancholy for their husbands who are sailing the endless seas.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because their ships got blowed day up by England, Spain, France.
Speaker 1: Well, also just because sailing the endless seas in the 1500s and 1600s was a lot more...
Speaker 0: You also just sink.
Speaker 1: Mysterious and scary and amazing.
Speaker 0: There'd be dragons.
Speaker 1: So that music was why that opener was the way it was and probably why Harlock is so fucking popular in Portugal.
Speaker 1: This is a video of Emilia...
Speaker 0: The old ladies are big Harlock fans because he reminds them of their husbands that died at sea.
Speaker 1: So Emilia Rodriguez, I can't pronounce Portuguese at all, I'm not sure what that accent means, is basically the queen of Fado music.
Speaker 1: And this is video of her performing Fado music.
Speaker 1: The melancholy might melt you.
Speaker 0: So, one of the best, speaking of comics from before, right?
Speaker 0: While Brian K. Vaughan might be one of the best living writers of comics that are printed in on the shelf of the comic book store, one of the best makers of webcomics these days be Casey Green.
Speaker 1: Nah, Casey Green.
Speaker 0: But did you know, creator of such great comics as Gunshow and Anime Club, which is part of Gunshow and such, Gunshow be ending, yo.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 0: He's already uploaded the final Gunshows and they are displaying on a schedule, and by the end of this year, there will be no more Gunshows.
Speaker 0: Possibly ever.
Speaker 0: Likely ever.
Speaker 1: You know, if you never read Gunshow, this is your trigger.
Speaker 1: You might as well start because you're just going to read it all the way to the end and not have to wait.
Speaker 0: However, do not fret.
Speaker 0: Casey Green is doing two other com- well, he's doing a lot of other things.
Speaker 0: He's done some regular show comic books and things like that.
Speaker 0: But he is doing two other webcomics right now.
Speaker 0: One of them is called Back, which seems to be a continuing story, beginning with some dude kicking his way out of a grave.
Speaker 1: That's already up my alley.
Speaker 0: So that, you can be found at backcomic.com, B-A-C-K-C-O-M-I-C.
Speaker 0: And then he's also doing Carlo Collodi's Pinocchio, adapted by Casey Green.
Speaker 0: [laughter] And that is at Carlo Collodi's Pinocchio.
Speaker 1: I want to fix your nose.
Speaker 0: Dot.
Speaker 0: tumblr dot.
Speaker 0: tumblr dot com.
Speaker 0: So once you finish Gunshow at the end of this year, delete that from your comic rocket, which you should be using, and add these two things to your comic rocket, and you're now plus one comic.
Speaker 0: It's only a good thing in my book.
Speaker 1: In the meantime, we're going to be at PAX South performing bad games on Sunday in the Armadillo Theater.
Speaker 1: It's going to be awesome.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, we'll just be there eating barbecue and making fun of the South.
Speaker 1: The book club book is Watership Down.
Speaker 1: It's about rabbits on a journey.
Speaker 1: It's a great book.
Speaker 0: Find us on the internet.
Speaker 0: We are everywhere on the internet that you are.
Speaker 0: If you are not on the internet enough, be on the internet more.
Speaker 1: And join the Geek Nights Forum.
Speaker 1: We pay a lot of money for that fucking thing.
Speaker 0: Close your eyes and imagine a room with many tables and nerds hanging out, doing many things, such as playing games with each other and chatting it up and hanging out and doing stuff.
Speaker 0: That is the internet.
Speaker 0: Why are you not in that room all the time?
Speaker 0: We are in this room.
Speaker 0: It has a big ass sign out the door.
Speaker 0: You can't miss it.
Speaker 0: Come in that room and then we'll lock you in.
Speaker 1: Also, we ban people from the room who have bad grammar and spelling or who make dumb arguments.
Speaker 0: There are no smelly bad guys in that room.
Speaker 0: Occasionally, we go *sniffing* in a dumb ass into the room and have fun with them, and then they walk their own ass out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like when that Gomer Gator came in.
Speaker 1: Notice how he's gone.
Speaker 0: -He gone.
Speaker 1: -Yeah, he gone.
Speaker 0: -He sleep.
Speaker 1: Worldstar!
Speaker 1: I need a Worldstar gift to post every time we drive that guy out of the forum.
Speaker 0: -Well, go find him.
Speaker 1: -I will.
Speaker 1: So, speaking of webcomics that you should add to your Comic Rocket, if you haven't been reading Cucumber Quest or QQ, as the cool kids call it, that's what we're about to talk about.
Speaker 0: So, Cucumber Quest is a webcomic made by a very awesome person named GG DG.
Speaker 1: Who you should follow on Twitter.
Speaker 0: The best name ever.
Speaker 1: 'Cause, one, she tweets awesome art.
Speaker 1: Two, her Twitter is hilarious, and it's exactly 50% as crazy as Natasha Allegri's Twitter.
Speaker 0: I followed Natasha Allegri for two days and I couldn't handle it.
Speaker 0: It was too strong.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: Following her on Twitter is like just mainlining internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, anyway.
Speaker 0: So, Q, I always knew this existed, but I didn't read it.
Speaker 0: 'cause it was so far along I didn't have time to catch up.
Speaker 1: -I read it, like, religiously.
Speaker 1: -Right.
Speaker 0: Rin was reading it religiously on the webcomic version.
Speaker 0: So, what I did instead is she has kickstarters for every volume, and she just finished kickstarting volume three, and I kickstarted one and two and received one and two, but never read them.
Speaker 0: And volume three's on its way, and I'm probably just gonna kickstart it and read it in volumes.
Speaker 0: 'Cause each volume, it's sort of like, it's one of those segmented stories with, you know, bosses on an adventure.
Speaker 0: So, each volume is like one segment, so it's really easy to read that way, and a lot more comfortable and fast than reading the webcomic going next, next, next.
Speaker 1: -Though at the same time...
Speaker 0: -And I'm sure one day the printed volumes will catch up to the webcomic, and then I can switch over.
Speaker 1: The reason I enjoyed reading it as a webcomic primarily was that because I was already pretty much caught up the whole time...
Speaker 0: Where was it when you started reading it?
Speaker 1: I was reading it from near the beginning.
Speaker 1: Like, we hadn't gotten too far...
Speaker 0: -Yeah.
Speaker 0: I did not discover it early enough.
Speaker 0: But when I did see it many years ago, you know, I saw the arts, and I was like, "Oh, my God, this comic is...".
Speaker 0: I mean, regardless of anything else I know about, I saw, like, pictures of it, and I knew it was incredible.
Speaker 0: I just didn't read it because...
Speaker 1: So, my enjoyment of reading it on the web was that because I only got one page at a time, I would spend a lot more time appreciating the art of the page.
Speaker 0: I spent quite a lot of time appreciating...
Speaker 1: -'Cause the thing... I mean, things to appreciate...
Speaker 0: -Any page with crabs on it.
Speaker 1: The colors and framing, it has this kind of watercolor-y, awesome, washed-out...
Speaker 0: -There aren't a lot of webcomics that look like this.
Speaker 0: -Exactly.
Speaker 1: The character's super cute.
Speaker 1: She puts a lot of attention into their hair and outfits.
Speaker 0: If you look at some of the extras in the back of the printed volumes, she shows, like, the development of, like, the character design for, like, Princess Nautilus over the years, and it's like,
Speaker 0: "Whoa!".
Speaker 0: And you can just see, like, her drawing skill getting better, and the design getting better, and everything getting better, and it's, oh, my gosh.
Speaker 1: So, it's a story about a rabbit named Cucumber who's trying to go to wizard school, and his stupid dad makes him go save the world.
Speaker 1: -Yep.
Speaker 1: -And he doesn't want to.
Speaker 0: This is somewhere in between, right, like, Bone and...
Speaker 1: -Yeah, a little bit of Bone.
Speaker 0: -And Adventure Time, right?
Speaker 1: That's a really good way to put it, actually.
Speaker 0: It's like, Bone has some comedies, you know, but it's sort of, like, a more serious adventure, even though it has comedies, and Adventure Time is also serious and has comedies.
Speaker 0: But it's mostly, "Eh..." Right, and this is, like, right in the middle of those two.
Speaker 0: Like, you take Adventure Time, and you tone it down with some Bone, and you add some cuteness to the Adventure Time side.
Speaker 1: Yep, like, Cucumber Quest is very self-aware, and it does a little bit of that, like, trope deconstruction, like, "Oh, the great hero has to
Speaker 1: come.".
Speaker 1: "Well, this has happened, what, 99 times before?
Speaker 1: That seems
Speaker 1: stupid.".
Speaker 1: "Oh, and all the characters recognize this.
Speaker 1: Mmm.".
Speaker 1: But at the same time, it doesn't rely on that as the only reason you care about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, the greatness of Cucumber Quest is really just that.
Speaker 0: most of the characters are just awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: Scott, on three, one, two, three, what is your favorite character?
Speaker 0: Anyone that's a crab.
Speaker 1: Just the crab bros?
Speaker 0: Well, okay, so here's the problem.
Speaker 0: How do I choose, right?
Speaker 0: At first, they come out with these crab mafias, and I'm like, "Crab mafia is the
Speaker 0: best."
Speaker 0: Crab bros.
Speaker 0: And then, this crab bro, which is one crab who wears sunglasses, who's, like, deal with it, "I'm crab bro, but I'm the nicest, awesomest dude, but I'm a
Speaker 0: bro.".
Speaker 0: And then, they got Bubblebeard, the giant crab pirate king, who runs a tropical resort because he's done pirating, and it's like, "How can it be better than
Speaker 0: that?".
Speaker 0: Well, crab bro is about equal to that.
Speaker 0: And pretty much anyone that's a crab is the best.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, I'm just a fan of, like, peridot.
Speaker 1: Peridot is also awesome.
Speaker 1: More like peridont.
Speaker 0: Yeah, peridot is, like, so awesome.
Speaker 1: She reminds me of the witch girl from the old Game Boy Legend of Zelda.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the ages and seasons.
Speaker 0: The only thing wrong with peridot is that she is not a crab.
Speaker 0: That is the only thing that keeps her from being tier one is that she does not have two big red claws and a beard made of bubbles.
Speaker 1: I also really like Kyuko's little sister.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she's okay.
Speaker 0: She's good.
Speaker 1: Well, partly because she's got that very much, like, "Fuck it, I got a sword.
Speaker 1: Let's just fucking do this.
Speaker 1: What's
Speaker 1: wrong?".
Speaker 0: There are a lot of, like, the main characters from Attack on Titan, right, where the dude is sort of, like, you know, the plot dude, and then the badass, well, Attack on Titan is not actually his sister, but, you know, sort of, like, the sister character.
Speaker 0: The person in that slot is the badass, awesome, sword, stabby, killy person.
Speaker 1: Yep, but what's funny, too, is that- Mikasa, right?
Speaker 0: Mikasa and Eren.
Speaker 1: I was reading this, and then, like, relatively recently, I got into the amazing world of Gumball.
Speaker 1: In Gumball, the little sister, Anaïs, is a rabbit girl, and her and Almond are extremely similar.
Speaker 0: Alrighty.
Speaker 1: Which is just kind of interesting.
Speaker 1: I also really like Cucumber's Dad, because you know he's up to something.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like Cucumber's Dad started out as, like, his first time I saw him, I was like, "This guy
Speaker 0: sucks.".
Speaker 0: I still don't like him that much, but he's definitely doing something, because he's hanging in that- he's not stupid.
Speaker 0: You can tell he's not dumb, and he's hanging out in that prison cell, even though it's locked, and he obviously spied on the bad guys once already.
Speaker 0: At the minimum, he's staying there on purpose to spy on the bad guys.
Speaker 0: If not more than that.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: And, like, why didn't- he could've messed up those balls, but he chose not to.
Speaker 0: But he knew the deal.
Speaker 0: So...
Speaker 1: Well, this- it's interesting, because if you read the story, it's pretty much the story of the heroes around their adventure, and all the adults around them know what the deal is and won't tell them.
Speaker 0: Well, the friggin' Oracle, she can go suck a dick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she's the worst.
Speaker 1: She's mean.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, obviously there's some big plot around that.
Speaker 0: Hey, Auril, why don't you do it yourself?
Speaker 0: Don't tell me how to do my job.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: It's like, what?
Speaker 1: But I like how Nightmare Knight is one of my favorite kinds of villains, because obviously, he's bad.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: And even if he is bad for, like, good reasons- It's like, you haven't seen him personally do anything bad, but it's like, he brought back all the masters and told them to do bad stuff, so he's bad.
Speaker 1: But he has that sort of, like, bad, sad characteristic of great villains, because obviously he's- Yeah, he's more like a Doctor Doom or a Magneto than just a blow up the world crazy bad guy.
Speaker 1: So you're way behind, but there's a lot of really great interactions between him and other characters along the way.
Speaker 0: Well, I got to a part where, towards the end of volume two, the three dumb characters- Oh, those guys.
Speaker 0: I hate those guys.
Speaker 0: Well, Bacon's good, but the other two are not so good.
Speaker 1: Bacon's got one star in every attribute.
Speaker 1: He's the worst.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but the lead of those guys was trying to get kissy kissy on the French princess- Oh, yeah, Nightmare Knight's like- A Nightmare Knight's like, "Yeah, cut that shit out.
Speaker 0: I'm a Nightmare Knight.
Speaker 0: Do what I
Speaker 0: say.".
Speaker 1: So there is a continuing relationship between him and Parfait.
Speaker 1: that's just really, really fun.
Speaker 0: Oh, I hope that they get it on and kick a carrot at- What's his name?
Speaker 0: Carrot?
Speaker 1: Carrot's not bad.
Speaker 1: He's just really, really earnest.
Speaker 0: Listen, Parfait and Nightmare Knight would be way better than- Oh, Parfait and Nightmare Knight's a pretty good ship.
Speaker 0: Right, but forget Carrot and Parfait, the canon one.
Speaker 0: Fuck that relationship.
Speaker 1: I like Queen Cordelia, too, because the sort of initial "baddie" is basically a lot like Queen Beryl in Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: You said- I really- I loved interviews- She's better than Queen Beryl.
Speaker 1: But in terms of- you don't know Queen Beryl's full story, so I can't really spoil anything, but she's- I don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: She's obviously trying to play two sides of a coin and failing at it.
Speaker 0: But it's like.
Speaker 0: she's also bad, but she's not stupid bad, and she's not crazy bad.
Speaker 0: She's just, you know, sort of, you know, naughty.
Speaker 1: That's not how I would describe it, but I see.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, it's one of those Queen Beryl's trying to-.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm not going to spoil Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about that later.
Speaker 0: Actually, I think that- who's the guy who made the boat that exploded or whatever?
Speaker 1: Oh, that guy!
Speaker 0: He's actually the baddest, right?
Speaker 0: In terms of, like, attitude and personality, he is the most evil, I think.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I do like that.
Speaker 1: he's all technology-y, but other than that- I don't know if it's just the face or what, but whenever I see him, he's no good.
Speaker 1: I think, just without any question, my brain is like, "Is that George
Speaker 1: Rohek?"
Speaker 1: And I'm like, "No, it's
Speaker 1: not.".
Speaker 0: Anyway, so short plot summary, right?
Speaker 0: He wants- the kid, Cucumber, wants to go to wizard school, the best wizard school in the land.
Speaker 0: He's going to go tomorrow.
Speaker 0: But then, suddenly, that's when the bad guys decide to resurrect the great evil, and his dad is like, "Well, you have to be the chosen one because it runs in our family, so go get the sword and do it.
Speaker 0: Go on the adventure.
Speaker 0: Go do it
Speaker 0: now.".
Speaker 0: He's basically ordered to go on the adventure, even though his sister's probably really the hero.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But he has to do it anyway.
Speaker 0: So he starts going on the adventure, and the adventure is basically get the dream sword, magic sword, secret of mana sword, master sword.
Speaker 0: And then beat all eight robot masters, I mean, regular masters of evil, starting with the spla- you know, there's one in each kingdom, so you have to go to all the- The disaster masters!
Speaker 0: Right, you have to go to every kingdom in the whole world, meet all the characters, meet all the princesses and people that live in every place, create an awesome adventuring party, collect the items on the quest of magic, learn things and grow up and become awesome and beat these masters, and then come back to the central kingdom and beat the final bad guy, and then everything will be revealed at the end, all the secrets and the webcomic will end at the end.
Speaker 1: Yep, so RPG world, RPG plot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it doesn't really matter, the plot, it's all about- because it's such a straightforward plot, it's all about the details of each situation and what the characters are doing.
Speaker 1: And I guess that's where it really shines.
Speaker 0: And of course, what the final deal is.
Speaker 0: Why is this- we've seen this cliche story a zillion times before, but here the characters are openly recognizing that there has been a pattern that's repeated a hundred times of- Well, 99 times.
Speaker 0: Right, 99 times, summoning, and then temporarily banishing the nightmare knight, and it has to be at the end of this hundredth time that they're going to figure out the real deal.
Speaker 0: Well, it could go a fire emblem route, like it could go a route of, like, is the story- Well, they could, A, realize why it has to be this way and just do it the way it's always been done.
Speaker 0: B, see the way it's always been done and figure out some way around it, and what that way around it is then becomes important.
Speaker 0: Is the way around it- Don't banish him.
Speaker 1: Is it a Shinseke Iori sort of, like, come of age in a new world and understand it for what it is?
Speaker 1: You know, basically, is the end cucumber and everyone's saying, "Okay, we understand what the adults are all
Speaker 1: about."
Speaker 1: Or, mole breaker.
Speaker 0: It could banish him for real, permanently.
Speaker 0: Kill him.
Speaker 0: And then it's like, "Oh, the sister was actually the hero.
Speaker 0: You get to go to wizard school.
Speaker 0: Oh, you don't need to go to wizard school because you already became a wizard on this quest, so now you're in charge of wizard school.
Speaker 0: You're the new
Speaker 0: king.".
Speaker 0: You know, stuff like that can happen at the end.
Speaker 1: The other interesting thing is that the characters and just the story and the setting and things very commonly surprise me.
Speaker 1: Every time I think, "Okay, I see where this is
Speaker 1: going.".
Speaker 1: Nope, nope, something crazy happens.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know what else I can say.
Speaker 1: It's a webcomic.
Speaker 1: You can just read it for free.
Speaker 1: You don't need to buy anything.
Speaker 0: Well, you can.
Speaker 0: You should buy the books because the books have extra shit in them and they're Kickstarted.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you can get the old volumes.
Speaker 0: It can't be that hard to get them.
Speaker 0: But, if you get the old volumes, then you can start doing what I'm doing.
Speaker 0: Just Kickstart each volume as it comes out.
Speaker 1: You can do that.
Speaker 0: And then, if you pay more money than I'm paying, because I'm only paying the book level, if you pay more levels, you can get more stuff.
Speaker 1: But, I guess, put it this way.
Speaker 1: If you're not sold on this by our unabashed joy about just talking about it...
Speaker 0: You can read the webcomic for free to figure out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, go read the first bit.
Speaker 0: So, click on "Shop" and see if they're selling the books.
Speaker 1: Oh, let's see.
Speaker 1: "Shop.".
Speaker 0: Oh, are they selling any other merch?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there it is.
Speaker 0: Volume 1.
Speaker 1: "Disaster Stone Pins," "Print Sets,".
Speaker 1: "Print Set,".
Speaker 1: "Print Set," "Group Print," "Cucumber
Speaker 1: Dress.".
Speaker 0: How much are the volumes?
Speaker 1: Sold out.
Speaker 1: A lot of these things are sold out.
Speaker 0: How much are the volumes?
Speaker 1: Hardcover of book 1, $65.
Speaker 1: Softcover of book 1, $20.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't get the hardcover one.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It depends.
Speaker 0: You're gonna pay $65?
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: It depends on how into it you get.
Speaker 0: You gotta be way into it to need that.
Speaker 0: For $65, you could get three volumes instead of one volume.
Speaker 1: Well, that depends on how into it you get.
Speaker 0: How into it are you?
Speaker 1: I really like "Cucumber
Speaker 1: Quest.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's good.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: (singing in Italian).