Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, May 5th, 2014.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights Tonight, talking about adventure time in continuance with a guest.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So it was really warm today.
Speaker 1: It was warm today.
Speaker 0: I was thinking about biking to work.
Speaker 1: I bike to work every day all week.
Speaker 0: You don't have to go home after this show, do you?
Speaker 0: If I had biked to work, I would have to bike now.
Speaker 0: And I'm leaving right from your place.
Speaker 0: So it's nice out.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: It's gonna rain.
Speaker 1: Scott, I note this now.
Speaker 1: For all the years you've been living here, if you look at the forecast and it's like 1% chance of rain, you're like, "Not biking!
Speaker 1: Not
Speaker 1: biking!".
Speaker 0: I now have more accurate weather reporting thanks to pimping Yahoo weather.
Speaker 0: The Yahoo weather app tells you the hour.
Speaker 1: Scott, so does the built-in Android app.
Speaker 0: Fine, it tells you when the rain will begin.
Speaker 0: Look at this timeline.
Speaker 0: Alright, when is the rain gonna begin?
Speaker 0: Scott, it said the rain will start at 8 and right now it's 7.20.
Speaker 1: Yes, you know what?
Speaker 1: At 8, there is only a 20% chance of rain in Long Island City and Astoria.
Speaker 0: That's not what mine said.
Speaker 1: That's what mine said.
Speaker 0: Mine said like 90% tonight.
Speaker 1: Also, you're a little baby.
Speaker 1: It's some rain.
Speaker 1: Just suck it the fuck up.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna ruin my clothing by biking in rain.
Speaker 0: But anyway, this Sunday is gonna be amazing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: This Sunday I'm gonna bike all day.
Speaker 1: So I was biking home and I was a little late to do the show.
Speaker 1: Partly because with my Google Glass on biking, which by the way, the Strava app on Glass is pretty great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I get to install it and set it up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't just use the phone for GPS.
Speaker 1: It's all in the Glass 100%.
Speaker 1: Basically, you just tap and say start biking and it just immediately starts counting down and it shows you your speed.
Speaker 1: While you're biking and your time and all this stuff, it's great.
Speaker 1: And you can still do other Glass stuff while it's running.
Speaker 1: So I'm biking.
Speaker 1: I'm biking.
Speaker 1: And I witnessed a car accident.
Speaker 1: So I immediately turned on the video and took a bunch of pictures.
Speaker 0: What kind of car accident?
Speaker 1: So a Time Warner van just fucking smashed into this parked car and ripped the bummer.
Speaker 0: So the car was parked and a Time Warner van just drove right into it?
Speaker 1: Just like turned into it.
Speaker 1: Just like crunch, crackle, crackle.
Speaker 0: Huge noise.
Speaker 0: So it turned around a corner and just went right into it?
Speaker 1: No, it just like tried to park and just fucking derped, I guess.
Speaker 0: Oh, so it was trying to park and he stepped on the gas.
Speaker 0: too much?
Speaker 1: Yep, and he turned in too quick at speed.
Speaker 1: And they get out of the car and they're kind of looking around.
Speaker 1: And I decided, because I was videoing, I just go right over there and I look at his license plate.
Speaker 1: So I have a good picture of it and I look at his face.
Speaker 0: Detective Rim is on the case.
Speaker 1: Well, because I do not like the fact that a lot of people do egregious shit in New York City or in just cities in general.
Speaker 0: And get away with it.
Speaker 0: Injustice.
Speaker 1: I did not want them to get away with it.
Speaker 1: So on the off chance that they were going to flee the scene, I wanted to make sure I had video of that.
Speaker 1: And then I waited like 15 minutes, the owner came down, "Look at the fuck, my
Speaker 1: car!".
Speaker 1: And then I exchanged contact info and I sent him all the pictures and video that I had and gave him a little deposition.
Speaker 1: So he's good to go.
Speaker 1: So that's what I did.
Speaker 1: That was fun.
Speaker 1: I was kind of, maybe it's wrong, I was hoping a little bit to see some sort of confrontation just so I'd have a better video.
Speaker 0: So you could upload something to YouTube and get views.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Get some Reddit karma.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, I wonder if the fact that I was standing there and people were talking to me like, "Oh my god, is that Google Glass?
Speaker 1: What's
Speaker 1: up?"
Speaker 1: That the fact that I was standing there and I was videoing everything.
Speaker 1: I think if a conversation would have happened otherwise, it wouldn't because everyone was afraid of the camera.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So, the news action.
Speaker 0: There's not a whole lot of news going on right now.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there will be in a couple months, the San Diego Comic-Con, whatever.
Speaker 0: But, at least comic animation news.
Speaker 0: But check this out.
Speaker 0: Drops of God, awesome manga that we love that got stopped publishing in English because I guess the Japanese company wasn't happy with how much it sold in the US.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Japanese company, seriously, find an American vigner wine-brewed seller.
Speaker 0: And then you made verticals skip a bunch of volumes, which no one cared.
Speaker 0: That's the reason we...
Speaker 1: You needed to cross-market that shit in... To kind of take Kazuo Koike's golf manga and put it in Golf Digest.
Speaker 1: Take this thing, release it in floppies in wine stores.
Speaker 0: So, I'm going to have to find some scanlations somewhere to finish reading this thing because I've got to know what the drops of God are.
Speaker 1: So, Scott, when I was in France, I went to several wine tastings and I tasted a wide variety of Grand Cru.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Did they taste like God dropped them?
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: If they were in a different bottle, would you... And I just said, "Here's some
Speaker 0: wine.".
Speaker 1: So, the taste, because this was like a proper tasting, so I wasn't drunk or anything.
Speaker 1: And unlike other tastings I've been to, later I was drunk.
Speaker 1: But I did take tasting notes and I used that Vivino app that I use to take pictures of some of the bottles and everything.
Speaker 1: What was interesting is in America, when I go to expensive or fancy wine tastings, they tend to tell you all the stuff about the wine and then have you drink it.
Speaker 1: In France, they make you drink the wine without telling you shit.
Speaker 0: Do they mix in shitty wines?
Speaker 1: Not all the wines were good.
Speaker 1: Then, they ask you what you think of it.
Speaker 1: They ask you what you taste.
Speaker 1: Then, they explain what the deal is with the wine.
Speaker 0: Oh, how about that?
Speaker 0: And you didn't get to see the bottle until after.
Speaker 1: So, the sommelier is not coloring my perception of the wine.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 1: And the best wine...
Speaker 0: Well, other than the fact that a sommelier gave it to you is coloring it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but some of the wines were kind of cheap and not that good.
Speaker 0: Well, but the wines that you said that you liked happened to be the expensive ones.
Speaker 1: The wines I liked the most were, every Grand Cru, my notes were, "This is the best
Speaker 1: wine.".
Speaker 1: Like, "This one stands
Speaker 1: out.".
Speaker 0: What made them stand out?
Speaker 1: They were like the flavor.
Speaker 1: Most wine, I guess...
Speaker 0: This isn't really winning you any drops of God contest.
Speaker 1: No, but I'm not great at differentiating wine.
Speaker 0: I don't feel like I'm at a Queen concert right now.
Speaker 1: So, in fact, there are studies that show that people who don't pay attention and study wine, a lot of times, they can't tell the difference between red and white wine if you blindfold them.
Speaker 1: But when I drink wine, I like this wine, don't like that wine, like these kinds of wines.
Speaker 1: I like Chianti's and Colorettes more than I like, Merlot's, that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: But the differences, like the Grand Cru's, the flavors I tasted are flavors I just don't taste in the wine that I have at home.
Speaker 1: Ah.
Speaker 1: Like, there were flavors and notes that just aren't there that actually stood out.
Speaker 0: What flavor?
Speaker 0: is that?
Speaker 0: Is it a good flavor?
Speaker 1: So, one of them had this like really sort of like almost cherry flavor in there.
Speaker 1: But usually when I get that kind of cherry flavor in a wine that I would buy.
Speaker 0: Did someone dump sugar in it?
Speaker 1: It's also really oaky.
Speaker 1: Like it'll be oaky.
Speaker 0: Because it was in an oak barrel.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, this stuff, like the cherry was there.
Speaker 0: Oh, cherry oak, I get it.
Speaker 1: The cherry was there without the oak and I've never tasted that before.
Speaker 0: Ah, so it's an oak barrel.
Speaker 1: And in my tasting note, I was like, "Tastes like
Speaker 1: cherry?".
Speaker 1: Really tastes like cherry, period.
Speaker 1: And then the sommelier was like, "You may have noticed notes of cherry.
Speaker 1: That is what makes this wine
Speaker 1: distinct.".
Speaker 1: And I was like, "I fucking got this now,
Speaker 1: bitches.".
Speaker 0: It's a test.
Speaker 0: You're trying to beat everyone else there.
Speaker 0: You can't help but turn it into a contest.
Speaker 0: No, you know what it was?
Speaker 1: I just, I like wine a lot and it's really vindicating to say, like to think I taste something.
Speaker 1: And then the expert is like, "Yes, that is what you
Speaker 1: tasted.".
Speaker 0: Anyway, so yeah, the manga in Japan is coming to an end.
Speaker 0: So, as soon as that happens, I guess it's in June.
Speaker 1: Just get a scandulation pack of the whole thing?
Speaker 0: That's fucking a right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, gonna find out what the drops of God are.
Speaker 1: Don't read Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: It spoils shit.
Speaker 0: 100% gonna check out all them drops and not actually drink any of them.
Speaker 1: See, if someone were smart, I would take that manga, take all the kinds of wines and specific vineyards and everything that are mentioned in it and set up crazy cross promotions.
Speaker 0: I would go and find one bottle of each of the apostles and the drops of God and sell it in a package.
Speaker 1: For like 10 or 15 grand.
Speaker 0: Right, one bottle of each, drops of God.
Speaker 1: Well, except for the ones that you can't get.
Speaker 0: I would get them.
Speaker 1: You can't get them all.
Speaker 0: It would be part of the package.
Speaker 0: In fact, so what I learned in Paris is that a lot of the great wine- I'm still pretty sure the actual drops of God are gonna be something like water or the wine you make yourself at home with your own feet.
Speaker 1: So a lot of the best wine I had in Paris, other than like the Grand Cru crazy stuff, was just fucking grocery store wine that cost like a euro.
Speaker 1: A lot of the best wines, they're really great and they don't export it because it's like the cheap wine people drink every day with dinner.
Speaker 1: So that wine can't be like hundreds of dollars.
Speaker 1: So it's cheap, made locally.
Speaker 1: It's not worth exporting and the demand internally is constant and high.
Speaker 1: So all the cheapo grocery store wine is just really, really good.
Speaker 1: Like here, cheapo grocery store wine tastes like shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like why does the-?
Speaker 0: there's no law of the universe that says the best grapes have to be the most rare grapes, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, what if I have the rare grape plant and the rare land, you know, the best grape plant, the best land, but I have a fuck ton of it.
Speaker 0: It's like, oh, they're just- the best wine on earth happens to be a fuck ton of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like a lot of the Grand Cru are like, this particular part of one vineyard just tastes different for reasons.
Speaker 1: So only that counts.
Speaker 1: So they can only make so many barrels of that.
Speaker 0: Right, but what if there's like a million acres that taste like that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well you know what?
Speaker 1: That's the kind of wine that everyone in France drinks with dinner every day.
Speaker 1: that never gets exported outside of France.
Speaker 1: Apparently people in Britain will like drive to France, fill their car with wine, and drive back to Britain.
Speaker 0: Isn't there people like in the channel checking you?
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't get caught.
Speaker 1: was what I was told.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: So in other brief news, if you live in New York, Atlanta, Cambridge, Baltimore, Alexandria, Columbus, a bunch of other cities, Ghost in the Shell arrives.
Speaker 0: It's not even a movie.
Speaker 0: It's like OAV movie things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, kind of like Stand Alone Complex was.
Speaker 1: That was like pay-per-view originally.
Speaker 0: Well, Stand Alone Complex, Solid State Society was OAV.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the first two are just being screened in movie theaters and you can buy tickets.
Speaker 0: But I kind of wanted to wait until they were all done before I watched them.
Speaker 1: I did, but at the same time I kind of really want to see more Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 0: In a movie theater.
Speaker 1: Because I like Silver Spoon, I like Jo-Up Petal.
Speaker 0: Did you watch Silver Spoon?
Speaker 1: I didn't finish the first season.
Speaker 1: Okay, I finished the whole thing.
Speaker 1: But shows that give me that feels, that fuck yeah feels, Kill La Kill did that, Ghost in the Shell did that.
Speaker 0: Who knows if Arise will do that.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling it will.
Speaker 0: You're willing to pay to find out?
Speaker 1: I'm willing to pay to find out.
Speaker 0: Similarly, other situations, Gundam Unicorn UC is almost done, the last episode.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: Which means then that's another one.
Speaker 0: I watched none of that.
Speaker 0: I'm going to watch all of as soon as it's complete.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should watch it together and just do straight up episodes on it.
Speaker 0: We could do that.
Speaker 0: And then I guess those Evangelion movies at some point.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: Will be all done.
Speaker 1: I'm waiting until they're all, all, all done.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm waiting for, you know, 10.1010, you will not watch this again.
Speaker 0: We cannot remake.
Speaker 0: 8, 10, 9, 10, 10, 10.
Speaker 0: End of Anno.
Speaker 0: It's just a video of his funeral.
Speaker 0: He died of smoking too much.
Speaker 1: Maybe what we should do is when they're finally done, let's just marathon the whole goddamn thing.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: So things of the day.
Speaker 1: There's a movie, you know, we're talking about anime, it's anime day.
Speaker 1: The first anime I ever saw when I was in fourth grade.
Speaker 0: How many times are you going to talk?
Speaker 1: And my little brother was too.
Speaker 1: So my brother was so much lately.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should watch it and do a show on it.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to.
Speaker 1: So that's what I think of.
Speaker 1: the day is when my little brother was six and I was eight.
Speaker 1: My parents made us watch vampire hundred D the dub, that dub, the dub that I watched.
Speaker 1: The first anime I ever saw in its entirety is just on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, uh, if you want to see what a very young rim and his young brother watched and decided anime was our fucking thing, it was this.
Speaker 1: When I was eight, this was the greatest thing I had ever seen in my entire life.
Speaker 1: I dressed up as D for Halloween.
Speaker 1: Nobody fucking knew what that was.
Speaker 1: Except my mom and my dad, my brother.
Speaker 0: Let's get a picture of that on the internet.
Speaker 1: I should try to find a picture of that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I don't know how many of you are familiar with the on beastie boys, right?
Speaker 0: Better be.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, you may also know that MCA, right?
Speaker 0: Adam passed away with two years ago.
Speaker 0: Something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: On May the fourth, which is I guess inconvenient.
Speaker 0: I would not want to die on a day associated with the silly star Wars holiday.
Speaker 1: I'd much rather die on yell at the sky day, international day of Slayer, something like that.
Speaker 0: But anyway, around that time every year, uh, they have an event known as MCA day to celebrate him.
Speaker 0: And I hope one day that I am celebrated so that my, the anniversary of my death is a day.
Speaker 0: But anyway, he was known in his life, you know, not just for the music he created, but he was a huge, like.
Speaker 0: his thing was free Tibet, right?
Speaker 0: That was his thing.
Speaker 0: The way that free the internet is our thing, right?
Speaker 0: He was actually, you know, a Tibetan Buddhist himself and you know, he was friends, all these Tibetan Buddhist people.
Speaker 0: That was his, his jam.
Speaker 0: So on MCA day, some Tibetan Buddhist monks honored him with some awesome breakdancing.
Speaker 1: They honored him in the way that he should be honored.
Speaker 0: That is right.
Speaker 0: So that's just fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: And it's awesome shit that happens in New York.
Speaker 0: So watch this goddamn video.
Speaker 0: Oh man.
Speaker 1: In the meta moment forums, we got them.
Speaker 1: They're rocking.
Speaker 1: They're awesome.
Speaker 1: If you don't use good spelling and grammar, we'll fucking ban you.
Speaker 1: That's how awesome they are.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We have IRC channel.
Speaker 0: Like people are getting in it.
Speaker 0: We even have a newsletter.
Speaker 0: I sent it out.
Speaker 0: We have, what else do we have?
Speaker 0: We have lots of videos of all our panels and lectures on YouTube, Twitter, Facebook, and Google plus, and maybe even Twitch and all the places on the internet.
Speaker 0: We are there.
Speaker 1: If you like our shit, spread our shit around, share our shit with other people.
Speaker 1: The more you spread it around and the more people like it, the more we'll do.
Speaker 1: You know, if you young kids don't realize we've been doing geek nights for almost 10 years.
Speaker 1: For many years, we did four fucking episodes a week.
Speaker 0: If you spread our shit, maybe one day we'll just get lucky and hit that pot of gold and we can just do this all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You want us to make 12 episodes a week?
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: You want us to make video games?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We can do all kinds of stuff if maybe someone with a lot of money likes us someday.
Speaker 0: The book club selection is Canicle for Leibowitz.
Speaker 0: You should buy that and read it because I've seen it mentioned in like so many places.
Speaker 0: I have to check it out.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Also, you should look at the rest of the geek nights book club.
Speaker 1: We've done a bunch of books.
Speaker 1: They're not all awesome, but they're all worth reading for one reason or another, except the King Killer Chronicle.
Speaker 1: Don't read that one.
Speaker 1: I cannot express to you how rustled my fucking jimmies are about that book.
Speaker 0: You just can't get over it.
Speaker 1: It did rustle me and it continues to rustle me.
Speaker 0: You should make your next selection something so bad.
Speaker 1: That it'll wash it out?
Speaker 1: Alright, Scott.
Speaker 1: Atlas Shrugged.
Speaker 0: Go for it.
Speaker 1: Have you read Atlas Shrugged?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think Atlas Shrugged is worse.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Ulysses.
Speaker 1: I'll read Ulysses.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: No, you won't.
Speaker 0: I don't have time for that.
Speaker 1: You're going to break the book club?
Speaker 1: Ain't?
Speaker 0: no one got time for that.
Speaker 1: Ethan Frome.
Speaker 0: I already read that.
Speaker 1: I've actually never read it.
Speaker 0: Guy rides a sled down a hill, dies.
Speaker 0: The end.
Speaker 1: He doesn't die.
Speaker 1: Spoilers.
Speaker 1: That's the point.
Speaker 0: I read it in like, I don't know, sixth grade.
Speaker 0: What the fuck do I remember?
Speaker 0: I can't even remember Adventure Time.
Speaker 0: I watched it last year.
Speaker 1: That he wants to commit suicide on a sled and fucks that up.
Speaker 1: And it makes everything worse.
Speaker 0: And you're the one who hasn't read the book?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I read excerpts from it for class in like high school.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Adventure Time.
Speaker 1: So we've been watching Adventure Time for a long time, as you guys know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we already did an episode on it.
Speaker 0: So why would we talk about it again?
Speaker 1: Well, I guess we could turn into Anime Pulse and just review every episode of every show we watch as it comes out and not talk about anything else.
Speaker 0: That's someone else's job.
Speaker 1: Anime Pulse's job, apparently.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: But no, I think Adventure Time warrants a little more discussion since a lot, the show's done a lot since we first watched it.
Speaker 1: And while our reviews were pretty on point, what we didn't do is kind of talk about where it's going and all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: Kind of like an ongoing review.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's hard to say, oh, we've reviewed, you know, Space Dandy because there's only one season.
Speaker 1: There might be more stuff.
Speaker 1: Imagine if Space Dandy had 50 seasons.
Speaker 0: It's sort of impossible.
Speaker 0: How do you review something?
Speaker 0: It's like when something is a single item, it's easy to review, but when it goes on forever, how do you even do that?
Speaker 1: Well, you do it by, I guess, story arc you could review.
Speaker 1: You could do it by...
Speaker 0: You got to break it into some sort of item.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But anyway, since there's so much freaking Adventure Time and I only watched every episode once and my memory is awful, right?
Speaker 0: We called our friend Adventure Time expert Judith to come and help us talk about Adventure Time.
Speaker 0: Hello.
Speaker 1: Judith is pretty much the most expert at Adventure Time that we know.
Speaker 0: Also Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: In fact, I think I scheduled her to do an Adventure Time panel at Kineticon.
Speaker 0: Oh, how about that?
Speaker 1: It was either that or one of the 19 Ask a Homestuck panels that got submitted.
Speaker 0: So are you telling me that Kineticon, a relatively smaller convention in Hartford, Connecticut, where no one ever wants to go, has a better Adventure Time panel than every other convention ever?
Speaker 1: It might have the best one that's ever happened.
Speaker 0: That's crazy.
Speaker 0: No pressure.
Speaker 1: Don't worry.
Speaker 1: We'll just video it and livestream it on the internet.
Speaker 1: Oh, alright.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: So the only thing I'll warn you guys about is kind of good to spoil stuff, because we're just going to talk about the show.
Speaker 1: So if you really care about spoilers in Adventure Time, I would suggest watching Adventure Time.
Speaker 1: The episodes are not long.
Speaker 0: The number of episodes, it doesn't take long to watch all of it.
Speaker 1: Well, I remember when I thought, oh, I'll watch Adventure Time.
Speaker 1: Everyone's talking about it.
Speaker 1: I feel like I'm left out by not watching it.
Speaker 1: And then I saw there's like a bajillion episodes, and that was back when there were only like three seasons.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Alright, so should we begin with the recent events that are on everyone's mind?
Speaker 1: So Finn finally lost his fucking arm.
Speaker 0: Saw that coming so far away.
Speaker 2: Everybody did though.
Speaker 1: Did everyone.
Speaker 1: The internet did not seem to see that coming.
Speaker 2: It was only foreshadowed like hell.
Speaker 1: Two smart people.
Speaker 1: It was Chekhov's arm.
Speaker 1: I mean, I remember when I noticed that it wasn't until the alternate reality world.
Speaker 0: Where you had the metal arm and the farm and shit.
Speaker 1: And then was it Puhoy?
Speaker 1: Was that the episode where you met the cloud people and had sex with them and then made cloud babies?
Speaker 2: Yeah, and he got a pillow arm.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And that was when I noticed that there was a trend of...
Speaker 0: I forgot all about that.
Speaker 1: You forgot about that?
Speaker 0: I forgot about that.
Speaker 1: I watched that episode a couple of times because I'd keep seeing the title and be like, "Puhoy?
Speaker 1: The fuck was that
Speaker 1: episode?".
Speaker 0: I'll have to go back and rewatch that one.
Speaker 1: Do you remember why it's called Puhoy?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: That's just what cloud people... Or cloud people.
Speaker 1: That's what pillow people say.
Speaker 0: Oh, pillow people.
Speaker 0: Oh, now I don't remember even more than just cloud people.
Speaker 1: I kept saying cloud people because there are cloud people.
Speaker 1: We saw one.
Speaker 0: Is it just me?
Speaker 0: People always talk about how Adventure Time is one of those shows that's on multiple levels.
Speaker 0: The adult sees this and the kid sees that, right?
Speaker 0: But it feels like, especially that newest episode, The Tower, it's 100% adult.
Speaker 1: Not just the newest episode.
Speaker 1: The latter half of this season has been pretty much since Finn blew it with Flame Princess.
Speaker 0: What does a kid get out of watching The Tower or the episode with Prismo and whatnot?
Speaker 2: I kind of agree with you on that one, especially since the start of season six.
Speaker 2: I was watching it and thinking, "This is not for
Speaker 2: children.".
Speaker 1: Could we say that?
Speaker 1: maybe, as you've noticed, Finn is aging at about the rate that the show is coming out, so he's getting older.
Speaker 0: But no one else is because everyone else is magical?
Speaker 1: It's Oz World.
Speaker 1: Ozma of Oz does not age.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: Just like Peebs.
Speaker 1: People don't age in that world.
Speaker 1: So Finn's getting older.
Speaker 1: Maybe the audience is just getting older at the same rate?
Speaker 0: But everyone else has an excuse for not aging, right?
Speaker 0: It's like Jake is a magical dog guy and Princess Bubblegum is made of gum, but Finn is a human.
Speaker 1: With apparently ultra psychic powers.
Speaker 0: He's not a hot dog princess or a lumpy space princess.
Speaker 1: So thus he's aging.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and no one else is aging because everyone else is a talking pig or some shit.
Speaker 2: Jake's getting older.
Speaker 2: It's just harder to see because he's not going through puberty.
Speaker 2: He apparently already did.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's like 30.
Speaker 2: He's gaining a lot of weight.
Speaker 0: Jake's supposed to be way older than Finn, though, right?
Speaker 0: He's like a middle aged dude.
Speaker 1: That might just be of mind because of dog years.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: I pretty much always assume that.
Speaker 0: So Jonathan was actually kind of young, is that what you're saying?
Speaker 1: Well, Jonathan, I think he died in like his late 40s.
Speaker 2: You mean Joshua?
Speaker 0: Joshua, right?
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Way to go.
Speaker 2: I told you my memory's awful.
Speaker 0: That's why we needed you here.
Speaker 1: But so we don't need an excuse.
Speaker 1: That's why Finn's aging.
Speaker 1: So maybe just the target demographic of the show is aging with Finn.
Speaker 1: I mean, a 14 year old could learn about revenge.
Speaker 0: So the show is what, five, six years old?
Speaker 2: Something like that.
Speaker 0: Something like that?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 2: Don't ask me numbers.
Speaker 0: I'll actually look it up because that is somewhat interesting.
Speaker 1: The pilot was in 2007.
Speaker 1: The first season was in 2010.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So the actual show, because you know, the only people who saw that pilot were people like us, right?
Speaker 0: On the YouTube.
Speaker 1: I remember we watched that on YouTube.
Speaker 1: It was one of the first videos we saw on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Um, but yeah.
Speaker 0: So, okay.
Speaker 0: So it was like four or five years old.
Speaker 0: So I guess how old would like an eight year old would start watching it.
Speaker 0: And now they're 13.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it was 10 to 12 year olds even at the beginning.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: But you know, I guess that can make sense.
Speaker 1: Finn was not eight years old in season one.
Speaker 0: Like a four or five year old wasn't watching it, right?
Speaker 0: In 2010.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The demographic seemed to be 10 year olds and 30 year olds.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: It's like, I guess that can make sense to the people who are now in their young teens who started watching it then, even though it's only been a handful of years.
Speaker 1: But partly I've, I've kind of noticed, I don't know if you guys agree, but the show every season has had a, an arc where the very, after the first season where the beginning is just resolving the previous season stuff and it's super serious, then it's a bunch of unrelated funny stuff and then all the Chekhov guns build up and then they all blow up at the end of the season and suddenly it gets all adult again.
Speaker 0: Pony does the same thing.
Speaker 0: They put their plot episodes at the beginning and the end.
Speaker 1: Don't use that word with those people anymore.
Speaker 0: For the season premiere and the season finales.
Speaker 0: And then all the middle episodes are just fillers.
Speaker 1: Not the same way that the Chekhov's gun in Pony is like Chekhov party poppers.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying that, I'm just saying this, the same model of, you know, because they have seasons of shows, right?
Speaker 0: They put all the big episodes as season premieres and finales cause.
Speaker 0: that's the big deal.
Speaker 0: Even South Park doesn't.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least the US shows.
Speaker 2: Yeah, but if we're talking about like a range of darkness, then I would say adventure time.
Speaker 2: season six and five had extremely dark starts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, definitely.
Speaker 1: Of course then again, well let's see.
Speaker 1: So season two ended with heat signature and the flame princess stuff.
Speaker 0: That's that long ago?
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 1: Mortal recoil, mortal folly.
Speaker 2: That was the end of season two.
Speaker 0: That feels way more recent than the mortal.
Speaker 2: real recoil stuff was the end of season two.
Speaker 2: I believe flame princess's introduction was the end of season three.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: I was going to say.
Speaker 1: Yep, incendium, incendium as opposed to heat signature.
Speaker 1: It feels like flame princess came in way later, right?
Speaker 1: But I think when the show first hit his real dark notes that were obvious was the whole alternate reality.
Speaker 1: fin wakes up as a human after making the wish.
Speaker 1: Like that shit was kind of creepy.
Speaker 2: That was the most blatantly dark, but there were some darker seeds before that for sure.
Speaker 1: There were, but they could be written off by a child.
Speaker 1: True.
Speaker 1: Like a child could just kind of go, whatever, not notice.
Speaker 1: Like you could kind of write those off as the, those elements that are in children's movies that are kind of just brushed aside before the end happens.
Speaker 2: You always had this safe, fantastical adventure time world to retreat to.
Speaker 2: It would always go back to the status quo.
Speaker 2: And even though it did, after the season five premiere, there was still kind of an uncomfortable feeling leftover.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Cause it kind of showed you this other world and what could have been, and it was just horrible.
Speaker 1: Like really, really horrible.
Speaker 1: And you start to realize that Jake's not the most responsible person.
Speaker 2: That was kind of obvious.
Speaker 1: I just remember when he's watching the video of what's going on in Finn's alternate reality.
Speaker 1: He's kind of like, yeah, he's got this whatevs.
Speaker 0: I think Jake is just sort of like, it's really inconsistent and all over the place.
Speaker 0: Like if you watch the episode just now, right?
Speaker 0: The tower, he was relatively stable and you know, in control other than supporting Finn's crazy idea to build the tower.
Speaker 1: Are you thinking of the episode where they're in, they're trapped in the sand kingdom?
Speaker 2: Oh, he was that guy in that episode.
Speaker 1: He's just a that guy fuck up in that episode.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, sometimes it'll be like an adult and other times he will totally be the most dangerous possible person to be around.
Speaker 2: Sometimes he'll give terrible advice, but with the utmost of confidence and young Finn will be like, oh yeah, yeah, let's just do that.
Speaker 1: Listen to your Mellenhart.
Speaker 1: Mellenhart's telling me to kill my dad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not your Mellenhart.
Speaker 0: See?
Speaker 0: That's the responsible Jake.
Speaker 1: Except I think that was his Mellenhart.
Speaker 0: Probably.
Speaker 1: But it really, the moment the show got it, I don't want to say it got sexual, but kind of do because it was honestly that episode that led up to you blew it man with flame princess because there is no way to cast that episode as anything other than puberty.
Speaker 2: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean those dreams, the one where he's wriggling around in his little, uh, his pants are on fire and he loves it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: This feels great.
Speaker 1: And then he's trying to recreate that feeling and then in doing so he pushes away the only girl who ever probably loved him.
Speaker 1: You blew it, man.
Speaker 1: Granted, I think the cosmic owl was being kind of a dick there.
Speaker 1: Could've just told him.
Speaker 0: And then when you know, it's cosmic owl is weird too.
Speaker 0: It's like he seems so mysterious, but now that you've seen some mysterious and then he's just like hanging out in like the hot tub at Prismo's place and it's like, his job seems to be to, uh, there's drama going on here.
Speaker 1: I'm out of here.
Speaker 1: See ya.
Speaker 0: I mean, princess Luna is more responsible than my cosmic owl.
Speaker 1: All Luna does is just watch everyone's dreams and then she helps them out and intervene in them.
Speaker 0: She's doing the cosmic owl's job right.
Speaker 0: That's what the cosmic owl should be doing.
Speaker 2: That's really creepy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but she is.
Speaker 1: I mean, she's straight up watching people's dreams and then she doesn't even stop Sweetie Belle from doing her bullshit.
Speaker 1: She lets her do it and then she tells her wrong.
Speaker 0: show guys.
Speaker 0: I know it's my fault, but seriously, it always is.
Speaker 1: But from that moment, I mean, if we look at the list of episodes in season five and six, especially season six, I mean, let's see, we've got, oh my God, there's a lot of episodes in season five.
Speaker 1: So Finn, the human Jake, the dog, that was, that was kind of serious.
Speaker 1: Uh, Pahoy had those elements.
Speaker 1: Simon and Marcy, there's been a lot of those episodes lately and they just go full on in now.
Speaker 1: They don't dance around.
Speaker 1: They don't leave anything ambiguous.
Speaker 1: They're like, let's explore this world some more.
Speaker 1: Oh, look at this exact flashback of what happened back then.
Speaker 2: What else is there to hide now?
Speaker 2: We know what happened, kind of mostly true, but notice how.
Speaker 1: in the old days they'd hinted these things.
Speaker 1: They'd give you vignettes, they'd give you little flashes and ideas, but then they sort of transitioned into this.
Speaker 1: Let's just have a long running flashback that tells all and kind of assume that all the other characters now couldn't keep up those hints forever.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Well, that's the thing that I'm seeing now is they're facing all the Chekhov's guns are firing and all the, they're all empty, like there's nothing else to fire.
Speaker 0: What are they going to possibly add more to other than just rolling the things that they've already got forward?
Speaker 2: I don't know.
Speaker 2: Flame Princess is still a powder keg.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah.
Speaker 1: And they haven't really resolved any of that, even though honestly it fins the state up until now.
Speaker 1: I think Cinnamon Bun's a better person for her to be with, a little more stable and adult.
Speaker 2: I seriously don't think that's romantic though.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 2: If that's what you're implying.
Speaker 1: How would that possibly, that'd be, it's like, yeah, yeah, because that's any less plausible than a human boy and fire.
Speaker 0: It's at least got more merit than a flammable big good.
Speaker 1: Plus, I mean, the world is mostly candy people and monsters.
Speaker 0: It's this area of ooh.
Speaker 1: Most of the world is monsters then.
Speaker 0: But I mean, there's other dimensions, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, where, you know, the hell place where Marceline's dad lives.
Speaker 2: There's infinite dimensions.
Speaker 2: They established that a long time ago.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: When is that established?
Speaker 2: The first time Prisma was introduced.
Speaker 0: Oh, he says there's infinity dimensions.
Speaker 2: The little keeper guy introduces them to that in this really, really fast spoken monologue.
Speaker 1: With the whole Enchiridion thing.
Speaker 2: You have to listen to it a lot.
Speaker 1: I take it.
Speaker 1: you've watched that part.
Speaker 0: I've listened to it once.
Speaker 0: Over an hour.
Speaker 1: I've watched those episodes a bunch of times.
Speaker 2: I've watched it like three or four times.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 2: It's 11 minutes long.
Speaker 0: I'll just trust you then.
Speaker 0: Because I have no choice but not to do so.
Speaker 1: But we had like the two part Lemon Hopper, which seemed to just be about internet libertarians.
Speaker 0: I love that at Lemon Hope.
Speaker 1: At the wedding, we learned just how creepy tree trunks really is.
Speaker 0: For some reason, the whole lemon situation, when it first appeared, it's just like, shut up lemons.
Speaker 0: Never appear again in this show.
Speaker 1: I love lemons.
Speaker 0: It's just like, why isn't this a lemon episode?
Speaker 2: I love lemon grab after his first appearance.
Speaker 2: He was hilarious.
Speaker 0: I meant the first appearance of any lemons whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Well, Scott, you were the same way with LSP.
Speaker 1: You were like, oh my God, I hate this character.
Speaker 0: No, LSP from the beginning was like, oh my God.
Speaker 1: I remember I was using LSP as an example.
Speaker 1: We were at a con.
Speaker 1: It was like an anime Boston.
Speaker 1: You weren't watching Adventure Time yet.
Speaker 1: And I was like, you saw an LSP and you were like, what's that thing?
Speaker 1: It's really cute.
Speaker 1: And I was like, you're going to watch Adventure Time someday and you're going to really hate what that thing is.
Speaker 0: It's definitely not cute, but it's still the best thing.
Speaker 1: But they've left Betty unresolved, Flame Princess unresolved.
Speaker 1: Rattleballs is out there.
Speaker 1: He could do something.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: So it's like the Chekhov's guns are just characters that happen to exist.
Speaker 0: That's like saying that in The Simpsons, Moe is a Chekhov's gun because he hasn't been.
Speaker 1: These are characters that exist, interacted with the main characters and have still unresolved issues.
Speaker 2: I thought Rattleballs was going to be the one to provide Finn with a new arm since his arm kind of looks like the one that Finn has been depicted with.
Speaker 0: Look who's looking at the details there.
Speaker 1: While that might be true, every reality where Finn has lost his arm, he has gotten a different arm.
Speaker 1: I don't think he can get the same kind of arm in two places.
Speaker 2: I'm not going to confirm or deny that.
Speaker 2: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: That's just my theory.
Speaker 1: I feel like every version of Finn has a different arm.
Speaker 2: Well, Rattleballs was thrown into the mix for a reason.
Speaker 2: Maybe they haven't come up with it yet, but definitely for a reason.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about this arm though, right?
Speaker 0: So he had the leaf sword, the grass sword, right?
Speaker 1: Well, that episode alone, that episode had all appearances of being a throwaway episode and got serious real quick.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: With my favorite character, choose Goose, who needs to show up more often.
Speaker 1: I thought LSP was your favorite character.
Speaker 0: Also choose Goose.
Speaker 2: LSP is better.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so he gets the leaf arm, right?
Speaker 0: The sword.
Speaker 0: Then he's cool with it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Then it basically, when he needs to use it, it devours his whole arm and pops off.
Speaker 0: And then the magic goop, right?
Speaker 0: That I guess that goop was keeping people alive and stable and unaging for long periods.
Speaker 1: Well, that goop is a perfect heal-all.
Speaker 1: It heals anything 100%.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it healed his arm into this flower.
Speaker 1: Well, it healed it back into the flower.
Speaker 1: So that means that his arm's essence was replaced by that cursed plant.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Now, if he gets more goop somehow, would the flower grow even more?
Speaker 0: or is that the max for that flower?
Speaker 1: I think it's going to grow back into a flower.
Speaker 2: It looked like the goop healed the sword and not the human arm.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: So the sword should grow back into a proper sword, I guess.
Speaker 0: Is he going to maybe have a plant arm eventually if it keeps growing?
Speaker 0: Is he giving it enough water and sunlight?
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 2: Well, where would he give water?
Speaker 2: Just sweat on it?
Speaker 0: I guess.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Dip it in water occasionally?
Speaker 0: Drink the water?
Speaker 0: It's got roots probably in his upper arm.
Speaker 2: It's magic.
Speaker 2: It probably doesn't need any of that.
Speaker 0: Why doesn't he go ask some wizards about it or some shit?
Speaker 1: You know, it's kind of a aside.
Speaker 1: You know what that arm reminded me of a lot?
Speaker 1: And I thought about this.
Speaker 1: Dajan.
Speaker 1: That whole episode with the cursed arm reminded me of Dajan and the feather just because that arm is kind of wicked powerful.
Speaker 0: Well, now it's not.
Speaker 0: Or maybe it still is.
Speaker 0: Nah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But actually.
Speaker 1: So the mechanical arm he had in his previous life as that awesome thief girl is similar to the arm he had in the alternate reality where he becomes the Ice King and fights Jake the Lich.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: I thought all of his mechanical arms at least looked a little bit smaller.
Speaker 1: But they are distinctly different in that the human, Finn the human arm has two bits and two bits and a sort of like and the joint is different.
Speaker 1: But the grabbers the same.
Speaker 0: It's a. it's a metal arm of the grabber.
Speaker 0: Go find a picture of Rattleballs and let's check his arms out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm looking at Rattleballs.
Speaker 1: I think Rattleballs had a hand.
Speaker 2: I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: I'm not looking it up.
Speaker 1: But when Finn saw the flash forward future of him on the train, his arm is just his fucking whip.
Speaker 2: Wasn't his arm all decked out?
Speaker 1: It was all decked out, but it's a decked out whip.
Speaker 1: It's like a. it's like a weird arm with a hook.
Speaker 1: And then on the end of the hook is a whip and then the other arm's got a semi-permanent looking gauntlet.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: But oh, it's just a pillow.
Speaker 1: So why don't you
Speaker 0: make a list of like all the plot episodes of Adventure Time so you can like breeze, you know, not because you should only watch the plot episodes, but because if you've already watched the whole show but you need to refresh yourself because you only watched it once like me, you can refresh quickly and not have to rewatch, you know, the episodes that aren't.
Speaker 1: Well, is it?
Speaker 1: is it plot episodes or gun episodes?
Speaker 0: Any episode will count if it is an episode that affects either is, you know, a direct main plot episode like the two that started this season or the end of the season.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Or one that has some sort of effect.
Speaker 0: Because like the one where he gets the grass sword doesn't you know, it seems like a one off.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And that's the thing they do.
Speaker 0: is even their one off episodic episodes don't?
Speaker 0: it's like they have some sort of like.
Speaker 0: they leave a mark on the universe in some way.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: By like creating a character or creating an item or changing a character or changing a place or a thing.
Speaker 0: Or or the nature of a character's relationship.
Speaker 0: And then they bring that back and it stays that way in all future episodes until it's changed again.
Speaker 2: You mean the show has continuity?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Rattleballs just has a fucking hand, but it's not.
Speaker 0: you know, there are a lot of things that have continuity.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Like Marvel Comics or whatever, but they don't necessarily modify the continuity all the time.
Speaker 1: It's like almost every adventure type episode does something or at least it has an element that is probably intended to be used in the future if they want to.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Whereas other things that have continuity will still have just episodic shit that doesn't affect the continuity in any way.
Speaker 0: Like, OK, these are is a bunch of filler that doesn't affect anything.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Like one piece movies.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the difference is Adventure Time does it much more subtly and aptly than ponies has lately and that ponies will zoom all the way in on the thing and be like, hey, guys, hey, guys, hey, guys, look at this.
Speaker 1: Look right here.
Speaker 1: This is the plot.
Speaker 1: And Adventure Time is like just gets a cursed sword and then it becomes his arm at the end.
Speaker 0: And then it's still.
Speaker 0: it's actually still there the next episode.
Speaker 0: Oh, my gosh.
Speaker 1: But then some other things aren't still there.
Speaker 0: What other show does that?
Speaker 1: So in the preview for the next episode, he just has two human arms.
Speaker 1: Just point that out.
Speaker 1: I saw it.
Speaker 1: I saw pictures from it.
Speaker 1: I think it's just because that episode was directed and put together before.
Speaker 2: Is that the food chain episode?
Speaker 2: Yes.
Speaker 2: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 2: That's probably why.
Speaker 1: So are they going to do deal with that in some way?
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm curious.
Speaker 0: How about this Masaki Yuasa episode?
Speaker 0: If you that's the episode.
Speaker 0: I thought I didn't think that was the next one.
Speaker 0: I thought that one still a ways out.
Speaker 1: It's coming up soon anyway.
Speaker 1: At any point, at any rate, he has two arms.
Speaker 0: But that episode and the preview for it, you know, who's there?
Speaker 1: LSP?
Speaker 0: Magic Man.
Speaker 1: I like Magic Man a lot.
Speaker 0: I don't like Magic Man.
Speaker 0: He's a jerk.
Speaker 1: So do you think the show is going to keep getting more and more adult, like for real adult?
Speaker 1: Like, is it going to be dealing with like?
Speaker 1: really will it deal with more serious issues that it already has in the next season?
Speaker 2: I think it might have to dip back into the subtlety after a while, because, you know, they they can push the boundaries being as popular as they are, a massively popular cartoon.
Speaker 2: But if they push it too far and stay too adult for too long, Cartoon Network is going to take issue because it's very, very important to them to keep that 8 to 12 little boy demographic watching the show.
Speaker 2: And if they start, you know, losing interest because we're just dealing with grief and relationship issues and.
Speaker 0: Or maybe they'll get interest, you know, when I was eight to 12, I wouldn't want to watch this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I think when I when I was eight to 12, I'd already seen Vampire Hunter D.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 2: Not everybody had the same eight to 12 foot as you guys.
Speaker 1: They should have.
Speaker 0: They can get all the money from the smart kids, not the dumb kids.
Speaker 1: It's like Donald Duck in Math Magic Land.
Speaker 2: Right.
Speaker 2: Money from the smart kids.
Speaker 1: I think I think one easy thing they can do to move forward is resolve the fucking shit with Flame Princess and have Finn get over his grief.
Speaker 0: Well, no, is they can start to combine different things.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So it's like you don't see me like Finn's arm and Finn's dead.
Speaker 0: No, like, you know, there are parts of the plot that sort of go together like Finn's arm and Finn's dead.
Speaker 0: But there are other things that don't really go together.
Speaker 0: Like, how about Flame Princess plus Lemon Hope?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like those things don't even touch each other whatsoever.
Speaker 0: What if they did?
Speaker 1: That's the most is like goes with Lenny on a trip episode.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: You've got to have 10 seasons before you start that shit.
Speaker 1: Minimum.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying there's a whole lot of territory of that nature.
Speaker 2: They already know what's going to happen to Lemon Hope.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we do.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: We'll probably never see him again.
Speaker 0: But there's a lot of time.
Speaker 0: There's no need.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's resolved.
Speaker 2: He's just off hippying for the rest of his life.
Speaker 1: Granted, the only real takeaway from Lemon Hope is, one, libertarianism is a failed philosophy.
Speaker 1: Two, there's no such thing as fate and destiny.
Speaker 1: Three, Peeves could have planned that better.
Speaker 2: Oh, come on.
Speaker 2: Come on.
Speaker 2: You don't even know what happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we have a good idea of what happened.
Speaker 2: It looked like a war.
Speaker 1: Actually, it reminded me a lot of the end of a book from a series.
Speaker 1: I shouldn't say what it is because it might spoil things.
Speaker 1: At the end of this book, it ends and you get an epilogue that takes place like 50,000 years later and it just kind of offhandedly reveals pretty much everything.
Speaker 2: Man, that episode left me feeling drained.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that last scene, that was just so I loved it.
Speaker 1: But geez, well, there was.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you've seen Brazil, I have not that episode, that whole Lemon Hope.
Speaker 1: that one Brazil's really good, but it's also really long and allegorical and at times boring.
Speaker 0: I see where you go with this.
Speaker 0: But Brazil is the Lemon Kingdom.
Speaker 1: The Lemon Hope stuff was a straight up reference to Brazil.
Speaker 1: OK, with the wings and all that stuff, with Lemon Hope, it's 100 percent.
Speaker 2: I do want to see that movie.
Speaker 2: You should watch that movie when I have several hours to put aside.
Speaker 1: Just make sure you watch the correct version.
Speaker 1: If you watch the wrong version, you'll know because it has a happy ending.
Speaker 2: Oh, which version is on Netflix?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I really don't know.
Speaker 1: Just if you see a happy ending, you fucked up.
Speaker 1: That's all I can say.
Speaker 1: It does not end happily.
Speaker 2: One important thing to note, the storyboard for the episode Lemon Hope.
Speaker 2: at the very end, when they're showing the ruined city, they put a note there that said it was not bombed.
Speaker 2: It's abandoned.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, I mean, you could tell that watching it, right?
Speaker 1: But it's interesting that they made that that was intentional, that they wanted to make it clear that these people left, this kingdom failed.
Speaker 0: Well, clearly, we're going to get an episode at some point.
Speaker 0: Or move down.
Speaker 1: Maybe they reintegrate with the candy people.
Speaker 0: Where the Lemons leave the, you know, abandon the event, the Lemon Kingdom.
Speaker 1: Well, I kind of like that more if they don't tell you how that resolved itself.
Speaker 2: The Lemon stuff?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 2: But that would mean we wouldn't see Lemon Grab again.
Speaker 2: We have to.
Speaker 1: We could keep seeing Lemon Grab because...
Speaker 0: What else is he going to do?
Speaker 1: That could have resolved itself 500 years down the road.
Speaker 2: He's going to come back and scream some more.
Speaker 2: That's all I need.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's acceptable.
Speaker 1: Is it now?
Speaker 1: What we need is the episode where, like, LSP goes on an exchange program to cast a Lemon Grab to try and make diplomatic relations.
Speaker 0: That's another kind of combo, right?
Speaker 0: It's some Lemon Grab plus Marceline.
Speaker 1: Well, they did have that episode where it was Lemon Grab, Tree Trunks, The Little Worm, Shelby, Ice King.
Speaker 0: I loved that episode.
Speaker 0: Sesame Street.
Speaker 1: That episode was...
Speaker 2: What does that noise mean?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the episode where the armor is so...
Speaker 1: That's season one, that armor.
Speaker 1: Chews Goose's armor.
Speaker 2: Oh, I only saw that one once, actually.
Speaker 0: That's one of my favorite episodes.
Speaker 0: It's so... Really?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Scott just really likes Chews Goose.
Speaker 1: Like, really likes Chews Goose.
Speaker 1: Well... But I expected the show, because up until now, every time they've introduced some of these big plotty things, they ratchet down the tension within five or six episodes tops.
Speaker 1: But since the Flame Princess incident, like, they've just left that hanging and they've referenced it.
Speaker 1: And every time they've referenced it or gone back toward it, they've just ratcheted it up more.
Speaker 2: Yeah, and the only way they resolved it this time was to give Finn even greater grief than losing his girlfriend.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like any episode you watch, even if it doesn't even mention it at all, it's like, they'll be like, for like a second, you know, Finn will be like, "Hmm," or something.
Speaker 0: And you just can't not think about it.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it's like if someone hadn't seen those earlier episodes, they wouldn't think that.
Speaker 0: But it's just like just seeing the characters there.
Speaker 0: You think about all the things that they're carrying because you're carrying them because you saw that shit.
Speaker 1: And they haven't unburdened us.
Speaker 0: Even if they don't mention it or show it or anything.
Speaker 1: Like Billy's bucket list, like that episode.
Speaker 1: I mean, one, they introduced what's-your-name, Billy's ex-girlfriend, Canyon, who's kind of awesome in a big way.
Speaker 1: And just now we had, like he was talking to that Cloud girl and they keep introducing him to female characters in the same manner that they originally introduced him to Flame Princess, in the sense that it's just sort of this character that's there.
Speaker 0: That's how Marceline showed up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're all just passing by.
Speaker 1: And every time you see Finn just continuing to not deal with his issues.
Speaker 2: Most of the characters Finn has met, encountered, or helped since the beginning has been female.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 2: I don't know if the intention behind that has changed since the beginning and it's slowly evolving.
Speaker 2: I think that is the case because it was just like rescue stuff in the beginning.
Speaker 1: And they, well, they used to make a lot of jokes about how all the princesses really want to marry Finn.
Speaker 0: Well, I even saw that in the tower.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, all these princesses bought you all these gloves, fake arms, Finn.
Speaker 1: So they reference that again, meaning maybe they're leading up to something again.
Speaker 0: I think there was an episode on the list of upcoming episodes that it was something princess.
Speaker 1: Sad face, food chain, princess day.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 1: That one's written.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's, uh, so, uh, try to look at who did it.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll learn something about all these similar crowns.
Speaker 0: All the princesses wear some shit.
Speaker 1: Well, we learned about that with the Enchiridion stuff way back.
Speaker 1: What else more are they going to do?
Speaker 1: So I think the loudest I laughed in all of Adventure Time was when LSP's Crystal just bounced off the Enchiridion and wasn't involved.
Speaker 1: I laughed out loud so hard.
Speaker 1: Like, I think back to that moment as being something that I really enjoy.
Speaker 2: One of the moments that squicked me out the most from the show was when they were pulling it out of her head.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know, we know.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it's quick.
Speaker 1: Me out is anytime True Trunks is talking.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: We know that much about the Enchiridion, but it's like, where did the Enchiridion come from?
Speaker 0: Who created it?
Speaker 0: Why did Billy have it?
Speaker 0: Who wrote that shit, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, we know this post-apocalyptic stuff we know at least enough about.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Like, how other than radiation did you get from the post-apocalypse to the magical world?
Speaker 0: You know, where did these specific magic things come from?
Speaker 0: Like, where did the Lich come from?
Speaker 1: Well, the Lich was, I mean, either that bomb blowing up in that place released something that was always there or that bomb itself was special in some way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's stuff like that, right?
Speaker 2: That bomb seemed to be the thing that released not only destruction, but also magic into the world.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But with magic comes the Lich.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 2: Because a world where the Lich never existed is one where the bomb never went off.
Speaker 0: But what about the rest of the universe?
Speaker 0: Like, the shit on Mars and whatnot and other dimensions and...
Speaker 1: That's something they have not addressed very well.
Speaker 1: is the rest of the cosmos, because that was much more sinister and mysterious all the way up through when the Prismo stuff happened, and now it's getting increasingly humorous.
Speaker 0: They've run out of room on ooze that are reaching into space more frequently.
Speaker 1: Like, the space stuff is being more and more prominent, which is interesting, but at the same time, it removes the sort of ominousness of the fact that there is an outside world.
Speaker 1: Like, the fact that everything that we'd seen up to this point could have been undone by Prismo in one wish is not as ominous.
Speaker 1: now that there's basically Green Lantern space stuff happening and space is dead.
Speaker 1: Space is dead.
Speaker 1: Finn's dead in space.
Speaker 1: The space Hitler is out doing his thing and, like, wherever he is...
Speaker 0: You gotta assume he's space Hitler.
Speaker 1: I am 100% sure he's space Hitler.
Speaker 0: But think about all those other space Hitlers that were also released.
Speaker 1: No, those are space Goibels.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: They're not Hitler.
Speaker 1: They're not... He's the leader of the space Hitlers already.
Speaker 1: He became their leader in, what, eight seconds?
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 2: Maybe less.
Speaker 1: I wonder if he was always their leader.
Speaker 1: I wonder if everyone on that place was arrested with him.
Speaker 2: They're not going to revisit that again for a while.
Speaker 2: They're going to treat it the same way they did with the Lich Stuff.
Speaker 1: Which I think is fine.
Speaker 1: I'm more interested in resolving Finn's emotional baggage.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I believe they're going to work on, you know, I would put "resolve" in quotes because that's a lot of shit to get over, but they're going to work on building us back up to some fun episodes, not just, like, one interspersed with all these depressing ones like we've been getting.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, James 2 was the most back to old Adventure Time we've seen, I think, because it had all those scenes where Finn and Jake are just like, "Yeah, we're going to sit this one
Speaker 1: out.".
Speaker 1: That was funny.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they're just in the background the whole time giggling and not getting involved.
Speaker 2: And they got PB to chill for a little bit, too.
Speaker 1: That's my favorite scene when they're all up there laughing and you see the Banana Guard and the James both trying to work it out, can't quite get there.
Speaker 2: Yeah, PB's sitting out there being like, "Yeah, I made those idiots.
Speaker 2: God damn
Speaker 2: it.".
Speaker 0: Those are definitely some of my favorite episodes, the ones where it's just Adventure Time, like the one where she's like, "Finn goes in the dungeon,
Speaker 0: woooo!".
Speaker 0: That's the whole episode, right?
Speaker 0: Or even the one where the armor is, "It's about questing, adventuring, and...".
Speaker 1: Most of those episodes from season four-ish onward have had moments of issues.
Speaker 0: Or even like Infinity Train.
Speaker 1: But it's interesting because the more I watch the show, the more I want to see those issues and see that stuff be addressed.
Speaker 1: Yet, as you kind of pointed out, that's the opposite of what young kids want to see.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 2: Maybe they're trying to Harry Potter it and have it actually grow with its audience.
Speaker 2: But there will be a time when most of that audience will just stop watching Cartoon Network because they suck.
Speaker 1: I think most of the people who watch Adventure Time pirate it.
Speaker 1: I mean, every Tuesday when I go to watch the episode, I'll just note that the Pirate Bay has a lot of people seeing Adventure Time.
Speaker 0: There is sort of a thing happening.
Speaker 0: My coworker, he has a baby.
Speaker 0: The baby's maybe not even one or whatever.
Speaker 0: But he watches Adventure Time with the baby.
Speaker 0: And he says the closing song puts the baby to sleep.
Speaker 0: The one with the bees.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you're gonna see people with babies who want adults, 20, 30 year olds who make babies watch Adventure Time with their kids.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But they can, you know what?
Speaker 1: They can do a thing like newspaper comics too.
Speaker 0: More so than the other shows.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's like other shows appeal to adults as well.
Speaker 0: Powerpuff Girls, Ponies, whatever.
Speaker 0: But I think Adventure Time more so is one that people will actually watch together and spread to younger folk, right?
Speaker 0: And especially with having it available on many, many formats.
Speaker 0: It's like if you have my parents' cable, you can just watch every episode on demand up to like the newest one.
Speaker 2: Yeah, Adventure Time is going for staying power.
Speaker 2: I mean, they pretty much already have that.
Speaker 0: So people can definitely start at the beginning with ease, even if they're not pirates.
Speaker 1: Well, that's what I was getting at.
Speaker 1: The beauty of Adventure Time is that because it had, I mean, the show really, really evolved season to season.
Speaker 1: Like season one is vastly different from seasons three and four.
Speaker 0: So is any long running show, Simpsons, Flintstones?
Speaker 2: No, this is a really stark difference.
Speaker 1: And Sailor Moon episode 199, not that different.
Speaker 2: Not the best example though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm talking about long running American shows.
Speaker 1: Okay, so long running American shows.
Speaker 1: Like Ponies, pretty much the same so far.
Speaker 2: Powerpuff Girls still, status quo is God.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Nothing ever affects the Powerpuff Girls universe.
Speaker 0: I didn't even know that show was still going.
Speaker 2: It's been remade.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: But because the archives exist is the kind of show that like we'll watch.
Speaker 1: And then if we add babies, we could start again from season one and we know where it's going.
Speaker 1: so we can just kind of watch it as the kid grows up.
Speaker 0: I don't know, Judith, do you actually watch it on real TV?
Speaker 0: No, I don't have real TV.
Speaker 0: Okay, but I heard from someone who had real TV that what happens is the episodes are only like half an episode slot, right?
Speaker 0: That what they'll do is when you go to watch the new Adventure Time, if it's not a two-parter, right?
Speaker 0: In the first half of the 30-minute slot, they'll show the old episode.
Speaker 0: that's relevant to the new episode, right?
Speaker 0: So that you know what the hell's going on.
Speaker 2: Typically, yeah.
Speaker 2: Anytime I've caught it on cable, that's what they've been doing.
Speaker 0: Right, so it's like...
Speaker 1: Ponies does the same thing.
Speaker 0: Right, so if you're starting out and that's part of what... It's weird how they cram so much into these short episodes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, more happens in these short Adventure Time episodes than in like an hour of a lot of shows I like.
Speaker 0: It's like they really use like... There'll be scenes or shots that are like less than a second that say like 10 million things, right?
Speaker 0: That no other show can pull that off really, right now at least.
Speaker 0: But you know, that first slot, they'll be like, "Oh, okay, so this episode's gonna be about Flame Princess again.
Speaker 0: We're gonna show the last appearance of Flame Princess in the first
Speaker 0: slot.".
Speaker 2: Some people analyze which episodes are paired with the new ones to foreshadow things.
Speaker 2: When Betty premiered, it was paired with I Remember You, which is a pretty obvious connection, but they were laying it on thick.
Speaker 0: But it's like they couldn't do that if the episode was full 20, 30 minutes long.
Speaker 0: You wouldn't have, you know, there wouldn't be a time slot for it unless they made it an hour long thing, you know.
Speaker 1: Of course, at the same time, technology, if this was just internet distribution, you could just have every episode has the paired episodes that are relevant to this episode.
Speaker 1: Just kind of there.
Speaker 1: Watch it if you want to or not.
Speaker 0: Make a website that is every Adventure Time episode, not necessarily in order, right, but with arrows pointing to the ones that, you know, come off of it, right?
Speaker 1: Just make a web.
Speaker 0: And then, you know, a website where you can, like, search the episode.
Speaker 0: So it could be like, "Show me every episode with Chews Goose.
Speaker 0: Show me every episode with Lumpy Space Princess.
Speaker 0: Show me every episode with Hot Dog
Speaker 0: Princess.".
Speaker 2: I think there's only like three episodes with Chews Goose.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's not that common.
Speaker 0: He's in at least five or six episodes.
Speaker 1: It's probably a pain in the ass to write.
Speaker 1: It's probably why Zecora doesn't say that much either.
Speaker 0: He's in the video games.
Speaker 1: I like in the comic, Flame Princess tricks the fake Chews Goose by getting him to say the word purple and then he just spazzes out.
Speaker 2: I remember that.
Speaker 1: Of course, the comic continuity.
Speaker 1: Flame Princess and Finn are just dating and everything's cool.
Speaker 0: So does the comic even count?
Speaker 2: There's several different comics.
Speaker 2: None of them count.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the comics are all very different in timbre and tone, too.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends on who's the writer.
Speaker 0: They haven't had like just one set of people writing the whole thing from start to finish, right?
Speaker 1: Well, Adventure Time is not that way either.
Speaker 1: There is a wide cast of people who write in storyboard.
Speaker 0: That is sort of interesting.
Speaker 0: One thing that really interests me is you look at the list of Adventure Time episodes.
Speaker 1: I mean, look, Episode 79, Hot to the Touch.
Speaker 1: Cole Sanchez, Rebecca Sugar.
Speaker 1: The next episode, Five Short Gravels.
Speaker 1: Tim Herpich, Skylar Page, and Cole Sanchez.
Speaker 0: Right, but those episodes have nothing to do with each other.
Speaker 0: Look at the first two episodes of this season, which are pretty much tied together as one episode.
Speaker 0: Different writers.
Speaker 0: These people must have some kind of communication going on.
Speaker 2: They all work in the same studio.
Speaker 0: They're all on the same page all the time.
Speaker 1: You know there's a continuity Bible.
Speaker 0: Right, but like other people who can't seem to pull it off when they have different writers like that.
Speaker 2: And they all have a discussion before they finalize the storyboard.
Speaker 2: Like everybody meets and discusses the script.
Speaker 0: How come other shows don't have all their writers so tight with each other like that?
Speaker 2: Because they suck more.
Speaker 0: I guess that's true.
Speaker 1: I might come out of the fact that how Adventure Time started and came to be.
Speaker 1: A group of friends who trusted each other bring other professional people who they trust in and they give each other a lot of leeway.
Speaker 1: Which you don't see with other things.
Speaker 1: It's like South Park.
Speaker 1: has that going to a degree that they only bring people in who they trust.
Speaker 1: A hundred percent.
Speaker 0: The South Park didn't bring people in?
Speaker 1: Well they brought people in until they had enough people.
Speaker 1: But there's nobody on their crew.
Speaker 0: Most of their people are animators.
Speaker 1: Yeah but I'm saying the people in their crew are people they trust a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: Like this guy's gonna get the comment right.
Speaker 0: People who work 24 hours a day for six weeks a year and then the rest of the year take off.
Speaker 1: I kind of really want that production schedule in my life.
Speaker 0: Just we'll make geek nights for like six months out of the year and the other six months do nothing.
Speaker 1: Like Penny Arcade.
Speaker 1: The four paxes should be on four weekends in a row and then they don't do anything the rest of the year.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Microhoolik just goes and draws all the comics for the whole year and I'm in a month and the rest of the year doesn't do anything.
Speaker 1: But Adventure Time?
Speaker 1: I think it still is my consistently most favorite cartoon that I'm watching or have watched in recent memory.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's my favorite.
Speaker 1: I really like ponies.
Speaker 0: But because it's so long and it just doesn't stop, right?
Speaker 0: It's like all other.
Speaker 0: regardless of how much I like Adventure Time relative to say something like Kill la Kill.
Speaker 0: It's like, well, Kill la Kill's over.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So even if I like that more, it's gone.
Speaker 0: And, you know, Adventure Time, at least for now, looks like it ain't going anywhere.
Speaker 0: So it just by the fact that it'll just always be there, regardless of how much you like it, it will have a stronger emotional bond to you simply because time makes the heart grow fonder, I guess.
Speaker 2: Sometimes.
Speaker 2: Adventure Time is my American cartoon favorite hands down.
Speaker 2: It beats out ponies like.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely.
Speaker 0: He's beaten ponies now.
Speaker 1: There was a time where, for me, ponies would have beaten Adventure Time.
Speaker 1: But that time is long gone.
Speaker 0: In the middle of season one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe through season two of ponies.
Speaker 0: Not really, no.
Speaker 1: Yeah, season two of ponies.
Speaker 1: Because what was contemporary Adventure Time at that point that you were watching?
Speaker 0: I didn't watch any Adventure Time.
Speaker 1: But also the time between seasons is pretty short.
Speaker 1: with Adventure Time, I've noticed.
Speaker 1: Compared to, say, Archer, which just stops for a long time before it starts up again.
Speaker 0: Also, the Adventure Time season has so many episodes.
Speaker 2: Season five, I think it played for like a year or a year and a half.
Speaker 0: How do they even count when the season?
Speaker 0: Aren't they supposed to start and stop seasons at the same time as every other show starts?
Speaker 2: Season five was a little weird because it was split into season 5.1 and 5.2.
Speaker 2: And it's twice the length of any other season.
Speaker 0: The first 5.1, 5 and 5.26.
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 1: They have stupid reasons for this stuff.
Speaker 1: I was reading a long article about how Hasbro does its seasons and when they do a half season or a whole season of ponies.
Speaker 1: And it depends on these marketing metrics.
Speaker 1: It's all this complicated crap.
Speaker 0: I've been noticing the live action shows that I don't watch, but my co-workers are talking about how what they'll do is like, okay, this is the last season of Mad Men.
Speaker 0: Instead of just making it the last season, they'll just take it and cut it in half to make two seasons to make the show last another year or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: Even though they won't make any more episodes, they'll just take that last season and cut it in half just to drag the show a little bit more.
Speaker 0: It's like, why?
Speaker 0: Does it really, you know, just to keep it in people's mindshare for another 12 months or whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't know what these people are thinking.
Speaker 1: So let's try to predict what's going to happen in the rest of the season.
Speaker 0: Right, because our obvious prediction of arms getting off, well, it happened, right?
Speaker 1: So where is this going?
Speaker 1: Judith, where's adventure time going?
Speaker 2: Pin's gotta find a replacement.
Speaker 0: Well, okay.
Speaker 1: Arm or girlfriend?
Speaker 2: I don't know about girlfriend.
Speaker 2: Flame Princess has got to be addressed again for sure.
Speaker 2: I don't know where that's going.
Speaker 2: At first I thought that her kingdom was going to fall apart because her policy for just honesty seemed so naive and doomed that I thought that the kingdom was going to have like an internal war or something.
Speaker 2: But that doesn't, well, that didn't work.
Speaker 1: I think it helps that all the subjects of the flame kingdom are actually really derpy.
Speaker 1: They're not the brightest.
Speaker 0: Not even Flame King.
Speaker 0: Flame King's derpy too.
Speaker 1: Flame King is really bad at conspiracies.
Speaker 0: Even his Boba Fett guy is dumb as shit.
Speaker 1: That guy was totally a Boba Fett though.
Speaker 0: I don't remember his name.
Speaker 0: Every time he was on screen, I'm like, that's the Flame King's Boba Fett.
Speaker 2: It's really hard to predict adventure time though.
Speaker 2: I typically don't try to unless I find something extremely obvious.
Speaker 1: Like I can predict the really broad strokes, but that's as far as I've gotten.
Speaker 1: All my specifics have pretty much been wrong unilaterally.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: Well, the one, the only thing that like is, is strong in my memory of like a loose end is the episode where Marceline and the doll or whatever, and the witch took the shit away.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like that witch is coming back hardcore.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: She said she was coming back.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: That's, that's, that's the thing that's been looming.
Speaker 1: And in the Betty episode, sort of like intentionally forgotten and un, in the Betty episode, we saw specifically why objects like that are so powerful.
Speaker 1: Think about what that means.
Speaker 1: This is an object that has power over either Princess Bubblegum or her legacy for as long as that shirt has been existing and treasured.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: Which means theoretically the Sky Witch could mess with the origin of the Candy Kingdom in the same way that Ice King messed with his own backstory.
Speaker 2: Except she doesn't because the Candy Kingdom continues to grow and expand until it's eventually abandoned within the span of a thousand years from the point that we're watching.
Speaker 1: Well, abandoned, moved, was it just the Lemon Kingdom?
Speaker 0: Maybe there were just some people who really liked fucking candy.
Speaker 2: That wasn't the Lemon Kingdom.
Speaker 2: That was the Candy Kingdom.
Speaker 2: You could see the castle in the middle.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, you're right.
Speaker 1: You're right.
Speaker 0: Maybe if you just really liked candy and ate it.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: Maybe that's just that deer came back and kidnapped everyone again.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of, that's the kind of thing that deer was basically just this joke.
Speaker 0: That would be the lamest thing.
Speaker 2: that that deer died, by the way.
Speaker 0: Oh, did it?
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Magic Man turned him into a telescope.
Speaker 1: He's not dead then.
Speaker 1: He's just a telescope.
Speaker 1: He's dead.
Speaker 2: Confirmed.
Speaker 2: Word of God.
Speaker 1: I do not believe in word of God when it comes to analyzing shows.
Speaker 0: What is this word of God?
Speaker 2: I don't know.
Speaker 2: Somebody asked if that was the same deer who got turned into a telescope and is it now dead?
Speaker 2: I think they asked at one of the panels at a convention.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: I was talking about the deer in the tower episode that we just saw.
Speaker 2: Oh, that deer?
Speaker 2: Maybe that was his father.
Speaker 0: Maybe that's why he's alone.
Speaker 1: But that deer is just a telescope.
Speaker 1: So it's dead temporarily.
Speaker 1: We could turn it back into a deer.
Speaker 2: Nobody's ever going to find that deer again.
Speaker 2: Magic Man isn't anyway.
Speaker 1: Magic Man.
Speaker 0: Who's the, who's the, the other thing is who's the shitty magician guy?
Speaker 0: The shitty wizard.
Speaker 1: What, Avrica Daniel?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There's something up with him too.
Speaker 1: He kind of got resolved.
Speaker 2: Kind of, but he's just like Ice King's bestie for a while and then he ditched.
Speaker 1: That's about it.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: There's something.
Speaker 0: The fact that they even brought him back at all, right?
Speaker 0: Beyond his one episode.
Speaker 1: I got to say, since they've kind of just spilled Ice King's entire load, it's really hard to watch any scene with Ice King without just being really depressed about Alzheimer's.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of, I'm kind of glad that there's.
Speaker 0: no, we haven't even seen Ice King since then because I don't like Ice King.
Speaker 0: I never liked Ice King.
Speaker 1: Well, Finn just fucked up his house apparently in the episode we just watched.
Speaker 0: That's happened like 10 million times.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 0: He just makes a new one with his ice powers.
Speaker 2: One thing I can predict is Betty's presence in Ooo means that the Ice King will eventually become cured and returned to being Simon.
Speaker 2: Otherwise they wouldn't have kept her there.
Speaker 1: Or, well, they could do something really tragic with that.
Speaker 2: What?
Speaker 0: What would that be?
Speaker 1: Maybe she finds a way to give him succor and peace and there is no cure.
Speaker 1: And maybe that's the moral.
Speaker 2: Maybe that would be super dark.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that would be.
Speaker 1: But it's weird because as an adult who likes media and has seen a lot of movies, I'm almost as I get older, I'm drawn more and more towards shocking, dark, severe endings to things.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, I'm almost pleasantly surprised when that doesn't happen.
Speaker 2: That would be killing a major character.
Speaker 2: I don't know if they could get away with that.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, they can't use him for his original purpose anymore.
Speaker 2: Being creepy and sad.
Speaker 1: Creep, but creepy, sad and hilariously stealing princesses is now just creepy and sad when it happens.
Speaker 2: That's probably why they're giving him some time, because they can't do anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but how do they bring him back without it being depressing?
Speaker 1: Any time he steals a princess now, it's, oh, Ice King with Alzheimer's stole a princess because he's fucked up.
Speaker 1: How tragic.
Speaker 2: Bet he's still out there.
Speaker 2: Maybe maybe she'll come back if she's watching over him.
Speaker 2: Maybe she'll stop him from doing that shit.
Speaker 0: Maybe they can somehow get him to where, you know, like you basically they can have their cake and eat it, too.
Speaker 0: Like, oh, he knows he's Simon, but he's still a kooky ice king.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Like he gets his memory back and he's somewhere in the middle.
Speaker 0: But he's still kooky and he's still, you know, likes ninjas.
Speaker 1: But then he takes the mad scientist role away from peeps.
Speaker 2: He's not a mad scientist.
Speaker 1: That's what he would become if he had some memories.
Speaker 2: And he believes in all the kind of stuff that she doesn't.
Speaker 2: So he would be on the opposite end of the spectrum.
Speaker 1: She believes in magic.
Speaker 1: She's just pissed off that it works.
Speaker 2: She thinks magic is science or she denies that magic is anything but science.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which she's probably right about.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, her science isn't quite there yet.
Speaker 1: I love how dismissive Jake is of her time travel.
Speaker 2: He was just like the viewer.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Of course, granted, that episode, you know, we're talking about dark.
Speaker 1: That episode was fucked up.
Speaker 2: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: LSP murdered that dude.
Speaker 2: Yeah, well, he he got sent to another dimension.
Speaker 2: He might as well be dead.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But when they first present that, oh, the time travel have that outside cool thing where you see that alternate world.
Speaker 1: Then that episode is just.
Speaker 1: she killed him by cutting him in half and then sent the rest of the body to join the dead half.
Speaker 2: Yeah, that episode premiered just around the end of season five.
Speaker 2: And we thought it was going to be like a little breath of fresh air between all the tragic stuff.
Speaker 2: It wasn't.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But look at the last major LSP episode we had.
Speaker 1: It was similarly.
Speaker 0: I mean, the end, the more she's trying to get in the wedding and she's hiding in the woods.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was just, wow, she's fucked up.
Speaker 1: And then the episode before that was her and the pizza guy.
Speaker 1: And the moral was Finn and Jake being like, oh, it's just LSP is emotional bullshit.
Speaker 0: That's something they could resolve if they wanted to.
Speaker 0: They could resolve bread.
Speaker 0: They could be like, here's bread.
Speaker 2: Oh, who cares about bread?
Speaker 0: I care about bread.
Speaker 1: You want to end it?
Speaker 0: He's probably so lumpy.
Speaker 2: Yeah, that that episode with LSP and Johnny, the guy who she not killed, that was actually storyboarded by Penn Ward himself.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Twisted fucker.
Speaker 0: Doesn't he do the LSP voice?
Speaker 0: Yes, he does.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 2: So that one ended with Princess Bubblegum drinking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it did.
Speaker 1: Princess Bubblegum also is increasingly not a happy person.
Speaker 2: Yeah, she's going to crack one day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because she's been a lot happier in older seasons.
Speaker 1: She still had issues, still working on stuff, but she was a lot more good natured and easygoing.
Speaker 1: And now she seems to pretty much always be harried or angry.
Speaker 2: They're evolving her character into something much more, I would say darker, but really much more neutral.
Speaker 2: Just a character who believes the ends justify the means.
Speaker 1: And of course, at the same time, the show has done nothing.
Speaker 1: but tell me that she is right.
Speaker 2: I know.
Speaker 2: I know they make us question her morally because she does things that make us very uncomfortable as people, but it doesn't prove her wrong ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, let's go all the way back.
Speaker 1: So, James, ignoring James 2, where he found out that James is just fucked up in his own way, the way that episode played out, it's pretty obvious that she brought him along to be cannon fodder.
Speaker 1: So it wasn't just that he died and he was expendable, so she made the choice.
Speaker 1: She brought him to be expendable and then had to basically knock Finn out so she could expend him without him stopping her.
Speaker 0: Well, that's her move.
Speaker 0: is that she's basically so much smarter than everybody and knows it, She knows it, but she can't possibly like, even if she's talking to banana guards, it's like, even if she's talking to Finn, she can't just say anything smart.
Speaker 0: Imagine being so smart and literally everyone is dumb.
Speaker 1: Like, imagine if you were the only not crazy conservative person trying to explain to Finn or to Jake why Flame Princess is dangerous.
Speaker 2: You just stop.
Speaker 0: So imagine how frustrating that is.
Speaker 0: Like you were literally the only intelligent person there is.
Speaker 1: So why doesn't she just go talk to Prismo?
Speaker 1: I guess.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess now she can't.
Speaker 0: Well, that's why she hangs with.
Speaker 0: Marceline is like the only thing even close to being smart because she's so old.
Speaker 1: Marceline is always kind of a bitch to her.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Oh, they're getting better.
Speaker 1: They are.
Speaker 2: Last time they hung out, it was really actually pretty friendly.
Speaker 1: I miss Marceline not being pissed off and sad and just causing trouble for people.
Speaker 2: Yeah, they're evolving her character into more of a good guy instead of this chaotic neutral thing.
Speaker 1: She was always chaotic neutral with good tendencies, even from the beginning.
Speaker 1: All of her pranks were funny and chaotic, but they weren't just chaotic neutral because she actually did prevent real harm from coming.
Speaker 0: I think the very first Marceline episode ever, right?
Speaker 0: At that point, I don't think she was meant to be this long recurring character, right?
Speaker 2: She killed Jake in her first.
Speaker 2: Right.
Speaker 0: In that very first episode, she knew she wouldn't kill one kind of character.
Speaker 0: And then when they decided to make her recurring, they switched it up right in that second appearance.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh, OK, she's just fooling around.
Speaker 0: She's not actually just a one off bad guy monster of the week.
Speaker 1: I just I miss episodes like when Finn needs help with his relationship stuff and she gives him the worst possible relationship advice in the world.
Speaker 2: Yeah, that's because she was jealous.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course, even in that episode, look at the way she reacted to Finn asking her to go.
Speaker 1: She's got a lot more issues than just her issues with Peeves and her issues with Simon.
Speaker 2: He has a thousand years of issues.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Daddy issues.
Speaker 0: French fry issues.
Speaker 2: Who knows how many exes she's had.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Granted, we the only one we've seen is the douchebag guy.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: The guy, the band guy.
Speaker 1: We haven't seen any of the other ones.
Speaker 1: But we've.
Speaker 1: we've seen like Peeves was dating that one candy guy at one point.
Speaker 2: Yeah, she probably made him just saying, yeah, almost definitely.
Speaker 1: It's possible that two other candy people made him the natural way.
Speaker 0: That would be really that that is a thing that happens, right?
Speaker 0: Like there's those candy orphans.
Speaker 2: Yeah, that is the thing that happens.
Speaker 2: He was there really early on, though.
Speaker 2: I kind of when she was still building stuff, I kind of get the feeling she thought I should have a boyfriend.
Speaker 2: What should I do about that?
Speaker 1: Or maybe she made a bunch of them and then one of them was just kind of and she just put up with him.
Speaker 1: I get the impression that anyone she has dated over this whole time, she's just kind of put up with like the kind of there.
Speaker 2: Do you remember in Lemonhope that that guy who helped Lemonhope out of flannel boxing day, I mean, Princess Bubblegum in disguise.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 2: You remember when he he she was talking about romance and he was like, it's been so long and he starts dropping the paddle he was using.
Speaker 1: I forgot all about that.
Speaker 2: I cracked up so hard at that.
Speaker 1: So is she thinking back to Marceline or?
Speaker 2: That's what I like to think, but who knows?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Let's end with something lighter, right?
Speaker 0: So what?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Something lighter.
Speaker 1: Something lighter.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 2: Scott, what do you like most about Chews Goose?
Speaker 0: What do I like most about Chews Goose?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: His neck.
Speaker 2: I want to see some Scott X Chews Goose fan fiction.
Speaker 1: Guys, get on this.
Speaker 0: Make it.
Speaker 0: Also, I like his his his equipment.
Speaker 0: It's very.
Speaker 1: You just like making that noise.
Speaker 0: I like making that noise.
Speaker 0: And I like.
Speaker 0: I like inventories.
Speaker 0: Hook me up with that plus two armors and that plus five swords.
Speaker 0: For whatever reason, I really like Chews Goose will never give you the cursed shit.
Speaker 1: I think Flame Princess is actually my favorite non-main character.
Speaker 2: Yeah, she's your type.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she kind of is.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Favorite princess.
Speaker 1: Favorite princess.
Speaker 1: But she's not a princess.
Speaker 1: That's just her surname.
Speaker 1: That was that was explicitly stated.
Speaker 2: Yes, God, you got to think harder.
Speaker 1: You've got to pick a princess princess.
Speaker 2: We'll just say Scott's favorite is Princess Princess Princess.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Is there such a princess?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: She's three princesses like mashed together.
Speaker 1: She's horrifying.
Speaker 0: I don't remember that one at all.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess LSP isn't a princess either.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Because Princess means something in this world.
Speaker 1: We know that because of the Enchiridion.
Speaker 2: So we know that a little bit because of the video game, too.
Speaker 0: Does video game count?
Speaker 1: I know scenes count, but fuck the rest of that game.
Speaker 2: Fuck that game.
Speaker 0: All the games are more than one of them.
Speaker 1: Those games are the worst.
Speaker 2: I gave up on it and just watched the rest of the season on YouTube.
Speaker 1: I can't believe you even bought it.
Speaker 2: I was trying to be a good fan.
Speaker 0: No, the first one.
Speaker 0: So don't reward them.
Speaker 1: That would be like if the creators of Cowboy Bebop came to America and just shit on their individual fans one by one.
Speaker 2: Some people have to learn their own lessons, Ram.
Speaker 2: That's the path to adulthood.
Speaker 1: Except if Finn was allowed to learn his own lessons, he would have died like 15 times.
Speaker 0: Well, we need your favorite princess also.
Speaker 1: And it can't be Marceline.
Speaker 1: She's not a princess either.
Speaker 2: My favorite princess is Peebs.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Sorry.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: She's the most interesting character on that show.
Speaker 2: What are you all groaning for?
Speaker 1: I guess in Tenchi Muyo, you're like Iyeka the most.
Speaker 2: That is not even a remotely...
Speaker 0: That's like having Sailor Moon be your favorite Sailor Scout.
Speaker 2: No, no.
Speaker 1: Who's your favorite Sailor Scout?
Speaker 1: It's Michiru, isn't it?
Speaker 0: The green one.
Speaker 0: Just because green.
Speaker 2: No, I like Sailor Uranus.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: Because butt jokes.
Speaker 2: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yes, that is exactly why.
Speaker 2: No, Princess Bubblegum is the most complex character on that show.
Speaker 2: You're not going to convince me of otherwise in this short conversation.
Speaker 2: And just because she appears more than any other princess doesn't mean that my decision is lazy.
Speaker 1: No, I can see that.
Speaker 1: I can see that.
Speaker 1: I like her a lot, but for whatever reason, I like Flame Princess more.
Speaker 2: Yeah, whatever reason.
Speaker 1: I really don't know why.
Speaker 1: I couldn't really... I'd have to think about it a lot.
Speaker 2: That's the second most lazy answer, by the way.
Speaker 1: If I had to pick a non-lazy answer, I kind of like Slime Princess as well.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Because one, she just seems pretty rational and funny.
Speaker 2: And because Maria Bamford's doing her sexy voice for Slime Princess.
Speaker 1: I also liked at the end of that episode the way they handled the knot attraction between the two of them.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: No love for Hot Dog Princess.
Speaker 2: I like her design.
Speaker 0: Hot Dogs, like the theme of Hot Dog Princess is probably the best, but she's just sort of...
Speaker 1: Wildberry Princess with her stocks of murdered meat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no.
Speaker 1: I love how she just is really into meat and slaughtering.
Speaker 0: Maybe the Library Turtle Princess is acceptable.
Speaker 1: Turtle Princess, really?
Speaker 0: Hey, girl.
Speaker 1: Hey, girl.
Speaker 1: That was my ringtone for a while.
Speaker 0: That's not a bad ringtone.
Speaker 1: But now I've changed it to Don't Lose Your Way.
Speaker 0: That's a good ringtone, too.
Speaker 1: I might never change it again.
Speaker 1: Because then I'll lose my way.
Speaker 0: I should change mine to UY Shock.
Speaker 1: It's also my alarm in the morning.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 2: That's a great idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I have two.
Speaker 1: I have one that's just Don't Lose Your Way.
Speaker 0: I'm still using the Tribes 2 song.
Speaker 1: It starts right up with the "Don't lose your
Speaker 1: way.".
Speaker 1: That's the ringtone.
Speaker 1: The alarm.
Speaker 1: one plays the song slowly fading in, fading in, fading in, fading in.
Speaker 0: Don't lose.
Speaker 1: So I have time to stop it.
Speaker 2: Wow, I would fly out of bed and right into the dresser.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I thought I would do that.
Speaker 1: You know what happens?
Speaker 1: I listen to the song for a while.
Speaker 1: I turn it off.
Speaker 1: I fall back asleep.
Speaker 1: I wake up a half hour later.
Speaker 1: I'm late to work.
Speaker 2: Oh, you suck.
Speaker 1: I'm just... I can't get out of bed.
Speaker 1: Is there a sleepy princess?
Speaker 1: I guess that would be the pillow princess.
Speaker 1: But that's alternate universe.
Speaker 0: That's Prismo.
Speaker 1: Rest in peace.
Speaker 1: Oh, Prismo.
Speaker 1: Is it just me or was the Lich creepy as fuck in that episode?
Speaker 2: He's always creepy as fuck, but yeah.
Speaker 1: He was extra creepy in that episode.
Speaker 0: I think ever since he donned the skin of Billy, it's been more creepy.
Speaker 2: He was creeping out Death.
Speaker 1: I love that scene where Death is like,
Speaker 1: "Yeah.".
Speaker 1: Also, Death might be...
Speaker 0: Couldn't Death just kill him because he's Death?
Speaker 1: Death's powers seem to be surprisingly limited.
Speaker 0: And what's Death... Like, is the dimension that Death lives in the same place where Marceline's dad lives?
Speaker 1: God, no.
Speaker 2: No.
Speaker 0: No, okay.
Speaker 1: That's pretty well established, I think.
Speaker 1: Marceline's dimension... Well, Marceline's dad's dimension is the nightosphere is pretty much sequestered off from everywhere.
Speaker 0: So the nightosphere is not the same as Hell?
Speaker 2: No.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 2: It's kind of like Hell, but I don't know if that's where dead people go.
Speaker 0: It's its own thing.
Speaker 0: We haven't seen any Heavens.
Speaker 0: We've just seen two Hells.
Speaker 1: Bad places to go.
Speaker 1: I guess your options are get sent to a Hell or get reincarnated as basically the same person.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.