Speaker 0: It's Wednesday January 15th 2014 on rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: space dandy Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Also known as the third anime to save anime.
Speaker 1: That's a lot of anime.
Speaker 1: save an anime.
Speaker 1: I don't think you'd be saved by now wouldn't need any more saving.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well apparently the anime industry is flush with money and everything's going great now.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: I didn't know that I.
Speaker 0: I Don't have no idea how profitable any of this stuff is.
Speaker 1: to be honest at least people are paying attention.
Speaker 1: Yep to animes Right now.
Speaker 0: yeah, even though a lot of the people I know don't like a lot of these shows that are kind of the the mold breakers.
Speaker 0: Okay, I'm just.
Speaker 0: I've noticed that a lot of people are really down on kill.
Speaker 1: I kill in space dandy If you don't like boobs you're not gonna like these shows that save anime.
Speaker 0: I'm more of a big but man the amateur is after boobs.
Speaker 1: These shoes are all about boobs And nakedness.
Speaker 1: every single one of the shows is still you know It's like wearing clothing.
Speaker 1: It's like you like you perverts watching all your moe crap shows that are just about wanking off to little girls.
Speaker 1: you pedophiles I'm gonna go watch real anime.
Speaker 1: That's not Who are really explained about a teenage girl who doesn't look that cute with a giant sword who's naked.
Speaker 0: You can't be my cute woman.
Speaker 1: aliens that are naked as well.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I'll come.
Speaker 1: none of the girl.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I we skipped a show earlier in the week.
Speaker 0: Sorry about that.
Speaker 0: I had a last-minute trip to Omaha, Nebraska.
Speaker 0: ha never never been to Nebraska before and As far as my brain is concerned Nebraska exhibit Omaha specifically exists as a hotel and one Other building that sits through an airport door.
Speaker 0: because I flew out of Newark Airport The worst Airport in I don't know the East Coast of the United States.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's the worst.
Speaker 1: It's not a good name.
Speaker 0: a worse one.
Speaker 0: a worse Airport because at least smaller shittier airports have better food and less of a security line.
Speaker 0: Newark has all the problems of a real Airport, but none of the amenities of a real Airport.
Speaker 0: There isn't even food.
Speaker 0: past security.
Speaker 0: you're fucked if you go through that line.
Speaker 0: All right, so I got.
Speaker 0: I basically went to Newark flew to Nebraska Slept in a hotel went to a four-hour long meeting.
Speaker 0: immediately flew home.
Speaker 0: less than 24 hours after I walked out of that plane I walked back into Newark Airport at the same gate.
Speaker 0: That was actually really surreal.
Speaker 0: I hope I never do that again in my life.
Speaker 0: I had Airport food at both sides.
Speaker 1: Okay Let me tell you airplane food.
Speaker 0: No, there was no plane food cuz it's like a two and a half hour flight.
Speaker 0: if that it's a really short flight Nebraska is not that far away.
Speaker 1: That's scary.
Speaker 1: I want to be as far in for Nebraska as possible.
Speaker 0: This is not so bad.
Speaker 0: They they were not in move there.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Nebraska.
Speaker 0: well, Omaha is a city.
Speaker 0: seats about Boston sighs Like that's the size of that city.
Speaker 0: There's stuff going on.
Speaker 0: There's actually a lot of IT and tech workers.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean, it's not a city I want to move to because I'd have to own a car.
Speaker 0: but if my parameters are have to own a car is a deal-breaker.
Speaker 0: Not only can I only really live in like parts of Seattle and New York But the parts are actually kind of small like if I go out into Queens or parts of Brooklyn need a car.
Speaker 1: You live in Flushing can't need a car.
Speaker 0: Yeah But yeah, that's that's why we didn't do a show.
Speaker 0: but I'm back from Nebraska And hopefully I won't go to Nebraska again anytime soon, but on the list of places that I don't like Nebraska way low.
Speaker 0: There's places.
Speaker 0: I dislike way less than Nebraska.
Speaker 0: So Nebraska not so bad, Afghanistan Lots of places in the United States.
Speaker 0: I would rather live in Omaha, Somalia.
Speaker 0: I'd rather live in Omaha than any city.
Speaker 0: That's part of the proper former Confederacy Detroit.
Speaker 0: I would I Would give it 50/50 between to Omaha and Detroit right now because Detroit's kind of gentrifying.
Speaker 0: there's stuff going on there suddenly Like very recently, but I digress.
Speaker 0: so got any anime news.
Speaker 0: it's Wednesday anime.
Speaker 1: It's really anime news.
Speaker 1: This is the best news.
Speaker 1: Well, this is the news worth talking about.
Speaker 1: that of the list of news is worth talking about This is the one most closely related to animes, right?
Speaker 1: So what this guy did is he had a booth at CES, right?
Speaker 1: The consumer electronic show which is in Vegas at the beginning of every year where they show off all the electronic goodies, right?
Speaker 1: And this isn't like a convention like PAX or anything.
Speaker 1: this is a typical, you know trade show where it's pretty much like imagine take PAX just the expo hall and Only people in the video game business.
Speaker 1: no video game players, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like no one's there Who's like a person who watches TV?
Speaker 1: Well, I guess they are.
Speaker 1: but there are people who buy TVs sell TVs make TVs etc, right?
Speaker 1: And it covers all consumer electronics every category Cameras fucking everything right?
Speaker 1: I like you had one example like cameras Everything everything they sell at Best Buy pretty much.
Speaker 1: Hey Best Buy sells it.
Speaker 1: It's at this show.
Speaker 1: So, of course one of the controversies is all you know booth babes cuz they're there and there's a lot of them there.
Speaker 1: It's like place if you're booth, babe, that's you want to go to get a job.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually last year there were a little bit less booth babes than usual But it's apparently because no one had any money and this year they had money again.
Speaker 1: So everyone had him again and people were like grumble grumble and doing the usual same thing They do every time the booth babes story comes up, which is interviews and booth babes Interviews and people who hire booth babes, right?
Speaker 1: Etc talk about the creepy dudes who were there and talk about the.
Speaker 0: you know A lot of people like to complain about packs but packs actually bends booth babes and no one else is really following that right?
Speaker 1: But anyway, here's the real here's the interesting news story, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz it's not news so far so far.
Speaker 1: It's same old same old.
Speaker 1: Yeah, nothing.
Speaker 1: We're talking about one guy had a booth and He was anti booth babe guy, but his company pretty much just always paid for it and made it happen.
Speaker 1: Right and the people above him, you know, just you sort of believed that it worked so they always did it.
Speaker 1: now Somehow someone offered him some free space somewhere else.
Speaker 1: So he had two booths, huh?
Speaker 1: So he called up, you know the staffing people, right?
Speaker 1: And for that second booth, he asked not for booth babes.
Speaker 1: He specifically said I don't want anyone who is you know hot I want people who have really good people skills Etc, etc, right because you still have to hire people to work the.
Speaker 0: I hope this is going toward the anecdote Proving the good point and not the cynical bad point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so he got people.
Speaker 1: they sent him people to work that booth.
Speaker 1: One of them was literally a grandma.
Speaker 1: there was no pictures of them.
Speaker 1: I don't think it was a joke like GOG did right where they have grandma's acting as grandma's now It was just they sent him some people who were you know people people that weren't hot people Right.
Speaker 1: They were normal people.
Speaker 1: They weren't there for their bodies.
Speaker 1: They were there for their you know, human interaction skills, right and He a/b tested the booth babes in the one booth and the normal people with sales skills in the other booth and the booth at the booth babes.
Speaker 1: Alright, it got.
Speaker 1: you know They got contacts there.
Speaker 1: He measured based on how many like contacts they got and like leads they got because that's what you're there for.
Speaker 1: you're selling something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's biz dev people like to make.
Speaker 0: they make a really specific distinction.
Speaker 1: So they had a right.
Speaker 1: so they had computer systems where people would like enter in like their contacts and right and whatnot.
Speaker 1: So it was how many did we get at this booth and how many did we get at that booth?
Speaker 1: So first of all Not only did the non booth babe booth get like double or triple or even more the amount of you know Leads and contacts or whatever, but the ones they got at the booth babe booth Were really low quality shitty people that didn't really, you know, not good quality.
Speaker 1: The ones they got at the other booth were all real deal.
Speaker 1: We can make money off this shit.
Speaker 1: I can kind of speak at least his business which was you know The people above him were people who believed in booth babes or whatever and wanted to pay for them all the time.
Speaker 1: At least they were convinced by the data and I guess they're not getting them anymore in the future, right?
Speaker 1: Even though those same people believed in them not a few weeks.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'll say straight up when I go to do my trade conferences in the financial sector any booth and any one of these things that has a bunch of that bullshit on it is usually a Worthless contact to have from my side the guy walking around.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So I actually avoid booze that have big stuff.
Speaker 0: I'll only go to booze that have big stuff that are also giving away expensive free things.
Speaker 0: And I have a fake set of business cards that goes to basically forwards through to Gmail.
Speaker 0: So if I win something I can get it, but they will never trace it back to me and my real job in my real name.
Speaker 1: So yeah now we have definitive proof of what we suspected Which is that booth babes don't even help you.
Speaker 1: All they do is get sleazy guys to come to your booth and get their picture taken and they kind of scare smart people away.
Speaker 0: Well, you know the traditional help your business.
Speaker 0: the traditional wisdom always shines through.
Speaker 0: the kinds of people you see patronizing strip clubs are the kinds of people you probably don't want to have a conversation with right and also the place it's.
Speaker 1: you know, It's also probably true the places that have booth babes are probably people where the product doesn't sell itself.
Speaker 1: It needs some kind of help right look at packs at the booths that tried and failed to have booth babes, right?
Speaker 1: There's like that energy drink booth.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I forgot about that, right?
Speaker 1: Which they have hot people of all genders there, you know who are fully clothed, but they are not energy drink specialists.
Speaker 1: Shall we say yeah I would love to see the person the kind of person who is like the Red Bull Connoisseur and that Duke Nukem booth not the highest quality game you could say Needed some marketing help to get sales.
Speaker 0: Yeah those booth bae.
Speaker 0: Well, there were booth babes at that booth.
Speaker 1: there were but they for a limited time only.
Speaker 0: they yeah they also to their credit because I kind of got pulled into the back of the booth and got to talk to a lot of them had All memorized a lot of information about the game and all.
Speaker 1: yeah Sure, but they don't have the the sales skills, perhaps then maybe they do but you know The other people did.
Speaker 0: well packs is different because no one you're not it's not the same kind of.
Speaker 0: no I'm not know what valve software is not thinking.
Speaker 0: Well, we got a lead that don't rims gonna buy this game on steam if we email him later Like the games are.
Speaker 1: so valve developer conference is happening now.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I almost wanted to go to that but I couldn't justify going.
Speaker 1: well, it's sort of it's like all secret and shit.
Speaker 1: I know it's like packs dev but one thing that is not secret about it Is that if you went in the goodie bag was a steam controller, which is not cheap.
Speaker 1: Those things are gonna be like a lot of money.
Speaker 0: I saw someone made a pretty apt tweet that's been making the rounds.
Speaker 0: that valve is Basically right now doing the equivalent of handing out muskets in the night to eventually overthrow the king.
Speaker 1: I was the one who saw that article and tweeted it and then you just copied what I saw and copied.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've retweeted your tweet.
Speaker 0: That was from someone else.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's hard.
Speaker 1: Oh So yeah, so this is related to anime.
Speaker 1: I got to bring this back to anime.
Speaker 0: Okay, bring it back babe story.
Speaker 1: There seems to be this assumption among the anime makers right that you know?
Speaker 1: I guess virtual boobies sell mangas and animes.
Speaker 1: Maybe they don't.
Speaker 0: I Suspected that for a while.
Speaker 0: I think they.
Speaker 0: it's the same situation with superhero comics in the US.
Speaker 1: Even these new shows that we say are saving anime All have boobies in them.
Speaker 1: maybe They don't.
Speaker 1: maybe maybe like the booth babes Like imagine if kill la kill didn't have all this nakedness.
Speaker 1: like you'd made the show about something beside you could still make it Just as good but instead of being about clothing.
Speaker 1: It could just be about hats only or something, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it could still be just as good.
Speaker 1: It's all the craziness and everything Would even more people watch it.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll put it this way.
Speaker 0: Well, there's that lol.
Speaker 0: Well, that was basically anime fans.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: Look at that deconstruction of clothing.
Speaker 0: blah blah blah non anime fans.
Speaker 0: Why isn't that girl wearing pants?
Speaker 1: That's right Exactly 100,000% correct.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Every every anime fan has had that moment.
Speaker 0: we were watching some show on a subway or on a train and You kind of pause it and make the windows smaller and then start again.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you can't even scroll your Twitter.
Speaker 0: Yep Especially with some of the people I'm following lately.
Speaker 0: entice guys with your gay porn all over my Twitter.
Speaker 1: suddenly I don't know who you're following, but I'm not following that.
Speaker 0: I'm following a few people recently anyway.
Speaker 0: but That what I say when it comes to all this sort of like.
Speaker 0: I like a good exploitation film Whatever it might be for example black dynamite.
Speaker 0: But anytime there's media that is that has twinges of racism I heard there's a black dynamite sequel or anything anything that is bad or untoward.
Speaker 0: All it does is raise the test by which the media has to be reviewed.
Speaker 0: So some shit moe show that has its creepy moe bullshit.
Speaker 0: It's held to a higher standard.
Speaker 1: then it has to.
Speaker 1: if I'm gonna watch that it better be fucking incredible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it better be the great Gatsby equivalent, right?
Speaker 0: So in my mind like a show like kill I kill the exploitation.
Speaker 0: it Has met so far the higher standard I have held it to in terms of its overall quality.
Speaker 0: But many other shows with the same accoutrement shall we say to use a Sailor Moon term talents Has not lived up to even the most basic test.
Speaker 0: There's a reason we're not watching most of this anime that has come out recently.
Speaker 0: So we'll see we'll see.
Speaker 0: but to bring it back to Sailor Moon There's news.
Speaker 0: that wasn't news, but apparently it's news because everyone's saying this was making shit.
Speaker 0: up until now Everyone had assumed that the new Sailor Moon anime announced in August last year to air in December Last year and failure now announced that it's going to air in July.
Speaker 0: But I'm not super confident in that either considering reason news that they renamed the series Sailor Moon forever.
Speaker 0: We have literally seen no art from this.
Speaker 1: I've seen pictures of Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: Yes, every picture I've seen related to this is something that's just scanned from the manga usually by a fan.
Speaker 1: Oh, I thought that I saw a picture of Sailor Moon that they drew.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she looks like Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: Dad.
Speaker 1: That's still a picture from the show is a picture I don't know if it's from the show.
Speaker 0: that gives me promotional art a bull shot.
Speaker 1: Sure It's a promotional picture of Sailor Moon that they drew.
Speaker 1: the people who are animating the show stop for a minute and they drew a Picture Sailor Moon for the poster.
Speaker 1: it
Speaker 0: had been assumed by many people and we I said this Even when we did our how to or our Judge anime by its cover thing in anime Boston that it appears that it's going to be a reboot That is based very much more strictly on how the manga.
Speaker 1: I read the same thing.
Speaker 1: I that was that's all I ever thought this was gonna be.
Speaker 0: so I tried to verify a sequel.
Speaker 0: I had tried it could be a sequel actually to the anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah after Sailor Stars do the crystal millennium or something I don't know what the fuck that is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't know.
Speaker 0: All right Don't know anything about Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: Who's the cat?
Speaker 0: Can you name the cat?
Speaker 1: moon moon Luna?
Speaker 1: All right, it's also because it's the same as.
Speaker 0: uh, you know, you know, there's two other cats.
Speaker 1: There's one that sort though.
Speaker 1: The main one's black.
Speaker 1: It has a moon on its head.
Speaker 1: Yep She is one that's sort of dark purple that has stars on its butt, right?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm surprised.
Speaker 0: I'm surprised that this that cat is the one you know second and not the other main cat.
Speaker 1: I don't know any other cat Artemis the dude.
Speaker 1: There's a dude.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: What does that one look like?
Speaker 0: He's a white Luna.
Speaker 1: I didn't know that.
Speaker 1: I thought I just thought there was the black one and then the purple one.
Speaker 0: He shows up when Sailor V aka Sailor Venus shows up because Sailor V is actually a superhero on her own Before she finds out she's a sailor like straight up Like she uses her powers and has a cat kind of like Sailor Moon and has a TV show About
Speaker 1: her
Speaker 0: that she's in but she's also a real superhero.
Speaker 0: So Sailor Moon The girl is a fan of Sailor V and then meet Sailor V and it turns out that Sailor V is for real a sailor Scout and also a superhero.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah Let's not watch that show Too late for you.
Speaker 0: So I tried to find more information about the new Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: It turns out that was just a giant clusterfuck of people making shit up.
Speaker 1: So it was all lies.
Speaker 1: It's not a reboot.
Speaker 0: So that was people making shit up but being very good at guessing because it was announced scant days ago Officially that this is not a sequel and is not a remake of the anime but a new reboot adaptation of the manga.
Speaker 1: That's what.
Speaker 1: so I'm guess everybody guessed right?
Speaker 0: We probably didn't guess.
Speaker 1: it was probably known but I can't figure.
Speaker 1: There's no way people could have guessed that it all.
Speaker 0: I read it many places Having read a bunch of the manga and seen the original Sailor Moon all the way through including the three movies and the special.
Speaker 1: Oh, you don't want to see a reboot based on the manga because it's gonna be bad.
Speaker 0: No, I'm saying I Would have made the same guess But I wouldn't have coached it in terms of.
Speaker 0: this is what the studio said.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so now we know we'll see if it actually premieres in July.
Speaker 1: There's like a dub cast already set up in July 20-20 something 15 But 18.
Speaker 0: I'm really curious.
Speaker 0: I really want this to happen.
Speaker 0: I really want to see it because if I had to describe the Sailor Moon manga to people who have seen Sailor Moon Imagine Green Lantern universe, but with a lot of lesbians.
Speaker 1: That is what that is.
Speaker 1: What is that in shit in volume one?
Speaker 0: Print comes in pretty quick.
Speaker 0: It is Green Lantern space bullshit.
Speaker 0: There's a shield around this planet, but then this kind of thing It sounds like Star Control to shield around a planet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's shields around the place.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: You got to read that manga.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna make it the next book club.
Speaker 0: Like manga is there like novels the next book?
Speaker 0: I've got one signed by the author.
Speaker 1: What is wrong with you?
Speaker 0: But anyway things the day Our good friend Casey Green known as that guy on the internet.
Speaker 0: You might not know who he is But you'll see his stuff and you'll be like, oh, you don't know who he is.
Speaker 1: Have you read the anime club comic aka the truth gun show comic?
Speaker 1: You should read that webcomic every day of your life.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna throw.
Speaker 1: you can read it before or after.
Speaker 1: you read doctor big ninja every day of your life.
Speaker 0: This is video video by the famous Casey Green About the archer set sir.
Speaker 0: I Don't.
Speaker 0: I showed this to some people last night It's it and one of them was kind of laughing the whole time Like what is this?
Speaker 0: and the other one was just shaking his head like what is this?
Speaker 0: Not in a good way.
Speaker 0: I just want to point out that the very end of this the woman says I don't need this and The protagonist the archer set sir does not say yes, you need this.
Speaker 0: He says I need this.
Speaker 0: Just pointing that out.
Speaker 0: You watch it all the way to the end.
Speaker 0: You have to trust me.
Speaker 1: You know what your problem is.
Speaker 0: Want to know what the fucking problem is.
Speaker 0: How do you know?
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna want to know what the problem is.
Speaker 1: I know that you're not gonna want to hear me tell you your problem.
Speaker 0: Seriously guys this stands alone.
Speaker 1: problems your face.
Speaker 0: What Anyway Do I have something my god the song is like stuck in my head again now.
Speaker 1: So This is a thing of the day that involves games and technology perfect for Wednesday, huh?
Speaker 1: There's nothing to do with anime whatsoever unless I guess you count the fact that there was a Mario anime at some point.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, you're right.
Speaker 0: I keep forgetting about that.
Speaker 1: So there was This thing was all over the internet.
Speaker 1: If you haven't seen it I don't know how you how you must not internet at all besides geek nights in which case you're internetting all wrong.
Speaker 0: They're getting a filtered stream of only the hardest of brow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're internetting wrong if you're in geek nights before anything else anyway, so What these guys did it?
Speaker 1: Well this guy?
Speaker 1: Master June, I think his internet name is.
Speaker 1: he took Super Mario World for the Super Nintendo and he hooked it up to some equipment.
Speaker 1: So it's like it, you know for time assisted speed running, right?
Speaker 1: So basically the equipment he hooked it up to had two multi taps.
Speaker 1: so he was as if there were eight controllers Connected to this Super Nintendo, right?
Speaker 1: and he goes into the first level while the level to the right of Yoshi's house, right.
Speaker 0: and He starts doing all this crazy the third level for people who know how to play that game.
Speaker 1: Yeah He starts jumping around and doing this crazy random shit, you know, well the computer is doing.
Speaker 1: you know, he scripted the controls.
Speaker 1: It's only inputting controls.
Speaker 1: He's only pushing buttons on the controller.
Speaker 1: He's not doing anything else.
Speaker 1: You can even see what buttons he's pushing, right and Through.
Speaker 1: pushing these buttons in this crazy sequence making Mario do all this random shit with like Yoshi's and all this craziness that happens It seems like just like random crazy hacks and weirdness that doesn't really get him very far in the game.
Speaker 1: eventually, I think he activates a p-block or something and The game sort of freaks out.
Speaker 1: and then the games like in this menu.
Speaker 1: And in the menu there's three options Pong snake and quit.
Speaker 1: and if you choose Pong you play Pong with a Mario head.
Speaker 1: and if you choose snake you play snake With a Mario head.
Speaker 0: and I did not personally verify if this is a hoax.
Speaker 0: This is
Speaker 1: all Scott 100% not a hoax because there is a separate video which is when this was premiered at Awesome games done quick, right which raised over a million dollars for cancer and is like the greatest thing to watch on twitch TV ever Which is also where they did that Metroid speedrun.
Speaker 1: We just saw.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, right.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, so And basically they had a rob the robot hooked up to the you know Super Nintendo right and they did it there.
Speaker 1: and then they had two guys after it was done play Pong and Snake and it was not the same Pong and snake.
Speaker 1: So it wasn't just like a recording, right?
Speaker 1: It was totally legit.
Speaker 1: and he basically what this guy's done.
Speaker 1: He's he's reprogrammed Basically through these controller ports.
Speaker 1: only he programmed the Super Nintendo to do something else.
Speaker 1: Well plus the Mario cartridge, right?
Speaker 1: Think about crazy.
Speaker 1: that is like he didn't you know open up a dev kit or recompile anything or any.
Speaker 1: all he did Was literally push buttons on controllers.
Speaker 1: imagine if you could push buttons on your game your Xbox controller and You're when you're playing Halo and you just push enough buttons That you've somehow loaded in all of counter-strike through the controller port and then the Xbox starts playing counter-strike.
Speaker 0: This is off the hook.
Speaker 1: It is ridiculous.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's ever.
Speaker 1: this might be the first time ever any game has been Reprogrammed through the controller ports alone.
Speaker 0: This is incredible Like I'm not even really sure what I would say about this.
Speaker 1: there's nothing to say about it It's just it is what it is.
Speaker 1: I've always like thought about.
Speaker 1: I've thought about this in the past like once or twice like could it be possible and I was and I was.
Speaker 1: the only way I could see it being possible would be if Somehow the game had like an interpreter in it and let you like, you know enter something like that.
Speaker 1: But I guess he you know was able to.
Speaker 1: I don't know But he had the eight controllers to enter the data real fast.
Speaker 0: You know this and Kurt the current state of speedruns basically Illustrates a greater point we can talk about someday in depth on geek nights in the modern world.
Speaker 0: No matter what your thing is Stepping up your game will never get you close to the people who have stepped up their game unless you are So the person stepping up your game in that area.
Speaker 1: either be a generalist Who's are you a lot of things or you step up your game a hundred times just like these guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're a gamer for example you've either got to be good at all games than general sense like E&M banks player of games good at games or you've got to pick one game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean look the people who become truly famous right in this world are people who max out one thing to be you know Sacrificing other things right like Michael Jordan basketball only a baseball.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah Didn't go so well Right Tiger Woods golf only his whole life.
Speaker 1: pretty much right.
Speaker 1: if you want to be that kind of somebody You have to sacrifice all your other things and that's why we are nobody's because we do too many things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we have not quit our jobs to do geek nights full-time geek nights would be a lot better if we did this full-time.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying it wouldn't be but we do many many things I like to.
Speaker 0: I like to go to beaches and fuck around play Nidhogg.
Speaker 1: Let's met a moment.
Speaker 0: All right met a moment.
Speaker 1: The book club book is I do by William Gibson.
Speaker 1: I finished reading it.
Speaker 0: Thank God next Thursday That means I got to pick a new book.
Speaker 0: So in the time it took you to read I drew.
Speaker 0: I read it again because I'd already read it in the past and then I read three Culture books in the time that you were reading three culture books.
Speaker 0: I played many games of netrunner yep, so I know a lot about the culture now.
Speaker 0: and Seriously if you didn't read player of games from our previous book club before read that fucking book Seriously, because the rest of the culture books are great, but I think that one stands apart.
Speaker 1: I picked the right one.
Speaker 0: No, cuz that one tells one story All the other ones all the other ones.
Speaker 0: you have to already care about the culture.
Speaker 0: be like man.
Speaker 0: I wonder what's up with the culture?
Speaker 1: What's the the one that I didn't finish?
Speaker 1: you consider Phlebas?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that one only told one story the moral.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the moral of that one it no it tells two stars.
Speaker 0: the moral of that one is you're fucked.
Speaker 0: yeah The moral of use of weapons is weapons suck.
Speaker 1: You're fucked.
Speaker 1: I know that.
Speaker 1: yeah I have to tell me that I don't need a book now the more that one is you are a weapon.
Speaker 1: Yes, that's also true.
Speaker 0: Yep ideas are weapons.
Speaker 0: Everything's a weapon.
Speaker 1: that is well-known.
Speaker 1: Yeah book not needed message received.
Speaker 0: Yep, so far the message of look to win data is the culture is just awesome.
Speaker 0: It really sucks to live anywhere else.
Speaker 1: I also did not need more than one book to know that.
Speaker 0: yeah But the degree to which it is better anyway.
Speaker 0: So I guess I got to pick my book.
Speaker 1: How about other metamoment things?
Speaker 0: uh we got a fuck ton of videos on the internet.
Speaker 0: you should watch him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're going to anime Boston.
Speaker 0: I got to submit the rest of my panels.
Speaker 0: They haven't submitted all my panels yet.
Speaker 1: Gotta go to PAX East.
Speaker 0: we're gonna be doing some panels there.
Speaker 1: We don't know what ones.
Speaker 0: yeah Yeah, not gonna announce yet, cuz I'm not sure if we're doing one or two and zero.
Speaker 0: yeah Well if it's zero then I guess we're just enforcing.
Speaker 1: so come and play games.
Speaker 0: at least we're enforcing.
Speaker 0: We're guaranteed to get in no matter what.
Speaker 1: that's for sure.
Speaker 0: Thank the gods.
Speaker 0: Thank glob I think.
Speaker 0: uh what else we got going on?
Speaker 0: our forum is actually really rocking again.
Speaker 0: So if you had joined our forum in the past, and it's slacking away the forum is new improved Costing us money to be new and improved And is way better in every way.
Speaker 0: There's lots of stuff going on in there.
Speaker 1: In fact pretty much every place that exists on the internet where people can socialize and connect and Publish and share and do that sort of stuff geek nights is there.
Speaker 1: so come and look for us on the internet.
Speaker 0: Kinetic on submit your goddamn panels.
Speaker 0: They've been open for months.
Speaker 0: well I'm starting to schedule stuff guys.
Speaker 1: also if you want to go to Kinetic on No reason not to buy a badge right now cuz it's gonna be way cheaper.
Speaker 0: It's way cheaper.
Speaker 0: You can sell in badges now.
Speaker 0: the more way in advance the more you guys buy badges now The more I can try to get some budget to do cooler shit.
Speaker 1: also I'm not sure of this right, but they have those Kinetic on member appreciation days at the tournament center.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you buy a badge you buy a badge for this year But you haven't even gone to a kinetic on yet.
Speaker 0: You can still go to those right yes And you know what those things are really awesome if you live anywhere near Hartford.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think it's in Hartford.
Speaker 1: I think it's in Connecticut.
Speaker 1: I think Connecticut Connecticut Like if you're a nerd in Connecticut basically right.
Speaker 1: where are you gonna?
Speaker 1: Go to play.
Speaker 1: you know magic or any other sort of nerdy tabletop.
Speaker 0: You're just like watch anime with people.
Speaker 0: basically Kinetic on is your local anime and gaming club if you live anywhere near Connecticut.
Speaker 1: pretty much.
Speaker 1: So there's a Connecticut con Tournament center that is like a you know all-year-round gaming place.
Speaker 0: also Kinetic ons board gaming tabletop content is Literally the best non packs non magfest gaming con there is yes In the u.s..
Speaker 1: Yes I'm not in terms of tabletop library.
Speaker 1: It's probably the best.
Speaker 0: Oh my god the tabletop library.
Speaker 0: there though magfest is much better now that cold guy commits.
Speaker 1: basically his entire Kinetic ons library is greater than cold guys library.
Speaker 1: not the cold guy has bad tasting games.
Speaker 1: I kind of yes a fuck ton of games, but it doesn't have that many.
Speaker 0: well He is but a man.
Speaker 0: that I'm saying is an organization.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: It's exactly.
Speaker 0: yeah stay tuned We're gonna start ramping up the kinetic on panels workshop special events stuff.
Speaker 1: Is anything else in the calendar?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Stuff do your geeky thing.
Speaker 0: So yeah, uh space dandy space Dandy.
Speaker 0: space dandy is the anime that many people are saying saved anime along with kill-all-kill space dandy.
Speaker 0: space dandy is a dandy in Space a dandy guy in the space.
Speaker 0: so people have been anticipating the show for a long time because mostly It's made by the cabi by people yep, and it has some superficial stylistic elements that are reminiscent of cowboy bebop But it's in space, but they're equally reminiscent of Lupin.
Speaker 1: the third money well can we view up was as well?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the money.
Speaker 1: the money is who longs.
Speaker 1: so it might be the same universe in the distant future.
Speaker 0: I'm assuming it's the same universe, right?
Speaker 1: Also, it is airing on Adult Swim Cartoon Network.
Speaker 1: in fact it airs in the US before it airs in Japan.
Speaker 0: Is there space dandy dubcast set yet?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's dubbed on TV.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I haven't watched it on TV.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no we watch it on the internet where it's up.
Speaker 1: there were some minor complaints with the dub as there are with all dubs Whatever.
Speaker 0: yeah I realized recently that we always kind of talk about the cowboy bebop dub as being one of the greatest Dubs of anime ever done even though it pales before.
Speaker 0: I don't know dubbing.
Speaker 0: that happens for real movies Like why does anime fuck this up, but I've found on the internet that a lot of people really hate the cowboy bebop dub.
Speaker 0: It's not anime enough, okay, they like that anime bullshit dub that they're so used to That it doesn't sound enough like anime I found.
Speaker 1: oh, so they don't like.
Speaker 1: they have a b-bop dub because it's better and they like the other shitty dubs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't have people who talk like this all the time.
Speaker 1: Oh I thought it was just people who typically sub fan it.
Speaker 0: They know the sub fans hate it for their own reasons.
Speaker 0: Okay, they hate it cuz it doesn't have the right cast as in the original Japanese cast sure.
Speaker 0: And they also quietly Back away when you try to point out that mushroom Samba's sub the Japanese voice acting in that is kind of bullshit.
Speaker 0: But I digress space dandy.
Speaker 0: It's hard to really Describe space dandy without just telling you what happens.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm not even sure what happened in this show.
Speaker 0: So let's recap in episode 1 the entire cat main cast.
Speaker 0: Okay, okay.
Speaker 1: So the main premise is a guy space dandy who is way dandy, right?
Speaker 1: He's so he's sort of like a combination of you know, it turns a cowboy b-bop, right?
Speaker 1: He's a combination of spike and the cowboy guy and but also Lupin.
Speaker 1: Lupin is already in spike.
Speaker 1: That's like saying yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's milk in this butter You know.
Speaker 0: one way you could put him is imagine kind of like how Andy in Cowboy b-bop was almost imagining of what someone like spike could have been without Tragedy in his past.
Speaker 0: space dandy is without tragedy and without forethought Yeah, living in a moment.
Speaker 1: So wackiness level is way high right and the other aspects are toned down a bit.
Speaker 1: So this guy dandy, he's not man.
Speaker 0: That's very important.
Speaker 0: He's a butt man.
Speaker 0: Only amateurs are into boobs, right?
Speaker 1: So he's a space guy in a spaceship right much like spike was and whatnot, but he's not bounty hunting say butts.
Speaker 1: He's doing something similar.
Speaker 1: He is looking for rare aliens.
Speaker 1: So any alien I mean, it's basically it's.
Speaker 1: it must be if it's in the cowboy universe with oolongs and whatnot It's in a distant future or faraway place.
Speaker 1: Well, it can't be that far away from earth because actually mentioned earth.
Speaker 1: So it's in a distant time in the future, right?
Speaker 1: So there's all kinds of alien races unlike me how I bebop where there's just humans, right?
Speaker 1: And there's so many alien races all over the place.
Speaker 1: There's more than Star Wars.
Speaker 1: It is insane how many different aliens there are.
Speaker 1: So and there's tons and tons of aliens.
Speaker 0: like the aliens are all like the background shots in red line, right?
Speaker 1: So this guy dandy He is trying to basically find alien species that are extremely rare or perhaps even undiscovered and if he brings them to the alien Registration place he gets mad moneys.
Speaker 0: if he does that now He's nominally doing this to get money And I think the only thing he spends money on is food at the space equivalent of Hooters, right?
Speaker 1: Which is called boobies?
Speaker 0: so That seemed dumb and I was like really boobies.
Speaker 0: But then we get this panning shot and you see the boobies splice pep space platform in the distance and it's just two gigantic Boobs, yes this show.
Speaker 1: So yeah, this is where the boobies come in.
Speaker 1: The one thing I have with boobies How come all the girls at boobies are Human girls, why aren't there alien girls at boobies who are not human?
Speaker 0: or was that one fish girl?
Speaker 1: Sure, but she was humanoid body with boobies, right?
Speaker 1: How come there are out there?
Speaker 0: I'll come.
Speaker 0: maybe he's on the humanoid floor or maybe no.
Speaker 1: how come the other Aliens are on the same floor who are not humanoids.
Speaker 0: You're telling me all the not.
Speaker 0: How do you know?
Speaker 0: there are other restaurants called egg sacks?
Speaker 1: Sure, but how come the non?
Speaker 1: Humanoid aliens?
Speaker 1: men we presume right?
Speaker 1: I can tell you why these people of a sexuality desiring women are hanging out at boobies looking at humanoid boobies.
Speaker 0: I can tell you why and liking them.
Speaker 1: I can tell you as the as the alien unit far distant universe.
Speaker 1: like media like promoted You know human shape as the ideal form of beauty.
Speaker 1: So now like alien women can't get laid because all the alien dudes only want to go with human lady.
Speaker 0: I will tell you why.
Speaker 0: if I'm alive in a future where there are aliens and cool stuff I would probably check out an alien strip club just to see what the deal was with their equivalent of if they have females.
Speaker 1: Sure, but this didn't look like tourists were coming through for their one time looking at the humans.
Speaker 0: Ah, I mean, maybe there's all these other floors We really don't know.
Speaker 0: that is not the part of the world that and it's called boobies.
Speaker 0: It is called boobies.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's a themed restaurant like check out the humans and their boobies.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh Sure, cuz most of the client.
Speaker 1: I mean you got a pretty thin Explanation there.
Speaker 1: the reason it's way way way humans are watching the show.
Speaker 0: my explanation of something in space dandy is I think space dandy Is thin sure so?
Speaker 0: That one I don't think he's actually trying to find rare aliens cuz he fucking doesn't.
Speaker 1: Oh, I mean how many bounties despite cash, but he doesn't even try.
Speaker 1: he tried.
Speaker 1: No, he doesn't a little bit fucking he just kind of walk even went to the alien registration place.
Speaker 0: Yeah, kind.
Speaker 0: he just kind of walks in the direction and stuff happens to him and he's super competent.
Speaker 1: He reacts to things in a spike Spiegel level like okay Sometimes he does but other times he gets like in an inspector gadget situation where he totally fucks up, but it ends up succeeding Yeah in the first episode.
Speaker 1: especially like.
Speaker 1: so like action scenes He would like go oops and then somehow you beat the bad guy with that oops move.
Speaker 1: Totally expected gadget.
Speaker 0: He has a robot who seems to be referred to as a she who just robot is smart and vacuum and way out of date.
Speaker 1: It's like a crappy version of bemo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it kind of pissed off version of bemo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've seen bemo pissed off and then he meets this beetle juicien because he's stupid.
Speaker 0: but the beetle juicien is actually stupid Yeah, and he is just kind of an otaku pervert nerd in a cat body.
Speaker 1: But he's beautifully animated Most of the things are beautifully and I know this show is so beautiful to watch and the designs of all the aliens are really unique.
Speaker 0: and and the attention to detail on the facial expressions and these three jackass is just basically the the meow The the cat guy joins the shit because he's like.
Speaker 0: I know where some aliens are and then he's like randomly Points at some spot on the space map is like they're there.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and space dandy's like really?
Speaker 0: Okay, and they go there and they almost die and then at the end of the episode they get trapped and space dandy's like QT use the thing.
Speaker 0: so QT is like, okay and he hits the button.
Speaker 0: He's like.
Speaker 0: what the thing do?
Speaker 0: he's like self-destruct and then they all die.
Speaker 0: and that's the end of the episode And the beginning of next episode.
Speaker 1: they don't even mention that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, so so here's the other thing.
Speaker 1: there's bad guys.
Speaker 0: There's a plot thread that's contiguous that doesn't actually directly involve space dandy.
Speaker 0: It's meta to him.
Speaker 1: So there are these bad guys.
Speaker 1: and how do we know they're bad guys?
Speaker 1: Cuz they're so obviously stereotypically designed as bad guys.
Speaker 0: So Commodore Perry who is just a giant flaming floating skull, huh?
Speaker 1: And it's a Japanese made show.
Speaker 0: and the guys named Commodore Perry interesting and dr Gel who I think is one of the pirates in one piece, right?
Speaker 1: And then there's the guy on the TV screen I guess the Emperor who I'm pretty sure is a flaming skull.
Speaker 1: and what the fuck is better than a flamethrower Perry?
Speaker 1: Nothing flaming skulls are the best.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wonder.
Speaker 0: I wonder if he's a distant relative of infernal cop.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter my favorite.
Speaker 1: He's my favorite guy now because he's a flaming skull.
Speaker 1: Yeah All flaming skulls good and ghost rider while awesome is probably the worst of all flaming skulls.
Speaker 1: So that tells you how good.
Speaker 0: so the meta plot is Commodore Perry the flaming skull ordered.
Speaker 0: Dr Gel the the one-piece villain to find space dandy and kill him supposedly or something.
Speaker 0: We don't know why because space daddy has.
Speaker 1: we don't even know that these are bad guys.
Speaker 1: The only thing we know is that they look like guys and act like bad guy.
Speaker 1: what we know is that At all they could be doing this to save the universe.
Speaker 0: what we know is that their ship is a giant Statue of Liberty head With a ball gag.
Speaker 1: we do know that.
Speaker 0: What is it with these new anime and ball gags?
Speaker 0: I mean Goma gory's Actually has an explanation for that does have an explanation.
Speaker 1: the Statue of Liberty is just I guess stylistic whatever.
Speaker 0: I wonder if that is actually the Statue of Liberty.
Speaker 1: It could I. it could possibly be but that would give us a really good idea of how big that ship is.
Speaker 1: Which is not that big because the Statue of Liberty's head is not that big.
Speaker 1: So so I get it's not the Statue of Liberty because you could not make a spaceship out of something that small.
Speaker 0: Well, you could make it walk through Manhattan.
Speaker 1: The Statue of Liberty in its entirety could maybe make a small spaceship for humans.
Speaker 1: That was like a real space.
Speaker 1: We don't know how many people are on that ship But the Statue of Liberty's head alone could not make a giant space-varying vessel that had an entire fleet around it of which it was the biggest ship.
Speaker 0: so Episode one ends with our entire cast being killed by a self-destructive device and begins with these guys trying to find the space dandy.
Speaker 0: episode 2 These guys are trying to find the space dandy again.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and space dandy's personality is completely 180 now He's a boob man, and he's not into butts anymore.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I almost think that's irrelevant.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm well, I'm thinking based on only two episodes of information.
Speaker 1: Is that Basically you can't die.
Speaker 1: It's like a Kenny from South Park situation, right?
Speaker 1: He's like this invincible guy and he has some effect on the universe right this crazy shit happens to him.
Speaker 1: he seems to luck out whatever and This is why they're trying to hunt him down, but he doesn't know it about himself, right?
Speaker 1: He doesn't know anything that he's special or whatever.
Speaker 0: I think him and everyone around him literally cannot die but don't remember anything that happens to them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, QT seems to remember and seems to be vaguely pissed off about the real plot.
Speaker 1: is some sort of meta thing that you Know like that something along those lines and the bad guys know it and the robot seems to know it.
Speaker 1: but space dandy doesn't have enough memory or coherence himself and Neither does the meow thing really?
Speaker 1: so it's sort of like, you know, you're just sort of watching it from the wrong perspective to understand what's really happening and It's gonna get crazy serious.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes So this revealed but maybe not that serious.
Speaker 0: dandy and meow died again in the second episode and meow died I think twice.
Speaker 1: yeah, they died when they were like ejected into the vacuum of space But then they were alive at the end of the episode.
Speaker 0: They just yeah, but every time they die like the next cut is just everyone fine again.
Speaker 1: Yep They don't even.
Speaker 1: and this is large time skips.
Speaker 1: not super large like months, but super large like Shit could have happened in between there and there.
Speaker 1: that was not explained and could be important.
Speaker 0: and everyone around space dandy Like all the people who get noticed are Badasses in some sense and seem to be secret agents of some kind.
Speaker 0: Yeah and seemed to be against dr.
Speaker 1: Gal and Commodore Perry, well, it doesn't seem like anyone even knows.
Speaker 0: gal and Perry exist But I fought off the guys who were after space dandy.
Speaker 1: sure but you know, I don't know You know what?
Speaker 0: There's nothing else to say.
Speaker 0: watch your show.
Speaker 0: You're an anime fan.
Speaker 0: This is the show to be watching.
Speaker 0: if you're not already watching kill la kill.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think though I mean, you know in terms of the promise of the show It was gonna save animes just like the promise of all these other shows.
Speaker 1: I don't think space dandy alone would have saved any anime.
Speaker 1: No, but well, here's the thing at least not based on two episodes.
Speaker 1: We're wait till I kill the first episode.
Speaker 1: That was enough right.
Speaker 0: Monica saved anime for people who are Into anime and paid attention to.
Speaker 1: Monica saved anime in three episodes.
Speaker 1: So we have to give space dandy at least one more.
Speaker 0: What I'm saying is that kill la kill brought a lot more people who were more far-flung in anime fandom back into anime.
Speaker 0: Space dandy is the kind of thing you could show on TV and someone who doesn't watch anime like what the fuck is it?
Speaker 1: That's a netrunner meetup, right?
Speaker 1: There's you know, some people who are you know nerdy and other people aren't just in a netrunner.
Speaker 1: They're shocking, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know some animes came up and like three people were like space dandy.
Speaker 1: all shit.
Speaker 1: That was that with a time when there had only been one episode and and they would tell me like yeah I really only watch anime like in cartoon network or never.
Speaker 1: but they were like, holy shit that show that was and they were like.
Speaker 1: so the people who are you know, the Casual anime fan who aren't crunchy rolling or fan subbing right?
Speaker 1: They're into this.
Speaker 1: It's it's a it is a hit with that.
Speaker 0: Well, I get the impression because this is the kind of show that if I just showed one episode of this to my dad You would probably watch the rest of it.
Speaker 0: Maybe I mean good chance, so Watch your show.
Speaker 1: She's a boob and or but man anime fans.
Speaker 0: It's I Don't know what else to say because I don't know where this show is going.
Speaker 1: if you're watching some crappy other show You have time.
Speaker 0: you have time Blah blah blah not technically my and you have.
Speaker 1: if you have time to watch that shit you have time to watch this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because it's not you know, it is remains to be foreseen the exact quality of this show overall You know, there's yet to be determined, but I guarantee it's better than all those.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm watching yo-wa pedal.
Speaker 1: if I can watch you a pedal I can watch these.
Speaker 0: My life has entered the sort of golden eight like this renaissance of watching animation.
Speaker 0: because right now look adventure time started again Archer started again.
Speaker 0: I'm venture brothers is kind of on hiatus.
Speaker 0: I got space dandy.
Speaker 0: I got kill la kill.
Speaker 0: I got silver spoon.
Speaker 0: I got so much animation.
Speaker 0: You know, you just reminded me of huh?
Speaker 1: So on Cartoon hangover they posted a video.
Speaker 1: they interviewed one Yonan Vasquez.
Speaker 1: I saw that because you know why they interviewed him not because he just stopped in the office Although he did because I'm assuming that they're bringing his shit back.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: No, he is writing an episode of I Didn't even mention bravest warriors, which I fell behind on.
Speaker 0: I gotta watch her and you know, what's not in that episode?
Speaker 1: Ger cat bug.
Speaker 1: and he was like, there's no cat bug.
Speaker 1: Don't hate me.
Speaker 0: What I hate him now cat bug.
Speaker 1: He said he likes cat bug but didn't put cat bug in his episode.
Speaker 1: So yeah cat bug is like ten BMO's also now and I know what that guy looks like.
Speaker 1: He's younger than I thought I thought he was old.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so It's problematic because I'm watching so many shows suddenly not even counting a House of Cards that it's cutting into my time for other stuff like playing games, you know, it's show I've been watching lately CVS NFL football On Fox, yeah, you know what I almost did.
Speaker 0: I almost bought tickets to the Red Wings Rangers game at MSG Found tickets.
Speaker 1: how much was it?
Speaker 0: So I had legit tickets.
Speaker 0: I could have got.
Speaker 0: I almost just did it.
Speaker 1: How much are they?
Speaker 0: they were next to each other in section two.
Speaker 0: They were great seats.
Speaker 0: They were $430 each.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I almost just bought him.
Speaker 0: Listen I want if of all the sporting events that I realized the cost of that I could fly to Istanbul and separately watch a minor league hockey game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so then I decided not to buy the tickets.
Speaker 1: Of All these sporting events in the world that I could go to I would choose first to go to Madison Square Garden.
Speaker 1: I have not been there.
Speaker 0: I've never seen a thing there either.
Speaker 1: I have been to.
Speaker 1: I have been there in my life, but I haven't been there in with my own money.
Speaker 0: I've never seen hockey there.
Speaker 0: I've seen hockey there once I should just I got.
Speaker 1: I've been there total three times.
Speaker 1: I've seen is if I go to.
Speaker 1: I went to Madison Square Garden when I was very young to see Sesame Street live.
Speaker 1: I Circus and I went there and saw hockey.
Speaker 0: Ah I feel like though.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna buy if I'm gonna go see a hockey game at MSG.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be like Stanley Cup something I'm gonna pay like a thousand dollars for that.
Speaker 1: I'll just go see the Super Bowl.
Speaker 0: I kind of well, I've never been to a Super Bowl.
Speaker 0: I kind of never will be.
Speaker 0: I Had a lien.
Speaker 0: I had a line on tickets, but they were.
Speaker 0: they were shall we say pricey.
Speaker 1: How many thousands?
Speaker 1: Actually five three three three three is about a little over three thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you're sitting in the top deck for three.
Speaker 0: No, it's a little lower than that.
Speaker 0: It was two seats three thousand each not for both.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they were one seat apart for that amount of money.
Speaker 1: The camera equipment we could buy to make videos.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right Yeah, actually you know getting back into meta stuff stay tuned because Scott and I kind of agree that it's time for a stepping up of game because we've we've cast our Making video content feelers in a lot of directions.
Speaker 1: also at the aforementioned CES the camera that I've been waiting to buy was at least Shittily fakily teased by taking another camera and putting a sticker on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Eventually a camera that isn't just an old camera with a sticker on it will be made and produced Supposedly within some months and I'll buy it.
Speaker 0: Scott and I are of agreement that we've cast all these seeds out.
Speaker 0: We did you know, we did that pony show and then we did geek nights presents, which we're gonna keep doing.
Speaker 0: Don't worry we're just been a hiatus for a while and Scott's been doing his netrunner and we've been practicing with streaming and Some of those things look like a correct path.
Speaker 0: So we're both willing to spend money to step up the game All right.
Speaker 0: So anyway, stay tuned.
Speaker 1: I gotta go home and watch space day.
Speaker 0: I'm so hungry I'm gonna die especially because this episode of space dandy was all about ramen.
Speaker 1: I'm not hungry.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: when I Indian
Speaker 0: when that fucking cat ate space dandy's ramen and he's got the naruto like stuck to his cheek like he didn't Even care and then it just fell on the ground and he didn't eat it
Speaker 1: I thought I said at least in the episode there was a reversal so it evened out.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, fuck him seriously, that cat guy is kind of a Really?
Speaker 0: He's a bad dude But not in the bad dude sense like hey, he could be in league with the bad guys, uh I think he's just dumb.
Speaker 1: It's either way is equally likely.
Speaker 0: Oh, I just went to Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: one of space dandy's partners Yeah is a dim-witted cat-like alien.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: That is correct about sums him up.
Speaker 1: All right, I'm good.
Speaker 0: All right This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 2: She came into the shop and said I want to know what the problem is.
Speaker 2: I Said you don't want to know what the problem is.
Speaker 2: And she said I want to know what the problem is so I can get the problem fixed.
Speaker 2: I Don't want to know what your problem is.
Speaker 2: She says, how do you know that?
Speaker 2: I'm not gonna like it.
Speaker 2: I said, I know you're not gonna like it.
Speaker 2: So she said just tell me what it is and I'll tell you if I like it.
Speaker 2: and I said maybe Maybe I'll tell you.
Speaker 2: she said why won't you tell me?
Speaker 2: I said the problems your ass.
Speaker 2: She said what I said the problems your ass.
Speaker 2: She said what I said the problems your fucking ass your ass is all fucked up.
Speaker 2: and you got problems with your ass.
Speaker 2: She said why are you saying this to me?
Speaker 2: And I said, it's your fucking problem.
Speaker 2: You're the one with the fucked up ass Started to storm out.
Speaker 2: so I said wait.
Speaker 2: She said what I said, wait, she said what is this about my ass?
Speaker 2: and I said no Kind of your ass is mad fucked up and you don't want to face the problem.
Speaker 2: She said what's your problem?
Speaker 2: I said my problem is that you come in here with a fucked up bass And you don't want someone to tell you that your ass is fucked up.
Speaker 2: I don't even know how you go to the bathroom.
Speaker 1: I don't even know how you sit on things when you stand up.
Speaker 2: Where does your ass go?
Speaker 2: Where was your ass in the first place?
Speaker 2: Where was your ass in?
Speaker 2: 1969?
Speaker 2: where was your ass on 9/11?
Speaker 2: I thought you said you'd never forget.
Speaker 2: She said I'm leaving and I said not before you get your official diagnosis here.
Speaker 2: It is you're fucked up and your ass is fucked up.
Speaker 2: Are you ready for the solution?
Speaker 2: She said what not said.
Speaker 2: here's the solution.
Speaker 2: Are you ready?
Speaker 0: Your ass Replacer.