Speaker 0: It's Thursday June 12th 2014.
Speaker 0: I'm rim Scott and this is geek nights tonight the shit that rim and or Scott don't give shits about.
Speaker 0: Let's do this geek nights titles now with swearing.
Speaker 1: you just started the show before I could find a news.
Speaker 0: Well there is big news.
Speaker 0: Apparently OJ Simpson murdered somebody you don't say I. just today I noticed multiple articles kind of popping up in all my different feeds.
Speaker 0: It was all about OJ.
Speaker 0: the farc one fell.
Speaker 0: he had the best headline.
Speaker 0: Can you believe?
Speaker 0: some people think that OJ actually murdered someone?
Speaker 1: You don't say?
Speaker 0: And I couldn't figure out why we were all talking about OJ When the rim started talking about it.
Speaker 1: I was like why is anyone talking about OJ?
Speaker 0: That's like what did he?
Speaker 0: and then do something new?
Speaker 1: and I remembered something and it's that's weird because my memory is not the greatest But it's the 20-year anniversary of OJ, and you know how.
Speaker 1: I know that.
Speaker 0: I'm really curious How you know that?
Speaker 1: because OJ?
Speaker 1: Happened on the during the Stanley Cup finals in 1994 which I normally wouldn't remember except the Rangers are in the Stanley Cup finals in 1994 and also in 2014 and also I predict in 2034. so watch out people are gonna be talking about OJ in June of 2013 OJ.
Speaker 1: In June of 2034 OJ is gonna be hot.
Speaker 1: I would buy up some OJ merchandise also.
Speaker 1: I've got you know what I have.
Speaker 1: you buy up some OJ merchandise in like you know 2033 you should sell it in 2044 cuz that'll be the 50-year anniversary.
Speaker 0: got to be careful though because sometimes those things just disappear Like OJ might not actually be remembered by then.
Speaker 1: Well look I'm telling you if you have a bloody glove or two you can make money on that.
Speaker 0: I Do have some OJ memorabilia though, so I was at a pog convention during the trial And I have two OJ pogs.
Speaker 0: They're two slammers one says guilty and one says innocent.
Speaker 0: They were two dollars each Which was pretty cheap for a slammer at a pog convention.
Speaker 1: I should go into the closet my parents house and dig out the pogs.
Speaker 0: should we do a show on pogs have we?
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: you want to play pogs.
Speaker 0: We should play.
Speaker 0: we got to play it again with our adult sensibilities before we can properly review that complex game.
Speaker 1: It's really shitty compared to something like say jungle speed.
Speaker 0: ah, but there's more to it than that.
Speaker 0: I mean Americans all played it wrong.
Speaker 1: They didn't actually gamble.
Speaker 0: No they didn't use actual pogs.
Speaker 1: Oh with the staple in.
Speaker 0: yeah, they didn't have.
Speaker 1: I had because it was hard to get real pogs.
Speaker 1: I think I had exactly.
Speaker 0: you know what you could.
Speaker 0: you could at least bootleg them by putting staples under American pogs.
Speaker 1: Exactly one real pog with the staple in it and one side fuzzy and everything.
Speaker 1: and you know what?
Speaker 1: That kind of staple that's in there is sort of like this perfect staple.
Speaker 1: It's not a staple that you can get from your stapler.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you need without any state me from like a staple go to the hardware store.
Speaker 1: You can get it.
Speaker 0: like the game didn't even work.
Speaker 0: not that it was much of a game Don't get me wrong.
Speaker 0: It's just I. I remember the OJ era being the era where pogs were a thing.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 0: and now thinking back because we're talking about the anniversary I do remember the because you know many of you younger people today like people are in high school middle school.
Speaker 0: now I don't think you understand what mass media was like when we were in middle school.
Speaker 0: The there wasn't an internet that let people see news the way that we have it now.
Speaker 0: and even if you did have access to internets to see news things you definitely could not look at that during school or Anywhere other than your kitchen where your 486 was hanging out.
Speaker 0: So and even then only if your mom wasn't using the phone line.
Speaker 0: so the trial was pretty much the only unifying aspect of pop culture other than football and Perhaps other sports at the time.
Speaker 0: so my school would give everyone an update every morning after we watched the Propaganda channel 1 news bullshit, then the morning announcements included an update on the OJ trial.
Speaker 0: really yeah Wow Everybody watched the OJ trial.
Speaker 1: the only OJ the only time I did Infiltrated our school is when the verdict was declared.
Speaker 1: it got whispered around from class to class.
Speaker 0: Wow whispered around I mean one.
Speaker 0: I knew all about judge Ito his shenanigans, and he was a like minor celebrity.
Speaker 0: in fact I saw someone who was dressed up as judge Ito.
Speaker 0: I guess they were playing before.
Speaker 0: I knew that cosplay was the thing.
Speaker 0: you know it was at the pog convention That there were a bunch of people dressed up as characters from the trial.
Speaker 1: So you got pogs from my pog convention.
Speaker 1: the only place I ever got pogs was a these temporary Stands guys set up in the middle of the mall hallways.
Speaker 1: And also I went to Florida once during.
Speaker 1: it must have been the summer of you know 93 94 and We went to like a flea market like an indoor flea market kind of place And there were a couple stands that had like I got some pogs.
Speaker 1: I got some magic cards, so I'm you know I must have been in 7th 8th grade.
Speaker 0: but anyway because we had those TVs for that propaganda channel 1 bullshit and Because everyone in the entire country was like obsessed with this thing I mean I haven't had a friend who had a screensaver that played the Simpsons theme and just showed a white Ford Bronco driving down the freeway.
Speaker 0: Okay It was the Midwest.
Speaker 0: what else do you do?
Speaker 0: but When the trial was nearing its conclusion and the verdict was going to be announced the entire middle school stopped classes And put the live trial on the TVs that we had in every single classroom because we had that bullshit channel one thing.
Speaker 0: So we all watched the verdict get read live and as soon as they said not guilty all the football bro dudes Jumped up cheering and yelling and screaming about how happy they were that OJ was not guilty and everyone who was smart was quietly dead inside.
Speaker 0: ah OJ you know if you didn't do it you really shouldn't have written a book called.
Speaker 0: if I did it were you explain how you Did it.
Speaker 1: listen no one ever said?
Speaker 1: No one ever said OJ was smart, okay?
Speaker 0: Well he was smart enough to get away with murder.
Speaker 1: also have to consider the fact right like what really complex murder.
Speaker 1: I mean you to consider the fact that seriously right You know what we know now about football and brain damage.
Speaker 0: Oh, I didn't think of that angle right.
Speaker 1: like you know It's like if this trial happened today They might be going in with a defense like look OJ's head is basically bashed in from playing football.
Speaker 1: Right he's not in his right mind or whatever.
Speaker 0: I mean like Chris Benoit.
Speaker 0: I mean Sports injuries can make people go crazy.
Speaker 0: sharing yeah Uh but still it was a pretty complex murder plot all things considered I guess.
Speaker 0: so ah oh well OJ is what he is and oh my god.
Speaker 0: I just noticed saw something I never realized the original cover for the book he wrote.
Speaker 0: if I did it the color of the word if is different from the Rest of the words in the title.
Speaker 0: so from a distance.
Speaker 0: It just says I did it.
Speaker 0: yeah I Wonder where Kato Kaelin's up to what?
Speaker 0: Remember much about the OJ trial Nearly as much as you did I didn't pay attention much.
Speaker 0: It was more that if you live in a place where everyone around you pays attention to a thing You learn a lot about that thing.
Speaker 0: by osmosis I mean think about how much you know about weird subculture cultures on the internet just because you encountered them tangentially.
Speaker 0: We know a lot about Homestuck kids even though we don't read any Homestuck.
Speaker 0: We know a lot less about Homestuck that we might think yeah But we know more than say grandma or anyone over the aid anyone else over the age of 19.
Speaker 0: Yes, that is in fact.
Speaker 1: We know that Homestuck exists.
Speaker 1: That is a lot.
Speaker 1: and candy corn horns are thing that is Homestuck related.
Speaker 0: It took me a long time to realize that candy corn horns were a thing and then to figure out what they were kind of like.
Speaker 0: how and I'm gonna admit something I Thought Slenderman was from a video game until like six months
Speaker 1: ago The video game that I thought there was some connection between Slenderman and that video game that people cosplayed as two enemy of Austin's ago With like the baseball bat and the white heads or whatever it was.
Speaker 0: Oh, I could see why you would think that.
Speaker 1: that French RPG or whatever the fuck that thing.
Speaker 0: I could see that that aesthetic actually kind of fit.
Speaker 0: so I could see why you would think that yeah But I thought it was from a video game because I encountered it for the first time of all places on VG cats.
Speaker 0: And did you cats made a funny joke?
Speaker 1: there are various games and game mods that have like put Slenderman characters in like.
Speaker 1: I think You can play Minecraft and encounter Slenderman.
Speaker 0: Oh, you can't.
Speaker 0: Slenderman is ways.
Speaker 0: It's a. it's a. you know the term for it is fake lore.
Speaker 0: now that that's what people call that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: It's the situation where someone makes up something that has the trappings of folklore and then other people Extend that until it eventually becomes Paul Bunyan.
Speaker 1: you mean an urban legend sort of.
Speaker 0: But they actually they already have a word for this they make a distinction between urban legends and fake lore in that Urban legends tend to not get expanded upon and tend to survive as their core mostly unedited over time.
Speaker 0: I mean I don't know about the story.
Speaker 0: look at older urban legends like the the dress that was stolen from the corpse that was filled with Embalming fluid and caused the girl to die after the prom.
Speaker 1: I've never heard that one in my life.
Speaker 0: really What about the hook on the door from makeout point?
Speaker 1: I've heard it make out point Hooks on any doors Scott How do you not this?
Speaker 0: the story is to put it in a summary a guy and a girl?
Speaker 0: Drive their car out to go make out it make out point.
Speaker 1: got that story.
Speaker 1: so far We're on the same page.
Speaker 0: yep, and there were reports that there is a deranged Madman killing people with a hook hand.
Speaker 1: I know there's a story of a deranged man killing people With a hook hand.
Speaker 1: I the specific detail of the hook hand is not in my mind.
Speaker 0: Do I have to read you the actual legend at this point?
Speaker 0: Hand hook a tool.
Speaker 0: no I want the story not the my head not my.
Speaker 0: I don't want the movie Tropes, I don't want the movie hook Blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: no it's main slash hook head not Miami.
Speaker 1: yeah TV trope of hook hand.
Speaker 0: so well there I found a weird part of the internet.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna back out of where I just went.
Speaker 1: tropes calm is not a weird part of the internet.
Speaker 0: No, I got into a ghetto within TV tropes of all things that are related solely to hooks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yes, how awesome is that?
Speaker 0: kind of like the goal yesterday?
Speaker 0: We looked up a sailor wound video, and you know we ended up on.
Speaker 0: we ended up in a YouTube ghetto.
Speaker 0: There was nothing but videos of every Sailor Scout dying.
Speaker 0: sweet Yeah, so we watched those for a while anyway, so they start to make out and then they hear a rustling noise and a tap tap tap on the window and The guys like come on let's just keep making out and the girls like no This is I'm scared.
Speaker 0: just go home and the guy's super pissed.
Speaker 0: But then he drives her home, and then he goes home.
Speaker 0: the next morning.
Speaker 0: he wakes up And he goes to his car and oh my god.
Speaker 0: There's a hook hand embedded in the door.
Speaker 0: handle done done done.
Speaker 0: That's one of the most famous urban legends in modern history.
Speaker 1: Oh the way I know it is you go to make out point.
Speaker 1: this is psycho killer on the loose on the radio.
Speaker 1: They turn off the radio they make out right they hear something while they're making out But they ignore it and then while they're driving home Dun dun dun guy in the backseat murders him and then next day They find a car accident.
Speaker 0: stories like that don't become Paul Bunyan stories.
Speaker 0: They stay as urban legends.
Speaker 0: I Guess.
Speaker 0: maybe also it's interesting that Slender Man kind of became real.
Speaker 0: now that you know two girls actually tried to murder someone Because they thought he existed we can make up pretty much any story and get people to murder of each other exactly.
Speaker 0: I just find this all interesting.
Speaker 0: Slender Man is becoming more and more real as time goes on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's in the closet.
Speaker 1: watch out.
Speaker 0: So was that enough time for you to find some news.
Speaker 1: I found a crappy news.
Speaker 1: all right, so Tesla the people make the electric cars right.
Speaker 1: they're doing something that is mildly interesting more interesting than any news at e3 at least so whatevs.
Speaker 1: It says first like the headline was like Tesla opens patents, and I'm like wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Patents are open right.
Speaker 1: that's the thing with a patent as opposed to a trade secret.
Speaker 1: Is that people can't use your patent if it's a legit patent right without paying you money?
Speaker 1: But you can just go to the patent office or even Google patents and just look at any freaking patent.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 0: it's like the trade-off.
Speaker 0: if you want to have patent protections you have to give up the secret right.
Speaker 1: so it's like if I Figure out how to cook the most delicious cookie.
Speaker 1: No one's ever cooked cookie like this before with some new ingredient or some shit that I invent.
Speaker 1: It's a real legitimate invention.
Speaker 1: somehow my new brand new.
Speaker 1: unlike any other cookie recipe You freeze the cookies to bake them.
Speaker 1: freeze baking.
Speaker 1: sure I made it up.
Speaker 1: Okay If I invent freeze baking and I want to patent that so people have to pay me when they freeze bake or have freeze baking Businesses I have to tell everyone the secret of freeze baking Specifically the government and then via the government the entire world the secrets of freeze baking.
Speaker 1: so we already know all the secrets of Tesla Car batteries that they've told anyone.
Speaker 1: they're not secrets really right.
Speaker 1: But the news is they decided to be like look if you want to use our patents legitimately to make electric cars for reals go for it and It's sort of like okay other companies.
Speaker 1: Don't have the balls to do it.
Speaker 1: good on you good on you.
Speaker 1: golf clap.
Speaker 0: Yep, also kind of falls in the realm of the really who's gonna use any of these patents?
Speaker 1: anyone who wants to build an electric car Doesn't really have the means to do so.
Speaker 0: Well we'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: who has the desire and means to use these patents that will compete with them and actually beat them at anything eventually.
Speaker 1: smarter traditional car companies, maybe Maybe but you know what?
Speaker 1: They'll probably just like if it was if someone if like Ford just looks at all these patents and starts to make Tesla the cars That are better than Tesla.
Speaker 1: They'll probably just end up buying Tesla not because oh this Tesla technology We have to get because we got it all in the patents, but because hey let's not build an electric car factory look There's one right there.
Speaker 1: Let's just buy it.
Speaker 0: Man the thing is the the thing that bothers me the most about telling the technology and Tesla is a company whatever.
Speaker 0: But it's the whole fact that one of the biggest things holding these cars back is the ancient protective laws on car dealerships that prevent car companies from just selling cars direct.
Speaker 0: I mean If I have to buy a car again like if we ever move out of New York And I got it, you know because if that happens I gotta buy a car, okay?
Speaker 0: I pretty much just want to go to a website like Toyota's website.
Speaker 0: Just pick a car Amazon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as easy as buying something Amazon.
Speaker 0: I want to pick a car pick the options.
Speaker 0: Oh look.
Speaker 0: There's the MSRP.
Speaker 0: I'll just pay that.
Speaker 0: yeah I lived.
Speaker 0: I literally think Negotiating and haggling over car prices is one of the most fucked things that we do as a country that we could fix But refuse to.
Speaker 1: huh you know a good way to solve this would be Maybe if car dealerships weren't so influential in their local governments.
Speaker 0: Oh, is this a plug for Lawrence Lessig's Super PAC?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying all problems that we complain about most of the time 90% of them are really just one problem.
Speaker 1: Especially this one is definitely that one problem.
Speaker 0: actually my news for the second half of the show Is very relevant in relation to what you just said.
Speaker 1: anyway if you didn't know there's In the United States there's a PAC and it's basically Only trying to get people elected who are not corrupt and will not you know be evil and don't want to take money from Corporations.
Speaker 1: yeah the way they're doing it is give them money And then they use the money to basically play the game To get people who don't want to play the game to win the game.
Speaker 1: And then if we do that enough to imagine a game.
Speaker 0: imagine if if you win the Stanley Cup You get to change a rule in hockey for the next season.
Speaker 1: It's like so.
Speaker 1: then once you get into the ace square you make the rules.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 1: So if I win the Stanley Cup But you gotta play by the person whose rules are in currently in the a square to get out of the a square.
Speaker 0: And I got a really fast team.
Speaker 0: I remove icings.
Speaker 0: those just aren't a rule anymore.
Speaker 0: Anyway So an actual news isn't just OJ.
Speaker 0: I just want to point this out because it's kind of amazing.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of ads running in New York City right now as I learned from some news articles about them.
Speaker 1: Where are they running?
Speaker 0: I guess TV and radio.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's why I haven't seen them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I usually see subway and billboard ads because I'm in fucking Times Square.
Speaker 0: They are Trying to convince people in New York that rents are actually way too low And that if rents get raised nobody will believe that.
Speaker 1: who lives in New York?
Speaker 0: that if rents aren't raised all our buildings will collapse?
Speaker 1: Because no one will tell me only the ones owned by slum lords will collapse and that's already been true.
Speaker 0: Nobody would ever build a building or maintain real estate in New York.
Speaker 0: if we don't significantly Raise rent then how come the buildings haven't collapsed yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: Landlords in New York City can eat a bag of dicks.
Speaker 0: I Eminent domain, I think the city.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean if your building is falling apart, you know what happens.
Speaker 1: They take your building.
Speaker 0: Oh, hey, yep Plus eat, let's say we had some sort of rent stabilization and we build millions of additional apartments in New York City.
Speaker 0: one They would all still get rented.
Speaker 0: because the demand for apartments is so crazy here And I don't know why they only fill the World Trade Center with office space.
Speaker 1: Why I can tell you why they put apartments in there?
Speaker 0: because if there's more apartments rents might go down.
Speaker 0: You Don't say and it's not like real estate in New York is not barring global warming destroying the city or nukes destroying the city Literally the most perfect investment you could ever make.
Speaker 0: so Really have zero sympathy for anyone who actually owns land here.
Speaker 0: and I think New York City should eminent domain all Residential property in all of New York City and manage it.
Speaker 1: Maybe not manage it itself, but I don't know about that.
Speaker 1: How would I say how would you feel if you owned a building and were a good landlord?
Speaker 0: Oh, fuck you You know why it's New York.
Speaker 0: New York is so special and weird at this point that we can't just owning personal property.
Speaker 1: Well, you can at least pay people for these buildings that they up eminent domain means you pay them a fair market price.
Speaker 1: This would cost the city billions, but the fair market price Will suddenly be changed dramatically by the legislation that you just passed.
Speaker 0: what it though?
Speaker 0: because what if you don't even change rents?
Speaker 0: because really?
Speaker 0: The only difference is if the city owns say all the real estate on the Upper East Side You're gonna fight every landlord ever in court forever over the price of each and every building forever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what you're gonna.
Speaker 0: All those building assessments are gonna be questioned in every single detail.
Speaker 0: Yep And you know what?
Speaker 0: Fuck them do it because once you do it the city could just make.
Speaker 1: imagine all that's like building is a cathedral by the time Even one building is actually eminent domain.
Speaker 1: The person who decided to do that will be dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah got a plan long term.
Speaker 0: But imagine that because right now the reason I have no sympathy for these landlords is that realist like rental properties in New York City are Ridiculously profitable they could be a little less profitable.
Speaker 0: It would be fine for everyone invested in this shit.
Speaker 1: So if the city and I spend my whole life making enough money to buy a building and I buy the building I don't want to have to work anymore.
Speaker 1: I just want to live off the fact that I own this building.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I can't do that, why the fuck did I buy a building?
Speaker 0: for I don't know fuck you.
Speaker 0: It's New York.
Speaker 0: Don't really care about you in your opinion.
Speaker 1: But I want to own a building.
Speaker 1: So I own a building someone else But I won't be able to just live my whole life without having to work simply by owning a building if it's not a New York Building.
Speaker 0: well then own something else.
Speaker 0: that makes similar amounts of money somewhere else.
Speaker 1: What else can I buy?
Speaker 1: that just spits out money?
Speaker 1: many businesses But that involves putting work in.
Speaker 1: if I don't buy the buy an existing business is already profitable But I have to run the business.
Speaker 0: No, just own it.
Speaker 0: Don't run it.
Speaker 1: Is there any few businesses that you can just own without having to do it?
Speaker 0: Most businesses are just owned at least most larger businesses.
Speaker 1: You usually have to do something.
Speaker 0: Yeah own it Have put up capital for it.
Speaker 0: only if it's like a sports team managing people who then manage and do all the actual work.
Speaker 1: That's has to be a large business to just own.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you can afford one of these big buildings in New York.
Speaker 1: You can I'm not saying if you can afford to buy like IBM.
Speaker 1: I'm looking I'm not looking to own some luxury condom and stress you like this building Like, you know someplace has got like four apartments in it.
Speaker 0: So why don't we start with something simple just buy the ultra expensive super rich residential real estate around Central Park.
Speaker 0: Have it be owned by the city.
Speaker 1: You can't even buy a square foot.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, you mean you mean us buying it?
Speaker 1: I'm like you can't afford a square foot of that.
Speaker 0: No, if the city own it and then the city will just keep the rents ridiculously high because if you're a billionaire You'll pay whatever to live in one of those places and then that profit just becomes Revenue for the city.
Speaker 1: BAM.
Speaker 1: We already have property tax on those properties.
Speaker 0: It's not enough because those buildings are ridiculously profitable and we can just raise property tax on those properties.
Speaker 0: I have a. the thing is we can't Because of Cuomo.
Speaker 0: Okay, we can't do anything because of Cuomo.
Speaker 0: It's all.
Speaker 0: state politics prevents New York City from doing anything in.
Speaker 1: just do it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, send the New York police over to the building and find the landlord and be like we are collecting taxes.
Speaker 1: No, well, the city law says yes.
Speaker 0: We said it over like the sheriff of Nottingham.
Speaker 1: exactly.
Speaker 0: We should go one step further and just use our local police to secede from the state Sure, or just go conquer Albany.
Speaker 1: We could probably beat the state troopers easily.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got more helicopters in.
Speaker 1: that might be.
Speaker 0: we pay all the state troopers.
Speaker 0: if we just stop sending money upstate Things of the day.
Speaker 0: So there's a photographer named Arthur Tress and what I'm sharing here is a small collection of photos.
Speaker 0: One they're beautiful beautiful black-and-white photos taken all in New York City in the 60s.
Speaker 0: Okay, so like late 60s.
Speaker 0: so it looks like a desolate hellhole in most places.
Speaker 1: it wasn't too great.
Speaker 0: parts of it are also taken in New Jersey and That's even worse.
Speaker 0: Basically, I'm gonna let me find it.
Speaker 0: There's an actual description quote.
Speaker 0: Tess spoke with children about their dreams often nightmares and Would then photograph them experiencing these dreams in a safe stage setting.
Speaker 0: Okay, so these are staged photographs of children experiencing their nightmares and they're just.
Speaker 0: they're amazing photography.
Speaker 0: So that kids nightmare is that kids nightmare apparently being trapped in the TV with Tommy gun holding a gun I'll Tommy gun and the background is a I guess a bunch of buildings Trying to figure what buildings those are.
Speaker 0: that looks like someplace in the Bronx.
Speaker 0: I can't tell that looks brown.
Speaker 1: Those aren't familiar buildings.
Speaker 0: now that looks Bronx.
Speaker 0: He also be surprised.
Speaker 1: you can look at photos of me If you know, New York.
Speaker 1: You can look at photos in New York from like the 19 O's and if you see like one building or a street you recognize You know, I know where that is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because a lot of that stuff is not actually changed.
Speaker 0: Yeah In fact the things that change the most are just like the fashion of the people in those photos.
Speaker 0: The cars usually out the roads are in the old days.
Speaker 0: People are all wearing black suits and black coats and hats.
Speaker 0: No more nowadays They're wearing black suits and black coats, but no hat.
Speaker 1: the old picture will have streetcars in it and it'll be a lot filthier Yep, old enough.
Speaker 0: You'll get horses.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of pictures you can find that overlay like the old and the new on that that exact thing you're talking about Has been my thing of the day more than once.
Speaker 0: Yeah Though that kids afraid of ice hockey, I guess Jason mask hockey is pretty scary.
Speaker 1: But that was that photo was taken before Jason for he's existed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's still scary though.
Speaker 0: Sure All right Got a got thing of the day.
Speaker 1: It's also a photo gallery.
Speaker 1: Oh photo time Yeah, so I guess there was more than one person who did this, but this is the flicker account of the Bruce Sterling and Apparently people have been going in the Ukraine to the former Maybe current depending on your interpretation The president of Ukraine's vacant mansion.
Speaker 1: people are busting in and taking mad photos and you can see What the life of not a rich person but a wealthy person really looks like.
Speaker 1: dude has a boxing ring in his house.
Speaker 0: He has a 3d theater like the kind of theater you'd watch movies in but it had.
Speaker 0: it's gigantic But it has a grand total of nine Leather chairs in it.
Speaker 1: every room like the walls and ceilings and whatever look like an opulent museum room.
Speaker 1: you know of Middle Ages style with like gold foil leaf and shit everywhere and He's got like bas reliefs on the walls.
Speaker 1: who reliefs, you know of like guys, you know Greek dudes playing sports or whatever and It's pretty insane I don't even like.
Speaker 1: no matter how rich I was.
Speaker 1: if I suddenly had all the money on the world and I was just the king Everything I would still not live in a place anything like that.
Speaker 0: No But what I might live in is there's the Woolworth building.
Speaker 0: apparently the top like 30 floors are being turned into apartments and cobble condos.
Speaker 1: So they used to be the tallest building from what I gather a long time.
Speaker 0: what I gather there are 30 floors being turned into Condos.
Speaker 1: 30 apartments total 34 apartments.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So one floor is gonna be split into four and the other ones top nine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so some of the apartments spend nine floors.
Speaker 1: Okay with private elevators, yep, that's pretty typical.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're selling for over a hundred million.
Speaker 1: I would see I wouldn't even need that.
Speaker 1: I would need it most I Would.
Speaker 0: I would live in that nine floor?
Speaker 0: Monster apartment with a whole bunch of friends.
Speaker 1: maybe if I had every take a lot of people Apparently it wouldn't take that many people.
Speaker 1: I just most I would ever need to live in would be one room for like TV stuff Right like to sit on the couch and watch stuff and that room would probably have no windows.
Speaker 0: that I wouldn't I wouldn't.
Speaker 0: what I Primarily would need is a function space wherein I could have my own private like mini gaming cars
Speaker 1: like a room to have You know All my books and shit and sit quietly maybe almost on my desk of my computer in there a room with a bed in it and clothes and shit like that a Bathroom with a nice tight quality shower.
Speaker 1: I would have the best kitchen you could ever you'd ever seen in the kitchen with like a Big fridge and a dishwasher and oven, you know all that stuff.
Speaker 1: Maybe lots of counter space lots of cabinets more than one drawer A balcony or something like that.
Speaker 1: right a nice roof access a planetarium maybe no I don't need a planet in my own planetarium Window with some views a place to put bikes and shit and you know, maybe Building amenities like a swimming pool Scott for like 15 or 20 million.
Speaker 0: you could have that in a borough other than Manhattan today.
Speaker 1: That's I can have all that with like a house in the middle of I don't know Wyoming.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah If you want you go, okay.
Speaker 0: So if you move to Arizona and somehow still have income then yes, you could have all of that pretty cheaply.
Speaker 0: So in the meta moment the book of the book is a chemical for Liebowitz the precursor.
Speaker 1: actually continue reading it.
Speaker 1: You're going away another business trip, right?
Speaker 1: So if I read it probably I'll probably do when you get back.
Speaker 0: Yep Well, apparently the book club book is still wool.
Speaker 1: I Didn't put it on my reminder thing.
Speaker 0: I'm going to be in Istanbul for the first part of next week and I'm going to be in Munich for the second part of next week and I'll be spending A little bit of time in.
Speaker 0: it looks like Dusseldorf.
Speaker 0: So if you're in Munich, like I don't know Thursday I Pretty much have nothing to do but fuck around and hang out and my only real goal if you live anywhere near there Just take a train to it.
Speaker 0: my only real goal that afternoon is to find as many copies or at least one copy that I can do a high-res scan for Of the expansion to Hansa, Teutonica can't just find a scan online.
Speaker 0: No, okay people have been looking for it All right.
Speaker 0: Also, if you want to see us and a lot of other awesome people doing awesome stuff pretty
Speaker 1: much anyone that matters Kinetic
Speaker 0: on Which is a convention that we have a big part of and that we also perform at and have been going to for a very long time it is it is on its way to being the next Dragon Con like It's actually growing it.
Speaker 1: Well, it's similar to Dragon Con and that it's one of the only cons.
Speaker 1: that covers all areas of full spectrum geekery Exactly other other than that.
Speaker 1: It's not too similar to Dragon Con.
Speaker 0: It will be given time simply because the space it's in is hitting limitations already.
Speaker 0: So we're starting to spread out into the rest of the city of Hartford.
Speaker 0: That's true And for what it's worth the city is like.
Speaker 0: you guys are the only thing we got.
Speaker 1: so he's basically vacant cuz no one's here In downtown except during work hours on a weekday and you're here on a weekend.
Speaker 1: So it's a ghost town.
Speaker 1: fill it with nerds.
Speaker 0: So we've spread into like all the local bars and the theaters and all this stuff.
Speaker 0: I would not fly across the country or over an ocean to come to Kinetic on If
Speaker 1: I could use a train bus or car to get to it in a reasonable amount of time and I could afford a hotel that was within close distance and the badges I would go to it if I didn't have a more pressing schedule.
Speaker 1: conflict which there wouldn't be many things that would be more pressing.
Speaker 0: and Like we said it is the full spectrum of geekery.
Speaker 0: I cannot express to you the wide range of panel content on the at this convention now.
Speaker 1: that might turn you off.
Speaker 1: You might be being like well, I only care about games.
Speaker 1: So why would I go to this con where most of its gonna be other shit?
Speaker 1: I don't care about cuz I'm one of those non, you know branching out nerds.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what?
Speaker 1: There's enough of each thing that you can just do your one thing the whole time.
Speaker 1: if you're just like want to play fighting games Or whatever you can do that the entire time.
Speaker 1: at Kinetic on they're having some crazy.
Speaker 1: The con chair realize the League of Legends is popular.
Speaker 1: He's running this mega League of Legends tournament.
Speaker 1: So League of Legends is your thing.
Speaker 1: You can go to Kinetic on and play League of Legends pretty much the whole goddamn time and win crazy prizes.
Speaker 0: And if you care about things that aren't anime or video games I point out that there are very few conventions where there's any panel content, but the panel content we've got for those things is Above average compared to most fan cons as well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's like no matter what your geekery is There'll be a panel or two for you to care.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: We've got Power Rangers Q&A with some people who were Power Rangers.
Speaker 0: It looks like oh my god guess thing.
Speaker 0: We've got a hell hell which is basically anime hell but anything hell.
Speaker 0: Okay, we've got writing fiction through the female gaze team four-star I guess if you're into that sort of thing the early films of John Waters a sculpting workshop that you actually sculpt stuff in Money though right a little trivial amount of money.
Speaker 0: some Doctor Who some Sherlock a bunch of anime an Adventure time panel a whole bunch of guests anime directors.
Speaker 0: You should know juggling 101 Jojo's Bazaar Adventure manly poses and you okay I can't a full-on cabaret.
Speaker 0: That's 18 plus And is geeky.
Speaker 0: This is a pretty awesome kind of.
Speaker 0: you should be there.
Speaker 0: So Scott this was a crab people episode to be sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mr.
Speaker 1: Crab.
Speaker 0: so you said when we were talking about what did the show?
Speaker 1: I say that let's bring up the chat log.
Speaker 0: Oh, let's bring up the chat logs.
Speaker 1: that will kill time.
Speaker 0: that will exactly.
Speaker 0: let's see.
Speaker 0: I gotta bring up the chat log scrolling back and let me want to say once again This is the reason why I have a record of every instant messenger conversation.
Speaker 0: I have ever had.
Speaker 0: Since the days of ICQ.
Speaker 0: I have logs of anything I have ever said to anyone or anyone has ever said to me.
Speaker 0: However, Google's Historical archive search is actually not that great.
Speaker 0: Blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: You said I'll literally be dead before I get other chefs.
Speaker 0: These Stanley Cup.
Speaker 0: Okay, I was there was earlier in that conversation.
Speaker 0: Fuck all that chef puppet.
Speaker 0: What oh, okay.
Speaker 1: That's later.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's later.
Speaker 0: I'm narrowing in on where we talked about this.
Speaker 1: I Don't think we did a show about music.
Speaker 1: Sutton Sutton.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, cuz I thought we should do a show on music.
Speaker 0: Here we go Scott.
Speaker 0: Let's just reenact our conversation.
Speaker 0: Let's read our own lines starting from Okay, I'll start with.
Speaker 0: let's see tomorrow.
Speaker 1: I don't see you.
Speaker 0: Let's see tomorrow if they drop it.
Speaker 0: It's bits of one.
Speaker 0: That's the thing I said before.
Speaker 0: I said music and anime.
Speaker 1: I Don't see that either.
Speaker 1: Music in general is the date and time on it.
Speaker 0: Wednesday at 9 31 a.m.
Speaker 1: When Wednesday is what the 11th I guess yesterday at 9. doesn't this chat like not complete?
Speaker 0: what the fuck Scott I can read all of our lines All right, I'll read them all.
Speaker 0: then I guess cuz you you don't keep archives.
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 1: I'm using Google.
Speaker 1: It's it's a. it's stored in the cloud.
Speaker 0: Yeah, look look right here.
Speaker 0: Here's our timeline.
Speaker 0: Here's the conversation we had.
Speaker 0: Look at it right there.
Speaker 0: Let's see tomorrow if they drop before the game.
Speaker 0: We're talking about ticket prices to a Stanley Cup game.
Speaker 0: We should just go otherwise geek nights.
Speaker 0: and then Scott said, alright I found the same part.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I was about to do your voice in a really stupid and derpy way to annoy you.
Speaker 1: Alright, let's then you do my voice and I'll do your voice.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, if we can't get them at a reasonable price before work is over.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it.
Speaker 0: What's our show tomorrow?
Speaker 1: the Music in the a nine.
Speaker 1: did we ever do show one night?
Speaker 1: tomorrow is Thursday music in general.
Speaker 1: Eric contour Quote tenu who on the?
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 1: Like how we get news, how is baby formed?
Speaker 0: So I suggested We should do a show on the news like how we get news how we care.
Speaker 0: like what news do we care about what?
Speaker 0: Is and isn't news, you know that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: and then I kind of sub Text there.
Speaker 0: I kind of explained I'm reaching for a topic and Then Scott says and I quote I can come up with some topics that you have nothing to say about.
Speaker 0: Yep, and that is now the topic of the show.
Speaker 0: Do we do a showdown spelled spelled show?
Speaker 1: You can.
Speaker 1: you're gonna call it something corny cuz.
Speaker 1: that's your corny style anyway, so I can't really stop you.
Speaker 1: That's the name of the episode Sure Anyway, so yeah, it's like this, you know lately.
Speaker 1: There's been a lot of geekeries.
Speaker 1: I've been doing Rims not doing well lately.
Speaker 0: Scott decided that he hates German board games and hates video games and doesn't like to play any of them anymore.
Speaker 1: I just don't play him that often ever.
Speaker 0: When was the last German board game you played?
Speaker 1: I was a two-time.
Speaker 0: when was that?
Speaker 1: when we played it at Scott Johnson's house.
Speaker 0: Yeah at a party.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, what was the last German game you played before that party?
Speaker 1: What's that convention?
Speaker 1: we went to thank icon.
Speaker 1: so zenka That was too long ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah summer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was still summer is not how I would his netrunner account.
Speaker 0: Is it German?
Speaker 0: No, I said specifically German games.
Speaker 0: We're used to.
Speaker 0: we did a panel called German board games at kinetic on like 2006.
Speaker 0: Yeah So you said you could come up with topics.
Speaker 0: I have nothing to say about.
Speaker 1: Oh, so I should do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what's your topic?
Speaker 1: All right Let's talk about Gundam models that you don't build and have no interest in.
Speaker 0: I was really into models as a kid.
Speaker 0: No, it's always really bad at them.
Speaker 1: And I I'm Gundam model specifically.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Do you even know anything about them?
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 1: well, so one I know there's different grades of them, you know Can you name any grade or know the difference between any of them is here's giving me the fake nerd test.
Speaker 0: Yes But that's I can talk about the hobby.
Speaker 1: How can you talk about it when you don't even know the first thing about?
Speaker 0: well, let's see What would you say about it?
Speaker 0: Cuz this is the topic that you would do a show on.
Speaker 1: I could talk about the different grades Do it.
Speaker 1: Okay, so Gundam models, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, first of all, we got to start every topic the way geek nights do.
Speaker 0: No, right anecdote stuff.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: So I actually bought a Gundam model from the second Otakon that I went to did.
Speaker 0: Yes, and I'd sat in a box.
Speaker 0: I never built it and then I eventually lost the box.
Speaker 1: So you've never built one in your life.
Speaker 0: I've never built a cool.
Speaker 0: No, I did build the Gundam model that came with a new type that Emily bought once.
Speaker 0: Okay Well, I didn't.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I started to build it and then I lost a bunch of the pieces.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I started see Gundam models like started to try to come into the US like in the Toonami era and they had him Like the stores here for reals and they were like easy medium and hard levels and they didn't actually tell you the grades.
Speaker 1: Ah, well, we're like these Americanized versions.
Speaker 1: I never built them.
Speaker 1: But you know who built those?
Speaker 1: Tom Ian Harris built those.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so did Tom.
Speaker 1: like the first time I ever saw anyone actually building one was like I was at Ian's house And he was and he had one that was like half-built and I was like, whoa people actually do those things whatever?
Speaker 1: and Then it wasn't until I actually saw Gundam seed and liked it that I had any interest in actually Building or buying any of those things.
Speaker 0: I think of all the Gundam designs.
Speaker 0: Those are actually my favorites.
Speaker 1: Well, because when you like a Gundam show you tend to like the Gundams from that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I like the style of those like the way the wingy things were on the two important Gundams toward the end Anyways, the winglings at Otakon.
Speaker 1: was it Otakon 02 or 03 the first Otakon after Gundam seed came out, right?
Speaker 0: I think that was 03.
Speaker 1: It was early really early.
Speaker 1: I bought the freedom Gundam model that was on sale there for like 40 bucks, which is way too much money for that model.
Speaker 1: But that's what you're paying when you don't know better.
Speaker 1: and it's Otakon, right?
Speaker 1: And I built it and I built it not knowing the first clue of how to build these things.
Speaker 1: And I did a bunch of stupid shit that you didn't use the paint markers.
Speaker 1: I didn't even have the paint markers.
Speaker 0: Did you just tore them out of those little?
Speaker 0: Structures.
Speaker 0: so they had flash all over them right?
Speaker 1: So I went to like the regular old hobby store and I bought like test stores paint or whatever like, you know.
Speaker 1: And I tried to make the right colors.
Speaker 1: and then I put I tried to use a brush and just paint it on there And it's like nope that.
Speaker 1: and I soon as I realized that wasn't going to go Well, I stopped and I have all those paints still but I don't even they're probably dried out.
Speaker 1: Well, they've been sealed.
Speaker 1: Maybe they're not dried out.
Speaker 1: Since then I was like not trying to paint any of these things because that does not go well.
Speaker 1: So they don't ask me about painting.
Speaker 1: All I know about painting is if you want to do it easily and amazingly you need an airbrush with a compressor and you basically Mix the good paint with with.
Speaker 1: you know Some thinner put it in the airbrush and you first you spray primer on all the pieces you put the pieces on sticks And then you spray paint the you know, the real paint on them afterwards.
Speaker 0: So I do in fact have a very Relevant anecdote related to gonna models.
Speaker 0: Do you recall you know you're talking about how they were like They're trying to push into the US.
Speaker 0: There was an anime store.
Speaker 0: Oh, by the way There was an anime store that we would hang out in when we lived up in beacon years ago And then there was the ghetto one that was in the good mall.
Speaker 0: There was a ghetto one that well It was a good one in a ghetto mall and then a ghetto one in a real mall Like it was a store that had no business being in a real mall And basically this store.
Speaker 0: we're walking through the mall the real mall the normal mall Not the weird mall and we see a store and we're like that looks like a bunch of anime and Gundam models.
Speaker 1: It was the fuck.
Speaker 0: It was all bootleg crazy next to a gap or whatever.
Speaker 0: So we go in there and the guy sells two things.
Speaker 0: He sells Legit like for real Gundam models and he is super into them and knowledgeable about them.
Speaker 1: Too much money though, and he sold up straight up just like DVD our bootleg anime Like he downloaded from the internet put it on DVD printed DVD case Yeah, and he didn't lie about.
Speaker 0: I was like, uh, this is a bootleg.
Speaker 0: and he was like no shit Yeah, and I was like, you know, that's illegal right.
Speaker 0: and he was like, no one cares He was really adversarial about.
Speaker 0: I was pointing out that everything in his store was bootleg except the Gundams.
Speaker 1: Yep So the fact that that store exists, it's hard to bootleg gun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there's bootleg Gundams out there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm gonna look for them.
Speaker 1: So anyway So what I ended up doing was people don't know this.
Speaker 0: you buy Japanese Gundams bootleg Gundams for sale in the mall Whole rack of them.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, they look legit, but they're bootleg.
Speaker 1: Okay, that's I'm surprised.
Speaker 1: what factory is making this?
Speaker 0: Wow Looks like Chinese factories are just making knockoffs all of the legit ones Mmm, I'm surprised like they don't just fall apart or whatever.
Speaker 0: Ah The brand the brand of all of these bootlegs is Bong Lee and they sell them for about 2,300 yen.
Speaker 1: That's about some Gundam.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's the the one 100 scales.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay, so let's talk about scales, right?
Speaker 1: So the first gun I ever bought was a freedom Gundam and I only later did I realize that is a one 100 No grade.
Speaker 1: So no grade is pretty much just like you're the no grade hero.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like just yeah It's a fucking Gundam.
Speaker 1: build it.
Speaker 1: It's really simple, right?
Speaker 1: It's it's you know, and you can build any Gundam no matter how complicated with the with just the instructions Even if you read no Japanese whatsoever, it's.
Speaker 1: it's like Lego instructions.
Speaker 1: There is no language required like there's some Japanese characters like the decals, but you just match the symbols.
Speaker 1: You don't need to know what the fuck symbol it is.
Speaker 1: Right, you really don't need to read it all and some of them even have translations online if there's a complicated bit Which is pretty rare.
Speaker 1: So don't be afraid to buy any you know model from any country because if it's a if it's a legit one you can do It right.
Speaker 1: So the no grade is like really simple.
Speaker 1: There's like no details on it.
Speaker 1: There's no small pieces.
Speaker 1: It's lots of big pieces that go together really easily.
Speaker 1: if you just put it together You can put it together really fast.
Speaker 1: it like as easy as you can put together Legos, right?
Speaker 1: So the grades they have today.
Speaker 1: that matter is no grade, right?
Speaker 1: They have Hg, which is one 144. so 144 is actually smaller, right?
Speaker 1: Which means if you increased its size by 144 times, it would be the same size as a Gundam in the anime.
Speaker 1: I don't know how they measure that but I guess they do right.
Speaker 1: So those are actually the ones I like more now because they're sort of tasteful like the one.
Speaker 1: 100 ones are kind of big and sort of garish and then they have like 1/60 which are like gigantic and ugly and really should only see that.
Speaker 0: now you're getting into why I Pretty much never like.
Speaker 0: I always nominally had an interest in models.
Speaker 0: I would make a lot of non Gundam models for much of my young life Yeah But I was never proficient enough at it for the where they would look like they weren't.
Speaker 0: they wouldn't look good enough to where I would display them prominently.
Speaker 0: And as I'm older, I don't want to have anything I need to display prominently.
Speaker 0: I don't want physical goods.
Speaker 0: the Gundam models in New York would be a disaster as a hobby for me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing with Gundam models is it's like I really don't care about displaying them that much either.
Speaker 1: I just sort of put them on my dresser all whatever like not trying to pose them or anything.
Speaker 1: It's just way fun to build them.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like putting together Legos is the good part.
Speaker 1: then if you just have Legos sitting there It's like that's boring as fuck.
Speaker 1: You want to smash them and build it again or build something else?
Speaker 0: I think the way to really make that an interesting hobby again would be to make ultra high-quality ones and then pose them into sort Diorama and do different kinds of photography with it.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: You can do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah people do that.
Speaker 1: So right, so this HG which is the smaller ones, right and they're just about as easy to build as whatever.
Speaker 1: They're just small and tasteful and cheap and easy.
Speaker 1: So that's that's a good place to go.
Speaker 1: but Then is the master grade.
Speaker 1: master grade is like the fanciest right?
Speaker 1: It's the 1/100 size.
Speaker 1: So it's bigger, right?
Speaker 1: But everything is super detailed.
Speaker 1: You've got light and some of them even have crazy shit like LED lights or you know, they have like an internal skeleton and then armor on it and it gets crazy, right?
Speaker 1: That's like the most popular one.
Speaker 1: is the master grade whoo masters.
Speaker 1: then there's the perfect grade which is even crazier.
Speaker 1: It's usually even bigger than master grade and it costs like a zillion dollars to get one of them and it comes in a ginormous box and it's just.
Speaker 1: you know, the insanity of Gundam like Building one hand will take you all day or whatever.
Speaker 1: I've never even bothered to even care about any of those because I'm not spending that kind of money on a model like that Ever in my whole life.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So we've proven because the show is not about Gundams that you have nothing to say about this.
Speaker 0: I had plenty to say.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Well, let the listener be the judge of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so on my side Scott claims not care about politics at all despite bringing up Lawrence Lessig's super PAC In the earlier.
Speaker 1: there's no point in caring about anything else and as long as everything's corrupt as fuck.
Speaker 0: No, but the one the greatest thing I can say about Bob that super PAC is that Scott here actually donated money to it.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean the only chance we have to do anything ever.
Speaker 0: So so the other night I was hanging out You know online it was before bedtime and the news went apeshit or at least the news that I follow at apeshit.
Speaker 0: Because Eric Cantor, do you know who that is?
Speaker 1: No clue.
Speaker 0: He's the house majority leaders.
Speaker 0: So he is in charge of the Republican Party in the house Isn't the Speaker of the House in charge of the house is in charge of the house But that figure the house is a Republican.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so wouldn't the Speaker of the House who happens to be a Republican also be in charge of the Republic?
Speaker 0: You don't know how political parties are structured.
Speaker 1: Do you why do you need what is it?
Speaker 1: What is other person's responsibilities?
Speaker 0: Do you know?
Speaker 0: do you know?
Speaker 0: what have you ever heard of the majority?
Speaker 0: The majority or minority whip.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's usually why I thought that's when you're not in charge.
Speaker 0: What is the whip do Scott?
Speaker 1: So it's.
Speaker 1: it's like if you're the Democrats, you're not.
Speaker 1: you don't have the house seat right now because you're not in the majority But you still need someone to sort of be in charge of your party.
Speaker 0: So you think the minority whip is in charge of the Democratic Party in the house?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's like.
Speaker 0: you need someone to lead you and tell you know, yeah a minority leader, which is separate from the minority whip.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's hard to have an opinion politics.
Speaker 0: You don't know.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so he is why we should just ban political parties after we get rid of corrupt at money in politics You just get rid of parties.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the old there are arguments against removing.
Speaker 1: George Washington said we shouldn't so not yes.
Speaker 0: However, here's the argument that's usually given against removing part.
Speaker 1: I mean in the kind of government that we have parties will form no matter what we have.
Speaker 0: No No They wouldn't because the reason parties are so powerful is because the electoral system supports them with by kind of defaulting in the large parties into all the national debates everything and letting them control the debates and giving them official recognition and Letting them use our voting system to do their primaries.
Speaker 0: Imagine if the Republicans had to do their own primary on their fucking own with no help from the government at all.
Speaker 0: That is why we have parties the way we do, but if we didn't have parties then Individual people would have to become individually popular Mm-hmm, and in that case you're all.
Speaker 0: the argument is that it's too easy to have a government solely of attractive people ideologues demagogues People who individually can form cults of personality around themselves.
Speaker 1: now, there are clear problems with that But I don't see how that's much worse than what we have now.
Speaker 0: No, I kind of like the more Slight improvement we could go to the mix-and-match party system where like you have a party that cares about these three things.
Speaker 0: There's ten other parties and you form a coalition so you can form a coalition.
Speaker 0: That's pro-gun anti-abortion anti-religion socialism.
Speaker 1: but That's how Israel works.
Speaker 1: It's not good.
Speaker 0: That's how Europe works and right wings are coming up in there.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but also the Pirate Party has seen yeah, so I'm thinking enlightened despotism is really the only way forward.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I got dibs.
Speaker 0: So Eric Cantor what like?
Speaker 0: he's an important person.
Speaker 0: He wields power within the Republican Party and He like most other Republicans was challenged from the right in his primary.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm by some nutjob Tea Party person.
Speaker 0: yes, I mean Mitch McConnell.
Speaker 0: all these people, you know, their whole Republican Party is being pushed to the right.
Speaker 0: because Every time there's a primary now someone way to the right whoever is currently in office and currently running for the incumbency And will challenge them.
Speaker 0: So if the person who's already those people used to just run on some other party Yeah, so the org is not running or not exist party or something.
Speaker 0: So now The Republican guy might be like I'm against amnesty but for immigration reform and so for who?
Speaker 1: in what situation?
Speaker 0: Immigrants in a general sense.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Amnesty is just the term being used for that issue.
Speaker 0: Okay So then the right will come in and say we shouldn't let anyone immigrate here.
Speaker 0: my opponent a far leftist Wants to let immigrants come in and ruin everything you mean like your grandparents.
Speaker 1: Oh Are you a Native American Republican?
Speaker 1: because I don't think there's too many of those.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I guess that thing that that strategy was pretty well probably but yeah.
Speaker 0: So these crazy Tea Party challenges within the Republican Party by and large failed and No one expected Eric Cantor to lose his name.
Speaker 1: failed because he got a primary.
Speaker 1: the only people who show up are crazies.
Speaker 1: So yes, he's would vote for crazies.
Speaker 0: But the Republican money is funding the establishment Republicans because they at least are not stupid enough to think That those crazy people should actually be in office.
Speaker 1: but money can influence the general population in a in the real election But in a primary, it's just the crazies who show up.
Speaker 1: You can't really know money And especially in a non-presidential primary year like this.
Speaker 0: Ah, so money historically has always been enough to control the primaries.
Speaker 0: Upsets in primaries are pretty much unheard of in Republican land.
Speaker 1: How do you influence people with money in a primary?
Speaker 1: hardly anyone's there?
Speaker 0: It's like ten people, uh, you still won.
Speaker 0: you run ads and to you run and people are seeing those ads.
Speaker 0: You're on ads to target people who normally wouldn't vote in those primaries and get them to join the primary.
Speaker 1: So those ads are only on during.
Speaker 1: the price is right early.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I hope a whole bunch of crazy things happen.
Speaker 0: So Eric Cantor who was the shoo-in who was expected to run he was wasn't even really campaigning much.
Speaker 0: He was in DC because he's just doing like National Party Republican stuff.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm this nobody from nowhere Ran David Bratt.
Speaker 1: Okay, and he pretty much ran last name really brat Hard time in school.
Speaker 0: He pretty much ran on an anti-immigration policy and not much else.
Speaker 0: He had $500,000 if that in his campaign a lot of fucking money.
Speaker 0: That's zero money.
Speaker 1: five for Paul.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean if I had $500,000, why would I want to become a congressman when I could just live with?
Speaker 1: $500,000.
Speaker 0: Eric Cantor spent five million dollars on the primary campaign alone because it's a corrupt government, whatever Yep, and so I don't know he quit government.
Speaker 1: go live with his five million dollars.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's what he's gonna do in like four years.
Speaker 0: So basically he was or no because he lost right?
Speaker 0: He's gonna act as he was acting as though he's just gonna be in office.
Speaker 0: The entire Republican Party was acting as though he's gonna win the primary and he's gonna win the election because the district He's in is so heavily Republican.
Speaker 0: The Democrat has zero chance.
Speaker 1: Where is this?
Speaker 0: It's the seventh district in Virginia.
Speaker 1: All right, never moving there.
Speaker 0: So it gets really interesting here because Eric Cantor helped put forth the gerrymandering that happened after the last census Fucked up as gerrymandering to make these Frankenstein districts that are so Republican.
Speaker 0: They're invincible.
Speaker 0: That's the only reason the Republicans control the house.
Speaker 0: you realize in the last election The Democrats won the majority of the popular vote in house elections But yet they lost the majority of the actual body because of gerrymandered districts.
Speaker 0: Yep So this Frankenstein district is like plus 12 to plus 15 points.
Speaker 0: Republican meaning by default Republicans get an extra like 12 points above a Democrat regardless of all other factors.
Speaker 1: It's like oh the only people who live in this district are like hicks on farms the polls that the Republicans Commissions here to track this district.
Speaker 1: He actually live in that area Technically nominally own a house.
Speaker 1: I'm like a farm somewhere.
Speaker 0: He lives there by all laws that require him to live there to the letter of said laws.
Speaker 0: so One thing led to another.
Speaker 0: the Republicans were polling in the district.
Speaker 0: They realized that Eric was gonna win by shoe in.
Speaker 0: so they spent proportionate amounts of money.
Speaker 0: They were aiming mostly the general election.
Speaker 0: It turned out the polls were a hundred percent wrong.
Speaker 0: Well, the aim of the general election they're guaranteed to win Because they use that election to ensure like if they don't want to mess it up for one They don't want like something crazy happen there.
Speaker 1: But it's like if you have plus 15 points like rip Whoever the Republican is in this district will win.
Speaker 0: then the primary becomes more important because you in the general election They'll do spillover ads where they can use money nominally aiming at one person that's earmarked for one person.
Speaker 0: But they get this sort of splash effect of.
Speaker 0: they're also just promoting the Republican ticket as a whole.
Speaker 0: Republican issues in the state.
Speaker 1: So the corruption part.
Speaker 0: Yeah, lots of corruption.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so this guy came out of nowhere spent almost no money and Won by a lot.
Speaker 1: did he just get like all his friends from like one small town in the district to show up?
Speaker 0: So what happened?
Speaker 1: And there's only like a hundred people can tip it up.
Speaker 0: So actually don't.
Speaker 0: so blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: the number of registered voters in the district was five hundred and twelve thousand people.
Speaker 1: Okay, how many voted in the primary?
Speaker 0: The population is seven hundred and fifty thousand people.
Speaker 0: 130,000 people voted for this upstart.
Speaker 1: Whoa How does that even happen?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so they have open primaries meaning you don't have to be registered in a party to vote But there's no evidence that Democrats did what I tried to do in New York.
Speaker 1: You know why there's no evidence of that?
Speaker 1: because Democrats don't live there in The the weird-ass district so basically in shape so that they don't live there.
Speaker 0: all the tea party crazies in this Frankenstein district Saw Eric Cantor as a left-wing radical.
Speaker 0: they saw him as being too mainstream too liberal and they voted for nut jam and they voted for someone who speaks to their Conscience.
Speaker 0: and what this district proved which is kind of crazy Is that if you if a politician has a message that actually for real resonates with the people who actually?
Speaker 0: Vote in the area that can overpower money.
Speaker 0: Sure That really hasn't happened in recent history and the fact that it happened Basically, the Republican Party is like a hornet's nest that just got poked with the stick.
Speaker 1: who was managing this dude's campaign?
Speaker 1: like some really genius.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like the Robert coup of PR.
Speaker 0: no, this guy got interviewed now and it was the Sarah Palin situation.
Speaker 0: like he doesn't know shit about shit and No one knows anything about this guy.
Speaker 1: How did he get his name out in that district?
Speaker 1: But what what did he spend his five hundred thousand dollars on?
Speaker 0: Oh, so he went around talking to people and going to tea party rallies and all the a.m Radio conservative like radio crazies.
Speaker 0: We're talking about it.
Speaker 1: He was just on a.m.
Speaker 1: Radio all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah And FM radio and local conservative TV shows.
Speaker 1: Why don't we lie and pretend to be crazies get people to talk to us rather than the a.m Radio and get elected and then be like up.
Speaker 1: Sorry.
Speaker 1: It wasn't crazy.
Speaker 1: Just kidding.
Speaker 0: It's not a bad idea.
Speaker 1: You can do now.
Speaker 0: So the Republicans are going crazy because now like their whole structure is fucked and they don't know what to do about it And the Democrats are like we might win that election now.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know right.
Speaker 1: I mean if it's if it's a Frankenstein district Yeah, and the Democrats didn't vote for the crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there probably aren't any Democrats there.
Speaker 0: So the things that could happen?
Speaker 1: you think that all that you think the normal Republicans.
Speaker 1: there will just all those 400,000 you know registered people who didn't even vote in the primary Will vote Democrat now because the Republican primary persons are crazy.
Speaker 0: There are a few possibilities.
Speaker 0: the least likely one is that Eric Cantor will run in the general election.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you can do that.
Speaker 0: Hey, but by law it would have to be a write-in campaign.
Speaker 1: Really, I thought it's just is it?
Speaker 1: you can't just a rule of their party.
Speaker 0: Uh, well for the actual election you have you can't be listed as Republican.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's nothing in the law about political parties like that, you know You don't get either by Scott you realize and just make its own rules.
Speaker 0: You realize you don't get on the ballot unless you meet certain requirements.
Speaker 1: I thought it was just like signatures or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you're not the Republican nominee, then you need your own way to get on the ballot.
Speaker 1: But the Republican Party doing it the rules of the Republican Party.
Speaker 1: They can just write a rule like a bylaw and be like, yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: in that district primaries don't count Whatever fuck you.
Speaker 0: If they did something like that there would probably be a legal challenge.
Speaker 0: saying that would only apply to the next election And more importantly the Tea Party people.
Speaker 0: that would be like if Obama said I'm taking away all the white people's guns.
Speaker 0: the Tea Party people would probably actually pull out weapons and go crazy if that happens awesome.
Speaker 0: and So if he runs if he runs as a write-in campaign Then basically the Republicans will split the vote and the Democrat will win.
Speaker 0: so he's probably not gonna do that.
Speaker 1: He'd rather have the crazy person than a Democrat.
Speaker 0: The Republicans would because this is what this is all getting down to.
Speaker 0: we've gotten to a point to where Local elections in places like this is just the seventh to house district of Virginia.
Speaker 0: yeah, yet the entire nation was pumping money into this and Involved in this because all that actually matters is the number of seats your party has in the national house.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a national Senate.
Speaker 1: is what we had to solve.
Speaker 1: the election in Virginia should only be Right, at least was intended to be for Virginians.
Speaker 1: and what the fuck they care about in, Virginia, right?
Speaker 1: No What anyone else thinks who doesn't live in wherever this is in Virginia should have nothing to do with it should have no say should Have no input whatsoever.
Speaker 1: right and back in the days before Telephones existed that's pretty much how it was because even if you were mad rich or some shit You couldn't really do anything.
Speaker 1: Where are you gonna send your newspapers?
Speaker 1: to?
Speaker 1: the middle of nowhere, Virginia?
Speaker 0: No, I'll be the same time Do are not?
Speaker 0: because these are people are representing their same in the National Congress's the arguably many of the issues the u.s.
Speaker 0: Is facing.
Speaker 0: they are in fact national issues.
Speaker 0: and if you're gonna if you want to influence those issues You've got to influence those, you know the house and the Senate Right, you know influence them via.
Speaker 1: you're supposed to write on paper at least invite your votes.
Speaker 1: Influence those issues by the person who's from where you are By voting your representative not anyone else's representative.
Speaker 1: Your representative represents you.
Speaker 0: that's covered by representative.
Speaker 1: You just don't give a fuck because they're not representing you.
Speaker 1: give a shit what you say.
Speaker 0: My representative represents me because I vote in those elections Yeah, and then independently I have free speech so I can just talk about other people in other places.
Speaker 1: I Can endorse someone in Virginia sure but you you know It wasn't intended to be that way and technology has fucked it up and made it impossible not to be that way.
Speaker 0: How do we know it wasn't intended to be that way?
Speaker 0: How do we if we you I'd you know I was I don't.
Speaker 1: it wasn't really intended.
Speaker 1: It was more that it was impossible for it to be any other way because it you couldn't communicate.
Speaker 0: I don't think those things were intended by the founding fathers.
Speaker 0: founding fathers I imagine that document.
Speaker 1: they made it.
Speaker 1: they made a system under the US.
Speaker 1: It wasn't an intention like aha We don't want Pete.
Speaker 1: they didn't say that or think that right.
Speaker 1: it was simply that they made rules that worked given the you know Reality of the world at the time in which they made the rules.
Speaker 1: and the world has changed and the rules have not changed.
Speaker 1: So, of course the rules are now fucked up because the world is not the same as it was.
Speaker 0: in whatever ah Mechanism design the rules of the game are controlled by the people who have a vested interest in how the game turns out nowadays.
Speaker 1: So it's like if I invent, you know, let's say like the rules of poker, right?
Speaker 1: You don't don't see other people's hands.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, that's gonna stop working.
Speaker 1: the rules of poker Once I get ghost in the shell x-ray eyes suddenly, we're gonna have to change poker, aren't we?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So we're now in a time period where everyone has fucking x-ray eyes and communicate with the people in the middle of nowhere Virginia and send them money and bribe them whatever the hell the hell else they're gonna do, right?
Speaker 1: But the rule still said.
Speaker 1: the rule was made in a time when that was not possible.
Speaker 0: Wow, you said a lot of words.
Speaker 0: we're not having anything to say about this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I didn't talk about.
Speaker 1: he's only talked about one thing which is shit is corrupt as fuck Which is the only thing that matters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you keep worrying about like all these other things And I don't affect your life in any way whatsoever that you have no influence on.
Speaker 0: Right and I've got one who says I worry about them.
Speaker 0: I'm just informed about them.
Speaker 1: Why what does it even matter?
Speaker 1: Well for one could fill that space in your brain with something actually useful that could change your everyday life.
Speaker 0: If you look at the game of politics, it's an amazing game and I enjoy it.
Speaker 0: the same way I enjoy football Like I enjoy it more than I enjoy football.
Speaker 1: but football can affect your life anymore and you can influence football more than you can influence politics and Football can have a more immediate effect on you.
Speaker 0: I have money.
Speaker 0: I can influence politics more than I can influence football.
Speaker 1: I can influence football a lot by going to the stadium and yelling.
Speaker 1: I Football.
Speaker 1: if things happen I can get a parade which is a lot more than Paul we ever get.
Speaker 0: Scott We get parades for politics all the time.
Speaker 1: Those are shitty ass parade.
Speaker 1: That's a bad parade.
Speaker 1: That's a parade that blocks me from going to work.
Speaker 1: Not afraid that I go That's a negative thing.
Speaker 0: All right kids See you in a week.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: Yo, the beach is strong with a knighted long too strong.
Speaker 0: yo the beach is strong with a knighted long.