Speaker 0: It's Thursday December 11th 2014.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight buses.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: It was either that or torture, and you probably didn't want to hear us to talk about torture.
Speaker 0: It would be torturous, so I Explained this to Scott a while ago, and and a thing happened.
Speaker 0: this happened many times over the years where Scott asked a question and I Start answering, and I say a bunch of things and then later Scott acts like I never actually told him what the answer to that question was Definitely what I said.
Speaker 1: you were definitely saying something you said.
Speaker 1: I knew you were saying some words.
Speaker 1: I just not listening to them.
Speaker 0: You said what are you doing over there, and I explained in detail what I was doing over there.
Speaker 0: So what do you think I was doing in the hallway?
Speaker 1: peeing on the floor?
Speaker 0: yeah, so Basically what happened?
Speaker 0: we had some nice rugs that we used for the rabbits to run out in the hallway And there were nice rugs, and they worked fine.
Speaker 1: all right the rugs you talked about yesterday.
Speaker 0: I talked about them today because you asked me what I was doing and I assumed that you hadn't listened to me yesterday.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't listen.
Speaker 1: I didn't listen to you today is what I didn't listen.
Speaker 0: So we got these rugs, and I went to pick one up because it was kind of dirty And I vacuumed in it didn't quite clean it enough.
Speaker 0: So I just thought I'm just gonna pick it up and take it out and shake it on the balcony.
Speaker 0: I go to pick it up, and it's stuck to the floor.
Speaker 0: so I Investigate a little bit.
Speaker 0: It looks like the latex and other things backing on the rug Has just fucking rotted away and kind of fused to the hardwood, and it was a giant mess.
Speaker 1: Well didn't you know?
Speaker 1: that's one of those auto-adhesive rugs.
Speaker 1: it turns into a carpet for free now.
Speaker 0: so I Put it back.
Speaker 0: so I threw it away, and then I proceeded to try to figure out how to remove this Residue from my floor without paying anyone a lot of money.
Speaker 0: alcohol Yeah, no alcohol has no effect.
Speaker 0: I tried a number of different solvents and There here's what works best number one water Okay, number two which is actually a much better solvent and works super well Benzene which I'm not going to use because we know better now as humans not to fuck around with benzene.
Speaker 1: a dish soap.
Speaker 0: Nope, no effect.
Speaker 0: Ammonia of any none of those things any effect, but apparently turpentine is also super effective.
Speaker 1: How about your face just like get down really near and lick it and bite it and?
Speaker 1: It's not the worst solution, so it'll work slowly, but get the job toothbrush.
Speaker 0: so basically There's two rugs the other larger rug.
Speaker 0: I Have chosen not to deal with that for the time being and was leaving that rug where it is and the rug that already pulled Up.
Speaker 0: I've spent the last few days with up with water and A putty knife and a whole bunch of elbow grease.
Speaker 0: fucking sucks.
Speaker 0: However the good news is there's a chance that actually our renters insurance covers it.
Speaker 0: so if they do I'm Probably just still gonna deal with it myself And then we'll just make a claim based on the cost of the remediation and see if we can just get a bunch of money
Speaker 1: Mmm,
Speaker 0: or maybe I'll hire someone to do the second half of it.
Speaker 1: I just didn't get rugs and scratched up my floor instead.
Speaker 1: that won't matter until I move out in which case they'll probably just be Like we're keeping your security deposit like fine I don't give a fuck.
Speaker 0: you have the New York City our rug claws in your lease, or is it just our lease?
Speaker 1: I think I do.
Speaker 0: yeah a lot of New York leases a little insight into what it's like to live in, New York.
Speaker 0: They basically have this clause in most New York leases.
Speaker 0: that says something like 80% of the non bathroom Floorage in your apartment must be covered by carpets that are at least like 0.5 centimeters thick mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: The actual reason that's there so that they want to kick you out.
Speaker 0: They can go up and be like look They didn't cover their floor, and we warn them and they still haven't bought enough rugs to cover their floor.
Speaker 1: Why did I?
Speaker 1: why did I buy this?
Speaker 1: Apartment with such a nice floor?
Speaker 1: if I'm gonna cover it up Why did I buy this table?
Speaker 1: if I'm gonna cover it up with a tablecloth?
Speaker 0: It's kind of well.
Speaker 0: I only cover things with the tablecloth because the tablecloth is really nice to use when you're playing a board game.
Speaker 1: I cover things in the tablecloth because if there's gonna be like a huge mess.
Speaker 1: I'm not about protecting the table I'm about cleaning it up in two seconds by just throwing away the tablecloth away.
Speaker 0: Paper tablecloth you just take a fabric one just throw it in the washing machine.
Speaker 1: same deal all good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's fine same deal Yeah, so uh got any news Cap'n I do have a news.
Speaker 1: so yet again for like the fifth time in our lives Ye Pirate Bay is let down.
Speaker 0: however this time it might be the end.
Speaker 1: I mean it could always be the end.
Speaker 0: well No like one of the founders something else will come out.
Speaker 0: one of the founders I just got out of jail the one he basically said yeah, it was only intended to last ten years.
Speaker 0: The Pirate Bay has increasingly been funded by increasingly abhorrent ads So much more important than I could have ever imagined they would be.
Speaker 0: yeah that we need a new paradigm.
Speaker 0: So fuck it next generation pirate away in a new fashion, and we'll pirate away in a new fashion.
Speaker 1: No problem however.
Speaker 0: This is this inconvenience me in the short term because Most of the shows I'm watching ain't that?
Speaker 0: the?
Speaker 0: the pay for HBO thing?
Speaker 0: Still isn't actually available yet, so I really can't watch a lot of the things I watch except on the Pirate Bay.
Speaker 1: I mean I just need a new place to get torrents from.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's plenty of them.
Speaker 0: Torrance of what.
Speaker 0: what are you even watching a bit time?
Speaker 0: Yeah adventure time South Park South Park?
Speaker 1: That's the only things.
Speaker 0: really is Pirate Bay for the amazing world of gumball?
Speaker 1: don't watch that you really should.
Speaker 0: that's it.
Speaker 0: I love that show is actually one of my favorite cartoons now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though Rick and Morty you can actually watch for free at least Whatever.
Speaker 0: I can't believe you haven't watched Rick and Morty either.
Speaker 1: How much y'all pedal have you watch?
Speaker 1: 12 episodes shut up.
Speaker 0: how much Sailor Moon Crystal have you watched?
Speaker 1: one episode?
Speaker 0: Ah How much Breaking Bad did you watch.
Speaker 0: zero Game of Thrones zero all right all right?
Speaker 1: Daily show I watched like the clips when someone links to it John Oliver.
Speaker 1: They're all same.
Speaker 0: oh Crash Course none really really.
Speaker 0: you haven't watched Crash Course It's you know that chemistry show you like.
Speaker 0: take that make it a hundred times better.
Speaker 0: and about things you actually care about.
Speaker 0: I care about chemistry a lot, I think you'll care about the Mongols and Such much more.
Speaker 1: are they breaking down my shitty wall?
Speaker 0: But yeah the Italy.
Speaker 0: interesting to see what comes out of this because the one thing that the Pirate Bay did not do you know every iteration of Getting information to places for free in a way that doesn't require trust and direct knowledge.
Speaker 0: like you know.
Speaker 0: you can trust and direct knowledge with IRC if you want, but Basically every way has been has had like one Fatal flaw and we fixed fatal flaws along the way, but right now the fatal flaw of current torrents Is that there has to be a place where you find the tracker?
Speaker 0: So what we really need is the distributed tracker system.
Speaker 0: We do sort of have that that exists Yeah, but how do you get to the the entry point to a tracker?
Speaker 1: you have to you know figure it out?
Speaker 0: So there's a lot of people talking about making a tour basically a torrent web browser Which is the future.
Speaker 0: some smart person will make that unless the drink-or-die spirit is good and truly dead.
Speaker 0: hmm Yeah, so I don't think the Pirate Bay is going to bet on it.
Speaker 0: You want to bet if it's gonna come back?
Speaker 1: So here's the thing that's really interesting about how it went down.
Speaker 1: so the Pirate Bay claimed That it was up in so many places that were all secret.
Speaker 1: that you did.
Speaker 0: it would never be able to be taken But as far as I can gather is pretty much just up in Sweden.
Speaker 1: Yeah Secondly I Remember a rumor happening a long time ago that sounded pretty plausible right in that in Sweden similarly to the u.s.
Speaker 1: The people in the legislative branch like can't be like.
Speaker 1: if you're a congressperson in the u.s.
Speaker 1: You can't really be charged with crimes you commit in the Congress right.
Speaker 1: so it's like if you're just lighting up some meth in The Capitol.
Speaker 1: they can't do anything about it.
Speaker 1: so similar thing in Sweden.
Speaker 1: There was a rumor that hey They'll just set up the Pirate Bay like in Swedish government building which would have been brilliant, and they wouldn't be able to do anything about it.
Speaker 0: but no apparently it was in a data center in NACA.
Speaker 1: yeah that the the.
Speaker 1: When the news first came out they were like they they won't say where they went to go and take down the server.
Speaker 1: So I was like oh, maybe it was the Swedish government thing.
Speaker 1: yeah, but it wasn't.
Speaker 0: Apparently a Super Bay is down as well as is BAM.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well they were all running your lead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so BAM your leading site for digimon porn is finally gone.
Speaker 1: I mean imger really don't means you don't need BAM.
Speaker 0: Yeah, BAM was never actually useful from day one.
Speaker 0: It was just digimon.
Speaker 1: It would have been useful if imger did not exist.
Speaker 1: it would have taken would have been.
Speaker 0: no because even then it was nothing.
Speaker 0: But digimon porn it was hard to use doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter if what imger isn't about what's on there It's about you.
Speaker 1: use it for yourself.
Speaker 0: Yes, but imger was easy to use and it wasn't just a haven of digimon.
Speaker 1: maybe if more people use BAM.
Speaker 1: And because imger didn't exist a non-digimon porn fashion You're just obsessed with digimon porn.
Speaker 0: Go find the episode of geek nights where we talked about BAM when it first came into existence because we're I sort of forgot it existed.
Speaker 1: So they mentioned that.
Speaker 0: yeah, so did I because in that episode live I was like ooh This will be a way to destroy and I clicked on it live in the show.
Speaker 0: And if you and I'm pretty sure it was nothing, but digimon porn and I was like I gassed at this Yeah, and then we just talked about that for a while.
Speaker 0: Oh Pirate Bay you will either be back or Pirate Bay had the longest run of any of these things ever.
Speaker 1: the one thing about Pirate Bay That I will miss if it doesn't come back is that they would promote good things on the home page.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, that's how I found that this is what happens when you call the police music video.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: They live in lately like the front page of the Pirate Bay like promoted things that you know, we're good and then you know, we're.
Speaker 1: it was like basically the thing of the day of Awesomeness, yeah, here we go.
Speaker 0: Peter Peter Sunday the pirate.
Speaker 1: He's the guy who just got out of jail should stay down Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean he's basically like he's definitely quote.
Speaker 0: the Pirate Bay has been raided again Again.
Speaker 0: that happened over eight years ago.
Speaker 0: last time.
Speaker 0: that time a lot of people went out to protests and rally in the streets.
Speaker 0: today Few seem to care and I'm one of them.
Speaker 0: The site was ugly full of bugs old code and old designs.
Speaker 0: it never changed except for one thing the ads.
Speaker 0: More and more ads were filling the site and somehow when it felt unimaginable to make those ads more distasteful They somehow ended up even worse.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know who was running the Pirate Bay or how they got a hold of it But the people originally made it like Peter here.
Speaker 1: They didn't cover it in ads.
Speaker 1: They were doing it for the sake of pirating.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know how these other people came to possess it, but they definitely were in it for the money.
Speaker 0: Maybe therefore maybe the reason it was so resilient.
Speaker 0: You could use that money to fund a lot of different data centers and servers and shit.
Speaker 1: Maybe hard to say I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe yeah, maybe they just needed the money and they were to fund to keep it up and they were desperate.
Speaker 0: So we either need distributed torrents or any data centers on Satellites and on barges in international waters.
Speaker 1: Let's just code it ourselves or let's set up waste rewrite waste.
Speaker 0: Someone's gonna have to rewrite waste.
Speaker 1: if we why don't we get the guy who wrote waste the win amp guy?
Speaker 1: What's his name?
Speaker 0: Why don't we actually I actually forgot his name?
Speaker 0: So I feel really bad and dumb about that because he's one of the more important people in the history of the modern internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah Call him up.
Speaker 0: No soft guy.
Speaker 0: I'm just searching for null soft guy Justin Frankel.
Speaker 1: That's the guy.
Speaker 0: that is the guy.
Speaker 1: How do we call him up?
Speaker 0: I'm glad that null soft guy as a search actually turns it up.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: So in other news There's a bunch of news around the same topic and I don't want to cover all the ground We've covered on this before so I'm gonna skip a lot of things.
Speaker 0: I would normally say here So Scott, you don't need to be like ah this again.
Speaker 0: So one there's a new extension a Modern one for browsers that doesn't just block ads it clicks on them a random Percentage of the time and also acts like it downloaded all of them.
Speaker 1: So to cost the people buying the ads money up and to make money for the people who are hosting the ads.
Speaker 1: So you visit a website they get money.
Speaker 0: It also hides the fact that you're running ad blocking software because some sites now like disable functionality if you're blocking ads and Because it clicks randomly it removes or reduces the value of the data Generated from the ad clicks because it fills them with random shit.
Speaker 0: It looks like it'll even like fill out forms with random garbage.
Speaker 0: Okay, so that's interesting and a lot of people are mad about it.
Speaker 0: independently a bunch of French publishers are filing lawsuits against adblock plus.
Speaker 0: Um, you know the grounds the fraud and all the kinds of stupid fraud.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what are they committing?
Speaker 1: The growing rejection promise to block ads and we block them.
Speaker 1: fraud.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well that blocking ads while looking at websites is itself fraud.
Speaker 0: your steal, you know the same bullshit argument that just failed.
Speaker 1: I mean that could be described as many things but fraud is not one of those things.
Speaker 1: It could be described as accurately.
Speaker 0: so neither of these things is new.
Speaker 0: You guys may not pay attention because you just run adblock and don't think about it.
Speaker 0: Or I know people who are young who don't run adblock.
Speaker 0: I don't know how you fucking use the internet.
Speaker 1: I definitely don't know how to use it.
Speaker 0: Like I've seen what the internet looks like without an adblock.
Speaker 1: It's bad It's.
Speaker 0: I would not use it if it looked like.
Speaker 0: well not not the internet the World Wide Web Yes to be fair to be do you talk about this stuff correctly, but none of this is new.
Speaker 0: I mean I was running ad blocking software when I had a modem.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and I was also you.
Speaker 0: well anyway, so Coupled with all this somehow the advertising industries still make a shit ton of money with online ads, of course.
Speaker 1: So same way that spammers made a shit ton of money even though they were sending like Viagra Viagra Viagra Somehow.
Speaker 1: that makes money.
Speaker 0: So there are stupid people who click on ads and buy things from ads and There are also people who aren't stupid But they click on ads to give money to the person probably who runs the website they like and they're just stealing money effectively From the person who's you know, actually bought the ad.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That whole ecosystem is not changed in forever.
Speaker 0: But There's an article a couple articles that have come out recently that have done some investigative journalism and kind of pointed the same thing.
Speaker 0: It is likely that the majority of ad clicks at least in the modern internet are pretty much entirely from Organized crime run ad clicking networks that are part of giant global money laundering schemes.
Speaker 0: Because ad clicks, you know what this is like in the old days.
Speaker 0: if you wanted to launder money What's the most effective way to do it?
Speaker 1: Unless you're already rich and in the government open a business and then have legitimate Purchases on record for that business.
Speaker 1: Okay, like I need to launder a thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: Well this barber shop I set up that no one ever seems to come in Had like a hundred haircuts for ten bucks each thousand dollars laundered.
Speaker 1: all good the barber shop.
Speaker 0: That's the reason why especially in the 60s 70s and 80s.
Speaker 0: There were so many barber shops That somehow managed to stay open in the shittiest parts of town.
Speaker 1: But this liquor store just managed to sell so much goddamn liquor.
Speaker 0: Well liquor is hard because it's a physical commodity you're selling.
Speaker 0: the point is it's a business where there is no real way to Prove whether or not you're doing business other than a stakeout.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So in the modern world You don't need a barbershop because there are two things that are ready-made to launder money and there's basically no way to ever get Caught.
Speaker 0: number one ads online.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Number two DLC in Shitty video games.
Speaker 1: Ah, that's a good one.
Speaker 0: If I was going to launder money today I would make a free-to-play game that was garbage but had people playing don't care if it makes money or not.
Speaker 0: People who needed to launder money would basically buy cards with cash or whatever They would do to buy items in the game.
Speaker 0: My game company has nothing but clean money Except apples taking a cut.
Speaker 0: Oh, no apples taking a small percentage of my illegal free money To turn it legal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean that that is a good plan.
Speaker 1: That would probably work for I think it's happening.
Speaker 0: I think it is a huge part of the freemium gaming industry.
Speaker 1: Sure I'm dead serious, but at the same time If you did that it, you know.
Speaker 1: The one thing that our justice system is actually very good at is going after mafias.
Speaker 1: That's like their special move.
Speaker 0: They just arrested another Gambino in New York like today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all of the laws that we have like RICO Act, etc, etc.
Speaker 1: We're all originally designed to go after organized crimes, right?
Speaker 1: Which is why they're also good at going against gang because those are organized crimes and they're really bad at going against Unorganized things like anonymous.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah today looks like today 30 FBI agents and Italian authorities and Interpol Rated a New York apartment and caught one of the last free Gambino under bosses.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: That's how these look.
Speaker 0: It's counter-strike.
Speaker 1: Anyway, right, but that's like the thing that they are ridiculously good at because they were designed to do that.
Speaker 1: However, so that's why anything that they do that doesn't fit that they usually try to be like.
Speaker 1: there's a leader here Who's you know, they try to you know, make it so that there is some sort of organization or conspiracy or something.
Speaker 0: However, they can use their anti-mafia technology by doing this with gaming technology like DLC and in-app purchases and things like that.
Speaker 0: Technology makes it almost impossible to prove malfeasance because you are actually literally selling real things that are a legitimate Economy on their own.
Speaker 0: So it's almost as like you have a store or a factory that for free is Making things that you're actually selling for real money except that factory doesn't cost you anything to run.
Speaker 0: So it's free money laundering The tech and with encryption and deniability this makes it an order of magnitude easier to launder.
Speaker 1: Listen laundering money was never the problem.
Speaker 1: getting the money to launder is always the problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah However, they do that.
Speaker 0: I'm Convinced selling drugs perhaps selling community.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I really really really think that online advertising is hugely bolstered as an industry by organized crime.
Speaker 0: and I suspect if you are able to crack down on the organized crime that is likely Blondering money and or using this network for other purposes and get remove it from advertising That online advertising as an industry would fall fucking apart and there would be a big disaster.
Speaker 1: Well, they would still exist in you know cases where it's like the big companies buying ads.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's about it.
Speaker 0: But I think like a big chunk of advertising would disappear and the internet would just radically be Stabilized.
Speaker 1: for example things like the Pirate Bay that have a million shitty ads all over them that no one ever clicks on and everyone Hates.
Speaker 1: no one's buying those ads.
Speaker 1: You ever wonder why those ads are mostly for porn and casinos.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like That.
Speaker 0: Facebook ads 80% of the clicks are bots.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's about right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So all these things together are really interesting and this is a world that More investigative journalism needs to be done.
Speaker 0: I don't want to name names and I don't want to be guilty of libel or slander or anything.
Speaker 0: But there's some specific game companies.
Speaker 0: I actually suspect of doing this like for real.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day Scott's is super serious.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna give you the non serious one first.
Speaker 1: How could non serious could it be?
Speaker 0: So Jackie Chan Super funny dude super funny movies.
Speaker 0: I'm a big fan of Jackie Chan movies in general.
Speaker 0: I'm also a big fan of kung-fu movies in general.
Speaker 0: but this is a video where someone analyzes Jackie Chan films and Explains basically how to do action comedy why Jackie Chan did it very well why modern movies are awful at it and It's just a really good 10-minute video that goes into a lot of depth and was made by someone who's very observant very intelligent Knowledgeable, I
Speaker 1: mean really what it comes down to is that modern movies have an action scene and a comedy scene and they don't do Them in the same scene.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or even if they do do them in the same scene The comedy and the action will be not the same thing.
Speaker 0: They're not integrated.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like separate.
Speaker 0: There'll be.
Speaker 1: someone will like do some punching and kicking and then stop it like spider-man, you know Well, even the comic spider-man doesn't really merge his stuff
Speaker 0: But up there hanging then he says his witty one says
Speaker 1: his witty one-liner and then he fights and then he stops and then But his fighting itself is not funny Jackie Chan.
Speaker 1: His thing was his actual action of fighting was in itself Comedic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know what actually.
Speaker 0: our friend the juggler Luke Burrage explained this with a nice analogies.
Speaker 0: We were he was talking about doing a new bit and juggling and a bunch of us were like Ah, you should do the bit like this.
Speaker 0: and he was like you Americans You always have if you want to do a juggling routine You always think of it as you're gonna do some juggling and you're also telling jokes and things and they're separate.
Speaker 0: The whole point is that the juggling itself is the joke and you're augmenting it exactly.
Speaker 0: so this video is great and If you watch this This is why I don't find a lot of the action movies that you guys like to be particularly entertaining or funny Even when they're intending to be funny, I mean It's not like action.
Speaker 1: comedy is like a particular thing that I'm like mega into but it's just one more example of reasons I hardly ever watch any new movie ever.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean one of the like.
Speaker 0: it talks about how a genre of any kind even good like modern action movies in the u.s.
Speaker 0: At least usually have a ton of jump cuts and they do all these things to obfuscate the actual like Transformers.
Speaker 0: those see those action scenes in the Transformers movies are just a bunch of Nonsensical garbage flying around the screen.
Speaker 0: Jackie Chan is a long cut of him hurting himself physically.
Speaker 1: All right, so serious thing of the day.
Speaker 1: so I know a lot of people out there.
Speaker 1: They just so mad about politics and shit all the time and I'm just like shut up everybody.
Speaker 1: All you guys keep doing the same the same thing over and over again for no reason with no effect whatsoever.
Speaker 1: So I have found a key piece of evidence to support my position.
Speaker 0: Yep This video other than the fact that the word Negro comes out in the first 30 seconds Yeah, as does the words the word Arabia yep, but otherwise this video might as well.
Speaker 1: it is 1965.
Speaker 0: that wasn't that long ago as long ago.
Speaker 1: So in 1965, mr.
Speaker 1: X. Mr Malcolm X appeared on the CBC the Canadian Broadcasting Company and A bunch of white dudes asked him a bunch of questions a lot of back-handedly insulting questions.
Speaker 1: Pretty much the same kind of questions you'd get from a white right-wing dude on Fox News today But coached with a nice sort of Canadian sensibility very very masking.
Speaker 1: The one major difference is that unlike say a Fox News of today these white dudes Actually shut up and didn't say anything or interrupt.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: X while he was talking and mr.
Speaker 1: X?
Speaker 1: Well, I don't agree with everything.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: X stood for in his day, you know, I'm not exactly a Muslim You know quite the opposite in fact.
Speaker 0: So Pretty much is Judaism or that Judaism is the opposite of Islam the combination of the two.
Speaker 1: He pretty much argues his point in an intelligent rational Educated fashion the same way that we would argue our points in an intelligent rational educated fashion Even though lately I've been giving up and just calling people ignorant bad, right?
Speaker 1: Because it's pretty much no point.
Speaker 1: even though he did this back in the day on TV It didn't matter.
Speaker 1: All you're yelling and whining doesn't actually change anything.
Speaker 1: and that's part of what mr.
Speaker 1: X has to say.
Speaker 1: He says look, you know, I love Martin Luther King sand, but it's not getting anything done and all you guys blocking traffic.
Speaker 1: It's like look.
Speaker 1: I love you blocking traffic out there.
Speaker 1: I totally agree with you.
Speaker 1: I hate cars too, so I'm actually happy that you're fucking up the traffic But notice not a goddamn thing has happened or changed as a result of it.
Speaker 1: that is a tactic that is not Effective.
Speaker 0: thus the ever-present question whenever you bring up one of these things What is to be done?
Speaker 1: murder all the rich people?
Speaker 0: Pretty much out.
Speaker 0: Well, no There was a time in your life Scott.
Speaker 0: Yeah when you had a different answer to that question I remember what your answer used to be wait for the rich people and all people to die.
Speaker 1: Even earlier than that don't give a shit just live your life.
Speaker 0: destroy television.
Speaker 1: That's also a good move.
Speaker 0: That was we were pretty serious about.
Speaker 0: maybe a bunch of nerd terrorists should get together and just one day Literally destroy the entire global television infrastructure at once.
Speaker 1: The only reason that I don't think that's a good idea anymore.
Speaker 1: Is that if we used a method of blowing up satellites We really it was.
Speaker 1: it was hard for the space people to get the satellites up there.
Speaker 1: It would sort of not be cool to blow them up.
Speaker 0: think of the space people we need.
Speaker 1: We need some way to disable television besides blowing up all the satellites.
Speaker 0: I still think the best shot We've got is Lawrence Lessig's thing because as you can see.
Speaker 1: well I mean he is.
Speaker 1: he is correctly identified the ultimate root of the entire problem And but he has not found an effective solution because I don't know What did he say.
Speaker 0: the whole point of this first initiative is to try to find what yeah?
Speaker 0: Data and he just published all the data they gathered on to and how to mess with the light and it is now appears to be even more hopeless.
Speaker 0: yeah, because seriously the the gist of the statistics and the research was number of dollars equals winning election.
Speaker 0: Literally nothing else mattered.
Speaker 0: yes, so we need to gather dollars to fight against the people who have all the we only gathered like 12 million million.
Speaker 1: We're up against hundreds of millions.
Speaker 1: Yeah Only way that this can possibly be fixed is if one of the ridiculously rich people Turns coat against the other ridiculous church code.
Speaker 0: But does your classic cling to the other people and set themselves on fire burn their fortune?
Speaker 1: Yes, as well as their own.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so That was depressing.
Speaker 0: but also If you don't know a lot about Malcolm X which I suspect a lot of you young kids Probably they might not even know who it is.
Speaker 1: There is a movie.
Speaker 1: It's not bad It's pretty good, but it's not a hundred and historically accurate as any movie would be.
Speaker 1: but I figure you punk kids Who know nothing you know I'm lucky if I can get you to watch the movie.
Speaker 0: It is accurate in one sense.
Speaker 0: Malcolm X has one of the most intense facial expressions Generally that a human being is ever held as a resting face.
Speaker 0: Yeah pretty much In the meta moment the booklet book is water ship down.
Speaker 0: it's about a bunch of rabbits, and it's really good, and I've moved on.
Speaker 0: I'm reading the Yiddish policeman's Union, and I'll see if I finish that before Scott starts.
Speaker 0: water ship down, okay?
Speaker 0: Yeah We're gonna be a pack south presenting on Sunday in the armadillo theater bad games an updated version of our old panel also called bad Games.
Speaker 1: you can't make it to pack south magfest same weekend.
Speaker 0: Yeah, same weekend, and then not too long after that we're gonna be at PAX East and then the first weekend of March yep And tiny chance we're gonna go to generic on after it.
Speaker 1: I say that because we've not invited generic on every year of like a zillion years.
Speaker 1: I've never gone to it ever.
Speaker 0: well.
Speaker 0: I feel bad isn't it?
Speaker 1: a tiny college con?
Speaker 0: We actually don't.
Speaker 1: in the cold upstate I often don't even respond to emails from conventions that ask us to attend But they've kept us on their mailing list all these years even though we've never once responded to them.
Speaker 0: So I'm asking you the least.
Speaker 1: some listener went there once and that's why you the listener.
Speaker 0: I ask you Will you be a generic on and all being?
Speaker 0: Oh Rensselaer, New York should we go to generic on?
Speaker 0: it's up to you.
Speaker 0: Do you think we should be there?
Speaker 1: Because kind of thinking about doing it does anyone who plays netrunner going to be there cuz?
Speaker 1: then even if it's garbage You can save my weekend, and we can make it netrunner weekend Or we'll just play wizard over and over and over again.
Speaker 1: anyone who wants to play wizard will you go yeah and play wizard all Weekend if it sucks Otherwise?
Speaker 0: watch all their stuff on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Yeah, utenna, it's happy.
Speaker 0: yes, we recorded another episode of geek knives presents utenna.
Speaker 0: I'm editing it currently.
Speaker 0: I'll put it up as soon as I can, but I'm skiing Saturday and go to a party on Sunday.
Speaker 0: So we'll see when I actually get it done.
Speaker 1: break the world shell.
Speaker 0: Except the world shells cracking apparently according to episode 13 all the easier for you to break it actually.
Speaker 1: So get cracking.
Speaker 0: so Real talk guys buses Fucking awful.
Speaker 0: well mostly I mean there are occasionally good buses very rare and even then The best buses are at best tolerable.
Speaker 1: Yes the most.
Speaker 1: Basically the history of buses is a history of being bad on purpose.
Speaker 1: So I don't know if anyone here has watched Roger Rabbit the movie who framed Roger Rabbit.
Speaker 0: We did an episode about it.
Speaker 1: You should have seen it by now.
Speaker 1: Roger rabbit is actually a true story Not the anime cartoon part the the replace the streetcar with the bus part.
Speaker 1: basically what happened was way back in the day.
Speaker 1: There were streetcars everywhere, and they were fucking awesome and people use them all the goddamn time.
Speaker 1: so people who lived in cities Didn't own any fucking cars because they didn't need that shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just like me today right only a lot more people didn't.
Speaker 1: now in the city even on my street.
Speaker 1: sure I don't have a car But this car is parked all the way up and down the street and auto shops all near my right.
Speaker 1: so How did that come to be?
Speaker 1: why was the streetcar which is here just decades ago now gone?
Speaker 1: It was like every city.
Speaker 1: even medium and small cities like Rochester New York had streetcars, and they don't have them anymore.
Speaker 1: well what happened was is GM and other car companies in the US Realized huh we could sell a lot more cars if people actually needed them to get around and couldn't just use a streetcar.
Speaker 1: some shit.
Speaker 1: So they bought the streetcar owning companies which were private companies.
Speaker 1: They weren't like the MTA some public thing you couldn't buy and they just shut them down.
Speaker 1: and Then they said oh, I guess they had to replace these with something.
Speaker 1: They replaced him with buses.
Speaker 1: so okay people just use the bus instead of buying cars.
Speaker 1: What did they accomplish?
Speaker 1: Well number one since their car companies and not train companies.
Speaker 1: They made buses.
Speaker 1: They didn't make train cars.
Speaker 1: and number two it also You know buses use roads, and if they made roads for buses while you're making roads for cars Which is good for them yep making things like superhighways for their cars.
Speaker 1: and three They made the bus schedule since they own the bus companies Really shitty on purpose.
Speaker 1: and they made the way buses work.
Speaker 1: Just shitty on purpose so that you would ride the bus and hate it and then get a car to save you from the horrible Bus.
Speaker 0: and meanwhile even if they hadn't done that because of the rising cars the buses got stuck in traffic Thus defeating the purpose.
Speaker 0: buses are way less comfortable than streetcars because of bus suspensions.
Speaker 0: Yep, the everything is wrong with them.
Speaker 0: and now today I mean Scott and Emily and I live in literally one of the only places in North America You can live and not own a car and even then not all the parts of this place can be lived in without a car
Speaker 1: Even the rest of the world.
Speaker 1: somehow this problem spread because I guess you know they looked at us as a model.
Speaker 1: We did invent the car right the Model T and whatnot.
Speaker 1: so you know.
Speaker 1: but the rest of the world pretty much You know copied the model of America like oh you want to be awesome like America got have roads everywhere.
Speaker 0: so Gothamist Which is basically you should not read the Gothamist unless you live in New York But if you live in New York you will get the wrong idea about New York.
Speaker 1: if you read this without living here if you Live here, then you will understand these articles the way they are meant to be understood.
Speaker 0: These articles are this is real, New York for New Yorkers and literally not that context.
Speaker 0: you don't live here It's not for you Yeah But they recently had that they linked to the survey of like average bus speeds in New York two miles an hour.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so they listed like the buses in terms of how fast and slow they go.
Speaker 0: a good number of buses average less than two miles an hour yep meaning I Walk faster than most buses in New York.
Speaker 0: yep, and these are the buses I would take to like go cross town.
Speaker 0: I mean I remember once I was walking to the Javits for a New York comic-con and My options were fucking walk there or take the m42 bus soon.
Speaker 0: We'll have a new option the m42 go.
Speaker 0: yeah No, because we'll ever be m34.
Speaker 0: no I mean the m42.
Speaker 0: okay take the m42 across 42nd Street all the way to the end and then walk down a little bit.
Speaker 0: You get to the top of the Javits.
Speaker 0: okay way more convenient than taking the m32 all the way across or Taking the e train to Penn or whatever and then walk into that fucking underpass and then walking forever.
Speaker 0: And I remember I was walking.
Speaker 0: I was walking.
Speaker 0: I saw the m42 bus.
Speaker 0: I was like oh, maybe I'll just get on that That'll get me there faster, and then I like didn't have a metro car.
Speaker 0: and I was like yeah, whatever fuck it.
Speaker 0: So I just kept walking and yeah, I beat the bus there in fact.
Speaker 0: I passed a second m42 bus while I was walking mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So buses in New York are useless and the few people who have to commute on buses.
Speaker 0: I feel really bad for you if I had to commute on a bus in New York.
Speaker 0: I'd buy a car Mm-hmm like for real.
Speaker 0: I'd buy a car yeah.
Speaker 1: So the last time I tried to take the city bus The subway wasn't working.
Speaker 1: it wasn't going up.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: so I was here basically at rims house Effectively same area.
Speaker 1: oh yeah, and the subway would not go north to where I live.
Speaker 1: so there's only two lines.
Speaker 0: They go where you live.
Speaker 1: there's a bus that actually takes a more direct route.
Speaker 0: Yeah The bus that Emily always wants us to take to visit Scott.
Speaker 0: because on you know the buses route goes Literally right from our apartment to like right next to Scott's house like it's great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you take the subway the subway is a bit east from both of us.
Speaker 1: So I have to.
Speaker 1: then if I take the subway Which is what I usually take I then have to walk a bunch West to get to where I live the subway the bus Stops right at my apartment effectively like a block away.
Speaker 1: So why not take this bus?
Speaker 1: well I went over to take this bus and of course there was mad Crowding on the bus stop because no one could take the subway.
Speaker 1: And they were trying to do this.
Speaker 1: but even without that crowding The bus comes like once every 20 minutes or something.
Speaker 1: the subway comes like every Five minutes even less than that.
Speaker 0: yeah during rush hour a seven train comes every make a train comes in the train goes out another train.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like there's a train queued up to come in as soon as the next train land the train carries a zillion people and the bus Carries like 50 people at best.
Speaker 1: That's a crowded ass bus with 50 people.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you're lucky Maybe 30 people.
Speaker 0: and even then when you get on a bus This is the read that the biggest problem I have with buses.
Speaker 0: and why even if we fix a lot of the problems with buses this Fundamental flaw makes buses still a bad idea.
Speaker 0: do to ride a bus that you don't ride every single day.
Speaker 0: You have to pay attention For much of the time you're on the bus to make sure you get off at the right place.
Speaker 0: you have to know the neighborhood You're going to.
Speaker 1: you have to know where the bus stop is and push the thing.
Speaker 0: it's not like the bus Tells you where it is.
Speaker 0: you have to look out the way.
Speaker 1: I'll be like stop something something we are currently at this stop.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: you get to like know the bus route like it requires a lot of specialized knowledge And didn't be able to ride the bus It's not.
Speaker 0: or you have to sit and stare at your phone on the GPS and like watch it until you figure out where you Are and then get off at the right spot keep
Speaker 1: looking out the window And you see a stop and you're pretty close to where you want to be and you're like well Do I get off here or will the bus stop even closer?
Speaker 1: I don't know the streetcar the tram like even if I stay on it for you know it's like okay I'm really close to where I am now if I stay on how far past.
Speaker 1: where I want to go is the next stop.
Speaker 0: Yep, but like a tram network.
Speaker 0: leaving in Melbourne like we were there for Pax Australia last year.
Speaker 0: the tram network There is super extensive, but you know what?
Speaker 0: Every station like you knew exactly where you were getting on and off.
Speaker 0: It was really easy to actually ride it.
Speaker 0: as a result you didn't have to pay attention the whole time yep.
Speaker 0: So buses are super uncomfortable to ride from the fact that you can't just zone out on the subway.
Speaker 0: They go from predefined places to other predefined places.
Speaker 0: You can look at the subway map and immediately know how to get from point A to point B and take a nap Exactly and then get wake up and get off because a thing goes bong.
Speaker 0: The next station will be Grand Central terminal.
Speaker 0: blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: You know exactly where you are.
Speaker 0: Also the Subways are just generally way faster because they don't get stuck in any traffic other than subway traffic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're also way faster because they're giant awesome trains.
Speaker 0: Yep, and they hold a bazillion people Also energy efficient.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's talk about looting.
Speaker 1: well some electric buses out there like Seattle has the Catenary buses.
Speaker 1: yeah those buses and a lot of buses in New York are all like Hybrid electric butts.
Speaker 0: it's yeah, so they can recapture all that braking when they stop at every intersection for an hour.
Speaker 1: yes Exactly sometimes.
Speaker 1: There's a bus only lane on certain roads also.
Speaker 1: There's no one's ever parked in that or biking in it.
Speaker 0: There is another problem.
Speaker 0: That's kind of the.
Speaker 0: it's a touchy subject to bring up But it needs to be talked about because the buses suck.
Speaker 0: the buses are primarily used by lowers those Geoeconomic strata in most places in the u.s..
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: No, it's because the buses Well are.
Speaker 1: so in areas
Speaker 0: it has
Speaker 1: 22 yes in areas where people who don't have a lot of money live They don't build awesome subways, and if they do build an awesome subway there it gentrifies And those people get kicked out of that neighborhood
Speaker 0: like they just added a new subway.
Speaker 1: So on the seven line if you buy the Javits if you don't have a lot of money You can't really live in an area that's convenient by subway very easily.
Speaker 1: So the only thing that's gonna help you in your area is bus.
Speaker 1: oh and by the way you're poor So you can't buy a car or anything.
Speaker 0: So it is not a lie to say that in most parts of New York and most parts of America Buses are ridden by people who don't have a lot of money, which is highly correlated with things like crime.
Speaker 0: So a lot of shitty things happen on buses way more frequently than they happen on subways and trains.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's so.
Speaker 0: as a result as a person.
Speaker 0: I really try to avoid riding buses.
Speaker 0: That is one of the many reasons why I try to avoid your wealth privilege.
Speaker 1: Yes, you don't have to ride the bus.
Speaker 1: exactly poor people.
Speaker 0: if the subway isn't running I'll actually just take a cab.
Speaker 1: and if you did ride the bus you wouldn't have to ride in the back because you're white.
Speaker 1: What too soon Yeah, so I prefer the back of the bus.
Speaker 1: I never knew why anyone thought the front was better.
Speaker 0: Well, what about it?
Speaker 0: School buses?
Speaker 0: the back of the bus is the best bus driver can't fucking get you and you're back there.
Speaker 0: Let's try.
Speaker 1: ever can't get you even if you're in the front seat.
Speaker 1: What are they gonna do?
Speaker 1: get up and stop driving?
Speaker 0: You can rate how cool a kid is in the United States by how far back they're sitting.
Speaker 0: the coolest kid in any middle school Is the one sitting in that short seat next to the emergency exit at the back by himself?
Speaker 1: Yep, that is then when they get off the bus to go home They open up that emergency exit and jump out.
Speaker 1: and don't give a fuck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the bus drivers like get back here.
Speaker 1: Jimmy Joe it's like I'm in my house motherfucker.
Speaker 1: what you can do about it?
Speaker 0: Good what you're gonna write my head.
Speaker 1: You're gonna pick my ass up to go to school tomorrow.
Speaker 1: That's what you can do.
Speaker 1: Yep, you know, I'm about to play Nintendo games.
Speaker 0: Whoo Yeah, the kids sitting in the gimpy short seat at the back of a middle school bus is cock-fucking-robin.
Speaker 1: That's right Because if he wasn't the kid who was it beat him up and kick him out and get him.
Speaker 0: Though it's complicated because then after you get a few seats up the kids who were like three or four rows up are the least Cool kids who are trying to be with the cool kids.
Speaker 0: Yeah And then at the way front are the cool kids who are smart and don't want to be bullied by the shitheads near the back The middle distance.
Speaker 1: people are just like the normal kids who don't give a fuck about social whatever.
Speaker 1: They're just going to school and they're out.
Speaker 1: Those are the normal cool people.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, that's that's a lesson in middle school.
Speaker 0: So there are some buses that are quality like the Express buses that go directly from like a neighborhood in Connecticut to Midtown, right?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean those are okay, but they're like, you know, for example the boat bus, right?
Speaker 0: It's it's a bus is barely tolerable and getting worse It's.
Speaker 1: uh, I mean it is getting worse, but it's at least you know, it gets the job done.
Speaker 1: I need to get to that city for an extremely low price.
Speaker 1: It will mostly much more safely than say shady Chinatown bus which are all gone now.
Speaker 1: Yes, thankfully take me to that city in a reasonable fashion I won't have to.
Speaker 1: a lot of the problems that you talked about don't exist on there.
Speaker 0: Like the few times he took mega buses like shit like a couple of times shit went down when I was not a mega bus.
Speaker 0: that Would not have happened on a bolt bus.
Speaker 1: Yep, but functionally the reason is you have to buy your boat bus ticket on internet.
Speaker 0: yep, and somehow people haven't figured out how to get that fries a Priority boarding.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The answer is if you buy it online you get a.
Speaker 1: no you get a. if you register and log into the Bolt bus website then buy the ticket.
Speaker 1: if you just buy the ticket as like a guest without logging in then you don't get a. You get B or C.
Speaker 0: and meanwhile I was amazed at all these people who like line up without a ticket like trying to get onto the bus in case someone like Doesn't show up.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Like everywhere I travel like at airports at train stations.
Speaker 0: So many people are at an airport or a train station on standby.
Speaker 1: I don't understand how that happens.
Speaker 1: I've never had to be on standby in my life.
Speaker 0: The only time I was ever on standby was when the only time I can airlines like all their staff went on strike and they canceled Every flight.
Speaker 1: the only time I can imagine this happening is literally if my flight got canceled in which case I would go to the Counter and be like look my flight was canceled.
Speaker 1: I gave you fucking money.
Speaker 1: You're gonna fly me where I want to go.
Speaker 1: When is that gonna happen?
Speaker 1: And they would tell me if they said I don't know I would go to a hotel Immediately.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then wait and make phone calls when appropriate and cetera until you know We had Scott.
Speaker 0: that is that is the privilege of someone who has money and is willing to suffer any amount of financial.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna make them pay for that hotel room - yeah, I'm not paying for that and then follow it up with righteous indignation.
Speaker 1: Yes, exactly.
Speaker 1: So, I mean, there's no reason me to stand at the airport on standby for anything.
Speaker 1: I guess there could be some emergency.
Speaker 1: We're like.
Speaker 1: I just have to get to Saskatchewan like it like today and then there's no way I could buy it.
Speaker 1: I just gotta go to the airport.
Speaker 0: No, you know what I would do.
Speaker 0: I Like if you can't like if you can't fly and like standbys.
Speaker 0: not I'm the kind of person who's rent a car and drive Right out of the airport.
Speaker 1: we could do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I did From here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if we drove in shifts we could be there and if I had to guess two or three days No, we could do a faster than that.
Speaker 1: if I need to be there I drove.
Speaker 0: we fucking.
Speaker 0: it takes two days to drive from Detroit to like the middle of Florida If you drive in shifts and with some sleeping.
Speaker 0: so we could totally get to Saskatchewan Inside of two days.
Speaker 1: if we drove in shifts and never saw this mad bad weather right now, and it's Canada.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Canada knows that deal with bad weather.
Speaker 0: I grew up in Michigan.
Speaker 0: I could drive in bad weather's fine.
Speaker 0: Where are we gonna rent a car that has snow chains in the trunk?
Speaker 0: Do you know how to put snow chains on?
Speaker 1: I know how to Google and watch a YouTube video showing me how to do it.
Speaker 0: So the you know, it's funny because you brought up bolt bus and like I said mega bus and all these things.
Speaker 0: There's another bus like that.
Speaker 0: In fact, I'm riding one on Saturday urban Sherpa in New York.
Speaker 0: I can pay somebody like 60 bucks and they will at 6 a.m You pay 60 bucks for that.
Speaker 1: now, I don't feel bad about things.
Speaker 1: I've wasted 60 bucks.
Speaker 0: They picked me up in Times Square Drive me to Hunter Mountain and drop me off at the ski mountain and then at 4 30 p.m Drive me back to Times Square and drop me off.
Speaker 1: There's no white privilege bus like a bus going to a ski resort.
Speaker 0: So from New York City, this is what I'm getting at New York's like bolt bus kind of like jet-blue all these things.
Speaker 0: They exist because of New York, they don't exist anywhere else.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they exist somewhere else.
Speaker 1: new most cities
Speaker 0: do not have the kinds of buses that we have access to here Mmm, like if you want to take a bus to somewhere outside of New York That isn't serviced by like bolt bus one almost no one goes there and two you're on fucking Peter Pan and that bus is just a Eight-hour nightmare.
Speaker 1: Yeah something else though.
Speaker 1: I think other countries Some of them, you know, especially the nice ones have much better buses than we have.
Speaker 0: Yes, they do That is true.
Speaker 1: If we if we go to like Asia's or Europe's or you know places like that.
Speaker 1: I'm sure that they have buses that are like they go on.
Speaker 0: Hey, we're just talking about American buses.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it's a lot of those are just indicative of the.
Speaker 1: you know You can see how just talking about one thing the bus.
Speaker 1: We're really just talking about the problems of America.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're just all appear on the bus To get more.
Speaker 0: because I was talking about like the privilege of these buses networks we have in New York.
Speaker 0: our Friends like we go to conventions and we take bolt bus to a lot of the conventions we go to because it's just like it Goes.
Speaker 0: it's the best way It'll pick us up in New York and go directly to like the convention.
Speaker 1: So the bus that goes to Boston is pretty much a few blocks away from PAX East.
Speaker 1: Yes, you can walk.
Speaker 1: it's so great.
Speaker 0: Our friends are all like oh how you guys get into PAX and for them taking a bus is a nightmare Because both bus doesn't go direct from where they live to Boston.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we live in New York City.
Speaker 1: They live like even if you live in White Plains pretty close to New York City You're gonna what you knew you did come to New York City on Metro north and then take but it's like and there's no transportation directly from there too.
Speaker 0: So instead like pretty much for all of them driving is the best option except then they got a park and park is like 60 Bucks a day for like Boston.
Speaker 0: Yeah 60 bucks a day is a pretty low-end price.
Speaker 1: to park Bus cost me like me possibly $1 each way if I buy my ticket early enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I usually like 12 bucks each way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: So so Buses work like there's buses and all these mass transit options related to buses that we have here Don't exist in most of the rest of New York because there is such a demand for mass transit.
Speaker 0: But at the same time we won't build it and as a result buses For the vast majority of humans who will ever ride them who don't live in New York City.
Speaker 0: fucking nightmares.
Speaker 0: Yep Yep, like I if my only option is a bus I either won't go or I'll rent a car most of the time and most of the country.
Speaker 1: Right pretty much anywhere you live in the United States.
Speaker 1: Like I don't think there's been a civilized place I've lived where there isn't actually like a bus system.
Speaker 1: it's like there's no other public transportation usually except outside of major cities, but even near my parents house or You know out in all kinds of middle-of-nowhere places There's still some sort of bus system and some sort of bus stop like remember we live in Rochester, right?
Speaker 0: Remember when we didn't have a car as freshman we wanted by.
Speaker 1: Rochester doesn't have a subway or anything, but they have buses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it would take us half a day to buy groceries by using that bus.
Speaker 0: That bus took for fucking ever and then we had to carry all our groceries on the bus.
Speaker 1: It was awful, but we did a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it sucked but Wegmans was nice.
Speaker 0: And then you know as soon as we were sophomores, I had a car.
Speaker 0: I drove Everyone we knew to the grocery store Everyone.
Speaker 0: repeatedly I was I bought me driving people around was how I afforded gas.
Speaker 0: so But beyond that our friend Luke, I remember he was like, ah, the bus is fine You need to own a car in Rochester.
Speaker 0: and then one day I was like Luke How long does it take you to get to work?
Speaker 0: How long does it actually take you door-to-door?
Speaker 0: and he was like like an hour and a half It's not that bad and one he was lying.
Speaker 0: It actually took like two and a half hours and two.
Speaker 0: It sucked and he hated it.
Speaker 0: But he couldn't admit to it because he already committed to this.
Speaker 1: buses are okay position and if you use the car to make that Trip, it was like 15 minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah If there's traffic 20 minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if there's you can pretty much cross all of Rochester in like a half hour.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like it took us half a day to do grocery shopping.
Speaker 0: I could drive To the Wegmans and back including grocery shopping 10 15 minutes Including the grocery shopping 45 minutes, maybe how many groceries you getting?
Speaker 1: I mean like I'm talking like you're getting an orangey and running out so that I'll get an orgy running out.
Speaker 0: I would just drive to.
Speaker 1: Actually, the Wegmans you went to didn't have any orangey.
Speaker 0: That's a different Wegmans and that usually took all night.
Speaker 0: Then again in the morning.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think is This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: I hate the sky dome and the CN Tower - I hate Nathan Phillips square in the Ontario zoo.
Speaker 1: The rents too high the air's unclean The beaches are dirty and the people are mean and the women are big and the men are dumb.
Speaker 1: And the children are loopy because they live in a slum The water is polluted and the mayor's a dork.
Speaker 1: they dress real bad and they think they're New York in Toronto Ontario.