Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, January 7th, 2014.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, you got it right.
Speaker 1: I'm Rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Night.
Speaker 1: Scott, I think, was betting with himself on that.
Speaker 1: And tonight, we're talking about the games of MAGFest 11?
Speaker 0: MAGFest 2014.
Speaker 1: The 11th MAGFest.
Speaker 0: I think it might be more than the 11th MAGFest.
Speaker 1: Maybe the 12th MAGFest.
Speaker 1: We went to 9, 10-- I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think it may have been the 12th.
Speaker 1: The most recent MAGFest.
Speaker 0: 2014 MAGFest.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: I'm almost relieved that we don't have any conventions until PAX East.
Speaker 0: You skipped my opening bit.
Speaker 0: You know what my opening bit is?
Speaker 1: What was your opening bit?
Speaker 0: Woman?
Speaker 1: It's warm today.
Speaker 0: It's a little bit warm today.
Speaker 0: We didn't do anything nice.
Speaker 0: Only relatively speaking.
Speaker 1: Now, I just want to point out that it wasn't that cold in New York.
Speaker 0: Compared to other places, it wasn't as cold in New York.
Speaker 0: It was still fucking cold.
Speaker 1: But it was not below zero Fahrenheit, because growing up in Detroit-- It came close.
Speaker 0: We were in the single digits Fahrenheit.
Speaker 1: We hit four.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I will admit that four is pretty nippy.
Speaker 0: Only pretty nippy?
Speaker 1: Well, it was funny.
Speaker 0: It's ridiculously cold.
Speaker 1: So I did not-- my life, I think about these things.
Speaker 1: You have hair.
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 1: Hair that I wash in the morning so it gets wet.
Speaker 0: Dry it before you go outside.
Speaker 1: That takes too long.
Speaker 1: You know what I did?
Speaker 1: I did not wash my hair in the morning for three days.
Speaker 0: Hair makes a big difference.
Speaker 0: I was really cold.
Speaker 1: Also hats.
Speaker 1: So when I walked outside, one, I didn't get my hair wet, because a group in Michigan went to school in Rochester.
Speaker 1: I've experienced frozen head hair.
Speaker 1: It's not pleasant.
Speaker 1: I get down to the street, and I start walking toward the subway, and there's a cop.
Speaker 1: And he stops a guy who's walking out of his apartment.
Speaker 1: And he's like, yo, dog, you should put on a hat.
Speaker 1: And the guy's like, what?
Speaker 1: It's not that cold.
Speaker 1: Then he kind of pauses, and the cop's like, you're going to get frostbite.
Speaker 1: And the guy's like, yeah, and he goes back inside.
Speaker 1: But there were actually cops going around telling people.
Speaker 1: That was the thing I saw people tweeting about, to put on hats, because it was cold enough to get frostbite if you live too far from the subway.
Speaker 0: I did not witness that.
Speaker 1: Maybe it was just your neighborhood?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: There's a lot more cops in my neighborhood, because there's that bridge thing right there.
Speaker 1: Like, there's the cop every day.
Speaker 0: Forcing people-- No, the traffic cops.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they talk to people.
Speaker 1: Like, they hang out.
Speaker 0: When I bike in the summer, past traffic cops and crossing guards, they talk to you.
Speaker 0: They try to.
Speaker 1: Try to?
Speaker 1: I imagine, yo, asshole, you're the-- hey, you can't go there.
Speaker 0: Something like that.
Speaker 1: So yeah, we're back.
Speaker 1: We're bad.
Speaker 1: I don't expect there'll be that many interruptions to Geek Nights for a few months.
Speaker 0: PAX East.
Speaker 1: PAX East is in April?
Speaker 0: I thought it was March.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: So why-- it's a ways out.
Speaker 0: Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Anime Boston, still got to submit panels to.
Speaker 1: What else?
Speaker 1: What other cons?
Speaker 1: PAX Prime, I guess.
Speaker 0: When's Zenkai Con?
Speaker 1: Sometime in the summer.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: We're committed to going.
Speaker 0: Are we?
Speaker 1: No, yeah.
Speaker 1: We're doing like four panels.
Speaker 0: I see a bucket.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't see a bucket.
Speaker 0: I see a pail and a word that rhymes with it.
Speaker 1: We also-- oh, it's this weekend, maybe?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Not doing anything this weekend except watching footballs and maybe baking some breads.
Speaker 1: You want to do some video or some game streaming?
Speaker 0: Does it involve football or warm bread?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: People really-- the antenna videos are starting to get some views.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: We should do that.
Speaker 0: But it's cold.
Speaker 1: It's going to be like 50 fucking degrees this weekend.
Speaker 0: It's going to rain.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: I'm going to bike on Saturday.
Speaker 1: Fuck y'all.
Speaker 0: I saw a dude biking this morning.
Speaker 1: Scott, two days ago, I was walking home wearing my heaviest jacket thinking to myself, fuck, fuck, walk real slow.
Speaker 1: Don't let the cold air in.
Speaker 1: I saw a dude wearing tights and a ski jacket running.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I see people running a lot.
Speaker 0: Running is one thing.
Speaker 1: It was six degrees.
Speaker 0: Running heats you up.
Speaker 0: Biking, it's like when you just-- it's like there's a fan blowing on you.
Speaker 0: You're creating your own wind chill.
Speaker 1: So Scott, I know you don't ski, but I'll say one thing.
Speaker 1: When I go skiing-- Same shit happens?
Speaker 1: So the temperature on the ground in the wind during the cold snap in New York was about the temperature I experienced on top of the mountains.
Speaker 0: Oh, another reason not to ski.
Speaker 0: Cool.
Speaker 1: So the problem is you get to the top of the mountain and it's that cold and it's windy.
Speaker 1: So you start skiing and your face starts to freeze.
Speaker 0: But then you're going down the mountain.
Speaker 0: It's getting warmer.
Speaker 1: So as you're going down, you're getting warmer.
Speaker 1: And you're exerting yourself.
Speaker 1: So by the bottom, you're so hot you want to take your coat off.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we're back.
Speaker 1: All that stuff.
Speaker 1: So I got a Geek Bite.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you have any news or anything.
Speaker 0: I have news.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of news, but I'll do my Geek Bite really quick.
Speaker 1: I played The Stanley Parable.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's really worth doing a whole show on unless we do a broader topic about that kind of game.
Speaker 0: I played the demo.
Speaker 0: That's the one where you walk around the hallways in the Half-Life engine and it just the guy tells you what to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so fuck the demo.
Speaker 1: Play the full game.
Speaker 1: It added a lot and really, really polished it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I played it a long time ago and then it's ignored.
Speaker 1: If I had to summarize this game, and Scott can talk about it because he played the demo, this is just more than the demo.
Speaker 0: It's like Bastion, the FPS, without the action.
Speaker 1: You know what it is?
Speaker 1: It's what Elevator Source should have been.
Speaker 1: It's the same kind of game as Elevator Source.
Speaker 0: It's an experience.
Speaker 0: It's a game.
Speaker 0: It's an entertainment software?
Speaker 1: Yes, interactive amusement.
Speaker 1: I would argue that it fits into our definition of ideal game.
Speaker 1: Because you play through the game and your decisions affect your personal outcome.
Speaker 1: Play the game again.
Speaker 1: Different decisions make a different outcome.
Speaker 0: This is only a limited set of outcomes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all games have a limited set of outcomes.
Speaker 1: The universe has quanta.
Speaker 0: NetHack has an effectively infinite set of outcomes, as does Dwarf Wars.
Speaker 1: But it is technically limited.
Speaker 0: Technically.
Speaker 1: There is a limit.
Speaker 1: The Stanley Parable, Scott, the new version, has more outcomes than you would expect.
Speaker 1: And they're subtle.
Speaker 0: Does it have more than Chrono Trigger?
Speaker 1: I'll put it this way.
Speaker 1: I played it for two hours, and I saw all the outcomes I cared to, and at no point did anything repeat.
Speaker 1: And what amazed me about this game, or I guess what surprised me, I shouldn't say amazed, is the number and variety of ways the narrator would react to things I did that I did not expect him to react to.
Speaker 1: And also the fact that in the kind of remade game, there's a very ominous feeling.
Speaker 1: Like, the game almost feels sinister.
Speaker 0: It felt sinister when I played it originally.
Speaker 1: The directions you take and where you go.
Speaker 1: I don't want to spoil it at all, but it's a game that everyone should experience.
Speaker 1: It is an interactive amusement that is highly amusing.
Speaker 1: And the moment that got me, as I walk around, and I'm doing stuff, and basically just this game, you get this experience, and you're walking, and eventually there's a choice.
Speaker 1: There's two doors, and the narrator is kind of describing, "Stanley got up and walked around, "and Stanley decided to go into the door on the
Speaker 1: left.".
Speaker 0: - And you don't have to go in the door on the left.
Speaker 1: - And I go into the door on the right, and things go off the rails.
Speaker 0: - Well, just go in the door on the left.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, and if you do that, it's just that.
Speaker 1: So, what surprised me was how reactive the moderator was to me.
Speaker 1: Like, at one point, I walked into a place, and I'm just kind of hanging out in there, looking around, and then the narrator's like, "There's really nothing to do in this room.
Speaker 1: "Stanley really should just get on with his
Speaker 1: journey.".
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: You're going to stay in that room?
Speaker 1: Well, fine.
Speaker 1: Stuff happens.
Speaker 1: So, I got to a point where there's a room, and there's a phone, and it's ringing, and it's like, "Stanley was about to embark "on the great journey,".
Speaker 1: and then I understand this long thing.
Speaker 1: So, I see there's a cord, so I run around the room, just click on everything, and I click on the cord, and it just unplugs the phone, and it stops ringing, and then the narrator's like, "Really?
Speaker 1: "Really?
Speaker 1: "Well,
Speaker 1: fuck.".
Speaker 1: It's really funny.
Speaker 1: It is as funny as Portal, but there isn't a, there's no skill game in there.
Speaker 1: It's Portal without the game part, but with the other game part.
Speaker 1: Because gaming's a lot of things.
Speaker 0: - These people who make these things should stop making entertainment softwares and should just make amusement park places.
Speaker 0: They should just become, what's it called at Disney?
Speaker 0: What's that job?
Speaker 1: - Well, this is that.
Speaker 0: - Imagineers?
Speaker 1: - In fact, if you took, you could make the Stanley Parable.
Speaker 0: - They should just become Imagineers and quit their video game making ways.
Speaker 1: - Now, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: You could not fully make the Stanley Parable.
Speaker 0: - Or, Imagineers should make entertainment softwares just like this.
Speaker 1: - The problem with making the Stanley Parable in the real world is that it uses non-Euclidean geometry heavily.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of places where you'll walk around.
Speaker 0: - So does the Haunted High Mansion, so.
Speaker 1: - But it's just, it's tricking you with mirrors and things.
Speaker 1: It's not actually non-Euclidean.
Speaker 1: This is an actually non-Euclidean space.
Speaker 0: - There's plenty of those, every amusement park ride nowadays is just four 3D screens surrounding you anyway.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, you could do it that way, but that's, the Stanley Parable, I laughed out loud a bunch of times.
Speaker 1: It is super fun.
Speaker 1: It is well worth interacting with this thing, this ideal game, this interactive series of decisions that gives you a personal outcome that you can repeat.
Speaker 1: And once you've played through and you think you're done, go on YouTube and find the endings you didn't find in the game.
Speaker 1: Don't try to save that fucking baby.
Speaker 1: It's not worth it.
Speaker 0: - So here's the news, right?
Speaker 0: Apparently there was a dude we never heard of until now, named Greg Martin, and he died.
Speaker 0: So I wanna give him some extra recognitions 'cause I saw this on the internet, but I didn't see it on enough internet.
Speaker 0: He's one of those guys--.
Speaker 1: - Rockin' gospel blues?
Speaker 0: - No.
Speaker 0: One of those--.
Speaker 1: - That's a football player, rugby player?
Speaker 1: - No.
Speaker 1: - Okay, if you like Greg Martin, I'm finding a lot of Greg Martins that aren't your Greg Martin.
Speaker 0: - That's a common name, okay?
Speaker 0: He's one of those people that did something really important that you know, but he was unheralded and unrecognized for his great works.
Speaker 0: And you know, it's like, well, we should recognize his great works, even though we are too late.
Speaker 1: - Is it this DeviantArt guy?
Speaker 0: - No.
Speaker 0: He is the guy who did lots and lots of video game box art in your childhood, and you didn't even realize.
Speaker 0: For example, Little Nemo Dream Master NES, Pac-Man Game Boy, Snow Brothers NES, Adventure Island Game Boy, Felix the Cat NES, Sonic 2.
Speaker 1: - Oh man, Sonic 2.
Speaker 0: - Bonk's Adventure, Bomberman, DuckTales 2, Flintstones, he did all the art for all these video game boxes.
Speaker 0: Pac-Attack SNES, Tengen Pac-Man, NES Pac-Man, Sonic Spinball, a lot of Sonic box art, Bomberman's, Time Gal, Arrow the Acrobat, and there's a whole thread-- - Et cetera.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, there's a whole thread here on Nintendo Age Forum that shows all his box arts, and once you see the box arts, you're like, that guy, all those boxes look the same, oh my God, that art.
Speaker 1: - I guess we have to add to the Google juice so that he'll pop up over all these rugby players and things.
Speaker 0: - Exactly, so yeah.
Speaker 0: Now the thing is, what this makes me wanna do is not only to recognize and remember him and his great and memorable box art-- - But to figure out other people who do box art?
Speaker 0: - To find other video game box art artists from back in the day, or we don't know the Atari guy, I forget his name, right, who did all the pitfalls and all those ones, and then the Breakout guy who did all those ones.
Speaker 0: I actually saw, I think I saw a video of that guy doing the super Breakout live sketching or whatever, anyway.
Speaker 0: Like yeah, there should be some more recognition of video game box artists from the '80s, '90s, early 2000s, not anyone who's doing it today, they can shove it, they just use their computer.
Speaker 0: They can't.
Speaker 1: - So things of the day.
Speaker 1: This video is just kind of amazing and so enjoyable.
Speaker 1: I can't, you just all need to watch it.
Speaker 1: This is Story Wars.
Speaker 0: It's an animation-- - Sure we didn't already do this?
Speaker 1: - I couldn't find any example of us having done it.
Speaker 1: I've searched multiple times in multiple venues.
Speaker 1: So Story War, this is actually on cartoon hangover, and basically this is an animation of the kind of stories that come out of Story War, the game.
Speaker 1: And it kind of makes, it's kind of an ad for Story War, but it's a really good ad because it's really funny and I really like the style.
Speaker 1: and this is the kind of show that I would watch if it was a show.
Speaker 1: In the being puppy cat, Dr.
Speaker 1: Lollipop, bravest warriors, it's in that genre almost, but with a little twist of slayers.
Speaker 0: - Definitely a twist of slayers.
Speaker 1: - This thing is great and you need to watch it.
Speaker 0: - Doesn't make me want to play the game though.
Speaker 1: - I haven't actually played the game.
Speaker 0: The thing is-- - I'd say it doesn't make me want to play the game.
Speaker 0: - Every-- - I'm not saying the game is bad.
Speaker 1: - Every game that makes stories that I've seen has not been as good as old nanofictionary.
Speaker 1: No one talks about nanofictionary.
Speaker 0: - Nanofictionary.
Speaker 1: - Pretty sure we've done a show on nanofictionary.
Speaker 1: - So good.
Speaker 1: - But yeah, watch this thing, it's great.
Speaker 0: - So, Space Dandy.
Speaker 1: - Space Dandy.
Speaker 0: - Is gonna save anime, or supposedly is gonna save anime.
Speaker 0: Watch the first episode, not bad, not bad at all.
Speaker 1: - Too late, Kill La Kill already saved anime.
Speaker 0: - Sure, everything that saves anime is saving it with boobies.
Speaker 1: But anyway.
Speaker 1: - I love how as the opening, if that keeps going on, the boobies are just boobying and boobying more and more and more.
Speaker 0: - So, you know, Japan gets all the video games we don't get.
Speaker 0: And mostly we concentrate on the unreleased console games that Japan gets that we don't get.
Speaker 0: Especially DS games, and mostly Nintendo games.
Speaker 1: - Yeah.
Speaker 0: - But, Japan actually gets tons and tons of mobile phone games that we never get here ever.
Speaker 0: And no one seems to care about that at all, even though some of them are probably really awesome, especially if you care about licensed properties that are Japanese.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there's plenty of crayon shin-chan phone games you could get that we don't have, right?
Speaker 0: But, we're never gonna have 'em.
Speaker 0: So, no elephant dance for us.
Speaker 0: So, here's a commercial for one such game, Space Galaga.
Speaker 0: Which is Space Dandy?
Speaker 0: Galaga for your phone.
Speaker 1: - It looks really stylish.
Speaker 0: - Basically, it looks like Galaga for your phone, but Space Dandy, how come we don't have that here?
Speaker 0: Hello?
Speaker 0: This is why you guys in America-- - Well, Space Dandy did just come out.
Speaker 0: - Right, but this is why you guys in America don't make money on the animes, 'cause you're trying to just make money on the animes.
Speaker 0: You gotta bring out every single thing that's related to, that's just how the Japanese-- - More importantly, you've gotta bring it out right the fuck away.
Speaker 0: - I remember when Madoka Magica-- - That's how they're making money on Space Dandy in Japan, 'cause they're putting out phone games and toys and toothbrushes and the whole shitload, right?
Speaker 1: - Even in the
Speaker 1: U.S.,
Speaker 1: remember way, way back when My Little Pony turned into the big thing?
Speaker 1: It was a while before there were things to sell, so you know who makes money off of you?
Speaker 1: If you try to make money off of a show and not of the merchandise, people who illegally bootleg stuff with your IP on it in artist alleys.
Speaker 0: - Right, make the shit and bring the shit out immediately.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, Space Dandy, the first episode aired in the U.S.
Speaker 0: first, but they got the Space Galaga already developed, already on their phones.
Speaker 0: right the hell now, and people here don't even know that it exists.
Speaker 1: - It's our roles.
Speaker 0: - Yeah.
Speaker 1: - So, in the meta moment, thank you all who came to MagFest and the four panels that Scott and I were on, especially the people who showed up at 10 fucking a.m.
Speaker 1: for our bad games panel.
Speaker 0: - Seriously, why would you do that?
Speaker 1: - Also, that mage's room was kind of in the back, and on the map, we're like, oh shit, is this tiny fucking room in the middle of nowhere?
Speaker 1: But no.
Speaker 0: - It wasn't that tiny.
Speaker 1: - The room was pretty big, and it actually was rocking the entire con.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, people were into it.
Speaker 0: It seemed like there were certain people, like that's what they were there for.
Speaker 0: Which was interesting.
Speaker 1: - Notice how the panel attendance has really gone up as they've pushed the academic stuff over the media, guests.
Speaker 0: - Super Art Fight was in a bigger room, and it was really crowded in there.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, MagFest is on the upswing, but I think MagFest is gonna have a cap next year, because-- - We'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: - We'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: So MagFest, you were great, everyone who came to see us at MagFest, you were great.
Speaker 1: If you wanted to play a game with us, we didn't play a game with you, I'm sorry, I was drunk and wandering around a lot.
Speaker 1: I might have said, "Yeah, I'll see you
Speaker 1: later.".
Speaker 1: I was probably drunk and I don't remember.
Speaker 1: Also, hot tub party.
Speaker 0: So, yeah.
Speaker 0: - Any other meta things?
Speaker 1: - The Book Club book is and was.
Speaker 1: - I do.
Speaker 1: - I do, we're done with it.
Speaker 0: - I finished reading it like yesterday.
Speaker 1: - Finally, I read two full books since I finished it.
Speaker 0: - All right, we'll see.
Speaker 1: - Two more Ian M. Banks books.
Speaker 0: - Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: -
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I might, I almost want to make the next Book Club book that wool book that listeners keep giving us copies of, and then we got more copies of at that charity dinner we went to at PAX Prime, because today, the CTO of my company is like, "Oh, hey, we're in,
Speaker 1: Bob.".
Speaker 1: So there's a book, and I know you really like good sci-fi, that I just read, and it's great, and it was that book.
Speaker 1: - It was wool?
Speaker 1: - Yeah, it was wool.
Speaker 0: - Is it about sheep?
Speaker 0: - I don't know.
Speaker 0: - Are androids dreaming of them?
Speaker 1: - I don't know, I've got five physical copies of it, because people keep giving them to me.
Speaker 1: One of them is signed by the author.
Speaker 0: - Okay.
Speaker 1: - So I guess, I don't know, I might make some dry history of my book instead.
Speaker 0: - At work, they gave away free copies of Fosse, if you want, which is pretty sure is a biography or something, it's a giant book, I could make that a Book Club book.
Speaker 0: - No.
Speaker 0: - I didn't even take my free copy, because who the hell wants it?
Speaker 1: - A company I do business with in Turkey gave me, as a gift, this huge, gigantic history book of a particular city in the old Roman Empire.
Speaker 0: - They know that much history, huh?
Speaker 1: - That book looks really, really good.
Speaker 1: And also, Emily's mom gave me a book that is titled Strategy, and so far, it is the kind of book that Scott and I will love and you will all hate.
Speaker 1: - Okay.
Speaker 1: - It is, take Characteristics of Games and go way more academic and way more historical.
Speaker 1: It's up our alley, it's also really fucking thick.
Speaker 0: - All right.
Speaker 1: - Join our forum, it's awesome, it's rocking again, now that the holidays are over.
Speaker 0: - Think about everything that there is on the internet, every protocol on the internet for communicating, right?
Speaker 0: That you can think of, Twitter, Facebook, Google+, social networks, IRCs, forums.
Speaker 1: - Gopher, what about gopher?
Speaker 1: Gopher.
Speaker 1: - Not gopher.
Speaker 1: - Gopher, no gopher.
Speaker 0: - All right, websites, everything that you, YouTubes, everything.
Speaker 0: We are there, come and find us in those places.
Speaker 1: - We're not on BitTorrent anymore.
Speaker 1: - Steam groups.
Speaker 1: - Those old torrents stopped working a long time ago.
Speaker 1: - Right, I mean.
Speaker 1: - If you can even find the trackers.
Speaker 0: - You can email us, geekknights@frontrecruit.com.
Speaker 0: There are so many ways.
Speaker 1: - Actually, a listener.
Speaker 0: - To communicate with us and the other people who listen to this show.
Speaker 1: - I have not looked at it yet.
Speaker 0: - You have to take advantage of at least some of them.
Speaker 1: - I have not looked at it yet, a listener sent us a video question once I watched it.
Speaker 0: - I watched it, it's the guy from Australia, who is, I already emailed, I answered him in YouTube, but I'll address it anyway.
Speaker 1: - Well, I didn't watch the video yet, so you can't, no spoilers.
Speaker 0: - This is a Tuesday show, right?
Speaker 0: - Yeah, no spoilers.
Speaker 0: - All right, so it's game related.
Speaker 1: - I was gonna do a video answer.
Speaker 0: - No, so remember-- in Australia, and we played Blockus and Hanabi-- - Oh, it's the smart couple.
Speaker 0: - Right, yeah, so--.
Speaker 1: - They were really smart.
Speaker 0: - The dude, his name's Bane, I guess it's his real name, which is fuckin' awesome, his real name's Bane, hell yeah.
Speaker 0: - Hello, Batman.
Speaker 1: You haven't even seen that movie, you don't know what I'm referencing.
Speaker 0: - I know who Bane is, though, 'cause I watched Batman the Animated Series.
Speaker 1: - Do you know his funny voice?
Speaker 1: I don't--.
Speaker 0: - I thought he talks like the way in the South Park episode, with the--.
Speaker 1: - It's hard to describe his accent.
Speaker 0: - You're talking more like Inspector Gadget.
Speaker 1: - That would be, move the clown to the other button.
Speaker 1: - That's what you're doing, right.
Speaker 0: You're not doing a Bane voice.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so he made a, he didn't need to make a video to ask this question, basically the question he was asking is, his partner, right, they're playing more games now, since, you know, PAXOS, right?
Speaker 0: More better games.
Speaker 1: - Ooh, steppin' it up.
Speaker 0: - But, the games they play, the game he was using, an example is a game called Cuba that we never played, but we don't need to know how to play it.
Speaker 0: In Cuba, sometimes, 'cause it's a game, right, you can make a move where you'll get four points, or you can make a move where you'll get three points, but other people might lose points, right, so it's like, you know, and basically, his partner doesn't like games where you attack people.
Speaker 1: - Welcome to the world of direct fucking, AKA highly political.
Speaker 0: - So my answer was, I don't know how to change a person's personality, sorry.
Speaker 0: The end.
Speaker 1: - The real answer is, if you want to play competitive games and want to get good at them, you have to either only play two player games, or be able to accept that you will lose due to politics.
Speaker 0: - No, but it's like, he wants to know how to make her accept that she will lose to politics, and I was like, she won't.
Speaker 1: - I was talking at her, not you.
Speaker 1: I remember our friend Luke, not Luke Crane, different Luke, way back, when we were first getting into German board games.
Speaker 0: - But he was the one asking.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, well I'm saying we started playing El Grande.
Speaker 1: Like, that was our first real, real German board game after, like, Settlers and Carcassonne.
Speaker 1: Like, that was the first, like, wooden cubes game.
Speaker 1: That's where we went, like, full on after that.
Speaker 1: And I remember, there was a moment when I had this realization.
Speaker 1: I was playing the game, and I realized, wait a minute, I can do this and get three points, or I can do this, get two points, and deny Luke four points.
Speaker 1: Luke is winning by one point, and can get two points on his turn, and I did all the math, and I did the series of actions that was guaranteed to win me the game, and he got really fucking pissed.
Speaker 0: - Right, there's no way to change that person.
Speaker 0: If you are that person, maybe you can change yourself, but as being another person, if you are not that person who is upset at people hurting each other in games, then you can't change someone else's personality.
Speaker 1: You just have to-- - You know how I've gotten around that?
Speaker 0: Play two-player games, because-- - Or don't play with, yeah, but he wants to play the multiplayer games.
Speaker 1: - No, no, you've got to get someone to be able to play those games.
Speaker 1: You have to get that person to play two-player games a lot, where there is no difference between getting three points or getting two points and denying one point.
Speaker 1: So that will, if you play two-player games a lot, that have direct attacks and aren't just races, and you have that differential, that is the most intuitive way to make it clear that hurting someone else is the same as helping yourself, and you cannot discriminate between the two.
Speaker 1: They're identical.
Speaker 0: - I don't, it's just, I think people, some people have a personality such that, where if someone's points go down, theirs or another's, right, it's like they don't want to see anyone harmed, even within the context of a game where no one's actually being harmed.
Speaker 0: It's like that just upsets them, that there is harm, whether they caused it or someone else caused it.
Speaker 0: - But I guess I've seen people-- And they just, those people, I've never seen a person who was that kind of person that didn't like that come around and become a person who likes it.
Speaker 1: - Many of our friends who are women have had that problem in the past.
Speaker 0: - I think most people have this problem, actually.
Speaker 0: Regardless of gender.
Speaker 1: - But I have seen people get over it, and the best way I can think of, 'cause I don't have a shared way, just based on my experience, if you want any chance at all, you have to play two-player games where both things happen, and that is the only way to reinforce viscerally that, oh, these are the same thing.
Speaker 0: Or-- - I think some people just don't, they have a higher priority than winning.
Speaker 0: They don't care, right?
Speaker 0: - Or, or, or!
Speaker 0: - They just can't make them care about winning as much as--.
Speaker 1: - Here's the other way.
Speaker 1: Play a game like Bonanza.
Speaker 0: Because Bonanza is-- - The fucking is concealed?
Speaker 1: - Well, it's extremely political, but it's so interactive that it sort of glosses over the fact that it's actually extremely political, and that could also-- - People don't know that they've been harmed, 'cause it's not obvious that you lose 10 points.
Speaker 1: - But eventually, if they keep playing, they might start to notice, or start to not notice when it happens more directly in more complex games.
Speaker 0: - Another thing is, if you're a game designer, right, and you notice that certain people get upset when someone loses a victory point, you could just renumber your game such that, let's say there's a move I could do where I get five and Rim loses one.
Speaker 0: You could just change it so that in that situation, I get six and Rim gets zero, 'cause it's effectively no different.
Speaker 1: - That is complex with multiplayer games.
Speaker 0: - Of course, but if you could somehow do, you know, rejigger the mathematics of your game to do that, then no one would get upset because no one's losing points.
Speaker 1: - I think they would still get upset because they would start to perceive the direct actions that get a lot of points as being unfair.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, maybe.
Speaker 1: - They would, in fact, I think it would cause almost the same effect.
Speaker 0: - Maybe, but I think there's just something about losing something, right, having your shit messed up.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, well, case in point, you've all gotten zars before.
Speaker 1: That's the worst thing in the fucking world.
Speaker 0: - Mario Party the zar.
Speaker 1: - Oh my God, remember the double zar that fucked us in the tournament, lost us the belt?
Speaker 1: - That's right.
Speaker 1: - That happens.
Speaker 0: - It happens, okay.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about games we played at MAGFest.
Speaker 1: - All right, MAGFest was four days of gaming, not gonna talk about every game we played.
Speaker 1: - Were you not there?
Speaker 0: Why weren't you there?
Speaker 1: - Yeah, seriously.
Speaker 1: - You must suck.
Speaker 1: - Listen, I understand--.
Speaker 0: - There's no other explanation for not being there.
Speaker 1: - I understand if you don't fly from America to PAX Australia.
Speaker 0: - I understand if you don't fly from Mozambique to MAGFest.
Speaker 1: That is acceptable.
Speaker 1: - I understand if you don't fly to PAX Prime 'cause you don't live on the West Coast.
Speaker 0: - Well, if you don't have tickets, right, it's understandable.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, I understand if you don't go to PAX East 'cause it's sold out.
Speaker 1: - MAGFest is not sold out.
Speaker 1: - MAGFest had no cap.
Speaker 0: - And it's four days and it's New Year's, you're on vacation anyway.
Speaker 0: And it's not that crowded.
Speaker 1: - MAGFest is the best non-Pax convention ever.
Speaker 0: - Period.
Speaker 1: - So, MAGFest was awesome.
Speaker 1: We played a lot of games, played a lot of Dig Dug.
Speaker 0: Scott and I were neck and neck on this one machine, but then-- - It only keeps the top five scores and some other dude comes and blows us out of the water.
Speaker 0: so we don't know what our scores are.
Speaker 1: - All right, D_T, you had two orders of magnitude higher score than me.
Speaker 0: - I don't know what the hell he's doing.
Speaker 0: - Winning.
Speaker 0: - I'm gonna go practice me some Dig Dug.
Speaker 1: - I'm gonna practice some fucking Dig Dug.
Speaker 0: - That's some bullshit because I said I was gonna practice Mike Tyson's punch shot, I didn't do that either.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, I did some of the challenges and it was fun.
Speaker 1: I played a lot of Dig Dug.
Speaker 1: I played a lot of that weird eyes game that's like Pac-Man was shooting.
Speaker 0: - What?
Speaker 1: - You didn't see that?
Speaker 1: - No.
Speaker 1: - You're a floating eyeball on a Pac-Man board.
Speaker 1: There's pills to pick up and you pick them up by shooting them.
Speaker 1: There's other eyes flying around.
Speaker 1: If they see you, they shoot at you and you can shoot them.
Speaker 1: You pick up the things by shooting at them.
Speaker 1: If the other eyes shoot you, you die.
Speaker 1: It's really hard because if there's pills between you and the eye, you shoot at it, you hit the pill, its beam hits you.
Speaker 0: - I played Magical Drop 3.
Speaker 0: There were a lot of Magical Drop people there.
Speaker 0: You know what else?
Speaker 1: - The same motherfuckers around the initial D machine the entire con, I didn't even bother.
Speaker 0: - You know what else?
Speaker 0: Apparently, there's a game called Windjammers which is sort of like Frisbee volleyball, Frisbee tennis.
Speaker 0: It's for Neo Geo.
Speaker 0: So the Magical Drop machine was frequently a Windjammers machine 'cause it's Neo Geo, right?
Speaker 0: But, Giant Bomb, that podcast video show we don't watch and whatever, but we know exists, they have made Windjammers ridiculously popular for some reason.
Speaker 0: So during MAGFest, all these bros are playing Windjammers like crazy and I was like, what the fuck?
Speaker 0: Get away from my Magical Drops.
Speaker 0: We wanna drop some magic balls on your heads.
Speaker 0: Stop throwing the discs.
Speaker 1: - We never got, there was an Araki table.
Speaker 1: we never got a chance to use.
Speaker 1: - Justice.
Speaker 1: - There was an Artemis Space Bridge that Emily and a bunch of our friends played.
Speaker 0: - Yep.
Speaker 1: - They got nuked and had some trouble.
Speaker 1: I think we're gonna play some of that in the near future with our crew.
Speaker 1: But the games we played that we wanna talk about are the tabletop games.
Speaker 0: - That's right.
Speaker 1: - 'Cause there really aren't new console games that we haven't already talked about.
Speaker 0: - So there's one game, the big one, right?
Speaker 0: It's one that I've heard about for many moons but I've never had a chance to play.
Speaker 0: but I've heard it oftenly spoke.
Speaker 0: It is maybe one of the highest ranking board game geek games I haven't played or, you know, and--.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, it's also a hundred fucking dollars on Amazon.
Speaker 0: - Right, the game is called Hansa to Tonica.
Speaker 1: - So if I had to analogize it after looking at it and learning the rules, wrong twice.
Speaker 1: We'll get to that.
Speaker 0: - Talk about getting rules wrong.
Speaker 0: This is the worst case of wrong rule ever, ever.
Speaker 1: - I like the point that there were multiple people in one game who were all playing on a radically different assumption because different other sets of people who weren't playing told them wrong.
Speaker 0: And all of those people were wrong.
Speaker 0: - One person read the rules, another person super read the rules, right?
Speaker 0: Y'all got it wrong.
Speaker 1: - The game feels a lot like some aspects of Thurn in Texas, some aspects of Web of Power.
Speaker 0: - See, the thing is those are games that I am A+ at and those aspects I did not have in this game.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, this game-- - Partially because of wrong rule.
Speaker 1: - Has extremely obscured positional heuristics to the point that it is almost impossible for a novice player to have any concept of how well they're doing until the game ends.
Speaker 1: And they will also not likely see the end of the game approaching.
Speaker 0: - Nope, unless it's the victory point kind.
Speaker 0: That one's easy to see.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, but even then they might not notice because the victory points seem to not get to that point usually.
Speaker 0: - Basically what it is, it's a game where you're basically putting guys on roads similar to Ticket to Ride, but you have to sort of fight to control the roads and some roads are better than others.
Speaker 1: - But controlling a road means you pick up all your guys and then interact with one of the end points of the road.
Speaker 0: - Finishing a road allows you to put a real guy on the board, which is hard, right?
Speaker 0: And then the real guys, it would actually matter.
Speaker 1: - But they're limited power grid style in where they can go.
Speaker 1: There's multiple kinds of guys and the places they can interact with not only are limited but are radically different.
Speaker 1: Like you put a guy in one spot and you control the office.
Speaker 1: You'll get victory points when other people will finish routes that touch that.
Speaker 1: Or you can put it on the action thing and then like get more actions, get more workers to place later, or upgrade your bag or upgrade all these things you've got on your little thingy.
Speaker 0: - But really what makes it hard to figure out is the side effects.
Speaker 0: It's like upgrading the book, for example, right?
Speaker 0: So if you build a road in a certain place you can upgrade your book, right?
Speaker 0: Okay, if you upgrade your book then when you use the airlift action you can airlift more dudes.
Speaker 0: But at the same time you also get another merchant 'cause you upgraded your book.
Speaker 0: So it's like all these, when you do something it actually has like crazy side effects all over the place and certain things you need really badly that go with other things you don't need so badly and vice versa all over the place.
Speaker 0: So there isn't like this clear path of do these things in this order for optimal efficiency.
Speaker 0: It's like, oh I can just go get more, everyone is trying to get more actions 'cause that was so obviously good.
Speaker 0: But it's like, wait a minute, if I upgrade my bag that's effectively getting more actions 'cause I'll have to take less bag actions and can do more non-bag actions.
Speaker 1: - But in the game I played--.
Speaker 0: - 'Cause my bag is more efficient.
Speaker 1: - Because of counter attacks I was able to do what I wanted with almost no bagging at any point.
Speaker 1: So the game is very reactive in that you can put your guys out on the road but if you have guys out that haven't finished a road other people can spend more guys to displace your guys.
Speaker 1: but then you get kinda like double guys.
Speaker 1: So if I displace one of Scott's guys he gets to put two guys on a nearby road.
Speaker 0: - Then I can use the airlift to just move the guys that I've now gotten free extra guys.
Speaker 1: - So you see this strategy where people will put a guy in the way of someone else hoping to get displaced and that person might then not displace them because it would displace them somewhere that would fuck up their shit elsewhere.
Speaker 0: - And now your guys are all trapped and shit.
Speaker 1: - Yeah or--.
Speaker 0: - 'Cause they're just hanging out there not being displaced.
Speaker 1: - Or you displace, someone else displace, you have a displaced cascade over multiple rounds because people are getting all these guys on the board from being displaced.
Speaker 1: The board can change so radically between one turn and the next that you gotta rethink your whole strategy but the actions you take are extremely simple.
Speaker 0: - Yeah there's only what, five actions you can take?
Speaker 0: Bag, put guys, airlift guys, claim and something else?
Speaker 1: - Something like that.
Speaker 0: - Yeah and then on your turn you get what, two actions?
Speaker 1: - I only played it once.
Speaker 1: I gotta read the rules in detail.
Speaker 0: - It's a game I definitely wanna play again but I think it has a lot of long-term play possibilities.
Speaker 0: - Yes.
Speaker 0: - But I think Tammany Hall, I wanna play again more.
Speaker 1: - I wanna play that too.
Speaker 0: - I wanna play that more than I wanna play Hans Doutanika but I foresee it having less long-term possibilities.
Speaker 0: I think it'd be more like fun while it lasts but I think Hans Doutanika could become a game you play for a long time.
Speaker 0: But I feel Hans Doutanika felt a lot similar to Brass which I have.
Speaker 0: So it's like I already have Brass, I don't need to buy that one.
Speaker 1: - I would buy Hans Doutanika if they weren't 100 bucks on Amazon.
Speaker 0: - Well I'll go check it at the Strad.
Speaker 1: - That's what I'm gonna do, you never know.
Speaker 1: - You never know, you never know.
Speaker 1: This game however, in the early days before we got into German board gaming culture and just played these games on our own, the way we'd learn is we'd all independently read the rule book and then we'd play.
Speaker 1: Then we got into the board gaming culture which is very much a culture of the oral tradition.
Speaker 0: - People don't wanna read rules.
Speaker 0: For some reason reading rules is not fun and people don't wanna do it.
Speaker 1: - So most people learn board games by having someone else teach them.
Speaker 0: - And they get the rules fucking wrong.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, one asshole gets the rules wrong, teaches 100 other assholes and then you'll have an entire generation playing a game wrong.
Speaker 0: - 'Cause of one guy who's illiterate.
Speaker 1: - Nevermind games that have rules changes.
Speaker 1: - Glory, oh not Glory to Rome.
Speaker 1: Seven Wonders has some of that, there's different copies of the rule book that say different things in certain key areas.
Speaker 1: Carcassonne has no less than three completely different ways to score farmers depending on what rule book you have.
Speaker 0: - I've never met a person who is new to Netrunner that plays it properly from the get go.
Speaker 1: - That's just how it goes.
Speaker 0: - They're like, oh if it doesn't have it in the run, do I still have to break this ice?
Speaker 0: It's like no, just keep going.
Speaker 1: - I am now going to fully read the rule book of any game, even if someone teaches it to me.
Speaker 1: 'Cause there are a lot of games I play that I've never read the rule book for.
Speaker 0: - Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: - Like Eclipse, I've never read it, I've been taught.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, there were games, well I've read the rule book for Eclipse.
Speaker 0: - But not the expansion one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are games where we've been getting the rules wrong the whole time.
Speaker 1: - Well remember the first time we played Puerto Rico.
Speaker 1: we got it way wrong.
Speaker 0: - Wasn't there something we got wrong in Seven Wonders this whole time that we discovered?
Speaker 1: - Now I'm trying to find--.
Speaker 0: - There was some game over the weekend where we discovered we'd always been playing it wrong.
Speaker 1: - Yes, but I found a copy of the rules online at least.
Speaker 1: that says the way we were playing, so I could do some research.
Speaker 1: But the biggest one was Amun-Re, which we got something wrong, we fixed it like a year later, wrongly.
Speaker 1: And then years after that, we were playing with someone at a con and they were like, "What the fuck?
Speaker 1: "That's not how that rule
Speaker 1: works.".
Speaker 1: And we all looked at each other and we're like, "What, no, no, no, we looked in the rule book, "no, no, no, we were
Speaker 1: wrong.".
Speaker 1: So even the gamer-iest gamers get this shit wrong.
Speaker 0: The moral, at some point, even if you've been taught how to play a game-- - Read all the rules, not just the sections that you're shady on, read every word, even the sections you are so sure of.
Speaker 1: - And read it cover to cover.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, every word.
Speaker 1: - And also, if you learn a game like Small World and then someone tries to play Vinci with you, just don't.
Speaker 1: If games are very similar, pick one and never play the other one.
Speaker 1: - 'Cause I still fuck up Small World because of Vinci.
Speaker 0: - Yes, I have a hard time playing Small World.
Speaker 1: - Yeah.
Speaker 0: - All right, what else did we play--.
Speaker 1: - So I played this game that friends taught us correctly.
Speaker 1: I have learned which friends are trustworthy and which ones aren't.
Speaker 1: Ginkgopolis.
Speaker 0: - Okay.
Speaker 1: - It's hard to explain what's cool about this game, but it works with two players.
Speaker 1: It can be played one player, kind of like Agricola can.
Speaker 1: I'm really at a loss for how to describe this game.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like tile worker placement, but the mechanics are, it has no less than three pretty unique mechanics.
Speaker 1: I really can't, Scott, I bought it, I ordered it.
Speaker 0: - Okay.
Speaker 0: - 'Cause I liked it.
Speaker 0: - You spent all the money you want.
Speaker 1: - It was cheap.
Speaker 1: We have to play it and then we have to review it because it's really difficult to explain, one, I don't know if the game's good, but I enjoyed it.
Speaker 1: Two, it is very difficult without going into extreme depth to explain this game, it needs an entire show.
Speaker 1: But even if it ends up being bad on multiple playthroughs, Ginkgopolis gets points for being way different from any board game I have ever played, yet using the concepts and mechanics of board games that I'm intimately familiar with.
Speaker 1: I like it and I can't explain it until later.
Speaker 0: - Did you play, we didn't play this at MAGFest, we played it at New Year's.
Speaker 0: Did you play Coop, C-O-U-P, Coop?
Speaker 1: - I watched other people play it, but I was involved in something else at the table.
Speaker 0: - Okay, so here's how the game works, right?
Speaker 0: It was a game that I've seen around a lot lately, just like I've seen Love Letter and The Resistance around a lot lately.
Speaker 0: It's a similar small box game, seemed to be played by the same kinds of groups of people, like that casual board game meetup kind of game.
Speaker 0: After playing it, I can see why.
Speaker 0: Here's how it works, real simple game.
Speaker 0: There's a deck of cards, there's different roles, there's two copies of each role in the box, right?
Speaker 0: Everyone gets two face down, you look at 'em, but you don't show anyone, 'cause it's a bluffing game.
Speaker 0: On your turn, there's certain actions you can do, right?
Speaker 0: Like take monies, kill people, et cetera.
Speaker 0: Killing people I think costs like $7 or something.
Speaker 0: There's a limit to how much money you can have, which actually ruined the most obvious strategy that I had.
Speaker 1: - Oh, I have my question and you can answer it after you keep talking.
Speaker 1: Is it just the balloon popping game?
Speaker 0: - Similar.
Speaker 1: - Okay.
Speaker 0: - Not quite though, right?
Speaker 0: 'Cause it's not about voting, right?
Speaker 0: It's you basically can only pop a balloon if you get up to seven, which is hard to do, right?
Speaker 0: So it's sort of like, it's like one person can, basically you have to earn a vote first, which is where the game happens, is the earning of the vote.
Speaker 0: Also, let's say there's certain actions you can do.
Speaker 0: Like you can always take one dollar, but if you want, you can try to take two dollars.
Speaker 0: But if someone is the Duke, they can say, uh-uh, you don't get two dollars, you get zero.
Speaker 0: They can cancel your action.
Speaker 0: Now, let's say that happens.
Speaker 0: Let's say it's me, Rim, and Emily, and Emily goes, "Taking two
Speaker 0: dollars.".
Speaker 0: And Rim says, "Uh-uh, I'm the Duke, you can't do that.
Speaker 0: "I'm gonna stop
Speaker 0: you.".
Speaker 0: Emily can either say, "Okay," and put the two dollars back, or could say, "Fuck you, Rim, you don't have the
Speaker 0: Duke.".
Speaker 0: And if you have the Duke, you turn it over and one of Emily's characters dies.
Speaker 1: - All right, so it's balloon popping game with bullshit.
Speaker 0: - Exactly, and if you do have a Duke, I mean, if you don't have a Duke, one of your guys dies 'cause you were lying, right?
Speaker 0: So that's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: Whoever the last person alive wins.
Speaker 0: So I realized the game gets really kind of silly and pointless after a few people were eliminated, and pretty much a lot of who wins and loses is determined by who people decide to eliminate early, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if someone decides to kill one of your guys first, well, you're not gonna win now, right?
Speaker 1: - Now, see, this is why a lot of listeners always try, like at conventions, they don't listen to the show that often, or they haven't listened to old, old episodes.
Speaker 1: They're always like, "Oh, man, you should play "The Resistance, all these
Speaker 1: games.".
Speaker 1: And the reason I'm always really down on them is because they're all either just synodels or mafia, so I might as well just play synodels or mafia.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, well, I haven't played The Resistance.
Speaker 0: It's supposedly the better mafia.
Speaker 1: - I played it, it's better in the same way that Eucharonia is better than Glory to Rome.
Speaker 0: - I was afraid of that.
Speaker 1: - Like, it's different, it does interesting things, but if I'm gonna play a game that's like that anyway, I might as well, I'd rather play a pure version of that game.
Speaker 1: I'd rather just play the purely political, purely psychological mafia.
Speaker 0: - But yeah, if you're that kind of, you know, gamer who's not super serious.
Speaker 1: - I love the way you said that.
Speaker 1: If you're stupid, you're like stupid shit.
Speaker 0: - You're that kind of person that goes to NerdNYC meetup and whatever and enjoys it and loves that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: - That's my new insult, Scott.
Speaker 1: Any time someone likes something that I don't like, I'll be like, "Well, that's a great anime.
Speaker 1: "if you're that kind of
Speaker 1: person.".
Speaker 0: - You're that kind of person, yeah.
Speaker 0: Then KU is actually, you know, it's just another one of those great games for the people who like games such as Pandemic, The Resistance, Battle of Sargalactica, et cetera.
Speaker 0: If those are your kind of game, put KU on the list.
Speaker 0: You'll fucking love it.
Speaker 1: - So speaking of KU, we played at MAGFest.
Speaker 1: We got a bunch of our friends together who they're all like hardcore gamers like us.
Speaker 0: They've never played Citadels.
Speaker 1: So we busted it out and played it.
Speaker 0: - We didn't finish it.
Speaker 1: - I love my friends because they'd never played this game before.
Speaker 1: We taught them, we started playing, and they did the right thing and ruined the game.
Speaker 0: - And they immediately shuffled the hands.
Speaker 1: - Everyone immediately, the whole game was random.
Speaker 0: - Half the table was randomly choosing.
Speaker 1: - Everyone acted randomly.
Speaker 1: At one point, I arranged the cards and handed them to my left.
Speaker 1: And that person was looking at the cards for a while.
Speaker 1: And then they stopped and they looked at me.
Speaker 1: And then they put the cards under the table and shuffled them and put one face up.
Speaker 1: It was beautiful.
Speaker 0: - I actually, twice, chose non-randomly to see if that would help.
Speaker 1: - I acted like I was choosing randomly, but decided hoping that at least one of our friends was gonna be stupid.
Speaker 1: And it turned out no one was stupid.
Speaker 1: I was really banking on one person being stupid.
Speaker 1: A person, not a particular person, but anyone.
Speaker 1: All I needed was a person who was stupid and I could've eked out victory 'cause I basically saw citadels.
Speaker 1: But nope, the game, at one point we were like, is everyone just going to act randomly until the end?
Speaker 1: And they're like, yup.
Speaker 1: And we're like, okay, we're done.
Speaker 0: - I think we just had something else to do.
Speaker 1: - Well, we wanted to play Eclipse.
Speaker 0: - That too.
Speaker 1: - I played a little game, Cheaty Mages, that Adam had.
Speaker 0: - Oh yeah, I saw that.
Speaker 1: - It was actually really fun.
Speaker 1: So it's this little game and it's gladiatorial arena and you bust out all these gladiators and they're gonna fight like the dragon and the demon and the goblin and your mages and you bet on who you think you're gonna win and it's horse betting.
Speaker 1: So you bet on one guy, two guys, or three guys with lower payout if you bet on more people if one of your guys wins.
Speaker 0: - I would just go all in on one guy each time.
Speaker 1: - Yes, and then you take turns playing cards, basically cheating.
Speaker 0: - To get the odds of your guy winning?
Speaker 0: - So you'll cast spells.
Speaker 1: Some spells are open, like make this guy weaker, make this guy stronger.
Speaker 1: Some spells go face down.
Speaker 0: - Can you bet on the same guy someone else bet on?
Speaker 1: - Yeah, it's secret betting.
Speaker 0: - This is obvious.
Speaker 0: what to do.
Speaker 0: In the round one, I don't wanna go first, right?
Speaker 0: I want someone else to go first.
Speaker 1: - You don't know what people bet on.
Speaker 0: - Oh.
Speaker 0: - Yeah.
Speaker 1: - Oh.
Speaker 1: - Yeah.
Speaker 0: - Well then nevermind, I don't know what to do.
Speaker 1: - So to make matters more interesting, here's the catch.
Speaker 1: Every battle--.
Speaker 0: - Can I wait to see how they cheat before I bet?
Speaker 1: - Yeah, you bet first and then you go around betting and doing stuff until everyone passes.
Speaker 0: - Oh no, I wanna bet after people do stuff.
Speaker 1: - You get six spells, you can cast as many as you want.
Speaker 1: You draw three at the end of the turn with a hand limit of six and you do three turns.
Speaker 1: Like three go-arounds.
Speaker 1: The key is that every go-around, you randomly flip over a judge and the judges all have specific rules.
Speaker 1: Like can't cast forbidden spells, can't cast direct spells, do whatever the fuck you want.
Speaker 1: And it's just really fun and really quick and really light.
Speaker 0: I think I played another game.
Speaker 1: - Jungle Speed Safari.
Speaker 1: you played.
Speaker 0: - Oh, that's the one I was forgetting.
Speaker 1: - So I watched you guys play and when you all went rah, rah, I decided that game looked stupid.
Speaker 0: - It is L-stupid.
Speaker 0: Do not play Jungle Speed Safari, just play Jungle Speed.
Speaker 0: - Yep.
Speaker 0: - The end.
Speaker 0: It's a baby game.
Speaker 1: - We played some Jungle Speed, I got cut.
Speaker 1: Like I got cut and bled all over the totem, it was awesome.
Speaker 1: - Chia cut me.
Speaker 0: - I think there's one other game we played.
Speaker 1: - Oh, we played Eclipse.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to talk about our game of Eclipse.
Speaker 0: - That's what I was suggesting.
Speaker 1: - All right, so before we get to Eclipse, played a lot of Glory to Rome, which Scott is down on.
Speaker 0: - I mean, it's not a bad game.
Speaker 0: It's just you guys play it so fucking much.
Speaker 1: - So I played it a bunch.
Speaker 0: - You played more games of Glory to Rome than I played of Netrunner.
Speaker 1: - So I played Glory to Rome a bunch of times.
Speaker 0: - Played so much Glory to Rome.
Speaker 1: - And I put a lot of thought into who was playing with me and why they wanted to play Glory to Rome over other games.
Speaker 1: And I figured it out.
Speaker 1: One, because Glory to Rome is fairly straightforward rules wise, like it's actually pretty easy to teach for as complex as it looks.
Speaker 1: Pretty much everyone we know knows the rules, which you can't say about almost any other good game we own.
Speaker 1: Any game, El Grande, Puerto Rico, Teen E.
Speaker 0: - You know why?
Speaker 0: Because people play Glory to Rome instead of playing those games and learning them.
Speaker 1: - Two, the game is pretty quick.
Speaker 1: Like 45 minutes at most, if everyone knows what the fuck they're doing.
Speaker 1: And three, it is a game of skill.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, and four, no one we know has solved it.
Speaker 0: - You can get a bad draw.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, you can, but I've learned to mitigate that.
Speaker 1: So the novel thing is that I played a few games of the Imperium version, which I haven't really played much.
Speaker 1: And I really like the Imperium version now because in the normal game, a lot of people follow the leader often.
Speaker 1: In the Imperium version, like I lead a role and most of the time, most people think.
Speaker 1: Like it is way hard to do anything.
Speaker 1: And you can't rely on luck of the draw.
Speaker 1: You've got to have a strategy and you've got to commit to that strategy.
Speaker 1: So I'm going to play Glory to Rome only Imperium version for a little while.
Speaker 1: And then I'm going to probably write something up about it.
Speaker 0: - I'll play some Imperium version.
Speaker 1: - Well, we'll do it, we'll do it.
Speaker 0: - So we played a game of eclipse.
Speaker 1: - With everything.
Speaker 0: - With every, absolutely every expansion thing there is.
Speaker 1: - I liked everything except for the, I think alliances.
Speaker 1: just, you cannot play eclipse with the alliance mechanic if you were smart.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, I'm not a fan of the, I'm definitely not a fan of the alliances.
Speaker 0: Not only cause they make the game way, way longer, right?
Speaker 1: - We can, we now understand exactly mechanically why it makes the game take longer though.
Speaker 0: - So the reason it makes the game take longer, the first reason is sort of a meta reason, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, let's say you're playing a game, any game.
Speaker 0: And on your turn, you think of what to do and you do it.
Speaker 0: And you're good at, you're a fast turn taker, right?
Speaker 0: Doesn't, right?
Speaker 0: Any game.
Speaker 0: If you have an alliance, suddenly on your turn, you're now discussing with your teammate what to do.
Speaker 0: Not like bridge, we're not allowed to discuss, right?
Speaker 0: You're discussing.
Speaker 1: - And that happened in our game.
Speaker 1: As soon as I was in alliance with the A.
Speaker 0: - The act of talking, hearing takes way, way more time than the act of just thinking and deciding.
Speaker 1: - I have to say things like you move your guys there so that when the gray token comes to me, I can build a unit to move it.
Speaker 0: - Every single turn, constantly talking, the two allied people took on their turns, Raymond, more time.
Speaker 1: - Three allied people.
Speaker 1: We had Pete too.
Speaker 0: - Pete wasn't really.
Speaker 1: - I'll get to Pete.
Speaker 1: I'm going to call Pete out for being shit at eclipse, but we'll get to that.
Speaker 0: - Anyway, you know, you just frigging took so long in your turns because you had to physically talk to other people about what you were going to do.
Speaker 1: - There's a secondary problem with the alliances that further exacerbates this.
Speaker 1: So with a lot, with I'm playing by myself.
Speaker 0: - This counts for any game of the alliances, but eclipse also.
Speaker 1: - I can use really rough heuristics to follow what's going on in sectors of space that are far away from me.
Speaker 1: And I only need to apply complex heuristics to my immediate neighbors or emergent situations that I could affect in some fashion.
Speaker 1: Like I ignore Scott 'cause he's behind Andrew.
Speaker 0: - I'm so far away.
Speaker 0: You can't affect me and I can't affect you.
Speaker 0: So don't even, you don't even need to pay attention to me on your turn.
Speaker 0: 'cause you can't do anything about it unless maybe I'm going to buy a science off the thing, in which case you couldn't stop me anyway.
Speaker 1: - So let's say there's you and me and we're separated by Andrew.
Speaker 1: And suddenly I see you move all your ships away from Andrew.
Speaker 1: 'cause you're going to attack Pete.
Speaker 1: That might affect my decision.
Speaker 1: and now I'm going to go attack Andrew, but notice how.
Speaker 1: it's something really broad.
Speaker 1: He's moving a bunch of guys away.
Speaker 1: If Chie is next to me, I'll be like, she built that fighter.
Speaker 1: I'm going to walk over to her.
Speaker 0: - It has this equipment in it.
Speaker 1: - I'm walking over and looking at what that ship has and then calculating some odds.
Speaker 1: But as soon as I was allied with Chie, I had to look at the whole board now.
Speaker 1: And more importantly, I had to look at the other alliance and I couldn't just look at Scott.
Speaker 1: I had to look at Scott's ally.
Speaker 0: - I wasn't in an alliance.
Speaker 1: - All right, the other two were in the alliance.
Speaker 1: You were by yourself.
Speaker 1: So now I have to look at the other alliance and every alliance.
Speaker 1: So if there's an alliance and then two lone wolves and then I'm in alliance, I have to analyze all the other entities every turn.
Speaker 1: I can't ignore anything.
Speaker 0: - You have to play for your whole team basically.
Speaker 0: Everyone on your team has to play for your whole team.
Speaker 1: - And every turn I have to calculate.
Speaker 0: - You're all the quarterback of the whole three team army.
Speaker 1: - And I have to calculate.
Speaker 1: not just will this get me points?
Speaker 1: I have to calculate, does this give my team more average points than it would if I did Y or Z?
Speaker 0: - That's the specific thing to Eclipse that makes it even harder for the alliance.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, and alliance's score is the average of all the members.
Speaker 0: - You're calculating the average of your three guys.
Speaker 0: So it's like, well, this is the way I can get the most points but if I did this, our average score would go up more.
Speaker 0: So we should do that instead.
Speaker 0: And suddenly everything takes longer to calculate.
Speaker 1: - And luckily, while they're highly political, that is unlike Dune, mitigated heavily by the fact that you can really only ally with people you've gotten into contact with.
Speaker 1: And interestingly, I don't think the alliances are actually political in most cases.
Speaker 1: Like in this game, I did not want to ally with Jie.
Speaker 1: I was forced to because the way the board ended up, we shared a border into the galactic center and then Pete drew tiles that had a wormhole on them and Jie drew a tile that had a wormhole on it.
Speaker 1: So there's a wormhole connecting Jie and Pete and I was neighboring Jie.
Speaker 1: We were forced into an alliance because otherwise Pete would have attacked Jie and there would have been this huge cycle of bullshit.
Speaker 0: - But why not have a cycle of bullshit if you can come out on top?
Speaker 1: - Because I didn't think I could come out on top in that situation.
Speaker 0: - Well, then if you don't think you could have, one of those other two people was going to.
Speaker 0: Is that not correct?
Speaker 0: - Ah, but.
Speaker 0: - So why did that person choose to ally and not just attack?
Speaker 1: - So Pete allied because he planned from the beginning to break the alliance and fuck us and the only way to get us to stay away from the wormhole was to be in an alliance with us.
Speaker 0: - Oh, so he wanted to ally to get you to move a certain way and then break it so they get lost.
Speaker 1: - So on the last turn, he's like, I betray you.
Speaker 0: - But you can't break an alliance on the last turn.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, so now we had to play the last turn with an ally who tried and could not betray us, who is still in our alliance, we couldn't kick him out.
Speaker 0: - Right.
Speaker 1: - Also, he derped around and kind of just fucked up.
Speaker 0: - Well, you allied with someone just because they were touching you.
Speaker 1: - We had to because we had no way to defend ourselves otherwise.
Speaker 0: - Why don't you defend yourself?
Speaker 1: - Yeah, so the alliances ruin Eclipse.
Speaker 1: Do never play with alliances.
Speaker 0: - Right, another thing is that there's all the extra stuff in the Eclipse that isn't alliances in the expansion.
Speaker 0: It just gives you more stuff.
Speaker 0: - I disagree.
Speaker 0: - It's not good, it's not bad, but I don't think it really makes a difference.
Speaker 1: It just makes more calculations.
Speaker 1: - Basic Eclipse is super boring.
Speaker 0: - It's not super boring.
Speaker 1: - I think it's super boring.
Speaker 0: - It's not mechanically different.
Speaker 0: You don't make different decisions, it just takes you more time to calculate.
Speaker 1: - No, the galactic center falls basically immediately.
Speaker 1: It's just a race to the center and a race to research and aliens are just victory points.
Speaker 1: At least with the strong aliens, it forces you to have a cycle of development and you have to plan between attacking aliens and attacking people.
Speaker 0: - Nah, the aliens aren't that much harder.
Speaker 0: The regular aliens are still on the board.
Speaker 0: The galactic center, I was gonna take it out if you didn't interfere.
Speaker 1: - Your ship sucked ass.
Speaker 0: - My ships are great.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, how come I destroyed your fleet with almost no damage to mine?
Speaker 0: - Because I built galactic center fighting ships, not rim fighting ships.
Speaker 1: - Scott, I said out loud because we're in that alliance, every turn for multiple turns, if Scott attacks the galactic center, I'm sending my glass cannons in to fuck him.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, which is why I thought you weren't gonna do it.
Speaker 0: And you also, on the very turn that you did it, you were ho-humming and not so committing to it and I was like, he's not gonna do it.
Speaker 0: - Well, because I could have glass cannon fell.
Speaker 0: - That's what I was saying.
Speaker 0: I'm like, he's not gonna do it.
Speaker 0: He's gonna go the other way.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, and then I looked at your ships and your ships were bullshit.
Speaker 1: So I attacked you.
Speaker 0: - My ships were great against the galactic center.
Speaker 1: - So were mine.
Speaker 0: - Also, I got fucked by the god of dice.
Speaker 0: But Alia acted.
Speaker 1: - That's your fault for leaning on the table.
Speaker 0: - Scott Johnson led on the table, not Scott Rubin.
Speaker 1: - I'll put it this way.
Speaker 1: We can debate about the other parts, like Scott and I don't agree 100%, but we agree, do not use alliances in Eclipse.
Speaker 1: But the parallel turn play actually is pretty great.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, that was the thing I was actually the most skeptical about was the simultaneous turns.
Speaker 1: - You were like, no, you were really mad about it before we played.
Speaker 0: - But it ended up not, and in fact, the only times it mattered, no one else seemed to notice.
Speaker 0: There were three times where I held on to the guy and someone else could have forced me to take my turn before they took their turn.
Speaker 0: But I really, really, really wanted them to take their turn first so I could see what they were gonna do.
Speaker 0: And they didn't even notice.
Speaker 0: They just took their turn and passed the thing, and then I took my turn and passed the thing and wiped the sweat off my brow.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, all right, if you're just gonna let me do that.
Speaker 1: - Look at the elegance of the mechanic.
Speaker 1: You don't have to make it an issue unless both people care.
Speaker 0: - But they were stupid not to care.
Speaker 0: Were they not paying attention?
Speaker 1: - Maybe they had other concerns.
Speaker 0: - They must have.
Speaker 0: - So I basically got my way three times.
Speaker 0: But if I had been playing with a bunch of Scott Rubins, maybe the simultaneous turn mechanic would not have been so pleasant.
Speaker 0: It's possible.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it was still, in the real experience, it was much better than I anticipated.
Speaker 1: - What game did I play?
Speaker 0: - Would play again with simultaneous turns.
Speaker 1: - I played this game.
Speaker 1: It was at Skelter's party.
Speaker 1: I don't remember which game.
Speaker 1: Oh, right, it was Homesteaders, where it had that mechanic where basically, everyone does something simultaneously.
Speaker 1: So we start playing, and I immediately just said, "I'm not taking my action.
Speaker 1: "till everyone else is taking their
Speaker 1: action.".
Speaker 1: And the guy who talks to the game sighs, pulls out the book and quotes a thing that basically says, "If any player makes an issue of this, "then play proceeds in this
Speaker 1: way.".
Speaker 1: And he was like, "You're that guy,
Speaker 1: Rim.".
Speaker 1: And I was like,
Speaker 1: "Yep.".
Speaker 0: - Yep.
Speaker 1: - You know what, I really wanna play Eclipse.
Speaker 0: - All right, let's play it.
Speaker 0: - Like right now.
Speaker 0: - All right.
Speaker 1: - Maybe we should play some two player.
Speaker 1: - See how that goes.
Speaker 1: That might be interesting.
Speaker 1: - Maybe I'll come over this weekend.
Speaker 1: Wanna play Eclipse over footballs?
Speaker 0: - Buy, oh we don't have a table in my house.
Speaker 1: - On the floor.
Speaker 0: - And we don't have an expansion.
Speaker 1: - Kitchen floor, no expansion.
Speaker 0: - Buy me the expansion.
Speaker 1: - I thought you hated the expansion.
Speaker 0: - I thought you wanted the expansion so badly.
Speaker 1: - I could play without 'em, I just really like 'em.
Speaker 1: - All right.
Speaker 1: - Maybe there's laughing.
Speaker 1: All right, Magfest was fucking awesome and I think we're done.
Speaker 1: Any more games, is that it?
Speaker 0: - I'm sure there might have been, but I wanna go home and eat, I'm hungry.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, I'm also super hungry.
Speaker 1: So yeah, we're back in town, guys.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be doing Geek Nights again.
Speaker 1: Watch out.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: - Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: - Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: - Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: - Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.