Speaker 0: It's Thursday, November 6th, 2014.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: I'm back from Australia and we're back from hiatus.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we're talking about the election that you probably didn't vote in.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh, I'm back.
Speaker 0: We've missed a lot of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: I was feeling pretty good yesterday.
Speaker 0: I landed on Tuesday night.
Speaker 0: I went to work on Wednesday, just like a boss.
Speaker 0: And today, I think I have a PaxBox.
Speaker 1: Oh, why did you call me over here if you had a PaxBox?
Speaker 0: Just don't touch me.
Speaker 0: It feels like one of those sinus-y kind of things.
Speaker 0: So just stay away from me.
Speaker 0: I feel pretty good.
Speaker 0: Just, you know, the usual sore throat.
Speaker 0: I'm going to mute Snaxit up and get a good night's sleep.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: Apparently, there is no term limit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no term limits.
Speaker 0: Meaning Clobo's going to keep running until he dies.
Speaker 1: I've never heard of anyone being governor for more than eight years anyway.
Speaker 0: How many governors can you name?
Speaker 1: Quite a few.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: So yeah, anyway.
Speaker 0: It's the lounge.
Speaker 0: It's Thursday on Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: No, it's not the lounge.
Speaker 1: This is actually a Monday-Wednesday week.
Speaker 1: This is a special.
Speaker 0: Wow, we haven't done a special in a long time.
Speaker 1: This is not a lounge.
Speaker 1: Get your lounge out of my face.
Speaker 0: It's only the lounge.
Speaker 0: if it's a normal episode on a Thursday, then.
Speaker 1: It's never the lounge.
Speaker 1: I'll find an excuse then, too, but I found an excuse today was easier.
Speaker 0: For those of you who found out about Geek Nights because of Pax Australia, which I seem to believe is a lot of people based on the number of Twitter followers I got and the surprising number of emails I got from people who had questions about the panel, yeah, this is Geek Nights, and we'll talk about Pax on Tuesday next week.
Speaker 0: That's gaming night.
Speaker 0: Tonight's Thursday, so we're talking about whatever.
Speaker 0: My butt.
Speaker 1: Stuff that Australians could care absolutely nothing about, because they're on the other side of the world, and this is pretty much a New York issue.
Speaker 0: So, last year...
Speaker 1: But it's okay to do a New York issue.
Speaker 1: It legitimizes my registration of the geeknights.nyc domain.
Speaker 0: That, in fact, is true.
Speaker 0: So, last year, Scott and I went to Pax Australia, but it was summer here, and we went in Australia's winter, meaning we lost two weeks of summer.
Speaker 1: It sucked.
Speaker 0: This year, I went in the fall, and it was summer there, so I got bonus summer, thus canceling that out.
Speaker 1: That would have been amazing.
Speaker 0: And my impressions on summer Australia are such.
Speaker 0: To keep it relatively brief.
Speaker 0: Not talking about Pax at all.
Speaker 0: One, Sydney is way different from Melbourne, and a lot like New York.
Speaker 0: However, imagine if New York had a beach that was 100 times better than the beach at Wildwood, and was literally 20 minutes via cheap mass transit from Midtown.
Speaker 1: So, you mean Rockaway?
Speaker 0: Rockaway is far more than 20 minutes away from Midtown, and not 100 times better than Wildwood's beach.
Speaker 1: Not 100 times better than Wildwood, but you can get there really quickly.
Speaker 0: Have you ever taken the subway there?
Speaker 1: No, I just biked there.
Speaker 0: It takes an hour.
Speaker 1: From Midtown?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: In fact, it takes more than an hour from Midtown.
Speaker 1: That makes no sense.
Speaker 0: Look at that train.
Speaker 0: Look at it.
Speaker 0: So, there's a ferry that just stops.
Speaker 1: Biking is faster than that.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, there's a ferry.
Speaker 0: There are people who live.
Speaker 1: I thought you were going to say, imagine if right where the Intrepid is is the amazing beach, and you just walk there from Midtown.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you get on a ferry, and the beach is literally 20 minutes away.
Speaker 0: It's still a little far.
Speaker 1: It's not walk there.
Speaker 0: No, you get on a ferry that costs seven bucks.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: Round trip.
Speaker 0: It was awesome.
Speaker 0: Two, you know in Wildwood, when we go swimming, when we go to the ocean, even in Florida or whatever, you can dive under the wave, you can ride the wave, jump over the wave, jump into the wave.
Speaker 0: Depending on the wave, you got to do a different thing, but it doesn't really matter, because if you miss, it's just like a wave in the balls or a wave in the face.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the waves, just the default waves at Manly Beach, were like eight feet.
Speaker 1: They're real surfing waves like in the movies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I'm swimming out there.
Speaker 0: Lifeguards, they'll try to save you, I guess, but they give zero fucks how far out you swim.
Speaker 1: No, it's Australia.
Speaker 0: So, I swam way out there.
Speaker 0: Basically, there was a row of people who weren't on surfboards that were the furthest down.
Speaker 0: I was one group back from them, because I'm not a pro swimmer.
Speaker 1: That's a good idea.
Speaker 1: That's like how I'm going to be second in line to get cyborg implants.
Speaker 0: So, the waves are coming, and it's like eight foot wave, which is already like five feet higher than like the peak we get in Wildwood.
Speaker 0: So, I missed reading one once, and it threw me head over heels like 20 or 30 yards back up the beach.
Speaker 0: Like, it was amazing swimming.
Speaker 0: And then a 12-footer came.
Speaker 1: I got my ass kicked.
Speaker 0: It was awesome.
Speaker 0: So, then a 12-footer came, and yeah, that was an awesome beach.
Speaker 1: I remember I was out there with a ruler.
Speaker 1: That's why I got picked up and thrown, because I was measuring each wave.
Speaker 0: So, in Wildwood, like a lot of people just kind of stand there.
Speaker 1: It's also why lifeguards didn't save him.
Speaker 0: And the waves hit him.
Speaker 0: So, there, like you see everyone in a row does the exact same thing at the exact same time.
Speaker 0: Like, suddenly a whole line of people just boop under the water, or boop up into the air.
Speaker 0: Like, everyone can read the waves.
Speaker 0: It was super fun.
Speaker 0: It's called Manly Beach.
Speaker 0: Do you know why it's called Manly Beach?
Speaker 1: Because you have to be manly to survive?
Speaker 0: Actually, kinda.
Speaker 0: So, it's not like Batman and Batman Avenue.
Speaker 0: So, I assume Manly Beach was named after, like, Lord Manly or something dumb like that.
Speaker 1: That would be my second guess.
Speaker 0: So, the first white dude that landed there, the natives were particularly manly to him.
Speaker 0: So, he called it Manly in honor of those manly natives.
Speaker 0: And I was climbing.
Speaker 1: And that gay, gay, gay explorer.
Speaker 1: The awesomest explorer of all time.
Speaker 0: I think they, like, stabbed him with a spear.
Speaker 0: And he was like, "It's okay.
Speaker 0: You guys are
Speaker 0: awesome.".
Speaker 1: "This guy's okay.
Speaker 1: This guy's the most amazing explorer I've ever heard of.
Speaker 1: He's my
Speaker 1: hero.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, Australia's fucking... So, this is the most Australian... Knifey spoonie expert.
Speaker 0: Beyond even Manly Beach is two monuments at Manly Beach.
Speaker 0: The first monument is a plaque that commemorates the first time white people stood there.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 0: And the second one, I was climbing on these cliffs around, like, the tidal basin, like the tidal pools.
Speaker 0: I was, like, both climbing on these cliffs.
Speaker 0: And the tide was, like, out, so it was pretty safe.
Speaker 0: I figured it was fine.
Speaker 1: Wouldn't it be more safe if the tide was in?
Speaker 1: Because then you'd land in water if you fell, as opposed to jagged rocks?
Speaker 0: No, if you land in that water, the water is only, like, a foot deep over the rocks.
Speaker 0: And it's super roiling.
Speaker 0: Roiling is the word I would use.
Speaker 0: Meaning, you know the phrase...
Speaker 1: It's not really going to help you either way if you fall.
Speaker 0: You know the phrase "dash upon the rocks to death"?
Speaker 0: That is what would happen if you were in that water when the tide was up.
Speaker 1: No, because I'd just climb down.
Speaker 0: I wasn't going to fall.
Speaker 0: So I'm climbing around, and I see this big boulder.
Speaker 1: Oh, I see.
Speaker 1: I saw you.
Speaker 1: You were thinking about the situation where you climbed down and not the situation where you...
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I have trouble, I was just going to climb down.
Speaker 0: If you fall to your death.
Speaker 0: And if I fell, like, fuck it.
Speaker 0: But what I didn't want to be in the situation of is I'm climbing, I get into trouble, and now the tide's in, and I can't climb down.
Speaker 0: So I'm out there, and I see a rock, like, a big rock just kind of hanging out, like, kind of on the beach and the other rocks.
Speaker 0: And there's a plaque on it.
Speaker 0: So I kind of, like, carefully make my way over there with a little bit of swimming and get to this rock.
Speaker 0: You know what the plaque basically says?
Speaker 0: "In 1912, this giant-ass rock washed up on the beach after a crazy
Speaker 0: storm.".
Speaker 0: And to commemorate this, plaque.
Speaker 0: So they have a plaque commemorating the day in 1912 that a particularly big rock washed up on the beach.
Speaker 1: In 1912, how exciting do you think things were in Sydney?
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: I mean, that big rock just showing up out of nowhere was probably, like, the biggest news they had in two months.
Speaker 1: It was probably, like, everyone was probably stopping to check, like, "Hey, did you see that rock that showed up?
Speaker 1: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: That motherfucker is
Speaker 1: big.".
Speaker 0: So the other thing, I was hanging around, you know, doing my thing, and I went biking.
Speaker 0: I rented some shito semi-mountain bike, and I biked, like, all around the Yarra River in Melbourne and a lot of Australia stuff.
Speaker 0: I passed by an apartment rental place, and I was checking out, like, apartments for rent.
Speaker 0: The rents were pretty reasonable.
Speaker 0: Then I remembered from last year that rents in Australia are written down per week.
Speaker 1: Can you actually rent it for one week?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: It's just that's how they denote rent.
Speaker 0: It's per week, not per month.
Speaker 1: Do you have to pay it every week?
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: And all that meant was that the rents were New York rents as opposed to pretty reasonable rents.
Speaker 1: It's a major city.
Speaker 1: It has New York rents.
Speaker 1: However, if it was actually 25% of the New York rent price, it would be a very crowded city with people trying to live there.
Speaker 0: So Australia might be my backup plan.
Speaker 0: if I ever have to leave the country, simply for the fact that I could- They're not going to let you in.
Speaker 1: It's very hard to get a visa or whatnot.
Speaker 0: I am confident I could get myself Australian citizenship or naturalization or a green card or a visa or whatever.
Speaker 0: I am super confident I can make that happen.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: Good luck.
Speaker 0: The industry I work in by day is that kind of industry.
Speaker 0: I mean, a lot of people I know live there or live in Singapore.
Speaker 0: And basically, because they work in that industry, they can just live there forever and work there and the government's totally okay with it.
Speaker 0: So yeah, Australia was super awesome.
Speaker 0: The sun doesn't fucking fuck around down there.
Speaker 1: You're pretty close to that whole no zone layer.
Speaker 0: And their sunscreen is way better than our sunscreen.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it is.
Speaker 0: Apparently, it's much more tightly regulated and they use that one chemical that we're not allowed to use.
Speaker 0: I brought back a shit ton of that sunscreen.
Speaker 1: Oh, they let you?
Speaker 0: Well, no one asked.
Speaker 1: Customs didn't find it?
Speaker 0: Customs didn't even look at me.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: White privilege.
Speaker 1: Smuggling.
Speaker 1: A little Han Solo over here.
Speaker 0: Well, I declared $40 of stuff that I brought back over here.
Speaker 0: Remember, Australia doesn't care what you bring out of the country.
Speaker 0: The US just cares what you bring in.
Speaker 1: Because it's an island.
Speaker 1: They don't want you bringing in shit.
Speaker 0: Though, Australia does have exit immigration, which the US does not have.
Speaker 0: So to leave Australia, you've got to go through immigration.
Speaker 0: And that line was longer than any line I've ever stood in to get into any country.
Speaker 1: We didn't have to go through a crazy line.
Speaker 1: we left last time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know why?
Speaker 0: Because some Australian little fucking teenager went and joined ISIS.
Speaker 0: And Australia's panicking about it.
Speaker 0: So they're super scrutinizing anyone who's leaving the country to make sure they're not intending to go to Turkey, which is apparently the way you go.
Speaker 0: if you want to then go fight for ISIS.
Speaker 1: So shouldn't they just check the people with plane tickets to Turkey?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that holds up the line, I guess.
Speaker 1: How is your passport with your turkey stamps?
Speaker 1: Does that help you out?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so people there... We were talking about passports.
Speaker 0: Because I ran into Brian Hicks and all these little people I haven't seen in forever.
Speaker 0: Since September.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's like, "What the fuck are you going to Turkey all the time
Speaker 0: for?".
Speaker 1: Gobble, gobble, gobble.
Speaker 0: Yeah, super fun time.
Speaker 1: It's gobble season pretty soon over here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: I'm getting all up in that.
Speaker 0: I'm excited about this.
Speaker 0: I'm feeling some turkey.
Speaker 0: I want to make some fucking stuffing.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh.
Speaker 0: Soap top.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no.
Speaker 1: You said yeah.
Speaker 1: I could just buy some and make it right at home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the reptile brain.
Speaker 0: The same part of your brain that when you're hungry smells McDonald's and says, "Eat some of that
Speaker 0: shit.".
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll just buy some stove top on the way home and then cook it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: Part of your brain is going to really, really enjoy that.
Speaker 0: And meanwhile, the rest of your brain is going to be getting ready to eject.
Speaker 1: We used to eat that shit so much.
Speaker 0: I know we did.
Speaker 0: And we even made it with margarine and butter.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: Tonight, I'll just go and get that and a tub of frosting.
Speaker 1: That'll be dinner.
Speaker 0: Tub of frosting.
Speaker 0: If you want to go full on, the entree has to be a Red Baron Four Cheese pizza.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I can find one of those.
Speaker 0: Also known as we brought...
Speaker 1: I could do macaroni and ketchup.
Speaker 0: I think Scott and I both burned our mouths severely ten times.
Speaker 0: A lot of times.
Speaker 0: And also being the number of times we ate the Red Baron Four Cheese pizza.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Those were good times.
Speaker 0: That really hurt.
Speaker 0: I remember not being able to taste things.
Speaker 1: It was mostly that microwave's fault.
Speaker 1: It wasn't the Red Baron's fault.
Speaker 1: He's a good guy.
Speaker 0: I think the Red Baron.
Speaker 0: That pizza.
Speaker 0: It depends on what side you're on.
Speaker 0: Remember, when I was in Turkey last, I saw World War I and all this stuff from the opposite perspective.
Speaker 0: Where the good guys and the bad guys were reversed.
Speaker 0: from the usual perspective you get in the West.
Speaker 0: So, Red Baron was a good guy to some people.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So you got anything to talk about in the front bit?
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 1: So, I'm going to talk about some netrunning.
Speaker 1: Because you know whatevs.
Speaker 1: So, the company that makes Netrunner is Fantasy Flight Games.
Speaker 1: They make a lot of games.
Speaker 1: Games you might, you know, just normal board games too.
Speaker 1: Like, um, Citadel's.
Speaker 1: They published that.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: And, uh, you know, they're a huge US game company publisher.
Speaker 1: So, their world championships are right now.
Speaker 1: But I'm not fucking going to Minnesota to play fucking Netrunner.
Speaker 1: That's insane.
Speaker 0: What if you could have won?
Speaker 1: I couldn't even win in Boston or Philadelphia.
Speaker 1: So what makes you think I'm going to win in Minnesota?
Speaker 0: How many New Yorkers went there?
Speaker 1: I know two New Yorkers who went there.
Speaker 1: But one of them won the Canadian National Championship.
Speaker 1: And the other one won the Boston Regionals.
Speaker 1: Well, Cambridge Massachusetts Regionals.
Speaker 1: So, let's hope they win.
Speaker 1: And they're going to, they're planning to win.
Speaker 1: I'll root.
Speaker 1: And they're better than me.
Speaker 1: So, anyway.
Speaker 1: So, they're live streaming that shit.
Speaker 1: You know, Fantasy Flight Games screws a lot of things up.
Speaker 1: But one thing they don't screw up is at least, you know, live streaming for the world championships.
Speaker 1: So, you can watch it twitch.tv/ffglive.
Speaker 1: And also, they realize Netrunner is the real game.
Speaker 1: And all the other games are sort of second fiddle at best.
Speaker 1: So, if you want to see all those other games like X-Wing Miniatures, Game of Thrones card game, etc.
Speaker 1: You got to watch like Today, Tomorrow, Friday, you know.
Speaker 1: Saturday there's going to be some Netrunner.
Speaker 1: Sunday is nothing but Netrunner.
Speaker 1: All day.
Speaker 1: No other game has a day dedicated to just itself.
Speaker 0: I think Netrunner is becoming the football of tabletop.
Speaker 1: It pretty much sort of is.
Speaker 1: It's becoming a big deal.
Speaker 1: So, you want to watch Netrunner World Championships this Sunday, twitch.tv/ffglive.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 0: So, not talking about PAX, but speaking of that and like sport.
Speaker 0: Because they're streaming a tabletop game.
Speaker 0: People keep saying esports, but I feel like it's just like G-sports, game sports.
Speaker 1: No, it's sports and games.
Speaker 1: Esports are just sports because they involve physical athletic ability.
Speaker 1: Even though it's only the athletic ability of your hands, it's still athletic ability.
Speaker 1: Something like chess is not a sport.
Speaker 1: It's just a game because there is no athletic ability required or tested by the game itself.
Speaker 0: So, poker is on ESPN 2 or 3 or whatever, but that's a game, not a sport.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Unless you had jungle poker.
Speaker 0: Jungle poker.
Speaker 0: Poker boxing.
Speaker 0: So, you flip over a card and whoever grabs the totem first gets that card.
Speaker 1: Poker boxing.
Speaker 0: I would poker box.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, you wouldn't because probably the best people at poker boxing would probably be boxers and not poker players.
Speaker 1: So, you would just get the KO.
Speaker 0: No, you just got to get someone who's immune.
Speaker 1: Someone like you stand up and then a professional boxer stands up.
Speaker 1: It's like I fold.
Speaker 0: You got to get the kind of person.
Speaker 0: I fold.
Speaker 1: It's all you.
Speaker 1: I'm all in.
Speaker 1: I fold.
Speaker 0: Who could hold out against Mike Tyson until his arms got tired.
Speaker 1: Nobody.
Speaker 0: A couple people were able to.
Speaker 0: Zero people.
Speaker 0: One or two people.
Speaker 1: No one on earth.
Speaker 0: I think Mike Tyson's got a TV show now, that cartoon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he does.
Speaker 1: It's basically Scooby Doo plus Mike Tyson plus Adult Swim.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's a thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not watching that.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: So, with all that, I was doing one of the panels at PAX and I talked about bad feedback and bad heuristics in games and I used Dodas and League of Legends, all those MOBAs as an example.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: In the US, when we shit all over MOBAs, people get really mad.
Speaker 1: I know they don't get really mad.
Speaker 0: But there's a little bit of like, "Oh,
Speaker 0: boo.".
Speaker 1: People love those games and if they're one of the people who plays those games, they defend them to some extent.
Speaker 0: In Australia, the people who came up to me after the panel play a lot of MOBAs and were like, "Wow, that explains why I am not the world champion at MOBAs.
Speaker 0: Playing MOBAs doesn't teach you MOBAs.
Speaker 0: How should I learn
Speaker 0: MOBAs?".
Speaker 0: And I was like, "Just find someone who's good and get them to teach
Speaker 0: you.".
Speaker 0: Is there any other way?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Read all the wikis and facts and practice like crazy.
Speaker 0: Or write a wiki by reverse engineering the whole game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, decompile the source code and figure out frame timings and whatnot.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's just like a fighting game.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So when I was in Paxos, another thing is I brought up Five Nights at Freddy's, so I was talking about horror games.
Speaker 1: My sister actually made a Let's Play of that for her work.
Speaker 0: I started recording myself playing it, live streaming it.
Speaker 0: I'm not interested in, but no one's really done a teardown of the mechanics.
Speaker 0: And I'm doing one of those kinds of videos like, "This game's jump
Speaker 0: scares.".
Speaker 1: Welcome, you're not playing TIE Fighter.
Speaker 0: 'Cause I just got back.
Speaker 1: No, I played TIE Fighter when you were away.
Speaker 0: And I don't have a joystick yet.
Speaker 1: If you play the 1994 version, you can use mouse and keyboard.
Speaker 0: Why the fuck would you even?
Speaker 1: It actually worked pretty well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not TIE Fighter.
Speaker 0: That's like... It worked.
Speaker 1: Would you rather do that?
Speaker 1: There were no TIE Fighter at all.
Speaker 0: No TIE Fighter.
Speaker 0: No, I'll play it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's good.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: The emperor is pleased with my performance.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you're playing... What about the shadow guy?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got a promotion from him.
Speaker 0: Do you have a tattoo?
Speaker 1: Not yet.
Speaker 1: I'm working on it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna live stream the shit out of some TIE Fighter, I have to get a joystick.
Speaker 1: I thought you had one around here.
Speaker 0: No, I did.
Speaker 0: So I did.
Speaker 0: But that joystick, I'm pretty sure doesn't actually work.
Speaker 0: And I haven't used it in a decade, so.
Speaker 1: I'll take it.
Speaker 0: I don't even know where it is.
Speaker 0: I might have thrown it away.
Speaker 0: Maybe in that blue suitcase.
Speaker 1: In one of these boxes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm looking at a line.
Speaker 0: Actually, there were a bunch of joysticks for sale at PAXOS.
Speaker 0: And they looked real nice.
Speaker 0: But things are expensive in Australia.
Speaker 0: Except Uniqlo stuff was cheap.
Speaker 0: So anyway, Five Nights at Freddy's, regardless of... I really like that game.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have a lot of replay value, but I think no one's done a game like that before.
Speaker 1: It's no FTL.
Speaker 0: No, totally different kinds of games.
Speaker 0: There's also that duck song on YouTube.
Speaker 0: That video.
Speaker 1: The stupid duck song.
Speaker 0: Everyone bumps into it occasionally as a recommended video.
Speaker 0: It's one of the most watched videos ever on YouTube.
Speaker 0: That stupid song gets stuck in your head, waddle, waddle.
Speaker 0: And someone mashed that up with Five Nights at Freddy's, and it is apt.
Speaker 0: The only thing more apt than that is an image that I just found that mashed up something old and amazing.
Speaker 0: I found this.
Speaker 1: Where did you find that?
Speaker 1: Did you search for that on purpose?
Speaker 0: I was looking for a picture.
Speaker 1: How could anyone have combined those two so remote things?
Speaker 0: I was looking for pictures from Five Nights at Freddy's to make my panel, and I found this.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: So this is my alternate thing of the day.
Speaker 1: It's incorrect.
Speaker 1: You should say, "It's Freddy time," instead of, "It's
Speaker 1: me.".
Speaker 0: Well, so "It's me" is an inside joke for Five Nights at Freddy's.
Speaker 0: It's me.
Speaker 0: Basically, one of the things that the game does to kind of explain how the game is horror, there's text.
Speaker 0: There's a sign that says, "Out of order," and whenever anything weird happens, that's like the unexplained and creepy catchphrase.
Speaker 0: So if you look at that room when the game's fucked up, the sign says, "It's me," instead.
Speaker 0: That doesn't make any sense, and it's kind of unnerving.
Speaker 0: And then you hear a voice at one point that just whispers to you like, "It's
Speaker 0: me."
Speaker 0: And once or twice, "It's me," just flashes on the screen for no reason.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: So it's one of those like, there's a consistent, unnerving, and not really contextually explainable thing that happens, which is the kind of thing in proper horror that puts someone's brain ill at ease.
Speaker 0: Like when you see something that your brain can't parse, like when you're laying in the room late at night, and you wake up, and a shadow's a certain way, and you see something that your brain cannot parse, and your brain gets into this mode of, "What is that, and what does it
Speaker 0: mean?".
Speaker 0: Before your smart brain wakes up a little bit and says, "The curtain moved, go back to
Speaker 0: bed.".
Speaker 1: It's a shirt on a chair.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: But before the shirt on the chair part of the brain steps in, there's a tiny part of the brain, some old ancient part that says, "Whatever that is, I gotta figure out if it's
Speaker 0: dangerous.".
Speaker 0: So yeah.
Speaker 0: So that's my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Don't wear it out.
Speaker 1: My thing of the day, there are pygmy seahorses.
Speaker 1: I like sea creatures.
Speaker 0: I'm typing this into Google right now.
Speaker 1: A pygmy seahorse is an excellent sea creature.
Speaker 1: It's a really tiny seahorse.
Speaker 1: Now, pygmy seahorses, I learned a lot about them from this video, and you're gonna learn everything that I know about them from this video.
Speaker 1: They're really tiny, and the pygmy seahorse comes in two varieties, orange and purple.
Speaker 1: The orange ones, they basically, no matter which color they are, they basically live in some sort of sea plant for their whole lives.
Speaker 1: They just sort of, you know, hang out on the plant, and they look just like the plant.
Speaker 1: They have little nurples on them, just like the plant.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, look at those nurples.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So the orange one lives in the orange plants, and the purple one lives in the purple plant.
Speaker 1: And they live their seahorse lives hanging out in that plant, and then they die their seahorse death living in that plant.
Speaker 1: So scientists were like, "Hey, how come you never see a purple one in an orange plant or an orange one in a purple
Speaker 1: plant?".
Speaker 1: It's like, do they just, you know, and it's perfectly, you know, maybe there's just two different genetic variations, and the orange ones are born in an orange plant, and so they live in it, and then the purple ones are born in a purple plant, so they live in that.
Speaker 0: Or maybe like they get a pigment from like their diet, like there's a lot of possible explanations.
Speaker 1: So it was very difficult, but eventually they managed to snatch two orange ones and bring them back to like an aquarium lab place without them dying.
Speaker 1: So they did.
Speaker 1: And then of course, you know how seahorses do, where the dude carries the babies and squirts them out, right?
Speaker 1: So they had it, they got the two orange ones make babies, and they put some of the babies with the orange plant and some with the purple plant to see if they would all be orange or some of them would be purple.
Speaker 0: And what happened?
Speaker 0: I'm skimming Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: I don't know the answer.
Speaker 1: Damn it.
Speaker 0: So those are pretty awesome animals.
Speaker 0: Should we do a Thursday show on sea animals?
Speaker 1: Rays are the best, the end.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty, I'm a fan of dolphins, different kinds of dolphins.
Speaker 1: They're okay.
Speaker 1: Dolphins are all smart, but not that cool.
Speaker 0: Whales are good too.
Speaker 1: Whoo.
Speaker 1: Whales are sort of big and mystical, but it's no octopus.
Speaker 0: Well, octopus versus giant squid.
Speaker 1: Giant squid is the king of the sea.
Speaker 0: Octopus is more mischievous, in my opinion.
Speaker 0: Giant squid's a little more frightening and bitey bitey, but I don't really know a lot about either of them.
Speaker 1: 20,000 leagues, kind of.
Speaker 1: Squid is the best little cracking action.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, we are back and on our regular schedule, I've got a bit of a post about Pax Pox, I think.
Speaker 0: It started coming on today, but hopefully I will be good to continue doing shows.
Speaker 0: So on Tuesday, we will talk about Paxos and I don't know, what should we talk about?
Speaker 1: Some kind of game.
Speaker 0: Have we even done a show on Pendante yet?
Speaker 1: Have we done a show on Tie Fighter?
Speaker 0: Tie Fighter, Pendante.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of games to talk about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot of gaming news as well.
Speaker 0: Lots of game.
Speaker 0: We could just do game shows forever.
Speaker 1: And next Thursday, I don't know what we're going to do, but maybe you should select a book club book.
Speaker 0: So the next book club book.
Speaker 1: Oh, great.
Speaker 0: I have actually selected one and it is Watership Down.
Speaker 0: Why don't you want to read Watership Down?
Speaker 0: What's wrong with Watership Down?
Speaker 0: It's one of the most famous and beloved books in English literature.
Speaker 0: It's one of the more read books ever.
Speaker 0: It's extremely popular and there's a pretty interesting story as to how and why the book was written.
Speaker 1: I don't really care.
Speaker 0: You don't care?
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 0: What do you think Watership Down by Richard Adams is about?
Speaker 1: Bunny war.
Speaker 0: That's yeah, kind of.
Speaker 0: In my... So I was asking like in Australia, I was like, "Hey, book
Speaker 0: club.".
Speaker 0: I was asking a lot of people there because a lot of our newer listeners are there.
Speaker 0: People who don't... They haven't listened to old episodes.
Speaker 0: They don't know what our fucking deal is yet.
Speaker 0: They're young and naive and don't realize what assholes we are.
Speaker 0: So I was asking them like, "Hey, what book should we do on the
Speaker 0: show?".
Speaker 0: And a lot of people said, "Prince of Nothing.
Speaker 0: You should read that book.
Speaker 0: That book's
Speaker 0: good.".
Speaker 1: People said that?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Multiple people recommended it when I was like, "Oh, what's a good fantasy book we could talk about on Geek
Speaker 0: Nights?".
Speaker 0: And they were like, "So have you ever heard of R. Scott
Speaker 0: Bakker?".
Speaker 0: I'm like, "Have you heard of R. Scott
Speaker 0: And I quote myself, "I'm sorry, but I believe I have come before
Speaker 0: you.".
Speaker 0: So yeah, that is the book club book.
Speaker 0: You can just call me the darkness.
Speaker 1: I'd be like, "Do I know R. Scott Bakker?
Speaker 1: What do you
Speaker 1: see?".
Speaker 0: But a lot of nerds I know.
Speaker 0: What do you see?
Speaker 0: A lot of nerds, especially nerds who are like art nerds, they all read Watership Down when they were young.
Speaker 0: So I feel like I should read it.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: Or Emily just told you to.
Speaker 0: I have bunnies and Emily really likes that book and I've never read it.
Speaker 0: And I would like to watch the movie, but I should read the book first in my opinion.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to read the book and I'm going to watch the movie.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, PAX South is coming up.
Speaker 0: Hopefully we'll be doing one or two or three panels at it.
Speaker 0: And then right after that is PAX East.
Speaker 0: Badges go on sale soon.
Speaker 0: So watch out for that.
Speaker 0: And then not long after that is PAX Prime.
Speaker 0: And in between the two is Kineticon.
Speaker 1: There's also a magfest that we're not going to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, magfest is awesome though.
Speaker 0: So if you could not get...
Speaker 1: I heard Rebecca Sugar is going to be a magfest.
Speaker 0: So if you were unable to get badges or hotels to PAX South or PAX South is too far away.
Speaker 1: You should be at magfest.
Speaker 0: You should be at magfest.
Speaker 0: Magfest is, in my opinion, the third best gaming convention in the English speaking world.
Speaker 0: Number one is PAX Prime.
Speaker 0: PAX OSS as of this year edged out both PAX East and magfest, I think.
Speaker 0: But that's only because PAX OSS has a real...
Speaker 1: But you spent all of PAX, he's doing video streaming, so I don't know if your evaluation can really be...
Speaker 0: Ah, but I think we both agree that magfest is more fun than PAX East.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: PAX OSS has, it feels a lot like PAX Prime due to both internal factors and external factors, meaning there's food.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: There's places.
Speaker 0: It's nice to walk around.
Speaker 1: Well now there is.
Speaker 1: There wasn't last year.
Speaker 0: There wasn't last year.
Speaker 0: Last year, eh, big top, glad I went, memories, but eh.
Speaker 0: They had this big sign that's like, "Pax OSS 2014, now with less
Speaker 0: tent.".
Speaker 1: They get all that shit right.
Speaker 1: That's the shit they never fuck up.
Speaker 0: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So yeah, the election happened.
Speaker 0: You probably didn't vote in it because young people just don't fucking vote in midterms and that's why shit's fucked.
Speaker 1: People in the United States don't vote.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so those of you who do not live in the United States, to explain this to you, every four years we elect our president.
Speaker 0: That's the only time most of the people who vote, vote ever.
Speaker 1: There are elections every single year on the same day.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: That's the first Tuesday of November is the election day.
Speaker 1: Even if it's not the president year, in all those three in between years, there are also votes.
Speaker 0: Now every four or six or eight years, there's always either a member of Congress on the governor, or goopener, if you know what I'm referencing.
Speaker 0: Governor races- Or mayors.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Or- State legislatures.
Speaker 1: There's all kinds of judges.
Speaker 0: Judges who run unopposed always.
Speaker 1: Dog catchers.
Speaker 1: So- Sheriffs in some places.
Speaker 0: I don't need to explain this because apparently John Oliver just talked about this.
Speaker 0: So go watch the most recent John Oliver last week tonight and he explains how almost all actual laws in the US now are passed at the state level because our national politics is completely deadlocked and will be for another two years minimum.
Speaker 0: Probably another 12 years.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: So this election happened and the main reason I wanted to talk about this, one, I didn't really want to do a show the day after I got back from Australia, and two, a bunch of our smart friends got tricked and voted the wrong way on a proposition.
Speaker 1: Yeah, afterwards they explained it to them, they actually realized.
Speaker 1: It wasn't a situation where they disagreed with us and they said yes and we said no.
Speaker 1: It was a situation where they said yes, we said no, and then when we explained it to them they were like, "Oh shit, I actually wanted to vote
Speaker 1: no.".
Speaker 0: And thus the problem with democracy.
Speaker 0: So, our friends are smart people.
Speaker 0: Smart people.
Speaker 0: People who I know to be smart.
Speaker 1: Who care about voting and voted.
Speaker 0: They voted in a midterm election, they care, and they even did some research ahead of time.
Speaker 1: They are educated college graduates.
Speaker 0: They're worldly, they've been around the block, they have jobs and monies, and are smart people.
Speaker 0: And despite reading the bill and researching ahead of time, they voted the wrong way.
Speaker 0: So New York State had three proposals.
Speaker 0: The two they had voted right on, pretty much everyone.
Speaker 1: Sort of, right?
Speaker 1: Let's talk about the second and third ones.
Speaker 0: Proposal two is my favorite one.
Speaker 0: Proposal two was, we don't have to print an entire copy of every bill on paper and give it to everyone before we can vote on it.
Speaker 1: That one is a good one to say yes on.
Speaker 1: Obvious reasons.
Speaker 1: It's basically saying, allow Albany to do some technology because the Constitution currently forbids using technology.
Speaker 0: And I read, I did some research on the bill just to make sure, like, is there anyone smart opposing it?
Speaker 0: And one motherfucker, and the state level, is actually against the bill and argued that it will be to the detriment of the pulp and paper industry, and that that is a huge part of upstate New York.
Speaker 0: Pretty sure they were referring to their particular district in upstate New York.
Speaker 0: Luckily, it passed.
Speaker 0: We can stop killing a whole bunch of trees for literally no reason.
Speaker 1: So that one was fine.
Speaker 1: The third one was, let's basically have a bond, which is a loan.
Speaker 1: It's basically borrowing a ton of money, two billion dollars to buy shit for schools, but specifically to buy it for public schools, to buy them fast internets and fancy smart boards and all sorts of technologies that they don't have.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure they're going to waste this fucking money, right?
Speaker 1: That's the thing.
Speaker 1: It's like, on the one hand, I was like, I should vote no, because this is probably some deal where the company that makes the smart boards is like, hey, we want like two billion dollars.
Speaker 1: So just get the taxpayers to take out a loan and pay interest for it and give us the two billion dollars and we'll sell you a bunch of useless garbage technologies to put in your schools that no teacher actually wants and is useless.
Speaker 1: And I sort of want to say no to that.
Speaker 1: But then I thought, you know, that some kid is going to school and the Internet in his school sucks.
Speaker 1: And even though this horrible companies or whoever contractor is going to make mad corrupt monies on this, at some point, they'll be that kid in school and the school finally has somewhat better Internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And that kid will be like, yes.
Speaker 0: And honestly, our schools are so bad at this point that I really want to pump some money in just because that at least fix a few of the grossest problems.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's like we're going to spend rather spend two billion dollars on this than on something else.
Speaker 0: The people who are going to vote against this are like libertarians.
Speaker 1: I don't think they know nonsense or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Last time.
Speaker 0: The other reason I was for it is while Cuomo's for it and he can eat a big old dick.
Speaker 1: That's what he does.
Speaker 1: In fact, he can and does.
Speaker 0: But apparently a bunch of people, mostly conservatives, were against this bill because one of the people who has a lot of over there, oh, they don't want to pay for school.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: One of the people who has a lot of oversight over how the tech like what is bought and how it's used is Eric Schmidt from Google.
Speaker 1: Oh, how about that?
Speaker 0: And those people are all mad because they're arguing that Google shouldn't get to, you know, a big corporation should be like if Microsoft that it is sort of corrupt.
Speaker 1: That's what I was saying.
Speaker 0: Except Google doesn't really sell products.
Speaker 1: Microsoft and Apple actually.
Speaker 1: Mark Microsoft the most sells those kinds of products.
Speaker 1: Google doesn't.
Speaker 1: Google doesn't have anything like.
Speaker 1: Google doesn't make a product that they could put that money.
Speaker 0: Google does not have a horse in the race.
Speaker 0: Google has a guy betting on the race.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Like Google just needs people that like people who use tech more in school are going to be better Google employees down the road.
Speaker 1: I guess they have Google shortcuts on the computer desktops.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Eric Schmidt's the kind of person where if if he has some oversight, I'm at least confident that through all the bureaucracy that's going to prevent any intelligent thing being done with this money, a little bit of good might happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, it'll be better than, you know, someone who doesn't know anything about technology.
Speaker 0: I trust him more than I trust anyone in New York state politics.
Speaker 1: I mean, he's not a perfect individual by any means.
Speaker 0: No, he's not.
Speaker 1: But what did I easily Google his list of fuck ups?
Speaker 0: What did I say?
Speaker 0: I trust him more than anyone in New York state politics.
Speaker 1: He is a person who, despite being a CEO of one of the largest companies on earth, said, you know, what do you care about privacy if you got nothing to hide?
Speaker 1: So Proposal one, the one that everyone fucked up.
Speaker 0: Listen, the correct vote was no.
Speaker 1: The correct vote was no.
Speaker 0: He's got an.
Speaker 0: Emily voted no.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Several of our very smart friends voted yes.
Speaker 0: So I did all my research at the airport waiting for my luggage and then I voted on the way home.
Speaker 1: I did my research by following Zephyr Teachout on Twitter because I figured, hey, she didn't win, but she's probably going to tell everyone else how to vote.
Speaker 1: And I already did the research that said I should vote for her.
Speaker 1: So if I'm going to vote for her, I might as well vote.
Speaker 1: however she says to vote.
Speaker 1: So that'll make my job real easy.
Speaker 1: And she tweeted many times saying, good God, vote no on one.
Speaker 0: I knew one was bad just by reading it.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, this is why it bothers me that smart friends got it wrong.
Speaker 1: Well, it was intentional.
Speaker 1: I remember, you know, we get to vote on it, but we don't get the fact that it gets on the ballot and what is written there next to it is controlled by the people who are already elected.
Speaker 1: So you can't trust them to write the correct thing there.
Speaker 1: They're going to use deceptive language.
Speaker 1: And I did now.
Speaker 0: So Emily's logic was basically because we were talking about the bill.
Speaker 0: She was like, I read the intense and it was obviously like stopping gerrymandering.
Speaker 0: But then I scroll down, I read like the actual implementation and I was like, wait a minute, intent.
Speaker 0: What did she say?
Speaker 0: She basically said either this is just written very badly, like bad board game rules or it's actually nefarious.
Speaker 1: It is nefarious.
Speaker 1: There is no question it was nefarious.
Speaker 0: Revising states redistricting procedure.
Speaker 0: The purpose of this proposal is to reform the process of establishing new state legislative and congressional district lines that the Constitution requires every 10 years.
Speaker 1: So basically and it was we have a process for drawing the districts for the state legislature in New York state.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: The process also Congress.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: The existing process is mad, rigged and corrupt.
Speaker 0: And it's run by the Republican and Democratic Party.
Speaker 1: And it's all crazy gerrymandered.
Speaker 1: And we need to fix that.
Speaker 1: That is correct.
Speaker 1: This is your intent is to fix that problem.
Speaker 1: That is a noble intent.
Speaker 0: And the abstract of the bill says we are fixing that with an independent or neutral or whatever commission.
Speaker 1: That sounds good to rule number one of legislation.
Speaker 0: Whatever a bill says, assume it does the opposite unless proven otherwise.
Speaker 0: Whatever this summary is, it's probably the opposite.
Speaker 0: So it's fair.
Speaker 0: And the better it sounds, the worse it probably is.
Speaker 0: So basically it replaces the existing system, which is pretty vague and just like the parties sort of.
Speaker 1: So keep in mind this past.
Speaker 1: So this horrible thing is going to happen.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Instead, they'll form a commission.
Speaker 0: Now, in my research, I discovered that the commission was originally in this legislation called an independent commission.
Speaker 1: It is now not.
Speaker 0: There was a lawsuit that was one saying that because the commission would not be independent, they can't lie and say it would be independent in the law.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's fucked up that there was a lawsuit against the law and it was one and the law still passed.
Speaker 0: So they were trying to hide what the law did.
Speaker 0: They failed.
Speaker 0: And yet they still succeeded in lying about what the law did.
Speaker 0: Basically, what it does is it sets up a commission that's half Democrats and half Republicans and they get to draw the lines.
Speaker 0: However, and this is how you know, the law is bullshit.
Speaker 0: If their proposal is not approved by the legislature twice, the legislature can then modify their proposal as they see fit in order to pass one, meaning the legislature can do whatever the fuck they want.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this commission literally does nothing.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Even worse, the original system.
Speaker 1: you could be right, because I mean, at that point, from what we've heard so far, you could basically say, well, it basically just adds bureaucracy.
Speaker 1: at worst, right?
Speaker 1: The legislature is still going to draw the lines in the end anyway, so it doesn't really matter if you vote yes or no.
Speaker 1: So there has to be some other thing going on that would make voting no really important.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So the last clause of the new restrictions.
Speaker 0: Well, there are one, two, three.
Speaker 0: There are five restrictions.
Speaker 0: The top four are basically already covered by the existing system.
Speaker 0: Don't gerrymander.
Speaker 1: But they do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: The fifth one.
Speaker 0: But maybe because it actually says that someone could try to know maintenance of cores of existing districts, of preexisting political subdivisions and of communities of interest must be considered.
Speaker 0: That is not a requirement.
Speaker 0: Well, now it's a requirement.
Speaker 0: It wasn't before.
Speaker 0: So in the old system, reformers could theoretically say, you know what?
Speaker 0: Fuck it.
Speaker 0: Let's have a computer and redraw everything randomly.
Speaker 0: This prevents that.
Speaker 0: the existing gerrymandering is the best we can ever get now.
Speaker 0: We can never be less gerrymandered than we already are.
Speaker 1: It's locks it in.
Speaker 1: So someone can't like, you know, if this commission and the legislature both.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Let's say we vote in all new.
Speaker 1: somehow miracle happens with the current gerrymandered districts.
Speaker 1: People in New York State move a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: We vote in like all like Green Party, Green Party and Libertarians.
Speaker 1: A bunch of old people die and a bunch of people move and we still have the same districts and we vote in awesome people and they make an awesome commission.
Speaker 1: And that commission draws an awesome, just like crazy grid of awesomeness that is not gerrymandered.
Speaker 0: One, they violated the law, so their proposals invalid.
Speaker 1: And even if the legislature approves it, we would need another similar constitutional referendum.
Speaker 1: So we'd also have to vote yes, no on a thing like this again in order to go back and undo this.
Speaker 0: So this bill is bad for two reasons.
Speaker 0: One, it is fake reform intended to deflect attention on gerrymandering.
Speaker 0: Basically, all the people who voted for this and like proponents of it in the state can now say, look, I backed the reform bill to fix gerrymandering.
Speaker 0: And two, so it's fake reform because it doesn't actually do anything.
Speaker 1: And it's basically when I put on my TV commercial, I'd be like, I tried to go against gerrymandering.
Speaker 0: Joey Jojo voted against it because he's pro gerrymandering.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And two, it actually entrenches gerrymandering forever, but pretends that it is fixing it.
Speaker 0: So how did our friends get fooled?
Speaker 1: Because when I read this, they can't read or they didn't read carefully because I school I school lawyer to its lawyer text.
Speaker 1: No one knows how to read it.
Speaker 0: I did, but I read the actual bill.
Speaker 0: And at the bottom, where is it?
Speaker 0: Where is it?
Speaker 0: There's the line where I knew it was bullshit.
Speaker 0: A hundred percent where I can't find it.
Speaker 0: The speaker is so right reading.
Speaker 0: Here it is.
Speaker 0: If the speaker of the assembly and the temporary president, the Senate belong to different parties, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: And you haven't fallen asleep by the time you've gotten to this line.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but basically what the line says, I'm trying to find it.
Speaker 1: And that's not the line you skip over because it's so boring.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It basically says that the legislature.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, proposed amendment, 60 day deadline, which the court must decide.
Speaker 0: a petition challenging an apportionment plan would be.
Speaker 0: it would provide the legislature with an opportunity to correct any legal problems the court finds with a redistricting plan.
Speaker 0: Guys, if you can read the rules to a board game, you can read this.
Speaker 0: Maybe this is why we're doing our panel on learning games at Pac South, probably because no one we know reads the rules to board games.
Speaker 0: We have to explain the rules to them.
Speaker 0: Apparently, no one reads the rules to government and we have to explain that to them to right now.
Speaker 1: Imagine being an actual representative in a legislature somewhere on the town state, whatever level you are.
Speaker 0: Now, you might say, well, I'll read the bills.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you won't because you have to spend 90 percent of your time fundraising.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Oh, not only that, even if you had time to read them, they're all worded like this only 10 times longer.
Speaker 1: And you fucked up reading this.
Speaker 1: How the hell if you were elected today, how the hell would you read any bill and understand its full consequences if you couldn't even read this tiny referendum thingy?
Speaker 0: I think I know how to fix this correctly.
Speaker 0: I think I know how to fix this one problem.
Speaker 0: I got a crazy.
Speaker 0: this is this is usually you're the one who's like, I know how to fix this.
Speaker 1: So I'm going to Scott, I'm going to pull the rim, then I'm going to find all the reasons that you're going to shut me down.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: So here's my idea.
Speaker 0: So, you know, in school, we study literature.
Speaker 0: And we study movies.
Speaker 0: sometimes, like in high school, like you watch a movie and you'll read a book and you'll like write a paper on it.
Speaker 0: People in school, like high school should do the same thing.
Speaker 0: for games, like in English class, someone should have to play like Half-Life 2 and write a paper on it.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: And how is that going to help with this situation?
Speaker 1: and how is that ever going to happen until we're like 90 years old?
Speaker 1: There'll be enough old people dead for that to happen.
Speaker 1: And then kids will think it's mad boring.
Speaker 1: Half-Life 2 will be like fucking Citizen Kane and they'll be like, what the fuck is this shit?
Speaker 1: I want to go do my, you know, feelies with the, you know, VR.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So to pull a Scott and I'll have to escalate.
Speaker 0: So, yes, all that happens.
Speaker 0: We like kill all the old people with guns or something.
Speaker 1: So no, we are the old people.
Speaker 1: There aren't the old people who are in our way are gone.
Speaker 0: So we make it happen.
Speaker 0: But we also like in math class or game class, you have to play some tabletop games and like learning the rules.
Speaker 1: Tabletop games will still exist.
Speaker 1: You won't just play them in cyberspace.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're virtual tabletop games in cyberspace.
Speaker 0: There's a table.
Speaker 0: So you got to learn the rules of these games.
Speaker 1: And while these laws, you know, and then we'll finally fix gerrymandering and nobody will care because they were living in cyberspace.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And cyberspace laws all that matter.
Speaker 0: No, there's a culture book about that where the machines, the AIs, the intelligences, the minds are like, yeah, in our in our Internet, which we call infinite fun space, we have infinite fun all the time.
Speaker 1: The best space.
Speaker 0: But because the physical world like something could blow us up back there, we have to at least keep an eye pointing at that to keep an eye on all that shit and take turns.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically that's what they do.
Speaker 0: So if people had to learn rules to games by reading them, my idea is that the same percentage of those people who learn how to read rules as actually learn math from math math class would now be able to parse these laws.
Speaker 1: I do not think the percentage would increase anyway.
Speaker 0: I think it would increase, but I think it'd be like the one to two percent increase.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you just improve education in general, I mean, that your specific class isn't really helping.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's it, you know, it's just education in general.
Speaker 1: I mean, and there was, in fact, an English class, I think, in 10th grade, we actually had to.
Speaker 1: there was an assignment where we had to read and write instructions to things as if you were explaining it to someone who knew absolutely nothing other than the English language.
Speaker 0: There was a Science Olympiad event.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it exists where.
Speaker 1: what would happen is they give you an object and you had any any proper nouns related to the task or unknown.
Speaker 1: You had to teach those.
Speaker 1: So it's like to be like it'd be like teach someone how to like peel a banana and write those instructions, but you can't use the following words unless you explain what those words are somehow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had assignments like that, but because it was taboo, basically like here's a list of words.
Speaker 0: you can't use a thesaurus later.
Speaker 0: But our event was more.
Speaker 0: you just have to describe a process.
Speaker 0: So like here's an object, write instructions on how to build that object from those materials.
Speaker 1: Yeah, peeling banana.
Speaker 1: It's like, all right, there's going to be a yellow object in front of you shaped, you know, vaguely crescent shaped.
Speaker 1: That is the banana.
Speaker 1: The banana is an harder outer coating, you know, which is the peel protecting the mushy inside part that you can't see.
Speaker 1: yet on one end of the banana.
Speaker 0: I would say a stick bite it and keep biting it and swallow all the parts that you can actually swallow without choking spit out all the other parts.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that's my that's my.
Speaker 0: you know what that is.
Speaker 0: That's my loop optimized version.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: Very good.
Speaker 1: So otherwise, I actually voted for almost all Green Party candidates because I voted for the Green Party person on the governor just to be, you know, obscenity.
Speaker 0: Fuck you, Cuomo.
Speaker 0: And then I would have rather let the Republicans burn it down.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It like I would rather the Republican have won than Cuomo.
Speaker 1: So I guess people who aren't from New York don't know this story.
Speaker 1: So Cuomo is basically the only reason he's governor, his name recognition, because his father was governor.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So name recognition is basically all that matters unless like you get your dick out in public.
Speaker 1: I bet people probably don't even know that it's a different person than his father, whatever.
Speaker 1: Anyway, he's governor and he was basically having a fight with Republicans.
Speaker 1: He wanted to do something and they didn't want to do it.
Speaker 1: So he said, all right, if you don't do it, I'm going to create this corruption commission that's going to find all your corruptions and get you in trouble.
Speaker 0: And that corruption commission, much like the choo choo bomb in Smash Brothers, came right back at it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So the corruption commission, you know, was finding stuff out and then the Republicans eventually like, OK, OK, you win, stop with the corruption thing.
Speaker 1: We were going to come with the compromise and they got the deal done.
Speaker 1: She said, OK, now the deal's been made.
Speaker 1: I don't need you anymore.
Speaker 1: Corruption commission.
Speaker 1: But meanwhile, the corruption commission was not only investigating the things the Republicans did, they're investigating corrupt things he did.
Speaker 0: I want to talk to the people.
Speaker 1: That's why he took that corruption commission down.
Speaker 0: I want to talk to people on that commission because those are the Eliot Nessus.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So even though Eliot Nessus was a super dick in real life, he in fact said at one point publicly, this corruption commission can investigate any corruption whatsoever.
Speaker 1: That's totally cool.
Speaker 1: And they were investigating him.
Speaker 1: And that's when he shut him down.
Speaker 1: So independent of that doesn't really get much more corrupt than that.
Speaker 0: Independent of that.
Speaker 1: And people voted for this person for governor.
Speaker 0: Again, more people live in New York City, like in our area than the rest of the state.
Speaker 1: That's correct.
Speaker 0: But the rest of the state has undue representation due to shenanigans because it's full of old people and gerrymandering.
Speaker 0: And because of the way the state constitution is, New York City can't do some things on its own like minimum wages in the city, rent controls in the city, speed limits in the city.
Speaker 1: Even the MTA is a state deal.
Speaker 0: I guess that technically, but I mean, MTA trains go upstate, but still, so the subways don't need state approval to do really internal things like lower the speed limit because a lot of people are getting hit by cars.
Speaker 1: We actually won that one.
Speaker 0: We did.
Speaker 1: Not that it's helping.
Speaker 0: Cuomo and the state have fought de Blasio and the city at every turn.
Speaker 1: Basically, the interests of the state and the interests of the city are basically 100 percent opposed.
Speaker 1: What New York City wants and what New York State wants from New York City are the opposite.
Speaker 0: Part of it's because it's way cheaper to lobby the state than the city.
Speaker 0: So real estate lobbies do all their lobbying at the state level, and then the state prevents rent and land reform in the city.
Speaker 1: I mean, you go to the state legislature.
Speaker 1: How many how many people in the state legislature are from New York City?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, how many people even know the majority?
Speaker 0: New York City is not the capital of New York State.
Speaker 1: You go around and you convince a bunch of people who are from the sticks to do a certain thing that benefits the stakes and hurts the city.
Speaker 1: And they're all like, oh, absolutely.
Speaker 1: I'll do that, of course.
Speaker 1: Oh, and you gave me money.
Speaker 1: How awesome is that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll do that.
Speaker 1: And then the city doesn't have a majority of representatives in there.
Speaker 1: So the city can't just, you know, force the state to do whatever it wants.
Speaker 1: So that's basically a bunch of people in the sticks.
Speaker 1: I decide what happens in New York City because we're in the same state.
Speaker 0: I voted.
Speaker 0: I also honestly, as much as I hated Cuomo, I voted for the green because I was pretty sure the Republican wouldn't actually win anyway.
Speaker 0: And for comptroller, I voted for the green person because I did some research.
Speaker 0: They they sound like one of us.
Speaker 0: They were like, just legalize marijuana and everything else to just go crazy on everything like radical, radical, crazy reform, because pretty much what's going on there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't really vote in the rest of them because I wrote myself in on everything that was unopposed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all basically everything was unopposed.
Speaker 1: And I'm thinking right.
Speaker 1: So there are all these unopposed judges.
Speaker 1: Why don't?
Speaker 0: why doesn't one of us like right.
Speaker 1: What does it take to run for judge certain number of signatures on a petition?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So if I ran for judge, could I win?
Speaker 1: And if I did win, I don't know anything about judging.
Speaker 1: I would be like, you know what that means?
Speaker 1: My job was just to judge things like based on my judgment.
Speaker 0: You're really good at that, Scott.
Speaker 0: You were perhaps the most judgmental person I know.
Speaker 1: I think I could do a pretty good job.
Speaker 1: And, you know, I think people would want to be defendants in my courtroom, but I don't think that I would be good at.
Speaker 1: I think every case that came to my court would then get appealed to some other court and fixed because I'd be bad at it.
Speaker 1: And it would cost the state a lot of money just to have me as judge.
Speaker 1: So but it's not illegal for me to run for judge despite lack of legal ability.
Speaker 1: And if I won, I would be the judge.
Speaker 1: And then what the fuck would happen?
Speaker 1: Would that be my job now?
Speaker 1: Do I get paid enough to do that all day?
Speaker 1: or like?
Speaker 1: how do I judge things like I don't even know to wear a robe?
Speaker 1: Can I be like, you know what?
Speaker 1: My courtroom, no robe.
Speaker 1: Take that.
Speaker 0: You would either be the best or the worst judge that New York has ever.
Speaker 1: I'd be the awesomest judge.
Speaker 1: Good.
Speaker 0: There's no middle ground with you on that.
Speaker 1: But I mean, regardless of if it's me or not, somebody.
Speaker 1: Just imagine anyone who doesn't know how to be a judge being elected judge.
Speaker 1: How the fuck do you do it?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: being representative is actually easier than being judge.
Speaker 1: You don't need to know anything.
Speaker 1: You can.
Speaker 1: you just have to vote on stuff, which is, you know, something I feel pretty confident and even a reasonably intelligent person can learn to do.
Speaker 1: But being a judge is actually a skill based job.
Speaker 1: That'd be like, what if I got voted as crane operator and I knew nothing about operating cranes?
Speaker 1: People would die.
Speaker 1: What if I got voted as train engineer?
Speaker 1: Now I next day I have to go to the train and make it go.
Speaker 1: People would not get to work on time if they got there alive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it would be bad.
Speaker 0: Or you start optimizing for the wrong thing.
Speaker 1: And what do you do in places where you can run for sheriff?
Speaker 1: What if I get voted sheriff and I know nothing about policing?
Speaker 0: That could be kind of fun.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm sure I could figure it out eventually.
Speaker 0: Probably easier than judge, but I didn't look at the actual numbers, but I should go find like how many people voted for that one Elliot, whatever who's running completely unopposed.
Speaker 0: And then we just got to figure out could like if we put you up.
Speaker 0: And just ran a purely Internet campaign.
Speaker 1: No, not if we could run a real campaign is only a so small area to purely Internet campaign because all the other people in a story to vote for.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: You go to every nerd and young person thing be like, just lie to just be like, I will do everything in my power to legalize marijuana if I'm elected to the position that has no control over that.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, something we could really do is just run in the Democratic primary for judge.
Speaker 1: And then if you're in the D slot, you're on.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I I actually am changing my.
Speaker 0: well, I did change my party affiliation because I was unaffiliated takes a whole year.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: For a long time, because fuck the Democrats.
Speaker 1: Fuck everyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but so.
Speaker 0: Democrat primaries are the only actual elections, the real election.
Speaker 1: Your vote counts a lot.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, I got to be in their stupid party.
Speaker 0: And I don't think parties should get the party power.
Speaker 0: They do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they can exist just fine.
Speaker 0: They shouldn't.
Speaker 0: the state and they sit in the government should not run their primaries for them.
Speaker 1: So now here's the thing.
Speaker 1: If you get elected judge, what kind of judge are you?
Speaker 1: Am I doing traffic court?
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: like what court am I judging in?
Speaker 0: You know what my problem is?
Speaker 0: I knew that I knew about what those positions did in Michigan, and I never looked up the differences between Michigan and New York when I moved here.
Speaker 1: I'm glad they were unopposed because then I don't feel bad for not knowing.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: I only do research uneducatedly if it could matter.
Speaker 0: And I considered unopposed all the elections where it was like a Democrat and then like a libertarian.
Speaker 0: Those libertarians got like 40 votes.
Speaker 0: Green Party actually for governor got almost like five percent of the vote.
Speaker 1: It's third.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of hippies in this state in the city, you know, they're voting for that shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: My big hope is I want to see Zephyr teach out, bust out and next time there's a big election.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling she's not going to try to go for governor or anything, though.
Speaker 0: No, she's probably going to go straight to national politics.
Speaker 0: Oh, maybe that's the common trajectory.
Speaker 0: is people go for governor or like something like that.
Speaker 1: Run for House of Representatives in my district and get rid of this Maloney lady who's not the greatest.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she's not the worst.
Speaker 0: She's just Gennaro.
Speaker 1: She's not the greatest either.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, that's politics.
Speaker 0: See you next week.
Speaker 0: Talk about Pax.
Speaker 1: Live somewhere better.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.