Speaker 1: When they met the Oda King, I was like, "Aw, shit!
Speaker 1: It's the Oda
Speaker 1: King!".
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think Blue Blaze is definitely, uh, I'm enjoying it.
Speaker 0: So yeah, we're back!
Speaker 0: We're finally back!
Speaker 1: This show exists?
Speaker 0: Geegnights is back after a long hiatus, cause- How long is it gonna be back for?
Speaker 1: Let's do this!
Speaker 0: Well, I'm going to Australia in, like, a couple weeks, and then, so- So, four shows.
Speaker 0: Show number one, here we go.
Speaker 0: Guys, November is when Geegnights is coming back on its completely regular, unchanging schedule for a while.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's weird.
Speaker 1: Geegnights' birthday is Halloween.
Speaker 0: Ah, funny about that.
Speaker 0: Except on the actual birthday, I will literally be in Australia, where they don't celebrate Halloween.
Speaker 1: They don't celebrate Halloween in Australia?
Speaker 0: As far as I can tell, they don't.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: Uh, Scott, most of the world does not celebrate Halloween.
Speaker 1: You need to bring Halloween to the people down under.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, we brought, uh, indie RPGs.
Speaker 1: I'll send you some candy corn.
Speaker 0: Scott, they're not gonna.
Speaker 0: let me bring poison over the border.
Speaker 1: They let you bring Vegemite back.
Speaker 0: Oh, someone in the forum just posted, it was, I don't know if it was Vegemite or Marmite.
Speaker 0: They're both vile, so it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: But basically, it's like, Cheetah tries Vegemite.
Speaker 0: And the Cheetah's, like, sitting there, and licks the Vegemite, and then it, like, rears up back and back and back.
Speaker 0: It goes really fast.
Speaker 0: It's like, oh my god, like, it wants to kill you.
Speaker 0: It is unhappy about that Vegemite or Marmite or Starites.
Speaker 1: Mite is not for Cheetahs to eat.
Speaker 1: You know what Cheetahs eat?
Speaker 0: People.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Antelopes.
Speaker 1: Rims.
Speaker 1: And Rims cannot run away from a Cheetah, because a Cheetah is literally the fastest.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much just, like, Cheetah, and the only way to get faster than a Cheetah is jet engine.
Speaker 1: Not even bicycle will help you.
Speaker 0: Are there some flying things that can go faster?
Speaker 0: I mean, a diving hawk.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the horizontal speed.
Speaker 0: So you're focused on horizontal speed.
Speaker 0: That's your criteria.
Speaker 1: I mean, I can fall really fucking fast, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'll just take the elevator at the Empire State Building and jump off.
Speaker 1: I'll be probably going faster than a Cheetah goes sideways.
Speaker 0: It's good to be back doing the show.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, it's anime day.
Speaker 0: I kind of wish, you know, we think whenever we have a sort of hiatus like this, or a sabbatical that I go on for work, we usually build up a whole bunch of shows we can do, but we pretty much mostly built up Tuesday shows.
Speaker 1: This is game season.
Speaker 0: We went to a PAX, and we haven't done a lot of shows since then.
Speaker 0: We've got, what, like three games we can review?
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess so, yeah.
Speaker 0: It says three shows right there.
Speaker 1: Some of them are tiny games, like Sushi Go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think we could do one show of, I almost said Euphoria, Splendor.
Speaker 0: And Sushi Go.
Speaker 0: We could do a separate.
Speaker 0: I think Pen Dantay needs a whole show.
Speaker 0: Pen Dantay.
Speaker 0: Spoilers, guys.
Speaker 0: That's a game that's more fun than it has any.
Speaker 1: It's going to be the joke of that episode.
Speaker 0: Flouches are not jokes, and I have a flouche right now.
Speaker 1: You do not have a flouche.
Speaker 1: Why are you calling me right now?
Speaker 0: I love how that game basically escalated to this point of everyone has a flouche every hand, no matter what.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I hung up the phone.
Speaker 0: Who was it?
Speaker 1: My parents.
Speaker 0: Your parents are calling.
Speaker 1: Because you know what?
Speaker 1: You know the news, right?
Speaker 1: Tomorrow is Rosh Hashanah.
Speaker 0: Oh, fuck yeah.
Speaker 0: God damn it.
Speaker 0: So yeah, that means a bunch of my development team is not going to be in.
Speaker 1: All right, so news number one, actually tonight is Rosh Hashanah, which means by the time you hear this, it'll be Rosh Hashanah.
Speaker 0: That explains why a bunch of you need notices.
Speaker 1: Rosh Hashanah is not the correct way to pronounce Rosh Hashanah.
Speaker 1: I am well aware of this.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I'm going to tell you a story.
Speaker 1: I'm going to tell you two things.
Speaker 1: Number one, even if you're not Jewish, you should celebrate.
Speaker 0: You have told this story on Geek Nights before in like 2007.
Speaker 1: Did I?
Speaker 0: I think so.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I'll tell it again because I'm pretty sure no one who listened to Geek Nights in 2007 is listening now or remembers.
Speaker 0: I'm just getting this out here so the next time I repeat an old story, you can say nothing.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so story number one, even if you're not Jewish in any way, shape, or form, if you're like some goyim from Florida, well, Florida has Jews, some goyim from Mississippi, you should celebrate Rosh Hashanah because you get to eat awesome bread dipped in honey.
Speaker 1: Just take some apples and some honey, which you can definitely get at your grocery store no matter how un-Jewish a place you live in, right?
Speaker 1: And put the apple, cut the apple up, put it in the honey, and then eat it and go, "Fuck
Speaker 1: yeah.".
Speaker 1: So rule number two, well, story number two, when you're in high school at the Jewish youth group, one of the advisors of the youth group, his brother or uncle or something, I think it was his uncle, came to talk to us and he was a Vietnam veteran, the kind that hadn't gone crazy but still saw real Vietnam.
Speaker 0: He had an onion on his belt.
Speaker 1: He didn't have an onion on his belt, he wasn't that old.
Speaker 1: He was like in 50s, 60s, he was not an old person, he wasn't damaged in any way, but he saw some shit.
Speaker 1: He saw all the shit.
Speaker 1: And he told us a story about how he was Jew, one of the few Jews in Vietnam, and he got leave for Rosh Hashanah.
Speaker 1: And while he was on leave, an MP stopped him and looked for, was like, "Hey, where are your papers?
Speaker 1: Are you AWOL?
Speaker 1: What's going on
Speaker 1: here?".
Speaker 1: He handed him the papers and the MP said, "What's this Rosh Hashanah
Speaker 1: business?".
Speaker 0: Because
Speaker 1: if you're an MP who's not Jewish and knows nothing about Jewishness in Vietnam and someone has a leave paper that says, "I'm allowed to not be shooting people or getting killed right now," and it says Rosh Hashanah on it, that seems like a load of bullshit or almost so much bullshit, it couldn't possibly be fake because who would be dumb enough to write something so fake?
Speaker 1: Paper.
Speaker 1: So now, because of that story, I always say Rosh Hashanah, even though it's Rosh Hashanah.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well, you have a similar story about Salda.
Speaker 0: Salda.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, the Australian guy who taught me how to Salda.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Salda on Rosh Hashanah?
Speaker 1: No, that is not really a good Rosh Hashanah technique.
Speaker 0: Attack on Titan?
Speaker 1: It's Titan.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: Hanging out in the sun too long, getting a Titan.
Speaker 0: So kind of an aside, but if you ever go to Turkey, one thing you might like if you're a fan of Rosh Hashanah food is Turkish breakfast.
Speaker 1: What's Turkish breakfast?
Speaker 1: Because we know what Australian breakfast is.
Speaker 0: Nothing.
Speaker 0: So a Turkish breakfast, a traditional one, is you just kind of say, "I would like breakfast,".
Speaker 0: and what they do is they bring you a bunch of little plates.
Speaker 0: They usually have like three kinds of jam.
Speaker 1: How come the U.S.
Speaker 1: is the only country that does the one big plate instead of... It seems like every other country on earth does a lot of little plates, except the U.S.
Speaker 1: which does one big plate.
Speaker 0: Because we're stupid.
Speaker 1: I'd rather have a lot of different things to eat than just a whole lot of one thing.
Speaker 0: Why do you think tapas is getting...
Speaker 1: Unless that one thing is ice cream.
Speaker 1: Then bring the one big plate.
Speaker 0: Tapas Fusion is getting increasingly popular, I think because many people are like me, and if I look at a menu, what I actually want at any restaurant is a little bit of everything.
Speaker 1: Right, now here's the other thing, right?
Speaker 1: If I'm at home, it's not reasonable to cook 100 different things and eat a tiny bit of each one.
Speaker 1: So if I go to... I can easily at home cook a whole lot of one thing.
Speaker 1: So if I go to a restaurant, I would very much like to pay money for the opposite of what I can do at home, which is...
Speaker 0: Basically, you want the Lina inverse option.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: I still someday think we need to go to Salt and Fat with enough people to literally say we would like one of everything.
Speaker 1: So Michelin just released the, not Michelin star list, I think this next week, but the like gourmand something list, which is like the almost one Michelin star list.
Speaker 0: And yeah, the almost...
Speaker 1: It has to be places that cost like $40 or less.
Speaker 1: Like you can eat for real there for less than 40 bucks.
Speaker 1: It can't be an expensive place.
Speaker 0: Meaning these might be the highest quality to dollar ratio you can get.
Speaker 1: Pretty much all the places we eat, we're on the list.
Speaker 1: Salt and Fat made the list for the fourth year.
Speaker 1: Alo bars on the list, like the coals on the list.
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: All the places in New York that we eat, because we don't eat at the places that are on this list.
Speaker 1: So it shows that we know where to eat.
Speaker 0: The only place I've ever seen a high, like a higher average restaurant quality is Providence.
Speaker 0: But that's unfair because Providence is tiny.
Speaker 0: It's really easy to have all great restaurants if you only have like 15 restaurants.
Speaker 1: It was just funny to see like, oh, I like the same restaurants.
Speaker 1: these guys to job.
Speaker 1: it is to like restaurants like, you know, I didn't even read this list before now.
Speaker 0: Because Emily was like, you know, we always eat the same like five places for brunch.
Speaker 1: Well, if you're on this list, it means they're affordable and amazing.
Speaker 1: To get better, we would have to go to expensive and to pay less, we would get worse.
Speaker 0: So what Emily said was we always eat at the same five places.
Speaker 1: What we need to do is eat at other places on this list that we don't go to yet.
Speaker 0: So she went and found a list of like the best brunches in New York City just to see like where's somewhere else we should go.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 1: Half the list was places you already went.
Speaker 0: Four of the places were places that we walked to almost every week.
Speaker 0: And the only places that we haven't eaten at are in furthest Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot of faraway places we can go to.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I had some news because it's right.
Speaker 1: Let's actually do news now.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Actually news.
Speaker 0: So we can't blow our whole.
Speaker 1: actual news is today is Wednesday, September 24th.
Speaker 1: Probably way after you hear this.
Speaker 1: Well, no way before you hear this, it will have already happened.
Speaker 1: The return of the greatest animation on U.S.
Speaker 1: television.
Speaker 0: South Park.
Speaker 0: I would say that Adventure Time is actually the greatest for all factors, but South Park is easily second.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It depends.
Speaker 1: That's really close right there.
Speaker 0: I would not say that if it weren't for the fact that it's basically a tie game.
Speaker 0: Adventure Time has been going for a long goddamn time.
Speaker 1: South Park has been going for even longer.
Speaker 1: They both have the same thing longer.
Speaker 0: Ah, but how many episodes?
Speaker 1: Good question.
Speaker 1: The thing is, but the episodes of South Park are full episode.
Speaker 0: Well, here's what I'll say.
Speaker 0: Both the shows have the quality that no other.
Speaker 1: Let's not do what's better, South Park or Adventure Time.
Speaker 0: No other animated show in history.
Speaker 1: As a battle, no one wins.
Speaker 0: It is run long enough to be past the point of like, it's good because it's novel.
Speaker 0: And the quality average quality of episodes has only gone up as time has gone on with no deviations whatsoever.
Speaker 1: There's a preview for tonight's new episode of South Park after this incredibly long hiatus.
Speaker 1: And in that preview, they are taking full advantage of the fact that the Washington football team has lost his trademark and it was quite epically amazing.
Speaker 1: Perfect South Park as usual.
Speaker 0: You know, all that reminded me of is back as the student athletes.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm liking when they make episodes that say things that I already believe.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: South Park is actually one of my favorite shows ever.
Speaker 0: And you should all be watching it.
Speaker 0: If you've never watched South Park, it's wrong with you.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Man.
Speaker 0: And think about it.
Speaker 0: That show started, it had like three episodes of It's Just Kids Swearing.
Speaker 0: And I was already sold on that.
Speaker 0: And then it got good.
Speaker 0: So in very brief news, if you're a fan of Hatsune Miku, you know, there's a lot of nerdy stuff going on.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to explain what that is right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Super art fight rejected Hatsune Miku from the wheel of death because they were like, what the fuck is that?
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: Is this another situation like James Rolfe and his friend where it's like, wow, you are really pro in like this one arena of the world and you don't know about other parts of the world.
Speaker 1: It's like, really guys?
Speaker 1: That I think is the one thing that makes Geek Nights maybe worth listening to in some far-fetched.
Speaker 1: is that we are so great.
Speaker 1: We know about so many things.
Speaker 1: Aren't we great?
Speaker 1: We aren't experts in just one area.
Speaker 1: We know about so many geeky things.
Speaker 0: You know what the listener, there is no area of geekery.
Speaker 1: We know nothing about.
Speaker 0: what the listener would say is that we are wide, but shallow.
Speaker 1: Listen, even though we are somewhat shallow, I know less about, you know, wrestling, pro wrestling that a pro wrestling because there is a small but dedicated cadre of listener.
Speaker 1: Anyone.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There are many listeners who are big into pro wrestling and I know less about it than any of them, but I know more about it than I know.
Speaker 1: I'm well above average in my knowledge, despite not having watched any of it since middle school.
Speaker 1: I've been watching bits and pieces again, just because people mostly just because I as most so much information from those people tweeting and such and also reading comic books about Andre the Giant.
Speaker 1: There's like, oh, yeah, pretty good.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, obviously, I mean, all this stuff with the comic con is happening.
Speaker 0: So Hatsune Miku is going to be doing a concert in New York at the Hammerstein Ballroom, October 17th and 18th.
Speaker 1: I guess that's because the Roseland Ballroom no longer exists.
Speaker 1: You only have one option now.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So if you ever wanted to see one of those virtual idol, you know, watch it on YouTube.
Speaker 1: I see no reason to actually go.
Speaker 0: You can go in person if you just want to experience Sharon Apple before she turns against us.
Speaker 1: I have experienced it via YouTube, but I am going to go more interesting as part of the expo.
Speaker 1: They're having an art exhibit in New York City that I'm definitely going to go to because it'll probably just take like a half hour or whatever.
Speaker 0: And that's October 9th through 19th.
Speaker 1: So free entry.
Speaker 1: Now it's called Universal Positivity, which I think is the most concise possible way to sum up what a virtual idol is all about.
Speaker 0: Oh, so before when you were like, yeah, people, they didn't know how to make.
Speaker 0: it was normally when video games come up in the course of like my discussions at these conferences or anywhere outside of like super nerdery.
Speaker 1: So you're discussing nerdery at a finance place anywhere.
Speaker 0: I will say the phrase, oh, they make visual novels?
Speaker 0: to which the expected response is, what's a visual novel?
Speaker 0: cuing me explaining what a visual novel is in Singapore when there was a nerd there up.
Speaker 0: Everybody knew what these were.
Speaker 0: because when I said, oh, they make visual novels.
Speaker 0: The response was, oh, you mean Japanese fuck games?
Speaker 0: Yes, that is exactly why I was taking it back because I had already queued up the explanation of what a visual novel is.
Speaker 0: And I'd never in my life in that context expected someone to not only know what a visual novel was, but you so succinctly define it.
Speaker 1: That is exactly what they're 100 percent.
Speaker 0: So anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So this video was.
Speaker 0: it was one of those things where, you know, when you watch a bunch of videos of one kind, like YouTube starts to recommend videos and eventually you'll see videos popping up all the time till eventually you'll watch them.
Speaker 0: So this video popped up and it looked like some sort of animation and it was pretty good.
Speaker 0: The next day, our friend Judith tweeted about it.
Speaker 0: So I think she was watching the same videos I was watching.
Speaker 0: We both got recommended the same animation.
Speaker 0: Basically, this person is making like.
Speaker 0: it's kind of.
Speaker 0: it's like a student film almost.
Speaker 0: But I think it's just for fun.
Speaker 0: And they're making an animation to a song.
Speaker 0: And this is like the work in progress.
Speaker 0: So it's half animated and half kind of sketched out and just it's super high quality.
Speaker 0: And it's pretty good.
Speaker 0: And you should check it out.
Speaker 1: Talented person is making videos on the Internet.
Speaker 1: News 11.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Both YouTube and and a person I know told me to watch this video in the span of about 20 hours.
Speaker 1: So, oh, that definitely when you see that's the rule, right?
Speaker 1: Something appears so often.
Speaker 1: It means you got to check it out, check it out when I get home.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, you know how to get me to read a book, get a bunch of people I know to mention that book separately.
Speaker 1: And then and it helps if they come from different circles.
Speaker 1: Like if a person at work mentions it and then a person at home and a person in your family, it's like, oh, wow.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like when grandpa also mentions the hot today, Miku concert.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So what is my thing of the day?
Speaker 1: I remember.
Speaker 0: now you remember.
Speaker 1: I do remember.
Speaker 1: It is getting cold, which means it is time again for baking things.
Speaker 1: So I usually make tall house cookie recipe.
Speaker 1: And you might think that's lame.
Speaker 1: This is the most generic cookie recipe from the back of the bag.
Speaker 1: And that is correct.
Speaker 1: But do you know why?
Speaker 1: It's the most delicious cookie.
Speaker 1: That's why it's on the back of the bag.
Speaker 1: You can't do better or maybe you can.
Speaker 0: Oh, what do you do?
Speaker 1: They found.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they found, but which they told house.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It was posted on the Internet.
Speaker 1: The original tall house cookie recipe from the tall house restaurant a zillion years ago.
Speaker 1: Well, not really a zillion years ago to cookies are actually more.
Speaker 1: They're newer than you think.
Speaker 1: At least chocolate chip cookies are.
Speaker 1: So the original recipe is slightly different.
Speaker 1: Also, the cookies are way small, which means they're hard, not like all soft and gooey, chewy and whatnot.
Speaker 1: So I'm going to try to make the original tall house cookie recipe as it was in the tall house restaurant.
Speaker 0: Huh.
Speaker 0: You know, if it's if it's from the era, I'm thinking, then wouldn't the recipe just be the same, but it's lard instead of butter.
Speaker 1: Listen, it's not that old.
Speaker 1: Tall house cookies are like it's got earlier 20th century.
Speaker 0: And I'm saying look at cookbooks.
Speaker 0: Lard was most cooking until about the late 70s.
Speaker 1: I forget the person who ran who made the desserts at the tall house restaurant, but actually tall restaurant was a way big deal.
Speaker 1: Like it was one of the few places that had like a separate dessert menu, like maybe even invented it.
Speaker 0: Cookies have their origins in seventh century Persia.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: There are many.
Speaker 1: There were plenty of cookies.
Speaker 0: Modern cookies came to America in the 17th century.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: But the chocolate chip cookie specifically was an invention of the tall house restaurant.
Speaker 1: Also, did you know a brownie is a cookie?
Speaker 1: It's a bar cookie.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, it's a ball.
Speaker 0: I just call it a bar, but I mean, hamantashins are considered cookies.
Speaker 1: Plenty of things are cookies.
Speaker 1: Tall house, the chocolate chip cookie is what we're talking about.
Speaker 0: Cookie also be a cake or a pie.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: Search for the word pie up.
Speaker 1: Moon pie, a cookie pie.
Speaker 1: You can make a pie out of cookies or you could even make a cake flavored cookie or a cookie cake.
Speaker 1: ice cream cake also.
Speaker 0: So is that an ice cream or a relation to moon pies called a scooter pie is considered a cookie.
Speaker 0: Oh, called a malamar.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's a cookie.
Speaker 1: That's what that is.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They're excited.
Speaker 1: I would eat malamar's every day.
Speaker 1: Thankfully, they're five bucks a box, so I don't.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, in the meta moment, the book club book is still mechanical for Lebowitz.
Speaker 0: Did you get the spaceships?
Speaker 0: I have.
Speaker 1: I finished part two and I have to read spaceship part three and then I'll be done.
Speaker 0: So no, no status update.
Speaker 0: I'm going to read, you know, what green star is.
Speaker 1: I'm going to read it this week.
Speaker 0: Is it related to Laplace's?
Speaker 1: We'll do the episode next week because I'll finish it this weekend because I got I have literally nothing else to do.
Speaker 0: I got to read that book again because I barely remember it at this point.
Speaker 0: So I'm reading of all things.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to make the book club book because, you know, I read every book club book worthy.
Speaker 1: Then why are you reading it?
Speaker 0: Because I had to read a bunch of books while I was waiting for you to finish the book club.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: I should.
Speaker 0: just every book club should be one of these.
Speaker 0: I'll be so far ahead.
Speaker 0: But so I'm reading our E.M.
Speaker 0: Banks, one of his earliest not if not the first.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one of his.
Speaker 0: It's called the wasp factory.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: All I knew about this book was that it was disturbing.
Speaker 1: I was told more disturbing than ultra porn.
Speaker 0: Well, so I was told that this book was disturbing and quote, not like his other works.
Speaker 0: Oh, it was in fact his first novel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's basically about a kid who's a fucking serial killer and his brother, who I think is also a serial killer, and they're dead, who's oblivious.
Speaker 0: And that's what I got out of the first chapter.
Speaker 0: Okay, so we'll see where this goes.
Speaker 0: It's just interesting that that's the first book of someone who then wrote all the culture books.
Speaker 1: Other meta type things going to Pax Australia.
Speaker 0: I will be at Pax Australia.
Speaker 0: presenting not one, but two lectures on Sunday shows how desperate Pax Australia is.
Speaker 0: Sunday.
Speaker 0: How to win every game.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: But it'll be the solo version.
Speaker 1: So sad.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And on Saturday, losing.
Speaker 0: I just called it losing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because you had to do a second panel.
Speaker 0: Well, it's based vaguely on a panel we did a long, long time ago called Losing Should Be Fun that we've, we ran like three times and we even ran a version of it at a like nerd night at a club in New York years ago.
Speaker 0: But that was back before we videoed our panels.
Speaker 0: So we have no like video of this ever.
Speaker 0: So I'm updating the panel to modern time.
Speaker 1: Too much info.
Speaker 1: Meta moments.
Speaker 1: Got to be a moment.
Speaker 1: Not a meta month.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Uh, book a book.
Speaker 1: Pax.
Speaker 1: And you should find us on the Internet because we're all over the Internet.
Speaker 1: All the places on the Internet.
Speaker 1: We are there.
Speaker 1: We even have an old fashioned email newsletter that I should send out again soon.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: And figure out what to write in it.
Speaker 0: Both the panels that we were responsible for at Pax Prime are on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Well, you can just watch them.
Speaker 0: That was probably the fastest turnaround ever.
Speaker 0: So share that shit.
Speaker 0: Less than a thousand people have watched one of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So Gundam UC.
Speaker 0: We're a little late to the party on this one.
Speaker 1: Well, okay.
Speaker 1: So I'm intentionally late to the parties.
Speaker 1: This is for those of you don't know, Gundam UC.
Speaker 0: It's not ended its run in 2009.
Speaker 1: It's an OAV.
Speaker 0: Oh no, that's the novel.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at the wrong page.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It ended recently.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It's an OAV, seven episodes.
Speaker 1: Each episode is like an hour ish.
Speaker 1: So I didn't watch any of it until all seven episodes were done, which was quite recently.
Speaker 1: So I finally made it, you know, once it finished its last episode, it entered the queue and now it's sort of actually bumped up to the front of the queue.
Speaker 1: So now is the time to watch it.
Speaker 1: I've only watched two episodes.
Speaker 0: I've watched three and a half, so I've seen enough.
Speaker 0: So we'll review this.
Speaker 0: No real spoilers, obviously, but I can't spoil anything.
Speaker 1: I've only seen like two episodes of it.
Speaker 0: So I will say this.
Speaker 0: This show is gun to me.
Speaker 1: So that's the first, that's the thing that's constantly in my mind.
Speaker 0: In fact, you know what?
Speaker 0: This is the first show we have ever reviewed on geek nights.
Speaker 0: That is openly pornographic.
Speaker 0: This is pornography for people who are really into Gundam.
Speaker 1: That's exactly the same thing as I'm watching this.
Speaker 1: I'm like, wow, this is so great because I know everything that is happening.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, imagine if someone it's like this one scene.
Speaker 1: I remember where they meet the guy who is probably char.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: That scene where he's like, can you just take your mask off?
Speaker 1: He's like, all right.
Speaker 0: I don't really need your mask.
Speaker 0: You have like a fucking scar or something.
Speaker 0: What's the deal?
Speaker 0: And then the other guy in the room is like, oh, and that would be like the big moment in an old Gundam.
Speaker 0: And he was like, yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: He just takes his mask off.
Speaker 1: He's got his mask all the time.
Speaker 1: But he's like, yes, this room is a recreation of Albo accused.
Speaker 1: And it's like, if you don't know what the fuck Albo acute is, you're probably just going to sleep right now.
Speaker 1: So that's like a five minute scene of sitting in a fancy room talking.
Speaker 0: So it's interesting because I actually have not seen as much Gundam as you, but did you know the things that they were talking about?
Speaker 1: Like the one year war and things like that.
Speaker 0: I would say that I knew about half of the references in general.
Speaker 1: So I'm going to spend five minutes here to give you Gundam 101 because you're going to need it to understand anything else we say.
Speaker 1: So Gundam, you see, you see stands for universal century in Gundam, much like, say, Marvel comics.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of different Marvel universes, right?
Speaker 1: There's the Marvel universe, which is like the one.
Speaker 1: But then there's like ultimate Marvel and the cinematic universe for the movies take place and all these other universes.
Speaker 1: But they're all Marvel, right?
Speaker 1: So Gundam is the same way in Gundam seed and Gundam see destiny.
Speaker 1: That's cosmic era.
Speaker 1: Gundam G Gundam.
Speaker 1: Some bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Gundam wing.
Speaker 1: That's some other bullshit, right?
Speaker 1: Main Gundam.
Speaker 1: The Gundam that counts is universal century.
Speaker 1: So what universal century is, is basically right now in the real human world, we had BC, then we had AD.
Speaker 1: I know Domini.
Speaker 1: Then they have.
Speaker 1: you see the entire Earth has one government and we have colonies in space.
Speaker 1: It's a new era of humanity.
Speaker 1: It's now you see one.
Speaker 1: So the first Gundam Mobile Suit Gundam takes place in 78 universal centuries.
Speaker 1: Year 78, the 78th year after you see one.
Speaker 1: So Gundam, you see Gundam Unicorn takes place, I think, in like 90 something or maybe 80 something.
Speaker 0: It's basically it's just on the cusp of 100 years after you.
Speaker 1: It's two or three years after as fake char comments on constantly.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: So basically the quote end up until the release of Gundam Unicorn, the quote unquote end of UC Gundam as a property was Charles Counterattack.
Speaker 1: So this is two or three years after Charles Counterattack.
Speaker 1: Interestingly enough, relating to an old geek nights episode, this is decades before Gundam F 91.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh, yes.
Speaker 0: That actually makes some things make more sense.
Speaker 1: Gundam F 91 takes place decades after Gundam Unicorn, decades after humans expressed any form of emotion.
Speaker 1: Yes, but so effectively effectively Gundam Unicorn is like aftermath of it's a couple of years after Charles Counterattack.
Speaker 1: What's going on in Gundam land for all you Gundam nerds?
Speaker 1: We're going to spend half the time talking about the history of Gundam, not actually talking about it, though, referring to it, expecting you to already know it.
Speaker 0: All this does.
Speaker 0: the thing is it doesn't refer to this stuff in any way that is relevant to what is actually going on, except perhaps as allegory.
Speaker 1: That's the thing is it's Gundam Unicorn is not about the events of Gundam Unicorn.
Speaker 1: It's about these events only have meaning in relation to the things that happened in quote real Gundam.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Which is Gundam and Zeta Gundam and Charles Counterattack, though I would argue that you can only care about these things in their relation to those other things because you care about the past and you.
Speaker 1: And this is it's like.
Speaker 1: I don't care about who's this kid is the main character.
Speaker 0: And we'll get.
Speaker 0: we'll get to Belanges.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't give a fuck about Belanges.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But I do give a fuck about, you know, like our white base and bright Noah and Char and Amaro, who's probably dead, you know, at the end of Charles Counterattack, him and Amaro are effectively dead.
Speaker 1: As far as you can tell.
Speaker 1: Well, so yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, well, notice his evasive answer of are you Char?
Speaker 0: And he's like, it doesn't matter if I'm Char.
Speaker 1: But then notice earlier, he's like, aha, my opponent is the Gundam again.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, Gundam, you are still my opponent.
Speaker 0: Several of the references do not actually relate in a meaningful way to what's going on now.
Speaker 0: It'd be like if I said proper nouns from World War One periodically in conversations during World War Two, but didn't refer to them in context or relation to what was happening now.
Speaker 0: But I referred to them.
Speaker 0: So the nerd would go, oh, my God, he's talking about.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So let's actually talk about Gun Unicorn.
Speaker 0: So this show is breathtaking.
Speaker 0: The animation is amazing.
Speaker 1: So I'm watching this in my surround sound.
Speaker 1: And just like when the Gundam just flies by or any mobile suit flies by, it's like you're watching Star Wars in a fucking movie theater.
Speaker 1: And that's the thing, because it's an OAV where you're watching a TV Gundam.
Speaker 1: It's like, pew, pew, pew, pew, pew.
Speaker 1: And when you watch this, it's like, oh, no.
Speaker 0: When they the first Itano circus that happens pretty early on.
Speaker 1: Well, when he went, oh, episode two, where he brings out the gun.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And the gun grazes the one dude's mobile suit and just explodes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like the way they animate the gun firing and the sound is that you just feel how ridiculously strong the rifle, the U.C.
Speaker 0: gun, the unicorn gun, because it makes that noise like.
Speaker 1: And then like you see the huge everyone else is like, pew, pew, pew, pew.
Speaker 0: Granted, he used a lot of that ammo and he's the only he had two more packs on the back.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: But he's the only one with that special magic Gundam that they stole.
Speaker 0: So how the fuck is he going to rearm that thing?
Speaker 1: That's a good question.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: That's starting to bother me a lot already.
Speaker 1: That didn't bother me right away.
Speaker 0: But well, here's why it bothers me.
Speaker 1: So before I get into the not the negatives, but that he flew it from the one from the place to the other place, he didn't bring any equipment with him.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So how did they get it?
Speaker 1: Where did where did that federation ship get that equipment?
Speaker 0: If there is not either another person who you unlike another Gundam that uses that gun because they just have ammo for it.
Speaker 1: How did it get there?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like or like it might.
Speaker 0: maybe that's just a common gun.
Speaker 1: It's just powerful.
Speaker 0: So it's a special gun and they don't make an issue of his ammo.
Speaker 0: I'm really disappointed in this.
Speaker 1: Gundam is usually, you know, for being fictional.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: In terms of its science, not being hard sci fi.
Speaker 1: It's always incredibly consistent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is.
Speaker 0: that's what's bothering me.
Speaker 0: Think about.
Speaker 1: you might like the first question you might have if you were one of those people who's like, well, why are they doing this?
Speaker 1: It makes no sense.
Speaker 1: You're like a military fan boy.
Speaker 1: You're watching Gundam.
Speaker 1: The first question you're going to ask is they're in outer space.
Speaker 1: They have like capital ships.
Speaker 1: They can just fire ridiculous weapons.
Speaker 1: Why would you fly around?
Speaker 1: Why is it a good idea to fly around in a robot with arms and legs and guns?
Speaker 1: That makes no military strategic sense whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And they explain it.
Speaker 1: That's why they're always talking about fucking Manovski particles.
Speaker 1: Manovski particles are basically the made up science.
Speaker 1: excuse for why the people are fighting war using Gundam mobile suit technology is that basically they found discovered Manovski particles and they fuck up all radio communications and targeting systems.
Speaker 1: So basically all those technologies are useless.
Speaker 1: So what happens is when ships enter a battle, they just fucking fill the battlefield with nasty particles like crazy.
Speaker 1: So no one else can use like a targeting system and just blow their brains out immediately with one shot, like, say, Star Trek, dumb ass battles.
Speaker 1: So you're pretty much forced to go into the battlefield with humans and incredibly maneuverable occasionally a hyper mega particle cannons, right?
Speaker 1: It's like the only thing you can do, the most effective weapon in a battlefield is covered in these things is a Gundam.
Speaker 1: It's like for every kind of military fanboy question like that, they have an answer.
Speaker 1: If they fuck up something like, where did he get this gun from?
Speaker 1: That's pretty sad.
Speaker 0: Well, that's it.
Speaker 0: Because one thing I noticed to compare this to a different Gundam, like Gundam seed, Gundam seed, while it was a little more pulpy and less Gundam-y, the one thing it did is that it really paid attention to bridge discipline and like sequence of events in battles.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the captain of the ship in Gundam Unicorn is sort of derpy.
Speaker 0: But all the ships are like that.
Speaker 1: You'll notice that like basically that Lieutenant guy is really getting it done.
Speaker 0: Scott, how many times do the kids get away?
Speaker 0: or the kid just like runs over and pilots the Gundam on his own and every other Gundam, if a kid runs over and tries to pilot a Gundam, there's the long drawn out drama scene where he's like, you've got to launch me.
Speaker 0: And they're like, no, we're not going to launch your security procedure or whatever.
Speaker 0: And they just like look and they're like, oh my God, he's in the Gundam.
Speaker 0: How did that happen?
Speaker 0: Like the bridge discipline is non-existent and the show will pause the action to have lengthy dialogues far beyond what other Gundams did.
Speaker 1: Well, I think also more so than other Gundams, the Unicorn Gundam itself is more magical than other Gundams are.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Why is it better?
Speaker 0: Because of love and psychics.
Speaker 0: And I guess it's programmed new types.
Speaker 1: It's new type power.
Speaker 0: It's programmed to kill new types because it was made by the Federation.
Speaker 1: It's like the special mode is called NTD.
Speaker 1: That definitely stands for like new type destroyer detected or something like that.
Speaker 1: It detects new type something.
Speaker 0: Well, it detects a new type and then it only goes into hyper mega fuck you up mode if it's fighting a new type because it's designed to genocide the new types.
Speaker 1: Is it?
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: But then they argue that that's just a cover and there's a better program under there.
Speaker 0: You know, Laplace's box or whatever, that crab.
Speaker 1: So that's the main plot is that there's a thing called Laplace's box.
Speaker 0: But no one knows what it is.
Speaker 1: No one knows what it is, but the Unicorn Gundam is the key supposedly, but they don't know what it is or how to open it.
Speaker 0: All they know is that it can literally destroy the Federation government.
Speaker 1: Which would be very happy for the Xayah, the Xion people.
Speaker 0: Xayah.
Speaker 0: Your slip up there covered one of the things I was going to bring up.
Speaker 1: The space people would be very happy if they got Laplace's box and destroyed the Federation.
Speaker 1: The Earth people would not be so happy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Earth be in every Gundam though.
Speaker 0: If you have to pick a side, I mean, the Earth people are usually the better guys.
Speaker 1: Well, that's so.
Speaker 1: usually the way a Gundam plays out is it's that you've unified the Earth, but now there are people in space and the space people are upset.
Speaker 0: The space anoids.
Speaker 1: Right, because why are Earth people have any say over what happens in space?
Speaker 1: They don't know what it's like out in space where our lives are completely different from theirs.
Speaker 1: They're all sitting on their Earth and we're all sitting here in our space stations, right?
Speaker 1: So the space though, it's like, we don't want Earth ruling us.
Speaker 1: You want to rule ourselves, right?
Speaker 1: We don't, you know.
Speaker 0: And then Earth's like, no.
Speaker 0: And they usually commit some atrocity or hold it back.
Speaker 1: Usually the good guys are fighting on the Earth side, right?
Speaker 1: In a ship.
Speaker 1: And you know, the bad guys are fighting on the Xeon side in space.
Speaker 0: But well, because the bad guys, the people would be good guys, but really, then they commit some crazy terrorist act that starts a season.
Speaker 1: But there is never any like clear line between good guys and bad guys.
Speaker 1: The guys in charge of the Federation are evil.
Speaker 1: The people in charge of Xeon, the original people in charge of Xeon were good, but now the Zabi family runs the show and then that becomes evil.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's like the beginning of God.
Speaker 0: Now we got the princess of Zabi.
Speaker 1: Char is completely evil.
Speaker 1: He's sort of like a Magneto kind of character where, you know.
Speaker 0: Yes, Magneto.
Speaker 0: I am not evil.
Speaker 0: Come join the brotherhood of evil.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: He's sort of that kind of guy where it's like, he means well and his method is bad, which is usually killing people.
Speaker 1: And
Speaker 0: yeah, but at the same time, like in different Gundams or throughout history, a lot of times like, wow, the new types commit some horrible atrocity,
Speaker 1: but like destroying a whole, because yeah, they basically use terrorism because they don't have the giant army that, you know, the Federation has.
Speaker 1: So they'll be like, well, we're going to do a colony drop and drop an empty colony on the earth or we're going to destroy a whole space colony.
Speaker 1: Boom terrorism.
Speaker 1: So, and that's why they're the bad guys.
Speaker 0: This is gundam porn, but it's gundam porn in the sense that the visuals are everything everyone ever wanted out of anything they would see.
Speaker 0: with gundam and the proper nouns Come like a machine gun, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: Full of frontal Laplace's frontal red comet.
Speaker 1: So I think it's, it's really good, but I'm a person who knows gundam and has seen all of original gundam and all of Zeta gundam and is reading the gundam origin manga and is built more than one gundam and knows a lot about gundam.
Speaker 0: So I have never seen Zeta gundam.
Speaker 0: That's like, that's pretty much the biggest hole in my gundaming.
Speaker 1: Zeta gundam is pretty important.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: Did you still have those bullshit broken subtitle DVD pack or whatever?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I should just watch the gundam, I think.
Speaker 1: So people don't know this.
Speaker 1: There's an official gundam YouTube channel.
Speaker 1: You can watch many, if not most gundams on this YouTube channel in many languages for free legally, including gundam build fighters, which is in my queue.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about the show specifically for getting the proper noun porn.
Speaker 0: And even if you don't know what those proper nouns are, we might end up using some of it.
Speaker 0: It's fine because it works out kind of like the prince of nothing.
Speaker 0: How in the beginning there's all these proper nouns.
Speaker 0: From pretty sure you can gloss over all of them and they just sound like historical.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can follow the show, but I think you'll lose some of the, not having seen any gundam.
Speaker 0: You won't get why everyone flips out when they figure out who Audrey Byrne is.
Speaker 1: You won't have like an emotional response to the things that they say, but you'll be able to follow the plot of this story easily.
Speaker 1: You just won't like have any sort of feeling that you're supposed to have when someone's like, Oh, red comet.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Except my problem is that the characters in this show, their emotional reactions to things make zero sense.
Speaker 0: And it's like people just react to things randomly.
Speaker 0: Like suddenly people will react to something very strongly in a way that doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 1: That is pretty much every gundam, but yeah, more so in this one than others.
Speaker 0: Like watch, you know, another, another non.
Speaker 0: like proper gundam and gundam seed characters, emotional reactions to things made sense.
Speaker 0: People would escalate into like emotional outbursts or escalator deescalate to or from every episode, losing it a little bit more.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: But in this one, like in the beginning, a kid is already like acting kind of weird.
Speaker 0: The main character, bland cheese.
Speaker 0: And then he inexplicably sees video girl.
Speaker 0: I falling out of the sky.
Speaker 1: Uh, well it's not video girl.
Speaker 1: Hi.
Speaker 1: It's uh, it's lock is Klein.
Speaker 1: At least as far as you're concerned, it's Lala soon.
Speaker 0: So he sees her and rushes to save her and then skips all of the emotional attachment and immediately has a scene where he says, don't go.
Speaker 0: What do I have to do to make you need me?
Speaker 0: I'm obsessed with you.
Speaker 1: It's the connection between new types.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They're new types.
Speaker 1: They feel a connection to each other.
Speaker 0: But the way it's handled in the show, like if you, if you know gundam, you obviously know that he's a new type and she's a new type and like this stuff.
Speaker 1: And you know who she is even before they reveal it.
Speaker 0: But if you don't know all that stuff, and even if you do the way they handle it, the characters reactions just, it's like he dials the volume up to 11 suddenly in the middle of a sentence.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: And the whole show is like that.
Speaker 0: It's like the people watching who know gundam and the people who are making the dialogue and like the character stuff in the show, they're just kind of skipping all the beats in conversation to get to the emotional high point immediately as they can move on to the next scene.
Speaker 1: Well, I only have seven episodes.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So as a result, like characters reactions on a human level just make no goddamn sense.
Speaker 0: Like people will react in a deadpan fashion to things that should be big revelations and people will react with yelling and soliloquy about what does it mean to be at war and what is the root of all violence to completely innocuous statements by people around them.
Speaker 1: They also use tons of it.
Speaker 1: They're basically using every shortcut in the book to like get characters in there and get you to know them and maybe supposed to care about them while giving them the minimum amount of screen time.
Speaker 0: So you've got the guy who's basically the special forces guys, the big mohawk guy.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: No, but I mean, you got the guy who's basically mula flaga.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So it's like they show a guy.
Speaker 1: he's got a mobile suit and he has a little tiny biplane charm that they focus on every time on screen.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, he's the ace pilot character who's basically taking that slot right there.
Speaker 1: That's the guy.
Speaker 1: That's him.
Speaker 0: Well, we know what his fate is going to be.
Speaker 1: And it's like, oh, he, you know, he fights in space and he's clearly not at the bad ass new type level, but he's the top of the human level.
Speaker 1: There he is.
Speaker 1: He's the guy like.
Speaker 1: they communicate all that in a matter of seconds.
Speaker 1: And now they basically don't need to.
Speaker 1: They only only need to bring him out when they want to use him.
Speaker 1: They don't have to actually bring him out to develop him because they only communicate that to you.
Speaker 0: if you've seen other Gundam, I suppose.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, as I think a person who had seen no Gundam before would just wonder why they keep showing this guy, because it doesn't seem like he's doing anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he really hasn't done anything other than fight in space a little bit.
Speaker 0: He reacted to the unicorn Gundam just going apeshit on everybody.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the other thing.
Speaker 1: is people like it's Gundam, right?
Speaker 0: Well, because the whole like Gundam, like that special program had all been shut down because of past drama.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So it's like even in the scene where people are like, Oh my God, it's Gundam.
Speaker 1: I was like, what does it mean?
Speaker 1: What's the difference between a Gundam and another mobile suit?
Speaker 1: Now that's how do they know just by looking at it that that one's Gundam and the other ones are.
Speaker 0: I think the show does that part?
Speaker 0: well, actually, because if you've never seen Gundam, they're like Gundam.
Speaker 0: You're like, why is everyone flipping out?
Speaker 0: And then the Gundam starts fighting.
Speaker 0: And the kid who knows nothing about fighting basically wrecks the entire battlefield.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: But how do the people?
Speaker 1: So you see this.
Speaker 1: It's an awesome robot, but they knew even before it started fighting, they just saw it and they're like, it's Gundam.
Speaker 1: How do they know?
Speaker 1: And the reason that they know is because the horns split in half and made the two little yellow things.
Speaker 1: And that's how, you know, and the face, you know, when it transforms, the face changes.
Speaker 0: I like how the face change into gun so dumb into Gundam shape.
Speaker 1: And it's like, that's how they know.
Speaker 1: it's Gundam because the Gundams have.
Speaker 1: That is what a Gundam's head looks like.
Speaker 1: But you don't.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you're just a person who's never seen a robot show before, you don't know that that's what makes that one a Gundam and the other ones just mobile suits.
Speaker 0: They've also, there are scenes you haven't gotten this far yet, but there's scenes where new types interact with each other.
Speaker 0: And that shit is pulled off like the last episodes of Gundam seed in the earliest episodes of this.
Speaker 0: Like five minutes of the naked characters having their psychic flashback conversation.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: They're not having no delay in the new type action here.
Speaker 1: I mean, and it's weird because they're basically just reusing the same things from the original Gundam.
Speaker 1: We're like, you know, Char and Omro would be like, he's Char is nearby.
Speaker 1: He is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can tell.
Speaker 0: But they do basically everyone thing.
Speaker 1: Like everyone does a girl falling outside.
Speaker 1: I can tell.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go rescue her.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: How did?
Speaker 0: every episode has ding, ding, ding.
Speaker 0: It's like they're just, I am in each other.
Speaker 0: It's pretty funny actually.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like they just come out right.
Speaker 1: They come out with it right away.
Speaker 1: There's no hesitation.
Speaker 1: Just reusing all their old tropes hardcore.
Speaker 0: So in the second episode, I think it was the first episode, right as he meets Audrey Hepburn.
Speaker 0: Did you notice the two movie posters that were like up in the?
Speaker 0: yes, I noticed the juxtaposition of those two was on subtle.
Speaker 1: It's not really much subtle in the show at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Except for the, you know, the terrible secret of space isn't subtle.
Speaker 1: It's just hidden.
Speaker 0: It's hidden in a stupid, Laplace's box was full of love all along.
Speaker 0: Oh, and a Gundam.
Speaker 1: Like the secret is, oh, he doesn't realize he's a murderer.
Speaker 0: You know what they're going to find in there?
Speaker 0: The end jammer.
Speaker 1: Uh, that's a different, I know, I know.
Speaker 1: Oh, what can I say about this show?
Speaker 1: It's not much.
Speaker 1: I think if you're a Gundam fan and you know, Gundam, you should watch this because it's pretty kind of epic.
Speaker 1: If you don't know, Gundam, you probably shouldn't watch this.
Speaker 1: You should watch some other Gundams.
Speaker 1: And if you become into Gundam, then you'll eventually get to this.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But if you've already known all the gun and you know what I'm going to say, this people are always there making suggestions, like what Gundam you should read first or watch first or whatever.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And people would say, oh, watch.
Speaker 1: I'm still a little tiny bit sick.
Speaker 0: Little Flemmy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They'll be like, watch the compilation movies of the first Gundam.
Speaker 1: And it's like, all right, that's all right.
Speaker 1: It's not a bad choice.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Watching actually the first Gundam.
Speaker 1: That's basically the same thing, but takes a little longer.
Speaker 1: Gundam seed.
Speaker 1: Definitely watchable.
Speaker 1: If you've never seen any Gundams before.
Speaker 1: Well, cause Gundam seed at least, even though that's not universal century, it's basically the same story as the first Gundam, just different characters and different robots.
Speaker 1: Um, but I'm going to say now available in English, uh, not completely in its entirety, but much of it, Gundam, the origin, the manga from vertical.
Speaker 0: Oh, you were talking about that before.
Speaker 1: It's basically among it's weird.
Speaker 1: Usually when, you know, a manga is turned into an anime or vice versa at best, you get a faithful adaptation that is not really necessary.
Speaker 1: I would say Gundam, the origin, the manga is, it's basically the same story as the original Gundam 78.
Speaker 1: I think it's just better.
Speaker 1: It's the same story, only better with more stuff and you, you can read it slowly and you won't miss anything.
Speaker 1: And it doesn't really differ from it.
Speaker 1: It just adds more like in the gaps, like things that were possibly even just cut out of the original or things.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's tiny, tiny details that were changed in the plot, but they don't really matter because the novels and the anime are already different from each other in those slight kind of ways.
Speaker 1: So it's almost like it's sort of just compromises between the novels and the anime in some parts, but, uh, just read that.
Speaker 1: And it comes in these awesome hardcovers that are amazing on the shelf.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: My, my recommendation is still always, if you want, if you've never, if you've never seen any Gundam ever, I would almost say just watch War in the Pocket because it's kind of different.
Speaker 1: Oh, you just want to watch the short ones.
Speaker 0: Well, because War in the Pocket is really, really short.
Speaker 1: 8th MS team, which is still the best Gundam ever made.
Speaker 1: It's funny.
Speaker 1: Like the main Gundam is like, you know, the Gundam, but the best Gundam anime ever is still 8th MS team.
Speaker 0: Well, it's a combination of, you know, like at PAX, a couple of people brought up the idea of the fun coefficient of like, what is the amount of enjoyment per hour spent that you get from a media?
Speaker 0: And because they're so short, the ad, like the average quality ends up being way high.
Speaker 0: I mean, original Gundam has a lot of points.
Speaker 0: We're kind of drags for a while.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And don't watch F91.
Speaker 0: That thing was just, so the other thing that's interesting is the character designs.
Speaker 0: Remind me much more of like a Wings of Oniyamis than they remind me of older Gundams.
Speaker 0: The faces and the fact that all the hair colors are natural tones.
Speaker 0: It's all browns and blacks.
Speaker 1: I guess so.
Speaker 0: Very non like non stereotypical anime hair stuff.
Speaker 0: The hair is much more natural.
Speaker 0: So as a result, everyone would look identical if they didn't do really different faces.
Speaker 0: So the characters all have pretty unique faces.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, Gundam characters tend to have really unique faces.
Speaker 0: A little bit compared to older Gundams.
Speaker 0: But that might just be partly higher animation quality, bigger budgets.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, the animation and everything, you know, the production quality of this in general is just, you know, it's like, it's like they used to spend a million dollars in OAVs in the eighties.
Speaker 1: It's like that.
Speaker 1: It's like, whoa, holy snap.
Speaker 1: Look at them robots.
Speaker 1: Whoa.
Speaker 0: Compare this to a crystal, which has like the lowest that has the bare minimum production qualities.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: If only crystal had gotten this kind of budget.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: This kind of love.
Speaker 0: I feel like at least the people involved in this, if only it had been an OAV.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, the people involved in this, I think we're doing it not just out of money, but out of, you know, they're like love for Gundam.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it was like, you know, Gundam project.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, because Gundam will never die.
Speaker 0: Gundam is one of those things that will continue to have things forever.
Speaker 1: Uh, eventually there will be people, all the people who cared about Gundam will be dead and there won't be enough left.
Speaker 0: They might, we could foster in a new generation.
Speaker 1: How many new kids are going to watch, you know, UC Gundams?
Speaker 1: Be the unicorn or otherwise.
Speaker 0: So Kazuhiro Furahashi is the director.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: And it's notable because he's directed a ton of stuff.
Speaker 0: Like most of his credits are actually director.
Speaker 0: And a lot of the things he's directed are, in my opinion, very clinically well done, but also kind of emotionally sterile.
Speaker 0: Uh, Get Backers.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: He actually directed that.
Speaker 0: Uh, Chevalier Deon.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: He directed that.
Speaker 0: Uh, but then there's some, or, uh, uh, you're under arrest, the TV and the OAV, which I was never- Classics that we totally forgot about.
Speaker 1: that even existed.
Speaker 0: We've never reviewed that on Geeknights, I don't think.
Speaker 1: Old school, like kind of comedy anime is the kind of anime club material.
Speaker 0: Those are the kind of buddy comedies, like a Gunsmith Catch that we were just really into back then.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh my God, it's territory.
Speaker 0: And, uh, so out of all that, all that stuff and there's other things I could mention, uh, he also directed Binchotan.
Speaker 1: Oh, the, uh, the little moe cute thingy.
Speaker 0: That was the last moe thing we ever saw before someone told us what moe was.
Speaker 1: That was before we realized- There's nothing but like this girl with a lump of coal doing nothing.
Speaker 0: Oh my God, this show is adorable.
Speaker 0: And then older, wiser fan boy was like, you know, that's just porn for creepy people.
Speaker 1: They care what they want to get with a girl that's like one inch tall.
Speaker 0: No, they're really into the idea that she's pure and that gets them off.
Speaker 1: She's pure, but she has a lump of coal, which is dirty.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was when a cute anime was almost ruined for me forever when I learned the terrible truth of moe.
Speaker 1: Yotsuba exists.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: We're good.
Speaker 0: And bunny drop.
Speaker 0: Don't forget bunny drop.
Speaker 1: Only watch the anime.
Speaker 1: Don't read the manga.
Speaker 0: I'm still amazed that this one guy on YouTube, when we posted that, uh, judge anime by its cover panel, he was really, really fucking mad at us for spoiling the, uh, the fact that the girl and the dad, uh, have sex and get married.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know exactly how far it goes, but it definitely goes.
Speaker 1: It goes in that direction for reals, and it should not go even one millimeter in that direction.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: The anime ended at the correct moment.
Speaker 0: So, Geek Nights is back and we'll be back for like two weeks and then I'll be in Australia.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.