Speaker 0: It's Thursday, August 21st, 2014.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 0: The angry video game nerd.
Speaker 0: The movie.
Speaker 0: The experience.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So, every year since the year 2000, I've gone to the Wildwoods, particularly North Wildwood.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Even the year 2000?
Speaker 1: It wasn't 2001 or 2002?
Speaker 1: The first year.
Speaker 0: That first summer.
Speaker 1: I don't remember it being 2000.
Speaker 1: Maybe it was 2001.
Speaker 1: I graduated high school in 2000, so I guess that was the summer.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it was '01, because it was the summer after our freshman year.
Speaker 1: It had to at least be '01 at the earliest.
Speaker 0: Yep, because it was the summer after our freshman year.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, I've gone there every year, and it's this beach that I just love going to.
Speaker 1: It's not the greatest.
Speaker 0: Within a four-hour drive of New York City, there are almost no, I can name no better public beach on an ocean.
Speaker 1: I mean, beach-wise, right?
Speaker 1: If you discount the people on the beach.
Speaker 0: I'm just talking about the beach.
Speaker 0: When did I say anything but the beach?
Speaker 1: It's nice.
Speaker 1: There's nice sands and nice waters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: Nice times, and there's some good stuff there.
Speaker 0: There's those little birds.
Speaker 1: And there's a nice bookstore, and a nice alumni grill.
Speaker 1: Nice Russos.
Speaker 1: Good times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that Wawa right there that was replaced by the bigger Wawa.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the Boardwalk.
Speaker 0: The Boardwalk has gone downhill, which is interesting.
Speaker 1: Every single year it's gone downhill, and it hasn't gone uphill in any way.
Speaker 0: But it's only gone downhill relative to what we want out of it.
Speaker 0: Because what did we want out of it?
Speaker 1: Arcades with decent games.
Speaker 0: And literally, the garbage-ist of the garbage pizza.
Speaker 1: And even one place to look at something remotely nerdy.
Speaker 1: Anything.
Speaker 0: Yep, but every year there were fewer arcades, and now the arcades are just dead.
Speaker 0: There's literally...
Speaker 1: There used to be a comic shop?
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: There used to be like 15 or 16 DDR machines on that Boardwalk.
Speaker 0: I'm not even joking or exaggerating.
Speaker 1: And now, you're lucky if you can find one.
Speaker 0: Yep, there was one broken pump-it-up machine, and one in the groove machine that was too quiet and you couldn't hear it last year.
Speaker 1: The only current saving grace is that the place that used to have Fist of the North Star, which is not there anymore, now has play old pinball machines unlimitedly, basically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're talking old, like made-out-of-wood pinball machines.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure every pinball machine, even the newest ones, is somewhat made out of wood.
Speaker 0: The flappers were made out of wood on a bunch of these things.
Speaker 0: Mechanical scoreboards.
Speaker 1: Yes, the good kind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know what?
Speaker 0: You know how we always talk about how our one, like the biggest regret we both have in life, is not going to PAX as sooner than we did?
Speaker 0: I do have a second, like my second regret in life on that list, is not buying that Fist of the North Star cabinet when it was on sale.
Speaker 1: I do not regret not buying that.
Speaker 0: Come on, it was like 800 bucks.
Speaker 1: Okay, and getting it somewhere and keeping it somewhere, etc.
Speaker 0: If I saw that machine on sale in Wildwood for 800 bucks today, I would buy it and deal with all those consequences later.
Speaker 1: And it barely worked, and where would you put it?
Speaker 0: I would have fixed it, because that would have been awesome.
Speaker 0: Where would I put it?
Speaker 0: Living room.
Speaker 1: There's nowhere to put it in there.
Speaker 0: I could fit it in there.
Speaker 1: That would take up your whole living room.
Speaker 0: It's not that big.
Speaker 1: It would have to also be your television.
Speaker 1: It would be a vertical television.
Speaker 0: I would replace the wine cabinet.
Speaker 1: You could only watch it laying on your side.
Speaker 0: I could replace the piano or the wine cabinet.
Speaker 1: You could replace the piano, then no one can sit at the table.
Speaker 0: I just really want that thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really want a DDR machine.
Speaker 1: You don't see me buying one.
Speaker 0: I had to book a place, because for the first time, I'm not just staying at a friend's house, because the friend had a baby.
Speaker 1: I feel like half the reason to go is because all these people I know are going, and spending time with them.
Speaker 0: Some of those people are going anyway, so that friend is going regardless.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: But arriving Saturday, because for them, a day trip's fine, but a day trip for us sucks.
Speaker 0: So he's going to be there Saturday afternoon.
Speaker 1: Then why are you booking a place?
Speaker 0: Because we want to get there Friday.
Speaker 1: Okay, but he's only getting the place Friday?
Speaker 0: No, I'm going to Saturday, too.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Solves a few problems logistically and all that, but regardless.
Speaker 0: It's been a long time since I've had to arrange transportation, or hotels, or order food in a place where no one knows how to use the internet.
Speaker 0: Good God, can you not?
Speaker 0: I had to call hotels and be like, "What do your rooms cost?
Speaker 0: Do you have one available on this weekend?
Speaker 0: Do you have
Speaker 0: parking?".
Speaker 0: A lot of these people don't even have email addresses.
Speaker 0: Every hotel there, if they have a website, has a rates page.
Speaker 0: that is their gigantic page.
Speaker 0: that explains this really convoluted system for what their rooms cost, and there's no way to know if they have vacancies or not other than calling them.
Speaker 0: A few places have email addresses.
Speaker 1: Let's contrast this to Australia, where we stayed at an equally tiny motel on some island in the off-season, and not only were we able to handle that entire thing technologically,
Speaker 0: but
Speaker 1: the dude, when we showed up there in the little motel office in the front, was able to use the internet on some sort of local island land
Speaker 0: or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he was like, "Here's the tide schedule in case you go
Speaker 0: hiking.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, he knew when the boat that went out to look at the seals was coming and leaving, a daily report came in.
Speaker 0: Yep, when he said, "One moment, let me see what the schedule
Speaker 0: is.".
Speaker 1: We could buy tickets to anything on the whole island at any other place on the island because they all partnered with each other technologically.
Speaker 0: Seriously though, and I was like, "Oh, maybe I'll just do
Speaker 0: Airbnb.".
Speaker 0: No one in Wildwood uses Airbnb.
Speaker 0: Zero.
Speaker 1: I feel like if you bought a hotel and just made it internet-y, that you could basically fill up immediately because you would get all the business from anyone who was internet-y.
Speaker 0: So I discovered something, and I kind of want to do some investigative journalism on this because I just booked directly with hotels on their websites.
Speaker 0: That's what you do.
Speaker 0: So I looked on Hotels.com, like one of those kinds of sites.
Speaker 1: Or Priceline or one of those.
Speaker 0: And they listed a lot of these hotels that don't have online registration.
Speaker 0: And they listed them at prices that were like $200+ above the rate if you call the hotel directly.
Speaker 0: I think these hotels are just smart enough to make a room online somewhere with a ridiculous price that no one will ever reserve.
Speaker 0: because if someone does, jackpot!
Speaker 0: And if no one does, free advertisement for the hotel on the site that internet people are looking at.
Speaker 1: You're neglecting another possibility.
Speaker 1: The Priceline, or whoever what site it is, sees this hotel as not internet-y and just fucking lists it at a ridiculous price, and if you buy it, that money is like a service charge that uses for them to deal with the bullshit of calling the hotel.
Speaker 0: You know, it is also possible, but based on reading some reviews people had on other sites, I saw that a common refrain... These hotels are like...
Speaker 1: I registered for this hotel at Hotels.com and I got there and they didn't know who I was?
Speaker 0: It was more the hotels themselves responding on like Yelp saying, "Yeah, just call us direct.
Speaker 0: Don't use the room that we put up on
Speaker 0: whatever.com.".
Speaker 0: So I think the hotels do it.
Speaker 0: No, it's weird.
Speaker 0: It's weird when I interact with a small business that seems to be like family-run, or the people who run it take things personally and take a personal interest in these really low-level things, and I kind of actually really prefer the faceless corporate interactions in these situations.
Speaker 1: That's why it's much better to have the management company and not a landlord as a human being.
Speaker 0: I like the fact that while we've had issues with our apartment, our landlord is a faceless company that gives zero fucks about us, which means they don't pry too much into my business.
Speaker 0: Unlike some other friends we know and their landlord issues.
Speaker 0: So yeah, the moral of the story, it really sucks when businesses don't do stuff on the internet, and there is a divide between businesses that are internet and businesses that are not, and I think the place that's happening first...
Speaker 1: There's a divide between the world that is internet and the world that is not.
Speaker 0: But in the US, like in New York, I think in the next few years, low, crappy-level Chinese places that aren't on Grubhub are just going out of business, unless they're in Chinatown.
Speaker 0: I think bit by bit, things that you can't order online are invisible.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So remember that deal where the guy was really upset, everyone was using his monkey photo on Wikipedia, and some of the Wikipedia editors were like, "We've got to take this down,".
Speaker 1: and some of them were like, "No, a monkey took the picture, therefore it
Speaker 1: stays.".
Speaker 0: And there was a pretty good debate in our forum about that shit, too.
Speaker 1: The Wikipedia people were fighting with each other, and then I guess the people on Wikipedia decided it would stay up, one, in the Wikipedia community, and then in our community.
Speaker 1: And it's like, while I'm not really a copyright fan, I was actually siding on, look, this dude set this shit up, right?
Speaker 1: He didn't take that specific picture, but he set this up.
Speaker 1: His effort went towards creating this thing.
Speaker 0: I could, for example-- Well, I think Luke Burge and a couple other people, they pointed out there's a common precedent for setting a trap that automatically takes a picture.
Speaker 0: The trap doesn't get copyrighted.
Speaker 1: If I use a lightning trigger to take lightning photos-- The lightning gets the copyright.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That's ridiculous.
Speaker 1: It's really hard to fucking take lightning photos.
Speaker 0: If I spend the money for a lightning trigger and set that shit up-- I want to send you a cease and desist from an individual photon.
Speaker 1: And set the exposure for the skyline and whatever.
Speaker 1: If you believe in copyright, which, you know, we're not going to discuss that right now.
Speaker 1: We're just assuming copyright is what it is and we believe in it.
Speaker 1: I believe
Speaker 0: in copyright in the same way that I believe-- We believe
Speaker 1: in the current copyright law that exists in the U.S No, I'm
Speaker 0: saying I believe in it in the same sense that I believe that I'm holding a screw in my hand right now and a hair tie.
Speaker 0: Those are physical things that exist.
Speaker 1: If you agree with current U.S.
Speaker 1: copyright policy, under that law and policy, me doing that thing with the lightning trigger, I should own the copyright on that and be able to make money by selling that picture.
Speaker 1: That was quite a pain in the ass to take.
Speaker 1: It cost money, time, and effort.
Speaker 1: You know, it's not trivial.
Speaker 1: So, I was actually saying, well, yeah, you know, morally, whatever, copyright, I don't think anyone should copyright some freaking photo of a monkey, whatever.
Speaker 1: But, if you are going to say copyright, I was on his side that like, yeah, you own that monkey photo, dude.
Speaker 1: So I wasn't-- Just because a monkey pushed the button.
Speaker 0: But I'm going to say this.
Speaker 0: The only reason I wasn't is because I wanted to see a hilarious and fundamentally shaking court case.
Speaker 0: I wanted to see some weird, crazy challenge to copyright law.
Speaker 0: That's the only reason.
Speaker 1: So, today, the Copyright Office, which I think is actually part of the Library of Congress, it's a weird thing, anyway, they released their third edition of their official practices, which is sort of a law, but part of it is a thing that says, here are the guidelines for what we will and will not register as copyrightable.
Speaker 1: And so, registering a copyright is not something you have to do.
Speaker 1: If you just make some art, like you just take some paint and throw it to canvas, you own the copyright on that.
Speaker 0: Copyright is automatic and intrinsic.
Speaker 1: You don't have to do anything, but if you do register it, which is optional, then that gives you some extra benefits, such as, you know, it gives you the right to sue and receive statutory damages.
Speaker 0: As opposed to just direct damages.
Speaker 1: As opposed to other damages, right?
Speaker 1: So, anyway, in this new official practices third edition, they gave some examples of things that they will not register.
Speaker 1: The first example is a photograph taken by a monkey.
Speaker 1: Other examples include a mural painted by an elephant, because there is an elephant that paints, a claim based on the appearance of actual animal skin.
Speaker 1: So, it's like, I guess, if you see an animal and there's some art shaped in its skin, or like a cow where the black spot in the cow is shaped like something.
Speaker 0: Check out my cat that looks exactly like the Mona Lisa.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: A claim based on driftwood that has been shaped and moved by the ocean.
Speaker 1: So, you find a piece of driftwood that just happens to be incredibly awesomely shaped.
Speaker 1: It was done by the ocean.
Speaker 1: A claim based on cut marks, defects, and other qualities found in natural stones.
Speaker 1: You find a rock that's just awesome, and you just try to copyright the shape of that rock, because it's an awesome, you know, make it tricky.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, I found this rock.
Speaker 1: This is a sculpture that I made.
Speaker 0: I didn't read the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Did they give just examples or rationale?
Speaker 1: No, this is the list I'm seeing here, but it's like, this is a list of things they will not register.
Speaker 0: I was wondering what the rationale was, and I suspect that the monkey example, if that's actually in there, was added because of the current discussions.
Speaker 1: It just says, the law only protects the fruits of intellectual labor that are founded in the creative powers of the mind.
Speaker 1: Original intellectual conceptions of the author.
Speaker 1: If a human being did not create the work, the office will not register works produced by nature, animals, or plants.
Speaker 1: Likewise, the office cannot register a work purportedly created by divine or supernatural beings, although the office may register a work where the application or the deposit copies state that the work was inspired by a divine spirit.
Speaker 0: I was going to go with a much more direct challenge under the idea that they would have to argue whether or not the photographer intended to take the picture of the monkey or not.
Speaker 0: Like, did he leave it there for the monkey to find, or did the monkey just find it?
Speaker 1: I'm sure he intended for monkeys to come and take the picture, but that specific picture of monkey taking that pose was just, you know, the luck of the draw, right?
Speaker 1: He was going to get monkey pictures.
Speaker 1: He set it up as a monkey trap.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: He could have just been killed by monkeys.
Speaker 1: It's like, if I take pictures of lightning with a lightning trigger, it's like, yeah, I intended to take pictures of lightning in that frame with this exposure, but did I know that exact lightning bolt shape was going to happen?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: I can't.
Speaker 1: I'm not supposed to control the fucking light, Thor.
Speaker 1: If I was Thor, I wouldn't need a lightning trigger.
Speaker 1: I would just push the button and swing my hammer at the same time, right?
Speaker 1: And the lightning would come down exactly the shape I want.
Speaker 1: It would be the big lightning, penis-shaped lightning.
Speaker 1: I get the greatest photo of all time.
Speaker 0: So this actually might have some interesting far-reaching consequences.
Speaker 1: It does.
Speaker 1: I wonder how many copyrighted things now we can just fucking say, "Oh, that's public domain.
Speaker 1: Fuck you," because it was made by animals or nature or something.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, there was another argument, too.
Speaker 0: I was making a very side argument in the forum just for fun, that because of the debate around the picture, most uses of the picture were therefore fair use in discussion of the picture itself, because the picture was newsworthy and notable.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: So that was just kind of a side step.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of bullshit that the Supreme Court would do if they didn't want to rule on the actual issue.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so there you go.
Speaker 0: So I got a crazy story for you guys.
Speaker 0: So this is on FARC.
Speaker 0: I found this news, but this is legitimate news.
Speaker 0: A guy, I guess he's in the sneaker trade.
Speaker 0: Like, you know those kids who line up and buy those ridiculous, expensive sneakers?
Speaker 1: Oh, so he lines up, buys them, and sells them for more on eBay?
Speaker 0: I'm not sure what he actually does, but he's involved in that, and he went to his sneaker convention, and he made a lot of money at it doing his thing.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, I mean, that's his deal.
Speaker 0: So he posted on, it looks like, they say social media.
Speaker 0: I think it's Facebook.
Speaker 0: A picture of the money.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of money.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's all cash.
Speaker 0: It looks like 20, 25 grand just based on this photo.
Speaker 1: Now he's going to get robbed?
Speaker 0: He got murdered and robbed the next night after he posted the photo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, good job, dude.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the moral is, if you have 20 to 25 thousand dollars in cash...
Speaker 1: Armored car, bank, you know the bank has that weird thing, that metal thing?
Speaker 0: If you take a picture of it, post it to social media after you took it to the bank.
Speaker 1: Listen, someone might come...
Speaker 0: But that would not have stopped him from being murdered.
Speaker 1: Someone might come and murder you anyway, and then look for the money, and they can't find it.
Speaker 0: So, what's worse is that, I'm reading some follow-up here, because the story has more info since when I was first looking at it.
Speaker 0: The person who shot him and went to steal the money may have been there trying to steal his shoes instead, and may not have known about the money.
Speaker 1: Oh, and the money's still there?
Speaker 0: There's a, Fark is speculating that the guy might have sold shoes to this kid, and then when he saw the picture, became enraged that the kid made a lot of money and might have paid him a couple hundred bucks for these multi-thousand dollar shoes or something.
Speaker 0: But, I don't know, I have no idea.
Speaker 0: This is the kind of story where you will literally never find out what actually happened.
Speaker 0: But the moral is, if you have tens of thousands of dollars of cash, do not take a picture of it and just post it publicly on social media.
Speaker 1: I got two better morals.
Speaker 1: Moral number one, don't be involved in shady, stupid businesses like selling ridiculously overpriced sneakers.
Speaker 1: Number two, if you want someone to get killed, take a picture of money, hack their Twitter, just find out their password.
Speaker 1: You know, you can't hack this, right?
Speaker 1: Find out their password, post it on their Twitter with the GPS location of their house, and hope someone comes and robs them and kills them, and then you'll get away with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well that's just a twist on the old put child porn on someone's computer gag.
Speaker 1: It doesn't end with them dead.
Speaker 0: It ends up with them in jail forever.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, how Monte Cristoian is your revenge at this point?
Speaker 0: So things of the day!
Speaker 0: This is utterly, utterly wonderful.
Speaker 0: So apparently, people in Bulgaria are vandalizing old monuments to Soviet bullshit.
Speaker 1: Okay, well I mean, come on, if there were British monuments lying about in the US, and it was still, I mean, remember, this is recent history.
Speaker 0: Yes, and Britain.
Speaker 0: So in 1790-something.
Speaker 0: And Britain was being a punk on the international scene to us.
Speaker 1: Right, so it's 1790, you're in the US, there's British monuments, and you still don't like Britain and you live in the US, you are vandalizing the fuck out of those.
Speaker 0: So that is what's happening in Bulgaria.
Speaker 1: Of course, why wouldn't it?
Speaker 0: What these vandals are doing is painting statues that are parts of these monuments to be superheroes, like Superman and the Joker and Robin and Wonder Woman and Captain America.
Speaker 1: So not only are they vandalizing, they're excellent vandalizing.
Speaker 0: This is so high quality.
Speaker 0: My hat is off to you, Bulgarian punk kids with spray paint.
Speaker 0: These are amazing.
Speaker 0: And also, what's even more hilarious, Russia is legit angry about this and is demanding that Bulgaria take action.
Speaker 1: Demanding this other country take action to do something about some other person.
Speaker 1: It's like, you left, you gave me something, or I took it back from you.
Speaker 1: that was rightfully mine.
Speaker 1: It's in my house, and you don't like how I'm using it.
Speaker 1: I got my NES, it's actually your NES that you stole, and I got it back, and I'm playing Mega Man, and you're like, "Stop playing Mega Man on my NES.
Speaker 1: Buy the commando
Speaker 1: only.".
Speaker 1: And I'm like, "I'm in my house with my NES now, just because it used to be yours, because you were pointing a gun at
Speaker 1: me.".
Speaker 0: So there's a similar war crimes.
Speaker 1: I'm going to play Mega Man 2 extra, just to piss you off more.
Speaker 0: There is a war crime/monument incident that happened to me as a kid involving Mega Man 3. that's very relevant to this.
Speaker 1: War crimes?
Speaker 0: So when I was a kid, there was a kid in my neighborhood who was kind of a little shit.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: And there was another kid who was a...
Speaker 1: Did he get shot, because is it true?
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: So the other kid was one of those horrific lower-middle-class bullies, like stereotype to a T of this particular kind of bully.
Speaker 1: Like, was he like on The Simpsons, was he Nelson going, "Heh, heh,".
Speaker 1: or was he the older kids?
Speaker 0: He was more like Jimbo.
Speaker 0: So that kid actually, unrelatedly, was eventually shot to death by his mother after him and his father tried to light her car on fire.
Speaker 0: I learned that like five years after the fact.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, Jimbo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, beside the point.
Speaker 0: So the little shit one day came over to my house, and I'd hang out with this kid occasionally, just because, you know, when you're a kid in like middle school, you kind of hang out with a lot of kids in the neighborhood, regardless of whether or not you like them.
Speaker 0: This little shit was the kid who, like, we'd have a super soaker war, he'd show up with a super soaker backpack.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that means he had money.
Speaker 0: He did.
Speaker 0: So one day he comes over and we're playing NES games.
Speaker 1: More parents who spoiled him.
Speaker 0: And then he was like, "Hey, you want a trade
Speaker 0: game?".
Speaker 0: And he's holding Hydlide.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, "Maybe.
Speaker 0: What do you want for that Mega Man
Speaker 0: 3?".
Speaker 0: And he looks down at the Hydlide he's holding, and he's like, "I'll trade you my Mega Man 3 for this
Speaker 0: game.".
Speaker 0: He'd never played Hydlide.
Speaker 0: He was looking just at the cover.
Speaker 0: So I said, "Yes," and I took Mega Man 3.
Speaker 1: And you gave him Hydlide?
Speaker 0: Gave him Hydlide.
Speaker 0: So you didn't get ripped off.
Speaker 1: He got ripped off.
Speaker 0: He got ripped off.
Speaker 0: So...
Speaker 1: He got pissed.
Speaker 0: So then, later, he's over at our house, and I'm playing Mega Man 3, and I'm just cheating.
Speaker 0: So I'm doing that thing where you use the second controller, just like that awesome glitch.
Speaker 0: And he got really mad that I was playing the game wrong.
Speaker 0: And he wanted to trade back.
Speaker 0: And I was like, "No.
Speaker 0: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: We made a trade.
Speaker 0: It's
Speaker 0: over.".
Speaker 0: It's over.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry Hydlide sucks, but...
Speaker 1: You made mistakes were made.
Speaker 1: And they're gonna stay made.
Speaker 0: So then, the next day, the other bad kids, like, Jimbo's mom comes over.
Speaker 0: And Jimbo's mom says that we stole something from her son.
Speaker 1: Oh, so the little shit took the Mega Man 3?
Speaker 0: The little shit had acquired that Mega Man 3 under dubious pretense and traded it to me for Hydlide.
Speaker 1: So he stole it from Jimbo and traded it to you for Hydlide.
Speaker 0: Yes, and then had the gall to try to get it back from me by claiming, falsely, that I was playing the game incorrectly.
Speaker 0: Take that, Russia.
Speaker 1: So you kept the Mega Man 3?
Speaker 0: Actually, because it appeared to be stolen, and because the advice that my dad gave me, which applies to times we've interacted with people in Beacon, is someone and/or their family poor and has likely nothing to lose of value?
Speaker 0: Do not antagonize them, even if you are correct.
Speaker 0: Because they will explode themselves to explode on you.
Speaker 1: Did your parents then buy you a Mega Man 3?
Speaker 0: I bought Mega Man 3 at a garage sale for, like, 20 bucks, three or four months later.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 0: But it's kind of like if someone crazy in a beat-up car messes with you and maybe bumps your car and runs away, if you call the police and try to sue them, and they find out who you are, they're going to key your car and egg your house for the rest of the time you live in that neighborhood.
Speaker 0: So anyway, you got a thing of the day?
Speaker 1: I do have a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: After my long, rambling anecdote?
Speaker 1: So America's Test Kitchen did some testing, and they found something fascinating.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh.
Speaker 1: They saw it and I found it fascinating.
Speaker 1: So, steak.
Speaker 1: The thing that has been studied perhaps more than any other food ever.
Speaker 1: Common sense would be, if you have a steak and it's fresh, you just fucking cook that shit.
Speaker 0: No, you age steaks.
Speaker 0: That's common knowledge.
Speaker 1: Well, also that.
Speaker 1: But the point is, you cook it fresh.
Speaker 1: And they agree that is the best way.
Speaker 1: You cook a fresh steak.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Let's say you have just too much steak, and you must freeze it.
Speaker 1: The common sense would be, if you have a steak that you had to freeze, you don't want to freeze it if you don't have to, but if you had to freeze it, you have a frozen steak already and you want to cook it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: People, the common sense would be that you would thaw that shit to bring it to room temperature and then cook it.
Speaker 0: That is in fact what most of my cookbooks recommend.
Speaker 1: That is what almost everyone... America's Test Kitchen tested.
Speaker 1: what to do if you have already a frozen steak.
Speaker 1: And apparently, you do not let it thaw.
Speaker 1: You can cook it frozen, and it's better.
Speaker 1: Now, you have to freeze it in the correct way, which they also show you how to freeze it without it getting all frosty and shit.
Speaker 0: This is sounding pretty fascinating.
Speaker 0: But
Speaker 1: basically, the long and short of it is that when you cook it when it's already frozen, if you do it properly, the outside is going to heat up really fast and get cooked, and the inside is really cold, so as long as you cook it enough, and it does take longer to cook and more effort.
Speaker 1: But because the inside was colder, basically, the non-pink area on the edge will be really thin, and the inside will be mad pink, whereas if you let it thaw, the gray area will be a couple of millimeters thick, and the pink area will be much smaller, and basically, all of their tasting...
Speaker 0: Do I need to cook it at a different temperature now?
Speaker 1: You have to follow the instructions in the video I'm linking you to.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: For both freezing and cooking.
Speaker 1: This is only if you have a frozen steak.
Speaker 1: If your steak is fresh...
Speaker 0: If you already found the war atrocity, and you're just trying to mitigate the damage.
Speaker 1: Or if you bought a whole ton of fucking steak, and you have to freeze some of it, right?
Speaker 1: Because you cannot cook it.
Speaker 1: You have too much.
Speaker 1: You can't cook it all.
Speaker 1: Fresh is still better.
Speaker 1: The end.
Speaker 0: I like how many times you had to qualify that.
Speaker 1: Because obviously, I don't want people coming up to me and being like, "No way frozen steak is better than fresh steak.
Speaker 1: I got to ward that
Speaker 1: off.".
Speaker 1: Because you know someone's going to say that if I come and be like...
Speaker 0: Yeah, but blacked out of mine.
Speaker 0: I take quotes out of context in the community.
Speaker 1: You're overusing and sometimes really stretching your use of black dynamite.
Speaker 0: I like saying black... I just like saying black dynamite.
Speaker 1: You're supposed to say, "But black
Speaker 1: dynamite."
Speaker 1: I stretch and sometimes misuse.
Speaker 1: But black dynamite.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So in about a moment, the Book Club book is a category for Leibovitz.
Speaker 0: Scott will probably read it when winter comes.
Speaker 0: So hang tight.
Speaker 1: It's coming.
Speaker 0: It's coming.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I've read a few more books since then.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: We are going to be at PAX Prime.
Speaker 0: We are doing a lecture called "How to Win Every
Speaker 0: Game."
Speaker 0: Not just some games.
Speaker 1: Not just one game.
Speaker 1: Every game.
Speaker 0: It seems obvious that when playing a game of skill, one attempts to win.
Speaker 0: Interestingly, this is not often the case.
Speaker 1: Why are you reading the description from the PAX catalog?
Speaker 0: Even skilled gamers rarely analyze to any real depth the underlying mechanics of a given game, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: We'll teach you specific examples like Stratego, Settlers of Catan, and even football.
Speaker 1: So not that you can change your mind about going to PAX at this point.
Speaker 1: At least 99.9% of people on Earth can't really suddenly decide to go now.
Speaker 1: Whoever's going is going.
Speaker 1: Whoever's not going is not going.
Speaker 1: But the guidebook came out, and the schedule is already up, but because the guidebook came out, I actually looked at the schedule.
Speaker 0: I was looking at it too.
Speaker 1: And I learned two things.
Speaker 1: Number one, the guy who created Final Fantasy is going to be there.
Speaker 1: Not Nobu, who we've seen at every convention ever, who made the music.
Speaker 1: Not Amano, who made the art.
Speaker 1: The guy who made the game is going to be there.
Speaker 1: I never even thought of that.
Speaker 1: It's like a guest I wanted to see, I didn't even know I wanted to see.
Speaker 1: Obviously, some of the big names that are always there are going to be there, like I think Inafune is going to be there again with his mighty numbers and whatever.
Speaker 1: I learned something else.
Speaker 1: The guy who made Tetris is going to be there.
Speaker 0: And somehow is not doing the keynote.
Speaker 1: Are you kidding me?
Speaker 1: Someone I wanted to see, I didn't even know I wanted to see.
Speaker 1: And now I've got to wait up how long to go to that panel.
Speaker 1: And he also has an autograph thing that I'm not going to wait in line for.
Speaker 0: The thing is, ever since they stopped doing the Q&A...
Speaker 1: Should I go and buy on eBay a Game Boy Tetris really quick?
Speaker 1: I don't care about autographs, but just like, it's how you make Tetris.
Speaker 1: Are you kidding me?
Speaker 0: The third thing in my life that I regret is eating that food that gave me food poisoning.
Speaker 0: But the fourth thing is that we didn't get up a couple hours earlier so I could get my Zelda 2 signed by Miyamoto.
Speaker 1: I guess we could have done that.
Speaker 0: We could have.
Speaker 0: We should have.
Speaker 0: We chose not to, and we had to live with the decisions that we made because our lives are, in fact, the sum of the decisions we made.
Speaker 1: It just so happens, if you look at the PAX schedule this year, right?
Speaker 1: Let me just open my guidebook here for a second.
Speaker 0: I got my guidebook open.
Speaker 1: Hold on, let me open my guidebook.
Speaker 1: No, not MAGFest 12, PAX Prime 2014.
Speaker 1: Shows how many conventions I'm going to.
Speaker 1: My schedule.
Speaker 1: So, Friday, all I have in my schedule is a keynote.
Speaker 1: Saturday, there's a bunch of stuff I kind of want to do on Saturday.
Speaker 1: There's a video game data panel, which I think is an update of that one.
Speaker 1: Alex went to that one time.
Speaker 1: And Alex Levitt has his Twitch Played Pokemon panel.
Speaker 1: And there's a Luke Crane panels twice on Saturday.
Speaker 1: But I'm probably going to spend all Saturday playing Netrunner.
Speaker 1: On Sunday, this Tetris panel, is it three on Saturday?
Speaker 0: I feel like we should go to that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean Sunday.
Speaker 1: Is it three on Sunday?
Speaker 1: And the Pac-Man CEDX tournament is at seven on Sunday.
Speaker 0: Is that going to be your Sunday night?
Speaker 1: For once, the Pac-Man CEDX tournament does not conflict with anything else I could possibly want to do at PAX.
Speaker 1: This is the first time.
Speaker 1: They've had this tournament at every PAX I've been to.
Speaker 1: Maybe not Australia, but it is always conflicted with something.
Speaker 1: It does not conflict.
Speaker 1: I might have to go practice Pac-Man when I get home because I haven't played in months.
Speaker 1: And then, of course, our panel and Omegathon final on Monday.
Speaker 0: Monday, Sandworm Theater, noon.
Speaker 1: Noon.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: We'll try to do some video and cool other stuff from the convention.
Speaker 0: And if you're a Geek Nights fan and you want to hang out with us, we're going to basically do an official Geek Nights meetup.
Speaker 0: Come to our panel or hang around near it if you can't get in because it fills up.
Speaker 0: And after that, we can all sort of go into the Omegathon line together.
Speaker 1: Well, I was going to meet that guy for lunch after the panel.
Speaker 1: But we can do after that.
Speaker 0: Oh, which guy?
Speaker 1: The YouTube guy.
Speaker 0: Oh, that guy.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so our panel is going to go to one.
Speaker 1: Omegathon is at 5.30.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So we'll probably go eat lunch.
Speaker 0: So what I'm saying is...
Speaker 1: And then go to the Omegathon line and have a meetup.
Speaker 0: Meet us at or after the panel and we will provide the details of the actual, like, for real hangout Omegathon lineup.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's still the best meetup location and time that we can give.
Speaker 1: That's a guarantee because we're going to be at the panel and we're going to be at the exit of the panel when it exits.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you want to have an official meetup and hang out with cool Geek Nights listeners and fans and friends, that is the time to find us to figure out the rest of Monday at PAX.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 0: So we'll be there.
Speaker 0: I'll be at PAX Dev.
Speaker 0: If you're at PAX Dev, totally let me know.
Speaker 0: Maybe we can hang out and talk about it because we can't talk about it with anyone else.
Speaker 0: So we have been fans for a very long time of James Rolfe, also known as the Angry Nintendo Nerd, later renamed due to copyright issues, the Angry Video Game Nerd.
Speaker 1: He is a person who is very similar to us in age and culture.
Speaker 0: Well, culture as it relates to console video games.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: And he enjoys many of the same works that we enjoy and he produces video content that we enjoy.
Speaker 1: And that's all there is to it.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: He's not like a lot of the other people on this level in the sense that he doesn't go to a lot of conventions when he does.
Speaker 0: He doesn't really do much or say much.
Speaker 0: He's pretty narrowly focused.
Speaker 0: Not that often you see him, other than on YouTube, but he made a movie.
Speaker 1: He did.
Speaker 1: He made a movie about... And he actually finished the movie, made it, and put it in theaters for reals.
Speaker 0: Yes, and we went and saw it in a real theater in New York City.
Speaker 1: We had an opportunity to see it in New York City, just had to buy tickets, so I did.
Speaker 1: And it's going to be screened at PAX, by the way, but I don't have to waste my PAX time on that because I saw it already.
Speaker 0: I need at least one of you to go to the screening because at the end of this episode, I have a question for you.
Speaker 0: But the question is a spoiler.
Speaker 0: Not for the movie, but for something else.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: But, yeah.
Speaker 0: So, we're not going to spoil it because you should see it.
Speaker 0: If you're a fan of him at all, it's actually really worth watching.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I mean, this is not fucking Citizen Kane, obviously.
Speaker 1: But he knows how to make movies.
Speaker 1: That's his thing, right?
Speaker 1: He's like his soul thing.
Speaker 0: He's a movie nerd.
Speaker 1: He's a movie nerd.
Speaker 1: So, did he do a good job?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's pretty much exactly what I expected.
Speaker 1: It's like an Angry Video Game Nerd episode, only longer, only bigger production value.
Speaker 0: Surprisingly high quality.
Speaker 0: Like, the production values in terms of just shooting and lighting and all the technical stuff, I was really, actually, seriously impressed.
Speaker 1: And it's almost two hours long, and it's not bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There's only a few things that drag.
Speaker 0: Like, there's an on-running joke with one of the girls toward the end.
Speaker 0: that's just kind of a little overdone and a little bad.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, there's other jokes that took me by such surprise that I laughed out loud and almost hurt myself because I didn't expect the movie to be that good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It is not without flaw, right?
Speaker 1: But it's the kind of movie where you're not going to be -- you will not regret going to see it.
Speaker 1: It's going to be available digitally pretty soon.
Speaker 1: If you are a fan of Angry Video Game Nerd, you will want to see this.
Speaker 1: It's worth seeing.
Speaker 1: Some of the things that I think I didn't like were, like, they had this running joke where they would use -- like, they would explode a toy.
Speaker 1: Like, if a van was supposed to crash, they would have a toy van and crash it, and it would be shot in a way.
Speaker 1: that's obvious.
Speaker 1: it was a toy van and not the way Star Wars does it, where it's not obvious it's a toy.
Speaker 0: I liked that when it kept happening.
Speaker 1: Right, so it happened, like, once, and it's like, "Ah, I gotcha," right?
Speaker 1: But then it happened, like, a bunch more times.
Speaker 0: But every time it happened, because it was a different model, like, it got to the point where the colander and the missile thing, like, that was funny, even though it was the same gag again.
Speaker 0: It also -- I had a colander like that.
Speaker 1: The checkoff's gun was also really obvious, but that's okay.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: I still don't know -- even watching it, I don't know what the name of that big boss monster was.
Speaker 0: Something.
Speaker 0: Hell's garbage.
Speaker 1: I can't even remember.
Speaker 0: My brain can't.
Speaker 0: My brain just thinks of it as word mash.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing, the bad guy thing.
Speaker 0: I like that bad guy thing, though.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But actually, I think, you know, it was funny, because everyone knows, if you know anything about it, right, the whole point of this movie is that he's going to review
Speaker 1: E.T.,
Speaker 1: which is the game he was never going to -- it's the unspeakable E.T So, you know, he saved it for the movie.
Speaker 0: But his moral was literally identical to what we have been saying in our bad games lecture for a couple years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everything we have been saying about E.T.
Speaker 1: for all this time is exactly what he said about
Speaker 1: E.T.,
Speaker 1: which is really interesting, because it's only sometimes that we say the exact same thing he says.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, like, I was really surprised that that was the moral, that the game wasn't actually that bad, guys.
Speaker 0: Seriously.
Speaker 1: But, like, the movie has -- It's like GameStop culture.
Speaker 1: It comments on, like, video game history.
Speaker 1: It comments on -- like, he comments on his own fans and, like, you know, their culture.
Speaker 1: It's like this movie, like, even though you could say the whole thing is a review of
Speaker 1: E.T.,
Speaker 1: it actually touches on, like, so many different things without, like, fucking up the pacing or anything like that or feeling, you know, too disjointed.
Speaker 1: It's also -- I don't think a lot of people -- Like, he manages to fit everything in very nicely.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like, it could have been cut a little bit shorter, I think, but not that much.
Speaker 0: Like, the editing was not bad.
Speaker 0: And there were a surprising number of very apt and very subtle film references that I don't think most of the people in the audience got.
Speaker 1: Well, I think -- That's Terminator 2.
Speaker 0: That's Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles 3.
Speaker 0: That's Vertigo.
Speaker 1: Well, there are certain things that, you know, if you're just watching this and you don't know tons about film, you're going to miss.
Speaker 1: But if you watch the videos on his site that are not Angry Video Game Nerd videos, if you're, like, a Cinemassacre fan and you've watched all of his content, all the Monster Madness and all his other stuff, then you're actually going to get a lot of that stuff.
Speaker 1: if you're observant, you know, because he's taught it to you in the past already.
Speaker 1: So even if you're not a movie fan -- If you're a fan of him.
Speaker 1: If you're a fan of him, he's sort of bled his enough movie fandom onto you.
Speaker 1: There were quite a few things I noticed that I would not have noticed just based on my movie knowledge, but I noticed because I had watched a video that he did.
Speaker 0: Specifically the reference to Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles 3.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That was really good when that happened.
Speaker 0: You'll know it when you see it, at least I hope you do.
Speaker 0: The critical response was kind of eh, but I don't really expect -- I wonder how this movie goes over with someone who knows nothing about him at all.
Speaker 0: Huh.
Speaker 0: Hollywood Reporter called it, quote, "an overly long and obsessively self-indulgent work with production value that hovers above home video quality by a few admirable
Speaker 0: notches.".
Speaker 1: So I do agree that it was -- there was a lot of self-indulgence.
Speaker 1: There were tons of stuff in there that was basically -- it wasn't self-indulgent as much as it was audience-pandering woo games.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: Which bothers me a lot.
Speaker 1: There was a section -- It bothers me a lot anywhere it appears, not just movies.
Speaker 0: This is where we got to talk a little bit about the experience of being in this theater, because that -- I would have enjoyed the movie a lot more had I watched it alone at home.
Speaker 0: Or with friends.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, me.
Speaker 0: Maybe not you as much.
Speaker 0: I was in a particularly difficult situation.
Speaker 0: I will get to --.
Speaker 0: so, whenever there was a joke that was obvious, like, people were not reacting heavily to most of the, like, more nuanced references.
Speaker 0: But when, like, some -- the equivalent of someone getting hit in the nuts happens, the entire crowd would go,
Speaker 0: "Ha!"
Speaker 0: Like, one loud "ha" as loud as they could, and then clap and hoot.
Speaker 1: Also, when there was lots and lots of cameos from other Internet videos, celebrity-type people.
Speaker 0: And they were pretty well done.
Speaker 0: Like, they were integrated, I think, the best way you could do that thing.
Speaker 1: Sort of, but it's, like, you'd see, like, Doug Walker was on screen for, like, five seconds.
Speaker 0: Oh, my -- so -- And the whole place exploded.
Speaker 1: Just -- you didn't even -- it's, like, what he was doing wasn't even funny.
Speaker 0: His bit was, like, 12 seconds long.
Speaker 1: Just because he was on screen and he was Doug Walker, everyone in the place is, like, exploding, like, cheering and hollering and hooting.
Speaker 0: Hollering and hooting.
Speaker 0: The guy next to me just screeched.
Speaker 0: He just went, "Ah!
Speaker 0: Ah!
Speaker 0: Ah!".
Speaker 0: I'm not even joking.
Speaker 0: And then, like, that cameo was maybe 12 seconds long.
Speaker 0: The crowd goes apeshit.
Speaker 0: They stand up and then give, like, a standing ovation to the point that you couldn't hear the dialogue of most of the next cameo.
Speaker 0: Like, what the fuck, you kids?
Speaker 0: They did the same thing for most of -- like, Keith Apicary had a cameo, and it was the same thing.
Speaker 1: And just throughout the entire movie -- His cameo was actually probably one of the better ones.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: He just electrocuted himself, and it was satisfying to see him get harmed, even if it was fake harm.
Speaker 1: He was almost Ernest-esque in his cameo.
Speaker 0: So, this sold out, obviously.
Speaker 0: And we met some friends, and we went over to this thing, and, you know, the movie was at, what, like, 7?
Speaker 0: So, you guys got there, what, like, 45 minutes early?
Speaker 1: Something like that, yeah.
Speaker 1: I went to the Duane Reade, got a water.
Speaker 0: It is obvious that at least the first 100 or so, maybe 200 people in line had been there for four-plus hours.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I noticed -- like, I saw how many people were in line in front of us, which is maybe 100 at most.
Speaker 1: And I checked the capacity of the place on the Internet, and I was like, "Oh, we're good.
Speaker 1: We can go even farther back in line.
Speaker 1: We'll be
Speaker 1: fine.".
Speaker 0: But, like, it was a sold-out show.
Speaker 0: Everyone had guaranteed tickets, and yet these people had been lined up, possibly all day, I get the impression.
Speaker 1: Well, there was actually -- we were at the second showing.
Speaker 1: Well, we were at the first showing that was offered.
Speaker 1: They added a second showing, and the first one sold out.
Speaker 1: That actually aired -- was before the one we saw.
Speaker 1: So, like, people had gone in, and other people were waiting outside while there were other people inside were watching.
Speaker 1: Those people left, and then we went in.
Speaker 0: Also, I ended up having an extra ticket, and what was interesting is that I tweeted, like, "Hey, I got this extra
Speaker 0: ticket.".
Speaker 0: The people who responded to that were frightening.
Speaker 0: They really fucking wanted that ticket.
Speaker 0: But, luckily, one guy who seemed pretty cool was -- and he had Simon Belmont from Captain N. Avatar -- There you go.
Speaker 0: -- was like, "Hey, can I have
Speaker 0: it?".
Speaker 0: And I was like,
Speaker 0: "Yeah.".
Speaker 0: But then he didn't show up in time.
Speaker 0: I told him to be there by 6.40.
Speaker 0: He wasn't.
Speaker 0: They let the line in.
Speaker 0: I didn't see his Chimchar.
Speaker 0: That's how he told me I'd find him.
Speaker 0: He was like, "Yo, I'll have a Chimchar,".
Speaker 0: and they sent me a link to a Chimchar.
Speaker 0: Like, dude, I know what a Chimchar is.
Speaker 1: You know what a Chimchar is.
Speaker 0: Luckily, I don't feel too bad because -- It's a fire monkey.
Speaker 0: After the movie, I saw on Twitter, he tweeted at me.
Speaker 0: He's like, "Hey, I got in.
Speaker 0: No
Speaker 0: worries.".
Speaker 0: So, at least he got to see it.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that worked.
Speaker 0: But the people in the line, mostly, like, the vast majority were, like, 14 to 19-year-old fat white guys.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I saw e-cigs.
Speaker 1: I saw fedoras.
Speaker 0: Trilbys.
Speaker 0: The Trilby e-cig pony shirts or AVGN shirt, you know, the equivalent of the guy wearing the T-shirt of the band at the concert that they're going to right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, AVGN cosplays were not numbered in the zeroes.
Speaker 0: And I was walking up and down the line looking for Chimchar guy, and I started overhearing conversations with the people in line in front of us, the people who'd been there for a while.
Speaker 0: Those conversations -- there's only one word I can use to describe those conversations.
Speaker 0: That word is
Speaker 0: "choice.".
Speaker 0: There were these two guys who were talking about a video game, and I think they were talking about the Stanley Parable.
Speaker 0: But neither one of them knew what the name of it was, and the one guy was explaining what the game is like.
Speaker 0: he was an authority on it.
Speaker 0: But he was making shit up, and obviously had never actually played it.
Speaker 0: And I hung around next to these guys just kind of listening to see where this conversation was going.
Speaker 1: This is like elementary school when there was no internet and you could just make shit up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like that's what was going on in this line in front of us.
Speaker 0: And then I walked to the back of the line, and yeah, that was a gigantic line wrapping around the block.
Speaker 0: There were dudes walking up and down the line, like one guy had a petition to get them to review some game.
Speaker 0: And then we go in.
Speaker 0: We go in to see the movie.
Speaker 1: I think he wanted them to play Earthrealm Jim 3D.
Speaker 1: That was the game he wanted reviewed.
Speaker 0: I like his reaction on stage.
Speaker 0: He was like, "Uh,
Speaker 0: okay.".
Speaker 0: So they let the line in, and the people in the front just basically fucking run to sit in the front center.
Speaker 0: So we just walk in casually, and we go in and we see there's a bunch of seats.
Speaker 0: So we kind of go around to the far right side instead of coming down the left side.
Speaker 1: We just sat down in pretty good seats.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We start going in toward the center.
Speaker 0: I held up our group before.
Speaker 0: Two seats before the next person.
Speaker 1: Well, you want to leave a two-seat gap.
Speaker 1: Leaving a one-seat gap is jerky because it's a sold-out show.
Speaker 1: Someone's going to be all alone there.
Speaker 1: You leave a two-seat gap so a group of two can come in and fit in that slot.
Speaker 0: However, my real rationale was due to the size and enthusiasm of the gentleman who was sitting there, really wanted to be two seats away.
Speaker 0: So we're sitting there fine, and then this other group of people who were slow-moving but had been pretty far ahead of us in line come around, and they asked the end of our group, "Hey, we're a group of four,".
Speaker 0: because there were two empty seats on either side of our group.
Speaker 0: And they were like, "Can you guys scoot over so we can fit our group of four
Speaker 0: in?".
Speaker 0: And Scott and everyone's like, "All right.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: Cool.".
Speaker 0: I'm looking at everyone like, "Please no.
Speaker 0: Please
Speaker 0: no.".
Speaker 0: But I'm not going to be that asshole.
Speaker 0: So we start to scoot over toward the middle.
Speaker 0: Then the guy's like, "Oh, no.
Speaker 0: We wanted you to scoot toward the end.
Speaker 0: We want to sit in the
Speaker 0: middle.".
Speaker 1: And I'm like, "Go fuck
Speaker 1: yourself.".
Speaker 0: What did you say exactly?
Speaker 0: You said, "What?
Speaker 0: No.".
Speaker 0: And then we just sat back down.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: So for the next 20 minutes, this group of people, that guy keeps talking loudly to his friends like, "We saw those seats first.
Speaker 0: They weren't using them.
Speaker 0: We got here in line before
Speaker 0: them.".
Speaker 0: And I think he was mad and stewing about that for the entire movie.
Speaker 1: I should just go to the Major League Baseball Stadium, and I'll buy nosebleed seats, and then I'll just go down to the behind-the-home plate and be like, "Okay.
Speaker 1: Can you guys move up to the upper deck so I can have these
Speaker 1: seats?".
Speaker 1: "Cool.
Speaker 0: Thanks, bro.
Speaker 0: Yeah.".
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: They'll be like, "Usher, how did this guy get
Speaker 1: here?".
Speaker 0: So the guy next to me was oozed into my seat to the point that he was bodily leaning on me the entire time, and I kept sliding closer and closer to Scott, but I couldn't get away from him because the more--
Speaker 1: And you kept elbowing my arm off the
Speaker 0: armrest.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because the more I moved away from him, the more he came into my seat.
Speaker 0: And I thought maybe the passive-regressive model of not moving and letting him feel like, "Oh, I bumped into someone,".
Speaker 0: either he did not feel me or he gave no shits because he just oozed over me.
Speaker 1: The blob.
Speaker 1: People are fans of James Rolfe.
Speaker 1: We like the blob.
Speaker 0: And I feel bad kind of calling this guy out, but every time something funny happened in the movie, he'd pump his arm and scream and kick me.
Speaker 1: Right, so we are not, me even less so than others, are not outwardly enthusiastic about things.
Speaker 1: We will clap politely.
Speaker 1: We rarely cheer and scream and get crazy.
Speaker 0: And even when I cheer, there are things that weren't--.
Speaker 0: For example, at a hockey game, I will jump up out of my seat and go, "Fuck
Speaker 0: yes!".
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I won't do that-- It can happen.
Speaker 0: I won't do that every time a minor joke happens in a two-hour movie.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Every single time.
Speaker 1: But this entire crowd, other than a few people, us included, was-- When James Rolfe came out at the end-- Basically, they celebrated like their team won the World Cup.
Speaker 0: With every dick joke.
Speaker 1: At every single thing.
Speaker 0: And there was a point at the end where-- Every reference, every day, every everything.
Speaker 1: All you had to do was stay up there and basically go like,
Speaker 1: "Ass!"
Speaker 1: And people would have gone like,
Speaker 1: "Whoo!".
Speaker 0: That actually pretty much directly happened during the Q&A, because James Rolfe was there.
Speaker 0: They did a Q&A at the end.
Speaker 0: And other than the fact that I missed a lot of dialogue from the movie because of the people screaming at every little joke, but the Q&A, when he came out on stage, the entire crowd stood up, and that was when we realized that to this crowd, he is their Jesus.
Speaker 1: Pretty much.
Speaker 0: And we looked around.
Speaker 0: First, we all look at each other like,
Speaker 0: "What?"
Speaker 0: And then we look out in the crowd, and there are about 10 or 11 other people who we all kind of met eyes, sitting down.
Speaker 1: We're all sitting.
Speaker 1: We're the only people sitting.
Speaker 0: And we all look at each other like,
Speaker 0: "Wow.".
Speaker 0: And what followed was one of the saddest and most uncomfortable Q&A sessions I have ever witnessed.
Speaker 1: Well, we counted who broke Scott's rules with Q&A, and to be fair, people asked legit questions that were interesting.
Speaker 1: There were a few.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not the first several, though.
Speaker 1: There were definitely questions that did not break the rules and were good questions, and I was actually interested to hear the answers, and they were good answers.
Speaker 1: But for the first thing, we had a streak going of not -- everyone was breaking the rules of Scott's Q&A.
Speaker 0: One guy right away was like, "Can I get your autograph right
Speaker 0: now?".
Speaker 0: One guy was like, "I have a petition I want to deliver to you, blah, blah, blah, about the earthworms
Speaker 0: thing.".
Speaker 0: And even then, I love these guys, but they don't really know how to work a crowd, so they didn't really repeat the questions.
Speaker 0: very well.
Speaker 1: No, they make movies.
Speaker 1: They don't have stage skills.
Speaker 1: When have they ever appeared on a stage?
Speaker 0: The way it went was eventually you'd just hear "mumble, mumble, mumble, mumble,
Speaker 0: mumble.".
Speaker 0: Oh, yes, that was in fact a reference.
Speaker 0: You'd hear "mumble, mumble" and then an answer to a question you didn't hear.
Speaker 0: And the crowd would react to pretty much everything you said, and we realized after a while that this was going to go on for another hour.
Speaker 1: I was going to go on until they stopped it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was going to go for a while.
Speaker 1: And there was really no value to be had from staying there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of the questions could have been answered by Google.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: So we look at each other and we're like, "Bail?
Speaker 0: Bail.".
Speaker 0: So we get up and we go to leave.
Speaker 0: We could not go to the left because of the excitable gentleman.
Speaker 1: And it was farther to go to the left anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we turn to the right to leave, and the guy, that group, the people that were mad at us, that guy looks at us and he's like, "What?
Speaker 0: What do you mean you want to leave?
Speaker 0: It's not
Speaker 0: over.".
Speaker 0: He was so visibly and viscerally offended that we were going to leave during the Q&A that they refused to get out of our way.
Speaker 0: They refused to move.
Speaker 0: He literally, they're like, "Well,
Speaker 0: bleh.".
Speaker 0: And they sat there, stopped looking at us, they faced forward, planted their feet, and refused to move their entire party.
Speaker 0: So we just stepped over them and left.
Speaker 0: It was amazing.
Speaker 0: I've never seen, I've never experienced something like that before.
Speaker 0: What's your life like that?
Speaker 0: this is what you do?
Speaker 1: Rewatching AVGN episodes every ten times a day?
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh, and during the Q&A, I think the most interesting part was that they didn't really have a process for it, so people would just raise their hands.
Speaker 0: I would say 80% of the crowd was Milhousing it the entire time.
Speaker 0: Like jumping up and down, me, me, me, me, me, me, me, me, me, me, me.
Speaker 0: The excitable gentleman next to me, large excitable, maximal in both those areas, elbowed me in the head like nine times.
Speaker 0: He just kept waving his arm around.
Speaker 0: Eventually, I just started ducking under him every time.
Speaker 0: It was time to ask more questions.
Speaker 0: And then there was a moment where there's too many sad stories.
Speaker 0: I just won't even tell the rest of them.
Speaker 0: You can imagine what this was like.
Speaker 0: So my task to you, tell us if it's like that at the PAX screening or not.
Speaker 1: Tell us if it's like that.
Speaker 1: If you went to any of the other screenings in any of the other states, tell us how it was like.
Speaker 1: And also, you know, this movie is going to come out digitally.
Speaker 1: It's worth watching.
Speaker 0: It is absolutely worth watching.
Speaker 1: I'll watch it once again even.
Speaker 0: There's a joke in the beginning.
Speaker 1: I'll watch it once again with people who haven't seen it and it will be a worthwhile expenditure of two hours.
Speaker 1: Whoever it was who played the manager of that GameStop, it looks like it's going to be a-- That's one of those pot of gold, guy who can't get work, amazing actors who does one thing that they found in Hollywood when they were there.
Speaker 0: That guy.
Speaker 0: Doing casting.
Speaker 0: Like he was average funny and then he took it up to maximum.
Speaker 1: I think if you go in Hollywood, there's all these desperate actors everywhere working nothing, right?
Speaker 1: But a lot of them have some kind of talent that just isn't like a movie for them or, you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: But if you go there, you can find these people.
Speaker 1: And it's like I kind of just wish I had enough money to go there.
Speaker 0: Get all those people.
Speaker 1: Maybe not even make a movie, but just make something with a bunch of those people like that all together, right?
Speaker 1: Like those talented-- Because people have like a hidden amazing talent at like a certain kind of character or something, you know, where like their performance really stands out.
Speaker 1: The one I always think of, right, is when I went to see Les Mis.
Speaker 1: like in the '90s, the master of the house is just like this incredible dude.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Was it like an all-time fucking greatest actor or anything?
Speaker 1: Probably not.
Speaker 1: But it's like dude got more applause than anyone else at the end because he was just so good at that thing right there, being that person.
Speaker 0: If you're the right kind of person, that's not a role.
Speaker 0: There are just people who are kind of like that.
Speaker 1: Right, obviously the role does part of the work as well, right?
Speaker 1: You know, you need to get both things combined.
Speaker 1: Like imagine if you went to see a show of some kind, play TV show, movie, whatever, and everyone in the whole thing was fucking like that ace character, you know, all across the board, you know?
Speaker 1: And even in things like, you know, Fullmetal Alchemist, like the Hughes character, it's just like the guy who's the best.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So in the end, this movie definitely worth seeing.
Speaker 0: I went into it with what I thought were like reasonable expectations.
Speaker 0: This movie actually far exceeded them and was like really worth watching.
Speaker 1: I think it just matched my expectation precisely.
Speaker 0: I expected less and I got more.
Speaker 0: I'm actually really happy about that.
Speaker 1: Wow, you expected less than me.
Speaker 1: That's rare.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is rare.
Speaker 0: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: Maybe just I've been jaded recently by stuff.
Speaker 0: Apparently used a Panasonic AGAF100 camera for a lot of this.
Speaker 0: Wikipedia has a lot of info on the movie already.
Speaker 1: That was the camera they were using on the stage.
Speaker 0: And also has a notability warning on it.
Speaker 1: I think it's notable.
Speaker 0: Nope, this article relies on all primary sources.
Speaker 0: There are no references yet except James Rolfe himself about this movie.
Speaker 0: That's why.
Speaker 1: Let's do Wikipedia policy.
Speaker 1: Someone's reviewed the movie.
Speaker 1: That's got to be enough.
Speaker 1: IMDb page, come on.
Speaker 0: Seriously, according to Wikipedia, the budget was around three or four hundred thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That, if this is the kind of movie that four hundred grand makes, we are in for a like platinum age of cinema in about ten years.
Speaker 0: Seriously.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because in ten years you could take three or four hundred grand and make something even better than this.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.