Speaker 1: It's Wednesday July 2nd 2014.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight Doesn't sound very brave.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Lately I found that a bunch of our friends just talking about anime.
Speaker 1: They're watching Almost like point-for-point all the shows we watched over the last three years.
Speaker 1: at a delay of about three years People are like all our friends are just starting to catch up on shows that we were watching between one and three years ago.
Speaker 0: I mean most people on the internet are watching like every current show and have watched the shows we were watching a hundred years ago.
Speaker 1: Yep, but like I got a message from someone recently who was like, oh my god episode 3 of Madoka And then someone else is like, oh my god, Senketsu and killa killa.
Speaker 0: That wasn't three years ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I've got all these people in this staggered like tail catching up on anime.
Speaker 1: I feel like I'm gonna be able to talk about all the shows.
Speaker 1: I like Repeatedly the same way that happened to us with the prince of nothing book.
Speaker 0: It's better to be in their position where you watch it for the first time and then talk about who the people who are already bored of it.
Speaker 1: The thing is sometimes when you do that you get in a situation where you're like, man I just saw a cool thing and the prince of nothing and they're like, yeah Well, you haven't gotten to the cool part yet.
Speaker 1: or oh wait till you find out what happens to that character.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, you know the darkness that comes before.
Speaker 1: yep, I mean they entered the circle inscribed by his sword.
Speaker 0: They sure did.
Speaker 1: Oh my god that new prince of nothing book.
Speaker 1: Our Scott backer can't write fast enough.
Speaker 1: No, you can't especially now that I'm pretty much reading the last culture book I can read.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: It's done.
Speaker 1: I've read it all do.
Speaker 1: There's also a crazy thunderstorm going on outside.
Speaker 0: So that rim said wouldn't happen.
Speaker 0: The National Weather Service that I said I didn't say it wouldn't happen.
Speaker 1: I said it was not enough of a storm to prevent me from biking.
Speaker 0: I'd sound bangs to differ with you.
Speaker 1: I what do you mean with me?
Speaker 1: I would bike through that I've biked through.
Speaker 0: worse bike me home then.
Speaker 1: Well, you want to sit in my handlebars?
Speaker 1: That's way more dangerous for you than it is for me.
Speaker 1: So it's Wednesday and not to not to do the metamome We almost skip the show because if you didn't notice I did upload the last plot episode of season one of our show Analyzing shoujo kakame utana.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Didn't you say that for the metamome?
Speaker 1: I could but I'm talking about the news because that almost was our show.
Speaker 0: have no news.
Speaker 1: I do have a little bit of news, but All I want to say is it kind of reminded me of something cuz a long time ago We did a geek nights episode on rewatching like when you rewatch anime that you watched in the past and why you do it and what shows how Like every there's every n years.
Speaker 1: I just get this feeling of it's time to watch Evangelion again, that's every n hours.
Speaker 0: Yeah Right now like so I should just watch it when I get home.
Speaker 1: So watching utana again for the I don't know sixth time and taking notes during it I feel like at this point I have an expert understanding of that show at least the first 12 episodes As much as anyone not named Ikahara can have.
Speaker 1: even you go hard as a fucking no You've seen those interviews with him.
Speaker 1: why did toga do X in the episode?
Speaker 0: why cuz I like that sort of?
Speaker 1: well Well, that was in the movie.
Speaker 1: That was No, that was answer to that question was basically.
Speaker 1: Well, you'd have to ask toga.
Speaker 1: I can't really speak on his behalf.
Speaker 1: Yeah, fuck you.
Speaker 1: But I feel like if it's time to rewatch a show and you're an anime person You should rewatch shoujo kakame utana and watch our show about shoujo kakame utana because goddamn is there never been another show that show stands out as pretty unique, but right now the show that I Like suddenly that clock started ringing that clock that never rings
Speaker 0: clock never really.
Speaker 1: I really know want to watch eska flone again.
Speaker 0: All right, go do that in a long time man.
Speaker 0: I'm good.
Speaker 1: You're good.
Speaker 1: Good.
Speaker 1: When's the last time you watched it?
Speaker 0: I don't need to watch it.
Speaker 1: You don't remember the nukes.
Speaker 0: I remember the news.
Speaker 1: remember the nukes.
Speaker 1: you remember Isaac.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's the whole show.
Speaker 1: cat girls, yeah, okay one cat girl up no three cat girls.
Speaker 0: What's her name with the orange dress?
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's two other much more important cat girls.
Speaker 0: Those are from tank police.
Speaker 1: It was a cameo.
Speaker 1: So you got any news.
Speaker 0: This really could also be a thing of the day or even a meta moment.
Speaker 0: But there's so little news because anime Expo should be this weekend, right?
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: anime Expo a bunch of the Gen Con of anime con This weekend, so that's where all the anime news is in the meantime.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about this.
Speaker 0: I was biking around on biking that we're talking about biking on Monday Yep.
Speaker 0: And I needed lunch and I remembered across the street from the Japan Society and 48th Street in New York on the east side There's a place where you can get lunch without going inside.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's just in that park there and you can get food And then eat it outside.
Speaker 0: So I did that You can even get a milkshake there, which is amazing.
Speaker 0: and they even you know When you get the food, they just hand it out a window at you.
Speaker 0: See, it's like whoa You don't have to leave your bike tied up or anything.
Speaker 0: and I'm looking at the Japan Society and they got a sign tied up Outside, you know and it's advertising Japan cuts which is not about swords while not entirely about swords, which is their annual contemporary Japanese film festival.
Speaker 0: and I said, oh, yeah that happens every year and I never go to it.
Speaker 0: and Will I go to it this year?
Speaker 1: Maybe Regardless What is it X?
Speaker 1: will I go?
Speaker 1: Yes, but you're like, what is it X?
Speaker 0: Hey, I will say the point is, you know in past years They've actually had movies that I knew about like knew what they were and really wanted to see and just didn't go for whatever reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah this year.
Speaker 0: I don't know any of these things on this list, but just the pictures and titles Seem pretty awesome just based on that alone.
Speaker 0: Let me just say names a few of the ones that look awesome based on the title and picture.
Speaker 0: So why don't you play in hell question mark?
Speaker 1: Oh anything with jikoku?
Speaker 1: I'm all down with the mole song.
Speaker 0: colon undercover agent, Reiji The extreme sukiyaki, I don't know what that's about.
Speaker 0: The eternal zero I would eat.
Speaker 0: I don't know what that I would eat the shit out of some extreme miss zombie.
Speaker 1: That might be scary.
Speaker 0: moe you don't know a little of a butcher shop.
Speaker 0: looks like it's actually a documentary about a butcher shop Which is also awesome.
Speaker 0: No wood job exclamation point looks to be about lumberjacks.
Speaker 0: Oh Shit, which looks awesome.
Speaker 0: I would watch that Uzumasa limelight has this amazing samurai lady with a sword in the picture.
Speaker 0: So yeah, the tale of II that looks like some frickin Zatoichi kind of shit only the dude can see.
Speaker 1: we should go do this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, you know you gotta buy tickets to movies and go see them but when else are you gonna see these movies Unlikely if you speak English and not Japanese, will you see these movies in New York at another time?
Speaker 1: So speaking of movies in New York quite some time ago.
Speaker 1: We saw a letter to Momo.
Speaker 1: It's Standard cute good anime movie.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna say it's the greatest movie ever, but it's by no means a bad anime movie.
Speaker 0: I didn't see it.
Speaker 0: I'll see it soon.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Well, it's gonna be in New York City on July 23rd of the IFC Center.
Speaker 1: shocking.
Speaker 1: So if you want to go see it, I would not mind to see it again in the theater.
Speaker 1: I'm sure we'll see all the same people.
Speaker 1: We see it.
Speaker 1: every anime movie.
Speaker 1: Letter to Momo is cute.
Speaker 1: It's basically about this girl and I don't want to spoil anything is you should just watch it.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's an anime movie.
Speaker 1: What do we say about anime movies?
Speaker 1: Just watch them all.
Speaker 1: Yep So a bunch of yokai are hanging out in her attic and they're it's a Kitaro sequel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it's got.
Speaker 1: look at these yokai.
Speaker 0: they look like yokai.
Speaker 1: you're kind of show.
Speaker 0: It's not really as good as Kitaro's dad though.
Speaker 1: Well, the Kitaro's dad is perhaps the the the ultimate form of yokai.
Speaker 1: I Don't know if I would take that form myself though.
Speaker 1: So in other news that's also related to Scott's news.
Speaker 1: biking You know a pedal seems to be really popular.
Speaker 1: I'm watching it slowly.
Speaker 1: Scott and Emily are watching it much more ahead of me Every episode the day it comes out.
Speaker 1: I really like the bad guy.
Speaker 0: Oh, why do you like the bad guy one?
Speaker 1: He's creepy - his face looks like a one-piece villain.
Speaker 1: Did I go on?
Speaker 0: That's the reason that you're not supposed to not like him.
Speaker 0: Scott is the least likable.
Speaker 1: You were talking to a gentleman whose preferred character in Soul Calibur is Voldo.
Speaker 0: I Is that when you got the Voldo disease?
Speaker 0: That dude is Voldo on a bike.
Speaker 1: that dude I just I love when he leans like backward around like I'm just waiting for one day his head to like pop off and it Turns out he's some sort of demon you're gonna have to get.
Speaker 0: you're probably gonna be upset because I like.
Speaker 0: I don't know this for sure.
Speaker 0: I'm just predicting.
Speaker 0: I want him to win because it's a predictable shonen.
Speaker 1: I'm just predicting based on shonen patterns He's gonna lose the race and then later he's going to join them.
Speaker 0: No, you're gonna learn his tragic tale the reason he wants to win so badly.
Speaker 0: He's gonna become a sympathetic good guy Just like me like half the boxers and he had you man Oh, it Bob who are bad guys because they had to fight against the main character.
Speaker 0: All right guys.
Speaker 0: after being to.
Speaker 1: why would I hate that if he has a awesome tragic back story?
Speaker 0: They stopped being crazy and evil up evil good guys gonna be like God.
Speaker 1: I am all about the evil good guy Zellows from Slayers.
Speaker 0: He's basically gonna be discord Discord for my little pony.
Speaker 0: That's what he's gonna be.
Speaker 1: These are a few of my favorite things.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's what that guy is gonna.
Speaker 0: Nice discord.
Speaker 0: so He's gonna sing me he may he may song while he's biking.
Speaker 1: so the voice actor June Fukushima bought an Awesome road bike and had been really getting into biking because of because he was working on this.
Speaker 1: Yes, and his bike was just stolen.
Speaker 1: We don't need to ask us to Keep an eye out for his bike.
Speaker 1: It was stolen in Shinjuku on June 30th.
Speaker 0: He bought the same bike of the character that he voice a red and black Pinarello Raza with the VIN of for Charlie Delta.
Speaker 1: five one double eight nine zero one seven.
Speaker 0: voice actor red spiky hair guy.
Speaker 1: and because Ridiculous over-regulation of bikes his registration number is Bravo 32 178.
Speaker 1: Does it have a license plate?
Speaker 1: Licenses bikes, it's ridiculous.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but regardless Bike thieves are one of the few exceptions I might add to my list of things that are worth corporal punishment for when the thieves are caught.
Speaker 0: Do we just set up bikes like bait bikes and they're electrified exactly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you just die if you touch them.
Speaker 0: Or if you touch them for longer than sir or if you try to actually ride them you die.
Speaker 1: How about one that just clamps you to it or explodes or no?
Speaker 0: if you actually try to bike on it Like it's X when you're sitting on it and a knife comes out the seat right up in your ass?
Speaker 0: That way you can't possibly accidentally hurt someone with it who doesn't deserve it.
Speaker 1: what if a poor beat cop chasing down a serial like double murderer is Tries to commandeer that bike is a tied up and locked.
Speaker 0: How's he gonna get it?
Speaker 0: He uses his bike commandeering equipment By the time he undoes the bike.
Speaker 0: It's the guys gone.
Speaker 1: There's some exigent circumstance that cause you use your cop car or your cop bike.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, so if you see this guy's bike anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: So this is not related to anything.
Speaker 1: We've talked about.
Speaker 1: this is a documentary from vice vice comm vice Came out of nowhere and went from shock journalism to some of the best journalism or investigative journalism I've seen in Recent memory.
Speaker 0: I mean I watched one about this crazy drug in Colombia and it seemed true.
Speaker 0: But I'm still.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: it's weird because it's like they have these documentaries about the crazy underworld in real life.
Speaker 0: But it's like so unbelievable, which is why it's compelling, but it's also Slightly unbelievable.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I the first thing I saw of theirs was their documentary on croco deal that horrible drug.
Speaker 1: That's.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's the one I saw.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know what Google image search for that.
Speaker 1: That is not much of an exaggeration.
Speaker 0: Was that the same?
Speaker 0: it might have been a different drug.
Speaker 1: the one there was a different one.
Speaker 0: You barely get any of it and you could die but also mostly just lets you control people.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: That's a different one.
Speaker 0: Okay, that was that's the one that I saw there was that the ghost rapes one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the one that I saw.
Speaker 0: It was a Colombian thing.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: This was the crocodile is way worse than that I don't know.
Speaker 0: this pretty much seemed like the worst drug.
Speaker 1: Do not actually Google image search for crocodile like really you might you might not be happy.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, here's a they.
Speaker 1: this documentary is benign and awesome Death of the American hobo.
Speaker 1: it talks about the history of hobos in the u.s.
Speaker 1: the modern state of hobos the last hobo convention where every year they crown the hobo king and the the reporters from vice actually hobo across the country And they video it with you with GoPros.
Speaker 1: That was the last good episode of the Simpsons.
Speaker 1: sure that was the end that was.
Speaker 1: that was the final straw.
Speaker 0: Here's a video that is probably everywhere on the internet right now Even though at least the YouTube link that I have only has twenty one hundred and sixty three views.
Speaker 1: I think this is a compilation of things I've seen in other places.
Speaker 0: maybe Bears doing human things.
Speaker 0: compilation guys.
Speaker 0: bears are Been enough cat videos and dog videos and every other kind of animal bears.
Speaker 1: bear day bears win for a couple of reasons.
Speaker 1: one They can walk on two legs like humans, which already makes them hilarious.
Speaker 0: do wicked dangerous Depends.
Speaker 0: fuck you the fuck.
Speaker 1: brown bears will totally just hang out unless their moms around.
Speaker 0: Yeah, bears also can reach into the water and just grab a motherfucking fish like yeah as they don't need a rod.
Speaker 1: We do that rod but more importantly they have grabby hands.
Speaker 1: see also raccoons and squirrels.
Speaker 1: I really like grabby hands Mmm, but I saw about half the things in this video.
Speaker 1: There's got linked to.
Speaker 1: I've seen as independent videos all around the internet.
Speaker 1: So whoever is compiling the story of bears.
Speaker 1: I Salute you you.
Speaker 1: They go to my favorite ones.
Speaker 1: I didn't watch the whole video.
Speaker 1: I drove was in there, but there's a guy.
Speaker 1: This is an old one.
Speaker 1: I think I even used this thing of a day.
Speaker 1: There's a guy and he's up in like a blind I guess he's hunting or something and there's a ladder and then he looks down and he's been.
Speaker 1: he starts videoing and this bears just Hanging out and sees the ladder and is like, huh?
Speaker 1: What's this?
Speaker 1: and he starts slowly climbing up and looking around like hey, this is pretty cool.
Speaker 1: This is pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Then the bear gets close to him.
Speaker 1: He's like, hey Get yourself down like get down from there.
Speaker 1: Stay away.
Speaker 1: He just says it really calmly and the bear stops looks up at him like oh fuck There's a human there and just slowly backs down and walks away.
Speaker 0: Well guy had a gun.
Speaker 0: I don't think he obviously wasn't bear hunting otherwise would have been bad news for that.
Speaker 0: bear.
Speaker 1: Have you ever seen the bad news bears.
Speaker 0: now the original movie don't need to know.
Speaker 1: that should be a Thursday show.
Speaker 1: No, we should have the gig nights movie club.
Speaker 1: No, why not?
Speaker 1: We're good.
Speaker 0: I'll make you watch all long quiet movies that are three hours each.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll make you watch gone with a fucking wind.
Speaker 0: I Did a lot less than you.
Speaker 1: have you seen that entire movie in one sitting?
Speaker 0: I don't remember but I don't care I'll be happy.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I don't think you would.
Speaker 0: I think you're the one who would be unhappy.
Speaker 1: Should we have a gun with the wind off?
Speaker 0: I'll win easily.
Speaker 1: So the better moment.
Speaker 1: the book club book is a canicle for Liebowitz the precursor to all modern post-apocalyptic science fiction.
Speaker 1: Pretty much started the genre of me and play God destroy the world.
Speaker 0: post-apocalypse I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about one.
Speaker 0: I don't think it did post-apocalyptic in general I but I pretty sure it was the first one where the post-apocalyptic situation and Humanity is isolated in some way.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's partly that it was yield in society.
Speaker 1: It was one of the earlier novels that moved from the old style story of apocalypse to this new style Mostly nuclear driven because we should go and try to find like an old like the first story.
Speaker 0: That's truly post-apocalyptic.
Speaker 0: the Bible It's up.
Speaker 0: that's apocalyptic not post-apocalyptic post-apocalyptic.
Speaker 1: the apocalypse happened in that story.
Speaker 1: No is bullshit.
Speaker 1: isolated human on a boat surviving the apocalypse.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much straight up saying mechanical for Liebowitz is a Noah's Ark metaphor.
Speaker 0: Uh, yes And where all the animals at?
Speaker 1: Did you read a canicle for Liebowitz yet?
Speaker 0: No, I don't haven't read any more since we did the last episode.
Speaker 1: Scott I've read two books since I finished canicle for Liebowitz.
Speaker 0: Were there animals?
Speaker 1: There were animals in all of those books.
Speaker 0: Which ones?
Speaker 1: dogs, uh humans Some birds bears lizards there.
Speaker 1: There were no bears in any book Since canicle for Liebowitz.
Speaker 0: Let's write a book about bears.
Speaker 0: Oh, I have one.
Speaker 0: It's called.
Speaker 0: I want my hat back.
Speaker 1: Yeah Not this weekend But next weekend is Connecticut and Hartford Connecticut the best convention in the northeastern United States.
Speaker 1: If you live within a day's travel of Connecticut, it is worth your while.
Speaker 1: imagine Dragon Con, but you can actually get into stuff.
Speaker 1: the panels are way higher quality and It's mostly.
Speaker 1: it's mostly in one building and the city it's in is way worse.
Speaker 1: Seriously it's super fun.
Speaker 1: We would not be plugging it unduly.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't go to it every year for X years in a row and do hard work to make it happen.
Speaker 1: If it wasn't worthwhile if we ever lied to you about a convention, I rest my case.
Speaker 1: And also just to bring it up again watch our show on shoujo kakamei utenna.
Speaker 1: The 12th episode is online.
Speaker 1: Share that shit around.
Speaker 1: in fact share all of our videos on the reddits and all those places Because the more views they get the faster will crank those things out.
Speaker 1: I've dumped a ton of videos on one.
Speaker 0: make some of our shit so popular right on to work anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, guys if we don't have to work anymore You realize there's geek nights like multiple times a week reliably for the rest of your lives a multiple times a day.
Speaker 0: More geek morning geek afternoon.
Speaker 1: you realize I would just stream every video game.
Speaker 1: All of them I would play.
Speaker 1: I would let you guys pick.
Speaker 0: I don't care RPGs every day.
Speaker 1: yeah stream the RPGs I had time to set up like a studio to stream us playing burning wheel.
Speaker 0: anyway anyway, so Bravest warriors.
Speaker 0: So bravest warriors, it's a show.
Speaker 0: I watched it when there was only one episode of it.
Speaker 0: I was like hey, this is new show on YouTube, but it's like.
Speaker 0: it's a real show that they're making for reals.
Speaker 0: But the episode is short, but it's made by the Adventure Time guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just watch it on YouTube for free.
Speaker 1: like I ignored it in the beginning because there was a lot of stuff on YouTube.
Speaker 1: I didn't really put the pieces together I didn't realize there's the Adventure Time people right away, or at least I didn't realize the Pendleton Ward.
Speaker 1: yeah, and then I sort of paid attention to it because Scott was watching it and It's awesome.
Speaker 1: It's really awesome.
Speaker 0: So it's it's a weird thing right because it's sort of Most things like this will give you some sort of like origin story for like what are the bravest warriors?
Speaker 0: who are all these characters?
Speaker 0: Right, but bravest warriors doesn't introduce anything.
Speaker 0: It just puts you right in the middle of whatever it is.
Speaker 1: the term for that is in media res.
Speaker 0: No, it's not in media.
Speaker 0: res is for like when you're in the middle of the act.
Speaker 1: Action to some some episodes.
Speaker 1: it doesn't some episodes It does for almost every episode starts in the middle of like the one you just watched again.
Speaker 1: It just starts in the middle of there in this crazy war with these bugs Sure, but in terms of character introductions, right?
Speaker 0: It's not like oh by the way everyone.
Speaker 0: This is cat bug.
Speaker 0: It's just like they're hanging out and cat bug comes in.
Speaker 0: It's like hey cat bug.
Speaker 1: Don't hit me.
Speaker 0: It's like they don't introduce this.
Speaker 0: Where did this cat bug come from?
Speaker 0: I didn't know they had a cat bug.
Speaker 0: What is going on here?
Speaker 0: and it's just there suddenly and then there's millions of merchandise about it out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: the way
Speaker 1: I described it originally after I'd watch a little bit of it was that take Adventure Time and pare it down to the essence of semi-random and humor like remove even the the Small framing story that season 1 episodes of Adventure Time had remove even that And that was what bravest warriors was.
Speaker 1: but then it did the same thing Adventure Time did and got Increasingly plotty and serious and all these threads kind of came together.
Speaker 1: But yet it didn't lose that start in the middle of something without any introduction or explanation.
Speaker 1: Aspect that has got going for it.
Speaker 0: pretty much every episode no matter what it has is some sort of monster of the week.
Speaker 0: But it's they're not.
Speaker 0: you're usually not monsters, right?
Speaker 0: It's usually like like take for example the episode where they have to get the two Creatures that inhabit their butts to like fall in love during the whatever.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: It's like they're on a mission to save something or to help some alien somewhere, but it's very.
Speaker 0: it's actually pretty rare.
Speaker 0: I mean sometimes it is just go and shoot things like on a you know that kind of mission.
Speaker 0: But even episode one it's like oh is a time-traveling thing to deal with.
Speaker 0: what's the deal, right?
Speaker 0: There's a lot of time travel going on in general.
Speaker 1: I think what married me to the show was you're married now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, where should I send the gift?
Speaker 1: It was in that the first episode.
Speaker 1: when they come into the room You know there's like this time paradox loop happening.
Speaker 1: And then when they come into the room and find themselves all dead in the room, and they're like yeah, nope I'm done Nothing to do with this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's that kind of show mmm.
Speaker 1: But I think what's interesting is I like you and other people were watching it further before I watched it So I'd see like the tail end of an episode and normally like I remember I'd see snippets of Adventure Time like I saw Before I watched the show.
Speaker 1: I saw that like all the characters singing a song in front of a door.
Speaker 1: it looked really good But it looked like there'd been a whole bunch of character development and build up that led to that moment.
Speaker 1: So it felt like that's something that happens later in a show like this and then watching the show again and seeing all the build-up To that.
Speaker 1: like that added a lot to it with this show.
Speaker 1: if you catch the end of an episode and Then later you see the entire series there what that little bit you caught at the end of the episode is basically it Like I saw the bit about the paralyzed horse and then when I saw that whole episode I was like oh that was just in that one episode like just in that one part.
Speaker 0: Have you seen all of season two?
Speaker 0: I think I'm one episode behind okay, because there's more paralyzed horse then.
Speaker 1: okay I'm one episode behind spoil.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like take for it.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 0: I'd like in Adventure time I guess because it's longer because they have more episodes right they can really introduce something and Recurrent a bunch before bringing it back right, but like wanker shim, which is a big fucking deal.
Speaker 0: It's always been wanker sure, but it's like.
Speaker 0: when did he first appear in?
Speaker 0: The butter lettuce episode in the best in the hollow John which is the best episode And he's just a dude in the hollow John is like there's nothing about him.
Speaker 0: Right when a jelly kid appear the episode with the losing memory every dog on the spaceship, right?
Speaker 0: and it's just oh, there's just some jelly kid on the thing and he ejects and There's nothing about him, but then later.
Speaker 0: It's like jelly kids.
Speaker 0: suddenly a big deal.
Speaker 0: this character that Didn't even have any building.
Speaker 0: It was just there.
Speaker 0: like a second You know becomes like a whole episode later on or more.
Speaker 1: yep, but oh, you're right.
Speaker 1: cuz adventure time I think it's just more episodes, and they fill in the details like this show Just is like the peaks along the way of what would be a show.
Speaker 1: you could have a show with the same pacing as adventure Time.
Speaker 1: that was just bravest warriors filling in all the time between those points.
Speaker 1: instead It's like they have this whole story, and they pick these points along the way, and they only animate those points.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have some of the comics.
Speaker 0: I haven't read them.
Speaker 0: I'm curious if the comics are just more bravest warriors Or if they fill in a lot of those blanks in between.
Speaker 0: like are they Canon?
Speaker 1: I almost don't want them to one thing I?
Speaker 1: Like about bravest warriors that adventure time has its own lexicon like its own Language like P the way thin and people say things like that's Greece.
Speaker 0: algebraic Mathematical said that in a while.
Speaker 1: yeah lately Greece has been the thing.
Speaker 1: I've been saying that lately myself, but in this show Instead of doing that with adjectives.
Speaker 1: They've been doing it with straight-up nouns Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I mean they'll be they'll be like blah blah blah the calliope of space And they just use these terms that literally mean nothing.
Speaker 1: It's just the gobbledygook that you'd use in.
Speaker 1: like Star Trek the next generation just applied whenever they needed some crab people nouns.
Speaker 0: I thought like a lot of the sort of Technologies that go on that they somehow keep consistent right like they all have these basically Pokemon holograms in these gym.
Speaker 1: that has zero Explanation right.
Speaker 0: well, but they keep coming up and actually mattering a whole lot.
Speaker 0: And yeah, and holograms have like mad powers.
Speaker 0: apparently they can turn them into bazookas and wings And you know basically all these powers come from like these little pokemons that they have.
Speaker 0: It's like whoa.
Speaker 0: those things do a lot, but they're mostly there visually.
Speaker 0: they rarely draw attention to them except for I think once when they're introduced And maybe one other time they're just always there, and if you don't actually look it's like oh he you know Chris always has the B and Dan always has the dog and Bets is a cat and wallow is The Eagle Hawk thing.
Speaker 0: yeah, whatever it is right It's like if you're not paying close attention you won't realize that or just the little things like.
Speaker 1: all the characters are actually really well Developed, but you only see it through these little Snippet lenses like wallows got all those little animals hanging around him all the time like he collects little guys.
Speaker 0: He's also the doctor.
Speaker 0: yeah, I'm gonna Lee Even though he's the big guy.
Speaker 1: He's walls are way better than Zoidberg ever was it being a doctor.
Speaker 1: The level of technology they possess is approaching culture level - well I think it's right.
Speaker 0: I guess the idea is that their parents were even better than them and we're like the real.
Speaker 0: what were they called the courageous battlers?
Speaker 0: Right yeah, and they're they guess their parent.
Speaker 0: all this shit I think is their parents shit Which is why it's so fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: And there's sort of like the half-assed people taking over for their parents and aren't as good and they often fail.
Speaker 0: So I guess that's where all their cool stuff comes from.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also just the level of technology in this world is pretty high.
Speaker 1: That's also true But the only other really interesting.
Speaker 1: I mean the episodes are so short.
Speaker 0: if you they have a video That's watch all of season one in one video.
Speaker 0: It's an hour.
Speaker 1: even if you could not ask yourself to watch all of adventure time with its short episodes Evens because there's so many of them you could watch this entire show.
Speaker 0: You could watch almost all of season one in less time than it takes to all listen to this.
Speaker 1: geek nights Exactly, and it's worth watching because this show And Frederator studios in general.
Speaker 0: Well the cartoon hangover.
Speaker 1: Yes are The like they're.
Speaker 1: this is the model for how to do the equivalent of television in a future of technology.
Speaker 0: Yeah, make a show that's pretty relatively cheap to produce but still high quality.
Speaker 0: put it on YouTube for free Everyone loves it and then sell a million zillion dollars of cat bug merchandise and more importantly invest in creating the show.
Speaker 1: and Before you've made that money And if you know a bunch of the pilots fail who cares?
Speaker 1: because the one that succeeds you're gonna sell a lot of cat bug backpacks.
Speaker 0: and If you've got a little kid who can talk in a funny voice Get them to be a voice actor because that cat bug kid is my god The kid is cute.
Speaker 1: The cat bug is cute.
Speaker 0: He is rolling in it hard-core.
Speaker 0: I Bet they're disappointed.
Speaker 0: They can't sell as much Imposter Bear merchandise because he seems more intentionally merchandise.
Speaker 1: I think he just.
Speaker 1: I think they like him a lot, but cat bug is more popular.
Speaker 0: Opposite bears like the chef on top.
Speaker 1: Well his greatest moment was gas-powered stick.
Speaker 1: Yeah Cat bugs greatest moment was What also I'm pretty sure I read somewhere that they do the voice acting for some of these episodes all in the same room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you should well like a lot of Japanese shows.
Speaker 1: do that American shoes.
Speaker 1: ten shows tend to not do.
Speaker 0: it's also I think Cheaper.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can just get it done quickly and not have to wait.
Speaker 0: have everyone it.
Speaker 0: basically if your shows ten minutes, right?
Speaker 0: And you know everyone's law has to.
Speaker 0: you know It takes 20 minutes to record their bit.
Speaker 0: Well, if they do it all at the same time that you're not multiplying 20 minutes times the number of people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the the voice acting is top-notch.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm like this an adventure time.
Speaker 1: both just have Perfectly excellent perfectly matched really well-done voice acting which once again just proves that anime Doug's dubs suck because the people who do them suck.
Speaker 0: Yeah What else is there to say about the Warriors that are so brave.
Speaker 1: well it grew kind of a real plot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that has.
Speaker 0: I mean the real plot.
Speaker 0: I mean emotionally of quantum leap.
Speaker 0: emotion.
Speaker 0: Lord shows up in like episode 2. so it's not like it grew the plot.
Speaker 1: It was always there, but the plot became more prevalent and the episodes got more serious.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean like Merrif tag ended on a really bittersweet note.
Speaker 1: Also, the concierge is one of my favorite things.
Speaker 1: He reminds me so much of the guy in quantum leap.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of weird little things going on there.
Speaker 1: Yep It's one of those shows like some of those comics where you want to pay attention to all the weird little details going on in The background and all the weird little jokes.
Speaker 1: Like the dialogue is very well written and there's a lot of subtle humor in the dialogue That the show does not go out of its way to point out to you.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Also their headquarters is the Iron Giant.
Speaker 0: Yes, interesting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like how it's invisible, but no one gives a shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like bird bird houses sticking out of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah And oh and their ship is a whale.
Speaker 1: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.