Speaker 0: It's Thursday, February 20th, 2014.
Speaker 0: I'm rim rim fucked up, and this is geek night tonight the dentist.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: so Seriously rim fucked up like my microphone wasn't plugged in and I said I'm Scott and then yeah Yeah, so by the power of editing We just had him say it again.
Speaker 0: And now I got this other Clip of him not saying I'm Scott because you fucked up thing is he doesn't listen to the show.
Speaker 0: I could remove all this And no one would know I could.
Speaker 0: just I could just complete.
Speaker 0: I could take the I'm Scott from a previous episode Just throw it in there.
Speaker 1: No one would know what a weird show that would be.
Speaker 0: How would anyone know I'd remove this part to me you and your muska hounds anyway, I just Stalling it up the.
Speaker 1: I Thought we had done a show on dentists or teeth or something a long time ago But it's like something we would have done in one of those Thursdays.
Speaker 1: I almost like it was a hundred percent sure we had done this episode when we were in Beacon at some point But I googled and I guess there isn't one.
Speaker 0: so if there is one and we didn't find it Scott's fault I'm gonna really regret it.
Speaker 1: I was I imagined a slight possibility that perhaps it long ago There was perhaps a suggestion to do this show and I may have said that's dumb idea.
Speaker 1: Let's not do that.
Speaker 1: that happens and if there's audio evidence of that that is bad.
Speaker 0: I mean to turn about his fair play anytime.
Speaker 0: I suppose a we should do a show.
Speaker 0: We haven't done one.
Speaker 0: You'll be like yeah, if we did do one, this is rims fault.
Speaker 0: He's the one who searched.
Speaker 0: That's right Whatever, but it's not Dennis time yet last night.
Speaker 0: We went and saw no man's land.
Speaker 1: There was a lot of landmines there and barbed wires.
Speaker 0: Well landmines of the heart.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a no man's land of the heart of the mind.
Speaker 0: It was interesting because you know, we went to see waiting for Godot, you know, Patrick Stewart McKellen basically some of the best actors ever and it was great, but everyone reads waiting for Godot in high school.
Speaker 0: Well, I didn't really.
Speaker 0: I said you ever read it.
Speaker 1: I saw the movie.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: So you least you were familiar.
Speaker 0: everyone sees waiting for Godot having already been familiar with it when they see it in the theater kind of like with Macbeth or Rosencrantz and Guildenstern are dead.
Speaker 0: any of those things educated people.
Speaker 0: Yeah But anyway, uh No, man's land.
Speaker 0: I very pointedly Did not read it did not do any research and do literally nothing about it.
Speaker 1: I knew it was about.
Speaker 1: I Thought I read that it was about like some World War one veterans, but maybe that's that is.
Speaker 0: that is Maybe true, but they were old enough to be World War one.
Speaker 1: better I guess that may be true But that has little to do with the plot or any plot.
Speaker 0: is that there's a no man's land Between all men where they never truly come together.
Speaker 0: and it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: every man's our friends Every man is in their trench and they may fire bullets across the way, but that's about it.
Speaker 0: when you're old It doesn't matter if you remember your friends or not because everyone around you might as well be the same And then the people that you did know are mostly dead.
Speaker 0: It was a really depressing play.
Speaker 0: It was funny in the beginning It was funny at the end at a couple of points somewhat that bit that little bit of the Breakfast where McKellen's character just going on and on and on and the guys like bit early for all this, isn't it?
Speaker 0: I Didn't expect to laugh out loud as much as I did and then feel so such existential angst by the end of it.
Speaker 0: Don't become an old man Working on that or at least don't become an alcoholic old man.
Speaker 0: I feel like the two were combined.
Speaker 1: How much of that alcohol was alcohol?
Speaker 1: What was it, you know?
Speaker 0: oftentimes because a lot of friends who are in theater I heard tell that in the last performance of plays that are like that.
Speaker 0: It'll be all real alcohol.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: If that's true, we gotta buy tickets again.
Speaker 1: No, dude, that's enough alcohol to send to the hospital.
Speaker 0: that was Hemingway level drinking.
Speaker 0: otherwise Bring me the bottle That there's a whole bit in the beginning where the Ian McAllen's just being kind of annoying and Patrick Stewart keeps Walking over and pouring himself more vodka.
Speaker 1: Why don't we make a stage production of?
Speaker 0: Like Sun Also Rises or whatever the Sun Also Rises stage production.
Speaker 0: I'm assuming that's been done.
Speaker 1: I'm assuming there's some shit musical about it and get totally and just all real wine all the time.
Speaker 0: You have a new cast real boys real bulls to new cast every time.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: new real bulls real wine Israel.
Speaker 0: That was actually a an assignment.
Speaker 0: I had to do in high school when we read real bulls and real wine.
Speaker 0: What are at what your assignment?
Speaker 1: drink seven bottles of wine when we did over the course of an hour?
Speaker 1: What do we did?
Speaker 1: our Hemingway said run away from some bulls and do it again?
Speaker 0: we had to keep track of how much alcohol people drank in different scenes and Determine what effect that would have on them and a lot of them ended in death death everyone All death no matter what human body they have.
Speaker 1: Even Andre the Giant would have been killed by that amount of alcohol.
Speaker 0: Yep, bottles and bottles and bottles, but so yeah, I digress in case you haven't been paying attention.
Speaker 0: The Ukraine is weak.
Speaker 1: No, I knew that in the 90s.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well apparently that guy on the subway didn't know well, but If you kids a lot of you don't really pay attention to world news as far as I can tell Go read about what's going on in Ukraine.
Speaker 0: It's not really at the top of the news But basically the country is on the verge of like Les Miserables style collapse barricades in the streets Parliament fleeing Kiev.
Speaker 1: right here's baby's first explanation ready.
Speaker 1: the people who live in the eastern parts of the Ukraine voted for basically Soviet government effectively a Putin puppet if you will.
Speaker 1: the people in West Ukraine are totally chill and awesome And they voted for good people or at least relatively good people the West.
Speaker 0: let's work with the EU.
Speaker 1: Why are people who live more West anyway?
Speaker 0: Yeah, Scott because people in Pennsylvania are so much smarter than people here.
Speaker 1: people in eastern, Pennsylvania are at least better than western, Pennsylvania.
Speaker 1: Not saying much though, it's like shit and diarrhea anyway.
Speaker 1: So yeah, the people in western Ukraine are totally chill But you know they're basically living under this shitty government the eastern people.
Speaker 1: Well, it's a little more complicated because it also goes heavily along urban rural delineations much like Right, but if you're the United States if you look at a map of like you know The the the states of the Ukraine and who they voted for.
Speaker 1: it's like two colors And it's not like the US or it's sort of like not a straight line.
Speaker 1: This is like a straight line down the middle.
Speaker 1: It's like oh all the ones in the wet, right?
Speaker 1: So they're super pissed that their government is all evil and corrupt and horrible.
Speaker 1: so they revolted.
Speaker 0: Well, it's it Revolted.
Speaker 0: there is a real revolution.
Speaker 0: There is Les Miserables riots and you know violence Militaries getting involved other countries getting involved.
Speaker 0: the UN will probably be involved.
Speaker 1: there might be NATO actions if this keeps escalating Right like going into the government building taking it over finding government people Doing violence upon them.
Speaker 0: if nothing else Look at the amazing Surprising images coming out of Ukraine.
Speaker 0: There's a photo that I saw people like to sit shit on fire there.
Speaker 1: Well, what is really popular?
Speaker 0: Well in a rioting Les Mis situation?
Speaker 0: That's your go-to Barricade fire fire fire barricade.
Speaker 1: Why don't they go for the ice be like, hey, it's Ukraine.
Speaker 1: We got more ice here.
Speaker 1: Let's do that.
Speaker 0: Ukraine is not northern Finland, but it's listen.
Speaker 1: It ain't warm.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe it is now but it's not like what they got on fire.
Speaker 1: it's not fucking Florida All right, but I saw one picture.
Speaker 0: there's basically this Barricade in the street and there's a man standing on top of it and it looks like the entire city is burning behind him.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and then there's another picture that I would be good posted on Facebook of Basically people who live just in the suburbs like the equivalent of Queens Seeing the smoke rising out of the city center going.
Speaker 0: What the fuck is that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's like you see these photos and you realize like man if I could just go you get like if you have any Interest in photography at all.
Speaker 1: you get this sort of idea Like I should go to a crazy place where shits going down and take photos.
Speaker 0: I was thinking that actually that is the worst idea.
Speaker 1: Well, I do not have that idea.
Speaker 1: It's a bad idea.
Speaker 0: an unnamed person.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what might be your job.
Speaker 0: Give you a journalist because the thing is that does not pay these.
Speaker 1: that is a job that makes you no money.
Speaker 1: You cannot live with that job.
Speaker 0: at least these pictures might generate world interest.
Speaker 0: Of course didn't really help serious so much.
Speaker 1: So you get lucky like one of your pictures might make you famous and then get you jobs doing other things in photography.
Speaker 1: That might make you money.
Speaker 0: remember that dumb anime flag about that picture of the flag.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Don't ever think that.
Speaker 0: so I a side anecdote.
Speaker 0: We have a friend who had a friend long time ago No names here And I got to an argument with that friend at an unnamed convention.
Speaker 0: and the argument that this person put to me Was that and he was being serious.
Speaker 0: It would be an actual tragedy if War ceased to occur because from where would we derive new war stories?
Speaker 1: We'd make them up.
Speaker 0: I Had a long debate that night.
Speaker 1: man It would be real problem if we stopped having the Middle Ages because no one's gonna write more Middle Ages if we actually develop Cyberpunk technology because then there wouldn't be any more cyberpunk stories.
Speaker 1: Yeah Wait, oh we can make stories about things that don't exist.
Speaker 1: Man it would really suck if there were no more Ancient Greeks is and we couldn't make up any more ancient Greeks.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute, but on that urban-rural divide which is also a big part of this I definitely did you see that thing?
Speaker 0: I tweeted of the United States GDP.
Speaker 0: No, okay.
Speaker 0: This this is one of the most amazing maps you'll ever see because this really Explains a lot of what's happening in Turkey in Ukraine trying to pull the map up again so I can show discuss.
Speaker 0: So basically it's the United States.
Speaker 0: I'm just a map of the United States and as two colors one color Represents 50% of the GDP of the United States geography.
Speaker 1: So it's like it's like tiny dots around New York and some other cities and one other color represents the other 50% entire rest of the country.
Speaker 0: Yes It's basically tiny little brown regions around the places you'd expect and the entire rest of the country is yellow, right?
Speaker 1: In other words, we're all you know us people who live in cities and actually do real work.
Speaker 1: We're basically paying for you to exist.
Speaker 0: In other words, here's the map.
Speaker 1: we should be in charge.
Speaker 0: Look at that map.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's basically it's almost the same as what the map would be if you looked at Democrat versus Republican voters, right?
Speaker 1: in other words Anyone who lives in the orange should have a vote and anyone lives in the blue does not.
Speaker 0: oh So you're saying only rich people should vote?
Speaker 1: No, I'm saying only people.
Speaker 1: it's not people who have money.
Speaker 1: It's people who produce.
Speaker 0: Well, oh, so it's the job created.
Speaker 1: It's the GDP not the how much money to have in your bank account.
Speaker 1: It's how much money did you bring into the country?
Speaker 1: right the same way that your parents are the boss of the house because they bring in money.
Speaker 1: when you say we should buy a Nintendo they say you don't get to make any decisions because you're just some kid who didn't make any money.
Speaker 1: and then when you get A job you can say I'm gonna buy a Nintendo and they can't say no because you earn them.
Speaker 0: Well until you're 18, they can still say no Whatever.
Speaker 0: yeah tough shit, of course, that's me Kids, I know a lot of you're in high school So I'm gonna let you in on a secret.
Speaker 0: once you're 18, you can sign your fucking self out of school Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So remember that use it.
Speaker 0: I signed myself out of school to the rolled eyes and sigh of the secretary in the eye.
Speaker 0: in the Administration office like once a week once I turned 18 I was just like round and decoster has a doctor's appointment and I signed it and they're like really You have a doctor's appointment.
Speaker 0: I was like, I'm gonna do about it.
Speaker 0: I'm an adult and I signed this.
Speaker 1: I went to the doctor.
Speaker 1: Um, I made my own doctor's appointment.
Speaker 1: I called the doctor.
Speaker 1: What do you get?
Speaker 1: doesn't matter if I'm lying?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was lying.
Speaker 1: What are you gonna do about it one time?
Speaker 0: I just why I said something.
Speaker 0: I just stopped giving a reason.
Speaker 0: I was like Brandon girls needs to leave school Got something signed by myself.
Speaker 1: In other news We lost at ice disc today.
Speaker 1: Yeah in some disc with a K captain It's this with a C. No Disc or the K is only for like floppy disk or hard disk Like a discus that an Olympian throws is a C and a compact disc is a C. Pretty much any other kind of disc is also a C except for a floppy disc.
Speaker 0: there was some debate on Twitter about this the same out by someone the same way that a Trackball.
Speaker 1: only the Atari trackball does not have the letter C is a TR AK ball.
Speaker 1: Every other trackball is here a CK Track balls.
Speaker 1: you can still get one Yeah, but I don't.
Speaker 0: I used to seem around a lot in the 90s and now I almost never see him.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's the people sort of you know There's still some crazy nuts out there who think a trackball is like good idea.
Speaker 0: There's a couple of uses.
Speaker 0: So our mutual friends got played quake and mega TF with a trackball instead of a mouse.
Speaker 0: great He was as good as me if not better.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't see anyone doing that Trackball.
Speaker 1: you should have seen no one in the Pro Circuit today is doing that.
Speaker 0: I want to.
Speaker 1: you can't tell me a laser mouse is less accurate than that laser trackball.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna help you.
Speaker 0: I want to see a dude with like an eight ball at one of these tournaments.
Speaker 0: That would be the walls cuz they'll lose It.
Speaker 1: basically it died the way the Devorah keyboard and the split ergonomic keyboard should die because they'd all just as bullshit Ergonomically speaking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I guess the trackball actually died.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: so anyway news that was the news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we lost at the ice puck, but you know what and we lost.
Speaker 1: bullshit.
Speaker 1: refs frigging, you know, score the final goal.
Speaker 1: You know, that's okay because you Canadians you lose.
Speaker 1: used up all your luck today and You got none left.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be GG.
Speaker 1: so enjoy it for the next like I don't know 14 hours or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, wait wait until some Canadian team wins the Stanley Cup next year and you and you Know what if we lose tomorrow?
Speaker 1: Then at least I had the balls to trash.
Speaker 1: talk in advance.
Speaker 1: I'm like rim.
Speaker 1: rim never does that.
Speaker 0: sometimes I do Sometimes I do and you know what it's rare.
Speaker 1: They're probably listening to this after that game is completed.
Speaker 1: Anyway, if we win that game I was right suck it.
Speaker 1: You should have let us win today and you could have maybe one tomorrow.
Speaker 1: But the refs they already gave you the.
Speaker 1: you already cashed in your favor.
Speaker 0: I would love to see what would happen.
Speaker 0: I know it can't happen.
Speaker 0: I know it's impossible to happen if NHL teams played by Olympic rules just once one year Can you imagine the announcers during the hockey games actually been discussing a lot how like the NHL ice is too small?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah And the Olympic ice is too big that in Finland and I think Norway or something They actually have like this in-between ice size.
Speaker 1: that is like the best ice size.
Speaker 1: It makes the game like, you know, it gives like enough room to like, you know, really show off your skills You know without being cramped in thing is I like?
Speaker 1: it's also Tight enough that you can actually get more action instead of like the puck goes around.
Speaker 0: I like wide hockey.
Speaker 0: I like four on four hockey even more.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like four four, but yeah They're talking about like.
Speaker 1: the best ice size is this in-between size.
Speaker 0: Anyway, what if you go bigger and have like 20 on 20?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know Olympic hockey is pretty much the best Sport there is so You don't have too many opportunities to watch it.
Speaker 1: and tomorrow is the day.
Speaker 1: Basically, there's two games tomorrow Sweden Finland and US Canada.
Speaker 1: Whoever wins those two games goes to the gold medal game in Which is Sunday the gold medal game.
Speaker 1: if you win you get a gold medal.
Speaker 1: you lose silver medal.
Speaker 1: So bad the two teams that lose tomorrow Still get to play.
Speaker 1: they go to the bronze medal game.
Speaker 1: You win the bronze medal game you get a bronze medal.
Speaker 1: if you lose you get shit.
Speaker 0: who's the comedian I think was Jerry Seinfeld who said that you want the gold.
Speaker 0: obviously, that's what you're shooting for But if you're not gonna get the gold you're better off with the bronze.
Speaker 0: Well, at least and here's his argument if you win the gold, you're the champion of the world.
Speaker 0: fuck everybody.
Speaker 0: If you win the silver, you're the guy who didn't win the gold, but if you win the bronze, hey, I got a medal.
Speaker 0: That was his argument.
Speaker 0: at least that was in the same album I believe.
Speaker 1: if I was in charge of the Olympics I would eliminate all bronze and silver medals and I would eliminate the gold medal - there'd be a platinum medal for the winner And everyone else gets nothing cuz everyone else gets shot.
Speaker 1: Second place is the first loser.
Speaker 0: You know in Science Olympiad, they did something interesting.
Speaker 1: End of story.
Speaker 0: I think they still do it because there'd be like 40 you're either the best or you're nobody.
Speaker 0: so Science Olympiads in high schools We have 40 or 50 high schools and like the regional tournaments for whatever They usually have eight places that got medals because you got a medal if the thing was worth points for qualifying for state or nationals.
Speaker 0: So medal meant you counted four points And then there was a meta score for your high school or your country or whatever if they want to give out like multiple awards.
Speaker 1: The way you need to do it is the way the bicycle races do it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you can win the bicycle race and win But like if you get up the mountain first you get the red and white dots.
Speaker 1: and it's like only the people who are the Best at something get something but it you don't get anything.
Speaker 1: if you weren't the number one in some category Number two people like I was the second guy up the mountain.
Speaker 1: You don't get shit.
Speaker 1: I finished the race second.
Speaker 1: You don't get shit, right?
Speaker 1: We only give out jerseys and medals to people who are first.
Speaker 0: That's also why I think some people enjoy like marathons those kind of long things because then there's almost this place of.
Speaker 0: I Finished it.
Speaker 0: I made it to the end.
Speaker 1: Did you finish it first?
Speaker 1: who fucking cares?
Speaker 0: I'm so you lost.
Speaker 0: So shut up, you're a loser.
Speaker 0: You wanna play some nidhag Olympic nidhag at least.
Speaker 1: nidhag only gives a win to the guy in first.
Speaker 0: Yeah No problems there but anyway things of the day Got a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I do you know the.
Speaker 1: the Commodore 64 Has a famous Audio chip in it the CID.
Speaker 1: right my machine supremacy has used it Famously as among many other people.
Speaker 1: it has a particular sound that is pretty unique amongst digital audio mechanisms and it has been said that that sound cannot be perfectly reproduced in software and even The way it works.
Speaker 1: every CID chip, you know, even though they're all the same chip is unique in its own Slightly varied way, but you know what the reality is.
Speaker 1: you can basically make that sound with software and your computer, right?
Speaker 1: It'll be 99% the same and I dare anyone to tell the difference.
Speaker 1: But where can you get software that does that, you know, you can get a Commodore 64 emulator and write software for it But that's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: This website, I think it this is like some HTML 5 website.
Speaker 1: I don't think they make this in JavaScript or something, but it's pretty crazy.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it has all the control.
Speaker 1: It's like a little keyboard like a musical keyboard not a you know computer keyboard.
Speaker 1: You could actually plug in a musical keyboard to a Commodore 64 and all the controls for the CID chip and you can Play musics on it.
Speaker 0: Not too shabby.
Speaker 1: Just go to its web CID.
Speaker 1: just web CID.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good.
Speaker 0: So there's an old song that I'm a fan of.
Speaker 0: we've had things of the day about this song a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Since that song a furry Robin Hood.
Speaker 1: That's the songs.
Speaker 1: an old song your favorite.
Speaker 0: since Way back at a bad an Otacon we went to where the anime music video contest had a Music video made by some fan of anime.
Speaker 0: That was so much better than anything that was submitted.
Speaker 1: It didn't win but it got the honorable mention from the judges.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the judges knew it was up and the judge Oh, yeah, the con goers didn't know shit.
Speaker 0: It was the best entry.
Speaker 0: It didn't win.
Speaker 0: the con goers The judges were like fuck it.
Speaker 0: this thing wins our thing.
Speaker 0: because that's right and the song is 25 25 famous song great song.
Speaker 0: I went the other day searching around to see if there's been any covers or remixes.
Speaker 1: Probably zillion.
Speaker 0: There's almost fucking nothing really.
Speaker 0: There is almost no one who is covered or remixed this song.
Speaker 0: 20 significant degree.
Speaker 1: that has made it digitally available.
Speaker 0: Yeah in any capacity.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, why don't we cover it?
Speaker 0: Maybe we should.
Speaker 0: so I listened to the few I could find Around the internet and many of them were bad But you're gonna make that one.
Speaker 0: So So of all of them I found one that was kind of special and The band is kind of special and that's my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Thank you Slovenia for live ovenia.
Speaker 1: They just lost it.
Speaker 1: hockey they did.
Speaker 0: Like blood new race rises from the mud Destroy the last skyline.
Speaker 0: the flaming crows appears in the sky.
Speaker 0: Man bows down loves the bullets fly Now.
Speaker 0: Oh So very far Or Former you former you former you go.
Speaker 0: slavian avant-garde music group Associated with industrial martial and neoclassical music.
Speaker 0: just just listen to this song.
Speaker 1: That's all you need to know should link to the original because people probably don't.
Speaker 0: I will link to the original and to music video.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll do the music video all in one.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 0: So, yeah, I've met a moment the book is wool, I should still take a copy home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have a good day cuz my bags pretty empty.
Speaker 0: I haven't started reading it yet cuz either.
Speaker 0: cuz I thought I reading more culture books still.
Speaker 1: I thought you read them all.
Speaker 0: No, I read most of them.
Speaker 0: I got a few to go.
Speaker 0: I tried to slow down because there's no more.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: We're going to be at coming up relatively soon really soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah Boston we will be doing on Friday fundamental anime at 2 p.m Judge anime by its cover.
Speaker 0: at 3 p.m.
Speaker 0: They're back-to-back in different rooms.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna cut off fundamental anime a little early and run the secret guide to running panels on Saturday noon and not all Anime are what they seem on Saturday at 2 30.
Speaker 0: The rest of that time will be hanging out in sports bars and playing German board games.
Speaker 1: shortly Afterwards is PAX East.
Speaker 1: if you don't have a ticket you ain't going.
Speaker 0: we will be presenting.
Speaker 0: No, I was about to say the wrong panel name why no one will game with you.
Speaker 0: Would you suck?
Speaker 1: And cuz you didn't get a ticket to PAX East and you can't play games if you're not there And the panel let's play games.
Speaker 1: Oh Anyone who's in this room?
Speaker 1: You don't need to hear this panel because people will play games with you.
Speaker 1: because you're here.
Speaker 1: everyone who's not at this Convention no one will play games with you.
Speaker 0: I will say this We for a long time had a philosophy of having titles of panels that were perhaps inflammatory Controversial, I think this started with our gecky guy Colin putting the man back in manga.
Speaker 0: So while we're bringing that tradition back, what's this a panel about?
Speaker 1: You'll find out your mom I'm gonna insult you could to make you go away So I don't have to play.
Speaker 0: we're actually gonna go through the room person by person Interview them and then tell them why we won't play games with them.
Speaker 1: That's right Because you don't know the rules because you're slow because you don't speak English because I don't like you because you're ugly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz you're not ugly ugly smelly ugly ugly smelly smelly ugly.
Speaker 0: No, it's gonna be a good panel.
Speaker 0: It's actually a complex topic.
Speaker 0: Whatever you'll see it.
Speaker 0: It'll be awesome.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be a zenk icon doing a bunch of panels.
Speaker 0: I forget what.
Speaker 1: I gotta let me go into this.
Speaker 0: I think we're doing anime openers for around the world.
Speaker 0: I think we're doing all anime are the same convention season if you haven't noticed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a kinetic on.
Speaker 0: Submit your fucking panels.
Speaker 0: We're Best yep.
Speaker 1: Oh One slight news.
Speaker 1: We're not going to this.
Speaker 0: That's not public.
Speaker 0: We can't talk about that.
Speaker 1: What about what?
Speaker 0: I'm not sure what you're about to talk about.
Speaker 1: the New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: Okay, we can talk about that.
Speaker 1: May is gonna make another convention.
Speaker 1: That's also the New York Comic Con Yeah, but it's basically the Philly wizard world variant, right?
Speaker 1: So basically because the New York Comic Con has no comics at it anymore.
Speaker 1: It's all movies and bullshit.
Speaker 1: But they're still gonna call it comic-con.
Speaker 1: They're making a separate comic-con on a different day like in the summer.
Speaker 1: That's gonna actually be just comics which means that one is actually also gonna be called New York Comic Con Special Edition or some shit and it's gonna basically end up being a Philly wizard world because it's comics only.
Speaker 0: No, it might be Philly wizard world with I mean song of mocha for that.
Speaker 1: I mean wizard world is everywhere.
Speaker 1: It's not just in Philly, but it's gonna be a crappy.
Speaker 1: You know bunch of tables really sad guys selling back issues.
Speaker 0: when we say Philly wizard was an artist alley You know what?
Speaker 0: I'll link to it.
Speaker 0: I'll link to the show we did on Philly wizard world, right?
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's just like every other comic show, you know a few sad comic.
Speaker 0: now a lot of people said Oh, it'll probably have a lot of that indie mocha stuff, but you know Virgil sitting in the corner You know what given any autographs?
Speaker 0: I We go to mocha still even though it's you know, the side of illustrators and everything.
Speaker 0: now I've been to SPX and what I saw at SPX was that a lot of the people who used to go to mocha and stopped hated mocha always hated it and only go to SPX.
Speaker 0: and the main reason is that New York fucking sucks to go to a convention Unless you are wealthy and you live here or you live here.
Speaker 0: So unless the indie comedy people live here It sucks for them to go to comic because they're poor.
Speaker 0: Also because it sucks to go to conventions in New York City.
Speaker 0: what you can go to some venue.
Speaker 0: That's not really a good fit in Manhattan where no one can afford a hotel.
Speaker 0: or you go to the Javits where there's fucking nothing There and no way to get there.
Speaker 0: No subway barely any buses no cabs unless you're going to the airport and no hotels.
Speaker 1: While you know build corrupt Convention Center near Airport.
Speaker 0: why Seriously, New York.
Speaker 1: Everyone else used their corruption to build shit.
Speaker 1: Why don't we use our corruption to build something we need?
Speaker 0: if we built something like the BCEC in Boston or the?
Speaker 0: BCC in Baltimore in like flushing there would be a PAX there.
Speaker 0: I bet Thanks would have been there instead of Boston.
Speaker 1: Imagine you fly to JFK you take the air train boom you're at the Convention Center this hotels there and Amazing New York food and after the convention is done you can take the Way for 250 to go to Manhattan and enjoy the rest of your vacation.
Speaker 0: non New Yorkers take note.
Speaker 0: flushing you might think oh That's like way on the end of the seven line like way out in Queens.
Speaker 0: Flushing is a.
Speaker 1: It's a $2 and change subway ride that takes less than a half hour.
Speaker 0: some of the best Chinese and Korean food You'll ever have in your life isn't flushing?
Speaker 1: also Chinese people.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right, so dentists dentists Everybody goes to the dentist.
Speaker 1: if you don't what the fuck do your teeth look like good God.
Speaker 0: Well, what did our what did chase say recently?
Speaker 0: He was like, I just went to the dentist and He said that you don't have to floss all your teeth All the ones you want to keep.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm actually overdue.
Speaker 0: I'm like a year overdue going to the dentist because my insurance changed like five times and I had to cancel my last dentist appointment that I had scheduled because of sudden travel and it's just been fucking impossible to reschedule.
Speaker 0: Finally way overdue and you know what?
Speaker 0: I'm yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah every adult I think has those dreams of oh my god a tooth fell out.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: yeah, that's a common thing.
Speaker 0: There's a Wikipedia article about you play hockey.
Speaker 0: No, but I'm like worried about like I got to go to the dentist.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking about it a lot, but I'm still trying to find a dentist and schedule.
Speaker 1: Okay, you just go to the dentist.
Speaker 1: I went to because my co-workers all recommended it.
Speaker 0: I think my new insurance will cover it and I went there and it's basically the bestest dentist ever.
Speaker 1: It's all super modern with like the highest technologies and they'll email you a confirmation and it's like yeah, this is for real That's kind of a meta point.
Speaker 0: that because I've realized this because you said that about your dentist Emily said that about her doctor and then independently when I got my Google last thing.
Speaker 0: I went to an optician that was like this Most doctors offices are run by old people who don't know shit about technology.
Speaker 1: Okay, what I think it really is is that any any kind of any any sort of office like that, you know?
Speaker 1: Mostly medical offices But really almost anything right.
Speaker 1: any.
Speaker 1: any small business when the business opens will have the latest and greatest technology of when it opens But then it will not upgrade unless it is absolutely necessary.
Speaker 1: So you feel like an old restaurant.
Speaker 1: it'll have like a cash register, but you've got a new restaurant.
Speaker 1: It'll be all like whoosh digital, you know systems putting in orders and everything, right?
Speaker 1: But this they'll never upgrade it because there's no reason to upgrade it.
Speaker 1: They have a system that works.
Speaker 1: as long as that system continues to work They will never change it.
Speaker 1: So the dentist I went to is a really freaking new dentist.
Speaker 1: It's super fancy.
Speaker 1: It's probably gonna remain at its current level of fanciness For as long as it exists and it probably won't upgrade ever unless it has to.
Speaker 1: so if you go to a dentist who's like Been around for 30 years.
Speaker 1: They have really good dentist experience probably probably really good at dentisting But they're probably using.
Speaker 1: you know Like Matt the dentist chairs are probably like 10 years old and they probably don't not gonna email you anything ever.
Speaker 0: I'm not not even just that kind of stuff like the you know Have like.
Speaker 0: they send you a calendar invite like basic shit like that I'm talking like most up.
Speaker 0: a lot of people I know have been to opticians that still in the year 25 20 the year 2014 Will manually with that big crazy looking thing that you put in front of your face Rotate a bunch of lenses and dials around and manually figure out your prescription instead of having the laser computer.
Speaker 0: Just do it They'll.
Speaker 1: they won't actually like do any sort of Expensive piece of equipment and they already have a piece of equipment that works and gets the job done.
Speaker 1: So it's a job done kinda right, but how much money are they gonna spend to upgrade to that other thing?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're starting off as a new optician.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you have your loan that you've taken out to start your business.
Speaker 0: Oh, so, let me tell you but if you're an old business It's like you don't have that the more modern opticians with the more modern stuff also charge about half what the old men charge.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm doing a little bit of investigative journalism here.
Speaker 0: So the moral is Our health care system is so fucked up that most people don't get to pick.
Speaker 0: because if if you could pick Freely what doctor and dentist and optician everyone you went to I think a lot of these old Style places would go out of business and there'd actually be pressure to modernize because there'd be actual competition.
Speaker 0: the problem is there's no competition because most people their HMO or whatever is like you can go to these five doctors and four of Them aren't taking fish.
Speaker 1: I think the real problem is not just you know, it's like I can pick from quite a few, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I can't go to anyone I want in the whole universe, but there's a lot of choices.
Speaker 1: leave for Dennis.
Speaker 1: I can actually go anywhere.
Speaker 1: I want.
Speaker 0: there's no way to compare them though.
Speaker 1: How do you compare them?
Speaker 1: You go make an appointment.
Speaker 1: Well, that was your appointment.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, why would you ever go make an appointment somewhere else?
Speaker 1: and then yeah, I have to make another appointment.
Speaker 1: Why wouldn't I go to the place?
Speaker 1: I already went.
Speaker 0: that already has records All right, so there's 20 doctors over the course of 20 years.
Speaker 0: I get a physical at each one to see which one's better and meanwhile that the first one you tried.
Speaker 1: It was 20 years ago.
Speaker 1: Who knows if they're even still around.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I need to be able to you know.
Speaker 1: How do you how do you chop around and figure out which ones I want to go to?
Speaker 1: the reviews?
Speaker 1: There's all sorts of legalities around doctor reviews that they don't have on restaurant reviews, right?
Speaker 1: Yep, so it's weird.
Speaker 0: It's all weird and messed up and American health care is just fucked right?
Speaker 0: I digress.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah dentists thing.
Speaker 1: So I hope you brush your teeth Floss your teeth.
Speaker 0: Yeah guys brush your teeth at least twice, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like a lot of people they're scared to go to the dentist for some reason.
Speaker 0: I think I think it's simple Everyone's.
Speaker 0: the people who are scared to go to the dentist are the same 40 year old men who don't go to get their colonoscopy they don't want to find out that something's wrong and they don't go to the doctor or dentist or anything until they're forced to by Crippling pain or months of blood.
Speaker 1: Well, I think what it is is that if you go to like a doctor, right?
Speaker 1: people some people are scared of the doctor too, but it's like in terms of things the doctor will do to you when you go To him it's like it might poke you with a needle.
Speaker 0: Yep, right turn your head and cough.
Speaker 1: if you go to a dentist pull your shirt up, right?
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: That's rather unlikely and not often most of the dentist that most doctor visits and really nothing happens.
Speaker 1: That's anything that could be painful, right?
Speaker 1: It's just like they talk to you and they you know stethoscope and whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you go to a dentist It's actually somewhat likely that they are going to do something to you.
Speaker 1: That will not hurt, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I got all drilled today and it was probably the least painful.
Speaker 1: whatever I didn't feel shit.
Speaker 0: You got the shot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't even feel the shot.
Speaker 1: I mean, what did they do?
Speaker 0: the tap first or the other?
Speaker 0: It's not actually a shot It's just like the numbing gel that comes right there.
Speaker 1: So usually the procedure nowadays is they put goop on a q-tip and then they put the shot where the goop was.
Speaker 1: so goop is like basically like topical antiseptic Topical anesthetic and then they put the shot.
Speaker 1: there is you don't feel the shot.
Speaker 1: That's making you even more numb, but whatever It's like I you know when I was in Australia They just gave me the shot straight in the chin and it didn't even that hurt a little bit, but whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well you had a. you had a sizable gash in your chin at the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so maybe your nerves I've had it.
Speaker 1: I've had it in my lip before too.
Speaker 1: It's like I think I'm pretty much This is the doctor show.
Speaker 0: cuz it's the doctor show.
Speaker 0: we're gonna talk about shots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my I've gotten some fucking shots.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so but the boys people are scared of dentists.
Speaker 1: cuz actually rather likely that a dentist will use implements on you That are frightening such as drills.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm going to drill your body that it would like a high-speed spinning thing That is usually used on like wood and you know heart.
Speaker 1: It's like they're gonna take the hardware store to your mouth and it's like the concept of that Can be alarming coupled with I think the secondary effects.
Speaker 0: I mean, even if it doesn't hurt if they're drilling your tooth you smell burning tooth.
Speaker 1: I didn't smell any burning tooth.
Speaker 0: I do if they do a proper drill.
Speaker 0: I've smelled burning tooth before.
Speaker 0: I guess it depends on what they're drilling out.
Speaker 1: really what it's all about that You want high-speed drills, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz the high-speed drill.
Speaker 0: well once again you wanna go to a modern dentist will not like vibrate your head, right?
Speaker 0: Kind of like how there's all those different kinds of fillings and everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, uh, you really these days you should go with the composite filling.
Speaker 0: it depends.
Speaker 0: I've still read the composite only last 10 to 15 years before they might need to be replaced.
Speaker 0: But good old amalgam will last 25 plus amalgam will poison you with mercury.
Speaker 0: No, actually, there's no evidence that it does.
Speaker 1: It's such a small amount of mercury.
Speaker 0: No, it's actually.
Speaker 0: every study I've ever found says that it doesn't.
Speaker 1: I just said it is a such a small.
Speaker 0: Get it drilled out and replaced with something else drilling it out will release a bunch of mercury.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I've got a bunch of amalgam filming fillings in the back of my mouth.
Speaker 1: I have one amalgam filling the rest are the composite kind.
Speaker 1: they've lasted way longer than 10 15 years.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean we're talking about dentists.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna get into orthodontia But this another episode we could do we good.
Speaker 0: I got braces twice me, too.
Speaker 0: So total of eight and a half years of braces between the two times I don't know how many years total and that actually caused some issues in my teeth that affect me to this day.
Speaker 0: So I've had a lot more.
Speaker 1: at least you had it and you're not one of those people the fucked up mouth.
Speaker 1: So Actually, you want to know something really sad like micro who like his mouth is fucked up to this day.
Speaker 0: one of the most direct And trivial way to determine in the West Whether or not a person was born into the middle of the middle class or up is whether or not they have straight teeth Not perfect teeth but straight teeth because orthodontia is not really accessible to people in the lower end of middle class and down.
Speaker 1: Oh, that shit is expensive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the odds are that almost everyone will need orthodontia.
Speaker 0: So as a result someone who has mostly straight teeth was probably born into a middle-class family.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: it's one of those things that might not be true in the far future but in this current day is Definitely true.
Speaker 1: So let's talk about dental procedures, right?
Speaker 1: So first obviously there's the cleaning.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: I've had Dennis clean my teeth in at least three different ways.
Speaker 1: Right way.
Speaker 1: number one is like the old-fashioned way where first they go with the metal picks and they go scratchy scratchy scratchy Yeah, remove all the tartar and then they have the rubber thing that polishes like Right, that's way number one.
Speaker 1: and then occasionally the fluoride afterwards thing that's usually when you're younger.
Speaker 1: they do that way.
Speaker 1: number two They do the scratchy scratchy a bit, right?
Speaker 1: But they use basically a sandblaster except it's sort of a saltwater kind of thing right and That works.
Speaker 1: and then the place I went to now right, you know, they did a little bit of metal picking or whatever.
Speaker 1: But actually the thing they used it wasn't a sandblasting saltwater It was a sonic vibrating just water.
Speaker 1: But it was all like so sonic that all the tartar like it shatters Right because it's like a very tiny screaming opera person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that was that was the third method.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure which method I like the most.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I find the cleanings to be less pleasant than the actual procedures.
Speaker 0: Hmm you'd rather have a drilling than a cleaning because the drilling is What the actual active fucking around in my mouth doesn't take that long.
Speaker 0: It's love just waiting for the amalgam to see waiting for this waiting for that.
Speaker 0: It's easier, I guess.
Speaker 0: But at the same time I'm not bothered by that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Like I remember my mom was always freaked out by not the pain because remember in the old days dentistry was a lot more painful.
Speaker 1: We are lucky in our day they have.
Speaker 1: it's like, you know, even that the local anesthetic has changed between different kinds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like the kind you get now is way better.
Speaker 0: I mean the old ones used to burn before they stopped before they numb to be like And then it would go away.
Speaker 1: Yeah now it's like at worst.
Speaker 1: you feel the pressure of the injection And I remember this sound distinctly as if you got Significant work.
Speaker 0: the shot that used to give you was like up into the roof of your mouth and it would make this like sickly Crunching noise and you feel it But you wouldn't feel like you wouldn't feel pain.
Speaker 0: You just feel like it going in.
Speaker 0: That really that messed a lot of people up.
Speaker 0: I think Yeah, so that might be part of it that you can't see what they're doing.
Speaker 0: If you're getting stitches, you can at least watch him doing it and the kind of removes that sort of existential mystery horror.
Speaker 0: But in your mouth, there's a guy with a drill and now you can't see the drill and you smell burning and you see him Doing stuff and you feel it in there.
Speaker 1: There's seen even a lot of people who are really pussies because a lot of the dentists I know Including the one I'm going to now.
Speaker 1: It's like they'll for extra money.
Speaker 1: They'll give you the gas and it seems like a lot of people are just so sissy that they go for it depends.
Speaker 0: I got the gas.
Speaker 0: I got a light.
Speaker 1: I've never gotten the gas.
Speaker 0: I got the non knockout gas.
Speaker 0: I've never had any gas when I had to get a pretty substantial drilling.
Speaker 1: There is no reason to risk any gas because the gas itself is risky.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends and general anesthesia is risky.
Speaker 0: just nitrous oxide not super risky it's still somewhat risky.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got it because I had a drilling that was pretty substantial and he was worried that he was gonna hit nerve And he didn't want to risk all that pain.
Speaker 1: So he was like look Well, the real reason is like they don't actually care if you feel pain.
Speaker 1: that this is Dennis doesn't feel it.
Speaker 1: I care the prop that the reason they care is because if you feel a pain your body will go.
Speaker 1: Ah, right, you'll move and like pull away and move your head Another human being to feel pain and they might like drill into your cheek.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure if you said I want to feel the pain they'd be like I'm okay If you want to feel the pain But I'm not okay with you jerking your head and the me.
Speaker 1: I got your face.
Speaker 0: I had two cavities drilled out once when I was a teenager with no anesthesia Whoa, and the dentist didn't give a shit.
Speaker 0: No because he was like probably not gonna hit a nerve.
Speaker 0: He was like tell me if it hurts because they were trying to avoid giving anesthesia for whatever reason if they could.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm as I remember that very distinct.
Speaker 1: It's like just a little bit and it's only in but I'll tell you an animal part of the tooth.
Speaker 0: It was a lot of not hurting but then he hit something once and there was this tweet.
Speaker 0: It felt like a line just went through my tooth into my brain.
Speaker 1: That's how it is.
Speaker 0: I went under once for a dental procedure completely.
Speaker 1: what the hell did they do to you?
Speaker 0: wisdom teeth?
Speaker 0: Oh, I had to get you know, I have wisdom teeth all of them.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: You're a crazy aberration.
Speaker 1: They took it because when I was doing orthodontia, which you're not supposed to talk about The teeth directly behind me.
Speaker 0: Oh you already got some teeth taken out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was with local anesthesia though.
Speaker 0: No, yeah, cuz the front teeth are much easier to get out.
Speaker 0: also kid teeth.
Speaker 0: They're much easier to get out.
Speaker 1: Those weren't kids eat.
Speaker 1: they were permanent teeth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you were a kid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they removed those teeth and then the braces pulled all the teeth forward and then the wisdom teeth.
Speaker 0: It's like a room.
Speaker 0: Yes, I was 17 and they were like, yeah, you gotta get your wisdom teeth out.
Speaker 0: It's time and Basically, I was like how much will it hurt?
Speaker 0: They were like a lot.
Speaker 0: I was like, can you put me under?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know what else hurts not having your wisdom teeth out.
Speaker 1: Yep, that also hurts.
Speaker 0: It's going to hurt.
Speaker 0: my stepdad had an extra tooth that grew Beyond a wisdom - yeah like a double wise - and it was past all his normal teeth and kind of growing out of the top Of his mouth straight down.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh that kind of - yeah that kind of - yeah.
Speaker 0: But so I got general anesthesia to get all four wisdom teeth removed at once Because they do local it's usually wanted it one Yeah, so they were like look back We'll do the other.
Speaker 0: they were like look if we put you all the way under we can do everything now You won't feel a thing.
Speaker 0: you'll wake up at home.
Speaker 0: and I was like sign me up doc.
Speaker 0: and I remember so distinctly.
Speaker 0: They put the mask over my face and they were like inhale deeply and count backwards from 10 And I inhale deeply and I said 10 and I remember thinking I wonder how long I can hold.
Speaker 0: and I literally woke up at Home and it was all over.
Speaker 0: I didn't even get through that sentence.
Speaker 1: I've heard right that if you do the general thing that what they do is cuz like you're not conscious You can't keep your mouth open Right intentionally is they basically put a like a jack inside your mouth to jack your jaw open?
Speaker 1: I can believe that right and I've also heard that basically They'll jack it way the fuck open and then you'll be all sore when you wake up.
Speaker 1: I was real sore that when I was young and part of the soreness is not just the tooth pulling obviously But also that they jacked your mouth all the way fucking and they wrench your.
Speaker 0: you're around a lot in there.
Speaker 0: Right seen videos of like what it looks like when they're taking wisdom to you that guy just fucking like holding on to a tooth With pliers cuz you're asleep.
Speaker 1: He doesn't give a shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he doesn't have to go easy or anything.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I'd want to try the Twilight anesthesia.
Speaker 1: What is that about?
Speaker 0: Uh, basically you're conscious and will respond but you won't remember anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah No, I worry that while you're under you feel all that pain.
Speaker 0: You just don't remember it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, my grandma got it.
Speaker 0: I saw some video when she got to some eye surgery.
Speaker 0: She's a hundred percent conscious and the doctor keeps talking to her.
Speaker 0: He's like don't open don't close that.
Speaker 0: I blink that I do this.
Speaker 0: do that and she's responding and talking to him And meanwhile, he's fucking just cutting her eye open with the scalp.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's like that crazy drug.
Speaker 1: They use in Colombia.
Speaker 0: Oh Oh the the zombie one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I forget what that was called me too.
Speaker 0: I saw a vice documentary But I think it's because croco deal took over all the news about crazy drugs.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's pretty much the final crazy.
Speaker 0: Like nothing will be crazier than that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess the only real dental procedure head besides teeth pulling is teeth filling which is not too bad I guess teeth sealing but that doesn't even you know.
Speaker 1: drill most of the time.
Speaker 0: funnily enough after we decided to do this show I had a tooth related incident at work.
Speaker 0: a co-worker was like Guys, my daughter just broke one of her teeth like in half.
Speaker 0: Yeah Okay, so we're like what and go to the dentist.
Speaker 0: He's like she ran into a door.
Speaker 0: So go to the dentist And she so he pulls out a picture and yeah, her tooth is like broken off like halfway down.
Speaker 0: Whoa, and you know cuz I had something like that happen once.
Speaker 0: but basically what it was?
Speaker 0: I was flossing and I had a tooth that had a filling from braces like braces fucked and this really just came out.
Speaker 0: So the braces fucked up the front of this tooth.
Speaker 0: So I had an amalgam filling like on the whole front of the tooth from a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Apparently a cavity grew behind it but didn't get into the nerve and didn't get around it.
Speaker 0: So unless I'd gotten an x-ray, which I just hadn't gotten for a few years There's no way to know.
Speaker 0: so one day I'm flossing and the whole front of my tooth just goes ping and bounces off of the Mirror and I'm like, oh, yeah Cuz you know when you break it - all you're thinking is I hope they can fix it.
Speaker 0: How can I get you a dentist like right?
Speaker 1: There's the one thing right?
Speaker 1: It's like I'm not it's like you.
Speaker 1: I go to the dentist for some drilling.
Speaker 1: I'm like, whatever even if I they said you have to have a root canal.
Speaker 1: Sorry, I'd be like, oh well And I just do it.
Speaker 1: the one thing that I am actually afraid to go to the dentist for is a dental implant.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if it's that's like you're a hockey player and you lose a tooth.
Speaker 1: What do you do?
Speaker 0: This is what they do general anesthesia and I wake up with a new robot - I don't care.
Speaker 1: They take a screw a literal metal screw and they screw it into your jaw in this in the spot where the tooth was.
Speaker 0: that's cool.
Speaker 1: and then on the Right on.
Speaker 1: that's awesome, I guess conceptually it's awesome.
Speaker 1: but if I think about someone screwing a metal screw into my general anesthesia, I Don't really want general anesthesia either because that is in itself also dangerous.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I really don't want to have that.
Speaker 1: But I guess the good part is if you have an implanted tooth like that and something ever happens to it They can just pop it off the screw and pop a new one.
Speaker 0: I think the cool thing is.
Speaker 1: the bad part is what if the screw just fucking shatters your jaw?
Speaker 0: that can happen.
Speaker 1: you can Don't get a tooth implant.
Speaker 0: So I'm at least confident unless you have to Our generation is gonna be one of the first ones we're in our old age.
Speaker 0: Dental technology has actually progressed a lot in the last.
Speaker 1: all these rumors about stem cells.
Speaker 1: Your tooth just grows back.
Speaker 1: I'm like all about that.
Speaker 1: I cannot wait.
Speaker 1: Yep I'm like, please just pop my filling out squirt some stem cells in there.
Speaker 1: My tooth grows back and I'll be like, oh, yes real teeth perfect shrank teeth.
Speaker 0: Oh Like a tiny doll.
Speaker 1: I'd be the greatest.
Speaker 0: guys get guys.
Speaker 0: Can you grow me a vampire tooth?
Speaker 0: I just got like a like one dog tooth like right there just and if like a tooth is chipped It's like up fixed it.
Speaker 1: Yeah with real tooth that actually grew from you your DNA your tooth not some fucking Cement or some of course.
Speaker 0: at the same time cybernetics and crazy material science could make a totally synthetic jaw or tooth or whatever.
Speaker 0: I think that's all coming.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 1: It'll just like take a matter printer.
Speaker 1: I put my bite onto it and it goes cuz.
Speaker 0: the reality is as far as I can tell my mouth Perfectly.
Speaker 0: if you don't take care of your teeth, you're fucked.
Speaker 0: But if you do take care of your teeth There's still a not zero chance.
Speaker 0: You're fucked.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I mean old people.
Speaker 0: just shit happens.
Speaker 0: your teeth They're not gonna be great when you're 80.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how many old people do you see with like amazing perfect teeth?
Speaker 0: My grandpa actually like his teeth are really good for how old he is.
Speaker 1: but it's like even if you brush a fuck ton as you're supposed to and floss and everything and whatever and It's not.
Speaker 1: there's no guarantees with the teeth department.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and plus I mean genetics like if your mouth is kind of dry or you sleep with your mouth open.
Speaker 0: Yeah, your gums are gonna get worse as time goes on just because no way around that.
Speaker 0: A lot of things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also just you know, avoid the obvious bad things for teeth like sandpaper Whatevs.
Speaker 0: don't just like.
Speaker 1: don't just like don't be a pussy and just go to the dentist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't wear a grill.
Speaker 1: How long have we gone?
Speaker 0: I think we're done.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't have any.
Speaker 0: I mean I've shared every tooth related.
Speaker 0: I have one more tooth anecdote.
Speaker 0: Okay, so when I was in middle school got to science Olympiad states.
Speaker 0: So we got to go to Lansing Someone.
Speaker 1: someone had a tooth problem.
Speaker 0: The bus broke down.
Speaker 0: school bus buses.
Speaker 0: tooth broke due to Liability concerns even though we broke down less than a mile away from the hotel We were staying at.
Speaker 1: you couldn't walk there.
Speaker 0: We had to stay on the bus until a bus came from our home To pick us up and drive us the rest of the way.
Speaker 0: So we said this fucking bus for like four hours.
Speaker 0: Then the bus got towed to a parking lot and we went into this other hotel.
Speaker 0: That was like a block away from our real hotel and I had to fucking sit there for another three or four hours.
Speaker 0: I would just run.
Speaker 1: I just run off the bus.
Speaker 0: I thought about it.
Speaker 0: I was in middle school.
Speaker 0: so we're hanging around just bored out of our goddamn minds playing mafia and Someone won.
Speaker 0: so she jumped up and down.
Speaker 0: The metal that she was wearing Flipped up into the air.
Speaker 1: So you had already won the science.
Speaker 0: Yes We already won.
Speaker 0: this is this all happened on the way to the hotel after the competition.
Speaker 0: Okay, jumps up in the air.
Speaker 1: The metal goes up into the air.
Speaker 0: It's her in the face levers around hits her in the face and just shatters one of her front teeth.
Speaker 0: Okay, completely into nerve exposed crippling pain.
Speaker 0: We had to wait till that fucking bus came.
Speaker 0: So before they would let her parents take her to the dentist Just call 9-1-1.
Speaker 1: That's a tooth emergency.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not it's not a fucking.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go to the dentist now.
Speaker 0: that is just me being mad about Everything in America related to law.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if that was my tooth, I would have fucking run away to a payphone and call that one.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, if it had been my tooth my parents would have been like, yes Anyone tried to stop me.
Speaker 1: I would have kicked him right in the junk.
Speaker 1: Whether they had junk or not Whatever is in the groin most people have junk just might be a different shape and you know what.
Speaker 1: if that didn't work I would have punched them in the teeth until I broke one of their teeth Such that they would then join me and fight with me.
Speaker 1: join me together How you like it when your teeth is fucking broken.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: Oh Each limitation fears the key to defend the nation.
Speaker 0: There is no need for politics.
Speaker 1: seen life with unseen eyes See man see through the disguise You.