Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, November 19th, 2014.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: B and puppycat the actual series.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So the other day I uh, I tweeted saying that I had the.
Speaker 0: I had the internet Encapsulated in a video and it was possibly internet overdose.
Speaker 0: I tweeted out and the expected responses came back.
Speaker 0: a lot of my friends OD'd on that video.
Speaker 0: So I'm not gonna make it a thing of the day Cuz it's way too internet.
Speaker 0: Like if you've ever complained about me Making a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: That's just like way internet like Mouse Fan Club, for example.
Speaker 0: This goes way beyond that.
Speaker 0: so I'm gonna link to it in the forum but it's not gonna be part of the actual episode or an official thing of the Day because seriously this shit's so internet.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: I cannot express to you how internet it is.
Speaker 0: Bonus points for one in the bathroom.
Speaker 0: So his mom doesn't over here.
Speaker 1: Why have we forwarded all the way to thing of the day?
Speaker 0: This isn't a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Well, this is just my my day.
Speaker 0: This is the opening that we just talk about stuff.
Speaker 0: It's not my actual thing of the day because it's seriously it's too internet If I link to that as the thing of the day, it might break geek nights.
Speaker 0: What you can't talk about biking?
Speaker 0: It's too cold to bike.
Speaker 1: It's too cold to do anything.
Speaker 0: It's not that cold to call the pod.
Speaker 0: you you forget yourself young man.
Speaker 0: You forget what it's like to live in Rochester.
Speaker 0: It is not cold It's cold.
Speaker 1: You go to Buffalo.
Speaker 1: See what happens.
Speaker 0: It's not that cold in Buffalo right now either just snowed Actually, so funnily enough.
Speaker 0: I was at work right?
Speaker 0: I got three emails today from co-workers or people I know who just live in not America and All three of them asked me if I was okay and if I was trapped by.
Speaker 1: Understand that New York City and New York State are two different things.
Speaker 0: So yeah We're further away from Buffalo than like like.
Speaker 1: I understand that it's right back to your point is from Buffalo.
Speaker 1: I know the Quebec and Quebec City are different things and I don't live All right.
Speaker 0: What's what ask the average person?
Speaker 0: Anywhere in the US or anywhere in the world what the capital of Canada is?
Speaker 1: all of Canada.
Speaker 0: Do you know the capital of Canada?
Speaker 1: I know the capitals of various problems.
Speaker 0: You don't know the capital of Canada of all of Canada.
Speaker 1: Yes, I didn't know capital.
Speaker 1: I guess I never even thought that it had one.
Speaker 1: I just only thought about provinces.
Speaker 1: I never even considered such a thing.
Speaker 1: Okay, uh, it's not Toronto.
Speaker 0: I'm glad you know that not Quebec.
Speaker 0: I'm almost more disturbed.
Speaker 0: if you had just said it's not Toronto I would have assumed you knew and let it go.
Speaker 0: But the fact that you admitted that you didn't know Canada had a cat I don't.
Speaker 1: I didn't even consider that it would have one.
Speaker 0: So yeah Anyway, guys Buffalo is so far away from New York City that it is effectively a different state and it's arguably Canada.
Speaker 0: It's like a shabbier version of Canada.
Speaker 0: So also Scott, it's only 31 degrees.
Speaker 0: It's not that cold with the wind.
Speaker 0: Wind chill is bullshit unless you're naked.
Speaker 0: Are you naked outside?
Speaker 0: Oh Scott.
Speaker 0: All right fine wind chill.
Speaker 0: You're gonna say wind chills.
Speaker 0: the problem.
Speaker 0: the wind chill only makes it 26.
Speaker 1: I also don't have hair.
Speaker 0: So that tiny amount of lost hair turned you from a man capable of walking outside in Rochester.
Speaker 1: Listen, I'm still capable.
Speaker 1: It's just not desirable.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you are.
Speaker 0: I think if we went to Rochester right now You might just die.
Speaker 0: Oh Oh No death.
Speaker 0: It's not cold out and you're a baby now.
Speaker 0: so anyway Wednesday Animation and all that you got news and Scott.
Speaker 0: It's only 23 in Rochester.
Speaker 0: So there's a list That can't you know.
Speaker 1: anime news network for a long time.
Speaker 1: I might have just been you know in dark.
Speaker 0: I probably was just in the dark As you know put up lists of like animation DVD rankings like oh I used to Look every time I go to anime news network thinking oh I need some news for like a Wednesday show.
Speaker 0: I see those lists I click on them and then I realize I have literally nothing to say about the DVD rankings.
Speaker 1: And then I don't talk about right, but I don't know if they've been doing this for a while, but they did TV rankings Which I'd never saw them do before which is really kind of interesting at least to me.
Speaker 0: So the way this is Japanese TV, right?
Speaker 1: So this is the animations that are most watched on Japanese television and it's like oh Alright as of when as of like as of like November 3rd through 9th, it's like last week.
Speaker 0: Ah see It's always tricky with lists like that because the things that like an uninformed person or an American anime fan might think are popular Are one not on Japanese TV right now?
Speaker 0: and two often not.
Speaker 0: what's popular in Japan?
Speaker 0: Did Naruto end yet?
Speaker 1: I assume it did.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Uh, so if I had to guess number one You're safe, it's got to be like size.
Speaker 0: I saw it or what it is.
Speaker 0: What's number two like door?
Speaker 0: I'm on those door All right number three.
Speaker 0: I can't think of any more shows like that.
Speaker 0: One piece.
Speaker 1: This is farther down.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: What about that?
Speaker 0: I just got us to be on TV that that show where the guy eats exotic animal Toriko.
Speaker 1: I don't know what that is and it's not on the list.
Speaker 0: Okay one you've never seen Toriko.
Speaker 0: that shits Delicious.
Speaker 0: Okay and terrible.
Speaker 0: Okay, I guess it's not an unlit.
Speaker 1: All right, so saw that sound Doraemon Let's chibi Maruko Chan is the next one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway This is really interesting to see.
Speaker 1: that like.
Speaker 1: oh all these animes that are the ones that people in America watch Like say y'all pedal and all, you know, basically no one in Japan is watching those things.
Speaker 1: He's not on TV.
Speaker 1: It's like a nerd only deal.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean look at old anime ask an average person in Japan Just like some kid like hey, what's cowboy bebop?
Speaker 0: They might not know.
Speaker 0: like not everyone cares about.
Speaker 0: that show wasn't like super remembered by everybody.
Speaker 0: Everybody knows what fist of the North Star is.
Speaker 1: I Guess that's true.
Speaker 0: Yeah Of course.
Speaker 0: then again even in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Like ask the average kid what Star Wars is and a lot of them have not actually seen any Star Wars, but I digress Mmm, that is sad indeed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I've actually for whatever reason it's been animation season for me Like I've been playing you've been doing your thing But I've been mostly watching cartoons and playing video like PC games lately.
Speaker 0: All right Yeah, so I'm gonna geek bite all the cartoons I'm watching right now because Scott's not watching any of them and of course.
Speaker 0: So, of course, it's a little skewed because this is like the off season.
Speaker 0: It's like b-team because there's no new my little pony.
Speaker 0: There's no new venture brothers.
Speaker 0: The adventure time just like stopped and we're waiting for it to start again.
Speaker 0: So There's no archers.
Speaker 0: all my standbys aren't growing.
Speaker 0: So I'm watching like my b-tier shows Mmm, so there's that my little pony like Gajinka show like the rainbow rocks Equestria girl that stuff.
Speaker 1: Well, you're watching it.
Speaker 0: No, so the first movie that they released I watched because I had to you know be able to say it was shit.
Speaker 0: You know, you got to try something before you can say it's shit and I tried it and it was pretty shit.
Speaker 0: Okay so they made a sequel and apparently they hadn't originally planned on making a sequel and as far as I can tell they're turning that Into a like full-on Continuing thing.
Speaker 0: It looks like they're taking all the all the stuff they would do with gem if gem was re-released and just making that like a Sub brand with all the same proper new nouns as my little pony but way lower production values.
Speaker 0: What's interesting is that because they're kind of going in this gem direction I watched a few bits from it and it's awful like it.
Speaker 0: It's awful.
Speaker 0: Like you get his own watchable baby stuff But it's actually popular among the demographic that the new my little pony friendship is magic was actually Originally targeted at.
Speaker 0: this shit is way popular among young girls.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: It's a perfectly fine little girl show like nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 0: But seriously, you're a fan of like actual my little pony and you watch this stuff.
Speaker 0: This stuff is really bad and you shouldn't be watching it.
Speaker 0: But the really interesting thing is that they have quadrupled down on the music and they seem to have made this franchise Completely about the music and about music.
Speaker 0: There are 12 songs in this short movie.
Speaker 1: Whoa.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like any Disney movie that's as many songs as what is rainbow rocks, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the previous one also had a lot of music.
Speaker 0: this one like quadrupled down on it.
Speaker 0: music music music.
Speaker 0: And it's interesting because it's the same guy Daniel Ingram doing this music.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm The music for this is way more generic and like lame poppy like way way way more generic.
Speaker 0: But the production values of the music in this one are way way higher than from the previous one.
Speaker 0: So I suspect I guess that among the like wider fandom of this stuff They're gonna be people who are fans of friendship is magic and you independently are fans of the music from this.
Speaker 0: But we'll never actually watch this or if they do they won't admit to watching it, but seriously shits way unwatchable.
Speaker 0: It's got.
Speaker 0: I don't know it's don't watch it I Won't.
Speaker 1: yeah, I wasn't planning on it.
Speaker 1: I still didn't watch that equestria girls movie either.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I watched that one.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Not great.
Speaker 0: Not great at all.
Speaker 0: However, one of the songs from the new one.
Speaker 0: I'm actually making a new tenant anime music video - Alright, yeah, I'm doing that that I have in all my life as an anime fan.
Speaker 0: I've never actually made an anime music video and I feel like it's time like that.
Speaker 0: Bell never rings.
Speaker 0: I never.
Speaker 1: I mean we keep saying that but it's like you ever seen a clock that rings?
Speaker 1: it doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like grandfather clocks cuckoo clocks That's that's what they do.
Speaker 0: Clocks used to make noises, you know, you know when it's like noon 15 and the clocks like doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you've never encountered a real old clock.
Speaker 0: You know, that's that sound like doo doo doo doo Doo doo doo, but that clock never rings.
Speaker 0: So That clock used to ring and then it stopped.
Speaker 0: so I've also been watching Steven Universe.
Speaker 0: that show.
Speaker 0: if you've been avoiding it or ignoring it or not, like paying attention to it is Way good like way good it.
Speaker 0: on one hand does this sort of like deconstruction of magical girls like very heavily Sailor Moon inspired but also Comedy show like, you know, the premise is that there's magical girls the gems, you know Sailor Moon magic.
Speaker 0: But they live openly as magical girls.
Speaker 0: Like everyone's like that's the magical girls They live in that house and they protect the planet from all the bullshit.
Speaker 0: one of them basically dies giving birth to her son and He inherits her gem.
Speaker 0: So it's a bunch of magical girls from space and this kid named Steven who's like 12 years old Who also has one of the gems and it's technically a magical girl And it's actually like.
Speaker 0: it's like it's way funny like way funny.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know I saw some episodes of it early.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you know what early episodes it's gotten better, you know, like Adventure Time like it was really good But then it like like the goodness got better at an accelerating rate after a certain point.
Speaker 0: Steven Universe did that too.
Speaker 0: Like it got like every like the episode started getting like Exponentially funnier and then much like Adventure Time plot happens.
Speaker 0: So it's got serious Dramatic like for real stuff and it kind of does.
Speaker 0: it doesn't do the full big O But it does a little bit of big O because stuff happens and all the early episodes That's just kind of funny.
Speaker 0: and you know magical girl monster of the week.
Speaker 0: But then the show kind of goes in this direction of.
Speaker 0: so look back at all those monsters of the week.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you feel really bad about that now, don't you huh?
Speaker 1: How many times has that happened?
Speaker 1: about a zillion?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know what that's often the sign of good media.
Speaker 1: Steven Universe is super worth watching if you haven't watched it yet And I had so many other things to watch is not high on the list even saying it's not good.
Speaker 0: What are you watching other than Yoah pedal?
Speaker 1: Not much because I'm trying to watch anything.
Speaker 0: So I'm also watching The Amazing World of Gumball.
Speaker 0: I've talked about The Amazing World of Gumball before on the show But suffice it to say it did everything that Steven Universe did in terms of.
Speaker 0: with every season It's getting funnier and funny like to the point that it is one of my favorite comedy cartoons.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess there's a new mushishi anime.
Speaker 1: I would watch that if I was gonna watch anything else that I wasn't already watching, you know I would watch that except I'm currently watching two Sailor Moons at the same time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I haven't watched a Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: I you know since like a long time ago I can tell you why.
Speaker 0: that is because Sailor Moon's at R. now You know what R is just filler before S. R is like watching.
Speaker 1: I'm still back in the like the The one where Sailor Moon's non-sailor friend when was getting with the bad guy That I'm still in that area.
Speaker 0: Well, you don't even remember any of their names.
Speaker 1: Do you something fright?
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: No, no What's the girl's name?
Speaker 1: Red hair girl.
Speaker 0: What's Sailor Moon's name?
Speaker 1: Usagi.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: What's Sailor Mercury's name?
Speaker 1: Yeah, temple girl.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, no, you already mixed him up.
Speaker 0: That's Sailor Mars Mercury's the blue one with her bubble mist.
Speaker 1: Yeah bubble mist.
Speaker 0: There's this great moment in a recent episode of crystal.
Speaker 0: Well, not a reason but the episode of crystal where Sailor Moon's like I can't do shit.
Speaker 0: All the other sailors guys got awesome powers like fire lightning and the cats like this is what your other power is?
Speaker 0: Yeah, she's.
Speaker 0: no she's like fire lightning and mist.
Speaker 0: if I were making if I were in charge of that show the person she was talking to would have been like yeah two of those Are cool.
Speaker 0: two of those are useful Yeah, but gumball also wallet is primarily Really fucked up and kind of dark comedy like.
Speaker 0: I'm actually really surprised at how dark this show is considering that it's like On Cartoon Network and is actually aimed at little kids.
Speaker 0: It's like take it's like Malcolm time is on Cartoon Network.
Speaker 0: The humor in adventure times.
Speaker 0: more of this is too real for little kids, right?
Speaker 0: but gumball is actually just too dark for little kids.
Speaker 0: like Messed up shit happens and not in the like.
Speaker 0: it's a very different kind of messed up shit from adventure times Like all kid shows like that nowadays all the good ones.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: It's always been that way.
Speaker 1: We watched Ren and Stimpy when we were kids.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, right and Stimpy was not actually aimed at little kids on purpose.
Speaker 0: I don't think It's always been.
Speaker 0: also Ren and Stimpy was held out as an exception back then.
Speaker 0: I mean Looney Tunes bringing people blow up Yeah, but everything was like that back then.
Speaker 1: What about put guns each other's faces?
Speaker 0: But what about the He-Man She-Ra era of the maximum sanitization?
Speaker 1: even today shows that exist only to sell toys They're still like that But there aren't that many anymore cuz there aren't any setting weren't cartoons?
Speaker 0: But gumball has also had a bunch of like really serious and touching episodes recently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so He-Man There's a very special He-Man.
Speaker 1: I'm sure we can go and find it.
Speaker 0: There is not serious touching in He-Man at any point.
Speaker 0: So Yeah, I'm watching a ton of cartoons, but the only anime I'm watching is two flavors of Sailor Moon one of which I've already seen Mm-hmm, which is interesting to me that I'm watching for the first time in my life since I Was in high school.
Speaker 0: No, cuz high school.
Speaker 0: I was watching all anime.
Speaker 0: I wasn't watching any American cartoons.
Speaker 1: I thought you meant.
Speaker 1: why is it Sailor Moon?
Speaker 0: I'm watching more Non Japanese cartoons than Japanese cartoons on a daily basis.
Speaker 0: That's a big flip from the majority of my life.
Speaker 0: I mean, I was watching anime like all the time when I was in elementary school.
Speaker 1: New animes come out slower than they are exist to watch them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a ton new anime and I spending on where you put your bar.
Speaker 0: I don't care about a lot of it and whenever there's an anime I care about it's like I've decided I'll never watch an anime.
Speaker 0: I'm so I'm not super into because there's some anime that I like.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: I like you a pedal But I'm not like oh fuck.
Speaker 0: I gotta watch the next episode.
Speaker 1: Oh fuck.
Speaker 0: I gotta watch next Yeah, but then like when Monica came out, like I watch that whole thing literally as fast as I could Let's just watch it again.
Speaker 0: I can watch it again tonight.
Speaker 1: No, it's like evangelical tonight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cowboy bebop Only got so much time.
Speaker 1: forget it work.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So yeah, that's what I'm watching.
Speaker 0: So Things of the day.
Speaker 0: If you are a person who sings there's like, you know in every hobby there's like the ridiculous bullshit that like people who are really good at that thing from a hobbyist perspective will do like the weird trick that Like a skier guy will do or like the guy who knows how to throw the baseball like swing the baseball bat But he like let's go of it and has a spin in the air and then catches it again.
Speaker 0: like those kinds of tricks.
Speaker 0: this is yeah, but but but things that require a Surprising and or extreme amount of skill and talent but which are not actually useful in the professional practice of that craft.
Speaker 0: So for most singers polyphonic overtones are that they're crazy hard to do.
Speaker 0: They're really interesting.
Speaker 0: Almost no music in the world requires it.
Speaker 1: Also, I never knew about this before like a minute ago It sounds 100% like a theremin.
Speaker 1: So there's no reason to do it.
Speaker 1: if you have a theremin It's like if you have a theremin.
Speaker 1: There is no reason to have this technique for musical purpose because and even if you wanted to make music with this sound You don't need to hire a person who can do it.
Speaker 1: You just buy a third Scott.
Speaker 0: There are kinds of music that you guys that so her singing in the way It sounds was just because of what she was singing.
Speaker 0: Mongolian music also uses it but it sounds more like deep farts.
Speaker 1: Couldn't I just tune my fucking theremin?
Speaker 0: No, actually It'll be sure.
Speaker 1: I could take my theremin run it through a computer and be all set.
Speaker 0: You could not make your theremin sound like Tuva music.
Speaker 1: I could make get a didgeridoo.
Speaker 1: That's pretty close.
Speaker 0: Uh Could you play a didgeridoo?
Speaker 0: I I would give.
Speaker 0: I will give you $500 if you ever successfully play a didgeridoo in front of me.
Speaker 1: Go buy me that a tiny cheap didgeridoo.
Speaker 0: You gotta buy one.
Speaker 1: If it cost me a lot of money you have not profiting.
Speaker 1: if you ever in the rest of the time that you and I are both alive Successfully and probably lives on his last 500 bucks in the retirement home and then I'll just pray I have nothing better to do I'll practice didgeridoo all day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then my last words will be Jefferson lives.
Speaker 1: And then my last words be So.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is a video that actually explains in pretty deep detail What that is and how it works like for real and it's fascinating if you are a singer or an audio engineer.
Speaker 1: It is fascinating and completely useless.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the most difficult yet useless talent I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: so Scott I also practice clicking on heads in video games.
Speaker 1: That is much less difficult than this.
Speaker 1: Otherwise equally useless.
Speaker 1: our actually not as useless because you can win a competition and mad moneys if you are very good at it.
Speaker 0: I'll bet there's competitions for polyphonic overtone singing.
Speaker 1: I bet they make you less money if you win.
Speaker 0: then the counter-strike I could do it with humming and whistling at the same time.
Speaker 1: We've done this on the show before.
Speaker 0: I can also do the for the fifth flip.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah But I can't do polyphonic whistling.
Speaker 0: no no Anyway, you got a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: So in Russia crazy shit happens like dash cams and produces many great things of the day.
Speaker 1: It's a great place to watch on YouTube and not a great place to go.
Speaker 1: So let us watch Russia on YouTube.
Speaker 1: here is a crazy thing that happens the dudes chilling out and what looks to be like a nice restaurant and Something strange is going on.
Speaker 1: There's like a lady with two dudes moving about.
Speaker 1: you can't tell what's going on.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: There's no audio.
Speaker 1: Not that we would understand the Pockner ease anyway.
Speaker 1: And then a whole bunch of dudes come in with a little bit of the ultra violence.
Speaker 0: Oh, I saw that sparkling to that thing.
Speaker 0: Let me see if I can find the headline they used.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then You know something happened.
Speaker 1: I guess this continues my trend of thing of the days of badass dudes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, watch and see how badass this dude is.
Speaker 1: I would probably be doing a similar thing to that, dude.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what is like to think I would be any.
Speaker 0: it's like those videos you see.
Speaker 0: occasionally We're like someone pulls out a gun at a bank and like tries to rob the teller and teller just like looks at them.
Speaker 0: They're like put that away.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, or they just like don't react.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Like no, sir.
Speaker 0: I really need to see.
Speaker 0: right behind a bulletproof glass There was a nut.
Speaker 0: so there's this high road you.
Speaker 0: there was a similar story on FARC recently along these lines like a similar thing happened and there was a picture of the two perpetrators and It was from an upward angle and one of them was really fat.
Speaker 0: The first post in the thread was a was a meme of tyro.
Speaker 0: It was beautiful.
Speaker 0: It's epic In the moment the book club book is water ship down.
Speaker 0: It's about rabbits and crazy cultist rabbits and Fascist rabbits and it's a pretty good book and I'm really digging it.
Speaker 1: the animal farmer rabbits.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except an animal farm.
Speaker 0: They're a rabbit farm.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, there is a rabbit farm perhaps less Orwellian though Literally less Orwellian In that sense, yes Watch all our stuff on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Also, you know, I say we're on all the place on the internet.
Speaker 1: Well, whenever I find a new place on the internet to be I go there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what is that thing?
Speaker 1: So here's the thing.
Speaker 0: face retweeted it, but I don't know what it is.
Speaker 1: So Facebook made an app That's currently only for iOS, but I'm sure will eventually be for other OS.
Speaker 1: It's called rooms and the way it works is you can make.
Speaker 1: you can make an account with no Facebook account.
Speaker 1: You don't need to have a Facebook account for you anti Facebook folks and way works.
Speaker 1: You make a room and a room is sort of like an IRC channel kind of.
Speaker 1: it's like a channel and you can invite people to the room and if you created the room you set the rules for the room and whatnot.
Speaker 1: and You invite people to the room and they join the room with a barcode or by typing stuff in or whatever.
Speaker 1: They join the room Once you're in the room.
Speaker 1: Imagine an IRC chat except instead of being an IRC chat It's more like an Instagram feed where you can post photo or text or both as each post is like a square.
Speaker 0: Wait, so is this just Google Wave?
Speaker 1: No, you're not editing things.
Speaker 0: Okay, so we're just sharing things, right?
Speaker 1: It's it's.
Speaker 1: imagine if there's an IRC chat room But instead of lines of text and each post each post was a square that could contain text or a photo like Instagram And you can just make as many of these as you want and have people join them.
Speaker 1: They can be moderated or free or you know, you whoever made it controls it, right?
Speaker 1: So It's pretty interesting.
Speaker 1: So I made a geek nights one and I put stuff in it Even though like the five people who are in it aren't paying attention probably deleted the app already that but you know I'm just gonna stick with it cuz the only way to make it work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sticking with every single Internet outlet that we have full-on.
Speaker 0: Yep In fact, I mean our IRC has actually been slightly rocking lately.
Speaker 1: I got an IRC client for my phone if you.
Speaker 1: so if you have iOS and you're wondering which I which IRC client should I get on my phone?
Speaker 1: There's one that costs money called palaver.
Speaker 1: That is the best one.
Speaker 1: pay money for it If you want to use IRC on your mobile iOS devices.
Speaker 1: duly noted if you're not using iOS, I can't help you.
Speaker 0: So long ago, there was the BN puppycat two episode Thing the pilot the cute thing that Surprisingly many of our friends every time they people came over were like blah blah blah BN puppycat.
Speaker 0: They didn't know what it was.
Speaker 0: Then we showed it to him.
Speaker 1: Well, you know that people aren't necessarily subscribed to channel Frederator slash cartoon hangover on YouTube not watching everything.
Speaker 1: They put out a lot of pilots for different things on there.
Speaker 1: Yeah single episodes of various animation good some man Yeah, but you know the BN puppycat one was particularly Interesting because it was had some hints of adventure time had some good voice acting and quality dialogues.
Speaker 1: The puppycat has a vocaloid voice which gave it props.
Speaker 0: Don't tell me what to do.
Speaker 1: Right, you know it was generally pretty interesting.
Speaker 1: So that one got a Kickstarter to make for real episodes like bravest warriors has yep.
Speaker 1: So this was like one of the first like really solid Examples of a new way to make media make a bunch of free one shots and when people figure out which ones a hit and Then make it for reals.
Speaker 0: But again the crowdsourcing of people paid just so that the thing would exist and once enough money Existed for the thing to exist then everyone gets it.
Speaker 0: You don't even have to worry about piracy.
Speaker 0: No
Speaker 1: It's a hundred percent 100% free because we paid for it to be made and the people who made it took some of that money to live with and they use the other money for Computers and whatnot that they needed to make it software's and that and they did it.
Speaker 0: So I got to see the first three episodes at a like it.
Speaker 1: Well, I've only seen two episodes.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, what's that third episode?
Speaker 1: you saw beach episode?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's So being puppycat that what's out now like there's gonna be a bunch of episodes.
Speaker 0: and Now that Scott's seen it too, and you've all seen it We can actually kind of review.
Speaker 1: I only saw the pilot and two episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz that's what they put out to start.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you've seen two episodes of the actual, you know season.
Speaker 0: I got the real scene three.
Speaker 1: I thought the characters names except for B and puppy.
Speaker 0: Yeah Deckard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's him.
Speaker 0: How could you forget Deckard?
Speaker 1: I just know that he's dude.
Speaker 1: He's the dude.
Speaker 1: I don't remember his name.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one else No one else's names.
Speaker 0: I think matter.
Speaker 1: What's the intelligent girl's name?
Speaker 0: Oh the sister?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I already forgot her name.
Speaker 1: She might be the best actual character though other than yes, that's the kind of character I like sane person with no drama or any fucked-up problem.
Speaker 0: Well also known as the straight man.
Speaker 0: Yes However, I also human being.
Speaker 0: I also like the.
Speaker 0: well, she is the furlough that guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well that guy is my kind of money a lot of bad guy.
Speaker 1: Puppycat is also sort of the straight man in a way the straight the straight animal.
Speaker 1: So it's a lot like the cat from Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: the newbie and puppy cat is Substantially different from the pilot as all shows are from the pilot.
Speaker 0: Yes, and you know what?
Speaker 0: I think it's a change for the better.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean if it was all like the pilot it would just be too much Right, like it'd be like full power all the time with crazy stuff like, you know Candy's gone.
Speaker 0: Yeah Right.
Speaker 1: So that's a great line.
Speaker 1: never gonna lose that one.
Speaker 0: But if the whole thing was like that it just become tiresome, you know coming on too strong Yep, so the newbie and puppy got basically back like it zoomed out a little bit so you see more of the world and Has like actual character.
Speaker 0: and besides just stop.
Speaker 1: Yes that way cuz I mean how far could you get with just be in puppy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it gives you there is a point of reference as opposed to literally no point of reference.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I Really like it actually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I'm gonna watch all the episodes that come out.
Speaker 0: I'm glad that the primary thing they kept is these like personality as Experience through the voice acting right.
Speaker 1: but then they sort of you know, it's not just who is this crazy person.
Speaker 1: It's like oh this part, you know, this person is actually crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and The friends are concerned about that and it's a problem.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: This is I think B is what will happen to Nana.
Speaker 0: remember Nana if she doesn't get her shit together Eventually, she's gonna be like this.
Speaker 1: Well, I think you know you look at some like adventure time, right and you have Finn and to a lesser extent Jake being sort Of immature crazily but also mature at the same time like they take care of themselves in their house You know, they can.
Speaker 1: they can get shit done when they have to.
Speaker 1: Yep It's like they can alternate between you know, having wacky dialogues and being seemingly, you know, complete children going But also just being adults and taking care of their shit Both things going on at the same time moving
Speaker 0: more forward toward adults as the show gets more and more adult and serious,
Speaker 1: obviously Yeah, but B on the other hand right seems to Less adult like there's some amount of adultness there and ability to realize to do something and do something.
Speaker 0: B is the kind of person who as a child ate that marshmallow immediately, right?
Speaker 1: But mostly it's like okay your incredible silliness being a cartoon character is actually a problem in this adult world.
Speaker 1: It's not so good and We're gonna have to fix that over the course of these episodes to some extent or maybe not and that's gonna be what this is.
Speaker 0: Yeah But I like that.
Speaker 0: I like how they made.
Speaker 0: they took her core essence and it's like it's like it.
Speaker 0: You know in utenna there's an example because we've been doing a lot of stuff with utenna lately Crazy anime crap happens in that show, but then the show stops.
Speaker 0: He was like yo dawg.
Speaker 0: all that crazy crap happened.
Speaker 0: Why did you just accept that that crazy crap was happening just because it was a cartoon?
Speaker 0: Yeah But then like he man like crazy cartoon craft happened just because crazy cartoon crap happened.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's a cartoon that literally never the fact that backgrounds were repeating and looping was not a commentary on the existential nature of man No in he-man, but a new tenor.
Speaker 0: a looping background is like how did that background loop?
Speaker 1: I mean, it's a cartoon sure But you know if you exist.
Speaker 1: pretend that these are real people.
Speaker 1: how does their looping background?
Speaker 0: and we'll talk about the looping background When we talk about episode 39 of shoujo kakamei utenna.
Speaker 0: in our series geek knives presents shoujo kakamei utenna.
Speaker 1: You should probably watch that.
Speaker 1: we're gonna continue it sometime soon.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Not like now that I got those bure's.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can see the Individual defects of brush lines on the cells if you zoom in.
Speaker 1: well Let's talk about more bees and cats.
Speaker 1: a puppy.
Speaker 1: cat is a puppy and a cat sort of this weird in-between character Obviously created to sell merchandise.
Speaker 1: much like cat bug.
Speaker 1: yeah But I like cat bug better.
Speaker 1: cat bug actually says funny things where?
Speaker 1: Puppycat has a cool vocaloid voice which is awesome But it doesn't really because of that inability to like really talk It's so I think I think it's partly catch phrases, or you can't really impersonate it.
Speaker 1: besides going like Tell me what to do.
Speaker 0: yeah, so I think it's that with cat bug Cat bug is an earnest little kid And it's kind of like that scene where cat bug killed that jelly kid whatever spoilers And then you know he's like.
Speaker 0: I don't see what the big deal is like.
Speaker 0: like there's cool stuff going on with that kind of Like earnest child character.
Speaker 0: that's also kind of this like animal predator thing, but puppy cats actually just Acts and Doesn't look, but acts like an adult.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's an intelligent adult person.
Speaker 0: It's like I need these weapons.
Speaker 1: It just happens to be in this body, and it's trying to get the job done.
Speaker 0: Yeah Is it just me?
Speaker 0: or was there a?
Speaker 0: because Two other people said this to me, and I agree with them that in the first two episodes of the newbie and puppy cat There is a direct romantic subtext between bee and puppy cat.
Speaker 0: there's malt there two indirect kisses A tiny bit.
Speaker 0: she steals the gum back out of his mouth.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I mean it's it's sort of one of those things where it's like a You know and then in the dream with the hand yeah, yeah, that's there, so that's there.
Speaker 0: It's not just me.
Speaker 1: is yeah is puppy cat like symbolizing another person gonna literally transform into another person?
Speaker 0: Well puppy cat is obviously that Prince.
Speaker 0: Sure, yeah, right trapped in the body of a puppy cat.
Speaker 1: yep Sucks for the dude character guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well he needs to move on with his life according to the plot so far.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So the deal with that dude who wasn't in the pilot is he's sort of taking care of bee Because someone like that needs taking care of like.
Speaker 0: you get the impression that she would starve to death locked in her apartment If he wasn't like watching out for her right And he can cook and do adult things, but at the same time like he's basically neglecting his own life.
Speaker 1: You know he's awesome at cooking and should go to cooking school apparently, but instead he's taking care of this person.
Speaker 1: He's not even related to that cooking school.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure is exactly like our on high school host club.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure that's how I imagine that is also.
Speaker 1: Are you cooking Academy also?
Speaker 0: He has heterochromia, and that's definitely on purpose Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And then there's the girl who like is basically just the same person.
Speaker 1: I forget her name.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well you and she's pretty much is telling him like hey, you should go to cooking school.
Speaker 1: Don't take care of this child girl person.
Speaker 0: Yeah your whole life That's not your problem, but it's definitely this show is very much a bunch of internet mashed together on Top of a thin but workable plot thread.
Speaker 0: yeah Like you just take a bunch of strong characters dump a ton of internet around them And then I think just kind of wing it in terms of the writing from that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only thing is it's sort of so.
Speaker 1: each episode is like a you know a real-world Conflict of some kind and then B goes to fight some sci-fi solve some sci-fi problems somewhere in like this other dimension or some shit and Then that somehow symbolizes Resolving the problem that's happening in the real world.
Speaker 0: I thought of that except notice how she doesn't actually resolve really any.
Speaker 0: It's very strange, so if you take this at face value B is a mentally challenged Person with problems Who like she goes she visits this guy goes into his bathroom passes out and has a fever dream And then wakes up at night and leaves.
Speaker 0: yep She's escaping the world and not actually solving her real-world problems.
Speaker 0: Escapism is the actual problem.
Speaker 1: the thing is is that other dimension problem solving mission heroism thing?
Speaker 1: That's going on.
Speaker 1: is that literal?
Speaker 1: or is that just in her head is like or is it just gonna be internet?
Speaker 0: And that's not the part that matters.
Speaker 1: yeah, and like the puppy cat something that like is anyone even see the puppy cat besides her?
Speaker 0: Well, we know Deckard sees it okay.
Speaker 0: She holds it up, and she's like smell it, but no one hears him talking.
Speaker 0: Only she hears him talk, and he is definitely a cat with dog smell.
Speaker 0: so if we're gonna analyze this shit It could just be a cat with dog smell.
Speaker 0: that doesn't exist.
Speaker 0: There's no cat with dog smell persistent dog smell and a cat could not.
Speaker 0: a cat-shaped dog also even like he's weird-looking and and He went and got all those weapons.
Speaker 0: Let's tried to buy all those weapons because they did buy that the brass knuckles anyway.
Speaker 0: Right I mean, maybe it could be Fight Club.
Speaker 0: Do we need to do geek guys presents being puppy cat?
Speaker 1: Is it be clever fight cat?
Speaker 0: I feel like we could actually do that for this show.
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: I would watch a show called fight cat.
Speaker 1: Let's make it a Cat and then And it fights for serious like doo-doo-doo.
Speaker 1: You know those sort of like.
Speaker 1: you know it'll be like cute cat like you know with boxing gloves like Right and then you get that zoom in on the face you get the fist of the North Star kind of face like That's a cat face, and then the opponent is like a dog.
Speaker 1: It's like And then you know.
Speaker 1: So just take a hajimana info script and just reanimate it with animals.
Speaker 0: so in the third episode Not to spoil anything, but there's there's another character that whoa.
Speaker 0: It's one of those characters.
Speaker 0: I don't care tell me everything a character that does not fit in the world in the same way that Detective Conan being in an anime.
Speaker 0: That's not.
Speaker 0: detective Conan as a cameo is always really weird.
Speaker 0: So just like princess bubblegum basically her landlord is a an actual child Like this little kid all right, and there's not just a small person.
Speaker 0: It's definitely a child.
Speaker 1: But is it just landlords child?
Speaker 0: That is.
Speaker 0: that is not the implication.
Speaker 1: is it like a child king of like a weird tiny country?
Speaker 0: now It is possible still that B is just crazy, and that's just a neighbor kid, and she thinks he's the landlord.
Speaker 0: So I guess I could still read into it that way.
Speaker 1: But how does she ever pay the rent?
Speaker 1: like how did she even pay the first rent?
Speaker 0: How did she even get the apartment in the first place cuz her mom's actually like dead in the other room and social security checks Just keep coming into an automated account and like the shows are gonna.
Speaker 0: Go real dark real quick.
Speaker 0: Remember when I was at that night that screening Natasha herself did a Q&A and when someone asked her What like what she does is a hobby what she's basically said?
Speaker 0: something along the lines of yeah I read that Wikipedia article on like the strangest deaths that have ever occurred in history to humans.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: and then we tie that like that became the topic conversation for a while so I would not put it past her for that to be the plot sure.
Speaker 0: but Notice how the.
Speaker 0: the show is very atmospheric in that music and background noise like it'll have a very slow Fuzzy dreamlike atmosphere all the time.
Speaker 0: It's more atmospheric than it.
Speaker 1: the other dimension is the real thing.
Speaker 1: This is the dream that looks like our real world.
Speaker 1: Actually, well you know she woke up in that bathroom.
Speaker 0: she didn't go to sleep in it because she moved from an apartment to a house like a part like the bit like the Setting change between the pilot and the real show.
Speaker 0: you can argue that the dream the the fighting monsters temp job world is more consistent than the quote-unquote real world.
Speaker 1: is the pilot even canon?
Speaker 0: I Will.
Speaker 0: I'm going to tweet at her and ask her if the pilot is canon tonight.
Speaker 0: Well see because I asked.
Speaker 0: I you know I got the official answer that the My Little Pony comic is canon.
Speaker 0: sure From the author of the comic like that's.
Speaker 0: that shit's legit as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 0: but the third episode is way atmospheric.
Speaker 0: When they go to the beach the beach the beach There's also a crabby guy you're gonna like I can imagine puppycat in some sort of like floating device the crab in the water.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think you're gonna like the crabby guys.
Speaker 1: aesthetic I mean you already have a beach and a crabby.
Speaker 1: that doesn't really.
Speaker 1: you know you're already hitting on all cylinders.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I guess when you watch the episode they eat crab.
Speaker 0: how they get to the beach You didn't answer me if they ate crab I had to.
Speaker 0: So how they get to the beach actually reinforces your possible idea that the real world of being puppycat is the dream.
Speaker 1: they use the dimension thingy They go to sleep, and they wake up as the beach.
Speaker 0: They wander there by accident.
Speaker 0: All right, you'll see it's it's it'll be out soon.
Speaker 0: I assume.
Speaker 0: I mean it's done, so Hmm yeah being puppycat shows like this like short pilots of animation and short kickstarter-y shows If you care about this stuff at all like any animation or TV the investment you have to put in to consume this media.
Speaker 1: Go to YouTube click on a thing and sit there for like five.
Speaker 1: ten minutes is so low.
Speaker 0: Da mecha dobutsu requires more investment than this show.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, it has all these long openers and closes and down with.
Speaker 1: you have to see it to fast-forward through The code of the RIT anime club.
Speaker 0: you never fast-forward through shit.
Speaker 0: We watch the opener and the closer to risky safety end times and being the number of episodes.
Speaker 1: If you haven't seen risky safety and especially if you haven't seen Tomokodobutsu you should watch Tomokodobutsu.
Speaker 0: Should we bring that panel back for anime Boston?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got any other better ideas.
Speaker 0: Let's do it.
Speaker 0: So you guys the anime Boston.
Speaker 0: by the way there are some new ones.
Speaker 0: anime Boston submission panel stuff is open.
Speaker 0: so yeah Packs out.
Speaker 1: that keeps extending.
Speaker 0: It's the new deadline for pack south unless they change it again is today.
Speaker 0: So you want to submit a panel to pack south?
Speaker 0: It looks like they need more panels.
Speaker 0: emissions sparse schedule, maybe We'll see if we go back to the old days because we used to do at PAX East.
Speaker 0: one time we did three so I did three at PAX Australia.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night Oh.