Speaker 1: It's Wednesday March 26th 2014 I'm rim it's really cold And this is geek nights tonight warm today, and we're talking about yamishibai Gary urban legend Japanese horror story anime on crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: Not yamishibai, I don't think it's ie I think it's yamishibai yamishibai Yamishibai no jikanda yo.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So yeah, we're back from anime, Boston.
Speaker 1: there was a time in an ancient past where we would review every convention we went to but an Average packs is not significantly different enough from the previous packs to say anything at length about it.
Speaker 0: There's not a full episodes worth of things to say that we haven't already said multiple times in the past.
Speaker 0: So you can just go listen to an old episode of any particular convention And you won't have to worry about there not being a new one.
Speaker 1: yep like but this pet this anime, Boston.
Speaker 1: You know good.
Speaker 1: anime, Boston.
Speaker 1: few things were different.
Speaker 1: few things were noteworthy.
Speaker 1: So as my news talk a little bit about what happened there, so we did our four panels.
Speaker 1: They went great.
Speaker 1: Interestingly the one that got the biggest line was the not all anime or what they seem Like.
Speaker 1: scarily people lined up way in advance for that and they turned a bunch of people away Q of people hanging out outside Trying to get in if anyone walked out.
Speaker 1: It's like why really that's the one they picked.
Speaker 1: But the funny thing was unlike our other panels where half the audience is like already knew who we were and they were there just Because of us.
Speaker 1: the people in this panel mostly didn't know who we were.
Speaker 1: so the power of choosing a provocative title Once again is proven.
Speaker 1: if you want to get people to come to your panel Think was gonna be at that panel that they wanted in so badly not all animator what they seem.
Speaker 1: Maybe they thought we're gonna talk about anime that look like one thing, but really there's something else Which is kind of what we did.
Speaker 1: kind wasn't much of a bait-and-switch?
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 0: So yeah this anime Boston notable differences from previous anime, Boston's.
Speaker 0: first of all the jam project was the Musical guest.
Speaker 0: right yeah, they did like two concerts on Friday night.
Speaker 0: They did like all jam project together, and then on Saturday.
Speaker 0: They did like individual whatever's which is that's new.
Speaker 0: It's like they did so much concert compared to other musical guests that have appeared in your actions, but We didn't go.
Speaker 1: yeah the thing is we thought oh We won't be able to go because we didn't arrive until Friday morning.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we wouldn't be able to get the wristbands, but it was kind of sad that there were staff going around Desperately trying to get people to take the wristbands or whatever to go to the concert.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was a surprise.
Speaker 0: usually you know when you have that kind of wristband situation It's like people will line up like crazy, but I guess they didn't need to.
Speaker 0: you know I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know why they did that.
Speaker 0: It's like they never really had a problem in recent years.
Speaker 1: Because for example here's two scenarios you have a good system to deal with a huge crowd and a huge crowd doesn't show up.
Speaker 1: No problem you have a huge system and a huge crowd shows up.
Speaker 1: No problem a huge crowd shows up, and you don't have a good system.
Speaker 1: disaster.
Speaker 0: It wasn't a disaster preview.
Speaker 0: I mean they just lined up and went in the room.
Speaker 0: You know I've never seen the concert for anime Boston Phil.
Speaker 1: Oh near capacity, so Well that that space is actually pretty big.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying I do.
Speaker 1: I wish somehow that that space existed inside of the BCE.
Speaker 0: see I wish they would remove the seats from that space.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when Pax removed the seats that space held off fuck metric ton of people.
Speaker 0: right then you wouldn't need to do any sort of Ridiculous you would.
Speaker 1: you couldn't possibly have a crowd big enough, but basically every year anime Boston since the bombings Has had ridiculous security yeah, and it's gotten to the point that it actually Significantly affected our ability to enjoy the con and our ability to record our panels.
Speaker 1: So Friday we literally almost missed running our first panel because getting through security was such a hassle.
Speaker 0: Well, and the bus was a little bit late.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the bus was a little late, but mostly the bus was late enough But there was a little bit of traffic But that would have been fine.
Speaker 0: the bus also decided to stop at a Wendy's for no reason yeah.
Speaker 0: So bolt bus I have to write an email to bolt bus.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna say listen There is no reason for pretty much any of the trips between New York and Boston in New York DC or New York To ever stop anywhere ever.
Speaker 0: it was telling those trips in one shot.
Speaker 0: The bus was right through him on the bus.
Speaker 1: the bus was running about 15 minutes late And they stopped at that Wendy's for like 15 minutes, huh?
Speaker 1: And then of course like three people get back on the bus reeking of cigarette smoke so that made it just all the more enjoyable right, and then you know they Yeah, yep, yeah, yep, but the security was bad for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: one It wasn't just like last year where they kind of glanced at my bag and walked me through.
Speaker 1: They sat there and made me open every individual zipper inside and outside of my bag And they rifled around every pocket.
Speaker 1: it took almost some minutes at one point.
Speaker 0: It was so inconsistent.
Speaker 0: sometimes They just feel like they'd look and they make I go and sometimes They'd be like hmm I'm gonna pretend to look like I'm looking through everything and then not actually really look through everything.
Speaker 0: So it's it's fake security.
Speaker 0: and then of course at like one entrance like the one that goes to the street They've got like metal detecting wands.
Speaker 1: Yeah They did metal detector pat-downs of every single person who walked in through entrance a but not through any other entrance ever.
Speaker 1: and when I when I asked the people there.
Speaker 1: I asked the security people I think I even got a video of this on my glass cuz I actually recorded video of a lot of the security.
Speaker 1: Do you guys realize that they're not doing this to any of the other?
Speaker 1: Entrances.
Speaker 1: and they looked at me, and they looked at each other and they actually look kind of shocked right But nothing changed.
Speaker 1: no also those people I want to point out they rifled through my bag for multiple minutes And they gave me the metal detector pat-down.
Speaker 1: the metal detector went off like four times on me And they did not investigate that at any point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in fact it went off on.
Speaker 1: what I had in my back pocket was a huge lithium-ion battery.
Speaker 0: I don't think they care if you have a battery But they didn't look to see what it was.
Speaker 1: they basically they took the metal detector.
Speaker 1: They waved it around me it went off on a bunch of spots, and they ignored it mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so Like I said on Twitter if you're gonna have security theater at least put some shit backstage guys.
Speaker 0: What was the?
Speaker 0: what was the joke right?
Speaker 0: What was the well?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was very proud of this joke.
Speaker 1: what?
Speaker 1: which theater had?
Speaker 1: the longest lines that anime Boston this year?
Speaker 0: the security theater?
Speaker 1: oh So that was bad, but it was manageable.
Speaker 1: But as a result once we left the convention center like to get dinner We really didn't want to go back into the con.
Speaker 1: so we almost right.
Speaker 0: It's like a pain in the ass to go back in.
Speaker 0: so it's like once you're in you're in and once you're out you're out Whereas before I'd be like in and out and in and out So either to carry my equipment with me all day, or does not bring it so we basically stopped videoing our panels.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz we have to carry like a tripod and all this shit through the security.
Speaker 0: Yeah, huge pain in multiple bags with a lot of equipment that they're gonna rifle through now apparently right It's like well I just won't carry it in.
Speaker 0: I carried in as little as possible But then it got worse.
Speaker 1: so on Sunday the line to get in was literally you just couldn't get through it at first Like it was blocking and even go in on Sunday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly we didn't go in.
Speaker 1: so The main reason we didn't go in is because you couldn't get in.
Speaker 1: with security.
Speaker 1: They wouldn't let people with big bags in at all.
Speaker 0: is that what it was?
Speaker 0: yes And I thought they just there was a pain in the ass to check them.
Speaker 1: No, no So they wouldn't.
Speaker 1: so if you had a big luggage they basically just wouldn't let you in.
Speaker 1: and if you had a luggage that for Whatever reason they would let you in they went through it Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so people had to check their bags the hotel wouldn't let you check directly because I mean anime Boston.
Speaker 0: every year that I've been There has turned the registration room in the hotel into sort of a free bag check room for all the attendees which brilliant Which is great, but the thing is because of the security that room was much more heavily utilized than in past years.
Speaker 0: So like to even get into the con on Sunday And there isn't much con on Sunday.
Speaker 0: you had to check your bag in there And then get through the unless you're staying in another hotel or something, but even then you're probably checking out on Sunday.
Speaker 0: It's not a con where you're gonna check out Monday, so yeah It made Sunday like not worth it to go into the con on Sunday like unless you're like someone who lives in Boston walking off the street.
Speaker 1: So it was unprecedented.
Speaker 1: usually we show up at cons Thursday night.
Speaker 1: We leave like late Sunday afternoon.
Speaker 1: I don't think I'm ever gonna go to anime Boston on Sunday again like we just won't do panels on Sunday We won't.
Speaker 0: yeah It's like we showed up sort of late ish Friday like middle of the day And we didn't do anything at the con at all on Sunday.
Speaker 1: So as a result I gave my badge away to our waitress.
Speaker 0: I Thought about I was just gonna give her my badge, but you wanted to keep it for.
Speaker 0: But then she said then she actually reminded me like doesn't have sentimental value, and I'm like shit.
Speaker 0: I guess I do have every convention badge ever and that will break the streak won't it?
Speaker 1: do you have your Ohio con?
Speaker 1: 2002 badge?
Speaker 1: probably yeah, I think I do too, so this is the only badge I don't have.
Speaker 1: and I took an empty sleeve and I wrote on a piece of paper Gave badge to waitress at Trident cafe, and so I'll remember that that happens.
Speaker 0: good enough also.
Speaker 1: She knows who we are me.
Speaker 1: if she might email us and be like hey I went to the con maybe and if she does then I'll ask her to mail my badge back.
Speaker 1: I'll be like I'll give you a dollar if you mail it back to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll pay for your postage.
Speaker 0: We'll see you next year at the Trident actually will be.
Speaker 0: we can go back there during packs.
Speaker 0: Maybe I don't know.
Speaker 1: yeah We couldn't get a hotel anywhere near packs.
Speaker 0: our hotel is near the tried anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's basically the worst possible location.
Speaker 1: That's so the only other bad thing and we're trying to get the bad stuff out.
Speaker 1: first because anime Boston was still fun.
Speaker 1: Is that though?
Speaker 1: they've always had problems in the connected hotel with the elevators, but it was kind of a party.
Speaker 1: It was especially bad this year.
Speaker 0: Boston's fault necessarily is the hotel is bad elevator.
Speaker 0: so did that magfest hotel.
Speaker 0: so of a lot of hotels You know they have conventions in them.
Speaker 0: They can't handle people you know they're does?
Speaker 0: they're not designed for all these people to go up and back and forth to their rooms Constantly.
Speaker 1: so my advice to all of you.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna tell you our secrets, but actually this is an anime Boston of secrets.
Speaker 0: right we had a secret breakfast.
Speaker 0: We have always been there.
Speaker 0: we had a secret entrance to get into the con with a minimal security line.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right we had a secret way to get up and down the building That you know decides waiting for an elevator.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right That was a pretty good way.
Speaker 1: that was the only way I was able to get up and down the elevator at the disastrous Anime central.
Speaker 1: what 2003 right 2003 or 2004 that anime central.
Speaker 0: good God There are just so many secrets at this anime Boston.
Speaker 0: It was the convention of secrets.
Speaker 1: It was also the secret of where the fucker rim and Scott because when we weren't doing our panels We literally just left.
Speaker 1: I went to one event at the entire con.
Speaker 1: that was my tools anime hell.
Speaker 0: I went to anime hell.
Speaker 0: So it was hellish.
Speaker 1: good things about the con.
Speaker 1: our panels were very well attended.
Speaker 1: The stuff you know.
Speaker 1: everything went great on that front other than like weird Contractor running the panel room in the hotel who despite the con and Lou very specifically saying VGA Which is what every projector in the world anywhere uses.
Speaker 1: this guy was all super weird.
Speaker 1: He was like.
Speaker 1: I don't have VGA.
Speaker 1: oh I can't run the cable to the table cuz I gotta get out like 50 cables to do that.
Speaker 1: Just give me your slides, and I'll use my Mac here to display him.
Speaker 1: Oh what you have a PDF.
Speaker 1: I don't have PDF reader.
Speaker 0: Well he does it mean it's a Mac has preview.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but he was like really resistant to the PDF He's like.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: You don't have a PowerPoint?
Speaker 1: But like this guy was just really kind of weirdly.
Speaker 0: I guess for some reason.
Speaker 0: in the hotel they have to have union guys do it and in the convention center anime Boston people do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we'll talk to the con on the side, but yeah basically pretty sure they can.
Speaker 0: it's probably some read rule They can't have the anime Boston people do it in the hotel.
Speaker 0: They have.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 1: But the trouble is Lou sends out an email that says use VGA You can plug your laptop in on the table unless you're in constitution or in the one of the hotel ballroom.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you're in the hotel You're basically fucked and got to just bring enough stuff to make do.
Speaker 1: it actually made our panel really hard to do.
Speaker 1: you're lucky.
Speaker 0: you Had your laptop had many display for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which I thought I had regular display for it, but it didn't yep.
Speaker 1: But even then like we're also lucky.
Speaker 1: I had a clicker.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we're lucky.
Speaker 1: well We're not lucky the truck.
Speaker 1: the main trouble was we plan all our panels Assuming that we'll have a monitor screen to look at on stage.
Speaker 1: So we didn't have that.
Speaker 1: so we couldn't read the text easily on our panel.
Speaker 0: I had to keep looking up to the left and the whole point and only really mattered for that panel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the whole point of that panel is that we don't know what's on the slides ahead of time.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 0: so the only panel.
Speaker 1: But yeah anime hell was great.
Speaker 1: and also Mike tool has inspired us because we used to give everyone.
Speaker 1: we knew I'm a danger.
Speaker 1: We gave everyone.
Speaker 1: Oh my god shake hands with danger danger.
Speaker 1: we used to give everyone an anime con shit for just not having their shit together and Anime hell was literally the cleanest smoothest most polished anime.
Speaker 1: Hell I have ever seen in my life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you played the videos.
Speaker 0: They just played in a row without seeing any wallpapers or backgrounds or fussing with computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he had the timing set.
Speaker 1: he could pause it and do his commentary in between.
Speaker 1: it was brilliant.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's how it's done.
Speaker 1: He leapfrogged us.
Speaker 1: We've said for years We're gonna buy a lavalier system and just bring it to cons.
Speaker 1: You got one.
Speaker 0: he bought a lot on Amazon, but he had the receiver and stuff.
Speaker 1: so yep And the con let him do it.
Speaker 1: so stay tuned.
Speaker 1: coming conventions Scott And I might be wearing the same microphones that TED talk people wear.
Speaker 0: They're expensive.
Speaker 0: Oh my god We're gonna spend more like three hundred dollars each And that doesn't?
Speaker 0: that only counts the microphone part.
Speaker 1: this microphone kit will cost more than the gigantic Mackey we use to do geek night cost more than a 4k video camera.
Speaker 1: yep, so exciting times there Mike tool You've inspired us and also that was a great anime.
Speaker 0: hell good hell.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: It's hell.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's as good as a hell can be.
Speaker 1: Hellish yeah your Kipo to Chico.
Speaker 1: Uh the cosplay situation was lot of pony Lot of kill la kill.
Speaker 1: yeah, there's a lot of kill la kill.
Speaker 0: I mean it was.
Speaker 0: there was plenty of it right There wasn't definitely not a shortage.
Speaker 1: I think Tony was the majority.
Speaker 0: still it wasn't like.
Speaker 0: yeah There was a lot of but it wasn't some like ridiculous dominating percentage.
Speaker 0: It's not like in the conventions of old like I for some reason.
Speaker 0: I didn't count them right so I have no statistics to back This up, but in like the Naruto heyday.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: It felt like.
Speaker 0: it felt like a good 25 to 50 percent was Naruto.
Speaker 1: I remember and I think I have a picture nowadays.
Speaker 0: It's like this so much.
Speaker 0: It's like well.
Speaker 0: We got 10% kill la kill.
Speaker 0: That's a lot.
Speaker 1: I was at no like 5% and they had the lotus war meetup, and there were like nine deedlets.
Speaker 1: Yeah a lot a lot of attack on time, and these are like 20 30 vashta stampede.
Speaker 1: yes But the attack on Titans were good kill la kill is special because that show just by what it's about kind of is Designed for cosplay.
Speaker 0: it's a. it's about cuz it's a. yeah.
Speaker 0: So there I even saw do you see?
Speaker 0: Pajamas ryuko.
Speaker 1: I saw that I saw every form of ryuko and every four fighting fighting Goku uniform mako.
Speaker 1: yeah, yeah, it was.
Speaker 1: I saw Goku uniform mako mako all over the place.
Speaker 0: so someone on the internet took cosplay photos Which were elite four group cosplay photos.
Speaker 0: yeah anyone anytime.
Speaker 0: the elite four was in a group, and they took whoever was being gamagori And they sort of selected them with the lasso Scaled the gamagori up appropriately and pasted him back with a cut with the movement with a content-aware paste in Photoshop.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, so it looks like he's huge.
Speaker 0: Oh They found any any Elite four you know group shots.
Speaker 0: They did that.
Speaker 1: it's hilarious that that's that's so great.
Speaker 1: There were a lot of a haramay new ease to which I was very happy.
Speaker 0: There was a lot of newy which is interesting.
Speaker 0: It's because newy's creepy fucking character characters really that popular?
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 1: I like her a lot.
Speaker 0: I didn't see any Dr.. Matui, which is what we should do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what.
Speaker 1: it's basically the same costume as dr.
Speaker 1: Wylie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, reuse your old scientist man cause yeah, Aramaki get the same wig.
Speaker 1: basically Just fries a little bit more.
Speaker 0: I could try being some of those.
Speaker 1: I didn't see a single.
Speaker 1: no I did see one Raghu.
Speaker 1: I did not see any of like.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: so I didn't see any of the like.
Speaker 1: no tennis club no cat.
Speaker 1: no - no two stars except Mako.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also the The athletic club Elite four guy.
Speaker 0: I mean there was at least one or two of him, but that's the least popular Elite four.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I apparently.
Speaker 1: So we did another thing and we'll have coverage of this later.
Speaker 1: We did some cool stuff at the con some experimentation for future cons.
Speaker 1: but we asked a lot of people around the con some questions and Kineticon as another con they all go to was surprisingly really high on the list.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: It's geographically close it is Players and Kineticon has a lot of cosplay.
Speaker 1: so at the same time we talked to one guy And we're like blah blah Connecticut.
Speaker 1: He's like where's that?
Speaker 1: It's on the moon, but we asked people like what anime they're into.
Speaker 1: most of the people we talked to Named a wide array of anime except the one guy who was like Solita, Naruto Darker than black blood lad, whatever.
Speaker 0: People are all over the map in terms of their favorite animes, but something beautiful happened.
Speaker 1: the last question We asked everyone was so what is homestuck?
Speaker 1: and without fail every single one of them responded like this Well some people were like I don't know.
Speaker 1: some people were like Yeah, it's a webcomic I don't want to explain anymore But there was just this if they if they legit didn't know they said I don't know.
Speaker 0: But everyone else even if they said I don't know had this sharp intake of breath Even to even describe what it is is like this labor right and that tells you everything you need to know about what it is.
Speaker 1: So the last thing that was kind of funny is that we did our fundamental anime panel Which is basically a recycle of.
Speaker 1: we have a format of panel.
Speaker 1: That's basically here's a list of anime We want to recommend and we have a generic title for it, so we did fundamental anime Which is to take on anime you should see.
Speaker 1: so some website covered it and gave our list which is cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah I guess there was someone in the room who writes or submitted to some link bait website that just like you know just tries to get content to get clicks and whatever right and So they did a write-up of that panel, and they it's basically like top ten animes.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, right which is cool.
Speaker 0: Which is why our panel is uh?
Speaker 1: It removed some of the nuance of our recommendations.
Speaker 1: so for example Yeah, it's like it's someone who said they updated it.
Speaker 1: it no longer says started the magical girl genre for antenna Okay, now says galvanized And served as inspiration for count.
Speaker 0: okay, so that's 100% sure.
Speaker 0: it's better than started.
Speaker 0: sure so they.
Speaker 0: But it's like someone just sat in the room and just basically paraphrase paraphrased and wrote whatever which is actually a hundred percent cool.
Speaker 1: It's fine if they do that I don't give a shit yeah But it was funny that I got a lot of to.
Speaker 0: really rim is like making a big deal out of this and like it's just Some little website.
Speaker 1: Why is everyone freaking out who's doesn't make it a big deal about it.
Speaker 0: You're talking about it Yeah, because it's not even worth noticing.
Speaker 1: It's because it's funny to watch someone paraphrase us and Seeing sort of how the filter breaks down very rapidly or like on the list like for example if you just look at the list Of anime you recommended.
Speaker 1: we recommended Domiko dobutsu.
Speaker 1: It's like really that's a fundamental anime.
Speaker 1: And it's not because when we recommended that we recommended it as like.
Speaker 1: This is an example of the short format shows that nobody would think to watch Like this weird stuff kind of like the show we're reviewing today Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But yeah all in all good panels good con other than the security theater.
Speaker 1: bullshit.
Speaker 1: If the security continues like if it's it's just as bad next year as it was last year.
Speaker 1: Honestly thinking about reconsidering continuing to attend anime Boston because I'm just not cool with what's going down in the
Speaker 0: hinds Yeah, I mean, it's like we went and it's like the four panels We did were really good and that whole part was great, but everything else about it was sort of like There's good things going on, but the amount of effort required to go there You know by pay for a hotel room and such it's sort of not necessarily worth it
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And the security kind of just really pushed it over the line into.
Speaker 1: Gotta reevaluate if we're gonna continue to go every year.
Speaker 1: But anime Boston has almost no control over that.
Speaker 1: you got to complain to the city of Boston.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we gotta get a right letters to the mayor of Boston.
Speaker 0: cuz I point out packs does not have this problem No, and they're in Boston as well.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Also other similarly sized events do not have this problem.
Speaker 0: Nope Okay, so just a quick news.
Speaker 0: That is not anime Boston.
Speaker 0: The mocha is coming up April 5 and 6 in New York.
Speaker 0: We go to that shit every year You know, there's some drama surrounding it since that Society of illustrators acquisition and whatever.
Speaker 1: but most people we know who used to go aren't going Anymore, they didn't sell all the tables right away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm really down on it.
Speaker 0: Well, no, none of that stuff matters.
Speaker 0: What does matter is the guest list, right?
Speaker 0: And usually the guest list for mocha is like and who?
Speaker 0: really?
Speaker 0: you know, it's a bunch of indie people.
Speaker 0: Maybe some of them are really cool, but they've got like eight panels at this convention.
Speaker 0: It's not a real, you know, it's like what does it guess to me?
Speaker 0: And it means autographs and you see the person maybe you buy their book that just came out something like that, right?
Speaker 0: But on the list is a very important person who's hot right now Fiona Staples artist on saga.
Speaker 0: Ah So it's like someone who would be at a real comic convention.
Speaker 1: Yeah Better format comic convention, right?
Speaker 0: You can actually go see her.
Speaker 0: So it's like yeah, let's Let's do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah somewhat more reason to go.
Speaker 1: I'm a comics.
Speaker 1: I'm still excited about mocha partly because I just take the subway to it's right there.
Speaker 0: I know right what convention is better and you can have a really crappy convention if I can take the subway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I can take you out the subway to your con, I'm probably going to your con.
Speaker 1: granted I skipped the last recess, but I skipped a lot of recesses.
Speaker 1: Yeah you and your netrunner.
Speaker 1: So things of the day.
Speaker 1: this is a compilation video but is a compilation video of Dogs who have had their beds stolen by cats Reacting to this situation just to hit the cat and then get in the bed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, some of the dogs are not the cat to death and then sit in the bed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so they're nice.
Speaker 1: Like if you're in my bed, am I gonna bite you to death?
Speaker 1: No, I'm gonna be like get the fuck out of my bed But it's market.
Speaker 0: you're real fucking loud.
Speaker 0: If you're still in the bed, then I'll bite you.
Speaker 0: Yep, but it's all you can't really say.
Speaker 1: Like one dog is about the same size as the cat and he doesn't want to hurt the cat.
Speaker 1: So he grabs the bed and starts like shaking it and roll it around like trying to knock the cat out of it and the Catches like fuck you.
Speaker 0: I am he claws into the Latches on with his cat claw.
Speaker 1: It's good stuff.
Speaker 0: All right, so, you know we rag on soccer a lot and rightfully so.
Speaker 0: football It's a broken sport because of many reasons that we have discussed often, but if it was fixed, right?
Speaker 0: It could be a great sport.
Speaker 0: It's basically hockey on big grass with feet if you just fucking fix it, right.
Speaker 0: so Soccer does have good moments and it could have even more good moments.
Speaker 0: But here's an example of one of the great moments of soccer in an awesome video.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh Oh my god.
Speaker 1: The only thing that would make this better is if after that that second bit if he just ran over and kicked that guy in The nuts maybe.
Speaker 0: but yeah this is the kind of thing if soccer was always like this and didn't have all of the Diving and penalty kicks and other horseshit.
Speaker 0: I would watch it all the goddamn time.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: It's like if all of basketball was like the last 30 seconds of basketball.
Speaker 1: exactly At a moment the book club book is wool and most of the way through it I finished it a while ago.
Speaker 1: Yep All I'm gonna say is I expected it to be X Y & Z and it was.
Speaker 1: But it had one one twist that I did not expect.
Speaker 0: How far are you along?
Speaker 1: Three-quarters the way through the twist came way before that though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a. there's a twist for a guy sees something happen and then goes to react to that in the secret place and what he does to react to it was a. oh This isn't about what I thought it was Like I'd like.
Speaker 1: it's about what I thought it was but it's crook slightly.
Speaker 1: So yeah direction.
Speaker 1: I literally just did not see coming.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't also Didn't think.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I think I know what your oh is - yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah So I'm enjoying it.
Speaker 1: It's a. it's about it.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good book.
Speaker 1: It's okay.
Speaker 1: You should probably read it.
Speaker 1: It's short.
Speaker 1: You can just blow through it.
Speaker 0: I blew through real fast.
Speaker 1: Yeah We did a bunch of panels the anime Boston.
Speaker 1: someone uploaded video I'll link to it of one of them just from the audience.
Speaker 1: Okay might coordinate with some of the people who videoed it to get the video that other people took and maybe I'll edit it together and Do a ghetto version of what we normally do.
Speaker 0: but video that we took plus their video equals.
Speaker 1: But sadly, like I said because of Anna Boston security We did not use any of our high def kit.
Speaker 1: So there's gonna be no high quality video of our panel like you're used to.
Speaker 0: oh, well, yeah They're mostly panels people have seen before.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you should find us on the internet like our IRC channel or Twitter Facebook Google+ website forum Everywhere that exists on the internet.
Speaker 0: come find us.
Speaker 0: We are there.
Speaker 0: YouTube twitch Every place.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I'm also gonna take a moment to plug something because if you scroll down through this Kickstarter There's a tiny spot where you'll see my name reference.
Speaker 1: Whoa that's.
Speaker 1: that's like a Z list celebrity right there.
Speaker 0: We're already Z list celebrity.
Speaker 1: No, we're like.
Speaker 1: why?
Speaker 1: maybe W?
Speaker 1: We're like W at list at this point.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 1: But Yeah, the starfighter comic kind of a porny comic.
Speaker 1: it's all about a sexual tension and Boys in space.
Speaker 0: Yeah If I was a girl, I would be all about it Yep, or the guy who wants to make a comic sexual tension cute girls in space.
Speaker 1: I will read that Almost the opposite of space to Andy.
Speaker 1: But This Kickstarter is pretty rockin and the kinds of people who listen to Wednesday geek nights Probably might be interested in this for reasons that will become apparent if you read the Kickstarter if you're the kind of person who watches Boy swimming shows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you watch free this or if you like Tokimeki boys side or girl side girl side then Yeah, this is up your alley.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So yeah, we watch this anime Yami shibi yami shibai.
Speaker 1: Basically, this is the kind of anime that we would recommend like on our bite-sized anime panel.
Speaker 1: It's one of those short shows not that many episodes.
Speaker 1: The episodes are Under four minutes long.
Speaker 0: at least the opener is just ridiculously short.
Speaker 0: So it's not a case where the opener and closer are longer than the episode, but the episode is Ridiculously short.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the closer is just this sort of forgettable vocaloid songs.
Speaker 1: You just skip it.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 0: these vocal I like.
Speaker 0: I noticed I'm like, oh it's weird.
Speaker 1: I would never say that anything about this show is weird except for the show itself.
Speaker 1: Yeah Also, I love the crap out of the show.
Speaker 0: It's okay.
Speaker 1: Well, so the best way I can describe it is that if you liked folk tales from Japan But you wanted stories where everybody's fucked set in the modern era.
Speaker 1: That's what this show is.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much what it is.
Speaker 0: Art styles is really interesting.
Speaker 1: The art style is based on the this old style of storytelling in Japan where you'd have a stage or like a little tiny stage and you'd have paintings of scenes and you'd pull the cards up or pull the scrolls up and
Speaker 0: that's the guy you see at the beginning is a Guy who does that or you have to do that back in the day.
Speaker 1: that dude is sufficiently creepy.
Speaker 0: It's like in the US or wherever they had puppet shows.
Speaker 0: Well, that's what I had in Japan instead of you know, they had that Yep.
Speaker 1: So basically this guy appears at a child's or children's playground every day at five.
Speaker 0: He tells them a creepy-ass story and that's the episode is the creepy-ass story.
Speaker 1: and these stories are all sort of.
Speaker 1: They're either based in Japanese myth or based in Japanese urban legends.
Speaker 0: So a lot of them might be more relevant if we knew the urban legends are myths.
Speaker 0: But because we don't like I feel like I'm missing a little bit, but I'm not missing much.
Speaker 0: It's pretty straightforward.
Speaker 1: You've seen a lot of anime or know anything about Japan.
Speaker 1: You'll cut.
Speaker 1: you'll vaguely recall that a lot of these seem like they're based on something you've heard of before like the Umbrella goddess.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who makes possibly the second creepiest sound I've ever heard?
Speaker 1: anything make ever.
Speaker 0: I guess rims watched all the episodes.
Speaker 0: It didn't take long, but I only watched like half of them and I'm gonna say this still enough It's hard to faze me.
Speaker 0: I'll watch the rest later.
Speaker 1: It's hard to scare me.
Speaker 1: This show does an amazing job of bringing back that feel when you're a kid And someone's telling you a scary story like a legit scary story for your age.
Speaker 1: This show presents that sense of menace and foreboding Better than most things that call themselves horror ever have.
Speaker 1: yeah Didn't watch all of them.
Speaker 1: watch Tomonari-kun.
Speaker 0: it's very hard to get scared anything But it is what this does.
Speaker 0: is you ever be in a situation where like, you know I guess if you have an imagination whatsoever, right?
Speaker 0: It's like maybe you'll be in your kitchen downstairs at dark at night and you'll imagine something and it's like you want to actually be Scared but it's like you.
Speaker 0: just you know You imagine some creepy shit and of course like maybe a monster in the fridge or some shit, right?
Speaker 0: And then you go up in the fridge.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, it's just the fridge dude, right?
Speaker 0: Well, a lot of these episodes just like what if that thing you imagine?
Speaker 0: Nope, it's there every time.
Speaker 0: It's there like you're on whatever that thing you imagine.
Speaker 1: Yep It's there like you're on an elevator and it's going down and it stops at a department store.
Speaker 1: It stops.
Speaker 1: It's just like an empty weird floor and you're like And everyone else on the elevator gets off on this weird empty floor And then the door closes and it just keeps going down and while you're thinking what the fuck what the fuck?
Speaker 1: The doors just fucking open on hell.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: whatever scary shit you can bet it's.
Speaker 0: and Sometimes I guess some of the episodes are like someone did something wrong and it's not necessarily bad just wrong Just wrong.
Speaker 1: like like in Tomonari-kun the girl basically her mistake was saying I promise as Opposed to no.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I'll come back and play with you later.
Speaker 1: I promise the moral is never promise anything creepy anything.
Speaker 1: Yep, if something's creepy do not promise it shit.
Speaker 0: and then you know, someone does something wrong and then they get haunted or whatever right, but some of them are just like Someone is there and there's a creepy thing and it's like is there really a creepy thing?
Speaker 0: Yes, the end Like like I'm late at work.
Speaker 0: Let me go use the copy machine.
Speaker 0: Oh copy machine.
Speaker 0: Something's freaky is happening with it.
Speaker 0: What the fuck is wrong with this guy?
Speaker 0: We should quote Dave Riley.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's haunted.
Speaker 1: Ah the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but to go Dave Riley the moral of that one is if creepy shit happens in your copy machine late at night all alone Push that shit out the window.
Speaker 0: I know I mean I never.
Speaker 0: I can't understand in some of these episodes like why the person does what they do.
Speaker 1: I can understand it perfectly because like here's why let's say you are In a situation like that where you're at work late at night, which I can't imagine.
Speaker 1: So already that's a weird situation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's say you're there for whatever reason like you go to make a copy and weird crap happens The wall part of your brain.
Speaker 0: anime character.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I'm an anime character I'm acting completely differently than if I'm in the real world.
Speaker 0: These people are acting the way they should in the real world Which is not how you would act if you're an intelligent anime character exactly.
Speaker 1: But in the real world when something creepy happens and you're an adult or you're intelligent you don't immediately go.
Speaker 1: Oh my god There's a demon in this copier.
Speaker 1: You think that's weird and you're scared a little bit maybe but you don't act like you're scared Like you think what if something's creepy, but you don't think.
Speaker 0: is this copier full of fucking hair?
Speaker 0: There's probably like a giant hairball or dead cat in it or something.
Speaker 1: Yep, and then you blink and it's gone.
Speaker 1: I must have imagined it.
Speaker 1: all these stories are when I must have imagined it is not what happened.
Speaker 0: But I know.
Speaker 0: but see being a viewer I know that I'm watching a scary show so you're not just blue I'm not can't disbelieve the Right the actions of the person.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yep but the actions of the person like some of them are kind of funny and they remind me of like scary stories to tell in the Dark like zon by episode 2.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically the dude just sees a bunch of people giving him the bonsai cheer and he's remembering it as he's leaving somewhere.
Speaker 1: He's like actually come to think of it.
Speaker 1: It's almost like they were doing it backwards Like they were doing it down instead of up and then the cabbie's like what the fuck get the fuck out of my cab.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, you're gonna die real soon.
Speaker 1: at and the episode zon by so like.
Speaker 1: if you give the bonsai chair, that's good But if someone gives you the bot the zon by chair, you're gonna die.
Speaker 0: Why did they give that guy that chair?
Speaker 1: Oh cuz they're assholes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just like he was a guy who got hurt in the woods.
Speaker 0: He went to a hospital and then some old guys at the hospital conspired to curse him for no reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's jerks.
Speaker 1: Well, isn't that the moral of a lot of Japanese myth?
Speaker 1: you're fucked?
Speaker 0: Well, no, it's usually I mean if you watch it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, unless you follow the arbitrary rules that you didn't know right?
Speaker 0: but then the nice folk tales It's like the evil jerk-off neighbor is the one who gets fucked and then in you the nice person gets rewarded, right?
Speaker 0: But meanwhile here, it's just you're just a normal person.
Speaker 0: You're fucked.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well shit get you You're fucked unless you take the world as you see it and as is presented to you Seriously, so when something actually creepy happens you treat it as creepy.
Speaker 1: And if some crazy old lady tells you to follow some rules you follow all of those rules.
Speaker 0: and if you don't yeah, I mean there was the episode with the With the family that has to laugh to keep the demon away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then they stop laughing and then the demon comes.
Speaker 1: They should have told the kid what they were doing and had him laugh with them like right Or the one where they locked the kid in the shed to hide from the Umbrella goddess.
Speaker 1: I didn't like you could have explained to him why you were doing this.
Speaker 1: You could have told his friend not to come and fuck it all up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, these are all gonna be bad endings.
Speaker 1: you just like, you know, anytime someone tells you a ghost story It's gonna be a bad ending.
Speaker 1: the spoiler of knowing that they're all bad endings almost makes the tension.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it does make the tension way higher than if you didn't know that.
Speaker 0: I mean the thing is a lot of them don't even really show the bad ending.
Speaker 0: It's basically just Yep, there's a monster at the end.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: One of the I think the creepiest one is actually episode 11 or episode 12 video Which is the classic urban legend of kid took a video of a graveyard, but when you watch the video, there's something in the video.
Speaker 1: And Yes, I was listen to Dave and Joel and they thought the same thing I did about that episode.
Speaker 1: they're like, all right.
Speaker 1: So your fucking friend comes over and says hey instead of studying Let's watch this creepy video that kills people and the video is like a VHS wrapped in tape to prevent you from watching it.
Speaker 1: I think Joel was the one who was like, yeah If someone starts unwrapping that video take it from him and just break it.
Speaker 0: There was I think I watched Something that was like how it was might have been one of those how movies should have ended or something like that, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and someone well, I think it was scream and it was like hey You want to watch that video.
Speaker 0: that like you die after you watch it and the guy says sure and he takes the tape He just smashes in a million pieces.
Speaker 1: Who would want to watch that?
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: why did you even take that video done?
Speaker 1: But episode 12 Tomanari kun is so close in aesthetic to the scary stories to tell in the dark and Especially because of what Tomanari kun is and looks like.
Speaker 1: it's pretty legitimately creepy Because it because that one is the kind of thing that you can almost envision like happening to you like you could see Experiencing something like that and acting exactly the way the girl acts because that's the rational thing to do is act away the girl acts.
Speaker 1: But when that fucking shadow appeared in her house, that was actually pretty creepy.
Speaker 1: Hmm I really like this show is put out by TV Tokyo by a bunch of people who seem to be pretty not Noteworthy in the anime world.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'll probably watch it just because it's so short.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 1: why not watch 13 episodes?
Speaker 1: They're four minutes long.
Speaker 0: that that includes the opener and the closer.
Speaker 1: that for me who's the opener and not the closer?
Speaker 1: Okay It's four minutes and 30 seconds.
Speaker 1: If you want to do the old RIT anime tradition of watch every opener and closer no matter what sure It won't take you long to watch this thing.
Speaker 0: So it doesn't have to be that amazing to be worried like you could watch Like five of these in the time it takes like watch one real anime episode.
Speaker 0: so you could watch this whole show in the time it takes to watch two and a half episodes of another show.
Speaker 1: what I would recommend is one.
Speaker 1: if you're an anime fan watch it because It's different.
Speaker 1: It's different from a lot of what you watch normally.
Speaker 1: It's one of those shows on crunchyroll that almost no one's gonna watch.
Speaker 0: But for some reason crunchyroll keeps getting shows like this which makes the crunchyroll subscription kind of worth it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like if you have it's like I wouldn't get a crunchyroll subscription to watch this right and it's like I only pay for country roll because there's like three or four shows I'm watching.
Speaker 0: right but and if that number goes down, I'll cancel and just use the free crunchyroll again.
Speaker 0: But it's like if you're paying for it.
Speaker 0: You know because of other shows like Kill La Kill.
Speaker 0: you might as well watch these shows on there.
Speaker 1: Yep, but what I would do if I were you is watch it because it's great.
Speaker 1: But if you have non anime friends and you have a Halloween party Like a spooky Halloween party you bust this shit out at night with all the lights off and make people watch a few of them.
Speaker 1: I guarantee you'll have some friends who will be legit scared by this babies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as in a lot of people you'd be surprised how many people like it's like you think like when you're a kid Scary movies are scary for no logical reason.
Speaker 0: when you're an adult It's just like what when you're a kid.
Speaker 1: non scary movies are sometimes really scary for no logical reason like Beetlejuice is a comedy But a lot of kids that is some scary ass shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So, I mean their kids are even scared of shit like Sesame Street the movie.
Speaker 1: I'll put it this way this show.
Speaker 1: but like I said, I'm not scared by media But this show ratchets up the tension in a way that is palpable.
Speaker 1: It's a very well Presented horror.
Speaker 1: It's like a good storyteller telling you a good horror story.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: It's not actually scary.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's not what I said, but I'm very surprised.
Speaker 0: I'm very surprised cuz you're a sissy on this.
Speaker 0: I'm surprised on the internet.
Speaker 1: I didn't say I was scared by it.
Speaker 0: how many people interpret how many people I mean?
Speaker 0: And I see are actually sissies like you think like every adult could just watch scary movies Whatever.
Speaker 0: It's actually an I go and I see a lot of people and they're like, yeah I just can't watch any horror movies ever.
Speaker 0: It's like they're actually just scared and it's like whoa, really?
Speaker 0: There's like a good percentage of adults who are scared for reals.
Speaker 0: It's like wow, really?
Speaker 1: Wow This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: so yeah, we're back from anime Boston and we We used to review give a full episode to every con we went to but those back when we did four shows a week.
Speaker 1: So if you think we're hurting for topics now back then yeah, but it's very rare that one packs is significantly different enough from another packs to warrant a whole show.
Speaker 1: Yep, so the only thing I want to say this is kind of my news is what was different because there were some things that Were different at this anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Yep No, oh your microphone wasn't plugged in.
Speaker 1: I'm stupid.