Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, July 8th, 2014.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights Tonight, a link between worlds.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: I guess Scott really wants to be a fish.
Speaker 0: You know, if I couldn't be a person, and I had to be a thing that exists in real life, various types of fish are not bad choices.
Speaker 0: Well,
Speaker 1: I recall a long time ago, we were talking about if we had demons that followed us around, or a daemon, or whatever you want to call it, and people were like, "Oh, Rym, you'd have a crow," or something like that, and then you were kind of tangential to the conversation, and then you suggested that yours would be a tiny human.
Speaker 1: When we told you that wouldn't work, you decided a mechanical fish.
Speaker 0: A robot fish would be pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: It'd be okay.
Speaker 0: Better than a regular fish.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm not a big fan of fish, except for the eating.
Speaker 1: I'm more a fan of, I don't know, sea mammals, like dolphins.
Speaker 0: Dolphins?
Speaker 0: Good enough.
Speaker 1: Is that a fish, though?
Speaker 0: No, but I'll take it.
Speaker 0: You're just trying to, in the absence of being able to be a human, you're just trying to pick the smartest thing that is out there.
Speaker 1: No, if I was going to pick the smartest thing, I'd pick one of the greatest apes, or like, I don't know, an African gray parrot.
Speaker 0: You know, a dolphin might be smarter than some apes.
Speaker 0: It just can't, you know, talk and do sign language.
Speaker 1: One thing I do enjoy, though, is watching human babies interact with, like, dogs and horses, because it's obviously the same.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they have the same level of cognition, and in fact, there's a point where I have seen dogs that were clearly cognitively superior to the humans they were interacting with.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, the humans are either so small or, you know, so dumb.
Speaker 1: Well, I had a friend in high school who, I think his ferret was a little bit smarter than him in a lot of ways.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, there's people like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wonder what he's up to.
Speaker 1: I think he fell for the Amway scam last time I talked to him, which was, like, 15 plus years ago.
Speaker 0: If that ferret could talk.
Speaker 0: DeBlasio was talking about legalizing ferrets.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm a big fan of that.
Speaker 1: I like ferrets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 0: I don't understand why they were illegal in the first place.
Speaker 1: The fear was, in olden times, a ferret- Is this law really that old?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: And they haven't changed it since then?
Speaker 1: I will look up when the law happened, but the fear was that a ferret would climb between floors in the old-ass buildings in New York City, find a baby, and kill it.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: And not that pickpockets would use them, which is a thing that happened at least once.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, if I was a pickpocket, do you know how many ferrets I would have?
Speaker 0: People would know, huh?
Speaker 0: I got pickpocketed.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's the guy with a hundred ferrets hanging out in Union Square.
Speaker 1: Okay, they were banned a couple of times in history, apparently, but the ban that's in effect now was put in place by Giuliani.
Speaker 0: So really fucking recent.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So there's no excuse for any wrong thinking in that decision.
Speaker 0: So what was their not-wrong thinking?
Speaker 1: Oh no, there was a lot ... Okay, this is getting really complicated.
Speaker 1: This isn't the show about ferrets.
Speaker 0: Are you just going to abandon this topic?
Speaker 1: I'm going to abandon this topic because I've noticed a trend.
Speaker 1: I don't have a word for this yet, but this happened three times over the course of the wedding we were at last weekend where there's a discussion, two people make opposing claims, and a third person says, "All right, I'm going to look it up," which is followed by the conversation happening next to them where they go, "Oh, okay, give me a minute.
Speaker 1: This article's really long.
Speaker 1: Oh crap, it links to these other articles.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay, this is going to take a
Speaker 1: while.".
Speaker 1: And by the time they find the answer, no one gives a shit anymore.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: We need a word for that.
Speaker 0: TLDR.
Speaker 1: But that's ... TLDR also is just.
Speaker 1: anytime you're reading anything that's too long.
Speaker 1: This is an argument where the actual answer is complicated enough that no one cares enough to continue the argument.
Speaker 1: They were in fact only arguing for the sake of arguing.
Speaker 0: Like this right now?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Or like the Berry incident.
Speaker 1: No, no, okay, the ban goes back to 1959.
Speaker 1: The Giuliani thing was an upholding of the ban after some losses.
Speaker 0: Why would they uphold it?
Speaker 1: Giuliani I guess fucking hates ferrets.
Speaker 1: I can't tell.
Speaker 1: So I guess it's Tuesday, gaming day.
Speaker 1: May or may not be a Thursday show.
Speaker 1: We'll see if we feel like recording a Thursday show right now after this Tuesday show.
Speaker 0: Why don't you wait for the meta moment on that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this weekend we'll be in Connecticut at Connecticut.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So you got any gaming news?
Speaker 0: This isn't really news.
Speaker 0: This is from 2013.
Speaker 1: Wow, 2013 is actually the last time I got an email about the thing you're going to talk about.
Speaker 0: Like a year ago, August 2013.
Speaker 1: Here's the email I got.
Speaker 1: The subject line is, "MechWarrior online mailing list.
Speaker 1: You are now
Speaker 1: unsubscribed.".
Speaker 1: And it was the September 19th, 2013.
Speaker 0: So anyone who doesn't know, there was a MechWarrior online game.
Speaker 0: And, you know, it's basically MechWarrior, but you play it online, which is amazing, except it was pay-to-win of the highest order.
Speaker 0: So fuck that shit.
Speaker 1: In 2011, I made my account and reserved my name.
Speaker 1: I never once played the game.
Speaker 0: I also, same thing.
Speaker 0: I reserved it when they announced it and then I never once played the game.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the reason that this is news is because A, I just found this recently and I don't think we've talked about it on the show before, but B, this game died horribly.
Speaker 0: And why did it die horribly?
Speaker 0: Mostly because this long tale that you can read about how the game developers mistreated the community so badly, worse than probably or as bad as any game ever, and this isn't like a tribe situation where they did what the community told them to, it was the opposite, where not only did they do the opposite of what the community wanted to do, they did stuff that even the people that weren't in the community didn't want them to do.
Speaker 1: Oh, you like miniguns?
Speaker 1: Banned from the game forever.
Speaker 0: Right, the number one thing that they did that was really bad is they put in basically this thing called CoolShot.
Speaker 0: Now if anyone's played MechWarrior BattleTech, you know that heat is like the number one mechanic in the game.
Speaker 0: You can't just fire your weapons wildly all over the place.
Speaker 0: Hell, you can.
Speaker 0: Sure, but your mech will overheat and explode.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know, BattleTech/MechWarrior is all about, you know, positioning and, you know, firing at opportune moments.
Speaker 0: Eating management.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and managing the heat.
Speaker 0: You can't, in other games, you could just be like, you know, like Advanced Wars, move and shoot, move and shoot, unless you have ammo, right?
Speaker 0: Move and shoot, just keep shooting, there's no reason not to shoot.
Speaker 1: Yep, games like World of Warcraft have their cool-down period, so you do your attack, and then there's a cool-down, then you do your attack again, but there's no reason to not do it at the maximum rate.
Speaker 0: But in BattleTech, you have this general thing, heat.
Speaker 0: All weapons generate some amount of heat, and so it's like, you can't fire weapons, period.
Speaker 0: Not like, okay, you fired that weapon, it's cooling down, but you can still go crazy with all your other weapons as much as you want.
Speaker 0: No, it's like, okay, you're at like max heat.
Speaker 0: If you fire anything now, you risk just exploding your whole robot.
Speaker 0: So, of course, every BattleTech game ever has heat, because that's the core mechanic that makes it BattleTech/MechWarrior.
Speaker 0: I'll just keep saying BattleTech, because it's better, even though there's a MechWarrior online.
Speaker 0: So, they put in this thing called CoolShot, which is basically an item, a disposable item, that you can use to cool your mech off, right?
Speaker 0: So, almost like nitro for your heat sinks.
Speaker 0: You press the button and your heat goes away, and you can get them and use them up, and then you're out of them, right?
Speaker 0: So, obviously, if someone had one of these, or a few of them, they could get close to you, fire all their lasers, immediately use it and fire the lasers again, and that's pretty much going to make them win.
Speaker 0: So, what ends up happening is, when you have that, the best design of mech ends up being something with like a million PPCs.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow, the mech you're describing here, I'm reading that paragraph, is basically the mech I always made when we played the tabletop version.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the ideal mech, if you have this item, is a JumpJet mech, full of PPCs.
Speaker 0: You jump close to them, you fire all your PPCs, you cool down and fire them again.
Speaker 1: Or, back against the wall, targeting computer, two Gauss cannons, go for it.
Speaker 0: Well, Gauss cannons don't really use heat, so, but anyway, well, they don't use that much heat, and they cool off pretty quick.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so, the thing is, these cool shots, to get them, it wasn't like a pickup, like quad damage and quake, you could just get them by paying fucking money, real goddamn money, real world dollars you got from your job, could be given to this company to cool down your mech and fire your PPCs twice in a row.
Speaker 1: So, we talk about pay-to-win, but this is egregious pay-to-win.
Speaker 0: This is the most egregious, I mean, sometimes I say something is pay-to-win, and people disagree with me, like maybe League of Legends or something like that, I'll say, "Yeah, it's pay-to-win, because you can't get all the possible heroes, so some people have options you don't have if you didn't
Speaker 0: pay.".
Speaker 1: But there's at least a Pareto Frontier that's pretty well designed in a lot of those cases.
Speaker 0: Sure, but here, no one, no one would say, "This is not
Speaker 0: pay-to-win.".
Speaker 0: In fact, the people who made the game said, "This is pay-to-win.
Speaker 0: We're going to pay-to-win, everybody.
Speaker 0: Pay-to-win.
Speaker 0: Yeah.".
Speaker 0: And this is the story of that.
Speaker 0: Read this epic tale and learn a valuable lesson.
Speaker 0: And when you see new games coming out, try to imagine, is that game going to be this game?
Speaker 0: And if it is, do not touch.
Speaker 0: Not even with a 10-foot, not even with your LRMs should you touch.
Speaker 1: LRMs go way more than 10 feet.
Speaker 0: Not even with your LRMs should you touch that game.
Speaker 1: Not even with your enhanced whatever claws and the muscles.
Speaker 0: Not even with your arrow forward should you touch this game.
Speaker 0: Or any game like it.
Speaker 1: I remember I wanted to use sniper rifles, but we never played on big enough maps, so the Gauss rifle was just better.
Speaker 1: So in other gaming news, the World Cup's happening, and that's, you know, that's the thing.
Speaker 1: People care about it.
Speaker 1: Not talking about soccer.
Speaker 0: We've talked about soccer?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: We've talked about it a lot, and we're doing a panel at Kineticon.
Speaker 1: We're going to talk about it again and piss some people off, because it's soccer time.
Speaker 1: But a historic or an-historic game just occurred a little while ago.
Speaker 1: Brazil lost to Germany.
Speaker 1: By a lot.
Speaker 1: In the semi-finals, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: So they didn't just lose like 1-2.
Speaker 0: Like usual soccer game.
Speaker 1: 0-1.
Speaker 1: Shootout.
Speaker 1: They won by 6.
Speaker 1: The final score was 7-1.
Speaker 1: This game...
Speaker 0: 7-1 Germany.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Was a blowout, which in soccer just doesn't happen.
Speaker 0: Is a hockey score right there.
Speaker 1: That's an outlier hockey score.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: That's a blowout in hockey.
Speaker 0: But at least in hockey, it's like, okay, we've seen that.
Speaker 0: The equivalent
Speaker 1: of what happened just now between Germany and Brazil was when at RIT, a local college, in quotes, called Newman, had a hockey team that was in the same division as RIT's hockey team, and they lost a game to RIT's hockey team, and the final score was 24-0.
Speaker 0: It was glorious.
Speaker 1: I think there's a phrase, and the phrase is, "You are already
Speaker 1: dead.".
Speaker 0: And they were dead after like half the first period.
Speaker 1: So Twitter exploded, and watching this happen just through Twitter and through social media was amazing.
Speaker 1: Someone just posted this picture of a Simpsons quote, "If they're already dead, why do you keep doing
Speaker 1: this?".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I was just like, hey, this is great.
Speaker 0: The more boring the game, the more exciting the Twitter is.
Speaker 1: But this, seriously...
Speaker 0: Twitter makes all the social medias... If the game is too boring, people get diverted to Photoshop, and suddenly amazing things happen.
Speaker 1: I would not find this game boring.
Speaker 1: A game like this, I'm more inclined to watch, because maybe I'm just a sadist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the beginning was really hilarious, and then after that, it's like, all right, nothing's happening now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've talked about this.
Speaker 1: Remember in the game One Must Fall 2097?
Speaker 0: That's a great game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, my God, that was a great game.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it holds up.
Speaker 1: I have not played it in a long time.
Speaker 0: It's a really... Fighting game, people wouldn't like it, and there's sort of an RPG level-up element to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is why we liked it.
Speaker 0: But it's a kind of slow fighting game, but it still has all the aspects of fighting game, and the theme in music is awesome.
Speaker 1: Oh, the music is some of the best music.
Speaker 1: It's up there with Doom II's music.
Speaker 1: So in One Must Fall 2097, one of the things that would happen is, you would do your Pacific Rim robot fight, whatever, and then you'd watch the newscast talking about what happened last night.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And sometimes it would say things like, "It was a close match.
Speaker 1: It was really
Speaker 1: amazing.".
Speaker 1: But if it was a blowout, if you just crushed the other mech and didn't even take any damage, they always said the same thing, and they were like, "If you enjoy a fair, two-sided, interesting competition, then last night was not for you.
Speaker 1: But if you enjoy a sadomasochistic pounding, I think I'm that
Speaker 1: guy.".
Speaker 1: I like to watch games that are ridiculous blowouts, because they tell me...
Speaker 0: I like a ridiculous blowout.
Speaker 0: I like seeing... Like, if I had been watching from the beginning, I would have been like, "One goal.
Speaker 0: Ooh.
Speaker 0: Two goals.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 0: Three goals.
Speaker 0: Whoa.".
Speaker 0: And then, like, the fifth goal, I'd be like, "Oh, my
Speaker 0: God.".
Speaker 0: And then after that, it's like, "All right, we're
Speaker 0: done.".
Speaker 1: It's got that Newman game.
Speaker 1: When they hit 23, I would have been yelling at the top of my lungs, going for 24, with a minute left.
Speaker 0: There's a different aspect there.
Speaker 0: We're not watching on TV.
Speaker 1: True, true, true.
Speaker 0: And the people on the ice can hear us, because it's small time.
Speaker 0: Those two things are necessary for me to care when the score is 23-0.
Speaker 1: But a score like that either means that the tournament structure was fucked, that something about the sport is fundamentally unexplored.
Speaker 1: Like, there is a strategy.
Speaker 1: There is a situation...
Speaker 0: Well, Brazil's best player was injured.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's also a factor.
Speaker 1: Yes, it was.
Speaker 0: Is it a six-goal factor?
Speaker 0: Are you losing one guy?
Speaker 1: Well, that's what's interesting.
Speaker 1: There aren't blowouts in mature games, unless those games involve extremely...
Speaker 0: With top-tier teams playing.
Speaker 1: Unless those games involve extremely high levels of luck, or extremely high levels of individual player input, which can translate into luck.
Speaker 1: And while some of those elements can be present in games like soccer, it would not translate into this unless there was something systemically wrong in the matchup between Germany and Brazil.
Speaker 0: Well, I did see something recently that was very interesting.
Speaker 0: They talk about the good soccer players being good, right?
Speaker 0: Like Messi and Ronaldo and whatever.
Speaker 0: And someone made a graph, and it showed goals per game or something like that.
Speaker 0: Those two guys, when you looked at this graph, were basically miles ahead of everyone else.
Speaker 0: The same way that Wayne Gretzky is miles ahead of every hockey player that will exist.
Speaker 0: And it's sort of like, well, they really score a lot more goals than everyone else.
Speaker 0: Twice as many.
Speaker 1: Like watching Michael Jordan play when he played, or watching Mike Tyson box at the height of his boxing.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like when so few goals are scored, and you're the guy, it's like, you make a huge difference, and big number disparities like that can happen, you know?
Speaker 1: So, I just find this utterly amazing.
Speaker 1: And also, as much as I bitch about soccer, nerds, sports, their games, things of the day!
Speaker 1: So, this is just hilarious.
Speaker 1: I'm going to link to two things of the day.
Speaker 1: One is the original video that this is from, as in the audio and the situation that occurred with these so-called bootleg-ass fireworks shit, or fireworks bootleg-ass shit, I forget the exact order of those words, but all those words are used.
Speaker 1: And that is mashed up with one of the greatest movies ever made.
Speaker 0: That's correct.
Speaker 0: People think I'm saying this sarcastically.
Speaker 0: It's like, no, I fucking love that movie.
Speaker 1: Moses, Moses, Moses.
Speaker 0: Let my people go.
Speaker 1: It's a great movie.
Speaker 1: It is a great work of fiction.
Speaker 0: So let it be written, so let it be done.
Speaker 1: And one would think that it might be difficult to mash up the two things that we're talking about, but this video literally made me laugh out loud at my office to the point that everyone looked over to see what the fuck I was laughing at.
Speaker 0: I want to make all the Ten Commandments mashups now.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, we should take turns.
Speaker 0: I have Creative Cloud and I'm not afraid to use it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: In fact, I'm afraid not to use it, because then I feel like I'm paying for nothing.
Speaker 1: Seriously, I had to use the GIMP today.
Speaker 1: I haven't used the GIMP in a while.
Speaker 1: And I thought, oh, I'm just going to add some text layers and just...
Speaker 0: So it is a soccer-related thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Uh-oh.
Speaker 0: Everyday football fouls.
Speaker 1: Wow, this is almost like a documentary.
Speaker 0: This is the most true video I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: Might be too real for you guys.
Speaker 0: It's so real.
Speaker 0: You gotta see this.
Speaker 1: We shouldn't even just watch it.
Speaker 1: Just watch our things today.
Speaker 0: I don't know what there is to say about it.
Speaker 0: The title says everything.
Speaker 1: Our things of the day are often good or bad or interesting or whatever, but seriously, today, these three videos better make you collectively laugh out loud.
Speaker 1: Or you're not human.
Speaker 0: Or you're just really sad.
Speaker 1: In the meantime, this weekend, Thursday, Friday, Saturday, Sunday in Hartford, Connecticut...
Speaker 0: Well, kinda Thursday, let's be honest.
Speaker 1: This is a foray.
Speaker 1: Kineticon has been growing for many years.
Speaker 1: The quality has been stepped up in pretty much every regard.
Speaker 1: And this year, it's reaching this tipping point.
Speaker 1: We've spread into Thursday.
Speaker 1: This is the tentacle, the little tendril going out.
Speaker 0: Listen, I can't take another day off work.
Speaker 0: Let's not spread into Thursday.
Speaker 1: We're going to spread full-on into Thursday.
Speaker 1: Give it time.
Speaker 1: Fuck you, Thursday.
Speaker 0: No one wants to go to Hartford on Thursday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but PAX has four days.
Speaker 0: PAX is like ten Kineticons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, give it time.
Speaker 0: Not ten Kineticons, maybe like five, six, seven Kineticons.
Speaker 1: Kineticon is not analogous to PAX.
Speaker 1: However, it is analogous to DragonCon.
Speaker 1: I think Kineticon is going...
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's analogous to DragonCon, but the thing they have in common is that they're the two conventions I know of that cover all the geekeries.
Speaker 1: Large conventions that cover all the geekeries.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Well-run conventions that cover all the geekeries.
Speaker 0: Well, DragonCon is, I guess, relatively well-run.
Speaker 0: Well, alright.
Speaker 1: Well-run above...
Speaker 0: I've never actually been to it.
Speaker 0: I'm going by what I hear.
Speaker 0: But I hear a lot about conventions, so I know more than most people.
Speaker 1: When we say well-run and we mean it, we basically mean PAX and, like, two other conventions.
Speaker 1: But well-run in an absolute sense of...
Speaker 0: It happens again every year without disappearing.
Speaker 1: Or in the sense of...
Speaker 0: Without any major fiascos.
Speaker 1: If you look at the average human being from the entire history of humans from 40,000 years ago to today, that average of capabilities, then yeah, a lot of these conventions are relatively well-run.
Speaker 0: I mean, MAGFest still happens.
Speaker 1: MAGFest still happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but DragonCon and Kineticon, they're the two conventions that have all the geekeries.
Speaker 0: Whatever it is, what are you into?
Speaker 0: What kind of geekery do you have?
Speaker 1: I only play Fox, Final Destination, no items.
Speaker 0: Well, guess what?
Speaker 0: You can play Smash Brothers at Kineticon.
Speaker 1: Yes, you can.
Speaker 1: I'm only into body art and tattoos and specialized contact lenses.
Speaker 0: We have that shit at Kineticon.
Speaker 1: We've got panels about all those things.
Speaker 0: Whatever nerdy shit you're into, odds are it's at Kineticon somewhere.
Speaker 0: The comics, the anime, whatever.
Speaker 0: If there's a night of geek nights about it, it's at Kineticon, except maybe tech.
Speaker 0: I don't know how much tech we have.
Speaker 0: We need more.
Speaker 1: Not yet.
Speaker 1: I was thinking about...
Speaker 0: We were actually working on it, but it wasn't easy.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, there's big changes in the backend.
Speaker 1: Like I said, Kineticon is reaching this tipping point of getting to this next level of content.
Speaker 1: And next level of things being awesome.
Speaker 1: So stay tuned.
Speaker 1: So this year, if you want to see myths of medieval combat, parkour, an introduction, queer fandom, Kill La Kill and feminism, drawing unique characters, Sherlock Holmes through the ages, Hyrule Historia, welcome to welcome to Night Vale.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of shit going on.
Speaker 0: That's funny.
Speaker 0: The name of the thing starts with welcome to, so then they added a welcome to.
Speaker 1: You realize when I saw that title, I basically decided unless there was something egregious in the description, I was scheduling it no matter what.
Speaker 1: And then I read the description and it looks great.
Speaker 0: Whoever made the panel is clever enough to make the title, so they're clever enough to be panelists.
Speaker 1: When I look at these submissions, I pretty much think, are these people doing the kinds of things that we do to other conventions?
Speaker 1: If so, second look.
Speaker 1: So yeah, Kineticon this weekend is going to be fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: Also, we're doing a bunch of panels.
Speaker 0: Mostly because a few people bailed and we had to fill in.
Speaker 0: So our schedule started at like two panels and is now.
Speaker 0: how many?
Speaker 1: Four, five if you count the Date Naito panel that I'm going to be on.
Speaker 0: But if you count morning announcement panel.
Speaker 1: If we count morning announcements and all the convention run panels, like con feedback.
Speaker 1: I'm not adding the Kineticon convention feedback panel to our resume of panels that we've run over the years.
Speaker 0: You sure?
Speaker 0: I'm going to make this one exciting.
Speaker 1: Are you?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm just going to cuss out all the attendees.
Speaker 0: Be like, all right, this panel is actually reversed this year.
Speaker 0: Feedback for the attendees.
Speaker 0: Your cosplay is awful.
Speaker 0: You were annoying.
Speaker 0: You didn't pay for your badge.
Speaker 0: What are you complaining about?
Speaker 1: If I was making a TV show and I was the writer for it about conventions and people who run them, that scene, after you do your rant, you do your crazy rant, or I guess the actor who's playing you.
Speaker 0: You're that guy.
Speaker 0: I wish you did something.
Speaker 0: I actually sort of wish you did something bad at this convention so I could ban you.
Speaker 1: I would have the guy who plays house play you.
Speaker 1: You would do the rant.
Speaker 1: And then there'd be like a mope, one of those awkward office style, the office style moments of silence as everyone in the room is just aghast.
Speaker 1: And then one attendee would raise their hand and be like, I have some feedback about the convention feedback panel.
Speaker 1: And that would be when the scene would end.
Speaker 1: Shut the fuck up.
Speaker 0: Black rage.
Speaker 0: Say what again?
Speaker 1: All right, we're mixing our links and metaphors here.
Speaker 1: The Book Club book is a Canada club for LeewaWits.
Speaker 1: I read it a long goddamn time ago, Scott.
Speaker 0: I would read it in the car to Connecticut, but I get carsick if I read it in the car.
Speaker 1: So do I. In fact, I get carsick reading my phone in a cab ride to JFK.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: That's what happened to me.
Speaker 0: I was in cars this weekend because I was in Connecticut.
Speaker 1: And you were bored.
Speaker 0: I read my phone in the car and then I got carsick and I was like, fuck.
Speaker 0: And the worst part is- If it was a book, I would have known, don't read that book.
Speaker 0: But it was a phone, so I read it.
Speaker 0: And then it's just like, ah!
Speaker 1: Telling someone like us, don't look at your phone is like saying, yeah, don't open your left eye.
Speaker 1: Just keep that shit shut.
Speaker 0: And I'm sitting in a boring car.
Speaker 1: And I can't play my 3DS because I've basically beat all the games I own out of it.
Speaker 1: You get pie-cross.
Speaker 0: They already came out of the pie-cross E4.
Speaker 0: You never run out of pie-cross.
Speaker 1: I don't understand you and pie-cross.
Speaker 1: Have you ever done a show on pie-cross?
Speaker 0: You might as well also mix in Sudoku, crossword, word search- Should we do a show on- And uh, tangram- no, not tangram.
Speaker 0: Tangrams are the triangle things.
Speaker 0: Anagram, cryptogram, and all those other things in the themes magazine.
Speaker 1: After Kineticon, our next convention will be PAX Dev, PAX Prime.
Speaker 0: For all of like the rest of July and August, we've pretty much got nothing.
Speaker 1: You know what that means?
Speaker 1: Lot of streaming and gaming.
Speaker 0: Lot of gaming while biking and whatnot.
Speaker 1: But also lots of Geeknight's video coming back.
Speaker 1: The only other meta moment I'll point out, if you like the anime Shoujo Kakumei Utena, We've done the entire first goddamn season of that thing in terms of reviews.
Speaker 1: It's all on YouTube and it's awesome.
Speaker 0: And if you like that, Sailor Moon is back.
Speaker 1: Sailor Moon is back and we're gonna be talking- If you don't watch it, I'll punish you.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be talking about Sailor Moon Oshiokyo.
Speaker 1: A tsukimi kawate oshiokyo?
Speaker 0: No, in the name of something else.
Speaker 1: In the name of what?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: What would you punish someone in the name of?
Speaker 0: Your mom.
Speaker 0: Your mom sent me here to punish you, smack.
Speaker 1: So, pretty much if I had to rank Zelda games in terms of me enjoying them, Of all the Zelda games that have ever been made, my list is actually very straightforward.
Speaker 0: Oh, let's do the list then.
Speaker 0: Alright, alright.
Speaker 0: And then I'll do my list.
Speaker 1: Alright, my list.
Speaker 1: Number one, Zelda 3.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 1: Best Zelda game ever.
Speaker 0: Can't go wrong with that.
Speaker 1: Number two, I'm gonna say Four Swords.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Because that experience is transcendent if you do it right.
Speaker 0: However- We're talking about GameCube.
Speaker 0: Four Swords, obviously.
Speaker 0: Because there's some other Four Swords out there.
Speaker 1: However, I will not actually put that on the list as number two because that's like saying Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles is a great game.
Speaker 1: No, that is a great chance at having a great game.
Speaker 1: So, my number two would be Zelda 1, my number three would be Zelda 2, and I never really- You and your Zelda 2.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Zelda 2 is fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: You and your Zelda 2.
Speaker 0: Look,
Speaker 1: of all the twos that suck in the world-
Speaker 0: You also like Castlevania 2, so-
Speaker 1: No, I appreciate Castlevania 2, and I like it in the same way that I like pain because it reminds me that I'm alive, but I'm not going to pretend that Castlevania 2 is a great game.
Speaker 1: So, it's Zelda 3, Zelda 1, Zelda 2, don't really like the 3D Zeldas that much.
Speaker 0: Alright, so for me, Zelda 1, best Zelda.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: Just because Zelda 1.
Speaker 0: That graveyard going on, mmm.
Speaker 1: There's a graveyard in Zelda 3.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like in Zelda 1, that graveyard is like mystical shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know why?
Speaker 1: Because that palette was scary as shit when you were a kid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and when you go in the final dungeon, it's like the music going on.
Speaker 0: Let me just say, Zelda 1 is the only Zelda that can give you the feels, right?
Speaker 0: Even today.
Speaker 0: It's not like because I was a kid.
Speaker 0: No, that shit's still scary as fuck.
Speaker 1: Anyway- Zelda 3 gave me those feels when I hit the dark world, and I was like, "Oh, oh, oh, there's like seven more
Speaker 1: dungeons.".
Speaker 0: Anyway, Zelda, next one, Zelda 3.
Speaker 0: And then, Zelda 64, because, you know, Ocarina's.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Then- I think it's Ocarina.
Speaker 0: The one you didn't play, Wind Fish, Game Boy Zelda.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I should beat that game.
Speaker 0: Game Boy Zelda, Wind Fish.
Speaker 1: That's probably a good one.
Speaker 0: I did not particularly- Then maybe Zelda 2 after that.
Speaker 1: I didn't particularly enjoy Seasons or Ages.
Speaker 0: Minish Cat was a joke.
Speaker 0: Wind Waker and Twilight Princess and Skyward Sword are sort of all equal.
Speaker 0: They're boring as fuck.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: They're all equal.
Speaker 0: They all come below Zelda 2.
Speaker 1: I enjoyed the lore.
Speaker 0: I guess Wind Waker is like, it's better in some ways game-wise, but it's worse because it has the stupid Triforce hunting, and it doesn't have enough dungeons.
Speaker 0: I base Zelda solely on the number of dungeons.
Speaker 0: And actually, you know what?
Speaker 0: Of the three, I'm going to put Twilight Princess slightly ahead of the other two.
Speaker 1: Twilight Princess did have enough dungeons.
Speaker 0: Because it had enough-ish dungeons, but mostly because the one awesome ancient Hyrule dungeon hidden in the woods where it's like, here's all this ancient Hyrulean shit.
Speaker 1: Ooh.
Speaker 1: Oh, you love that precursor stuff.
Speaker 1: That's why you like Samus games so much.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: It's a very Metroid- It was very Chozo statue in that area, which is why it was dope as hell.
Speaker 1: Guys, if you want to get me and Scott excited about things, the term to remember is, quote, precursor technology.
Speaker 0: Matt Cross.
Speaker 1: Can it go for Liebowitz?
Speaker 0: Star Control.
Speaker 1: The culture.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that's my Zelda ranking.
Speaker 0: So, of course, here comes Zelda Link Between Worlds.
Speaker 1: Which is attempted to be a remake of Zelda 3.
Speaker 0: Okay, so when I first saw Link Between Worlds, it was like, oh, they're remaking Super Nintendo Zelda 3, which is the second one on the list.
Speaker 0: But they had already re-released it on GBA or whatever, and I'm just like, well, why?
Speaker 0: Why are they re-releasing it again?
Speaker 0: I don't get it.
Speaker 0: But then they're like, no, it's actually a new game.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, oh, it's actually a new game.
Speaker 0: It's just like, you know, very similar to Zelda 3.
Speaker 1: It's set in a similar-ish world, which is interesting because I'll go to places where I remember secrets, and there'll be a different secret in that area.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or usually no secrets.
Speaker 0: Basically, it's like, I wish they would have just taken the same engine and made a new game, which they sort of did, but they also used the same map and had two worlds on that map.
Speaker 1: The second world, however, was kind of ghetto compared to the dark world in Zelda 3.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Because it was basically a bunch of discontinuous zones.
Speaker 0: Right, but the big thing- You couldn't really explore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they did add a bunch of new Zelda mechanics.
Speaker 0: Mostly, the big one is the one where you turn flat and go on the wall, which is 3DS style, right?
Speaker 0: They had to do 3D something.
Speaker 1: The other thing that they did is, elevation actually matters a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: To the point that if you turn off the 3D, some of the puzzles are really hard.
Speaker 0: In some places, the elevation is cool, and some places, it's annoying that you have elevation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the fact is, it matters for some of the puzzles.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Which at least, it was an attempt to use Nintendo's most recent gimmick bullshit.
Speaker 0: Oh, the 3D screen?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But as much as I enjoyed this game, I have never died.
Speaker 0: Did I die?
Speaker 0: I may have died just fooling around.
Speaker 0: If I tried really hard, I probably could have completely avoided dying.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, one- Have you gone to that weird place in the top right-ish area with the falling thing, where you got to go this sort of platformy underground?
Speaker 0: That place is a little annoying.
Speaker 1: Well, I died a couple times, but I had fairies with me, so it didn't matter.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: But I never at any point, playing this game, fighting a boss, fighting a mini boss, going through an area- Oh, hell.
Speaker 0: no.
Speaker 1: Even felt for a second like, "I wonder if I'll run out of
Speaker 1: hearts.".
Speaker 1: I never bought a potion either, because fuck potions.
Speaker 1: I never needed one.
Speaker 0: You just keep your bottles sold with fairies or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you scoop up five bottles.
Speaker 0: Scoop them up with your net, and you'll be all good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, five bottles.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Bottles were more important than heart containers in Zelda 3.
Speaker 0: And now they let you have five of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And you get one of them just by dumping a bunch of money into that fountain.
Speaker 0: Dude, there was one item in this game that you get just by talking to a dude in town, the Pegasus boot, I think.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it's like, I didn't get it for so long, because I didn't realize it was so easy to get, but it's just like, just sneak up behind the dude and you get it.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: I didn't realize.
Speaker 1: I thought, because I remembered getting them a different way, and I didn't think ...
Speaker 0: I was like, "Man, what dungeon am I getting the Pegasus boot in?
Speaker 0: I could really use
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: I could have gotten it the whole time.
Speaker 1: The whole game was like, "Oh, I could knock that thing off.
Speaker 1: I could knock that thing off.
Speaker 1: This is really
Speaker 1: slow.".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It was interesting.
Speaker 1: So, they had that weird mechanic where you could rent items.
Speaker 1: So, basically, I had infinite rupees for the entire game.
Speaker 0: Well, that is one interesting thing.
Speaker 0: Usually, a Zelda game makes you do the dungeons in order, but here, they don't make you do the dungeons in order.
Speaker 0: You can go to any dungeon that's accessible that you want, but you might need a certain item for the dungeon, so you can go rent it for rupees, and that's kind of good, because they made rupees matter.
Speaker 0: In other Zeldas, if you would buy everything you could buy, then rupees meant dick.
Speaker 1: But, they only matter if you die frequently.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: And it's like, eventually, you just literally outright buy every item in the shop trivially.
Speaker 0: Why bother?
Speaker 1: It's not like you're going to die.
Speaker 0: Well, eventually, you know, I think in the other world, you can't rent the item.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: I never lose the item.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: I played it longer ago than you.
Speaker 0: You're playing it now.
Speaker 0: But, yeah, I just outright bought every item really trivially, because there were so many rupees, and they were easy to get, and then that was that.
Speaker 1: So, I guess, my trouble is, but it's a complicated problem, because this game is not a good game for me, but it's a good game for other people, so I got to harp on the things that I think are just bad design, or are Zelda going in a bad direction?
Speaker 0: Well, the one bad thing, right, was because you can go to the dungeons in any order, right, just choosing the right item that belongs to that dungeon, what ends up happening is all of the dungeons that are on the same tier are equal difficulty, but your link, you're getting more heart containers, and you're getting more sword power, and whatever you're getting.
Speaker 0: So, like, the first dungeon is actually kind of difficult, no matter which one you pick, but then every other dungeon after that gets trivially easy, because it's like all the dungeons are, like, the level two dungeon, as opposed to in Zelda one, like, if you walked right into the level eight dungeon at the beginning of the game, you were dead.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: I mean, sometimes I'd go in there just to, like- You're going to fight those blue sword dudes with your sword, and maybe some bomb, like How many bombs do you have?
Speaker 1: Eight.
Speaker 0: Four bomb.
Speaker 0: You're going to use four bomb and sword on a room full of blue sword guys.
Speaker 0: Good luck, my friend.
Speaker 1: Wasn't that a challenge at Magfest?
Speaker 1: You're dumped in with half a heart in a blue sword room?
Speaker 0: Good luck.
Speaker 0: I forget.
Speaker 0: What are those guys' names again?
Speaker 1: Darknut.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you have blue darknuts, room full of them, and the things that are shooting at you in the corners, and you don't have the magic shield, and you only have sword, and you only have four bombs, yeah, it's not going to happen.
Speaker 0: But in this one, that basically doesn't exist, because all the dungeons in the same tier are equal difficulty.
Speaker 1: Here's what bothered me.
Speaker 1: One, the items are not really used too intrinsically in the dungeons themselves.
Speaker 1: They're just used at the entrance to keep you out.
Speaker 0: Sometimes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, most of the time.
Speaker 0: Usually that weapon is the most effective thing against the boss of the dungeon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I've found that all the items are really effective against all the bosses in most cases.
Speaker 1: I mean, that fire rod, I use that to kill most of the bosses, because it's just a fuck ton of damage and goes through a lot of their blocks.
Speaker 1: So my problem is, you use a particular item to get in every dungeon, you can just buy that item for a trivial amount of rupees and just have it with you, no matter what, and they don't even make you figure it out.
Speaker 1: They have an icon that shows you which item you even need to get in, and they explain what all the icons are in detail multiple times.
Speaker 0: Hey, Link, this item does this.
Speaker 0: Mega Man, Mega Man!
Speaker 1: So whereas, here would be a cool puzzle, where that guy's like, hey, check out that windmill over there, and you know that's where your bullshit is, so then you figure out, how can I get the door open on this windmill?
Speaker 0: Maybe with the wind item?
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe if I make some windmill, oh hey, it worked.
Speaker 1: No, instead there's just an icon of the wind item there in case you're a moron.
Speaker 0: So you want it to be basically, if it's just a windmill and there's a wind item, it'll be so easy that anyone but the dumbest kid could figure it out trivially, but you want it to be even easier to where literally anyone who's literate will get it right.
Speaker 0: And to top it off-- Third grade reading level, anyone.
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: in the dungeons,
Speaker 0: because
Speaker 1: you rent bombs, you have unlimited bombs all the time, which means finding secrets is trivial, there aren't that many secrets, and every time you need a bomb for anything that matters, there's always an infinitely respawning monster that drops a bomb every time you kill him.
Speaker 0: That way you can't possibly get trapped in a dungeon.
Speaker 1: Except you can't get trapped by that, you just would have to go rent the bombs again if you die.
Speaker 0: You'd have to go all the way, if you get to a place where you need a bomb and you don't have one, you might have to go all the way back to get one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like in every other Zelda game.
Speaker 0: Right, this way, it's like, well, no matter where you are, you won't have to backtrack 100 miles and come back again.
Speaker 1: But thus, renting the bombs feels pointless, and two, the monster you kill is always right next to the puzzle you need to use a bomb for, so you don't even have to figure out the puzzle.
Speaker 0: And three, while the game- I think you're underestimating how dumb people are.
Speaker 0: These people, if they played Zelda 1, would have no fucking clue what to do.
Speaker 1: I've watched people play Zelda 1 and have no clue.
Speaker 0: You remember PAX, those were gamers, people dedicated enough to gaming to go to PAX.
Speaker 0: They hadn't played Zelda 1 before, and they were under pressure on a stage, but still, they needed someone to tell them what to do on a fact, and Penny Arcade realized this and provided it in advance, knowing that that would be a problem.
Speaker 1: So this is the problem.
Speaker 1: It seems like Zelda games are aimed at basically children or people who haven't built a lot of skill in basically any game even close to this genre, but simultaneously, they're removing even the basic parts of the puzzles.
Speaker 1: So you can't fail, and there's almost nothing to figure out.
Speaker 1: The solution to every puzzle in every dungeon is right there.
Speaker 1: You can brute force every puzzle, just get flat and walk in every direction, see a rupee on the wall?
Speaker 1: That's the direction to go.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing I don't get, right?
Speaker 0: We gotta presume they're making it easy and accessible to get the widest possible audience, Which is fine.
Speaker 0: The dumbest person who's playing this game is some little kid who plays Pokemon.
Speaker 0: That kid can figure out fucking Pokemon, he can figure out fucking Zelda.
Speaker 1: That kid was EV training before they made that an obvious part of the game.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: Those kids figured out fucking the first Pokemon.
Speaker 0: They can figure out the newer Pokemon, which has even more shit going on.
Speaker 0: They can figure out Zelda without the hand holding.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, look at another type of games, all the Metroidvanias.
Speaker 1: Those games, I had a similar problem with because I really like those games, but I get really good at them, so then when a new one came out, the beginning was ridiculously easy and pointless before you got to the good parts.
Speaker 1: So if Nintendo made Zelda games more and more difficult, they're only chasing the expert gamers, so instead they're making them easier and easier, but like Scott alluded to, I don't know who they're going after.
Speaker 1: who doesn't already like Zelda games by taking the games even a notch lower.
Speaker 0: I think really the thing that disappoints me the most is the better.
Speaker 0: Zelda games are usually the ones that are bigger, right?
Speaker 0: The more, the better.
Speaker 0: Same thing with Metroidvanias, the bigger the better.
Speaker 0: Look at Symphony of the Night, fucking upside down castle, playing it twice shit going on, right?
Speaker 1: Yup, and remember the original design of the original Legend of Zelda came out of the idea that I was a kid wandering around in the forest, and I wanted to recreate that experience.
Speaker 1: Zelda's 1, 2, and 3 had a lot of exploration, and increasingly Zelda games, especially even this one, pretty much railroad you into.
Speaker 1: here's a box, and inside this box is a puzzle.
Speaker 0: I think that's what they were going for in Link Between Worlds, was letting you go all over the map right away, any dungeon you want.
Speaker 1: Except then they portioned off the Dark Zone, so there's no exploration.
Speaker 1: There's almost no sense of discovery in the game, it just gives you a checkbox of...
Speaker 0: Well, you can't discover anything on a map that you've known your whole life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they changed a bunch of things.
Speaker 0: Imagine playing, if you played this and you had never played the SNES Zelda 3, you're discovering the whole thing because you don't know this map.
Speaker 0: Exactly, but even if I were discovering the whole thing, because of the way the maps designed It's like you have Zeke at your house, of course it's less fun for people who know your house like you.
Speaker 1: But even if I'd never played a Zelda game before, the map is so small, and the puzzles are so telegraphed.
Speaker 0: It's the same size map as your favorite Zelda.
Speaker 0: It's the same map.
Speaker 0: How is it small?
Speaker 1: Because that one was more interconnected.
Speaker 1: In the dark world, you could walk in a lot of different directions, a lot of different paths, there's a lot of kind of weird stuff hanging around.
Speaker 1: In this one, they've kind of walled off every section, and they even put them into separate sections on the map.
Speaker 1: And you can't walk between those sections at all.
Speaker 0: What I really just want to see is someone make a Zelda 2 top-down game or Metroidvania, where the thing is so big, and the difficulty continues to scale exponentially, to where you don't feel you get ripped off when you didn't beat it, because you still played it for like a zillion hours until you got to the spot where you couldn't get past.
Speaker 1: Oh, so then the game is just how far did you get?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's how far did you get, and only the most badasses of the video game world will actually beat it, and the slightly less badass will get to the final boss and die, and the slightly less badass might get to the last level, and the difficulty just keeps scaling all the way up, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like, everyone's going to get really far, because it's so big, you're going to get at least a full Zelda game into the game, like 14 dungeons or whatever, something ridiculous like that, but the game has like 30 dungeons.
Speaker 1: Oh, tons of NPCs saying a bunch of useless shit constantly that you can't skip.
Speaker 0: That's in every Zelda game ever.
Speaker 1: Zelda 1?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: They don't, that takes two seconds, they don't say it again.
Speaker 0: The dark no-dislike smoke, you can't leave the room while I am typing it very slowly.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: That does not bother me nearly as much as- Pay me rupees and I'll tell you something completely useless that you can't leave the room while I'm saying.
Speaker 0: Oh, and you lost some rupees.
Speaker 1: I'm a sage, let me give you all this lore that has literally no bearing on the game, because you're just going to go do these check boxes.
Speaker 0: People really care about the Zelda lore for some reason.
Speaker 0: I know, I know, and I just- Even though it's the exact same lore, every single game, get all them sages, then beat Ganon.
Speaker 0: I just don't care anymore, like the lore- Hey guys, pro tip, at the end of the game, Ganon.
Speaker 1: The lore is so unsubtle, and honestly, pretty badly written in this game.
Speaker 0: It's the same lore that they've had since SNES Zelda.
Speaker 0: But the wording.
Speaker 0: They repeated that one lore every time.
Speaker 1: The way they- The little details about where the different sages went, and oh, this guy, someone rented my sand, whatever, and I wonder what happened to him, and the witch disappearing, and then you figure out she's a sage, because they show you a picture.
Speaker 1: They don't let you figure anything out on your own.
Speaker 1: Everything you could figure out, even stuff about the lore, they tell you immediately in multiple ways.
Speaker 1: There is no chance to miss any of the little subtle details that they could have just left undescribed.
Speaker 1: The game is unsubtle, if I had to describe it every word.
Speaker 0: Every modern game?
Speaker 0: What game that's new to subtle?
Speaker 0: For any platform, any- FTL.
Speaker 0: How is it subtle?
Speaker 1: The combinatorial complexity and the surprising interactions of different weapons and strategies makes very subtle and nuanced strategies interesting.
Speaker 0: What about the lore of FTL?
Speaker 0: How is it subtle?
Speaker 1: Have you actually played the advanced game at all?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: There's lots of little side dramas going on, and you can figure out a lot of interesting stuff about, like, which races are interacting with whom and what's going on in these parts of space.
Speaker 0: Rock man is love fanfic.
Speaker 1: Actually, you know what, Deus Ex Human Revolution had a lot of interesting, subtle lore that didn't get in your way, and they didn't go out of their way to say, "Hey, hey, check out this clever thing we did, like a Zelda game does.
Speaker 1: Look right here.
Speaker 1: This is the tiny, clever thing we did, in case you missed
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: In that game, it's just there.
Speaker 1: If you notice that guy looks like that other guy, well, that's interesting.
Speaker 1: I wonder, it's almost like the creators are afraid that you'll miss some little piece that they thought of, that they thought was clever, so they gotta have arrows and fingers pointing at everything they thought of to make sure you know how clever they were.
Speaker 1: I don't know, I'm just, I was surprisingly unsatisfied by the game.
Speaker 0: There's a reason it's not video game season and hasn't been for a while.
Speaker 1: I'm playing a lot of video games, I'm just not playing Nintendo games.
Speaker 0: I'm not playing really much video games right now.
Speaker 0: But I might soon.
Speaker 1: So yeah, see you at Kinetic Con.
Speaker 1: Out of the midst of the bush unsaid, Moses, get the water, Moses, Moses, Moses.