Speaker 0: It's Tuesday July 22nd 2014.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: ingress back from Connecticut completely rested Nothing to do till PAX nothing to do until the real packs.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, you know a month from now It's so the other day.
Speaker 0: I tried to call because Scott and I actually I through magic I got us a room in the Sheraton, but Scott has a backup room in the red line.
Speaker 1: It's no longer the red line.
Speaker 1: It's now the motif.
Speaker 1: something something or whatever.
Speaker 1: not trusting that also there's gonna be some tabletop in there.
Speaker 0: Did they announce that because they know about?
Speaker 1: Fantasy flight said they're having a netrunner tournament and it's on the third or fourth floor of.
Speaker 0: well did wasn't?
Speaker 0: last year There was some Final Fantasy stuff.
Speaker 0: They're separate from tabletop.
Speaker 1: Maybe yeah I think it's like that.
Speaker 1: you I'm pretty sure this network determine sounds like it's a real packs netrunner.
Speaker 1: Oh, it is because you have to sign up for it at 10 a.m.
Speaker 1: With the enforcers.
Speaker 1: So I think I think tabletop tournament is gonna be in the former red line.
Speaker 0: But guys it's like every year we go to all these conventions and like like Oh kinetic on really pumped out kinetic on and oh my god mag fast really pumped about mag fast and anime Boston and PAX East.
Speaker 0: but then Then in that few weeks before PAX Prime like I remember how much I fucking love packs.
Speaker 0: They're real facts like not just so real.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry guys, but in the last few years PAX East is a good con Not as good as PAX Prime.
Speaker 0: It is objectively worse by every measure other than number of miles I travel to get to it worse But it doesn't mean it's bad.
Speaker 0: No, it's still like the third best con we go to.
Speaker 1: it's like oh no LeBron James not as good as Michael Jordan.
Speaker 0: Yeah So, uh, I really looking forward to PAX and as Scott reminded me I keep forgetting that PAX is four days long.
Speaker 0: ah Shit, I could spend a whole day doing nothing about playing like indie RPGs or dive kick And I'd still have a whole packs.
Speaker 1: Oh No Steak not as good as filet mignon.
Speaker 0: Oh So, yeah, hopefully panels and all that stuff will be announced soon, but we're gonna be at PAX no matter what.
Speaker 0: we'll be there doing shit Emily and I'll be at PAX.
Speaker 0: dev Scott will not but All three of us are gonna be at that Charity gaming.
Speaker 0: What do they call that thing?
Speaker 1: I think it's sold out.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: It probably went to it last year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that thing we went to last year.
Speaker 1: It's a charity dinner to benefit Like this food bank that feed people.
Speaker 1: there will be a link to it and it's basically Thursday night before packs come to this place get dinner and tabletop game.
Speaker 0: It was super fun.
Speaker 0: But my warning to you is that if you want to go to it and you don't pay to be a VIP It's really hard to find space to play a game because there's so many people Mmm, and a lot of the pen.
Speaker 0: also if you're gonna go and you're like us bring your own games Most of the games people brought were baby tear.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot of non baby tear.
Speaker 0: So if you are at this thing, which I will look up what is called and link to it Uh, let us know because if you want to come into our VIP area We might invite you in where we will have.
Speaker 1: we can invite non VIPs in the VIP area.
Speaker 0: I think after dinner, we're allowed to because we're not actually special.
Speaker 1: We just paid for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not have money.
Speaker 1: It's not like oh, no, they care about us.
Speaker 0: Here's a pile of money.
Speaker 0: What are you doing with it giving it to children who might be dying in children's hospitals so they can have video games.
Speaker 0: Okay, that that's a worthwhile use of my money.
Speaker 0: I've spent more money on stupider shit.
Speaker 0: So I guess there's some news because Blizzard servers are down.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know if they're still down but basically Hearthstone right and just so people know.
Speaker 1: we know the guy who made Hearthstone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and he gave us beta keys way back and I played it on PC And even though I know the guy gotta be honest It was kind of a lame simple game and everyone I played it on PC.
Speaker 1: I was like, this is not worth my time.
Speaker 1: and then it came out for iPad, huh?
Speaker 1: It was a hundred percent the exact same goddamn game with no differences whatsoever that I could tell.
Speaker 1: there's one important difference It's on the iPad.
Speaker 0: You can play it while you're pooping.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: Think about this right?
Speaker 1: I think I think this is why I'm playing it at all, right?
Speaker 1: It's pay-to-win, which is already bullshit.
Speaker 1: It's super random right because you'd only have two of any particular card in your deck.
Speaker 1: So and a lot of the cards are just ridiculously random in them themselves like the card that says summon a random beast Which could summon the beast that wins you the game or could totally fuck you up, you know There's a card.
Speaker 1: It says take all the minions on the board kill all of them except one at random.
Speaker 1: It's ridiculous.
Speaker 1: this game is crazy, but As a game if you're sitting at your PC or you have friends nearby and you can play a board game like you can play netrunner or you can play counter-strike or you can play pretty much any game because you're sitting at a PC or with friends.
Speaker 1: Hearthstone just sucks ass compared to those games.
Speaker 1: But think about where you can have an iPad on a bus Pooping alone in the park booping on a toilet.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: What better game can you play?
Speaker 1: Than hearthstone against a human being.
Speaker 0: Yeah Hex I can't play against a human while I'm pooping.
Speaker 0: I'm playing.
Speaker 1: It's really lame compared to any real game, but compared to anything else you can play on an iPad When you're alone.
Speaker 1: in certain situations, it's actually the best.
Speaker 1: like what else is there angry birds?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and even though it's pay-to-win Which is bullshit It's I guess it's less pay-to-win.
Speaker 1: I mean you're still paying to win if you pay to get the awesome cards Like I lose to people just because they have awesome cards all the time, right?
Speaker 1: There's no question, but it's not like some games like that mech or your game.
Speaker 1: We talked about that failed Yeah, where you can literally just directly pay-to-win super hardcore.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so they came out with this thing today curse of Naxxramas Yeah, which is actually single-player Hearthstone right and here's how it works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there's five Winglings which are like campaigns I guess and each one has basically three opponents to play against right bosses and the bosses of like unique powers and unique decks or whatever.
Speaker 1: and The first wing is free at least for a month.
Speaker 1: at the end of the month the intro whatever that wing is gonna cost money.
Speaker 1: And so all the other wings right all the other wings are gonna cost money no matter what.
Speaker 1: they're gonna release one Wing a week, but the first one's free at least during the intro period.
Speaker 0: yeah, I love this.
Speaker 0: the first one is free, right?
Speaker 1: So it's a say hey, you want some goofballs, so it's a single-player thing a normal mode.
Speaker 1: You just pick one of your decks and play against the three bosses and beat them.
Speaker 1: I already did that.
Speaker 1: they were chumps.
Speaker 1: I beat him real easily right?
Speaker 1: then they have this mode.
Speaker 1: That's like hero challenge mode where they give you a deck For each hero and you have to beat these bot.
Speaker 1: you know that you have to basically beat it with the deck They give you.
Speaker 1: I did that.
Speaker 1: it was balls hard because they give you shitty decks and the opponents are ridiculously strong.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I they give you two and I think when you beat them then you get some more.
Speaker 1: I haven't beaten any of them So I don't know how many like.
Speaker 1: so if I beat one do I get one more or do I have to beat?
Speaker 1: two to go?
Speaker 0: that gave me an idea for a crazy magic tournament.
Speaker 0: imagine if you did a draft and then Everyone submitted their deck, and then you got a random deck from the draft And then you played magic.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the If you when you beat the three initial bosses you get some cards right that you can use in real Hearthstone right and when you beat these challenges you unlock cards you can use in real hearthstone.
Speaker 0: Wow the first post here is my only one.
Speaker 0: who thinks that the new boss cards are overpowered you right.
Speaker 1: the any card actual night Any legendary card is overpowered.
Speaker 1: That's how basically how the game works.
Speaker 0: spectral not ever.
Speaker 0: this whole thread is already people.
Speaker 0: today.
Speaker 0: Dateline five thirty two p.m.. Today.
Speaker 1: this thing came out this afternoon.
Speaker 0: Yes, spectral night is way overpowered.
Speaker 1: all the cards in the game that are legendary are overpowered.
Speaker 1: It's pay to win that.
Speaker 1: the rare expensive hard to get cards are up.
Speaker 1: Just better if you have them you will beat someone who does not have them.
Speaker 0: yep anyway.
Speaker 1: So and then they have this like super hard mode which is like I think you do this.
Speaker 1: I haven't even try it But if you beat that you get super awesome ridiculously good cards.
Speaker 1: But I think that I think you can use your own decks on that, but it's supposed to be ridiculously hard.
Speaker 1: I haven't played it, so I don't know.
Speaker 1: so that's the thing.
Speaker 1: luckily You don't have to use real money to buy these other wings when they go on sale.
Speaker 1: You can use in-game money that you got just by playing the game, so I actually haven't spent any of the in-game money I've gotten for weeks just so That I don't have to pay to get this other stuff.
Speaker 0: you engaged in forethought and planning to make this happen.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like you know.
Speaker 1: they've been teasing this shit for a long time right, so I have like 1,700 in-game golds Which is enough to buy 17 packs of cards?
Speaker 1: But I'm gonna use it to buy this shit instead.
Speaker 0: Interesting how hearthstone is becoming pretty wildly popular and the people who play it are really into the competitive scene right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: I'm really curious.
Speaker 1: What if someone?
Speaker 1: the reason it's popular is because you know it fills a niche that no other video game fills.
Speaker 1: really it's free.
Speaker 1: It's a two-player directly competitive game.
Speaker 1: you like this custom deck building thing going on right and The interface of it the actual application is pretty much as polished and amazing as can be and it's on the iPad and the desktop And it's exactly the same and you know it's just so well made as a piece of software.
Speaker 1: if Someone did this for a real game that was similar, but like wasn't pay-to-win and wasn't So luck-based.
Speaker 1: Imagine how well that would do if the software was just as good.
Speaker 0: possibly poorly because as we learned from Team Fortress 2 High-tier players represent a very small minority of actual gamers and games that are actually Primarily skill based like chess tend to be very unpopular among people who aren't very good Mmm.
Speaker 1: I just like to see Blizzard You know put the same.
Speaker 1: you know the programmers and artists who made this so nicely to make say an online turn-based strategy Two-player game that's not pay-to-win Adventure.
Speaker 1: somehow blizzard just buy the advance Wars license and just say they don't have to make it man So as they can just make like Starcraft tactics or some shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm really kind of married to the advance Wars aesthetic at this point.
Speaker 1: I'll take space Marines.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: We are space Marines That's right, so that's the deal with that.
Speaker 0: so in other news a games coming for the 3ds But I'm actually not gonna buy right away because my policy on all things Nintendo has gone from buy out of hand to wait and see.
Speaker 0: Yep, even this Tetris ultimate was announced with the most pathetic Teaser trailer I have ever seen in my life.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 1: how else can you what else gonna show from Tetris blocks falling?
Speaker 0: It's literally just the word Tetris.
Speaker 1: That's all you need to know.
Speaker 1: that's the trailer.
Speaker 1: What else do you need to know?
Speaker 0: so I'm worried about it in a few ways.
Speaker 0: on one hand is probably gonna be fun but the biggest fun of Tetris on the DS was that a whole bunch of us would play live multiplayer Right, and also it had this one awesome.
Speaker 0: Yes themes and yes, this one does not appear to have any NES themed stuff.
Speaker 0: it's more me themed and they list the modes that they've got here and The battle mode says one to four player brawl.
Speaker 0: Mmm the fuck.
Speaker 0: Where's my 16 player brawl?
Speaker 1: Where's my 128 player?
Speaker 1: Yeah has to be a power of two.
Speaker 1: We can't have a 17 player brawl.
Speaker 0: Well, unless you had the Turbografx-16 sure Five player games.
Speaker 1: I mean it's some.
Speaker 1: one person gets a Tetris everyone else dies, right?
Speaker 1: It's not it's not good.
Speaker 0: So anyway, I'm curious why.
Speaker 0: because that really wide multiplayer battle in the DS was 90% of our play of that game.
Speaker 0: the other 10% was that weird dual mode.
Speaker 0: We're throwing Tetris like at each other in the middle.
Speaker 1: The point is Tetris is official and unofficial have been released for pretty much every hardware platform known to man.
Speaker 1: But the best ones the true Tetris's are always the ones in the portable Nintendo system the Game Boy one The NES one kinda the DS one.
Speaker 1: Definitely.
Speaker 1: I guess the SNES and n64?
Speaker 1: well SNES had Tetris and dr.
Speaker 1: Mario which is an okay cartridge, but wasn't it.
Speaker 1: and then Tetris 64.
Speaker 0: So Tetris ultimate is also being launched later this summer on PlayStation 4 Xbox one PlayStation Vita windows, but I mean 3ds is gonna be the legit one.
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: who's gonna play those other ones.
Speaker 0: I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean, what about all the people who didn't buy a 3ds for the same reason?
Speaker 1: So all of know all of nobody there's people who didn't buy 3ds.
Speaker 1: Who do you know that does not have a 3ds Emily?
Speaker 1: She has a DS.
Speaker 0: She has a DS.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no 3ds.
Speaker 1: I think she'll be fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah We'll see.
Speaker 1: This is legit Tetris right here.
Speaker 0: But I worry that this is gonna be like the WarioWare situation where it's gonna be a legit Tetris that just isn't as Good as the previous one.
Speaker 1: like it always says you don't think it'll be good as DS Tetris.
Speaker 0: I worry it might not be the only thing I think it'll let.
Speaker 1: it's lacking.
Speaker 1: Knowing nothing about it other than the name I predict it won't lack anything except the cool NES themes and the many-player battling.
Speaker 0: four players is enough Tetris battling Yeah, but we almost always when we were doing this have more than four players wanna play tetranet.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, tetranet.
Speaker 1: Tetranet is hardcore Tetris.
Speaker 1: You can't play it.
Speaker 1: You'll just lose immediately.
Speaker 1: Yeah people like No.
Speaker 0: as an aside, uh, we talked about this a lot at least everyone over here in our crew except Scott.
Speaker 0: but we finally got together and played a multiplayer game of the newest most updated most expansion civilization 5 ain't gonna know.
Speaker 0: I got time for that and you know what it's working really well and Let me do it technologically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll get to that.
Speaker 0: So all at one it took us an hour to start the game.
Speaker 0: Okay, already.
Speaker 0: No one got time for that But once we got it going I just want to let you guys in on one of the one of the reasons why our gaming Group is so closed and insular and why no one will game with you out there.
Speaker 0: We set no turn timer No turn limit.
Speaker 0: You can take an hour to take your turn and everyone has to wait Because we trusted everyone playing and you know what?
Speaker 0: It was not a problem.
Speaker 0: if you play games with any person where you would not trust To leave that option the way that we left it your gaming group is someday going to explode in drama and fail.
Speaker 1: Or if you're the person who says no, no, we need to make it unlimited because I need to think you're the problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, take your turn.
Speaker 0: So it was super fun and they fixed most of the issues like the look like how does the timing issue work now?
Speaker 1: Like if I'm got guys next to each other and I'm gonna attack you You were going to attack me if you do something that would cause war including just declaring war.
Speaker 0: it Reminds you like are you sure?
Speaker 0: Fucking sure.
Speaker 0: and then what it'll do is everyone who's not at war can take their turns per turn simultaneously.
Speaker 0: Then the people at war take their turns sequentially.
Speaker 1: So if I'm not at war I get to go first or second or third or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: But I mean, it's just it's parallel with everyone else is not at war.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: So let's say you're warring with Scott Johnson.
Speaker 1: Yes, I want to jump in and attack you.
Speaker 1: I get to do that before you do your war with Turn.
Speaker 0: if you attack it says attacking will declare war.
Speaker 0: Do you want to?
Speaker 0: and if you say yes, and then you get added to the turn order of all of us going to war.
Speaker 1: So I get my turn.
Speaker 1: that turn gets shifted as basically art your turn stops.
Speaker 1: You'll get to continue it later.
Speaker 0: You'll basically yes your turn now will be in the sequence.
Speaker 1: Well, my my attacking dude gets a move before your guy.
Speaker 0: it depends.
Speaker 0: So you obviously have not played this at all.
Speaker 0: So in multiplayer, it shows all the people who are in the game left to right at the bottom And it shows you who didn't fucking take their turn yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah But - if there's war They the order will always go left to right on that.
Speaker 0: that's just set at the beginning of the game.
Speaker 1: So, you know, that order doesn't change ever.
Speaker 0: Yes, cuz if you play without hybrid mode and just pure turn-based it just goes in that order for the entire game.
Speaker 0: Okay, so in hybrid mode of the people at war it goes in that order every turn for them.
Speaker 1: So if I always go before you from the start of the game any war we have then I can just nuke you before you can Respond, you know one turn I declared war against link eg primarily because he was to the right.
Speaker 1: That's a good idea.
Speaker 0: Also.
Speaker 0: We founded fucking Humber right next to my capital.
Speaker 0: It's like dude, you see these six catapults.
Speaker 0: I built right?
Speaker 0: What do you think's gonna happen?
Speaker 1: Actually
Speaker 0: horsemen, so I went over and I stole his worker and then I was like
Speaker 1: fuck Yeah,
Speaker 0: and then I was immediately like I will gladly sue for peace If you don't want to have the returns take forever because of this war, but he tried to get the worker back.
Speaker 0: Hold the worker hostage in your capital Yeah, so I ran and then he cut me off so I couldn't get the worker back to one of my city.
Speaker 0: So eventually I ran north and north and north bandit.
Speaker 0: So I threw it into a city-state and I tried to gift it to that city-state.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even better Yeah, and then this work better more than disbanding it.
Speaker 0: So later his I'm just gonna tell you what happened.
Speaker 0: There's some crazy bullshit happened.
Speaker 0: So there's this this is going on.
Speaker 0: We're at war.
Speaker 0: I'm giving the play-by-play on the all talk voice chat because there's a bunch of us in this game.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm And everyone's like, how's the war going rim?
Speaker 0: And I'm like, I've got Humber down to half health.
Speaker 0: I got Humber down to a quarter health.
Speaker 0: Scott Johnson out of nowhere declares war Marches in and takes Humber.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So now Scott Johnson has Humber.
Speaker 1: Humbert's hot and Hans is you tonic.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah kinda sucks in our world.
Speaker 0: It's mostly in the desert, right?
Speaker 0: He considered raising it.
Speaker 0: So now Scott Johnson has it.
Speaker 0: So, of course, I have to declare war on Scott Johnson.
Speaker 1: I thought you meant the rows like the real world.
Speaker 1: I was like what?
Speaker 1: Humbert is not in the desert.
Speaker 0: So I declare war on Scott Johnson.
Speaker 0: we fight a little bit and now we gotta back up a little bit like eight turns prior.
Speaker 0: I proposed peace To link eg as a show of good faith because I was gonna turn my fucking army around on Scott Johnson Mm-hmm and and just end the wars.
Speaker 1: We were thinking of ganging up on you wisely But I don't vote for him to win the vote.
Speaker 1: who wins game.
Speaker 0: So I yeah I'll tell you who we actually voted for to win.
Speaker 1: I had Johnson.
Speaker 0: Scott Johnson gives it to me to end our war Partly because he realized it sucks.
Speaker 0: He was like, I'm out.
Speaker 0: It's cost more to have it than yeah I want it cuz it's next to my capital.
Speaker 1: So just expand it and move it.
Speaker 0: So I have it but it's a little tenuous cuz I have my army marching over to like secure it and like fill it Out and then link eg gets a bunch of guys near it attacks it suddenly and takes it from me no big deal like I'm literally surrounded with my catapults and Then accepts the peace overture that I didn't realize you could rescind.
Speaker 0: and we're at guaranteed peace for ten turns.
Speaker 1: Oh So clever.
Speaker 0: that was so beautiful It was.
Speaker 0: it was the thing to see.
Speaker 0: so so this these wars are ongoing in Foxton for a while.
Speaker 1: Why did you rescind your piece?
Speaker 0: I didn't know you could.
Speaker 0: I Did not when he was like what the fuck just happened to Hamburg and I hear him in the voice chat just laughing.
Speaker 1: He knows he knows the game better than you.
Speaker 0: so meanwhile We're all on one continent except for cold guy and Pegu.
Speaker 0: They're alone on the other continent.
Speaker 0: cold guys score has just been steadily rising faster than all of us and We're kind of waiting for the black ships to come over and fuck up our continent.
Speaker 1: So Pegu is not having a good time.
Speaker 0: Thank you is not doing so well over there.
Speaker 0: So Anyone in my continent We need to present a unified front against cold guys.
Speaker 0: Expected foreign aggression with his superior technology boats.
Speaker 1: So Anti-boat weaponry.
Speaker 0: I really need Hamburg.
Speaker 0: So and all the city-states so I can lead that charge.
Speaker 0: I need you guys to help.
Speaker 1: you can lead the charge.
Speaker 1: other words vote for him to win because if he leads your side of The world and then you beat the other side of the world is the only threat to him then he wins.
Speaker 0: nothing wrong with.
Speaker 1: You should vote for a different leader on your side of the world because that's who's going to win the game Assuming that you can even Pretty fucking ahead.
Speaker 0: We're gonna have.
Speaker 1: you guys are gonna have like trucks.
Speaker 1: You know, we invented the truck and I guess stealth bombers.
Speaker 0: But yeah took us an hour to start the game.
Speaker 1: invent radio and then what do you hear?
Speaker 0: like Rufus got his sieve 5 crash Nine times he was like guys like I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: I need to look at a computer.
Speaker 0: I know sieve 5 just like disconnected him from the game for like no reason.
Speaker 0: other people got disconnected Randomly every now in the game and just the game would just be like well fuck and then we'd all go to a loading screen For like 10 minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so glad I didn't waste my time on that.
Speaker 0: It's super fun mostly because we were just hanging out in the voice chat.
Speaker 0: But seriously sieve 5s multiplayer is like it is a millimeter above the line of unplayable.
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 1: we just do the play by mails or whatever.
Speaker 0: I Want to.
Speaker 0: we'll see.
Speaker 0: I kind of like hanging out.
Speaker 1: I got time for that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 0: We'll see things of the day.
Speaker 0: Just watch this video just to see what the deal is with this.
Speaker 0: There's a game an ancient game.
Speaker 0: in the year 1994 epic mega games released a game called one must fall.
Speaker 1: 2090 talked about this on a recent geek night.
Speaker 0: We've talked about it a lot But we haven't really gone into detail.
Speaker 0: Watch this video.
Speaker 0: this game has some of the greatest music of its era and it's interesting because Scott and I love this game yet.
Speaker 0: It does the kinds of things that we typically say are shit in games.
Speaker 1: Well, it's a fighting game, but as RPG elements.
Speaker 1: So imagine if like my Ryu has a leveled up fireball, so it doesn't matter how good I am at the game I just beat you cuz my reuse level 100.
Speaker 0: Yep, it goes to show that when we complain about like statefulness or all these things in games It's not because any of these concepts are universally bad.
Speaker 0: It's just that they're applied poorly.
Speaker 0: This is a game that does many of the things that we think are bad in most games.
Speaker 0: It does them well, and as a result, it was a good game.
Speaker 0: However, it is not a good fighting game by the modern definition of fighting game Good music and cool robots.
Speaker 0: It's also the kind of I have a chance at.
Speaker 1: So here's another game is it?
Speaker 1: apparently this game existed called Matrix path of neo which is some sort of matrix based like third-person walk-around action game.
Speaker 1: that based Basically retells the three matrix movies one two three, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you play as neo doing whatever and it's not a very good game.
Speaker 1: I guess it could be worse, but it's not good.
Speaker 1: The interesting thing about this game is that it's got so much videos in it right and like the Wachowski brothers actually worked on this game directed it
Speaker 0: like they're in it
Speaker 1: like it was a movie and They changed the ending because the ending of the third matrix movie while also bad as a movie would even be worse as a video game.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: So the ending of the video game is completely different and incredible.
Speaker 1: and his YouTube video where you can watch it without having to Acquire or play this horrible game spoilers.
Speaker 0: Also, I guess that are we pirating the game?
Speaker 0: No, no the book club book is a canticle for Lebowitz.
Speaker 0: I'm on my fifth novel I'm beginning that I've read since I finished it waiting for Scott to finish it.
Speaker 1: I haven't read any books.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm doing up the stuff.
Speaker 0: We were at Kinetic on video and stuff is coming as you.
Speaker 0: if you follow me on Twitter You might have seen that we did something that other cons just don't fuck.
Speaker 1: I don't think any con has ever done what we're doing.
Speaker 0: We publish the detailed stats of who is how many people were in panel rooms for the entire con?
Speaker 0: Like the half-hour by half-hour breakdown?
Speaker 0: mmm as soon as I predict all the internal notes We have in the full stats.
Speaker 0: I'm publishing it all.
Speaker 1: so how many people went to each individual panel?
Speaker 0: yup exact numbers Room capacities everything.
Speaker 1: well that might you know.
Speaker 1: you aren't some guests gonna get upset when we Publish the fact that like 20 people went to the panel only 10 people came to our 8 in the morning.
Speaker 0: Why no one will game with you panel that's true.
Speaker 0: yet We filled the room for our anime panel.
Speaker 1: when was that?
Speaker 0: uh one two I forget.
Speaker 1: Kinetic ons crowd is anime.
Speaker 0: what was very interesting is that there we had so few anime submissions.
Speaker 0: yet the anime panels We did schedule were pretty much universally some of the most popular shit We had.
Speaker 0: yeah But also this data was crucial because multiple people complained that the panels they wanted to get into were full And I could look at the stats and tell them actually there are more than a hundred seats free.
Speaker 0: you could have just walked in At any point.
Speaker 1: you didn't need to wait in line for that panel.
Speaker 1: And you know I tell people you don't do wait in line for this.
Speaker 1: just show up and walk in unless you want to sit In the front you don't need to do that.
Speaker 0: more important We have learned that a majority of the people who say they've tried to go to a panel, but it was full were lying Lying.
Speaker 0: they said a panel was full.
Speaker 1: that was objectively not full unless our panel staff were lying.
Speaker 1: No, they were not clickers.
Speaker 1: They weren't lying.
Speaker 0: yep one guy was like Oh, I saw someone with a clicker count in line and assumed that I wasn't gonna get in.
Speaker 0: it's like Why would you assume that?
Speaker 0: Like I was the clicker walked past you and kept clicking.
Speaker 1: people are just really bad.
Speaker 1: a lot of people complain about lines because they Know nothing about lines.
Speaker 1: they see a line and they're like though that lines too long and never gonna get in.
Speaker 1: it's like yeah That line goes all the way down the hallway.
Speaker 1: That's like 200 people.
Speaker 1: that room has four or five hundred seats.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: there were these home stocks in line to get into one of the much the very large rooms and I'm walking down the line counting and This kid and his and all his friends are like we're not gonna get in are we?
Speaker 0: hey hey Do you that?
Speaker 0: are we gonna make it and I look down the line?
Speaker 0: I'm like there's like 40 people in front of you.
Speaker 0: kid This room seats 400 and he was like dumbstruck one that there were so few people in that line.
Speaker 0: yep So yeah kinetic on fucking awesome, but next count for us is packs.
Speaker 1: I'm actually I gotta tell the story.
Speaker 1: so there's some people waiting for a panel way early in advance 90 minutes to an hour two hours in advance why?
Speaker 1: and there's like ten of them and it's a gigantic room and I know 100% it's not gonna fill that they could just walk right and I go to them and I'm like Why are you guys waiting here?
Speaker 1: You could just go enjoy the con and come back.
Speaker 1: I guarantee you will get in this room.
Speaker 1: I swear.
Speaker 1: and they were like no Kind of want to wait in line.
Speaker 1: one guy had his 3ds And he's just like I'd either be playing this 3ds here somewhere else, so what difference does it make?
Speaker 1: yeah, and I'm like Seriously, it's like you paid to get to this con and all you want to do is sit around and play your 3ds That you could do at home.
Speaker 1: You don't want it.
Speaker 0: We do that for the omega-thon finale every year at PAX.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if we walk right in just at the end we won't get near the front or anything.
Speaker 0: yeah I said you actually we always go up and sit in the fucking balcony anyway.
Speaker 1: well But it's the point is it's like You know.
Speaker 1: I said if you don't actually care about being in the front Then you could just walk right in.
Speaker 1: true true, but I cared about being actually.
Speaker 0: I'm just I don't trust anyone, and I'm afraid I'm not gonna get it.
Speaker 0: I've never missed an omega-thon.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: I miss one I know and I missed the ones in 07 oh six oh five.
Speaker 0: I got to watch the cornhole one from backstage And it's I watched the Cornell one from right near the cornhole.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or no I saw a bunch of people in Williamsburg playing cornhole.
Speaker 0: Oh Colonels not that fun, but it's not unfun.
Speaker 1: Listen you could do worse than cornhole, but you can also do better.
Speaker 0: You know what worse would be?
Speaker 0: horseshoes?
Speaker 0: Yeah, better.
Speaker 1: better would be bad men.
Speaker 0: ah bocce Bocce's way better.
Speaker 0: Shuffleboard's alright.
Speaker 0: Curling.
Speaker 1: Curling sucks.
Speaker 0: Curling's awesome.
Speaker 0: Anyway anyway, so a while ago I talked on geek nights about Ingress because you know I had Android and I'm kind of trying to do all the Google stuff, so I played it.
Speaker 0: I did it like a preview review, but Scott couldn't play it.
Speaker 0: Emily couldn't play it cuz iPhone and now it's on iOS.
Speaker 0: Everyone can play it and as a smartphone it as I said before and Scott will concur.
Speaker 0: now He's been playing it.
Speaker 0: it is if I had to give it a genre.
Speaker 0: It's in that like ARG space But it's pretty much a multiplayer versus candy box.
Speaker 0: It is candy box in the sense that You are better at it if you click more within it like just do more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's.
Speaker 1: no there's no real skill.
Speaker 1: There's some strategies, but they're obvious.
Speaker 1: But most of the game is just.
Speaker 1: you will be able to do better shit if you spend more time playing this game.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean I'm level seven and I got that almost level four.
Speaker 0: so I got to level six Just by five just by kind of like idly playing like at work like I just heck stuff.
Speaker 1: Are there nodes like you can reach from your office port?
Speaker 1: Yes Yeah, I can't.
Speaker 1: I have to like move around a little bit to get hit some.
Speaker 1: I can hit three portals pretty reliably from my Office like there's a bunch near my house, and there's a bunch near my work.
Speaker 1: But I actually like go outside and walk around a little bit.
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 0: So if I walk around I can hit like 30 portals in about five minutes.
Speaker 1: I can hit like maybe 10.
Speaker 0: East City Hall Park is a hive and it'll be all of late's.
Speaker 0: blue green blue green Like day by day.
Speaker 1: if I take the subway to work I can hit so many portals just riding the subway above ground.
Speaker 1: And if I go walking around work at lunch I can hit a ton of freaking portals.
Speaker 1: the most portal if I bike to work I can't.
Speaker 1: I could hit probably a zillion, but the problem is I can't really do it while I'm biking.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's the one thing cuz I'd and I also don't want to stop biking like when I go home like I don't hold my phone Bike slowly stop at every portal.
Speaker 1: fuck that.
Speaker 0: yeah I'm like there's a really good high-level portal at the base of the Williamsburg Bridge that I captured at one point While I was waiting for Emily like I fucked that thing up blew my whole load on it.
Speaker 0: But the most I ever hacked at once was when I was taking a cab in London to the airport from my hotel.
Speaker 0: I just had it open and I just hacked everything I passed.
Speaker 0: I hacked like a hundred portals.
Speaker 0: I Had so much shit.
Speaker 1: I have a lot of shit because I mostly what I do riding when I rode the subway and I'll probably ride tomorrow cuz it's Gonna rain.
Speaker 0: a lot of shit Scott.
Speaker 0: I have like 300 level one resonators.
Speaker 1: I have like a hundred.
Speaker 1: huh.
Speaker 1: I had like in the like even the level three resonators the ones I can use.
Speaker 1: I like.
Speaker 0: pity thing is I got a ton of level aids that I can't use mmm.
Speaker 1: I don't have anything as level eight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know they'll talk about that.
Speaker 1: They only give you something that's one level higher than you because that way when you level up you have stuff to use.
Speaker 1: yeah Which is brilliant yeah, but they don't let you get like.
Speaker 1: I'm level three.
Speaker 1: I can't get level five stuff, which I might give to you.
Speaker 0: yeah, but again It's brilliant game design like this little bit.
Speaker 0: So the way the game works in a general sense is that you have an Android phone or an iPhone?
Speaker 0: You can walk around like it's GPS enabled and there's portals on shit like.
Speaker 1: there's just a portal Map of the real world and there's portals in the real world and they're actually.
Speaker 1: each portal is attached to a physical object in the real world like murals or Post offices the fire alarm thingies on the street near me.
Speaker 1: those are all portals Statues in the park.
Speaker 0: pretty much every work of art in City Hall Park is there.
Speaker 1: yeah There's a zipcar that has the portal on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that might be a paid advertisement.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: no I've added portals for weird stuff like that.
Speaker 1: anyway has a zipcar logo in the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can do that all right.
Speaker 0: So uh you go.
Speaker 0: if you if you're physically next to a portal You've got to be really close, then you can hack it and get items out of it and get XP.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter if it's good friendly or neutral.
Speaker 0: now if it's a good portal Green means good.
Speaker 1: if you're not in the green team go fuck yourself.
Speaker 1: Yeah Let's talk about.
Speaker 1: let's talk about the story Let's do a little cuz.
Speaker 1: I don't give a shit about the lore But there's the tiniest bit of lore is when you turn the thing on for the first time it says Which team do you want to be?
Speaker 1: and it's a permanent one-time decision?
Speaker 0: And it gives you a little bit of info about like the vague idea that both are Fighting for right the blue team the shit team right is the rebellion and the green team.
Speaker 1: the enlightened are the smart good people.
Speaker 1: The smart good people are like Technology is awesome.
Speaker 0: a little bit further so the plot is that there's so you know the golden compass dust.
Speaker 0: yep Dust is falling on earth.
Speaker 0: spice Dust spice is falling on earth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's coming out of these portals that are just appearing everywhere.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: so the green people the smart people say wow this dust is powerful and makes humans who use it powerful.
Speaker 0: Let's use this to evolve humanity to the next level of awesome powerful existence and be awesome forever.
Speaker 1: How is that not the greatest and in totally in line?
Speaker 1: Philosophies of geek nights.
Speaker 0: the blue team is like human exceptionalism.
Speaker 0: don't evolve.
Speaker 0: Avoid this scary shit from space fight it off maintain our life.
Speaker 1: This is why we're going to use our awesome powers and just kill everyone in the blue team.
Speaker 0: yep pretty much so You get you join a team and then if a portal is oh by the way the evil blue team is outnumbering the green team.
Speaker 0: Oh, we flipped it back.
Speaker 0: Just recently.
Speaker 0: It's it's a pretty close fight right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's fuck him in the ass.
Speaker 0: So basically if you if a portal is unclaimed you can put resonators around it in the real world to claim it And if you get eight port resonators around it then it's like fully loaded and then Resonators have levels and the average of all the all the resonator levels that you've got in a fully loaded portal Determine the portals level.
Speaker 0: the higher level the portal the more energy It's collected and got the further you can make links from it to like.
Speaker 0: you can make miles miles miles away links But you don't really want to.
Speaker 1: you know I mean in New York you don't need to.
Speaker 1: it's got her to make.
Speaker 1: is the idea You want to link portals together?
Speaker 1: is you capture them for your team and two portals are captured for your team And they're fully loaded with resonators.
Speaker 1: you can link them together, and if you make a triangle between three You know portals full of resonators that triangle fills together and becomes a field.
Speaker 1: So the best thing to do is the game doesn't care how big the field is it just cares that it's a field and the field Unit field you're.
Speaker 0: basically you bring the brains of the humans who are not Enlightened enough to realize this war is happening in the lore.
Speaker 0: you basically Augment their brain.
Speaker 0: so you have sort of like your faction sort of controls the collected mental energy of the people Under that based on a statistical model of actual population.
Speaker 0: so a tiny field like in Manhattan is a lot of points.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and so those MU's the mind units.
Speaker 1: those are the actual points.
Speaker 1: you that score for your team, right?
Speaker 1: That's the real points.
Speaker 1: That's the victory points in this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: so when you look at the chart That shows blue slightly edging out green.
Speaker 1: That's mind unit points.
Speaker 1: It's counting right.
Speaker 1: so there you go.
Speaker 0: Yep, so you make these fields.
Speaker 0: your goal is basically to control a majority of Earth's population Or your faction And set up portals.
Speaker 0: they do like air just things all over the world.
Speaker 0: you should see.
Speaker 0: I actually I got into a huge war.
Speaker 0: I still have.
Speaker 0: I had a portal that I took over in Turkey and I eventually lost it.
Speaker 0: But my faction still hold nadu, and I got the key so I can check out about it every now And then mmm every time I go back there.
Speaker 0: I fuck it up.
Speaker 0: Yeah And then you can attack portals too, so if a portals on the enemy team you can hack it But you can also attack it and if you destroy the resonators you can take down its links Take it down completely reclaim it for your own team and The attacks are also physical.
Speaker 0: you gotta physically go find that fucking portal and attack it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, attacking it kind of sucks depending on the weapons you have.
Speaker 1: I think the only weapons I've seen are X MPs which are sort of these radius attacks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and when you use them It's like slow, and it takes a lot of energy it takes a lot of time, and they're not very strong.
Speaker 0: Yeah, wait.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so my high level ones like if I use a level 7 X MP I'll take out like in one shot every level one resonator within like 500 meters.
Speaker 1: oh they have a bigger radius.
Speaker 0: the higher level ones have bigger radius and do way more damage.
Speaker 1: I didn't know they bigger radius
Speaker 0: Can
Speaker 1: fuck some shit up and then as these ultra strikes which are like nukes and they're harder to get I only have a few They
Speaker 0: they hit a tiny area devastatingly
Speaker 1: yeah, but it's like if you want to take out one portal just use the ultra strike.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like go over to one individual level 8 resonator and just drop two ultra strikes on it can probably take it out.
Speaker 1: So the other thing is that you know when you're capturing a portal putting resonators on it You can put these mods on there.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like shields and heat sinks and I like it.
Speaker 0: the turrets.
Speaker 1: the turrets are good because the turret does.
Speaker 1: is anyone tries to fuck up The portal or hack it and it's an enemy the turret will fuck them up and drain their energy So that it's harder for them to attack it.
Speaker 1: You know constantly because they'll basically run out of their energy They need to attack with.
Speaker 0: yeah We held out as in portals near City Hall for a while because there were three portals like right next to each other like as Close as they can be and all of them had two turrets and two of those like attack enhancer items on them.
Speaker 0: So if you walked over there and you were blue and you hacked anything it was just like And it also.
Speaker 1: the shields are also really strong.
Speaker 1: Yeah They make it really hard for anyone to attack it You know and gives you plenty of time to go over and fix it.
Speaker 1: cuz like they'll run out of weapons and energy before they Kill it and the shield holds on and the next day you come and recharge it and put the shields back.
Speaker 0: so this game is basically a hundred percent replaced.
Speaker 0: the Nintendo 3ds friend Street pass whatever candy box.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah screw that.
Speaker 0: This is my soul candy box because for a candy box game.
Speaker 0: It's perfect.
Speaker 0: Just hey, I'm bored.
Speaker 0: I wonder if there's a portal near here.
Speaker 1: The other thing is that it's team candy box, right?
Speaker 1: You could go and have a fun act.
Speaker 1: You could actually use this candy box to support things that are not just stupid candy box.
Speaker 1: For example, you could say hey everyone Let's all of us have this game.
Speaker 1: Let's go around the neighborhood and find portals and you'll discover things in your neighborhood.
Speaker 1: You didn't know they were there.
Speaker 0: You know how many streets I've biked or walked down just to go to a portal and hack it that I never in my life Would have gone down Otherwise.
Speaker 1: there are like there's an owl statue in a park that I didn't know was there but I had a portal on it.
Speaker 1: So I found it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Also people like the other day I was biking right and I stopped at a stoplight and I looked at my right and there's a guy in a car and he's Cleared.
Speaker 0: him and his friend both have it open on their phones.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Were they on the green team?
Speaker 0: So I look and they're green.
Speaker 0: so I tap on the window and the guy looks like what the fuck cuz it's New York You don't talk to people and I hold up my phone and he's like, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Let's go green.
Speaker 1: But like if you get a team of people together Right, you can.
Speaker 1: you get eight level eight dudes together and you go somewhere.
Speaker 1: you can fuck shit up big-time all together.
Speaker 1: Because what you can do is you can all use your weapons at once and destroy a portal really fast.
Speaker 0: One and two.
Speaker 1: you can all put and a level eight resonator on the portal together and then make a max level portal.
Speaker 0: Because the way it works is like I can put any number of level ones on a portal but higher level ones One person can only put like one level eight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're level eight and you go to a portal and you try to fill it up with resonators all by yourself It's only gonna let you put like one level eight like a couple.
Speaker 0: level seven five four four three Like I can't like.
Speaker 0: I'm getting down to my low levels real quick, right?
Speaker 1: But if you have eight level eight people you can all put one level eight resonator and make a ridiculously strong portal No one can mess with easily.
Speaker 0: Put four of the ultra rare 60 defense shields up on that shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like well We've got this.
Speaker 1: and then you all since you all have a whole bunch of portal keys You can all send links out of that thing like crazy, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, someone might be lacking the energy or whatever.
Speaker 1: So if you're all together you can actually, you know, make some friends and go around fucking shit up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the game is like a built-in chat that actually works like you can chat with the enemy and message each other.
Speaker 0: There's a secure chat just for your faction.
Speaker 0: There's only two factions right now But wouldn't be surprised if something weird happens at some point because apparently You're saying they're gonna add a red team?
Speaker 1: Fuck you red team.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying Green team for life.
Speaker 0: The game's had a bunch of events and weird shit that I actually never really Interacted with and there's a whole bunch of lore and crap in there that I've been mostly ignoring.
Speaker 1: Don't give a shit about lore.
Speaker 1: All they care about is green team.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: level 8 used to be the highest level but they just recently added eight more levels that do weird shit.
Speaker 0: I've seen people who have clearly done things that as far as I know break the rules, right?
Speaker 1: There's a dude in Astoria named Atrocitus and I've run into that fucker.
Speaker 1: That guy is the most evil blue team guy.
Speaker 1: if I and like I'm I'm like worried about this game.
Speaker 1: Like if I'm going around Astoria and I'm you know, biking around hacking and I see this dude Should I beat him up just take his phone?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: should I take his phone throw it on the ground and run away?
Speaker 1: It's like I feel like I should.
Speaker 0: so I've seen.
Speaker 1: I'm also afraid so it might do that to me.
Speaker 0: I've seen in the community reports actually of in some especially in college towns.
Speaker 0: Like if a college is mostly blue or mostly green The people who are in that faction Kind of go like prison Stanford prison study on each other and get really Into the game in a bad way.
Speaker 0: Like I've seen some reports of that happening, which is understandable.
Speaker 0: Like I can see why people I mean people do that about sports ball.
Speaker 1: I know I don't think I would do.
Speaker 1: it's like imagine if we have a group of eight people we go around To capturing portals and we get the email that says your portal has been attacked.
Speaker 1: Like we just captured that portal.
Speaker 1: we turn around and there's someone there and there's eight of us and yeah one blue team guy Just stand next to each other.
Speaker 1: What are we gonna do?
Speaker 0: You know you do?
Speaker 0: you have someone go over and talk to them like hey, what's up?
Speaker 0: Like blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: act like they're on their faction to distract them.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Meanwhile, you just fuck the portal back up in the right direction take their phone and throw it in the street.
Speaker 0: Yeah This is probably.
Speaker 0: I mean honestly a lot of people have tried to make games in this ARG space.
Speaker 0: We're like there's a game overlaid on the real world and people playing the game see it Like I remember seeing so many of these booths at like old paxes and other conventions.
Speaker 0: It's probably the best one anyone's ever made.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Not great, but I'm still playing it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like Scott's playing it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's a good thing to get into because it's it's fun It's social you meet people it forces teamwork.
Speaker 0: And I've actually met a lot of people playing this game because you see you know, we've never met anyone playing candy box or cookie Clicker.
Speaker 1: Nope And you don't even really meet people doing Street pass, right?
Speaker 1: You sort of say you'll see people on Street pass.
Speaker 0: Street passes Hey a Person you will never meet in your entire life who is similar and cool because you don't need to do anything with the person you Meet on the street pass, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you just get there me and it's like you don't need to interact with them in real life in any way.
Speaker 1: and I guess Nintendo doesn't want you to either because you might be a child predator and the 3ds is probably owned by a child.
Speaker 1: But with this it's like no you.
Speaker 1: if you see people in your area like capturing portals and they're on your team It's like you got to find them so you can you know, it's like hey, you know, do you have energies?
Speaker 1: I need some energies or hey you got any weapons.
Speaker 0: It also gives fun content portal key for this.
Speaker 1: I want to make a field here.
Speaker 0: months ago katsu and a bunch of us we went out just to go get dinner and drinks like after work and I pull out my phone and Open ingress for a second.
Speaker 0: and a new guy who we didn't really know each other yet when I caught his friends It's like ingress and I was like, yep, and I kind of pull my phone back and he's like And there's this dance of like.
Speaker 1: are you on the blue team?
Speaker 0: Yep, and then suddenly I was like.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna work on my portal here and he looks and then he sees the portal under attack and he was blue and then We just were like, ah, I'm like spamming XMPs.
Speaker 0: He's trying to.
Speaker 1: why didn't you take his phone and like put it in his drink?
Speaker 0: But I'd recommend I've got a bunch of invites.
Speaker 0: if you guys want invites like I don't need invites You can just join this thing really?
Speaker 0: Yeah Because you need an invites for a long time now.
Speaker 1: you can just join now if you have a iPhone or Android or ever just join it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so guys join it.
Speaker 0: join the green team And you know what?
Speaker 0: We're actually kind of playing it.
Speaker 0: so we should meet at a convention like PAX and then all go out on a hunting expedition.
Speaker 1: We should find we should see if we can find on the internet like PAX and lighten meetup and go to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually, you know people do the button trading.
Speaker 0: Maybe this is it.
Speaker 0: We should make a green team button.
Speaker 1: Oh Little enlightened logo night sponsor in New York City.
Speaker 1: They keep this.
Speaker 1: someone keeps messaging all of New York City.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, there's like email NYC dot enlightened at gmail.com and it's like I feel like I should email it.
Speaker 1: watch.
Speaker 0: That's a like year-long running honeypot scam.
Speaker 0: It could be blue team.
Speaker 1: It could be but You know, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.