Speaker 0: It's Wednesday October 8th 2014.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight anime.
Speaker 0: We never watched or reviewed.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So for all my travels.
Speaker 0: I was actually in Vegas over the weekend, and I'd never been to Vegas before okay, so by expectation of Vegas was basically based on How I'd seen it portrayed in the media and based on other people I noted gone there, which pretty much was exemplified by the old Vegas strip.
Speaker 0: And the new Vegas strip is way different, and I have to say and I'm not going to review Las Vegas right here I was surprised at how enjoyable a trip to Vegas actually was.
Speaker 0: yeah Have you been there?
Speaker 1: no, so okay, but my betray my expectation was not based on incredibly old media.
Speaker 1: Everything's really fancy And really touristy, but there's you know tons of stuff to do all over the place not just gambling even though There is gambling everywhere, and you can just sort of you know have a good time if you spend money.
Speaker 1: And there's lots of shows and foods.
Speaker 0: And I would like in the new strip because what they've done is they basically like along the main drag You can't actually even get to the street.
Speaker 0: They sort of built up these like overpasses and pathways connecting everything So that you're basically like being on a giant cruise ship except just floating in the sand instead in the water.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the cool thing though.
Speaker 0: Is that the airport is?
Speaker 0: literally You could walk from the airport to most of the hotels But for the fact that you're not allowed to walk out of the airport as far as I can tell Remember, it's a desert right.
Speaker 1: so they just put everything right up on top of each other because we're all you know.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, you say that not like there's any it's not like you know.
Speaker 1: say in New York where there's a geography issue.
Speaker 0: Well it's got.
Speaker 0: you say that but most Airports in desert cities other than Vegas are not literally downtown next to all the hotels.
Speaker 1: most desert cities are not just tourist Destinations and nothing else.
Speaker 0: yeah, there are apparently people who live there But was funny there are Emily.
Speaker 0: I went to her for a run in the morning And we're running going out, and we tried to get off the strip Just like run outside of like the crowd.
Speaker 0: there was almost no way to get off the strip.
Speaker 0: So we finally get off and then we ran and then there was no way back by her hotel to get back on the strip.
Speaker 0: We were like behind Las Vegas.
Speaker 0: It was like being in an alley next to an amusement park with no actual way to get into the amusement park Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was a super good time and I saw Penn and Teller.
Speaker 0: and the thing I can say about Penn tellers.
Speaker 0: they put on the same good old show that they've always done and all their lives, but They're in the Rio which is kind of like a little bit away from the strip.
Speaker 0: the Rio is a shithole Is it?
Speaker 1: I thought it was just a fancy casino Are you kidding?
Speaker 0: No the Rio is like really.
Speaker 0: the Rio felt like Atlantic City.
Speaker 0: the Rio was dark Smoky dank.
Speaker 0: there are strippers dancing like out, and it was just really unclassy.
Speaker 0: the food over there was garbage.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm it's interesting.
Speaker 0: so we and well you know Penn and Teller ended, and they were like oh we'll just take a cab back because it's a really long walk to get back to the strip and Pretty much everyone who came to see Penn and Teller Took a cab there and the line for cabs was like over a hundred people deep.
Speaker 0: so we walked back.
Speaker 0: so uh Bear that in mind if you're gonna go to Vegas you want to see Penn and Teller don't actually stay at the Rio cuz it's kind of a shithole Unless you like to sit in front of a penny slot smoking and then have some mediocre American bar and grill food.
Speaker 0: All right, okay, all right captain enthusiasm.
Speaker 1: What's your thing about casino hotels?
Speaker 1: So in news important news important news at work right.
Speaker 1: we were discussing a few weeks ago whether or not Saturday morning cartoons still existed and No one was quite sure.
Speaker 0: cuz no one watches television I just read an article that said they don't exist anymore.
Speaker 1: in fact that is my news Starting like a few days ago.
Speaker 1: I guess the most recent Saturday They don't exist anymore.
Speaker 1: the CW was the last broadcast network still having cartoons on Saturday morning which is pretty much just like I guess Yu-Gi-Oh and some other crap and They got rid of it and replaced it with some live-action educational garbage.
Speaker 1: That's all family type whatever.
Speaker 1: so that is the end of Saturday morning cartoons, however You know what I have a feeling.
Speaker 0: if I were a kid today I would not watch Saturday morning cartoons on TV.
Speaker 0: I would watch Saturday morning YouTube cartoons sure.
Speaker 1: well I mean you watch YouTube whenever you want.
Speaker 1: That's part of the reason.
Speaker 0: They're dead yeah, but I would get up in the morning Saturday.
Speaker 1: Of course you know I mean I think it's a very good thing that you can watch cartoons not on Saturday morning.
Speaker 1: You just watch them whenever you want which is great.
Speaker 1: obviously There's no need to have force you to watch them on Saturday morning.
Speaker 1: It's also great You don't have to watch them with horrible ads all Saturday morning.
Speaker 1: It's actually part of the reason they died.
Speaker 1: is an FCC rule changed and limited the amount of kid ads you could put during kid Shows?
Speaker 1: yeah, so it wasn't very profitable to have these Saturday morning cartoons anymore.
Speaker 1: We don't regulate well how many ads super packs can put out there sure, but the one thing That's bothersome about the lat the death of Saturday morning cartoons.
Speaker 1: Is that you know?
Speaker 1: I guess this has been.
Speaker 1: this isn't new.
Speaker 1: This has been true for decades like since they've been dying which I guess is they're really only a big thing in the 60s 70s And 80s.
Speaker 1: in the 90s like NBC already quit you know and it was only like Fox and CW only the ones that held out.
Speaker 0: No, it's interesting cuz even by the 90s I didn't really watch cart.
Speaker 0: the only cartoons that watch on TV in the 90s were primetime Yep, Nickelodeon cartoon anyway, or or they were right after school Because it was some anime shirt tsunami?
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway.
Speaker 1: But the thing when Saturday morning cartoons existed in the heyday 60s 70s 80s right you had CBS NBC Fox ABC.
Speaker 1: if four networks basically Creating every single week Each one of them had like at least six seven shows.
Speaker 0: Remember guys there were not one, but two different Sonic the Hedgehog cartoons.
Speaker 1: that was later, but so six seven shows.
Speaker 1: I guess Fox didn't exist for until the 80s, but Six seven shows times three.
Speaker 1: that's like 21 new episodes 20 minute episodes of cartoons Every week.
Speaker 1: that was a lot of animation production quantity even if not all of it was quality Right.
Speaker 1: so now there are some amazing animations being created all the time.
Speaker 1: But you know even if you add up things that are on the edge, so you know ponies Adventure time if you push it all the way down to everything you can think of like the regular show Gravity Falls There are not 21 new episodes of cartoons in the United States.
Speaker 0: I would argue that the average quality per minute of animation is much higher.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not saying True I mean he man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he man.
Speaker 1: you are correct, but that is not to say that all Saturday morning cartoons were garbage either.
Speaker 1: You know you a little Muppet baby going on in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my baby is the one thing that you can't get legally.
Speaker 1: yeah, pretty much any Looney Tunes or You know All kinds of good stuff x-men fox Ninja Turtles.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what we need because it's interesting.
Speaker 0: I see the like the cartoon.
Speaker 0: I'm watching right now.
Speaker 0: That's new that we haven't really talked on.
Speaker 0: the show is the amazing adventures of gumball and it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not like ponies like this.
Speaker 0: Is the show pretty much aimed at kids?
Speaker 0: it's the kind of thing that you'd watch on a Saturday morning as a cartoon and What's interesting is that one?
Speaker 0: It's a lot more adult than you would expect.
Speaker 0: But I think that might just be a product.
Speaker 0: the fact that the last time I watched Saturday morning cartoons as a thing They were the most possible blend you could have For various cultural reasons.
Speaker 0: I mean remember even primetime The Simpsons was controversial When it aired.
Speaker 1: I think the thing is anyone who was alive in the Saturday morning cartoon era, right?
Speaker 1: You didn't have Netflix.
Speaker 1: He didn't have whatever.
Speaker 1: so there were certain cartoons that were syndicated.
Speaker 1: Those are the ones that were on.
Speaker 1: we got home from school.
Speaker 1: Yep, you could see them all the time.
Speaker 1: Disney afternoon was every fucking day.
Speaker 1: DuckTales, right?
Speaker 1: You know Batman animated series.
Speaker 1: every day you can watch Batman the animated series no problem.
Speaker 0: Usually you'd see the same episode just because that's how it all right.
Speaker 1: It's like there were a lot of shows.
Speaker 1: you would see these shows every day.
Speaker 1: They were they were good Most a lot of them, but it wasn't a big deal.
Speaker 1: a Saturday morning cartoon.
Speaker 1: There would be a new episode of it on Saturday morning And it would not be aired at any other time ever and you wouldn't get to see that episode again For weeks and weeks and weeks and weeks and weeks because there would be new episodes And there wouldn't be a rerun.
Speaker 1: and it was Saturday morning only in this one time.
Speaker 1: It's the only time you could see it unless you recorded it with your VCR.
Speaker 1: and it's not like.
Speaker 1: they sold Saturday morning cartoons on VHS tape that often and that was expensive.
Speaker 1: and So it was like a big deal to watch a Saturday morning cartoon.
Speaker 1: Yeah at that time Like I watched Fox x-men.
Speaker 1: I watched every single episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah up until I missed it at some point.
Speaker 0: Well, I remember the day.
Speaker 0: that was multiple years.
Speaker 1: I saw every single new episode times.
Speaker 0: I'd miss episodes because like oh we're going to Disney World or whatever like.
Speaker 0: I remember those weekends like ah, I miss the cartoons.
Speaker 0: Yeah Though there's such a part of like pop culture consciousness Even though they haven't really existed like they used to for a long time like they're relatively short.
Speaker 1: I mean there was you know decades anyone who grew up in the 60s 70s 80s 30 years worth of people growing up also early 90s ish Alright, so 40 years of people growing up the impressionable young childhood minds were slammed with cartoons Every week.
Speaker 1: at this certain time though honest that's gonna last in the rest of our lives.
Speaker 0: that memory the ads are my favorite part Because one thing about occasionally like I'll find old Saturday morning cartoons like someone has a VHS tape or something and there's ads on there.
Speaker 0: Seeing those ads today is a wonderful experience, but they're on YouTube - yeah, most of them are yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so this is kind of breaking news.
Speaker 0: I tried to find a few sources, but something I'm not gonna not gonna go too deep into this But there was an article that was an interview with a guy who was speaking at the New York Comic Con Matthew click Steen.
Speaker 1: I never heard of him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he wrote a book called slimed.
Speaker 1: Is it about Nickelodeon?
Speaker 0: Pete and Pete was all white people slimed blob.
Speaker 0: He was an author.
Speaker 0: He wrote this book.
Speaker 0: He was doing a panel.
Speaker 0: I didn't know or care about him or who he was but there's this interview with him and the interview starts out pretty normal and the guy's answering questions and Basically as the interview goes on he starts getting like more and more weird and racist.
Speaker 0: You know, it's one of those things.
Speaker 1: people who are fucked up can't hide that fact that they're fucked up.
Speaker 0: Like imagine you're talking to someone you're like hey I'm talking to Neal Adams at some point.
Speaker 1: if you talk to him long enough, you will learn about the expanding earth.
Speaker 1: Can't hold it in notice.
Speaker 0: There is no subduction.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: if you talk to us long enough, you know what you're gonna hear about Game theory maybe yeah, it's gonna come out.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk about the gays.
Speaker 0: heuristic Scott's gonna talk about dude, bro We got all right.
Speaker 1: So you talk to someone long enough the thing that they're into is gonna come out.
Speaker 1: It's even if you don't guide the conversation in that direction.
Speaker 0: So this thing just like it like it starts out as one of those things where someone says a few words that your brain says That there's no way he means it the way I think he might.
Speaker 1: might someone says something on the edge?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it could be interpreted as you know a legitimate point But it could also be crazy races.
Speaker 0: My favorite part about this isn't the guy going increasingly racist.
Speaker 0: It's the interviewer Reacting to this and basically like Getting like starting to argue with him a little bit and just not really sure what to do.
Speaker 1: I would just be like wow, you were a crazy fucking racist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so realize I'll give you a quote.
Speaker 0: This is a quote with the guys.
Speaker 1: I'm going to let everyone know this.
Speaker 1: this interview is gonna be posted everywhere and I'm your career will end.
Speaker 1: good day, sir.
Speaker 0: I Well, what's interesting is it's kind of like those people who get interviewed by the Daily Show a bad day to you horrible person But like not a good day.
Speaker 0: so the people being interviewed by the Daily Show not realize they're being made fun of.
Speaker 1: Well, there was that one with the Native Americans.
Speaker 0: Yeah That was beautiful.
Speaker 0: That was that was that was Scott Tanner and let me drink your tears.
Speaker 0: Quote.
Speaker 0: I think it's worse when they shove diversity in there.
Speaker 0: Sanjay and Craig is a really good example.
Speaker 0: That's a show by the way Has an Indian kid in it and a snake and stuff Which funnily enough is written in part by Will McRobb and Chris Viscardi from Pete & Pete.
Speaker 0: That show is awkward because and I'm quoting exactly here There's actually no reason for that character to be Indian.
Speaker 1: What reason is there for them to not be Indian?
Speaker 1: There's no reason for Pete & Pete to be white.
Speaker 0: Yes, that is an entire article.
Speaker 0: the entire interview just from that moment goes downhill.
Speaker 0: So the news is that the New York Comic Con as far as I can tell this just happened like a few minutes ago.
Speaker 0: So I'm going on.
Speaker 0: I found a few sources.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure this happened.
Speaker 0: New York Comic Con was like Yeah, your Nick nostalgia night panel is canceled.
Speaker 1: Okay, so Things move quickly.
Speaker 1: is this guy from a particular company or is he just on his own with this book?
Speaker 0: He wrote not sure I gotta do more research on him, but he wrote the book.
Speaker 1: I would a take his badge away.
Speaker 1: Right, I mean people would be like freedom of speech.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, you can say whatever he wants, but he's not coming.
Speaker 0: This is my house.
Speaker 1: This is a private convention.
Speaker 1: We can deny anyone entry for any reason.
Speaker 0: I feel like guys.
Speaker 0: Keith Apicary can't come to PAX.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just how it goes, right?
Speaker 1: So yeah, we if you find out that you're racist We're just gonna you know deny you entry because we can and we want to because we don't like racism.
Speaker 1: Oh, and by the way, if I was also in charge of New York Comic Con I would figure out whatever company he works for and whatever friends he has and deny them entry too.
Speaker 1: I'd be like your whole company can't come booth taken away.
Speaker 1: No refund Just to really dry.
Speaker 1: even if he was like working for Marvel drawing a comic.
Speaker 1: I'd be like Marvel.
Speaker 1: you can't come.
Speaker 1: I Would do that.
Speaker 1: I would go that big just to be like boom take that.
Speaker 1: what now?
Speaker 1: Maybe you shouldn't hire racist people and then every company would start checking every employee.
Speaker 1: It'd be great.
Speaker 0: Do you get a?
Speaker 0: Dora the Explorer was certainly something of a success, but there's no reason for Sanjay to be Indian at all.
Speaker 0: No one working in that shows Indian.
Speaker 0: They're all white.
Speaker 0: It's all white people.
Speaker 0: blah blah blah and The.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: that's the moment.
Speaker 1: people should only make things with white people in them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then he starts accusing it of being blackface.
Speaker 0: and then at one point the interviewer Let me find this moment is this Sanjay actor not an Indian person?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm trying to find the moment where the.
Speaker 1: is it a person pretending to be Indian?
Speaker 0: So here's what the interviewer says.
Speaker 1: after this guy goes crazy for a while Why does he stand there and let him do this just like keep embarrassing yourself.
Speaker 1: Let's get more crazy video content cuz he's gonna get mad hits of people wanting to see how horrible you are.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of issue other issues going on when you're working.
Speaker 0: the people just I wouldn't want to see.
Speaker 0: I you know I do it.
Speaker 0: why do it at all if you're gonna do it.
Speaker 0: Hey, look, there's our Indian guy.
Speaker 0: We're doing it too.
Speaker 0: We got Indian guys blah blah blah and then he's doing this rant and then the interviewer asked this question doesn't even ask the question.
Speaker 1: Let's see this interview is better than what here's.
Speaker 0: the interviewer Sanjay is voiced by an Indian American actor.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's a cartoon.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yes He just jumps right in there and The guy at one point says, uh, well, here's the great quote.
Speaker 0: I would be offended if one of the friends on Clifford the Big Red Dog had a friend who was in a wheelchair.
Speaker 0: Why I understand the idea of there's someone like me But it's necessary that the show is actually saying something Doing something with the disability if you just throw that character in there.
Speaker 0: Oh the friend just happens to be black.
Speaker 0: I feel that I'm being that it's being used.
Speaker 1: you know people just happen to be all kinds of things and they just live their lives and The thing that they are or happen to be doesn't really come up Or at least it shouldn't except for when there's people like you Time that it matters.
Speaker 0: This guy's a lot like those gamergate kids in the sense that they like.
Speaker 0: they'll say things that assume some very Very important things that are demonstrably false.
Speaker 0: Like you make a big assumption like the biggest possible assumption that you are in the year 1951. yep, that's like.
Speaker 0: that's a big assumption because that's not true Basically, well, I mean white is the default.
Speaker 1: I assume that the person interviewing me is a member of the KKK.
Speaker 1: That's a good assumption.
Speaker 1: to go on And I assume that anyone reading the media that they're creating is also a member.
Speaker 0: so I got two sources on this.
Speaker 0: So if I'd ends up that it was not cancelled I retracted.
Speaker 0: but for now good job.
Speaker 0: New York Comic Con.
Speaker 1: Yep, now the thing is would they have the balls to do it if say, you know some big-name hotshot movie industry person Who was like guest of honor did something like this.
Speaker 1: that I don't know.
Speaker 1: would they have the balls?
Speaker 0: You know, I am confident that Paxwood.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm confident that Robert Coo would kick his own keynote out.
Speaker 1: I'm confident Robert Coo would kick his own ass out.
Speaker 0: But yeah anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: It's not a video.
Speaker 0: if you want to see a video instead of my thing of the day go to College Humor.
Speaker 0: click on Something.
Speaker 0: they're all funny.
Speaker 0: So this is a quote from the anime news network forum from masa juice.
Speaker 1: What why is your thing of the day a quote?
Speaker 0: Because it's so.
Speaker 0: why did you?
Speaker 1: why did you dive into the one of the bowels of the internet to find anything?
Speaker 0: Oh, I did not dive in to find this.
Speaker 0: colony drop posted it So I just got to enjoy it without having to go in there All right.
Speaker 0: So it's like when someone else goes swimming in the poop field and comes back with a diamond and you can look at the diamond Without swimming in the poop.
Speaker 0: So like Zach Vershey, for example, my hat is off to you.
Speaker 0: You swim in a sea of effervescent poop for my amusement.
Speaker 1: All right quotes.
Speaker 0: I think that anime news network should stop making preview guides because reviewers only right there spelled wrong on opinion and most of the time they make all anime look like a waste as in my waste of time and mizzled potential viewers misled.
Speaker 0: So for all so called reviewers, I could go say go fudge yourself and then burn together with yours opinions Okay.
Speaker 1: So first of all, most anime is a waste of time and garbage.
Speaker 1: Yes So those are accurate guide.
Speaker 1: Also, let me give you a review now of an anime that has no opinion.
Speaker 1: Scott No opinion in this anime review.
Speaker 1: You ready?
Speaker 1: Gotta be objective.
Speaker 1: All right, so the anime is gonna be.
Speaker 1: let's look on the shelf.
Speaker 1: What's on the shelf there over there?
Speaker 0: The big boy golden boy.
Speaker 1: All right, here's a review of golden boy.
Speaker 1: That is no opinion in it whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Golden boy is an anime.
Speaker 1: It was made.
Speaker 1: I don't know the exact year 90s ish.
Speaker 1: I'm guessing I would say the exact year.
Speaker 0: But by looking at in retrospect I should have Randomly said the name of an anime that we both Remember more something that we know more information about without having to look it up.
Speaker 1: It has X number of episodes sailor moon sailor moon.
Speaker 0: sailor moon is 200 episodes long.
Speaker 0: It's based on a manga about magical girls, but it is significantly different from the manga in many ways.
Speaker 0: It was drawn on cells.
Speaker 1: in the story There are girls who are visited by cats given magical powers and they have to fight against dark forces to save the world From destruction, wait, wait, wait, don't it?
Speaker 0: You know, they're not necessarily all dark forces forces of Queen Beryl and others.
Speaker 0: That is technically true.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yes, okay There are transformation sequences in it.
Speaker 1: It is a magical girl show.
Speaker 1: They used color Episode.
Speaker 0: color episodes are 20-something minutes Delved in English by deke on crunchyroll right now.
Speaker 1: Pretty little crystals on crunchyroll right now.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah the other and Yeah, that's about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 1: That is an objective review.
Speaker 1: Just the spec sheet.
Speaker 1: This is if I say anything such as awesome transformation sequences or Suddenly that's opinion.
Speaker 0: So The reason I make this my thing of the day is that in the anime fandom this sentiment is So prevalent and so calm.
Speaker 1: you should make the no opinion review site and then of everything and see what people say.
Speaker 0: Well, there used to be those old reviews that were mostly reviewed like the encoding quality and whether like no that was okay.
Speaker 1: So that was specifically anime on DVD which no longer exists.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: people remember how good anime on DVD was actually really useful because it had the list of like animes coming out that When there was no sheet and whatever.
Speaker 1: but it's reviews were right They would basically reviewing the quality of the DVD and such.
Speaker 1: because up until that point You animates on VHS.
Speaker 1: It'd be like oh, this is like a third generation.
Speaker 1: You're looking at a really shitty version of this Right.
Speaker 1: So the actual quality of the anime was a big deal.
Speaker 1: It's like oh my god, you can actually see the show without a whole bunch of noise and grain.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah guys, you realize we watched the end of utenna.
Speaker 1: subtitles are readable and accurate.
Speaker 1: It's amazing.
Speaker 0: We watch VHS of the stereo.
Speaker 0: sound is actually like properly mixed and it's not some mono down mix Episode like like like the second to less of 37 or so of utenna like the episodes in that point to the end.
Speaker 0: Trackings we had sort of in tracking problems.
Speaker 0: If you don't know what I mean You're way younger than us right.
Speaker 0: and then we go to adjust the tracking and it turned out the tracking was burned in From the previous generation copy.
Speaker 1: Yep So now that no one gives a fuck about those kinds of issues anymore anime on DVD doesn't need to exist.
Speaker 1: But and it's time that was actually not a bad thing to you know At least get the information about the technology and the.
Speaker 1: you know The quality the physical quality of the media.
Speaker 0: So the reason this guy posted he has one more sentence about Trinity seven.
Speaker 0: This is why.
Speaker 1: what is Trinity seven anime?
Speaker 0: Okay I found it entertaining and fun and MC is not a wimp and that's one reason because I like it.
Speaker 0: so basically he was mad that someone else had a different opinion he had about Trinity seven and Here's where this is beautiful.
Speaker 0: He joined the anime news network forum on the 12th of March 2010 and has posted three times All of them about Trinity.
Speaker 0: this was his third post.
Speaker 0: So he was angry enough About someone having an opinion about an anime to make his third ever post in more than four years On the anime news network forum.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it is about anime fandom, but the whole How is that anything from any fandom?
Speaker 0: I don't see this specific.
Speaker 0: Don't review things.
Speaker 1: No, you don't see that in video game fandom ever.
Speaker 0: I do but not nearly as prevalent.
Speaker 1: You don't see it tweeted in your feed because you're not following those people and Also that those other phantoms.
Speaker 1: don't have the kinds of personalities in them that are trolling forums looking for hilarity and retweeting it.
Speaker 0: That may be true But it's there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel like it's more common in anime.
Speaker 1: No, it's in every fandom kind of like.
Speaker 0: how like look at look at the anti-professionals and that other side thing in anime Like don't see that nearly as much at gaming cons?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you do not not as much.
Speaker 1: I positive people like all indie gaming gray all this.
Speaker 1: your game is too Well, you know overproduced.
Speaker 1: you're your people type board.
Speaker 1: I've seen board game people make threads about games, which games are overproduced.
Speaker 1: Like st.
Speaker 1: Petersburg is overproduced.
Speaker 1: doesn't need that board.
Speaker 1: Let's go, you know wooden pieces really for serious It's a card game.
Speaker 1: make it a deck of cards.
Speaker 0: in the moment I'm going to be at PAX Australia talking about my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: All right, you have a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 1: this is a tiny thing of the day.
Speaker 1: It makes you feel bad if you own a GoPro and haven't done anything awesome with it because this kid and his dad they take the GoPro and they make an epic video so epic so amazing of Going to get groceries.
Speaker 1: so If you have a GoPro and you don't skydive or you know do crazy ridiculous dangerous shit.
Speaker 1: and you're thinking yeah That's the reason I don't have any epic videos with my GoPro's cuz I don't do any epic shit.
Speaker 1: Well, here's epic video of grocery run.
Speaker 1: So I want to see me And everyone else who has a GoPro who hasn't made epic video make epic video.
Speaker 1: Here's your example instructions.
Speaker 0: so at PAX Australia on Friday Halloween 11 a.m.
Speaker 1: Did they have Halloween in Australia?
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: Well, you must bring it to them.
Speaker 0: fruit bat theater.
Speaker 0: I will be presented an appropriate theater how to win every game and then on Saturday The first 2 p.m.
Speaker 0: Also in the fruit bat theater.
Speaker 0: I am presenting losing.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be a good time if you come.
Speaker 0: I'm very pleased that I've got two like pretty fucking primetime spots here Which means I really can't fuck this up.
Speaker 1: What's in your book club book there?
Speaker 0: I haven't decided yet.
Speaker 0: I haven't decided whether I want to punish you or whether I want to pick a book that you might enjoy.
Speaker 0: All
Speaker 1: right other meta moments tonight on the crappy and soon-to-be-dead David Letterman show is The exact opposite of crappy and soon-to-be-dead Hatsune Miku,
Speaker 0: yep,
Speaker 1: it is the clash of worlds The new replacing the old the newest possible amazing thing You know being ushered out guide the deadest oldest tree.
Speaker 0: you realize that Something like Hatsune Miku will one day replace The hosts of a late show and then will be the host of that late show for the rest of human history As long as people care.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, but at the same time The marginal cost of making that late show Drop close to zero to where you could just keep making it for free as long as there's electricity.
Speaker 1: I just think it's gonna be awesome to have the 20th century and the 21st century.
Speaker 1: Basically the 20th century is.
Speaker 1: this is like you could put this in the nerd history book as the moment the 20th century is Like.
Speaker 1: alright, goodbye.
Speaker 1: You got it.
Speaker 1: 21st century is here Just handing off the baton.
Speaker 1: So watch the.
Speaker 1: watch it on YouTube tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Yes, you don't watch.
Speaker 1: the rest is crappy show.
Speaker 0: No, no, you don't.
Speaker 0: So, uh, we were you know, we were trying to come up with a show to do.
Speaker 0: well You know Wednesday show and it's all rims idea.
Speaker 0: Well, did you have an idea?
Speaker 0: No, okay.
Speaker 0: So we realized, you know, we've been doing geek nights for almost a decade.
Speaker 0: We've got a lot of fucking episodes out there.
Speaker 0: I think we have.
Speaker 1: it's about to be the ninth year nine years.
Speaker 1: We started in October 05 and it's October 14.
Speaker 1: So that's 14 minus 5 is 9.
Speaker 1: I mean guys in.
Speaker 0: We won the first and I think only I don't know how long they kept doing it parsec award for best anime Podcasts great.
Speaker 0: That's and I think we've actually done more anime podcasts than anime world order despite the fact that they do way better Anime, but I think one of their anime podcast counts are like 30 hours.
Speaker 0: But what we did is, you know, we had seen all fuck ton of anime.
Speaker 0: I mean between Scott and I.
Speaker 1: we like there were a while ago like Obviously, I haven't seen all the anime ever but I have seen more anime than most people put together in like 2004.
Speaker 0: ish I remember this.
Speaker 0: a like here are the top 100 like pretty much most important or notable anime ever I'd seen like 90 plus.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we've seen basically all of them and the few we hadn't seen we knew a lot about.
Speaker 0: So we'd seen a lot of anime.
Speaker 0: So when we started doing geek nights Wednesday was literally the easiest night because we were just all the anime we had already seen.
Speaker 1: we could easily just talk about.
Speaker 0: Hey Scott, what should we review tonight?
Speaker 0: Evangelion?
Speaker 0: I could talk about that for an hour.
Speaker 1: Let's go down the checklist of this, you know hundred important anime.
Speaker 0: Let's do cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: That one will be even easier.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've never talked about that.
Speaker 1: on the show We've only done like 10 episodes of geek night kind of
Speaker 0: like how when I got to RIT as an anime fan and that First meeting when I went up to the anime club library and I was told I could check out up to three VHS tapes and then I saw the like 600 tapes up there and I had never heard of 90% of those anime I gorged on anime until my eyes fell out.
Speaker 0: It was amazing.
Speaker 0: But eventually I'd seen everything that was notable from the past.
Speaker 0: Yep, and As a result, I realize now, you know, we're scrambling We had to slow down our rate of anime reviews just because we have to actually finish an entire show to do a good review Of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't I haven't.
Speaker 0: we both have to watch it.
Speaker 1: I have you.
Speaker 1: yeah We both have to watch a whole anime That we had to order to do a show on it because every show we've already both seen has already had a show done
Speaker 0: Yep, and some of these shows are long like yeah, we could do a show on fushigi yugi Scott hasn't watched all that shit.
Speaker 1: I haven't watched any of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah So I was starting to think and then I realized there's a few anime that are pretty big That for whatever reason like I just never watched or even we both just never watched it.
Speaker 1: So the ones that didn't make that top 100 list like that the ones from like 100 to 200 Yeah, or the one it's you a lot of them were ones that were big at a time, but aren't big overall.
Speaker 0: So I think the example I got here the biggest one and this is kind of a wing in here because we're trying to figure Like what shows can we review that we haven't done already that we actually want to watch again?
Speaker 0: Oh, because that's another problem because for example, we hadn't seen my old sky time in a long time.
Speaker 0: So we watched it again because that show is delightful.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we reviewed it.
Speaker 0: I don't really want to watch cause they know you Jimbo again I tried to watch it twice didn't finish it either time do an episode on it at all.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: So we started watching the show at RIT and then we gradually tried to watch it again on Netflix and like o5 Or we made it like eight episodes in right?
Speaker 1: We were getting the DVDs from Netflix and I think those were like that's when we stopped watching the Netflix TV.
Speaker 1: We basically had a routine before watch a Netflix DVD every single night and then This is before they had the streaming and whatnot.
Speaker 0: It was also before we'd really did geek night some of that, right?
Speaker 1: We were watching South Park DVDs every night whatever and then just we caused a new Jimbo.
Speaker 1: so it was like we.
Speaker 1: that's when we stopped watching Netflix every night and It just like there was no urge to see the next episode.
Speaker 0: So later like in the moment that crystallized this in my brain was I was on Metro North later And I thought I'm gonna finish the show so I can at least talk about it.
Speaker 0: And I made it to about the same point like a few episodes past where we'd stopped and then the episode ended.
Speaker 0: I'm sitting there on the train.
Speaker 0: I got about 40 minutes before I'm getting off the train and I just didn't want to watch the next episode and Instead I watched episode 1 of Evangelion
Speaker 1: and then immediately as soon as it was over the train was pulling in the station I
Speaker 0: was like no fuck fuck and I went.
Speaker 0: I got into the house and then I watched episode 2 of Evangelion.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 0: So yeah, cause I know your Jimbo was just really lame and there's it didn't.
Speaker 1: I'm sure that show had good parts Especially if you know the story of your Jimbo, you know, it makes a lot more sense.
Speaker 1: But there was no desire to see the next episode after watching any of them.
Speaker 1: So there's no way to finish it or you'd have to force yourself to finish it and fuck that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just don't watch it.
Speaker 0: So I think the bit I remember.
Speaker 0: so when we were at RIT anime there was like the set of robot shows that people recommend.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: there was the cluster of robot shows and it was Evangelion Escaflowne Gundam just in general and one of the ones that was always on that list as a must-see robot show was Martian successor Nadeshiko.
Speaker 1: people don't even know that thing any now.
Speaker 0: that show was big.
Speaker 0: people cosplayed as it like in the early 2000s.
Speaker 1: that show was a big fucking deal.
Speaker 0: people cosplayed as characters from that like at the RIT anime club costume.
Speaker 1: They all every single time there was like, you know, like merchandise.
Speaker 1: you had seen a deshiko merchandise everywhere.
Speaker 1: Well, I remember seeing tons of Nadeshiko wall scrolls all over the place.
Speaker 0: So I just never watched it and I watched the first episode like four times and every time Didn't look that good and people swore to me was really good But I'm got the DVDs.
Speaker 1: Yep, and after I'd finished watching Evangelion Escaflowne, etc.
Speaker 1: on that train in the Beacon Days I ripped it to put on my iPhone 3G, which is how I watched Evangelion Escaflowne on those trains.
Speaker 1: And I had.
Speaker 1: I had the whole thing on my my phone my iPhone 3G and I still have those Ripped videos in my iTunes of all of Nadeshiko.
Speaker 1: Yeah Why did you watch?
Speaker 1: I watched like three on a train once and I just didn't watch anymore.
Speaker 0: I think these same same thing.
Speaker 0: these shows both typify one type of reason why you stop watching.
Speaker 0: These are these are the small roller coaster.
Speaker 0: Mmm I probably would have really liked Nadeshiko if I hadn't already seen Ava.
Speaker 0: Maybe probably what I've really liked Kazuno Yojimbo.
Speaker 1: if I'd never seen I don't know like cowboy bebop high school I would have watched the fuck out of any anime you gave me no matter how I got me.
Speaker 0: High school is when I watch shit like Doom Megalopolis and Armageddon because that was all I hadn't seen at blockbuster.
Speaker 1: It's like fatal fury on sci-fi channel.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes Now, you know.
Speaker 0: So then there's shows that just like marmalade boy Does anyone listening to geek nights even know what the fuck marmalade boy is?
Speaker 1: It was a show a show that only people that were like in anime clubs cared about.
Speaker 0: Yep, that was that was the kind of show is it?
Speaker 0: you know, it's interesting cuz marmalade boy Like only the super anime fans even know existed marmalade boy and Kim Iguirre orange road also same deal.
Speaker 0: Those were the two.
Speaker 0: those are like the shows like when we were freshmen at our IT.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the romance shoujo shows.
Speaker 1: Yeah that you know.
Speaker 1: the the hardcore anime people knew existed and were way into but no average anime fan ever heard of them ever.
Speaker 0: but it was interesting because if you went to the anime club and You went to conventions with those kinds of people and you were the freshman and they were the seniors You got the impression that marmalade boy and Kim Iguirre orange road were huge shows Really important really popular like they would just talk about this shit.
Speaker 0: They showed the Christmas special from kor for the Christmas showing at the anime club and the audience like oh my god it's the kor like.
Speaker 0: they called it kor and The shows were not that good and they're completely forgotten now except by people like us.
Speaker 0: and even then we were too young for those shows.
Speaker 1: Right that you know, they were acting like they were a big deal.
Speaker 1: But now, you know, if you watch like, you know Japanese television it's like you don't see a lot of References to marmalade boy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you see fist of the North Star jokes all the time.
Speaker 1: Those guys didn't.
Speaker 1: I had no one talked about fist the North Star at the RIT anime club.
Speaker 1: No one.
Speaker 1: Yeah Why not?
Speaker 0: I knew it existed.
Speaker 0: I wonder if it's because I think marmalade boy wasn't didn't?
Speaker 0: Greg?
Speaker 0: young fans of a bunch of that.
Speaker 1: He did.
Speaker 0: I guess there was.
Speaker 0: you know that they.
Speaker 0: you know We were talking about how Miku on letterman is like the end of one generation the beginning of another.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: that's the Nexus point.
Speaker 0: I feel like that year the year 2000-2001 was this Nexus point between the last of the anime fandom that went to conventions to copy VHS tapes and the first of the anime fandom that had the internet and didn't give a shit about fan subbers.
Speaker 0: Like that was the big turning point.
Speaker 0: So I feel like if you want like I almost want to watch kor to review it.
Speaker 1: it's all you.
Speaker 0: maybe That's the problem.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna watch it.
Speaker 0: We could just watch the movie.
Speaker 1: It's all you.
Speaker 0: Why are you poking me with the microphones?
Speaker 0: Does that want to?
Speaker 0: No kor I did.
Speaker 0: I Watched the movie and I saw a bunch of AMVs about marmalade boy and marmalade boy looks really creepy.
Speaker 0: I don't get the impression.
Speaker 0: It's actually that funny.
Speaker 1: And if you want to watch something somewhat romantic just watch touch Which is actually really important and significant and good or watch for Shiki Yugi, which I guess is better than on those two.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we've talked about this in panels a lot and we're talking on the show for Shiki.
Speaker 0: Yugi was the full metal alchemist of its era.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was a big fucking deal.
Speaker 1: You know just like and even shows, you know, what else is a big deal right then?
Speaker 1: Inuyasha was a big deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah No one talks about fucking Inuyasha except to say that shows too damn long Inuyasha's when I realized that Rumiko Takahashi can't fucking end a story, right but No one talks about Inuyasha anymore.
Speaker 1: It was a big deal then.
Speaker 1: now no deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 0: The people who talk about Inuyasha will obsess about the closing song from for Shiki Yugi.
Speaker 0: I guarantee it.
Speaker 0: if anyone ever mentions Inuyasha to you ask them what they think of the song that ended the first season of for Shiki Yugi.
Speaker 0: I'll bet a small amount of money that they will have an opinion about that.
Speaker 0: maybe Because well I was talking to Basically a for Joshi - that is that is the self-described label for this person and we were talking about Gundam.
Speaker 0: see there's a couple years ago and what they said was Gundam seed did the for Shiki Yugi thing and I was like and I paused and I was like.
Speaker 0: You mean the closing song starts like a minute before the episode ends sometimes and they were like exactly And they were really into Inuyasha - But yeah Those shows like you'd go to an Otakon and there'd be like a million Miyakas like half the cosplay skits were Bianca Tomahome Miyaka, I don't think anyone would get that reference anymore.
Speaker 1: No, I'm sure someone does listen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know we never reviewed that.
Speaker 0: actually we probably showed his koto chat.
Speaker 1: That's actually a good show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's also forgotten.
Speaker 0: Well, how much of that is you see?
Speaker 0: Have you seen we watch the like that compilation kind of movie?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've seen like a movie and I think I fell asleep during it cuz it wasn't yeah.
Speaker 0: And well you fell asleep during easily half the anime we watched it.
Speaker 0: Alrighty.
Speaker 0: Yeah, great digital target.
Speaker 0: I remember you fell asleep during the middle of mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Not that you missed anything.
Speaker 0: In retrospect whenever you fell asleep what we should have done is paused it and Just waited for you to sleep for a while and then wake unpause it and wake you up.
Speaker 0: So you would just have these weird memories of like eight hour long anime Or we could have just watched Odeon.
Speaker 1: Then we'd all fall asleep.
Speaker 0: I actually haven't seen all of koto cha.
Speaker 0: in fact I think my primary exposure to koto cha was actually that caffeine and conium AMV.
Speaker 1: It's funny.
Speaker 0: yeah Cute funny show.
Speaker 0: there's not a lot of other shows like it.
Speaker 0: It's it's got the kind of humor that modern moe shows pretend to have but are really just pornography.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Magic Knight rare I just remembered.
Speaker 0: that's a show that I didn't you.
Speaker 0: I couldn't even sit through the marathon.
Speaker 1: I had the manga which came out again recently, which is why I have it.
Speaker 0: In fact, that was the the first Marathon at the RIT anime club that I went to and then I was like, yeah, fuck it.
Speaker 0: I just left after like nine episodes.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But that's another one of those shows that people.
Speaker 0: it was popular enough in its era that everyone would refer to it by an acronym.
Speaker 0: That was MKR and everyone everyone knew exactly what you were talking about whether or not they've seen it.
Speaker 0: Do you want to watch MKR?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what it is.
Speaker 0: I had the manga read the manga.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I read a whole bunch of it.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm not all of it though.
Speaker 1: No, it's a few big fat books.
Speaker 0: So why are we watching Sailor Moon, but not MKR?
Speaker 1: Because Sailor Moon's actually entertaining.
Speaker 0: why what's the difference?
Speaker 1: Punishment.
Speaker 1: Yes That's a narrator doesn't have that kind of shit.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't it has.
Speaker 0: actually MKR is more like half Sailor Moon half Slayers, but with not the humor part of slayers the dramatic part of slayers Mmm, as I recall I actually haven't seen him care in a long long time And even then I'd see like random episodes along the way.
Speaker 0: You know what else?
Speaker 0: we never reviewed this.
Speaker 0: actually a pretty big and good show lotus war and oh my goddess.
Speaker 1: Well, okay.
Speaker 1: So those are two different shows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they're both.
Speaker 0: they're both like early formative American fandom show right.
Speaker 1: so lotus war when you went to like You know the FYE whatever in their VHS tapes of anime.
Speaker 1: in the late 90s lotus war TV Those red boxed ones were always there everywhere.
Speaker 1: They were widely distributed and easily accessible.
Speaker 1: So that's that sort of made it a bigger deal than it needs to be.
Speaker 1: Of course lotus or OVA is the only thing that's actually good besides lotus island.
Speaker 0: It's not actually good in my opinion In retrospect having watched it again relatively recently when was recent like three years ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think we watched it at beacon once and I think we did do an episode on it.
Speaker 0: I couldn't find one in a cursory search.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Well in my opinion lotus war Was great for me as a kid only because I was D&D starved Yep, and it was anime about D&D.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That is the only reason I liked it and Part of it was that I could only for a while.
Speaker 0: I only had access to like the first two episodes ish.
Speaker 0: So I was really obsessed with what happened later Just like Erislan heroic legend of our salon.
Speaker 0: Like I was really obsessed with like what happens next.
Speaker 0: and then I watched the end of lotus war.
Speaker 0: It was like I didn't really go anywhere and then I found out there was no more Arslan.
Speaker 1: No, something happened.
Speaker 1: The Arslan manga is still going for the anime.
Speaker 1: I think this actually I've read a news about like something big is happening in it.
Speaker 1: soon There's like a special announcement or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it might.
Speaker 1: I could be that it's ending.
Speaker 1: it could be a big twist is happening.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm I goddess like that was.
Speaker 0: that was another one of those like ridiculously popular forever.
Speaker 1: That was a lot like Nadesha.
Speaker 1: go where it was everywhere.
Speaker 1: There was much for it everywhere.
Speaker 1: They're everywhere and part of that was cuz dark cars dark horse is pushing the manga really hard.
Speaker 0: Yeah in the US and also I mean there was the original OAV and then there's like a bunch of other related things.
Speaker 0: Oh my god of stuff that came later.
Speaker 1: There's the movie the manga finally ended sometime recently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, super long-running.
Speaker 0: I wonder if they ever had sex.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: That's actually all I wondered because that nothing nothing fucking half the art was beautiful, but nothing fucking happened in that manga.
Speaker 1: That's really.
Speaker 1: that's the one thing.
Speaker 1: I remember.
Speaker 1: Oh my god is there was like they were real Number one thing that you would hear about.
Speaker 1: it was and see in all of the merchandise and other artifacts was just like how crazy Amazingly art was.
Speaker 1: you know it looked like.
Speaker 1: you know super colorful and clean and sharp.
Speaker 1: You know designs like in the.
Speaker 1: you know the CG days that we have now where computers are even used to make 2d animation.
Speaker 1: But it was hand-drawn in the olden days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it was like wow.
Speaker 1: It's just a TV show.
Speaker 0: It's not even like a Kira movie or anything, but look at the way It looks, but I feel like we should actually cuz I haven't seen it a long time And I don't think you've ever seen it.
Speaker 0: We should watch and review the original.
Speaker 0: Oh my god Sure you go get on that.
Speaker 0: Well, it's five episodes Scott.
Speaker 0: That is that is less than like one mid arc of Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: Are they 20 minute or is it an OAV where they're longer there?
Speaker 0: I think they're 23 minutes.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen him in a long time Yep, and actually I remembers I skipped I think the third episode because the tape at anime club like wouldn't play in my VCR.
Speaker 0: So I skipped that one.
Speaker 0: I never ended up seeing it and actually despite owning it and having paid $25 to the DVD when it came out I never actually watched the oh my god is movie mm-hmm Just for whatever reason wasn't that the one that you cosplayed as?
Speaker 0: Yes, that was the one I cosplayed as.
Speaker 1: yeah that one had like the even better arts.
Speaker 1: people were like losing their shit over how That movie looked.
Speaker 0: yeah, I remember we showed it at the anime club and people like lined up.
Speaker 1: and wasn't it a really bad movie?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I didn't watch it.
Speaker 0: I was running the club when I ran the club.
Speaker 0: I couldn't watch any goddamn anime.
Speaker 1: I didn't watch that.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz we lie everyone lined up and actually had to kick people out of the room.
Speaker 1: actually one of the reasons I didn't the main reason any watch is cuz I'd never seen any other.
Speaker 1: oh my goddess.
Speaker 1: And I was like well this isn't gonna make any sense to someone who's never seen any of it.
Speaker 1: I thought it was like you know an ending movie or something like that.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: It's not like the third tenchi movie.
Speaker 1: It's a compilation movie.
Speaker 0: I feel like we'd know it's just you could watch.
Speaker 0: It's like the tenchi movie.
Speaker 0: you can watch the first tenchi movie knowing nothing about tenchi, and it's a fine movie.
Speaker 1: It's like the Sailor Moon movie reviewed where it's candy something.
Speaker 0: yeah, basically like the movie Just like it's fine.
Speaker 0: You don't need to know anything.
Speaker 0: the movie will reveal everything you need to know and just throw you into it And it's fine.
Speaker 0: Actually, you know what.
Speaker 0: that reminds me of Why you a?
Speaker 0: hmm another one of those acronym shows yeah?
Speaker 1: You're under arrest.
Speaker 1: all I know about is is comedy police girls.
Speaker 0: Well, we show the the episode with the hurricane and there's the phantom speeder Who only comes during hurricanes and goes speeding because the cops can't catch him.
Speaker 0: We showed that like every year is a tradition to the anime club mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That was actually remember it.
Speaker 0: you know what it was.
Speaker 0: it reminded me a lot of palabor in the sense that it's like.
Speaker 0: It's that camaraderie comedy of a bunch of people who have a sort of police military kind of job But it mostly focuses on just them and their own like personal funny drama and also rhythm and police or gunsmith kids.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not called rhythm and police I know.
Speaker 0: You just don't remember what it's called.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's correct It's called.
Speaker 0: it's called.
Speaker 1: You're gonna say it I'm gonna go damn it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't remember either.
Speaker 1: cuz I remember it even though I've seen all of it even the TV episode.
Speaker 0: It's a Japanese phrase that I kept fucking messing up.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to look it up now rhythm and police.
Speaker 1: Wow Just search for like dancing police.
Speaker 0: That's the one I would.
Speaker 0: cuz.
Speaker 0: I would always say Die so sauce and So good.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh.
Speaker 1: Oh, don't you die so sauce?
Speaker 1: I haven't done an episode on that.
Speaker 0: we I do better.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna look right now.
Speaker 0: we didn't.
Speaker 0: we didn't do an episode on that.
Speaker 0: We're doing an episode on it like next Wednesday, even though it's not even animated.
Speaker 0: I Feel like we could watch why you a do a review of it.
Speaker 1: You'll find it.
Speaker 1: a lot of these animes are ones that are so off the radar now Because they were just sort of hot flashes in the pan in the u.s.
Speaker 1: At least that it's not the easiest to go.
Speaker 1: get them these days.
Speaker 1: if you don't have them already You got to find an old DVD or an old fan sub.
Speaker 1: or hope someone's still seeing the torrent or someone crazies on an IRC.
Speaker 0: Okay on June 22nd 2011 We did an episode about anime that only you or I had watched that the other one hadn't watched.
Speaker 0: and in the middle of that We talked about Bayside Shakedown Even though we'd both seen it and we even have a note here saying even though we both have seen it.
Speaker 0: So I guess we that's the only time we ever talked about a very similar episode of geek nights.
Speaker 1: We want a very similar tangent.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling that if we listen to that old episode of geek nights Here's the list.
Speaker 0: The anime list does not overlap at all.
Speaker 1: real interesting.
Speaker 0: Here's the list of anime we talked about on that episode Wolverine.
Speaker 1: So I'm a no meta x-men none of the.
Speaker 1: oh that you mean the anime.
Speaker 0: Yes Wow, galaxy railways birdie the mighty decode photons scrap princess Pat LaValle the melancholy of Haruhi Suzumiya captain Tyler seven billion needles or say it's Ranma one-half and Rosa Versailles.
Speaker 1: Have you seen any the ones in the list that you hadn't seen then?
Speaker 0: I've since watched a bunch of Rosa Versailles, but actually didn't finish it.
Speaker 0: Uh, I Still haven't watched galaxy railways.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you watch galaxy rails.
Speaker 1: You haven't seen galaxy Express.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Have not watched.
Speaker 0: I fell asleep during the second palabar movie.
Speaker 0: I gotta watch it again.
Speaker 1: That one's actually good.
Speaker 1: I know it's good, but it's also the end of palabar.
Speaker 1: You should only see that after you watch all the other palabar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know you have not watched birdie the mighty decode even though it's a really good show.
Speaker 1: No have not and take.
Speaker 0: uh, you know what feeling it gave me.
Speaker 0: Take like the Kill La Kill feeling and drop it down about three notches.
Speaker 0: That's birdie the mighty decode.
Speaker 0: Mmm Which means it's still pretty good.
Speaker 0: Oh Our things of the day where it's dragon out bitch and mama.
Speaker 0: Sheba mama.
Speaker 1: Heba.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh dragon.
Speaker 0: I bitches still up.
Speaker 0: So is mama Shiva.
Speaker 0: All right Yeah, what else we talked about then?
Speaker 0: spider-man is dead a kb48 Makoto Shinkai studio.
Speaker 0: something Is looking for cloud and powerline interns?
Speaker 0: Yeah Makoto Shinkai studio was looking for background interns.
Speaker 1: Yep Power lines.
Speaker 0: Yeah, our show notes were a lot more clever back then.
Speaker 1: I think you put more effort into it.
Speaker 1: I think I did put your effort into it tonight.
Speaker 0: I'll put some effort into it and I'll go home and eat dinner.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I'm hungry.
Speaker 0: so Full metal alchemist, you know was the fushigi.
Speaker 0: it was the biggest goddamn thing ever.
Speaker 1: We haven't done an episode on.
Speaker 0: we did but you know We never watched the other ones.
Speaker 1: remember the movie.
Speaker 0: We didn't watch the movie of conqueror Shambala or whatever that was supposed to like.
Speaker 0: answer all those questions Because remember did not see the anime diverged from the manga.
Speaker 0: We watched the anime.
Speaker 0: It was the best thing or the biggest thing ever at least like we watched every episode as it came out and it ended like During the Blitz like during like the interwar period in regular earth With a bunch of bullshit and then the movie was gonna explain it all.
Speaker 0: the movie Because everyone else said the movie was so bad.
Speaker 0: I never watched it.
Speaker 1: I Didn't watch it either.
Speaker 1: I have all the manga actually, but I haven't read it all.
Speaker 0: and Then Brotherhood came out and I just wasn't interested.
Speaker 0: and I think Dave I remember they were he was remember listen to he was talking about how we started watching Brotherhood and It kind of sucked because at the beginning pretty much is the same as the original anime.
Speaker 0: But then he ended up going back to check because he washed like the original one and he ended up just watching the original one All the way through again instead.
Speaker 0: I Don't think I'll ever watch Brotherhood.
Speaker 0: I just have no interest.
Speaker 0: and no one is supposedly the same as the manga Yes, meaning it diverges from the original anime.
Speaker 1: So if I just read the manga that I own I'll be all set.
Speaker 1: I guess I mostly just want to read all that manga so I won't feel bad about then selling it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm getting it off making shelf space open up.
Speaker 0: all right, I think we'll just cut it off here because Frankly, I got some cool stuff to do tomorrow that I'm gonna talk about Once I find out if I can talk about it or not and then I go go to Australia.
Speaker 0: So yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.