Speaker 1: Bunnies and flying.
Speaker 1: Bunnies like flying less than they like most things.
Speaker 0: Lucky rabbit's foot in Vegas.
Speaker 1: You know, the lucky rabbit's foots are really unlucky for the rabbits they get them from.
Speaker 0: Rabbit doesn't need money.
Speaker 1: How's a rabbit gonna get all that swag of hay?
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: It just grows out of the fucking ground.
Speaker 1: Yeah, where are they gonna get it?
Speaker 1: Rabbit in the city, not a lot of good grass.
Speaker 1: You need money.
Speaker 0: You gotta move.
Speaker 0: You're a rabbit, you're quick.
Speaker 0: You can get there.
Speaker 1: But you wanna leave New York?
Speaker 1: You wanna leave New York?
Speaker 1: That's where all the jobs are.
Speaker 0: You're a rabbit?
Speaker 0: There's no rabbit jobs in New York.
Speaker 1: I think there are plenty of rabbit jobs in New York.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: What's a rabbit job gonna get for a job?
Speaker 1: Eat all the dandelions.
Speaker 1: Where?
Speaker 1: Get 'em out of the park.
Speaker 1: No more dandelions.
Speaker 0: Rabbit live in the park?
Speaker 1: Uh, be cute.
Speaker 1: Photo ops.
Speaker 1: Rabbit model.
Speaker 1: If the internet has taught me anything, being cute is a business model.
Speaker 0: Alright, well, how come you're not taking advantage of that?
Speaker 1: Uh, there is no way to read that but you having just said that I'm cute.
Speaker 0: Oh, 'cause you own rabbits.
Speaker 0: You're not selling your rabbits for cute photo ops.
Speaker 1: So, uh, the other day, I was biking home from work.
Speaker 0: We did an intro to this show.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I guess we didn't.
Speaker 1: It's mechanical for Liebowitz.
Speaker 1: We recorded this way later than normal.
Speaker 1: It's October 2nd, Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, uh, anyway, so I'm biking home from work.
Speaker 1: And because they've added, like, three stop signs and a new light to my old way home.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So now, I actually go out of my way to take the bike path along the East River, like, all the way home.
Speaker 1: 'Cause that's just way... It's actually faster now most of the time.
Speaker 1: Unless I run every stoplight.
Speaker 1: But, which is fine.
Speaker 1: Like, I'll do the Idaho whatever protocol.
Speaker 1: But lately, there's been cops there, like, hanging out at the intersections.
Speaker 1: And I saw a biker getting a ticket.
Speaker 1: So, gonna just let that hang out for a while.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So, I'm biking on the bike path.
Speaker 1: It's a separated, two-lane bike path.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: A green painted one.
Speaker 0: It has some shitty areas, though, but most of it's okay.
Speaker 1: And they've actually, they've fixed it bit by bit.
Speaker 1: Like, it's getting better and better.
Speaker 0: Some of the good parts are even better than they used to be, but the shitty parts are still shitty.
Speaker 0: Like, the part by the power plant where it's really narrow.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And the part by the little warehouses where the street is, you're basically just going on this beat-up old sidewalk.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's the worst.
Speaker 0: And the part where you have to go onto First Avenue because it ends and the
Speaker 0: U.N.'
Speaker 0: 's on the way.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I don't know, I just don't go around the U.N So, I'm biking and there's a thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, no, you're thinking of the East River Bikeway.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm on the opposite side of the river.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 1: There's another, there's a bikeway right there, too.
Speaker 0: And it has the same properties as the one on the other side of the East River?
Speaker 1: Yes, it took three properties.
Speaker 0: It has a power plant that doesn't exist with a narrow bridge.
Speaker 1: So, it has a bunch of old warehouses and, like, generating stations that are being torn down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, by the sugar factory.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, anyway, so it took a couple of aspects.
Speaker 1: I was like, I think he's talking about the wrong, anyway.
Speaker 1: So, I'm biking there.
Speaker 1: I'm going, like, 24-ish miles an hour.
Speaker 1: I'm going pretty fast because it's, like, downhill.
Speaker 1: And this woman just literally steps out between two cars jaywalking right in front of me.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So, I swerve to the right because she doesn't even notice me and she keeps walking.
Speaker 1: And then her hand is back and she pulls into my path her young daughter.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So, now I literally almost flipped over my handlebars trying to not hit her daughter and probably severely injure her.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I considered just slamming into the woman because I figured she could take it.
Speaker 1: There's no way to avoid them both.
Speaker 1: I almost flipped over my handlebars.
Speaker 1: I stopped.
Speaker 1: I barely avoid them.
Speaker 1: She screams and starts yelling at me.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And for once, like, usually I just ignore people when that happens.
Speaker 1: I just, like, keep biking.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But I was like, "Listen, lady, you almost got your daughter killed.
Speaker 1: You're a terrible mother.
Speaker 1: Don't
Speaker 1: jaywalk.".
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And she was stunned into indignant silence.
Speaker 1: And then her daughter was like, "Mommy, you should really listen to the
Speaker 1: man.".
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then I started laughing so hard that I almost cried.
Speaker 1: And I biked away because she was so curious.
Speaker 0: You should have high-fived the little daughter and then biked away.
Speaker 1: But it was, like, it was the kind of thing that normally only happens in movies.
Speaker 1: Like, it was too perfect.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Go, little daughter, go.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna get killed once you cross the street on your own.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Though, funnily enough, I saw a video this morning.
Speaker 1: The Gothamist was like, "This is what it looks like when a pedestrian
Speaker 1: jaywalks.".
Speaker 0: Well, that guy, did you read that?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That guy had a car horn.
Speaker 0: Well, no.
Speaker 0: He saw this dude coming because he had a light on his bike like he's supposed to.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And he knew the guy wasn't looking, and he knew he wouldn't hit him.
Speaker 0: So he intentionally made it a close call to teach the guy a lesson.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I approve.
Speaker 0: Eh.
Speaker 1: You know what it's like?
Speaker 0: It's like- I think that was just an old guy who's not, can't learn a lesson.
Speaker 0: He's too old.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The look of terror on his face, though, was kind of beautiful.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So, yeah.
Speaker 1: It's Thursday.
Speaker 1: It's the lounge.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: Talk about anything.
Speaker 0: You don't have book clubs in a lounge.
Speaker 0: Yeah?
Speaker 0: Imagine a lounge with a book club in it.
Speaker 0: Not getting out of a good mix.
Speaker 0: Your book club belongs in the library or the Barnes and Noble.
Speaker 1: There actually is a writer's lounge near our building.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's not a lounge like the kind of lounge that- That's the kind of lounge I'm thinking about.
Speaker 0: A lounge is the place where you have a lounge singer.
Speaker 1: I was thinking about the book lounge.
Speaker 0: That's not a lounge.
Speaker 1: I guess in the Midwest, you could have the lounge as a room separate from the family room.
Speaker 0: A lounge is a place with leopard print couches and alcohol and a small tiny stage with a shitty keyboard on it.
Speaker 0: Possibly an organ with one of those circle curtains that goes around it.
Speaker 1: Now, if it's fancy, it'll be a real piano and there'll be a lady singing.
Speaker 0: That might be more of a club.
Speaker 0: If it gets too good, it's no longer a lounge.
Speaker 0: It becomes a club.
Speaker 1: Thing is, nowadays, club means bad music, playing so loud you can't talk to anyone.
Speaker 0: Well, there are many kinds of clubs.
Speaker 0: There's an anime club too, right?
Speaker 0: A lounge is much more specific.
Speaker 1: So, if you hit someone with a club- That's right.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So, anyway, it's the lounge.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: And recently, a time capsule was unearthed in New York.
Speaker 1: This is a time capsule from 1950, buried in Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: I think it was buried by the MTA or by the organization that became it.
Speaker 1: Time capsule buried beneath old Metropolitan Transportation Authority headquarters in downtown Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: They cracked it open yesterday.
Speaker 1: And what they found inside was basically a note to the past saying, "Time capsules need to be waterproof,
Speaker 1: motherfuckers.".
Speaker 1: It was just a rotten mess of garbage.
Speaker 0: You got to make a high-quality time capsule.
Speaker 0: That's what makes it a capsule.
Speaker 1: So, the funniest thing, everything was ruined.
Speaker 1: The microfiche, the document, it was all just this tomato soup-looking rust sludge.
Speaker 1: The line at the bottom of this article is beautiful.
Speaker 1: The line at the bottom of this article is why I made this my news.
Speaker 1: Quote, "The capsule itself might, however, be salvageable and will be put on display at the New York Transit
Speaker 1: Museum.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know what?
Speaker 1: Unless the caption is just the word "fail" in impact fonts.
Speaker 0: Out and flushing at the World's Fairgrounds in the park, there's a real time capsule that is definitely still in one piece.
Speaker 1: I know about that time capsule.
Speaker 0: It's not supposed to be open until well after we're dead.
Speaker 0: We should sneak there at night with jackhammers and get it.
Speaker 1: Hold it hostage?
Speaker 1: Scott, that's some Lupin shit.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, I could pull that off.
Speaker 0: Do you know how to use a jackhammer?
Speaker 0: Do you know how to make it so no one will hear it?
Speaker 1: I know how to use a jackhammer.
Speaker 1: Maybe put a silencer on it.
Speaker 0: There's a concrete sidewalk with a metal plaque thingy, and then underneath that is a bunch of dirt.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's directly underneath that or not.
Speaker 0: It might be offset slightly.
Speaker 0: If we dig straight down, we might not find it.
Speaker 1: There is a better time capsule that we could steal.
Speaker 1: Where?
Speaker 1: Oh no, it's the same one.
Speaker 1: The people who made the Westinghouse time capsule, the one in the Corona Meadows Park, they used that design to make a couple other ones as well.
Speaker 0: The quality ones.
Speaker 1: You know how these things work?
Speaker 1: They're suspended by a string, like a big metal cable, so they're just floating down in a deep pit.
Speaker 1: They're covered in this alloy that's designed to last 5,000 years without any sort of measurable corrosion.
Speaker 1: They're shaped like a missile.
Speaker 1: They have glass, wool, nose cushions, and all these things in case they break.
Speaker 1: The inside is actually Pyrex glass, and then inside of that is a ridiculous amount of shit.
Speaker 0: Actually, we don't have to dig.
Speaker 0: We just have to basically flip the lid open, grab the hook that it's hanging on, and lift it up.
Speaker 1: I think the lid is sealed.
Speaker 1: Look, here's what it looks like.
Speaker 1: The lid is sealed.
Speaker 1: You have to jackhammer this thing off.
Speaker 0: That is not sticking out of the ground anymore.
Speaker 0: You can't see that part there now.
Speaker 1: No, this is the exhibit.
Speaker 1: This just shows you what they look like.
Speaker 0: If you go there now, it's a piece of metal on the ground.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there it is.
Speaker 1: You have to bust the concrete up, and then winch it out of the ground.
Speaker 0: Why don't we just get a crane?
Speaker 1: No one will notice that.
Speaker 1: There's the problem with this time capsule.
Speaker 1: Here's a picture of what's in it from when they buried it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: It's got to last a thousand years, and no one's going to care, because here's the picture.
Speaker 0: But we could have that stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: I saw this exact camera for sale at a lomography shop in Brooklyn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that camera has film in it.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: These three things are reels of film.
Speaker 0: Yes, we could watch those films.
Speaker 1: That looks like a computer mouse, but obviously it's not.
Speaker 0: There's good stuff in there.
Speaker 1: So, anyway, got any news?
Speaker 0: I mean, well, I guess it's not really much news, but Windows 10, Windows 9 got skipped.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's nothing really to say about it.
Speaker 1: Did you see?
Speaker 1: I saw an article where someone posited why Windows 9 was skipped.
Speaker 0: It's a bad number.
Speaker 1: No, here's the deal.
Speaker 1: And they showed some code examples, so there's some plausibility to this.
Speaker 0: The catch up to Apple, which is OS X.
Speaker 1: A lot of Windows version detection functions.
Speaker 1: look for Windows space nine dot star.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 1: Because they're trying to detect Windows 95 or 98.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 1: That might be the only reason.
Speaker 0: That's a good reason, though.
Speaker 1: It is actually a good reason.
Speaker 0: Also, you know, 10's a much better number.
Speaker 0: It catches up to Apple.
Speaker 0: Apple has been on OS X for a thousand years.
Speaker 1: Remember when Winamp went one, two, three, five?
Speaker 0: But anyway, you know, the thing about it is I'm still using Windows 7.
Speaker 1: As am I.
Speaker 0: And it still feels perfectly new.
Speaker 0: It doesn't feel like there is a newer Windows.
Speaker 0: It's like, oh, yeah, Windows 8 is a thing that exists.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, I would have gotten Windows 8 if I built a new computer.
Speaker 0: Maybe, I guess.
Speaker 1: Since Windows 7 came out.
Speaker 0: But it's like, until there's a reason to get a new computer, it's like there's no reason for me to spend money on Windows 10.
Speaker 0: And I'm definitely not going to get a shady pirated one.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, that's the thing is with Windows.
Speaker 1: now is that desktop.
Speaker 0: And everything that you still use your computer for, Windows 7 is totally fully supported.
Speaker 0: It supports everything.
Speaker 0: Every hardware is supported.
Speaker 1: On a desktop computer.
Speaker 0: All new software supports Windows 7 and all the hardware I already have is supported by Windows 7.
Speaker 1: Well, Scott, here are the reasons to buy Windows 10.
Speaker 1: One, you build a new computer.
Speaker 0: And you can't get a copy of Windows 7.
Speaker 1: And you can't transfer your license that you already paid for because you bought the OEM license or whatever.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 1: Two, your current version of Windows is actually out of support.
Speaker 1: Those are all the reasons.
Speaker 0: So, I don't, you know.
Speaker 1: The thing is I feel like Windows 8 was the, it's not ME.
Speaker 1: Like people always talk, like I saw all these charts.
Speaker 1: It's like everyone's so young.
Speaker 1: They don't understand or remember Windows.
Speaker 1: They're like, man, every other version of Windows sucks.
Speaker 1: Like the TikTok with the Apple phones.
Speaker 1: They're like, Windows 95 sucked and 98 was awesome.
Speaker 1: I was like, alright kid, already you're stupid.
Speaker 1: Windows 95 was possibly one of the most revolutionary operating systems in modern history.
Speaker 0: If I was Microsoft, what I would do is I would just be like, alright, you know what the fuck?
Speaker 0: It's called Windows.
Speaker 0: It's free for everyone except businesses.
Speaker 0: Businesses have to pay a fucking fortune.
Speaker 0: The end.
Speaker 0: And then the business windows, the only differences would be things that businesses absolutely need that no human being.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what I'd sell?
Speaker 1: I'd sell things like holding, staging, and pushing patches.
Speaker 1: Security restrictions.
Speaker 0: No, I would just be like, yeah, uh, what's, what makes windows 10 like business-y, not windows 10, but like the business version, the business version, these applications that we also make that you absolutely need will refuse to run on the regular one.
Speaker 0: So it's like, oh, you need SharePoint that absolutely will just refuse to run on the free one.
Speaker 1: It's just really a shame that, I mean, there's Apple, which is always on hardware.
Speaker 1: There's windows and that's it.
Speaker 1: That in all this time there is still no BOS, Linux.
Speaker 1: So at my company, we were talking about, you know, like charting frameworks and whatever and all this stuff.
Speaker 1: And we were looking at compatibility and at one point we're like, wow, that framework is great, but it only works on windows.
Speaker 1: And then we were all quiet for like several seconds.
Speaker 1: And then our new developer heard is like, do we support the client on Linux?
Speaker 1: And I was like, well, yeah, it's Java, so it runs.
Speaker 1: And he was like, does any, has anyone ever used it on Linux?
Speaker 1: And I was like, my QA team, Linux desktop is a joke.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: But it's not Monday.
Speaker 1: It's Thursday.
Speaker 0: This shows you how little news there is.
Speaker 1: Well, there's plenty of news.
Speaker 1: It's just not news.
Speaker 1: We like, what am I going to say about Ebola?
Speaker 0: Don't get it.
Speaker 1: You know what you can learn about Ebola?
Speaker 1: Go to CNN.
Speaker 1: My opinion, don't touch people who look like they have Ebola.
Speaker 0: Don't go anywhere that you've heard about Ebola being.
Speaker 1: Unless you are an altruist who really wants to go help and make a difference.
Speaker 0: If you are a doctor, not just a dumb altruist who's not a doctor.
Speaker 1: I don't want, I don't want some like lame-o.
Speaker 0: And also a real doctor, not a made up doctor.
Speaker 1: Hi everybody.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: And like you actually know something about viruses too.
Speaker 0: If you're some other like an orthopedist, you're not going to be able to help.
Speaker 1: I'd happily talk about the fact that Kim Jong-il, Kim Jong-un, might have broken his ankles because he's fat.
Speaker 0: He's just walking around?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like he might have fractured his ankles.
Speaker 0: He must have been doing something.
Speaker 0: Isn't he always riding horses and shit?
Speaker 0: He probably fell off one.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: So there's a lot of video evidence that he's been gaining a lot of weight.
Speaker 0: Well, wouldn't you if you were eating the whole country's worth of food and everyone else was starving?
Speaker 1: I have access to infinite numbers of calories compared to what my body could consume.
Speaker 1: I ate seven or eight hundred calories of cookies right before we did the show and I'm drinking a beer.
Speaker 1: I consume as much calorie as I can on an hourly basis and I've weighed 150 pounds since like I was 16.
Speaker 0: Right, but he's eating food for an entire country of people to make sure that they continue to starve.
Speaker 0: That's a lot more than 700 calories.
Speaker 1: In a way, that noble man is protecting his people from obesity and type 2 diabetes.
Speaker 0: Yes, instead giving them things like scurvy.
Speaker 1: I would love to talk about Ukraine, but you don't know or care.
Speaker 1: I need Andrew.
Speaker 1: Andrew's my Ukraine buddy.
Speaker 0: Don't go there.
Speaker 0: Any place that's in the news is usually a place you don't want to go.
Speaker 0: That's my news.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's my advice.
Speaker 1: Oh, trying to think of an exception to that.
Speaker 1: PAX isn't really in the news.
Speaker 1: New York Comic Con is in the news and you don't want to go to that.
Speaker 1: It holds out.
Speaker 1: It holds up.
Speaker 0: Usually 9 times out of 10 or even more than that.
Speaker 0: If a place of a location is in the news, don't go there.
Speaker 1: So anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: This is cute and weird.
Speaker 1: So bear with me here.
Speaker 1: There is a pop song apparently called Anaconda that I'd never heard of.
Speaker 0: I didn't hear this either, but apparently it's just a Sir Mix-A-Lot remix.
Speaker 0: Yes, so it's basically Sir Mix-A-Lot, but with girls.
Speaker 1: It's not the greatest thing in the world.
Speaker 1: But the reason I found out about it is because CollegeHumor posted Anaconda, the educational version.
Speaker 0: So I saw this and I thought it was just a remix of Sir Mix-A-Lot because I didn't know that it was a remix of a remix of Sir Mix-A-Lot.
Speaker 1: So that is very much like the people who quote the phrase, "We don't need no stinking
Speaker 1: badges."
Speaker 1: And they don't know where it's from.
Speaker 1: That is from Treasure of the Sierra Madre.
Speaker 0: They think it's from Blazing Saddle.
Speaker 1: Actually, I've seen conversations.
Speaker 0: Which it is from, but it's also from Treasure of the Sierra Madre.
Speaker 1: I witnessed a conversation several years ago at a convention.
Speaker 1: The conversation went like this, "We don't need no stinking
Speaker 1: badges.".
Speaker 1: And then the guy was like, "Ah, The
Speaker 1: Simpsons.".
Speaker 1: And the guy was like, "Uh, no.
Speaker 1: It's from Blazing
Speaker 1: Saddles.".
Speaker 1: And then this other guy who was sitting nearby at a table looks up and he's like, "You two are
Speaker 1: children.".
Speaker 1: And he did not explain what he meant by that.
Speaker 0: That is the person that you should sit down and have a conversation with.
Speaker 1: That's the person you go sit and play Hanabi with right away.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Anyone who has listened to this who has not seen Treasure of the Sierra Madre, that movie is...
Speaker 1: So anyway, this is a parody of a song.
Speaker 1: that is a remix of a song.
Speaker 1: And it's kind of cute and funny because it's basically just a sexy, rappy kind of music video.
Speaker 1: Except it's literally about anacondas, the snakes, and sexual dimorphism.
Speaker 1: And it's just... I don't know.
Speaker 1: All my other things of the day would require way too much explanation.
Speaker 1: And I gotta save them for an appropriate... Like, I need them to segue into something.
Speaker 0: So, continuing my hockey-themed things of the day this week.
Speaker 0: Here's another hockey-themed thing of the day.
Speaker 0: The Dallas Stars, who are not very good at hockey right now.
Speaker 0: Not the worst!
Speaker 0: No, I mean, you know, it's still pre-season hockey.
Speaker 0: We don't know how... They could suddenly be great this year.
Speaker 0: Unlikely.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, Scott, I read a headline today.
Speaker 1: And it was basically like, "Rangers!
Speaker 1: Not seeing the Stanley Cup this
Speaker 1: year!".
Speaker 0: No kidding.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much probably going to be the West again.
Speaker 0: Because all the good players are still in the West.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So, the Dallas Stars, during their pre-season hockey game, on the scoreboard, put up memes that came up with making fun of the fans of opposing teams that were in the stands.
Speaker 1: The winter is coming one is great.
Speaker 1: Brace yourselves.
Speaker 1: Bandwagon Blackhawks fans are coming.
Speaker 1: You know what this is?
Speaker 1: This is Anime News Nina.
Speaker 1: For those of you who don't listen to the Anime Night.
Speaker 1: The Anime News Network, which is pretty much the Reuters press of anime.
Speaker 1: Well, in an English-speaking world.
Speaker 1: Like, outside of Japan.
Speaker 0: If you want anime news, or news about anime, manga, Japan stuff in the US, Anime News Network is the place.
Speaker 1: It is pretty much the top.
Speaker 1: Like, the top top.
Speaker 1: One step under that is, like, Anime World Order.
Speaker 1: Another step under that is, like, Oz and Dave and Joel.
Speaker 0: Uh, Taku USA Magazine?
Speaker 1: Uh, I put them on the level of... Halfway between Anime News Network and Anime World Order.
Speaker 1: Because there's a Venn diagram at that point.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: But they had a comic, Anime News Nina, that was pretty sardonic and funny.
Speaker 1: But the point was that it made fun of itself and of the thing that the organization was about.
Speaker 1: It's like the company making fun of itself and making the kind of humor that might offend really offendable people.
Speaker 1: But is actually funny.
Speaker 1: This is that.
Speaker 1: This is the kind of thing that I wish more everythings did.
Speaker 1: Actually be funny.
Speaker 1: Don't be completely corporate lame humor.
Speaker 1: And also just don't be, like, racist and sexist.
Speaker 0: Just hire young people and let them have control and don't put stupid restrictions on them or punish them for being cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Because seriously, if you're old, like, over the age of 40, and you're 21 year old, like, just out of college, motion graphics guy says, "Trust me, this is
Speaker 1: hilarious.".
Speaker 1: I guarantee it is hilarious.
Speaker 1: At least to the people who are at your hockey game.
Speaker 0: Just verify that it's not also offensive.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Because the other problem with that person is that he is trying to sneak the goatee in.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: There could be a hidden goatee there.
Speaker 1: You know how hard I'm trying to sneak the goatee into everything I ever do?
Speaker 0: Have you snuck the goatee into anything at work?
Speaker 1: No, I have not, but I've snuck a whole bunch of pony in.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: Lots of pones.
Speaker 0: Metamoments?
Speaker 0: In the metamoment.
Speaker 1: The Book Club book is Can it Go for?
Speaker 1: Leave It, which we're going to talk about it.
Speaker 0: What's the next Book Club book?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: I'm debating whether or not to punish Scott for taking so long.
Speaker 0: Summer, would you want me to read books when the sun is out?
Speaker 1: Yeah, to be fair, it's a little one-sided because the reason I read seven novels since I finished Can it Go for Liebowitz, well, six and a half, I'm not done with the seventh one, is because I've had a number of transatlantic flights.
Speaker 0: On your own.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: With no one else.
Speaker 1: So, if you're not flying with a friend and you're flying, like, nine hours multiple times over the course of a month, you're going to read a lot of books because you can only watch so many cut-down shitty movies on the back of a headrest and your laptop only lasts a few hours.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I gotta pick a book and I gotta decide how much I want to punish Scott.
Speaker 0: Alright, so in the metamoment, I want to talk about just a few events that are happening in and around New York City and other nerdy places, I guess, mostly New York City.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's a secret burger crawl next weekend in New York City that you should go to.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's good to know.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, most of these things are actually happening, like, October 11th, 12th, when we're at a wedding in Albany.
Speaker 0: It's Columbus Day weekend, I guess.
Speaker 0: Fuck Columbus Day, but, you know, that's a day off for work.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so here's the thing.
Speaker 0: So, first of all, because New York Comic Con is also that weekend, I'm pretty sure, there's a bunch of crazy nerdy events going on surrounding New York Comic Con that are vastly superior to New York Comic Con itself.
Speaker 0: So, I think the Ghibli movie is now screening in New York City.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I think Emily might have bought tickets for that.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's number one.
Speaker 0: Number two, there's the Hatsune Miku Expo in New York City, which includes Hatsune Miku concert in the Nokia Theater, which is 11th and 12th, but then there's also this, like, art exhibit you can just go to, so we can go to that later.
Speaker 0: That's open for longer.
Speaker 0: There is New York City, this is unrelated to nerdery.
Speaker 0: It's like New York City open house, where you can sort of sign up and go to things that are normally not open.
Speaker 1: That's super nerdy.
Speaker 0: Sort of.
Speaker 0: So, I really wanted to go to the CWA terminal at JFK, which you can go to.
Speaker 0: I think you can also go to, like, Woolworth Building and other shit.
Speaker 1: I was thinking about going to the onion domes, the digesters.
Speaker 0: Oh, you can just go there.
Speaker 0: That's not a special day, but yeah, we can go there.
Speaker 0: So, the website to sign up for those things is open now, but I'm not gonna be here.
Speaker 0: And the last one, I don't think it's that weekend.
Speaker 0: I think it's maybe November 1st.
Speaker 0: I gotta check the actual date and provide a link at some point.
Speaker 0: I'll mention this one again, because there's more time between now and it.
Speaker 0: College Humor.
Speaker 0: Super Art Fight team up to bring you Super Art Fight vs College Humor in Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: Guys.
Speaker 0: Super Art Fight in Brooklyn for the first time ever.
Speaker 1: If you don't know what Super Art Fight is, go to this thing.
Speaker 1: If you know what it is, go to this thing.
Speaker 1: Seriously.
Speaker 0: It's happening.
Speaker 1: The College Humor team, like the people from College Humor.
Speaker 1: If anyone's gonna take down some of these long-reigning champions of Super Art Fight.
Speaker 0: I mean, Caldwell is not new to the Super Art Fight, you know, canvas.
Speaker 1: No, he is not, but I imagine Caldwell teamed up with, I'd have to pick who I'd team up with.
Speaker 1: You know what we need?
Speaker 1: You know what we should make?
Speaker 1: Fantasy Super Art Fight League.
Speaker 0: You get points whenever they get a win.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Every time they draw a monocle, it scores a half point.
Speaker 0: Two points for a top hat.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Man, then you have a separate scoring system for, like, if someone does a webcomic.
Speaker 1: When those elements are included in the media they're publishing elsewhere, it's like the fantasy player.
Speaker 1: Someone else make that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's all the things I can think of right now, but I'm sure there's more going down.
Speaker 1: So, in a few weeks, October 31st through November 2nd, Halloween, the anniversary of Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: I will be live at PAX Australia without Scott.
Speaker 0: Unless someone wants to give me, like, a real lot of money right now.
Speaker 0: It's still theoretically possible if I'm given enough money in some currency.
Speaker 0: What's the number?
Speaker 0: That is legit.
Speaker 1: Would you go if someone gave you two grand?
Speaker 0: Well, no.
Speaker 1: Two grand would...
Speaker 0: I need a price of a plane ticket.
Speaker 1: I'm saying two grand would cover the plane tickets.
Speaker 0: Alright, and then I need a hotel to stay there, and then enough money to go from PAX, because I'm basically, if I'm going to go there, I'm going to go to PAX Aus, and then leave Melbourne immediately to go to the coral reef area.
Speaker 1: See, I'm landing in Sydney first, and I'm doing a professional conference.
Speaker 1: I'm lecturing, actually, on games at that.
Speaker 1: So, I'm doing a lecture called, I think, Games, Trades, Regulation.
Speaker 1: I forget what I'm doing.
Speaker 1: I've got to make slides for that.
Speaker 0: But, yeah, I want to go to PAX Aus, basically, like, a day before.
Speaker 0: See, you know, see the Melbourne stuff that now I'm familiar with.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 1: I'm going to go to Wilson's fucking Promontory this time.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: And I'm going to go to PAX Aus, and then I want to go to the coral reef area, which is far away.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh, I typed Wilson's into Google, and it didn't say Promontory.
Speaker 1: It said, uh, disease.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 0: Don't get that.
Speaker 0: Uh, just like, don't get your bullet.
Speaker 0: Go to the coral reef, hang out there for, like, a week or two, and then come back.
Speaker 0: So, that's how much money I need.
Speaker 1: Oh, also known as the prom.
Speaker 0: And to make up for the money I'm going to lose not working.
Speaker 1: Wilson's Promontory, also known as the prom, is Victoria's most loved place.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: Huh.
Speaker 1: Ooh.
Speaker 1: We really should have gone here.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, we were only there for so long.
Speaker 1: Take that Phillip Island hike we did and just multiply it by, like, a hundred.
Speaker 0: Uh, that's too long.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I will be at PAX Australia on Saturday presenting losing, and on Sunday presenting winning.
Speaker 0: I'll be in the United States chilling out, maybe streaming something, playing Netrunner, baking things.
Speaker 0: Someone at work today said, "Put cheddar cheese on an apple pie," and I said, "Fuck
Speaker 0: no.".
Speaker 1: That, I would do Swiss if I was going to do that.
Speaker 1: No, I would do Port Salut.
Speaker 0: I would not do any cheese.
Speaker 1: Port Salut.
Speaker 0: The only dairy product that belongs in apple pie is an ice cream.
Speaker 1: So, in Albany, right?
Speaker 1: Pete and Nury, they asked me if I wanted apple pie, and then they looked at each other like he doesn't know.
Speaker 0: How would they have apple pie that would be gluten free?
Speaker 1: You can make apple pie that's gluten free.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Pie crusts are actually one of the easier things to make gluten free.
Speaker 0: Why would you want a gluten free pie, though?
Speaker 1: Apples are the primary part of the pie.
Speaker 1: It's a good pie.
Speaker 0: Well, just have baked apples, then.
Speaker 1: So, instead of ice cream, they gave me white chocolate mousse.
Speaker 0: That's not a bad choice.
Speaker 1: It was dangerously good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: To the point that I ate so much.
Speaker 0: Was it actual white chocolate, or?
Speaker 1: It was actual white chocolate.
Speaker 1: Whoa.
Speaker 1: White chocolate mousse.
Speaker 1: It was so thick with caloric joy.
Speaker 0: Where do you get white chocolate mousse from?
Speaker 1: A mother makes it, is how you get that.
Speaker 0: That's how you get that.
Speaker 0: That mother doesn't have accurate recipes that I can follow.
Speaker 1: In fact, I asked, "What's the
Speaker 1: recipe?"
Speaker 1: Which was followed by more laughter and, "Will you take some amount of
Speaker 1: cream?".
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I can get the internet.
Speaker 0: The internet will help.
Speaker 1: So, the book club.
Speaker 1: A canticle for Leibowitz, which Scott chose.
Speaker 0: So, I chose this because, based on my knowledge of it, I thought it was in the genre of, it is a post-apocalyptic story, which it is, where specifically society has been sealed in.
Speaker 0: Such as in Logan's Run, or Phoenix Future, or Fallout, where the character, you're in a vault.
Speaker 1: Well, knowledge was sealed in.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: So, in the first chapter, it sort of is in that genre, right?
Speaker 0: Where it's about monks in a monastery that's far away from everything else.
Speaker 0: They're basically sealed.
Speaker 0: They encounter a vault where people were sealed at one point.
Speaker 0: But really, it's not about a society that is sealed in.
Speaker 0: It's about something completely different.
Speaker 0: So, I think it is not actually in that genre.
Speaker 1: I'm going to start off by saying that.
Speaker 1: It is definitely post-apocalyptic.
Speaker 0: It is the most post-apocalyptic.
Speaker 1: And it is one of the earlier instances of what we would call modern post-apocalyptic.
Speaker 1: Because I've heard most apocalypse stories before.
Speaker 1: books like this were floods, and mythology, and those kinds of things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is a pretty typical old-school sci-fi book in a post-apocalypse on Earth with a dystopian society and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Arguably, I guess, Mary Shelley's The Last Man is the first work in this genre of post-apocalypse.
Speaker 1: mechanical for liebowitz is widely regarded to be one of the earliest modern takes.
Speaker 1: A lot of people point to this as being the precursor.
Speaker 1: Like, a lot of books are based on this book in some fashion.
Speaker 1: Though, I suspect that that number is dwindling because this book seems to be increasingly unknown.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I heard more about it.
Speaker 0: That's why it came up.
Speaker 0: It came up in so many places.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It seems to come up in the same circles that a lot of our Book Club books come up in.
Speaker 1: That is not pop nerd culture at all.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the book is really sort of these three books that are loosely tied together, covering three periods in history of this post-apocalypse world.
Speaker 0: So the first one is still long after the apocalypse, but not so long after it.
Speaker 0: The second part is hundreds of years after that.
Speaker 1: It's like Renaissance, and then Space Future.
Speaker 0: And then the third part is way after the apocalypse.
Speaker 1: Now, if you guys read it, it's the Book Club.
Speaker 1: Spoilers.
Speaker 1: We're going to talk about the book and assume you read it.
Speaker 1: So if you didn't read A Canticle for Leibowitz, you should go read it before you listen, because we're not going to explain any of the plot.
Speaker 1: We're assuming you read it.
Speaker 1: Also, I read it a long-ass time ago, so my memory might be fuzzy.
Speaker 1: I already lost -- like, I had a bunch of specific parts I wanted to quote.
Speaker 1: I don't remember any of that anymore.
Speaker 0: That's okay.
Speaker 1: But if I had to summarize it, the moral of the first one, the Fiat Homo, is basically the church survives Renaissance dark ages, humans always have dark ages.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: And then monks in monasteries and staticness.
Speaker 1: The feeling of Fiat Homo, it feels like it's the idea of being static, that whenever there's a dark age, whenever society falls behind, parts of it wall themselves off, and they can't innovate.
Speaker 1: They become entirely static.
Speaker 1: So these monks, generation by generation, nothing changes.
Speaker 1: Nothing changes.
Speaker 1: That chapter drills it into your head that fucking nothing has happened as far back as anyone can remember.
Speaker 0: Right, he's making a commentary on the history of our existing world by showing you this new history of a world that happens after our world ends.
Speaker 0: A human society emerges after ours, presumably the real one that we live in now, ends.
Speaker 0: And then it's like, oh, it goes through the same exact shit that this one went through.
Speaker 0: And the first chapter goes through the dark age where there is still some sort of intelligence, but really it's a dark age and there isn't any overall.
Speaker 0: So the people who have it need to wall off and protect it and weather the storm.
Speaker 1: It's static and ritualized.
Speaker 1: The spores of society become static, become unchanging, become ritualized, and their only purpose is to replicate that data such to the point that when society catches up to where they can understand its meaning, you get chapter two.
Speaker 0: In a way, they're a time capsule.
Speaker 1: That story was actually my favorite.
Speaker 1: I enjoyed the book less as it went on.
Speaker 0: I agree.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess I cared less.
Speaker 1: I like the interplay between the guy who runs the monastery and the main character because the main character was way smarter than everyone gave him credit for.
Speaker 0: But he was so humble.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: But the other thing, that first chapter, I think the other reason I liked it more is because it gives you the world-building.
Speaker 0: The second and third chapters, the world has already been built by the first chapter, so they sort of just take it for granted.
Speaker 0: Whereas the first one's a bit longer.
Speaker 0: It's sort of explaining to you, introducing you to this post-apocalyptic world, and that part is just really interesting.
Speaker 0: So you're like, "Oh, it went down like
Speaker 0: this.".
Speaker 1: It's definitely, I believe, the first novel like this to use in this post-apocalypse.
Speaker 1: the idea of the reader knows more than the characters.
Speaker 1: So there's one point where they're obviously referring to resistors, like the resistors that actually most of you Geek Guys listeners have probably never seen.
Speaker 1: So that reference would be lost.
Speaker 1: But the kinds of resistors I played with when I was a kid that I'd buy at Radio Shack with little colored bands, there are a lot of references like that that are obviously looking to the reader and going, "You know what these are.
Speaker 1: You know what's going
Speaker 1: on.".
Speaker 1: And I see that trope used a lot recently in stories like this.
Speaker 0: He's making a bunch of little points along the way.
Speaker 0: When he's talking about the blueprints, like, "Why did they put white on
Speaker 0: blue?"
Speaker 0: It's like, "It makes no
Speaker 0: sense.".
Speaker 0: And he's coloring in the whole thing, trying to reproduce, just assuming that the people from the ancient pre-apocalypse smarter times knew better.
Speaker 1: I mean, think.
Speaker 1: Say I didn't know anything about computers and I found a computer in a post-apocalypse and I was trying to make it work again and make a new one, I would copy it exactly, not understanding why I was doing what I was doing.
Speaker 0: And do a lot of things that are dumb and be like, "Why did they do it this
Speaker 0: way?".
Speaker 0: It's like, "Well, because there's other things you don't
Speaker 0: know.".
Speaker 0: It's just interesting to think about recovering, just having the artifacts and then trying to recover the knowledge.
Speaker 0: That's what we do with archaeology in this world, when we look at ancient artifacts from some old civilization.
Speaker 0: We think we get it right, but you look at them and it's like, "Oh, it's obvious he's doing archaeology on our artifacts and look at him fucking
Speaker 0: up.".
Speaker 0: But it's sort of obvious how he fucks up, but we're fucking up in that same way with the archaeology that we do.
Speaker 0: We're probably much better at it than them because we are more advanced, looking at something less advanced, but even so.
Speaker 1: In a way, I found this interesting because most of the stories I read like this, the future society doesn't understand that the past was more advanced.
Speaker 1: In this story, every character is like, they know pretty much what went down.
Speaker 1: They know that there was a nuclear war.
Speaker 1: They understand the danger of those things.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like Adventure Time, like the Mushroom War.
Speaker 0: They have funny names for it, but they sort of know.
Speaker 1: How Liebowitzch is basically just like this nuclear engineer, just worked in the facility and had some personal drama, and how he became a saint, and I like that whole story there.
Speaker 1: I was disappointed, however, that St.
Speaker 1: Liebowitzch was a legit supernatural entity, as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: Yeah, from what I can tell, he was as well.
Speaker 1: That is the only part of this book I did not like.
Speaker 0: It didn't really seem to matter too much because he hardly appears or does anything notable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you could try to make an argument about maybe it was an allegory or something, but I just don't see that having been Walter Miller's intent.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: I feel like these books were written semi-rambly.
Speaker 1: I feel like when he was writing them, he was exploring these ideas, and I think his main goal was just to impress upon people the cyclical nature of human society, and how we're on the edge of a dark age again.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, this was written in a Cold War time.
Speaker 1: I mean, it was written in, what, 1960?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That was one of the most dangerous times in all of human history.
Speaker 0: Right, so he's writing like, "Don't have nuclear war, guys," and that was the time that we could have had it.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, he was almost arguing that it's inevitable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, it wasn't yet.
Speaker 1: Because look at the third part at the end.
Speaker 1: The spaceship goes into space.
Speaker 1: It's a monastery in space now because the second chapter will always happen.
Speaker 1: The Fiat Lux, the second chapter is basically suddenly the world catches up, and smart people can figure out what this shit all meant, but how the monasteries on their own were not capable of doing it on their own.
Speaker 1: They were only doing it for academic purpose.
Speaker 1: Someone has a practical purpose, and suddenly the world advances very quickly, and then the third chapter is they're going to nuke again and monastery in space.
Speaker 0: You wonder, was there a monastery in space the first time, right?
Speaker 0: Because this is the second nuclear war that happens on this planet Earth, this fictional Earth, and the second one, they have nukes, and they have spaceships at the same time, and the first one, didn't they have spaceships and nukes at the same time or not?
Speaker 1: If it was written in 1960, at that time, we did not have spaceships that were really capable of anything like that, and it seems like the nuclear war happened around that time.
Speaker 1: They had not gotten too far, as far as I could tell, technologically, beyond what was predicted in the near future.
Speaker 0: The technology in that third chapter is a bit weird, where some things are way advanced, like you can just walk onto the spaceship in your sandals.
Speaker 1: But his conception of a computer.
Speaker 0: It has a nuclear drive, and you can just go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the computer is like ENIAC, and it draws instead of having a monitor.
Speaker 1: Well, that part made sense, because computers were kind of like that back then.
Speaker 0: But
Speaker 1: it's interesting how they implied a lot of highly advanced capabilities to a lot of other things, but computers, as he envisioned them, were not significantly advanced in any interesting way beyond what existed at that time, and yet simultaneously had a few powers that to this day are basically impossible.
Speaker 0: Right, but it's like he could somehow imagine technologies being super advanced in some aspects, but couldn't imagine them being advanced at all in other aspects.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though it seems like the space stuff was the only thing that was really super advanced.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the medicine wasn't advanced, really, at all.
Speaker 1: It was partly just because he needed that for his plot at the end, I think.
Speaker 0: I guess so.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, the first chapter is pretty much this dark age.
Speaker 0: The second chapter is this renaissance, where people suddenly actually care what the monks are up to, right?
Speaker 0: But the monks are only inventing light bulbs and getting all Thomas Edison, because research.
Speaker 0: They don't actually want anyone to have light bulbs everywhere.
Speaker 0: But then, of course, the dude from far away comes, and he wants light bulbs everywhere, and he's like, "Oh,
Speaker 0: shit.".
Speaker 0: But the one thing in that chapter that actually stood out as interesting to me, because the rest of it was kind of eh, was the fact that it's like that guy, you know, the guy who thought he was the hot shit, I forget his name, he realized, you know, he was all proud of being a smart inventor, but because this was the second society, he was really only a discoverer.
Speaker 0: He couldn't be an inventor.
Speaker 0: There was no way he could be an inventor of anything.
Speaker 0: All he could do is rediscover things that were already invented.
Speaker 0: And it's like, whoa.
Speaker 0: Imagine, like, your whole life, you spend discovering shit, but it's like, no.
Speaker 0: Your whole life has to go into this, and knowing that you put all this hard work in, but there were previous people who were way ahead of you, and you will never catch up to them ever.
Speaker 0: There's no chance.
Speaker 0: And all you're doing is you're discovering and not actually inventing.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And also, simultaneously there, the idea that if secular, there's definitely this vibe that if secular, pragmatic uses of technology are brought about, nuclear war is inevitable again.
Speaker 1: There's no way around that.
Speaker 1: That's definitely heavily implied by the way the book is put together.
Speaker 1: Though, the third chapter felt really rambly, like the section about whether or not to let the woman commit suicide.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I mean, like, half--.
Speaker 1: It really zoomed in on that for a long time.
Speaker 0: So that third part is like 50% nuclear war, and 50% let's talk about abortion and euthanasia.
Speaker 0: And it's like, what?
Speaker 0: Was he trying to tie them together?
Speaker 0: Because he really didn't tie them together at all.
Speaker 0: They were just sort of like two separate topics.
Speaker 1: The best way I could tie them together, this is kind of--.
Speaker 0: Does he want to say that God is punishing everyone with nuclear war?
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: This is kind of a stretch.
Speaker 1: So here's the way, if I were in high school, and I had to write a paper on this book, what I would say is that the woman deciding whether or not to euthanize herself and her child is basically an allegory for society, because the woman knows she will die horribly.
Speaker 1: Society knows if it continues, it will nuke itself.
Speaker 1: Her choice is to stop the cycle and not exist, or accept her fate and die by the nuclear flame, knowing that society will be rewarded.
Speaker 1: That's where the analogy starts to break down already, because her kid won't survive if she does that.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, if everybody committed suicide, there'd never be another nuclear war.
Speaker 1: If society did not advance, if the second chapter didn't happen, you can never have a nuclear war.
Speaker 1: But it's hard to say what the author was advocating.
Speaker 0: Well, he's definitely advocating against nuclear war.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone's advocating for nuclear war.
Speaker 1: But was he pro- or anti-euthanasia, the author?
Speaker 1: Because the character, the priest, was against it.
Speaker 0: And the priest stayed against it.
Speaker 0: It wasn't one of those obvious ones where the priest sees the light at the end.
Speaker 1: And also, the whole thing was futile at that point anyway.
Speaker 1: And the priest was not portrayed terribly sympathetically in the book.
Speaker 1: He's kind of portrayed as this old, crufty priest.
Speaker 0: Well, the first thing they say in that third chapter is, "Yeah, this abbot was quick to action and didn't sit around thinking about things for a long
Speaker 0: time.".
Speaker 0: And the other ones in the first two chapters were the kind of person who would think, and is very impulsive and whatnot.
Speaker 0: And then you see him exhibiting those characteristics.
Speaker 1: Him and the church are kind of portrayed as adding to the suffering here.
Speaker 1: The book is very ambivalent on the issue.
Speaker 1: At least as far as I could read.
Speaker 1: Again, this is going from- I read this a long time ago.
Speaker 0: But also, at the same time, they're the ones who are saving, I guess, whatever.
Speaker 0: But what I find interesting is that- So, in the very first chapter, they're all about protecting the memorabilia, the things from the first civilization that are so important.
Speaker 1: Because they know that one day they'll be able to figure out what they are.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: At the end of the third chapter, they go into space again.
Speaker 0: And what do they bring with them?
Speaker 0: The shit from the first civilization.
Speaker 0: They didn't bring memorabilia from their own second civilization.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: The history of the second civilization is just, like, unimportant.
Speaker 0: It's like the first civilization is the one that, I guess, matters.
Speaker 0: Anything that happened in the second one, they couldn't even remember.
Speaker 0: They had all this history of the first civilization, but you see him lying there at the end, and he's got a bone with an arrow in it.
Speaker 0: It's clearly- we know who that is.
Speaker 1: What's his name from the first book?
Speaker 0: Right, but they don't have their own history down.
Speaker 0: They didn't record any of their own history.
Speaker 0: They were so obsessed with the history of that first civilization.
Speaker 1: Well, that's where this book gets complicated.
Speaker 1: Because there's a way to read this, I think, where if you look at the second chapter and really think about it, the church's preservation of the previous era was irrelevant.
Speaker 1: Those smart people were discovering these things and inventing them.
Speaker 1: The only reason they couldn't invent new things is because the knowledge already existed.
Speaker 1: But look at how far they'd gotten before they got access to that memorabilia.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that guy was on the verge of lightbulb, and they only barely beat him to the punch on lightbulb because they had the memorabilia.
Speaker 0: It was barely helpful.
Speaker 1: Whether or not it's intentional, this book is arguing that the preservation aspect of the church is irrelevant.
Speaker 0: As long as you preserved humans, right?
Speaker 0: And they can live and have resources.
Speaker 0: They're going to figure out the same things humans figured out again with just enough time.
Speaker 1: I don't know if the author intended this to be read this way, but it's very easy to interpret this book as though- Doesn't matter what the author intended, right?
Speaker 1: I think this is the one case where it does.
Speaker 1: Not the one case, but the reason I think it matters is that the book is obviously the author exploring these ideas at a time when the world is literally actually dealing with these ideas.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: If we were in the '60s, this book would be a completely different read if we read it when it was written.
Speaker 0: Yes, because in the '60s- What is this book?
Speaker 0: We don't care about the '60s.
Speaker 0: We care about today.
Speaker 0: We don't care about then.
Speaker 0: Then doesn't matter to us.
Speaker 0: We're reading this book.
Speaker 0: We're alive today.
Speaker 0: That's what is important.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but also, I was reading his history.
Speaker 1: He converted to Catholicism after the war.
Speaker 1: I think he was a tail gunner and a radio man in bombers, and he bombed a Catholic church as part of his duties being a bomber.
Speaker 1: Some other guy said- That's definitely irrelevant.
Speaker 1: That he suffered from post-traumatic stress disorder.
Speaker 0: Makes sense.
Speaker 0: I would too.
Speaker 1: This is a man who saw the horrors of war, perpetuated them, not saying the war was bad or unjustified, but saying that he was a bomber.
Speaker 1: That's what he did.
Speaker 1: He lived in the shadow of nuclear annihilation, and he wrote a book about it.
Speaker 1: You cannot read this book, but in the context of the world at that time.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: Because a lot of the stuff in the third chapter, there's a lot of terminology that I think would not be recognized by kids today because kids today don't really think about nuclear war the way that our parents thought about it.
Speaker 0: Isn't that a good thing?
Speaker 1: I think it is definitely a good thing.
Speaker 1: I feel like human society got to at least one major precipice, and we all collectively said, "Okay, guys, let's just back up a little
Speaker 1: bit.".
Speaker 0: Actually, I read something recently.
Speaker 0: The US was going to basically dismantle a bunch of nukes like we do because we don't really need them.
Speaker 1: And we didn't.
Speaker 1: in case we have to blow up an asteroid.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: I'm sure some nut out there is going to be like, "Oh, see?
Speaker 0: They're just making up excuses to keep a bunch of nukes
Speaker 0: around.".
Speaker 0: But actually, I kind of believe that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I feel like we should still keep the nukes that we have right now.
Speaker 0: I don't really believe that nukes are definitely going to save us from an asteroid, but what else do we have?
Speaker 0: I'd rather shoot them and try than just sit there and get hit by an asteroid.
Speaker 1: I still think we need to keep them from a complicated geopolitical game theory perspective.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 1: That's a separate discussion.
Speaker 1: But think about it.
Speaker 1: We just read a book on the horrors of nuclear war and the inevitability of nuclear war so long as humans make nukes, yet I still feel like we should not destroy all the nukes we have because I don't trust everybody.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the one thing in this book that really kind of -- I had no idea what it was there for, but it was fun -- is the poet guy.
Speaker 1: That poet guy.
Speaker 0: That poet guy is kind of awesome.
Speaker 1: He reminded me of the poet in Hyperion.
Speaker 1: He did.
Speaker 0: We all felt like the Hyperion poet, and he felt like a little bit of choose goose going on.
Speaker 0: I can see that.
Speaker 0: A little bit of choose goose.
Speaker 1: I can totally see that.
Speaker 0: I was kind of into him as a character.
Speaker 0: He was all cool and, you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, I couldn't understand what his meaning was to anything whatsoever, and then they bring him up again in the third chapter as sort of another one of those.
Speaker 0: they don't know their own history, they don't remember who the poet was, you know, the poet of the eyeball or something.
Speaker 0: What is the meaning of the glass eye?
Speaker 0: I have no fucking clue.
Speaker 0: I couldn't even guess.
Speaker 1: The eye of knowledge.
Speaker 1: I had a bunch of notes I wrote down, but they don't make sense to me now because I read the book a while ago.
Speaker 0: Right, and is there -- the only thing I could think of was like -- so the poet was sort of like the guy without an eye.
Speaker 0: was the sort of poet character of the third chapter, the lady with two heads?
Speaker 0: Was that sort of like the --?
Speaker 0: and then who was the poet character of the first chapter?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Well, the lady with two heads and the quote "miracle" there was interesting because -- That could have easily been a hallucination, too.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I was half -- you know, going on the hallucination -- or he was already in some sort of afterlife seeing that shit.
Speaker 1: So let's go yet again to reading this book in a particular way.
Speaker 1: So we have -- you know, Leibowitz becomes a saint, and there's this mythology around his life and his wife and all those things based on incomplete knowledge.
Speaker 1: There's the skull of the guy who got shot with the arrow.
Speaker 1: There's all these legends -- the eye.
Speaker 1: The fact that the eye thing was, from a literal reading, a totally just generic -- you know, the guy just had the eye, and the famous guy tried to give it back to him and couldn't, and you can see how later there became a mythology around this completely mundane and kind of humorous event.
Speaker 1: A mundane and humorous event became a for real serious mythology once enough time had passed.
Speaker 1: So the miracles of the Bible and all the times before these books even take place could easily be misinterpretations and failings of human memory from mundane events of that era, and him seeing that vision at the end could just be him hallucinating or interpreting something in a way that would make sense in light of his mythology.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of ways to read this book that basically really put down religion, the church, and preservationism.
Speaker 0: For someone who converted to a Catholic.
Speaker 1: But even though on a surface level, I think people who read this book and don't think about it too much would say it says the exact opposite.
Speaker 0: A deeper read -- it's almost like -- I almost feel like -- You can read it either way, and maybe that was intentional, right?
Speaker 0: Whether you're Catholic or not or anything else, religious or non, you'll read it and you can basically feel like it was telling you that you're right, but it's always telling you you're right, nukes are bad.
Speaker 1: Yep, I found some essays where people very passionately argued opposite positions on whether or not the book was pro or anti-euthanasia.
Speaker 1: I think Luke Burge even posted some of that stuff.
Speaker 1: That's why I was reading it.
Speaker 0: But either way, it makes you think about it, and it presents pretty much all the arguments both ways.
Speaker 1: May I present a crazy idea?
Speaker 0: It presents religious arguments a lot, but it presents secular arguments in both directions as well.
Speaker 1: I wonder if Miller, writing this book -- Didn't have a firm conviction himself?
Speaker 1: Or even if he thought he did, in actually exploring the idea, he went from optimistic to cynical in every chapter.
Speaker 1: That him writing, he started to see the flaws in the optimistic or religious arguments, and then started undermining them either consciously or not.
Speaker 1: Also, a note here about his life that might be relevant.
Speaker 0: It's going to be.
Speaker 1: After the success of Mechanical for Leibovitz, Miller never published another novel or story in his lifetime.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: In Miller's later years -- How successful was it when he wrote it?
Speaker 0: Really successful.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: He became a recluse, avoided his family, lived alone, never talked to his literary agent, never let him meet him.
Speaker 0: He was protecting the memorabilia.
Speaker 1: Struggled with depression, wrote a 600-page manuscript as a sequel to Mechanical for Leibovitz, and then took his own life with a gun.
Speaker 0: Where's the manuscript?
Speaker 1: In 1996.
Speaker 1: The sequel, St.
Speaker 1: Leibovitz and the Wild Horsewoman, was completed and published in 1997.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 0: We should read the sequel.
Speaker 0: No, we shouldn't.
Speaker 0: It's 600 pages.
Speaker 1: Set 80 years after the events of the second part, so it takes place between the second and third part, so I feel like this is gonna be a fall of Hyperion.
Speaker 0: I feel like there's no reason to read 600 pages.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's all about Texark stuff.
Speaker 0: That are written by a guy who is a crazy hermit in the woods.
Speaker 1: This looks like pulpy drama rather than serious exploration of nuclear holocaust.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you sort of had that sort of, you know, that Texarkana.
Speaker 0: That really felt more like a fallout.
Speaker 0: Like, you could see hints of that coming in, the plot of a fallout kind of world.
Speaker 0: When they were talking about the different bandit groups out there.
Speaker 0: There was this other universe where fallout kind of stuff was happening, but it was far away, and it only barely interacted with the characters of any of these chapters.
Speaker 1: So, I'm glad I read it, because it's such a precursor work to a lot of other things.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I enjoyed it that much.
Speaker 0: I mean, it didn't just take me a long time to read, because it was summertime.
Speaker 0: It's because any time I was sitting there, and there was a list of media to consume, it did not rank highly at any given moment.
Speaker 0: I mean, once I actually started, the first chapter went by pretty quickly.
Speaker 0: Then I didn't start the second one.
Speaker 0: And I feel actually the fact that it was split into chapters also sort of delayed the reading, because once I finished a chapter, it's like I didn't want to start the next one.
Speaker 0: But once I started one, I was able to go through it.
Speaker 1: But then again, look at books that are written, like The Prince of Nothing is an example.
Speaker 1: A lot of times, they're reading a chapter that follows a character, and I'm really invested in that.
Speaker 1: And then the chapter ends, and the next chapter is about a character I don't care about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a good time I'll stop.
Speaker 1: But, if I read more than one paragraph of that next page, Oh, forget it.
Speaker 1: Now I'm invested.
Speaker 0: And then, if you finish that chapter, it goes back to the other character.
Speaker 1: And then you're like, "Oh shit, Ryan, I wonder what Kellis is up
Speaker 1: to.".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But this is completely different.
Speaker 0: It's like three stories in one that are barely, they're not barely related, but it's not like you're skipping around different characters at the same point in the same story.
Speaker 0: It's really three short stories in the same universe with a tiny thread connecting them.
Speaker 0: And each one makes a lot of subtle and disparate points.
Speaker 1: I like Robotechs.
Speaker 1: Well, look at when the guy, I keep thinking, it's maybe not Catterley, but I was thinking of him as Catterley, the smart dumb monk in the beginning.
Speaker 0: Oh, I forget.
Speaker 1: You don't remember his name either.
Speaker 0: I don't remember names from people in books.
Speaker 1: He's surviving the war.
Speaker 1: Albertian order of Leibovitz.
Speaker 1: What's the guy's fucking name, Wikipedia?
Speaker 1: What's the guy's fucking name?
Speaker 1: Doesn't say whatever.
Speaker 0: I can just look through the book here, but it's an e-book, so it's kind of hard.
Speaker 1: So, reading the book from, just reading that first section, there's a bit about how he goes to the pope.
Speaker 0: Oh, yep, yep.
Speaker 1: And that long section about how overwhelming the experience of being in that place is and how different it is from the monastery and how it overwhelms the senses and it's so large and powerful and thick with portents.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, it's sort of run down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then after he's not overwhelmed by it anymore and he talks to the pope, he realizes that it's not any different.
Speaker 1: It's just more worldly.
Speaker 1: Everything's run down.
Speaker 1: The symbols are more powerful than the reality and the idea that that's why people are hustled in and out.
Speaker 1: The church has all this symbolic power, but no real power, but the symbolic power works unless you let people hang around too long or look too closely.
Speaker 1: It also has the whole bit about, not iconoclasm, but the book-leggers trying to save knowledge from the fact that when the apocalypse happens, there's a lot of survivors.
Speaker 1: It's a much more realistic nuclear war than most stories and the survivors destroy all knowledge because fuck those guys.
Speaker 1: And that whole section has a lot of interesting ideas, but again, they're all over the place.
Speaker 1: The rampaging mobs who call themselves simpletons, it's a lot like the Luddites.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it's in a way, right?
Speaker 0: The book is, again, you can find things in this book to support.
Speaker 0: Whoever wrote this book was a Luddite.
Speaker 0: He wanted anti-technology.
Speaker 0: You could also say the opposite.
Speaker 0: He shows how awesome all that technology is in the third chapter, except nukes.
Speaker 1: He was a sad, disturbed, complicated person.
Speaker 1: Who had a complicated, evolving view of what all these things meant.
Speaker 1: And this book is him exploring these ideas.
Speaker 1: And that's all it is.
Speaker 1: It's him exploring the ideas.
Speaker 1: The book, the chapters don't end with like, "Oh, that is what I should think.
Speaker 1: That is the
Speaker 1: moral.".
Speaker 1: The book ends with, "Wow, that's a lot of ideas and things are
Speaker 1: complicated.".
Speaker 1: So I guess I like it on that front.
Speaker 1: It's a lot like trying to interpret the man who was Thursday.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: In that regard.
Speaker 0: Only a lot less action.
Speaker 1: Though at the same time, the action in The Man Who Was Thursday was largely incomprehensible, but that's just an artifact of the writing.
Speaker 1: Thaddio.
Speaker 1: That's the cool guy.
Speaker 1: Thon Thaddio.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: I like Thon Thaddio.
Speaker 0: That's a good name, too.
Speaker 1: I like how Thon Thaddio was, he realized the danger of what he was doing, but he did it anyway, but he tried to be honorable.
Speaker 1: He's just a fun character.
Speaker 1: I liked him.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Is there anything else to say about this book?
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: It's relatively short, actually.
Speaker 0: I shouldn't have taken that long to read it if I actually tried.
Speaker 0: I mean, once I started reading the third chapter, it took literally like a day.
Speaker 0: Not even, like a couple hours.
Speaker 0: So you could probably read the book in eight hours total.
Speaker 1: Yep, easily.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.