Speaker 0: It's Monday December 15th, 2014.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 0: Strong artificial intelligence and why it's probably going to destroy us.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: And why?
Speaker 0: if you have a better idea for a Monday show, you should email us.
Speaker 0: Geeknights@frontrowcrew.com or post it on our forum.
Speaker 1: If you posted an idea and we haven't used it, it's because your idea was bad.
Speaker 0: Or we just forgot, so post it again.
Speaker 1: But you'd be surprised how hard it is to come with a valid idea.
Speaker 0: Well, I feel like really what we need to do is when people suggest an idea.
Speaker 1: We should tell them why we can't do it, like Kineticon feedback panel.
Speaker 0: We should do the show about it to show them why.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it comes down to some of these topics.
Speaker 1: I don't want to make a bad show, though.
Speaker 0: We've technically already talked about them in enough depth to where that should be fine.
Speaker 1: Like a news or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people don't search or they're things that would require research, which we don't got time for that.
Speaker 0: If we're going to do research and do like a for real thing about something we don't know.
Speaker 1: That's just us reading Internet and then saying what we saw on the Internet.
Speaker 1: And also you can just read the Internet yourself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not going to be geek nights.
Speaker 0: That would be like a YouTube video like how to set up NTP with RIM.
Speaker 1: How to read the Wikipedia page on this topic out loud.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or possibly synthesizing the Wikipedia with one or two technical documents.
Speaker 0: Or it's a topic that we just think is stupid or boring and we don't have a lot to say.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's like nothing to say about it or it doesn't fit or et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 0: I feel like we could do a lot more Monday shows if we started focusing more on.
Speaker 1: Also, a lot of the people things people suggest are overly broad and not nearly specific enough.
Speaker 1: Or they're so specific that there isn't 30 minutes of stuff to say about them.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: In which case we should just do a tech news round.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Actually, we should do that more often.
Speaker 0: We could.
Speaker 0: we could do the show every week just looking at whatever's on the front page.
Speaker 1: But then why even make this show?
Speaker 1: Because there are 100 podcasts that do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And the awesome thing is, like I've tried to listen to a lot of those podcasts.
Speaker 0: Those people don't know shit and those podcasts are really bad.
Speaker 0: We could do it better, but that's like being better at a sport that you're good at, but you don't like.
Speaker 0: Like making really boring and simple analogies and similes that do exactly like they're.
Speaker 0: so they're so functional and pragmatic.
Speaker 1: What's your news?
Speaker 0: So in the news, I got two things.
Speaker 0: I got some science and I got some technology being misunderstood and used inappropriately by people who should know better.
Speaker 0: So in science news, evolution is winning our war on HIV and AIDS for us.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 0: So something awesome is happening.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, HIV itself has the same evolution powers that we do.
Speaker 1: In fact, it should be even faster at evolution than people.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: And this is what's happening.
Speaker 1: So shouldn't it be winning against us?
Speaker 0: Ah, so here's what's happening.
Speaker 0: You know what it is?
Speaker 0: It's winning the battles, thereby losing the war.
Speaker 0: So what is happening?
Speaker 0: And I'll link to a slash article that links to an abstract from Oxford and an article explaining this in more detail.
Speaker 0: And I apologize to any of our virologist friends, both of you who are going to yell at me for getting this wrong.
Speaker 1: You're going to be so wrong.
Speaker 1: I'm glad this isn't my news.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to try to say this without saying anything that they can actually call me out on for.
Speaker 1: Well, you're an expert at that.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: So HIV, the virus that causes AIDS, is becoming less virulent in the sense that...
Speaker 1: What does virulent even mean?
Speaker 0: So it replicates more slowly because in order... Basically, some people are more resistant to AIDS.
Speaker 0: Obviously.
Speaker 0: If they get HIV, they get AIDS, you know, the syndrome that's caused by the eventually depleted immune system, depleted by HIV later.
Speaker 0: Those people are more effectively treatable by drugs.
Speaker 0: So in order to replicate better among those people, it replicates slower to avoid triggering the immune responses when the immune system is particularly strong.
Speaker 0: When it replicates slower, it's more effectively able to be treated, and this is becoming something that we are now able to measure.
Speaker 0: AIDS replicates 10% lower in Botswana than it does in South Africa.
Speaker 0: The virus is literally evolving in the places where we can't treat it that effectively.
Speaker 0: to replicate slower and effectively be more treatable because of the selection pressures of the people who are able to spread it and the demographics of those regions and all these things.
Speaker 0: Golder added that the average time from infection to the onset of AIDS has increased 25% over the past decade.
Speaker 0: So if this evolutionary trend in HIV continues, HIV is rapidly becoming a disease that is not that dangerous.
Speaker 1: Well, if it starts losing by going slow, won't it start going faster?
Speaker 1: Some HIV mutation will make it go faster.
Speaker 1: That one will catch on all over the place.
Speaker 0: It's tricky because if you go too fast as a virus like this and you kill your host, you're not spreading anymore.
Speaker 0: And if you go super slow and spread more widely but do less damage, you might spread more widely but people are less worried about it.
Speaker 1: So you just wait until everyone in the world has the AIDS and then you go fast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's my strategy when I play pandemic as a virus.
Speaker 1: So this article is fascinating.
Speaker 0: Read the actual article because it describes this in much better detail than I ever could.
Speaker 0: But the gist of it is evolution is happening in HIV and it's actually working out.
Speaker 0: It's like the one time when the thing that's happening that's demonstrable by science is actually the thing we kind of want.
Speaker 0: Like the good answer happens.
Speaker 0: Not like with space, like oh yeah, you'll never get to any other stars.
Speaker 0: Fuck you, speed of light.
Speaker 0: Like this time the answer actually fell our way.
Speaker 0: Like everything's coming up Milhouse.
Speaker 0: So in other news, Flickr is a platform that allows you to share your photos.
Speaker 0: And it is actually, still in my opinion, the best platform in the world to do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, it's the oldest.
Speaker 1: You might not prefer the interface but it's a good interface.
Speaker 0: Everyone, what are you going to use?
Speaker 0: Fucking Picasa?
Speaker 0: Picasa's bullshit.
Speaker 1: Facebook, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, there's some fancy ones like 500px and shit like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, however, Flickr costs a reasonable amount of money.
Speaker 1: Right, that's the biggest thing Flickr has going for it and the reason I've used it forever is because for a flat annual fee that is incredibly low, it's like 25 a year or something like that, it's so cheap.
Speaker 1: You get 100% absolutely unlimited space.
Speaker 1: Now there are other services that can give you unlimited space for a reasonable amount of money but those services do not have the photo abilities of Flickr which pretty much takes care of absolutely all of your photo needs ever.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: It's also one of the few things Yahoo has that's actually good so they're not going to let it die.
Speaker 1: Well, they bought it.
Speaker 1: They didn't make it.
Speaker 0: No, but of everything that Yahoo owns...
Speaker 1: Yahoo Sports and Weather are good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was about to say Yahoo Sports, Yahoo Weather, and Yahoo Online Games.
Speaker 0: That plus Flickr is all Yahoo's got going for them.
Speaker 0: So Flickr has an option where you can pick the license for your thing.
Speaker 1: Like Flickr was always... Every photo sharing site needs to have that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Flickr does a really good job about it.
Speaker 1: They were one of the first places to offer that feature.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they offer that pretty much from the beginning.
Speaker 0: And even better, they give you every useful option.
Speaker 0: So I can choose all rights reserved, non-commercial, no derivatives, non-commercial, share alike, non-commercial, no derivatives, share alike, or just attribution which is what I use because I don't care.
Speaker 0: Do whatever the fuck you want with my pictures.
Speaker 1: I don't think I have pictures that are going to make me any money.
Speaker 1: So if you can make money from them, well, that means I'll get noticed and then I'll make money from the next one.
Speaker 0: And if I don't get noticed, I wasn't going to make money anyway.
Speaker 1: You know how many photos there are in the world?
Speaker 1: One individual photo is worth nothing.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: If I took a really good photo of a bridge and some magazine uses that instead of paying a guy who took a slightly better photo.
Speaker 0: Sucks for slightly better photo guy, but good enough photo works fine.
Speaker 1: Magazine didn't sell extra copies because of your photo.
Speaker 0: So basically what's happening is there's a bunch of sensationalist articles going around about how Flickr is selling your Creative Commons photos for profit and not giving any of that to you.
Speaker 1: This reminds me of the story back in the day.
Speaker 1: Some guy in the UK was putting Firefox on a CD and selling it.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: I knew a guy at RIT who sold people CDs with like Nessus or whatever on it and that's all totally OK.
Speaker 1: There's nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 1: Hey, anyone want to buy Ubuntu?
Speaker 1: I got some Ubuntu CDs here.
Speaker 1: Ubuntu CDs.
Speaker 1: $10.
Speaker 0: In fact, if anyone would like to buy for me a really modern Linux operating system, I will happily sell it to you for like under $10,000.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, totally.
Speaker 0: In fact, it'll be compatible with Red Hat.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: So basically morons are mad because they actively tagged their Flickr photos as being attribution only.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, the default is all rights reserved.
Speaker 1: Meaning you're set to attribution only.
Speaker 1: That means you specifically and consciously made a decision or accidentally clicked a not easy to click box to specifically say I want everyone in the Internet to be able to use these photos for anything that they want ever.
Speaker 1: Just give me credit.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So other people, because there is a non-commercial option, you can trivially say anyone's allowed to use my photo unless they use it commercially.
Speaker 0: But these people didn't do that.
Speaker 0: What Flickr is doing is anything on Flickr that's flagged as being usable commercially under Creative Commons license, you can just buy prints and they just take the money and they send the person to print with an attribution sticker and attribution stuff.
Speaker 1: So someone else can go to my Flickr account, see one of my photos, give Flickr money.
Speaker 1: Flickr will print my photo and send it to them and not give me any money and give me the credit, which is all I asked for.
Speaker 0: Do you know how awesome that is?
Speaker 1: That's actually pretty cool.
Speaker 1: You could buy prints of your own photos without having to print them out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or like...
Speaker 1: And they're probably going to be way high quality.
Speaker 0: If my mom wants a print of something, she can just do it on her own.
Speaker 0: She doesn't even need to talk to me.
Speaker 0: So literally everyone who is mad about this is one, using technology improperly, two, actively made a poor decision, and three, misunderstands the ramifications of that active, poor decision.
Speaker 0: If you don't know what you're clicking on, either don't click on it or read the documentation, or click on it and accept the consequences of what you clicked on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't complain about it.
Speaker 1: It'd be one thing if the default was attribution only, but it's not.
Speaker 1: So shut up.
Speaker 0: And these people are really mad.
Speaker 0: and there's all this vitriol going around about how Flickr's selling my photos without permission.
Speaker 0: Like, no, Flickr's selling them with your express permission.
Speaker 1: Explicit, expressed written consent.
Speaker 1: You gave it.
Speaker 0: To use a real world analogy, this would be like if I took a table, like an old table, and I put it... And this is a real story.
Speaker 0: I did this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we had an old table, the previous table, the other table at RIT, and we had to get rid of it.
Speaker 0: So we put it outside our apartment and we put a sign on it.
Speaker 0: that said this is our apartment, come inside.
Speaker 0: Either take it for free or if you want, come give us like 20 bucks for it.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: Later in the day I went out and it was gone.
Speaker 0: If I then complained that someone exercised option one as opposed to option two, I'm a moron.
Speaker 1: Yes, you are.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, that's my news.
Speaker 0: I just really got to get ahead of this.
Speaker 0: The people who are mad about this are dumb, and if you're mad about it, you're dumb.
Speaker 1: Alright, another news.
Speaker 1: Tomorrow, a news is gonna happen.
Speaker 1: For the 8th time, T-Mobile is gonna have some un-carrier conference thingy, which is pretty much like the Apple keynote of T-Mobile.
Speaker 1: Where they do it every quarter, and they come out and they talk about how they're so much better than all the other carriers.
Speaker 1: Look at all the good stuff that we're gonna do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're better until you get more than 10 miles outside of any major metropolitan area.
Speaker 1: So here's the thing.
Speaker 1: It's like, T-Mobile, I want to use you as my carrier.
Speaker 1: In so many ways, you are correct.
Speaker 1: You are definitely taking the path that I would take if I was a phone wireless provider in the United States.
Speaker 1: Do the things that other people aren't doing.
Speaker 1: No bullshit.
Speaker 1: Contracts, no locking people.
Speaker 0: Global free international roaming, which I use monthly.
Speaker 1: Right, yeah.
Speaker 1: All these kind of awesome things, right?
Speaker 1: Here are the problems you got, T-Mobile.
Speaker 1: Here are the problems.
Speaker 1: The reason I'm still using Verizon.
Speaker 0: Alright, I'm really curious what these are.
Speaker 0: Because it's not like you ever fucking leave the city.
Speaker 1: No, but that, yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, Verizon, I can go around the world too.
Speaker 1: It's not a problem.
Speaker 0: You don't get free roaming.
Speaker 0: You don't get data roaming for free.
Speaker 1: It's shitty 2G roaming.
Speaker 1: I'm still gonna pay to get 4Gs when I go to some other country.
Speaker 0: Scott, I can pay like 10 bucks and get like a gig of 4G in those countries.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: I can pay 10 bucks and buy a SIM card in those other countries.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then you have to go activate it and all that bullshit as opposed to it starts working when you land.
Speaker 0: That's alright.
Speaker 1: Anyway, here are the problems with T-Mobile.
Speaker 1: Number one, you're not actually any goddamn cheaper.
Speaker 1: Not at all.
Speaker 1: In fact, sometimes more expensive.
Speaker 0: With all taxes and fees combined, for my effectively unlimited data whatever plan, unlimited everything, $74 a month after taxes and fees.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: And here's the thing.
Speaker 1: I pay like a hundred.
Speaker 1: So wait a minute.
Speaker 1: That's not right.
Speaker 1: It is cheaper.
Speaker 1: It's not because you don't have any subsidized phones.
Speaker 1: So you gotta pay full price for the phone.
Speaker 0: I buy unlocked phones unsubsidized anyway.
Speaker 1: And how much do they cost?
Speaker 0: Well, I paid I think like 200 bucks for this Nexus 4.
Speaker 1: Oh, for a crapo phone.
Speaker 1: If you get an iPhone, how much would you have to pay?
Speaker 0: A list.
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 0: $750? $740?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you take the $750 plus the T-Mobile lower cost compared to like my $300 and the increased pricing cost.
Speaker 0: Actually, I calculated this.
Speaker 1: Over the two years, it actually works out so that it's about even.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I was about to say.
Speaker 0: I did that calculation.
Speaker 0: It's about the same.
Speaker 1: It's about the same.
Speaker 1: So if I'm paying about the same, then why would I go somewhere that has, even though I agree with many of your policies, you're just slower and just less reliable?
Speaker 0: I wouldn't say it's slower.
Speaker 0: The 4G is fucking wicked fast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but have you used a Verizon with LTE?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've seen it.
Speaker 0: It's like it's not.
Speaker 1: It is night in the day.
Speaker 1: I've used the T-Mobile at work.
Speaker 1: It is not so good.
Speaker 0: I was in Istanbul and Germany and London all in the span of a few days, landing in all those countries along the way.
Speaker 0: There's no easy way to have gotten data in all those places without spending a lot of time at multiple airports or paying a ton of money.
Speaker 1: Walk into a drug store, grab a SIM card, pop it in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you go...
Speaker 1: Type some numbers in.
Speaker 0: Scott, how often have you traveled?
Speaker 0: Try that and see how quickly it all works.
Speaker 0: Also, if you do that in Istanbul, that SIM card gets blocked about two hours after you activate it.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 0: Because of the laws.
Speaker 0: You're not allowed to use foreign phones in Turkey with local data plans.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: A lot of countries have bullshit like that.
Speaker 0: Trust me, I travel internationally a lot.
Speaker 0: Buying a SIM card in the airport and putting it in your phone often has problems.
Speaker 1: There's a solution.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what the solution is?
Speaker 0: I have T-Mobile.
Speaker 0: I land there.
Speaker 1: And you got crappy 2Gs.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: That 2G is actually pretty fine because a lot of the times I end up getting HSPA speeds anyway.
Speaker 1: Also, I would never travel to a country that didn't have freedom of speech in that way.
Speaker 0: So you don't want to ever visit Istanbul?
Speaker 1: Just like I wouldn't take a job that blocked the internet, I wouldn't go to a country that blocked the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're not going to go to a lot of countries.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not.
Speaker 0: Okay, you're not going to see... You keep talking about.
Speaker 0: you want to see the old shit.
Speaker 1: And you're lucky I'm not in charge of this country because I would say, "Hey, if your country's evil, no one from your country is allowed here and we're deporting anyone who is
Speaker 1: here.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, Scott, you know what?
Speaker 0: The old shit in Europe is like baby's first castle compared to Istanbul.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Just saying.
Speaker 1: I know that, but that doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: If your country is evil, I'm not going to go to it.
Speaker 0: Okay, anyway, as I'm saying, I travel around a lot in the world.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: The fact that as soon as I land in any country in the world except North Korea and Somalia...
Speaker 1: 2G, I might as well have nothing.
Speaker 1: It's like I have free internet everywhere I go.
Speaker 1: It's a dial-up modem.
Speaker 1: But it's free internet.
Speaker 1: It's worthless.
Speaker 1: 2G is nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what, Scott?
Speaker 0: I used it as my internet when I was in Australia last time.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: It was 100% fine.
Speaker 0: The only thing I couldn't do was watch YouTube videos on it.
Speaker 1: When I was in Australia, when I had the 3G because the 4G didn't work, it was suffering.
Speaker 0: How?
Speaker 0: I don't remember you suffering.
Speaker 0: In fact, I had H-G-S-P-A+.
Speaker 0: It was wicked fast.
Speaker 0: It was totally fine the whole time.
Speaker 1: It was many slownesses.
Speaker 0: I did not have this problem.
Speaker 0: The fuck are you doing on the phone?
Speaker 1: It's because your... Because the thing is...
Speaker 0: Scott, that wasn't T-Mobile.
Speaker 0: I had the same fucking SIM card you did last time.
Speaker 1: Because you are not used to the... See, this is the thing.
Speaker 1: You don't have the incredible LTE speed of New York Verizon that I have.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't seem slow to you.
Speaker 1: That's what's going on here.
Speaker 0: Scott, I go to a web page.
Speaker 0: It loads instantly.
Speaker 1: You don't realize how slow it is because you have... It's like saying, "Oh man, my car is crazy fast because I'm driving a
Speaker 1: Ferrari.".
Speaker 1: You don't know.
Speaker 1: You just don't know.
Speaker 1: You don't know what fast is.
Speaker 0: I don't think that level of fat... Scott, I...
Speaker 1: I'll trade phones with you for a day and then we'll trade back and we'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, fine.
Speaker 0: Like, okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see how willing you are to take my much superior phone.
Speaker 0: No, because I'm not convinced it's that much of a difference.
Speaker 0: So anyway, those are your reasons?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: But yeah, no, they're going to announce something tomorrow that's supposedly crazy awesome.
Speaker 1: that will give us even more faith in them being the uncaring.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, the thing is it doesn't matter because...
Speaker 1: Well, maybe it's increased speed and lower prices.
Speaker 0: I'm just continuing to use my Nexus 4.
Speaker 0: Because honestly, now that I got Lollipop, Lollipop's fucking amazing.
Speaker 0: Android is accelerating in terms of being not shitty, like rapidly with Lollipop.
Speaker 0: And my battery lasts like 20 to 40% longer and like everything's great.
Speaker 0: I'm really glad I didn't buy a new phone because a lot of those new phones don't have Lollipop yet.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So pretty much, I think, unless this phone breaks, I'm just going to wait until Lollipop drops on that Z3C.
Speaker 0: And if it does and it doesn't break the Z3C, I'm going to buy a cheap Z3C, probably great market.
Speaker 0: And that'll be my new phone.
Speaker 1: That's another thing.
Speaker 1: iPhones just updates all the time.
Speaker 1: You don't have to wait based on the carrier, based on the phone.
Speaker 0: You don't if you buy a just standard Android phone.
Speaker 0: It just upgrades immediately.
Speaker 0: The problem is that all these companies, they put their bullshit carrier specific garbage on the phone.
Speaker 1: iPhone, they're not allowed to put carrier specific garbage on the iPhone.
Speaker 1: Apple doesn't let them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the iPhone's $750.
Speaker 1: No, it's actually like $200 or $300.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because you get it subsidized.
Speaker 1: Well, you're paying the same amount either way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except I can buy a gray market version of one of these phones way cheaper.
Speaker 1: I'm sure I can go steal an iPhone for way cheaper.
Speaker 0: Yes, I'll just pirate an iPhone and print it in my 3D printer.
Speaker 1: I wish I could.
Speaker 1: What if I could?
Speaker 0: You wouldn't download a car.
Speaker 0: Fuck you.
Speaker 1: If I could download a car, I would.
Speaker 1: I'd download a jet first though.
Speaker 0: Scott, if you could download a jet, that would be the day that you died.
Speaker 1: Why would I die?
Speaker 0: How would you pilot a jet?
Speaker 1: I'd print out a pilot.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: This is a photo from an earlier time.
Speaker 1: That's just a photo?
Speaker 0: It's just a photo because it's a photo that needs to be seen more widely to remind people of some facts.
Speaker 0: For example, for all you weirdly misogynistic computer science nerds who are mad about women in your spaces and whatever, computer programming was seen as women's work until relatively recently in the grand scheme of the history of computers.
Speaker 1: It was pretty much, oh mostly women had that job for the first few decades that the job existed.
Speaker 1: It wasn't until the 80s, 90s that it switched over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you don't know the names of people like Grace Hopper or Margaret Hamilton, and you're simultaneously one of those nerd programmer equivalents.
Speaker 1: Then you're someone who's not listening to this podcast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you know what?
Speaker 0: Spread this around, you who do listen to your idiot friends in CS.
Speaker 0: But anyway.
Speaker 1: Maybe one Unix beard will see it.
Speaker 0: This is just a wonderful photo of a woman named Margaret Hamilton, the NASA lead software engineer who wrote the Apollo Guidance Program, and the source code was printed out because this was a long time ago.
Speaker 0: That's what they did in those days.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: How else was everyone going to debug it?
Speaker 1: Sit in the terminal in the VT100s and scroll through it?
Speaker 0: Going to read your fucking punch card?
Speaker 1: You had to go through it.
Speaker 1: Read it on the paper with a red pen.
Speaker 0: It's a photo of her standing next to the printed out source code of the Apollo Guidance Program that she wrote.
Speaker 0: This is just an awesome photo.
Speaker 1: Written in some nasty old program like some assembly shit.
Speaker 0: You know what though?
Speaker 0: If you're smart and you go read that, a smart person who knows how computers work could read that code probably more effectively than they could read a lot of modern garbage.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: It's probably quite readable.
Speaker 1: At the low level.
Speaker 1: Pretty sure you can get the code online.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like old programming.
Speaker 0: It's just, what do I need to do?
Speaker 0: I've got to calculate some things and put them in these registers so something can happen.
Speaker 0: Like, go nuts.
Speaker 0: Variables in memory or not.
Speaker 1: Really, the input is pretty much just, where do you want to go?
Speaker 1: And the output is, thrust the rockets this way.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Maybe a feedback loop of, am I there yet?
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 1: Check where I am.
Speaker 1: Thrust some more.
Speaker 1: Where am I going?
Speaker 0: You're not passing around a bunch of objects.
Speaker 1: The program is just- Check all the sensors in this rocket.
Speaker 1: What do they say?
Speaker 1: Do some math, thrust some rockets.
Speaker 0: I mean, old programming is basically, what do I do next?
Speaker 0: Okay, now what do I do?
Speaker 1: Also, put out some numbers on the screen so the astronauts can see it.
Speaker 1: Send it over the radio so Houston can see it.
Speaker 0: All right, so what do you got?
Speaker 1: So, remember we did an episode last week about the bus.
Speaker 0: Macadamia.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not that bus, but that's a good bus.
Speaker 1: Here is a video taken on a New York City bus.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: This rig's a WorldStar.
Speaker 1: Well, the YouTube account that posted it is WorldStarHip- Oh, WorldStar.
Speaker 1: WorldStarHipHoop is the name of the YouTube account, but it's pretty much just a dude on the bus and the bus is going slow and late and in traffic as usual, and it also got slowed down because a disabled person got on the bus, which by the way, if you're a disabled person, getting around New York City is really awful,
Speaker 0: even
Speaker 1: if you use the bus and AccessorRide.
Speaker 0: Well, AccessorRide, so get this- AccessorRide sucks too.
Speaker 1: You got to give AccessorRide- And of course, handicap accessible cabs.
Speaker 1: They ain't going to pick your ass up.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And also, all the subway stations that matter are so old, like 100 years old, that they don't have elevators.
Speaker 0: And even if they did, the platforms are too small.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you live where I am, the subway isn't going to get you.
Speaker 0: Dude, Queensborough Plaza.
Speaker 1: You got to come all the way to where a rim is and you can only go to Queens Plaza, not Queensborough Plaza.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Queensborough Plaza is one of the most used subway stations in New York.
Speaker 0: Stairs only.
Speaker 0: Do you know how many stories up you have to go?
Speaker 1: Queens Plaza has an elevator though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, guys, I live in the third story of a building that has super tall floors and the platform for the Astoria-bound trains is higher than me.
Speaker 1: Right, so anyway, someone got on the bus with a wheelchair, so it slowed the bus down even more.
Speaker 1: And there's some cranky old lady on the bus who's complaining.
Speaker 1: And there's some guy and he's just like, you know, they're going to work in the morning.
Speaker 1: They're all late.
Speaker 1: It's all too early.
Speaker 1: And this lady's yapping, saying this is bullshit and complaining.
Speaker 1: And he's like, I had enough of this shit.
Speaker 1: I'm going to tug back to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: This video is great.
Speaker 0: I watched it.
Speaker 1: So he smacks that old lady down.
Speaker 0: We're all late.
Speaker 0: Everybody's late.
Speaker 1: Nice little tongue lashing going on.
Speaker 0: Just love it.
Speaker 0: Like everybody's late.
Speaker 0: You're mad because you got a shit ass job.
Speaker 0: You're late to your shit job.
Speaker 0: It's great.
Speaker 1: I'm not upset about being late to my job.
Speaker 1: What's the worst I got?
Speaker 1: I'll get a new shit ass job.
Speaker 0: This warmed the cockles of my heart, this video.
Speaker 1: And this is why the bus is not a good place to be.
Speaker 1: It's also why I love living in New York, because you got to sit in uncomfortable situations like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Thing is, that situation is not uncomfortable.
Speaker 0: I would because, you know, if you live in New York, it gets a lot worse.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But if you live in New York, like whenever things go down, like all the people who aren't crazy are on the like, you know, like two people get in a fight on the subway.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: There's like a couple hundred other people like crammed into that car, either trying not to be involved, but or actively like videoing it or, you know, yelling or whatever.
Speaker 0: But the most beautiful thing is that everyone who's not involved is all making eye contact with each other, sharing this look of, can you believe this shit?
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: Look, look what's going on right there.
Speaker 0: Look at this.
Speaker 0: I think he's about to hit him.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: Because none of it happens every day.
Speaker 0: It's like the people who get into a fight don't realize that it happens every day in the moment.
Speaker 0: The Book Club book is Watership Down.
Speaker 1: It's a handful of chapters now.
Speaker 1: And I can tell you that here are some things that I know about it.
Speaker 1: Number one, it opens up.
Speaker 1: It does that thing a lot of books do with the quotes at the beginning of every chapter.
Speaker 0: Did you did you read the authors like, here's how I wrote the book?
Speaker 1: No, I don't know if that's in my edition.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh, oh, because there's something interesting I could tell you about the quote at the beginning of chapter one.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's from my boy like a lamb none.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And so that's a positive.
Speaker 1: Other than that, so far, it seems like it's like.
Speaker 1: obviously it's not the same story, but it's pretty much the same kind of book as Lord of the Flies, only with rabbits.
Speaker 1: Like each person is representing some one aspect of society, whatever.
Speaker 0: So, you know, so, Scott, the author literally has said openly, this is not allegory.
Speaker 0: Nobody is symbolic of anything.
Speaker 0: It is just a story of rabbits trying to find a new home.
Speaker 1: Tolkien said the same thing.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: So you can try.
Speaker 0: I encourage you to continue to try to read in those aspects.
Speaker 1: But you got the military guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Peasant rabbit.
Speaker 1: You know, normal guy rabbit.
Speaker 0: So I'll say this.
Speaker 0: Every one of those rabbits is like you're going to expect the book to go in like a particular academic rabbit.
Speaker 0: The rabbits are all going to like surprise you a bunch of times.
Speaker 0: And it doesn't go in the direction you think it's going at all.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: Also, big wigs.
Speaker 0: My man.
Speaker 1: Also, Agamemnon.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: People don't know how bad ass Agamemnon is right.
Speaker 1: I didn't even learn.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: You are a badass.
Speaker 0: Agamemnon is going toe to toe with Achilles.
Speaker 1: But that's what I'm saying is like so Achilles is basically invincible.
Speaker 1: The baddest ass motherfucker in the whole world.
Speaker 1: And he could only be killed by this weakness that no one even knows.
Speaker 1: And it was random chance.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And Achilles.
Speaker 1: You think someone's so bad ass, wouldn't they be the king?
Speaker 1: But Achilles is not the king.
Speaker 1: Agamemnon is the king.
Speaker 1: And Achilles does what Agamemnon fucking says.
Speaker 1: That's how bad as he is.
Speaker 0: Of course, then.
Speaker 1: Agamemnon says Achilles.
Speaker 1: Lick my foot.
Speaker 1: He says I.
Speaker 0: So it's got if Agamemnon is that bad ass compared to Achilles.
Speaker 0: How bad ass is Hector?
Speaker 1: Don't even go there.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Don't even.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: You can't be too hubris here.
Speaker 0: I'll stop.
Speaker 0: Besides coming down.
Speaker 0: Besides, like, what's this?
Speaker 1: The baddest of all asses is me.
Speaker 1: Don't forget it.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Oh, you did forget it.
Speaker 1: That's a shame.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 1: Agamemnon.
Speaker 1: You wet your bed.
Speaker 0: What happened?
Speaker 0: That's a shame.
Speaker 0: Everyone look.
Speaker 0: Agamemnon wet the bed.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 0: You think you can repudiate me?
Speaker 0: You're going to.
Speaker 1: Oh, wait, wait.
Speaker 1: Are you about to get in a boat?
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 0: You'll just never get into a boat again.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Guess what?
Speaker 1: Oh, you're stuck in one place on this tiny island for the rest of your life.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Don't get in any boats.
Speaker 0: Oh, is that a food boat coming?
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: It sank.
Speaker 0: That sucks.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 1: Too bad planes weren't invented yet.
Speaker 0: I always imagine the Greek gods just being along the lines of Poseidon being a super dick to everyone and every other god being like, man, he's such a dick.
Speaker 1: Oh, here's a boat.
Speaker 1: Don't worry.
Speaker 1: I won't sink this one.
Speaker 1: I'll just move the sirens real close to it, like.
Speaker 0: But yet they never call him a dick to his face because then he'll start being a dick to them.
Speaker 0: It's like, he's being a dick to Agamemnon or he's being a dick to Odysseus.
Speaker 0: So I'm just going to hang out over here and let that happen.
Speaker 0: So.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, tell me when you get to the cult rabbits.
Speaker 1: They are they prasing on their you're in a little bit.
Speaker 0: So basically, you're at the point where there's Hazel, the smart rabbit and Fiverr, who's like, man, shit's going to get fucked up.
Speaker 0: We should get the fuck out of here.
Speaker 1: The prophetic religious rabbit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So did they leave yet?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they left.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 1: So they crossed a river or some shit.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The book moves real quick.
Speaker 1: It does move real quick.
Speaker 1: Like rabbits.
Speaker 0: Wait till you get to the cult rabbits.
Speaker 0: I think that's where you're going to go from.
Speaker 0: This book's OK.
Speaker 0: You're going to start really liking this book.
Speaker 1: Well, the cultist rabbits are too much book club and not book club episode.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Watch your shit on YouTube.
Speaker 0: We're going to be a packed south doing bad games on Sunday in the Armadillo theater.
Speaker 0: And otherwise, we're just going to be hanging out and south in and in barbecue and making fun of the south.
Speaker 0: And, you know, all the stuff we do at Pax is not getting shot by people in the south.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hopefully.
Speaker 0: Hopefully.
Speaker 1: What's the open carry laws at Pax?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure Pax is going to not allow open carry.
Speaker 0: We'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: Can they or is it similar to the Anita talk?
Speaker 0: We're going to find out.
Speaker 0: I mean, I will not walk out of our talk if people bring guns, but I see no one's going to shoot us.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, I might not be able to resist commenting on that during the panel.
Speaker 1: Aaron Sealby.
Speaker 1: There will be all right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm not afraid.
Speaker 1: I hope he'll be there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I think he's going to be there.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So that's it.
Speaker 0: Metastuff.
Speaker 0: Subscribe to our newsletter.
Speaker 1: So actual episode.
Speaker 1: So we wanted to talk about A.I.
Speaker 1: I thought we had talked about it before, but I looked and I couldn't find an episode.
Speaker 1: So what I was even if we did talk about it before, it was ridiculously long time ago.
Speaker 0: But we but yeah, but we actually don't know that much about A.I Now, we could like I was talking at length and Gigi from the forum because he actually is like it like he knows a shit ton about A.I.
Speaker 1: He's studying A.I.
Speaker 0: in the school and he's explaining to me like current actual real A.I.
Speaker 0: stuff and maybe we'll do a show and I get him or someone on.
Speaker 1: I only know the most basics of A.I.
Speaker 1: as a programmer, but who doesn't do anything involving
Speaker 1: A.I.?
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 1: I do know a lot about completely fictional A.I It's all made up and shit like Skynet.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So let's just talk about that, because that's way more fun and easy.
Speaker 1: So we're told I can go home and eat because I'm hungry.
Speaker 0: So we're going to talk about A.I.
Speaker 0: under the assumptions of, you know, the Y plus 30 idea that, you know, 30 years from now, can't imagine shit.
Speaker 0: Everything's bad.
Speaker 0: Nothing's real.
Speaker 0: I mean, imagine what the world was like 30 years.
Speaker 0: A bad sci fi book.
Speaker 1: You play gods.
Speaker 0: And the reason I thought to do this topic was because fairly recently, Stephen Hawking was like, look, strong A.I.
Speaker 0: will fucking destroy us.
Speaker 0: We should never make it.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That kind of sparked a debate among science types about what A.I.
Speaker 0: could and will do in a far future.
Speaker 0: And also, you know, the book club book way back, Player of Games, the culture series kind of is based on the idea that humans make A.I.
Speaker 0: that's smarter than them and tell that A.I.
Speaker 0: go nuts.
Speaker 0: Do what thou wilt.
Speaker 0: Let's see what fucking happens.
Speaker 0: So, Scott, what do you think?
Speaker 0: Like for real?
Speaker 0: Do you think A.I.
Speaker 0: is going to be the thing that destroys us?
Speaker 0: Just really like, you know, hundreds of years?
Speaker 1: No, because I think the development, the timing is off, right?
Speaker 1: It could be potentially the thing that destroys us.
Speaker 1: But something else is more likely to happen.
Speaker 1: first, because it will take us so long to create an A.I.
Speaker 1: cable destroying us that there will be so many dangers in the meantime.
Speaker 1: The caldera will probably explode and cover the earth in dark haze before we develop an A.I.
Speaker 1: that can kill us.
Speaker 0: But well, on a counterpoint that we can't stop, because it's interesting that I've been saying this for a long time.
Speaker 0: But John Green and Hank Green and like their big history show, they just made the same point in their life.
Speaker 0: Basically, they argue that there is actually an overriding theme for the entire history of humans and the entire history of life.
Speaker 0: And that that theme is rising.
Speaker 0: complexity is coming about as a result of and in the continuance of the increasingly efficient consumption of energy.
Speaker 0: to continue that rising complexity.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: So it's arguably.
Speaker 0: it's arguable and as I've been poking around, a lot of people way smarter than us have been arguing this point now that more has happened, more advancement of human technology in the last 30 to 50 years than in the previous entire history of humankind ever combined.
Speaker 1: That is correct.
Speaker 0: So if that is true, then the curve of technological acceleration is unfathomable.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: So that assuming it doesn't stop like, you know, the speed of light stops you.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Assuming we don't hit something, which interestingly, we have never hit to this point.
Speaker 1: Well, Moore's law sort of stopped.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, processing capabilities have not really stopped.
Speaker 0: Like we're able to process things way fast and we keep making more chips instead of making better ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We're like we're hitting this limit, like actually like modern CPUs tend to be slower than older CPUs in terms of instructions per second.
Speaker 0: But parallelism and all these other things that actually made them way better at doing the things we actually care about mostly except, you know, like in my day job, actually the things we do in old Pentium 4 is actually faster than modern Xeon chips for some things still.
Speaker 1: Depends what you're doing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I don't think it's that far off.
Speaker 0: in our future.
Speaker 0: I think like the 500 year span, we'll see A.I.s that are indistinguishable from humans.
Speaker 1: Sure, maybe.
Speaker 1: But before 500 years, something else will happen that will kill us first.
Speaker 0: When we were like still led, addled and dumb in the 60s.
Speaker 1: Killed by something else by that time, then that will almost definitely be the thing in a world where it will definitely not be the thing in a world before the Internet.
Speaker 1: If nothing else kills us or that resilient, A.I.
Speaker 1: won't kill us either.
Speaker 0: Before the Internet and before we got all that lead on the atmosphere that was pretty literally making us stupid and violent, we had nuclear weapons capable of ending all human life and somehow we didn't fucking use them.
Speaker 1: We still have them and they still might be used.
Speaker 1: Don't hold your breath.
Speaker 0: I think the chance of us using them has gone down over time, not up.
Speaker 1: Yes, but don't count it out.
Speaker 1: Do not count that shit out.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So so let's assume then that at some point we don't get destroyed and A.I.
Speaker 0: gets made.
Speaker 0: That is well, I guess already we have to talk about like an A.I.
Speaker 0: that is like us or an A.I.
Speaker 0: that is unfathomable to us because they're really two different roads.
Speaker 1: I mean, an A.I.
Speaker 1: that is like us is not really something to be afraid of.
Speaker 1: It's just fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except it might just also be an asshole and just kill us because it's right.
Speaker 1: But it couldn't kill us all because it's like us.
Speaker 1: It's on our level so we could kill it, too.
Speaker 0: But what if it's like us in the sense that it has, you know, humans not.
Speaker 0: I don't want to get into the whole like predestination, you know, all those arguments about free will or whatever.
Speaker 0: But if it's like us in the sense that we appear to have sensory input output into the world in terms of we can physically do shit and we have a consciousness, even if we don't have free will, in the sense that our actions are sort of this feedback loop of we get stimuli, we run it through our collective memories, we appear to have cognition, then we make decisions.
Speaker 0: So what if A.I.
Speaker 0: is like that in the sense that it is as conscious as humans are?
Speaker 1: I mean, sure.
Speaker 1: It could be an evil A.I.
Speaker 1: like the first Terminator or some shit.
Speaker 0: I don't think the first Terminator A.I.
Speaker 0: was evil.
Speaker 1: All right, Skynet, fine.
Speaker 1: It could be evil.
Speaker 0: Very clearly, Skynet reacted to us trying to kill it and defend it itself.
Speaker 0: It wasn't evil.
Speaker 0: It was just at best uncaring and unsympathetic to the person who tried to murder it.
Speaker 1: The guy in the first Alien movie then.
Speaker 0: But that A.I.
Speaker 0: was programmed to do what it did, just pretend it's something like an evil biaroid guy.
Speaker 0: I'm not even saying evil.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying if it's if it's like us in the sense that it is A.I.
Speaker 0: that is conscious in a way recognizable to humans as conscious, as in it passes the Turing test.
Speaker 0: And if I talk to it, it is indistinguishable from a human to me.
Speaker 1: Then it's just a new person.
Speaker 1: It's no different than making a baby.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: However, what if because it's built with technology, it's slightly smarter than any human on Earth?
Speaker 1: Only slightly?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Then it's not like us.
Speaker 1: It's better.
Speaker 0: It's like us.
Speaker 1: It's no, like us means like us.
Speaker 1: You want to talk about something better than us?
Speaker 1: Let's talk about something better than us.
Speaker 0: Scott, if you're going to use like in that ridiculously pedantic fashion, I don't know how we're going to have this discussion.
Speaker 1: It's I mean, if you want to talk about
Speaker 1: A.I.,
Speaker 1: I mean, you're talking about degrees here.
Speaker 0: But it's like literally point one percent smarter than that's not enough to make a goddamn difference.
Speaker 0: I think it is.
Speaker 1: How could that point one percent make any difference?
Speaker 1: Well, because all right, let's say it's exactly one percent smarter than you.
Speaker 1: What's the difference?
Speaker 0: Have you gotten a standardized IQ test in your life?
Speaker 1: I think we all know what's going on here.
Speaker 0: Have you gotten this?
Speaker 0: I'm accredited by the state of Michigan if we're talking about intelligence credentials.
Speaker 0: Pretty defensive over there.
Speaker 0: So let's say fine, Scott.
Speaker 0: It is as intelligent as the smartest human who has ever lived.
Speaker 1: That is just.
Speaker 0: it's as if we had another person who was smart, except for a couple of things, because it's a it's a computer program, it's immortal.
Speaker 0: And it has and it can store more data than we can store.
Speaker 0: So now so now it's not just as smart as us, except it can augment itself to be infinitely better forever and nothing can stop.
Speaker 1: Also, it's questionable whether it can actually store more data or not.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah.
Speaker 1: How much data would my memories take up if we filled up hard drives?
Speaker 0: But how much of that is just bullshit heuristics?
Speaker 0: How much do we actually remember?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, there's how much there's how much I can bring to mind at any given moment, but how much I could theoretically bring to mind given infinite time to remember things.
Speaker 0: We think we know as about how much we actually know, like I know songs, right?
Speaker 0: Like I there are songs that I know in my head.
Speaker 0: But how much of that is me actually knowing the fullness of the song versus some bullshit heuristic and like remembering some of the lyrics and figuring out the rest?
Speaker 1: You get a lot of compression going on.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Super lossy compression.
Speaker 0: So should we just go to a higher level then of this discussion?
Speaker 0: What if the A.I.
Speaker 0: is like the culture A.I.
Speaker 1: is like the culture
Speaker 1: A.I.?
Speaker 0: That's the best possible scenario.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, if it's exactly like it, then, yeah, it's awesome.
Speaker 1: But just assuming it's on the same power level, but not necessarily of the same nature.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Then the thing we had to be concerned with is not necessarily that it will be, quote, evil and kill us all, but that much in the way we look on ants, it will look on us as some lesser being.
Speaker 1: And it's like we don't go and kill all the ants.
Speaker 1: But if ants infest our house, we exterminate them.
Speaker 1: And so if they are underfoot, we may trot upon them without even thinking or caring.
Speaker 0: There's actually a super relevant YouTube video I'll find and link you to that shows if the A.I.
Speaker 0: are like us in any way and we are to them like ants are to us, we are fucked.
Speaker 1: because this video The thing is, millions and millions of ants live all over Earth without any getting killed by us.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: Some of them get eaten by anteaters, though.
Speaker 0: But this video is so very humans.
Speaker 0: And apparently this is a commonly done thing.
Speaker 0: And you know what they do for art?
Speaker 0: They will go out and find the biggest ant colony they can find, just like in the backyard or out in the woods or metal into it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And they'll pour molten aluminum into it, killing all the ants because it makes a cool thing that you can then dig out.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So the
Speaker 0: A.I.,
Speaker 0: if it's like us at all, would do that to us.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But there's just so many people.
Speaker 1: It would do that to some people's like it would go to your town and turn your town into a frozen work of art.
Speaker 1: And then some other town is going to be just fun.
Speaker 1: You know, it'd be like Attack on Titan.
Speaker 1: It's like maybe the Titans just won't come to your town.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Whatevs.
Speaker 1: And most, you know, there's tons of ants.
Speaker 1: Most ants are not killed by people, only many.
Speaker 0: So there are so many ants.
Speaker 0: The only reason the A.I.s don't do things like that is because for whatever reasons, not to get into all the like literature details of like those books, is that they have, for whatever reason, a sense of their own morality, though they recognize that it's entirely arbitrary and they seem the
Speaker 1: same that humans have their own morality.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: It's completely arbitrary.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: And they have a sense of humor.
Speaker 0: And I get the impression they feel kind of sorry for us because we're so dumb.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, there are some people who try not to kill ants because, you know, and they're much higher life forms than the ants.
Speaker 0: No, that is true.
Speaker 1: They just don't like hurting little antes because they're cute.
Speaker 1: But except the fire ants and the crazy ants.
Speaker 1: Fuck them.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 1: Fuck you, fire ants and crazy ants, I think.
Speaker 1: And then some people who take the fire ants, the crazy ants, put them together and see who wins.
Speaker 0: I think on the broadest boilers, the crazy ants.
Speaker 0: I don't think A.I.s will openly, literally destroy us if they're those kinds of A.I.s, because it's not going to be Skynet where they kill us all, because I don't think we will ever be stupid enough to give the A.I.s control of the physical things.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: That's another thing.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Like, yes.
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: The A.I.
Speaker 0: is a billion times smarter than any human and it controls the auto manufacturing facility that we just turn the power off.
Speaker 1: But I mean, if it just you know, the problem is, is at least our current real world, like I can just connect to the power plant and fuck it up.
Speaker 1: It's this stuff is way insecure.
Speaker 0: Well, but at least the nukes and it's on the Internet.
Speaker 0: The nukes are not on the Internet.
Speaker 0: The nukes use like 12 inch floppies.
Speaker 1: I hope so.
Speaker 1: They do.
Speaker 1: But yeah, the shit is like connected to the Internet.
Speaker 1: So if the A.I.
Speaker 1: gets on the Internet, which it probably will, at least the current modern day Internet, it can fuck a lot of shit up like the bank.
Speaker 0: You know what would happen?
Speaker 0: It would be exactly like summer wars, actually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot like summer wars.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Is that like?
Speaker 0: look, it couldn't like.
Speaker 0: it had all the that A.I.
Speaker 0: had basically all the powers that an A.I.
Speaker 0: that was somehow loose on the Internet's combined could like it.
Speaker 1: But in the regular everyday world, everyone is just fine except for their digital lives.
Speaker 0: Well, except like it could mess with hospitals to kill people and like that aspect.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Don't put your hospital on the Internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We should.
Speaker 1: we should make a special like.
Speaker 1: we should go build a hospital that has good Internet's like.
Speaker 0: Scott, I worked for a hospital Internet's.
Speaker 0: That is literally impossible.
Speaker 1: Let's make a brand new hospital and everything set up and it's super nice.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, make a brand new power plant where it's not on the Internet.
Speaker 0: But I don't I don't think that scenario is going to happen.
Speaker 0: But I am pretty convinced that what will happen is that eventually artificial intelligence is created by us, will replace us in the sense that those are the technology we make will be the only things that could ever get off this planet and go anywhere else.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: So we'll be destroyed by them in the same way that the beings that became homo sapiens were destroyed by homo sapiens.
Speaker 1: But another thing, if we have a technology that we can send on this voyage, we can also send frozen people bits like in some eggs and you know what we will also and it could create.
Speaker 1: it could be programmed to create people when it gets there.
Speaker 0: And I think we'll recognize that the eyes are literally in every way superior and won't bother.
Speaker 1: Maybe they won't bother.
Speaker 1: Maybe they will, because it's an experiment.
Speaker 1: Like you might bring some ants or a monkey with you in space if you went to the moon or something.
Speaker 0: But I think in the long run that now the question really to me, for me, to me, from me will be, will that kind of A.I.
Speaker 0: arise because we created artificially or because we take humans and their consciousnesses and augment or re implement them on better substrates and then continue evolving purely from a mimetic, cultural, technological standpoint and just leave biology behind.
Speaker 1: So are you talking about like a ship of Theseus person where you make a brand new person?
Speaker 1: Or are you talking about a ghost in the shell?
Speaker 1: Someone uploads their brain to the Internet.
Speaker 0: I think it's.
Speaker 0: I think the ship of Theseus is the most likely scenario to create the first conscious A.I.
Speaker 0: And I think that thing will go on to replace humans.
Speaker 1: We should name it Theseus and we should be the ones who make it so that we get to name it Theseus.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The thing is, I want to make it with me and we should put it on a boat.
Speaker 0: I want it to be me.
Speaker 0: I want my brain to be the first ship of Theseus.
Speaker 1: Well, you should have studied A.I.
Speaker 1: and stopped working in finance too late.
Speaker 0: No, someone else has to figure all that shit out because young people have to figure it out.
Speaker 0: And when I'm like 80 or 90, I need you to ship a Theseus of me before I go senile and die.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry, bro.
Speaker 1: It's not going to be you.
Speaker 0: There's a chance.
Speaker 0: The thing is, we're the first generation in history where the chance isn't literally zero.
Speaker 0: It's like point one.
Speaker 0: But the fact that it's literally not zero, it's not going to be you.
Speaker 1: For you, it's zero.
Speaker 1: For me, it's point.
Speaker 0: Listen, rich, scary benefactor who listens to geek nights from his secret satellite.
Speaker 1: They're choosing them first.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If your brain doesn't make it like, yo, dog, you've listened to me.
Speaker 0: You you're with me, right?
Speaker 0: If it can't be you, why not me?
Speaker 1: Because there's 10 million people are better than you.
Speaker 0: Name one Theseus.
Speaker 0: He actually.
Speaker 0: Theseus didn't work out so well.
Speaker 0: Listen, Scott, do you remember?
Speaker 1: Agamemnon then.
Speaker 0: Agamemnon.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Of course, he was kind of a dick, but he deserves.
Speaker 0: he was more of a dick than I am.
Speaker 0: I will give him that.
Speaker 1: Then that's why he's going to cut you in front of you in life.
Speaker 1: I'll just get and you're not going to do shit about it.
Speaker 0: You know what I'll do?
Speaker 0: Yo, Poseidon, look, you're awesome.
Speaker 0: Not denying that.
Speaker 0: So can you help me out?
Speaker 1: Besides, it's like, well, are you trying to become gods down there?
Speaker 1: Drown you all.
Speaker 1: I can't have that.
Speaker 1: I can't have this.
Speaker 0: No, me hubris.
Speaker 1: No, can't be having this action.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Is there anything else to say?
Speaker 1: I can eat dinner now.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays and comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.