Speaker 1: It's Thursday August 20th 2015.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We're talking about cookies the good kind.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I got an as holds, you know my files?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I got a crappy like old netgear to Bayness sitting right up there above the geek nights rig.
Speaker 0: So like last night I go to drag a file over to it and in Windows is like disconnected.
Speaker 0: I'm like I was working recently.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh it must you know, it must just be that thing.
Speaker 0: We're like, you know you restart and yeah, it's like oh one or more drives are not connected.
Speaker 1: You click on and then like, okay, we're good now, right exactly click on it.
Speaker 0: It's not good now.
Speaker 0: So turn around and look at it and it's off and I'm like, I didn't turn you off.
Speaker 1: That's weird.
Speaker 0: So I got to push the button and I push the button and literally nothing happened.
Speaker 0: No noise.
Speaker 0: No nothing.
Speaker 1: What kind of NAS is this?
Speaker 0: a ready NAS NV plus, okay So it served me well for many years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean my neck here is like the shittest tear netgear and it's been going non-stop for a long time.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's been like four or five years.
Speaker 0: the warranty is way over.
Speaker 1: so I have lost two drives in mine though I haven't lost any.
Speaker 0: so anyway When you push a power button on something and you check to make sure it's plugged in and you flick, you know If absolutely nothing happens the odds are the thing that is broken is the power supply.
Speaker 1: Yep, now you want you know why Luke needed those power converters, right?
Speaker 0: So I'm like well That sucks.
Speaker 0: What can I do about this?
Speaker 0: I go online and apparently not my version But there's a previous version of the similar NAS.
Speaker 0: the same model line Had serious problems with especially heat and the power supply dying.
Speaker 1: You keep your apartment warmer than I keep.
Speaker 0: well I don't even turn the air conditioning on when I'm not home But I don't turn the NAS off ever so it must have died from the heat while I was at work.
Speaker 0: Yep So, I mean it's a less common problem with my much newer model.
Speaker 0: I mean it lasted five years.
Speaker 0: the other ones apparently were like dying.
Speaker 1: But also honestly in consumer level stuff like power supply goes on everything eventually.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I'm like well What can I do about this?
Speaker 0: Can I buy the same exact NAS and move my drives over?
Speaker 1: See now this is the thing.
Speaker 1: This is why I hate consumer level.
Speaker 1: NAS is so much but at the same time I don't really trust Robo cuz.
Speaker 1: that's like the Apple of NAS is like your NAS.
Speaker 1: you have to us have that question.
Speaker 1: Well, can I use a suit up with a real NAS?
Speaker 1: You just fucking pull all the drives out put it in any equivalent NAS and it just immediately starts working.
Speaker 0: So yeah, if I can get the same NAS with the same firmware that would work.
Speaker 1: No, you don't even need the same.
Speaker 1: you just need like a compelling anything in this power server raid.
Speaker 1: Whatever series will work like I don't even care.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I could also get this software that's pretty easy to get and plug all the drives into a computer Tell it which one was which and that and be able to save the data that way.
Speaker 0: Yep, or I could fix this NAS better plate probably 90% chance.
Speaker 0: replacing the power supply will fix it, right?
Speaker 0: So I went online and this is such a common problem.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of third-party power supplies available.
Speaker 0: So I ordered one and assuming it works I'll be alright, but should I then?
Speaker 0: Try to replace the NAS with a newer one?
Speaker 0: that I would right, you know what I do.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm thinking about doing this I'm glad I bought some bigger drives for my main PC on the Windows 10 upgrade recently.
Speaker 0: I have been planning but it's a lot of money to buy a new NAS.
Speaker 0: I don't want to spend on for no reason.
Speaker 1: It's even worse if you want to.
Speaker 1: I mean the power supply was already like a hundred bucks Yeah, so if you want a goodness like even not a professional one.
Speaker 1: But so like here's the problem.
Speaker 1: drobos are just faster in a lot of ways and they work a lot better.
Speaker 0: in a lot of The network one is expensive.
Speaker 1: No, the network one is cheap.
Speaker 1: The Daz one is expensive.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: The network one's a few hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: It's not that much more.
Speaker 1: The drives cost way more than I have drives Yeah, but drives are fine.
Speaker 1: If a drobo fails The only way to get the data is to get another drobo.
Speaker 0: That's correct.
Speaker 1: You cannot get the data in any software any other device Yeah, and it's not a Terry kind of thing because it's not raid.
Speaker 1: It's something else.
Speaker 1: Now if the reality is raid is obsolete.
Speaker 0: Yeah effectively I mean my NAS is using some nonsense called raid X or whatever Mine is using.
Speaker 1: I have just a straight-up mirror up there.
Speaker 0: Just a mirror.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz you know what this.
Speaker 1: when I got it Space was actually not as cheap as it is now.
Speaker 1: This is an old - for two terabyte drives - two three terabyte drives But Like the difference between a four bay and a five bay in terms of speed and reliability is like night and day.
Speaker 1: But the price is way higher for that fifth spot the drobo and Professional NAS is that's one thing the drobo does that like pro NAS is do and like these don't.
Speaker 1: you can buy a sixth drive And I'm not to the ones that are just cards as these stick that in the bottom and It won't like use that for redundancy.
Speaker 1: It'll just cash the shit out of your data and make it way fast Mm-hmm, but that means buying a weird proprietary NAS from basically the Apple of NASes and then buying five drives and Buying a sixth m.2 drive.
Speaker 1: That'll be like a hundred bucks more than like a normal SSD.
Speaker 1: say that.
Speaker 0: Why do I need it to be that fast?
Speaker 0: I basically just use it for backups.
Speaker 0: It's just a backup storing place.
Speaker 1: I want to work on video that way.
Speaker 0: I bought fast hard drives and put them in my computer for that.
Speaker 1: So I would only do the caching if I was getting a Daz.
Speaker 1: that's a NAS that connects directly to your computer with light.
Speaker 0: It's not a NAS at all.
Speaker 0: It's just an external hard drive or a bunch of external hard drives.
Speaker 0: in a box that looks like one hard drive.
Speaker 1: a Daz is.
Speaker 1: Think of it as an external hard drive.
Speaker 1: That's actually like six drives all rated together and like super fast and performant and gigantic.
Speaker 1: That's what you do when you're like editing video from that thing.
Speaker 0: Drive in my computer that I edit video on yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's a more Monday topic.
Speaker 1: What I'm probably gonna do is as soon as we have some downtime after packs and I edit like the next round of video I'm gonna reinstall windows on an SSD and install a USB 3 thing and keep this computer for another like six or seven months.
Speaker 1: Well, I got a new computer.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna get a bunch of drives and use the windows redundancy inside the computer Hmm, and that'll be my fast stuff.
Speaker 1: and then I'll get some giant maybe like professional Like one of those just enclosures with like eight drives and just I need them.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll make that my data store forever and I'll integrate it with glacier.
Speaker 0: I wish I could just faster internet because then I wouldn't even need an as I could just back everything up in the cloud.
Speaker 1: Well what I want?
Speaker 1: my ideal situation I've been thinking about this a lot.
Speaker 1: just with the way I live my life is have some gigantic Dad like real sand in my apartment sand or like a high-level NAS you need a sand.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, there's there's a layer between the two.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think you're going overboard like six seven, whatever drives networks, obviously But obviously then I'd use the API on it to say every six months Just put a snapshot on glacier cuz that shit is so cheap Like glacier is so cheap.
Speaker 1: It's almost hilarious Like that's.
Speaker 1: that's my deal.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah my ideal stuff the cost of fortune Much an enclosure like that would be like over kill.
Speaker 0: Yeah my ideal is having like three CPUs even though we have multi-core CPUs these days and also like ten video cards.
Speaker 0: and It's not my ideal that you or a monitor the has to set up and my house to put it in.
Speaker 1: It is my reasonable ideal To have a upper-class NAS in my life.
Speaker 1: So got any news?
Speaker 1: It is Thursday, it's the lounge.
Speaker 1: did you forget your news already?
Speaker 0: No, I mean there wasn't really any good news.
Speaker 0: So I took a super mainstream news.
Speaker 0: Oh, cuz I also have a super mainstream not because I want to talk about the news itself But the topic related to it.
Speaker 0: briefly, right?
Speaker 1: I imagine this doesn't involve politics in any way.
Speaker 0: involves sports.
Speaker 0: Oh this week there was a big news, especially in New York.
Speaker 0: That was like Eli Manning asked for the most money ever.
Speaker 0: So Regardless of whether that's true or not, right?
Speaker 0: It brings up the topic of Professional athletes getting paid way too much money.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, it's already a complicated thing because like football like American football players They're a lot of them are pretty much fucked after they're like late 30s.
Speaker 0: Not a good a coda bag.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what if you're just like the fucking full back?
Speaker 0: just right if your teams don't even have full backs these days?
Speaker 0: But anyway, you know a lot of people especially anti-sport nerds is related to our packs panel, you know.
Speaker 0: One thing they often bring up is how athletes are overpaid.
Speaker 0: So I just want to address this for a bit.
Speaker 0: First of all, you're a professional athlete.
Speaker 0: You pretty much spent your whole life on this one thing Because that's how you'd be only way you could be good enough to do that.
Speaker 0: You don't have any other skills.
Speaker 0: There's not like some other job you can get.
Speaker 0: that isn't a piece of shit job.
Speaker 1: Yeah, your degree isn't something worthless.
Speaker 1: probably because you were doing you even have a degree.
Speaker 0: Yeah You see you invested all that time like a doctor right a doctor All their whole life into being a doctor.
Speaker 0: it takes years and years and years of practice.
Speaker 0: So when they finally become a doctor They need to be paid a lot of money to make up for the fact that they just wasted their whole life on this one thing.
Speaker 0: Also, you can't do it for very long.
Speaker 0: You can be a doctor and so you're like an old man Assuming you keep yourself healthy with doctor skills.
Speaker 1: a 45 year old football player That's a unicorn if you're.
Speaker 0: if you're a football player or even hockey or any kind even baseball You can only do this for a couple years.
Speaker 0: You need to make a lot of money in those years so that you can retire And be okay afterwards.
Speaker 0: Right and not everyone can like, you know be do awesome stuff afterwards and have a second act unless you're ridiculously You know ridiculously good in the first place especially if you've got, you know, repeated concussion syndrome.
Speaker 0: You just played baseball right.
Speaker 0: you made a million dollars a year for 15 years and now you have 15 million dollars.
Speaker 1: I can live on million dollars for the rest of my life from today.
Speaker 0: Sure, but you had to live for those years and you I've had to retire when you're 30 something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now now you can retire now with five million and live the rest of my life.
Speaker 1: just but that's you know.
Speaker 0: You need that right.
Speaker 0: normal people are gonna go to 65 before they retire.
Speaker 0: So you're making you know, if you add up all the money you make over time compared to a not ridiculously top-of-the-line Professional athlete.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're actually making about the same.
Speaker 0: We want to make more money than them in your life.
Speaker 0: Right just from to salary at your job.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz people forget, you know, you look at those salaries of these players.
Speaker 1: That's the top players.
Speaker 1: You hear their names of.
Speaker 1: you don't know the names of all the people.
Speaker 1: that don't matter.
Speaker 0: They're making one million a year 500 K. Yeah Like.
Speaker 1: there are hockey players five years and then they're out of the league and their hockey players are only on the ice and games.
Speaker 1: That don't matter.
Speaker 1: There are baseball players who never bat.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 0: there are people who are only in the minor leagues.
Speaker 0: That's their whole job.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: You got to spend time in the minor leagues to even have a chance again into the major leagues.
Speaker 0: Also, you know you look at these athletes.
Speaker 0: They make it so much ridiculous money.
Speaker 0: the owners right.
Speaker 0: you think like The athlete getting like 20 million dollars, you know a year or something is is making big bank.
Speaker 0: Hello, the owner has multi billions, right?
Speaker 0: And they don't want to pay the athlete who's making them those multi billions an extra million a year.
Speaker 0: It's like dude you just if I'm working for someone and they make that but I'm directly like just two steps under them.
Speaker 0: right because like quarterback coach owner now general manager owner and they make Literally a thousand times more money than I do They can go fuck themselves and pay me an extra couple million.
Speaker 1: You made me realize something.
Speaker 1: There's something very special about sports.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you're getting at this or not.
Speaker 1: So in the modern world the workers do not control the means of production.
Speaker 1: The workers are a byproduct.
Speaker 1: production is performed by technology capital and a small number of experts but in Professional sports there's only so many humans who can play that game.
Speaker 0: There are not enough quarterbacks in the NFL for every team to have a quality quarterback.
Speaker 1: Yeah If you are only like 10 NHL teams have a decent goalie, right?
Speaker 0: If you are good at this job, that is so incredibly rare for anyone to be good at Well, your labor actually has value and you can demand this large amount of money.
Speaker 1: So professional sports in the United States is an industry where full-on communism Probably work out right?
Speaker 0: I mean, there's a reason that you know, you need to have a union for these things, right?
Speaker 0: Because it's like, you know, normally I could go and be like, well, I don't like working here anymore I'll go work somewhere else.
Speaker 0: If you're the hockey goalie.
Speaker 0: It's not like you can't work anywhere else.
Speaker 0: you either work in the NHL or The KHS.
Speaker 0: you don't have a choice like football and I'll go play in the XFL, right?
Speaker 0: That does not around it.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 0: it's like you don't have a choice of where to work.
Speaker 0: So you need this union, you know to be very strong and to basically say hey It's not like you can quit and go work somewhere else.
Speaker 0: No competition for your labor.
Speaker 0: You have only one possible employer.
Speaker 0: You need to stick it to them and stick it to them hard to get what you deserve.
Speaker 1: I think the real problem is with all this is that a lot of people who are young Who literally have no chance of actually being in professional sports.
Speaker 0: No chance.
Speaker 1: Basically ruin their lives chasing that and Expecting that it's possible when it's probably not it is so that is the main possible is just unlikely, right?
Speaker 0: Thousands and thousands and thousands of people attempt it and only a few hundreds make it and the rest of them are Napoleon dynamite's dad Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so.
Speaker 0: But all we'll talk don't be getting mad I don't want to.
Speaker 0: you know, I don't like giving.
Speaker 0: people are getting mad at how much you know Some athletes are getting paid because they actually probably all professional athletes probably deserve way more and you know what?
Speaker 0: When you know 30 50 70 100 thousand people come to watch you work and are willing to pay $100 to watch you work Yeah, all right, then you can get as much money as they.
Speaker 1: I can barely get one person to watch me work.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: right okay, so occasionally
Speaker 1: the CEO will like wander over to my office and like look at my shoulder like
Speaker 0: things that you are capable of are so Amazing that people are willing to pay to see them right regardless of what it is that you were doing Then you deserve all that money.
Speaker 1: it's no different than you know, any other performer who just gave me an idea But I couldn't do it at my job.
Speaker 0: No one's gonna say oh man that that you know.
Speaker 0: dancer You know in the ballet is making too much money.
Speaker 0: It's like Yeah, I mean it's like a thousand people are willing to pay to see them dance.
Speaker 0: They deserve it.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I want to do.
Speaker 0: They're so good at what they want to do.
Speaker 1: a let's play of Me working for a whole day.
Speaker 1: Like here's my screen.
Speaker 1: Here's my face.
Speaker 0: This is what I do If only there weren't Security really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so someone who doesn't have those concerns like I would watch Conrad's.
Speaker 1: let's play.
Speaker 1: Let's work Let's work a thing.
Speaker 0: He's probably type it in passwords to things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you'd have to have like a little box you can move around to hide password things.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so in other news, there's a pretty good argument going on about this in the forum, so I figured it's actually worth discussing.
Speaker 1: So if you're not aware Ashley Madison is not a person.
Speaker 1: it was a person maybe I don't even know is a website and it's still up apparently and it Still has a fact like it still acts like it's real.
Speaker 1: We're basically.
Speaker 1: if you are married and want to cheat on your spouse They you can go and make a secret account and pay money.
Speaker 0: You just use any dating site for this.
Speaker 1: Well, the idea was that you no one can see your details fully like.
Speaker 1: it's secure.
Speaker 1: You can hit a button.
Speaker 0: It's a dating site, but it was specifically designed with this purpose in mind.
Speaker 0: having an affair They made some slight changes to it compared to say an okcupider or whatever.
Speaker 1: It is specifically cheat on your wife.
Speaker 1: And yes I say cheat on your wife because 80 plus percent of the profiles are men and the people who leaked the data said that Most of the female profiles were fake and made by the company.
Speaker 1: So it's a bunch of dudes trying to cheat on their wives and family and failing but paying money.
Speaker 1: Okay, and they had a feature where you could pay more money to delete all traces of your profile.
Speaker 0: guaranteed Yeah, not only money for that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she basically signed up and paid money for a service Which will then extort more money out of you.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Okay, and yeah, so if you sign up for this you are morons.
Speaker 1: So yeah, you're a best-case scenario.
Speaker 1: You're incredibly naive and polyamorous, but most likely you're just a shitbag guy trying to cheat On his wife.
Speaker 0: sure.
Speaker 0: I mean usually people who are legit polyamorous.
Speaker 0: if you go on real dating sites They're just like hey, yeah, you'll see people on there who are like, I'm gonna commit a relationship looking for some fun times.
Speaker 1: Yeah plus even if you're polyamorous and decide to use this site one.
Speaker 1: this site is marketed in the sleaziest fucking way ever and If you believe it if you go there and use it whoever you have sex with they're cheating on their husband or wife Supposedly.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: mean I suppose you could just sign up for this if you were really into getting with someone who is married So one
Speaker 1: so one guy regardless
Speaker 0: of your status what
Speaker 1: you're supposed to only sign up I think if you are currently in a committed relationship Mmm, but anyway, they uh one Farker was like, oh, yeah, I'm in there and he's like, here's my email address.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I signed up because I was writing this article about it.
Speaker 1: Then he linked to the article and he was like and this place was just full of sleazebags Of course full of sleazebags.
Speaker 0: So, huh?
Speaker 0: Who did I meet down at this strip club?
Speaker 0: a high-class individuals?
Speaker 1: Not at all.
Speaker 1: You you wouldn't enjoy it.
Speaker 1: it is quite lowbrow.
Speaker 0: No, I'm quite low.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not The opposite of lowbrow.
Speaker 1: So if unless you live under a rock you're at least are aware because this is in the regular news.
Speaker 1: The site got hacked.
Speaker 1: This got hacked probably more devastatingly than anything like this has ever been hacked before.
Speaker 1: the entire database of everything.
Speaker 1: It's just on Pirate Bay Right now.
Speaker 0: just SQL file.
Speaker 1: Yeah text files SQL everything.
Speaker 1: it's like this 12 gigabyte dump.
Speaker 0: I don't need I don't need to dump.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, I don't need to dump either.
Speaker 1: You know why?
Speaker 1: cuz like a hundred news sites are pouring through it.
Speaker 1: a couple of celebrities have already been not only caught But admitted to it because the evidence is damning.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I find this all vaguely amusing and There's a pretty good argument in the forum and the argument is thus I don't know we could do a show on this later, but just so you can set the stage This is the kind of thing to think about.
Speaker 1: What is the lot like when is activist hacking like this?
Speaker 1: Ethical or a good thing?
Speaker 0: because you got you mean that question is so loaded because you have so many overlapping topics here?
Speaker 0: Yeah that are bumping into each other and you have to address each of them separately.
Speaker 0: Well examples I use because someone was pressing because it's like if you can talk about like well is having affairs like the issues of Having affairs all right is involved here.
Speaker 0: So you have to take that out and address that on its own Right, then you have to address just the privacy issues in general the technical issues and they're all separate.
Speaker 0: or you Because they're all overlapping here.
Speaker 0: It's easy to get confused and it's not easy to discuss it properly.
Speaker 1: Like what if I'm gay and I'm trying to cheat on my wife who I don't love with men and I live in Saudi Arabia?
Speaker 1: Well, I'm gonna die because of this sure so theoretically.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so The the argument came down to the angle I was looking at.
Speaker 1: was the pure ethics of activist hacking a Fundamental level like that philosophical question because there are three use cases of it.
Speaker 0: Well activist hacking includes many activities only only one of which is take a database from someone's website and mature.
Speaker 1: So activist docks hacking like doxing hacking.
Speaker 0: Which is this doxing?
Speaker 0: in this hat you can docks without hacking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you can have Right, so those are completely separate doing both activist hacking to then release information.
Speaker 1: That is true about people.
Speaker 1: That was hidden.
Speaker 1: Okay, and you know, did you say oh well truth is generally good.
Speaker 1: So here's three three examples that are gonna keep you up at night Because this is the argument going on in the forum right now.
Speaker 1: The middle example is this where the vast majority of people on this side who actually used it are Undisputable shit bags.
Speaker 1: Sure, but some people might not be sure.
Speaker 1: So those people might get fucked by this.
Speaker 1: Okay I'm enjoying the hack.
Speaker 1: Anyway, even though yeah a few people probably get hurt cuz most of it.
Speaker 1: But anyway on the other side What if the KKK in the entire u.s.
Speaker 1: Every chapter you're gonna really close to Godwin here Yeah got hacked and that list just got released?
Speaker 1: Does that make the world better or worse to know that say some mayor is actually secretly a member of the KKK legit?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Well, what about ye sex offender registry?
Speaker 0: Which has a wave a whole bunch of people on who probably shouldn't be on there whose lives are ruined?
Speaker 1: All right, let's go the other way.
Speaker 0: What about on your KKK list wasn't actually in the KKK?
Speaker 1: Well, I'm saying what it was.
Speaker 1: a bona fide verified one like this one is interesting cuz Ashley Madison It's not.
Speaker 0: how do you know it's bona fide right?
Speaker 0: This is just something on pirate bay.
Speaker 1: No So this one's interesting because it does.
Speaker 1: there's one way to verify information like this and that is when there are many many Unstructured sources of data that all have to line up with each other.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the one thing that's super hard to hack and cheat.
Speaker 1: Like if you break into a Linux system It's actually real hard to like mess with stuff without leaving a trail Man, they might not be able to trace you back to like, you know, that person did the hack.
Speaker 1: But people look at the data and say oh that data was fucked with Because var log messages has a gap and this other log file show, you know that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: So here it's not just it's the profiles It's all the photos you posted of yourself all your communications your credit card number and all the transactions.
Speaker 1: It's pretty hard.
Speaker 1: Like you can pretty much prove for some of these accounts that it's bona fide like that person really did it.
Speaker 1: Hmm, but the other side what if an anti-abortion activist decided to hack Planned Parenthood and just released the database Everyone ever got an abortion.
Speaker 1: Mmm, that would be super bad and hurt a lot of people.
Speaker 0: I think in the first two examples, right?
Speaker 0: Those are databases all the fur.
Speaker 0: the KA one is database of bad people.
Speaker 0: here Right is a database of bad people right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like you want people like to talk about victim blaming right which is a real thing.
Speaker 0: where it's like Oh, well, you know you got murdered but it was your fault for walking into murder town Which is perfectly illegal and okay thing to do.
Speaker 0: and it's like well, you know what there's good tacos in murder town, right?
Speaker 0: Walking into murder town.
Speaker 0: you didn't do anything wrong.
Speaker 0: walking into murder town So it wasn't there was.
Speaker 0: no, you know justice there's like you just got murdered.
Speaker 1: It's not as you're going with this, but it is just wrong to be in the KKK, right?
Speaker 0: If you're in the KKK, I mean, so you're complaining that you got you know Messed up after you were doing something you weren't supposed to do.
Speaker 0: It's like if a kid, you know falls over and hurts his leg on the front porch.
Speaker 0: It's like oh my god It sucks, let me kiss it.
Speaker 0: make it better.
Speaker 0: if a kid falls off the fence and he was trying to climb into the neighbor's yard.
Speaker 0: It's a little different situation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right with that victim blaming right?
Speaker 0: It's like in both cases.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay The kid is the victim he fell down and hurt himself But in one case is he hurt himself in the act of doing something no good,
Speaker 1: but then the question is
Speaker 0: That's different than just the straight-up victim blaming of someone fell over and hurt themselves Blaming them for
Speaker 1: going deeper.
Speaker 1: What if his no-good was going into the neighbor's yard to steal bread just to feed his starving family?
Speaker 1: or you know The KKK guys think that they're doing good.
Speaker 0: Sure, so I do anything illegal unless they're lynching people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or even if they are and they're just burning crosses, which is legal I guess even if they are lynching people they not on someone else's lawn.
Speaker 1: They think that's a good thing.
Speaker 1: So, well, you know morals are pretty relative and arbitrary.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't agree that that's a good thing.
Speaker 0: So in the war of fighting against them if we win a battle, that's good in for me.
Speaker 0: Yep, and that is why philosophically, I'm confide a complex opinion and Whatever I believe in if we strike a blow against the enemy I say it's good.
Speaker 0: Yep, same as humans have done for a long time.
Speaker 0: only I'm willing to admit it and I don't have to have some sort of Consistent rule that applies to all situations like no, right if we beat the bad guys this way I don't need to apply the same principle to fuck the good guys Just because you know, I don't need to have this consistent principle.
Speaker 0: It's fuck the guys I don't like and yay for the people I do like.
Speaker 0: yeah That's how I don't have to be in the world.
Speaker 0: We'll always be trying to be like have this like.
Speaker 0: they need to have consistency and apply the same rules all the time.
Speaker 0: No fight the bad guys and go for the good guys.
Speaker 0: and who gives a shit if you apply the same here saying we should become terrorists.
Speaker 0: No, just fight for what you believe and you know, who cares about?
Speaker 0: you know, it's like it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, is it okay to probably like, you know blow up, you know, North Korea?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it probably is.
Speaker 0: Is it okay to blow up the UK?
Speaker 0: No, we don't need to make some rule that Blowing up things is always okay or always not.
Speaker 0: Okay, who?
Speaker 0: we don't need that.
Speaker 0: It's okay.
Speaker 0: If you do it to bad guys, it's not okay.
Speaker 1: if you do it to good guys Yeah, and of course bad guys include just random people in the desert happen to live in a town.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not saying that those people are right.
Speaker 0: In fact, I don't think anyone who's blown up anyone has been right in a very very very very very long time.
Speaker 1: Where it's also the separate question of I didn't do this hack But the data is there.
Speaker 1: What are the ethics of using that data if it's already there?
Speaker 1: That's the old, you know, there's a Star Trek about.
Speaker 1: they find a Nazi doctor's hologram.
Speaker 1: They bring him back and he has the cure to a horrible disease.
Speaker 1: But he got that cure by genociding tons of planets and killing trillions.
Speaker 1: Do you use the cure or not?
Speaker 0: The cure actually gonna work.
Speaker 1: Uh, yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah that use it.
Speaker 0: Otherwise those people died in even more vain.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's the question of do you use the Nazi doctors evil for good?
Speaker 1: But the argument against it is that by you can't undo the evil.
Speaker 1: by using it you encourage people to do more evil because they Know that the fruits of their evil.
Speaker 1: I don't use by good people.
Speaker 0: No, fuck that Just because you're saying just as I use that Those people who decide to do more evil because I did some good can go fuck themselves.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that is an argument.
Speaker 1: my whole point of this is that the Ashley Madison hack is a very complex issue that is not easy to argue about because even Poking it just glancing at it already opens like 20 different arguments.
Speaker 1: So if you have a discussion with a friend and they don't see how complex an issue this is.
Speaker 1: They're probably not that bright.
Speaker 1: That's the only point I got there.
Speaker 0: You got to split it up into the separate points and address each one individually without you know.
Speaker 0: You can't like suddenly start talking about you know Is an affair, you know, it's having an affair even bad it while you're still talking about like, you know, just you know privacy.
Speaker 0: It's like no you have to discuss privacy and then you had to discuss and they're completely separate.
Speaker 1: that is the.
Speaker 1: that is actually one of my easiest signs of a person who is incapable of argument or knows their position as Bullshit.
Speaker 1: when they take an issue like this and as soon as you make some headway against them on whatever it is They're arguing they shift to one of those other topics to make sure that you can dislike whack-a-mole.
Speaker 1: You can never actually finish them on anything because they'll always move a little bit to the left a little bit to the right Right.
Speaker 0: It's like no.
Speaker 0: those are all completely separate arguments and each one has you know Multiple different answers or perhaps no answer or a really easy definitive answer.
Speaker 1: Anyway things of the day My thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I'm using this only because this like I Scott doesn't like talk about politics and I follow politics like sports And they're not as highly paid in many ways as some sports professionals, but anyway I'm using this as my thing of the day because it's so beautiful.
Speaker 1: I don't even like.
Speaker 1: I cannot even you can only odd.
Speaker 1: I can only so Right now in North Carolina, which is far from the worst state in the United States.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll say that Yeah, like it's in it's in the top half.
Speaker 0: It's not great.
Speaker 0: It has issues but has serious issues in fact, but it's not the worst, you know I
Speaker 1: said it was in the top half, but that could also mean the northern half anyway, so The top three polling candidates there in the in the just general election Like you just ask people like hey who should be president?
Speaker 1: Yeah 40% right now is Donald fucking Trump.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: I remember only old people are answering these polls.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I don't mean anything.
Speaker 1: Hillary Clinton 38% but the margin of error is 3.2%.
Speaker 1: So it's a toss-up between the two of them.
Speaker 0: I think the margin of error is quite larger than that.
Speaker 1: So number three with almost 10% sitting in at 9%.
Speaker 0: Nice third party usually gets about 10% in the US.
Speaker 1: is these nuts?
Speaker 1: Yeah These nuts these nuts is actually polling pretty consistently well across the country.
Speaker 1: And if you watch American media because overseas I've realized people see like our big political stuff But they don't see like the internals of our primaries.
Speaker 1: Uh Watch our news a little bit because every newscaster in the world now in America now talking about this stuff has to say these nuts Has to refer to a candidate these nuts and not laugh.
Speaker 0: He's be a 9% of the people of North Carolina voted for these nuts.
Speaker 1: these nuts I think I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think I'm more a fan of Demball's.
Speaker 0: Scott brought that I you know, I am a supporter of Demball's.
Speaker 0: But if everyone's already gonna get another these nuts trained we would only be splitting our voter base.
Speaker 0: Get to four and a half percent.
Speaker 0: that doesn't work in the US election.
Speaker 0: I like them balls, but you gotta Already got nine percent on these nuts.
Speaker 0: We'll stick with these nuts.
Speaker 0: You can't be around these nuts than dem nuts.
Speaker 0: Them two nuts are falling better.
Speaker 1: This photo is just so beautiful.
Speaker 1: So you got a thing.
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 0: so this guy is really smart.
Speaker 0: He made a time-lapse video.
Speaker 0: It's really short, but it's of a very interesting thing.
Speaker 0: It's of his sourdough starter.
Speaker 0: Whoo overnight so you can see the yeasts going and the dough going bla bla bla bla bla.
Speaker 1: the secret life of sourdough starter.
Speaker 0: Yes, it's the secret light.
Speaker 0: You can basically just watch what this bread blob of flour and yeast and water does at night and It's not something you often see at this speed and it's just.
Speaker 0: you know There's so many things out there to time-lapse that people just haven't thought to time-lapse.
Speaker 0: and you know You can see a lot of interesting stuff like this.
Speaker 0: You know with high-speed cameras low-speed cameras, you know high magnification and also zooming way out.
Speaker 0: There's many things in this world even just on this earth to see that have not been seen and this is one of them That I had never seen before In the meta moment.
Speaker 1: This is our last episode probably before Pax Prime.
Speaker 1: Oh snap many of you Pax yep, not Ravenna, but Rome Correct so many of you might be listening to this episode of gig nights right now because you saw us at PAX and you were Like, oh, what are those assholes were?
Speaker 1: and you got what you chose?
Speaker 1: He chose this episode because it'll be the most recent episode.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be this dance dance revolution HTTP proxies and the lightning round.
Speaker 0: Oh great.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, uh We did or are doing two panels slash lectures at PAX on Sunday The far future of gaming.
Speaker 1: at 1 p.m The Sphinx theater with me and Scott Luke crane cat small Josephine foo and Emily Compton.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Like for real.
Speaker 1: we're gonna talk about like seriously not joking What games will be like 50 100 500 years from now?
Speaker 1: Like what?
Speaker 1: what will role-playing games be like in the distant culture future?
Speaker 1: nice.
Speaker 1: and then on Monday Like we said before at 4 p.m.
Speaker 1: Also in the Sphinx theater.
Speaker 1: sports are games Nerds.
Speaker 1: they are talking about eSports regular sports the overlap between the two games.
Speaker 1: sports are games.
Speaker 1: Not all games are sports.
Speaker 1: some games are but we're gonna say the brain isn't a muscle just because.
Speaker 1: otherwise anyway It's gonna be a real good lecture.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm might even take a question or two at the end very end of packs Yeah, and then we're gonna run hopefully to the omega-thon finale or not make it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe we'll live stream it.
Speaker 1: Who knows well to stay in the room because we're probably the last panel in there and just watch it on our phones.
Speaker 0: The enforcers are gonna want to take the room apart.
Speaker 1: Oh, they'll let us sit in there and watch it.
Speaker 1: I think we'll see.
Speaker 1: I mean we're enforcers just not at this packs.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they'll be cool.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: the enforcers have never not been cool in my entire Run, we've been to every packs as geek night since 2008.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna not take apart the room Yeah, but they might let us sit in the room watching the omega-thon anyway.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the book club book is the eye of the world by Robert Jordan.
Speaker 1: I Think because it's getting toward nothing happening.
Speaker 0: No, you know what at the end they go to the eye of the world.
Speaker 1: Wow, all right boilers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I get the impression that this book is Just.
Speaker 1: it's just like the beginning of a whole bunch of books that'll go at the same pace until the end and I worry I might actually have to read them all or read spoilers.
Speaker 0: I put the second book on my Kindle To check.
Speaker 0: the first chapter picks right up.
Speaker 0: it just picks right up and it's as if it's thought that you could have just put that first chapter as the Final chapter of the first book and it would have been like up.
Speaker 0: and then of course It would have been a weird conclusion because it's a starter and it sort of reintroduces the characters and things is.
Speaker 1: it's the first chapter Of a new book I might power through and read the rest of the Wheel of Time stuff just because won't be that long until Our Scott backers book comes out.
Speaker 0: Just just need some fantasy novel doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Just anything.
Speaker 1: No, once there's a date for the next Prince of Nothing book I'm pretty much gonna reread all those books because I've kind of forgotten details and I kind of want to be ready for that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you didn't forget how to break horses and men.
Speaker 0: Oh Remember how to break?
Speaker 1: or there was so long ago.
Speaker 1: We're so far beyond him.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, guess we never did a show on cookies which I'm pretty sure we have Dutch search for one.
Speaker 1: All right, our search fucking sucks.
Speaker 1: So Let me try I mean on the archive right now.
Speaker 1: I just had cookie.
Speaker 0: Try the actual admin search.
Speaker 1: I also searched there.
Speaker 1: Nothing came up.
Speaker 0: Nothing came up.
Speaker 0: Well people love them food shows and I love them cookies.
Speaker 0: So cookie show it is.
Speaker 0: So cookies are pretty much separated into two carrot categories in this world the bought cookie and the baked cookie.
Speaker 1: There's some overlap though because like fresh direct I can get cookies that are baked cookies Like.
Speaker 0: they're the same as something I would make at home effectively if it was made in a commercial bakery Then it is obviously even el fudge and chips ahoy are baked, right?
Speaker 0: It was made in a commercial bakery No matter how good it is a bought cookie if it was made in an oven No larger than the oven most people have in their homes.
Speaker 0: That's your line.
Speaker 1: I don't step above that because the cookie the oven at Takahachi Bakery is Significantly larger than the oven in either of our homes.
Speaker 0: That sounds like a professional place.
Speaker 0: It is a professional place like a bought cookie to me.
Speaker 1: But they make the cookies from scratch there every day.
Speaker 1: and you know, they make chips ahoy from scratch But they made a with a large mass recipe.
Speaker 1: mass recipes to be able to produce so much So consistently tend to be suddenly different from like the master baker decides.
Speaker 1: This is the kind of cookie I'm going to make today.
Speaker 0: I mean if you have a giant oven usually have a big mixer and a big tub of cookie dough.
Speaker 0: You're making a big.
Speaker 1: don't make that many cookies every day though.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you those run out of cookies then.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they run out of almost everything every day.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Well, that's not good.
Speaker 0: You want to make some more cookies then so you don't run out until the very minute you close your store.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what those cookies real dangerous.
Speaker 1: I've stopped buying them because I'll eat all four of them.
Speaker 0: But anyway, both bots and baked cookies can be quite delicious Right.
Speaker 0: They can also be quite nasty.
Speaker 0: Some people suck at baking and they bake a shitty cookie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also a lot of people like basically stale preservative filled trans fat cookies in boxes and bags, right?
Speaker 0: Well, you know, those are the shitty baked cookies.
Speaker 0: But even some of the mass-produced cookies can still be yummy.
Speaker 0: You know you get a nice get a nice golden Oreo.
Speaker 1: I thought that I thought that I've decided Golden Oreos are a trap.
Speaker 1: I only like them because I'm like out of packs and rower.
Speaker 1: someone brought them and I'm desperately hungry and the cookie Brigade hasn't been buyers.
Speaker 0: a golden Oreo is so delicious.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know Gordon golden Oreo when you have other things available.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, I usually don't eat a cookie, you know, just sugar all the time when I have other things available.
Speaker 0: All right, but a cookie is Like the first most easiest thing to bake because you don't need to use any yeasts You know, you can get the same you can do the same consistent thing every time you just.
Speaker 1: they are Incredibly consistent to make and also incredibly shelf stable.
Speaker 0: You just mix up a dough and you spoon the dough and blobs onto a sheet and make it hot.
Speaker 1: Now there are complicated cookies that that is not true for but those are the cookies grandma makes.
Speaker 1: don't worry about that.
Speaker 0: Grandma's cookies usually harness good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, depending on things depending on the grandma.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my grandma may go cookies.
Speaker 0: yeah, depends.
Speaker 1: so I Kind of have a problem with cookies.
Speaker 0: Cookies you eat all of them.
Speaker 1: So yes, I will get like fancy cookies.
Speaker 0: Maybe this is why you don't like the golden Oreos.
Speaker 0: if I get a bag golden Oreo I'll eat like two and that's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I'll eat two again way later like days later.
Speaker 1: But I eat good cookies on such a constant basis Like I eat so many cookies that Emily is vaguely horrified at it.
Speaker 0: Yeah You'll buy a box of like cookies the big kind like eight or nine like huge Shortbread the kind that are like three inch diameter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and like half an inch thick and you'll eat all of them at once.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well now I will eat all of them over the span of about 48 hours.
Speaker 0: All right I don't see how that's really any different than like the Red Bulls you drinkin.
Speaker 1: You know what.
Speaker 1: there are So many more calories in those cookies.
Speaker 1: Red Bull actually is not that like Red Bulls way less than soda.
Speaker 0: You're really just filling yourself up with sugar.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really matter which vehicle the sugar is.
Speaker 1: I'm also filling myself up with fat and shortening.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's it's the sugar truck the sugar boat the sugar plane the sugar cargo plane.
Speaker 1: When you need a lot of honey and you're in I go sugar sugar sugar from your head to your toe.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really matter how the sugar gets in there.
Speaker 0: It's getting in but cookie is a great way to go.
Speaker 1: So yeah, there was a famous incident where so I would buy these cookies and I'd be like, oh Emily I bought us some cookies and there's.
Speaker 1: then I put him in the fridge.
Speaker 0: You mean about you some cookies?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I bought us some cookies and by the time Emily gets home.
Speaker 1: I've already eaten three of them.
Speaker 1: So there's only like four left and then I eat one more and I'm like, oh Emily you want one?
Speaker 1: So she eats one and I eat one and then I eat another one.
Speaker 1: cuz I'm hungry.
Speaker 0: That's the last cookie.
Speaker 1: So one day it's gotten to the point to where I tried buying two things of cookies and they just eat more.
Speaker 1: They disappeared at the same in the same time period.
Speaker 1: we'll put it that way.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe this is why you should keep buying the you know Not mass manufactured cookie because even if there are some delicious ones like golden Oreo I worry that I would eat an entire the entire bag.
Speaker 0: That's way too much sugar.
Speaker 0: and Even you know baked cookies while they still have a load of sugar Usually have less and are usually have more say flour.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well also, you know what cookies the most the kind of like crapo cookies the most people eat like generic cookies.
Speaker 1: They're good But the reason the like special cookies are better tasting is that they usually have a lot more butter sugar stuff in them.
Speaker 1: So they're actually way more calories than you realize.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: There's way more.
Speaker 0: You're usually will be more butter.
Speaker 0: All right, where's that?
Speaker 0: a chips?
Speaker 0: Ahoy that doesn't have real butter in it.
Speaker 1: Like our friend Judith with you know the bait like the her blog on baked goods.
Speaker 1: The secret to making most things taste better than store-bought is just to put four times more butter in right.
Speaker 0: I mean it chips.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm telling you doesn't really have butter.
Speaker 0: It probably uses shortening or some other sorts of vegetable oils or like.
Speaker 0: so, you know Who knows what kind of oils they're using right?
Speaker 0: Because that has to be stable on the shelf you put butter in a bag on the shelf in the grocery store.
Speaker 0: Right, I mean bake some cookies.
Speaker 0: How long do they last?
Speaker 0: like a couple days and then they're hard.
Speaker 0: Yep You know and then it's not a good situation.
Speaker 1: but even then cookies are good.
Speaker 1: like they're relatively shelf stable.
Speaker 1: They keep like some kinds of cookies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they just they'll just get hard but doesn't mean they're not good anymore.
Speaker 0: other things get hard And then you can't eat them like a muffin ones a muffins hard It's done.
Speaker 1: but meanwhile like but a hard cookie is like still good.
Speaker 1: But like if you bake a cookie like Scott McElmett cookies cut off you have a little as much.
Speaker 0: recently It's too hot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but like they get hard, but they're still really good.
Speaker 1: But like Oreos if they're out too long Once they break the seal and they're open they get stale.
Speaker 0: Well, they either have preservatives and they don't.
Speaker 1: yeah, but stale I can eat a hard cook.
Speaker 0: That's why they keep putting them in bags these days that reseal Yeah, and then they stay fresh.
Speaker 0: really a lot of people don't oh, you know, they'll open the bag wrong or something.
Speaker 0: It's like oh you just ruin that fuck that.
Speaker 1: That's that's that's one of the.
Speaker 1: There's very few things that I will judge someone on real hard about.
Speaker 1: like if someone just openly racist in front of me Like there's a permanent mark on their like record in my brain like alright.
Speaker 1: or like if someone's smoking cigarettes and hasn't quit.
Speaker 1: If you don't reseal cookies That's that's a mark.
Speaker 0: if you're at a party and someone opens up a bag and leaves it open on that tip I'm like, you know the snack table that's not making it till the morning.
Speaker 0: But if you reseal it and at home you buy a bag of cookies and keep take to put them back take to put them back That'll be good for days long time.
Speaker 1: So I experienced something kind of recently because I Started occasionally sampling marijuana against put it that way and that really hadn't really been a thing since a few times in college and Just so happened last time.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of cookies around and you know my problem with cookies already.
Speaker 0: Did you eat too many cookies?
Speaker 0: So I'm sure they wouldn't.
Speaker 0: they taste bad the cookies.
Speaker 1: No, they just so.
Speaker 1: no they taste the same.
Speaker 1: So they were not marijuana cookies.
Speaker 1: There were regular cookies A lot of marijuana.
Speaker 1: Okay, and it's I'll put it this way This is gonna make me sound a real old.
Speaker 1: when we were at our IT and I would occasionally have marijuana That was way weaker than what marijuana is like nowadays.
Speaker 1: well I'm sure you can still get the weak stuff if you probably can but like the way people consume it and just that there's.
Speaker 1: So I had more than I was accustomed to.
Speaker 1: and I'm sitting there and we're playing Mario Kart and whatever and everything's fine.
Speaker 1: and I think to myself I would like a cookie and I walk over to where the cookies are and I can only tell you that this was exactly like Cookie Monster.
Speaker 1: Think about how bad I am with the cookies now coupled with the munchies.
Speaker 1: I basically ate like an entire thing of Oreos.
Speaker 0: That's what you do.
Speaker 0: Yep All right, just oh no, no And this is why I don't smoke weed.
Speaker 0: you get stoner stories like this like oh my god I ate a bunch of cookies.
Speaker 1: Okay But it was such an order of magnitude more cookies than I eat with my already Not smoking marijuana cookie.
Speaker 0: That's stoner brain.
Speaker 0: Imagining the magnitude of the cookies like you're probably in your mind.
Speaker 0: There was like an avalanche of cookie like the frickin Those.
Speaker 0: what's that frickin cereal that tastes?
Speaker 0: Oh Cookie crisp cereal like the good.
Speaker 0: right the disgusting shit, right?
Speaker 0: And you're probably imagining like you were in a cookie crisp commercial or whatever.
Speaker 0: in reality.
Speaker 1: You ate a whole bunch of cookies Yeah, but it was like 20 or 30 of these Oreos.
Speaker 0: I mean I can eat 20 or 30 or If I don't eat anything else, I won't say to a whole full bag of Twizzlers.
Speaker 0: It's not really that different.
Speaker 0: Well, I can eat a giant pixie stick.
Speaker 1: The idea used to have those pixie six star it cuz we could buy them at the corner store.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah but Yeah, those cookie cereals.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna those aren't cookies.
Speaker 1: No, it's just disgusting.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right, so let's talk about cookie variety.
Speaker 0: I Can't make a top three because basically without you don't have to order them.
Speaker 0: See what really these days people are mixing together so many different cookie ingredients Right to make all sorts of you know delicious combinations So that it's like you can't pick one single favorite cookie because it's like, you know, there's so many possible variations.
Speaker 1: Well, you go by your class of cookie then right?
Speaker 0: Well, I think the number one thing is I like a cookie.
Speaker 0: There are factors of cookie and if you combine these factors you will achieve perfect cookiness, right?
Speaker 0: So the first factor is heat right and chewiness.
Speaker 0: I like the chewy cookie.
Speaker 0: I don't like the crisp hard cookie.
Speaker 1: I like both in different circumstances.
Speaker 1: People say they like chewy cookie but like the average of person in Peoria the kind of cookie they want is that mrs Fields like it's just warmed up cookie dough, right?
Speaker 0: So the heat that's it.
Speaker 0: the chewiness can't come from fake chewiness like a chewy Chips Ahoy Although those are good, but you know, that's not the right kind of chewiness, right?
Speaker 0: It has to come from the heat of having just been baked and cooled off enough.
Speaker 0: You can't get it straight out of the oven.
Speaker 0: You'll burn yourself right cooled off enough so that it's ready and cool to be eaten But still chewy because active molecules from just being baked That is the right.
Speaker 0: if the chewiness comes from any other source is not the right kind of.
Speaker 1: yeah You want a little too, but that's the yes the walk.
Speaker 0: Hey, right.
Speaker 0: So then, you know in the doughy part, right?
Speaker 0: It's all about the sugars being as tasting as close to caramel slash butterscotch as possible.
Speaker 0: All right, when you make a cookie really you're just taking butter sugar flour You know egg possibly and just trying to get caramel into some sort of bread like shape and texture Right, but really you just want it to taste like fucking caramel.
Speaker 0: So the closer it tastes to that the better the cookie part is.
Speaker 1: so I guess on that note in terms of that flavor I like really complicated weird cookies like fancy ones.
Speaker 1: But like I had I'm not gonna lie my favorite kinds of cookies aren't sugar cookies Bread cooking cookie and cookie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's the chocolate chip cookie.
Speaker 1: That is a fundamentally different class of cookie.
Speaker 1: Sure, whatever like they serve a different purpose.
Speaker 1: They feel different and they serve a different craving.
Speaker 0: And then in terms of the filling in the cookie, right?
Speaker 0: The best filling you can possibly put in a cookie is Pretty much fruits nuts and chocolates of any kind.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really matter, but you're a medium.
Speaker 1: I like just the sugar cookie.
Speaker 0: the best fruits you can put in are dried fruits like say a Raisin or a craisin, right?
Speaker 1: What about the fancy grandma cookie?
Speaker 1: There's like shortbread on the outside and then like that apricot stuff you get in a hamantashen.
Speaker 0: on the inside That's like a fruit filling.
Speaker 0: That's not needed.
Speaker 0: So you're venturing slightly out of cookie.
Speaker 0: That is a cookie.
Speaker 1: Sure I'm gonna go the Wikipedia page on cookie.
Speaker 0: It's a hamantashen by the way.
Speaker 1: anyway, the I pronounced it with my Midwestern media for the.
Speaker 0: For the nuts, right the absolute best nut is the walnut.
Speaker 0: There's pretty much no better not to put in a sweet cookie treat.
Speaker 1: that is true.
Speaker 1: That's why de Bella's has chocolate chip cookies and chocolate chip cookies with walnuts.
Speaker 1: The latter are just superior.
Speaker 0: Well, that's a real expensive for a reason.
Speaker 0: And of course chocolate you want to put in Not the sweet chocolate.
Speaker 0: the sweetness is coming from the cookie You want to put in to contrast the flavor the dark chocolate or the semi-sweet or the bitter chocolate.
Speaker 0: and you don't want to Put in too much either.
Speaker 0: you want to put in so this is enough in each bite.
Speaker 0: So you get a little chocolate in each bite.
Speaker 0: You don't get like a face full of nothing but cookie.
Speaker 0: But you don't want to just be eating a chocolate bar with extra sugar added either.
Speaker 0: All right, it's got to be the right amount in there.
Speaker 1: All right, the Wikipedia is pretty much like spot-on.
Speaker 1: It's very clear.
Speaker 1: Like this is United States centric a sweet baked treat flour eggs sugar butter cooking oil Or another fat of some kind.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and maybe with something like raisins oats chocolate chips or nuts.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: That's cookie Yeah, or biscuit if you live somewhere weird.
Speaker 0: Now there are certain very popular cookies.
Speaker 0: I would like to comment on right?
Speaker 1: Oh, here's a list of all known names.
Speaker 1: There's a Wikipedia page list of all cookies, but then on the cookie page there is a list of notable cookie variety, right?
Speaker 0: So here's some notable cookie varieties.
Speaker 1: Whoa, what's a fatigue man?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know that kind of cookie.
Speaker 1: that's a doughnut though, it's not a cookie.
Speaker 0: All right, so notable important cookies to discuss.
Speaker 0: Number one the Girl Scout cookie, you know what?
Speaker 1: overrated?
Speaker 1: I don't like him anymore.
Speaker 0: Most people seem to like the really fancy ones that are complicated like the tag along right?
Speaker 0: I Prefer the thin mint but even more I prefer the one that no one gives a shit about which is the trefoil.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the shortbread one.
Speaker 1: That's the best girl.
Speaker 0: The trefoil is just the shape of a Girl Scout logo and it's a cookie.
Speaker 1: It's a shortbread cookie, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's just really freaking good and no one gives it any respect cuz it's so boring compared to Like the do-si-do or whatever.
Speaker 0: So you can get them real easily, but they taste great.
Speaker 0: I don't know and I you know the complicated ones I think just trying too hard.
Speaker 0: But the problem is I used to really like girls and the thin mint, you know The the chocolate quality in the thin mint.
Speaker 0: either I've been able to taste better chocolate or it's gotten worse because the chocolate and the thin mint is like the lowest Quality chocolate that there is I'd say and the mint is not nearly as strong as it used to be with the trefoil.
Speaker 1: Once I started eating fresh baked shortbread cookies, those things are just garbage.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, it's just it's not a good version of that, but I'm comparing girls cookies to other girl But I'm saying comparing them to real cookies.
Speaker 0: and with the thin yeah I mean a girl's got cookies a mass manufactured not great cookie.
Speaker 0: No matter which one you get.
Speaker 1: the thin mint is in the same tier as the Andes mint.
Speaker 1: cheap chocolate Barely any.
Speaker 0: and you would be surprised.
Speaker 0: the chocolate and mint in the Andes candies Which are not cookies, by the way, it's better than the chocolate and mint in a thin mint.
Speaker 1: I'd agree with that.
Speaker 1: thinking about it.
Speaker 0: It's actually you know.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the girl scout cookie, okay So the Oreo Oreos been doing the thing lately, but they got tons of crazy flavors.
Speaker 0: That's their stick now and they have limp.
Speaker 0: They're all limited time.
Speaker 1: So, you know about the difference between Oreos and hydrox.
Speaker 0: Oh you want to talk about hydrox.
Speaker 1: Hydrox came first and in blind taste tests was better.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: I Have eaten both.
Speaker 0: I've never done a blind taste test, but the cookie part the frosting I can never tell the difference.
Speaker 0: But I could tell without even looking Eating the hydrox because the cookie is drier and the hydrox but has a more chocolatey flavor.
Speaker 0: That is true, but the dryness of the hydrox cookie You know Even though the chocolatey flavor of the hydrox cookie part is better because the Oreo cookie the chocolate one really doesn't taste like anything.
Speaker 0: It's really just a vehicle for the frosting except the golden Oreo, which tastes great.
Speaker 0: The dryness of the hydrox just may cancel it out.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I just I always remember as a kid There were a few people in the neighborhood who always got hydrox and everyone else got Oreos and I remember even make hydrox anyone.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to figure that out right now but basically everyone always assumed that hydrox was like this bullshit knockoff and Like that was what the poor kids would eat.
Speaker 1: But now it was the opposite.
Speaker 1: the hydrox was like the high quality one and Oreo was the knockoff of hydrox.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Let's see purchase.
Speaker 1: so formed in 1908.
Speaker 1: It's old.
Speaker 1: The company was bought by Keebler in 1996 mmm.
Speaker 1: and in 99 they replaced hydrox with a similar but reformulated thing named Roxy.
Speaker 1: So hydrox is dead.
Speaker 1: Okay, as far as I can tell a bunch of carrot carvel Use the hydrox cookie crumbs until 2012 Because I guess they're kosher.
Speaker 1: Alright interesting.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so Oreos got all these crazy flavors in the shtick and my co-workers sort of like.
Speaker 0: we're always get whatever those new flavors are and They usually do a pretty good job of tasting like what they say on the package.
Speaker 0: But it's I think they keep them limited for a reason is that you'll realize like oh, there's really no point to this It's just you know more Oreo.
Speaker 1: They also don't taste that different like I wonder in blind tastes.
Speaker 0: I'll bet we just had.
Speaker 0: the one we had most recently was like brownie batter Oreo where the filling was replaced With something that tasted like brownie batter and it was pretty much just chocolate Oreo chocolate filling.
Speaker 0: it's like yeah, it had a very subtle difference.
Speaker 0: that was clearly brownie batter.
Speaker 0: ish, but What big deal?
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: It's not like blowing you away.
Speaker 0: Like my life has changed.
Speaker 0: I love these so much.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not something insanely good, you know, that's not you know, I'd rather eat just plain old golden Oreo.
Speaker 0: so Anyway, yeah And you know a lot of the weird flavors.
Speaker 0: like you don't even want to eat them at all like the watermelon one It's like oh, yeah, let's go to watermelon flaving.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's enough for that for me.
Speaker 0: I'm done.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: It's like with cocktails.
Speaker 1: I like the pure sort of classic cocktails with cookies.
Speaker 1: I like the pure classic cookies.
Speaker 1: I like, you know, tall house style cookies.
Speaker 1: I like oatmeal cookies.
Speaker 1: I like shortbread and sugar cookies.
Speaker 0: so the animal cracker is a cookie despite being called an animal cracker and It's usually Even though it's you know in the shape of an animal which is always fun.
Speaker 0: cuz like I'll bite off the giraffe's head And then his legs and I always get it on JetBlue.
Speaker 0: cuz I don't want these little garbage.
Speaker 0: They're handing out Animal crackers regardless of who makes them seemed mostly just be like graham crackers in a different shape.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're very cinnamon-y and honey.
Speaker 1: We can't get into that because if we talk about graham crackers, you know, like, you know really like those.
Speaker 0: uh, Teddy Graham's That's usually what an animal cracker tastes like.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, except Teddy Graham's always have like some weird coating to make them extra sweet.
Speaker 0: Well, that's what animal cracker tastes like depends on the animal cracker.
Speaker 0: Sure Also, they remember when that is Teddy Graham's where they stuck to Teddy Graham's together with filling between them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like really really I remember I would own nowadays.
Speaker 1: I only get animal crackers on airplanes Mmm, and I actually only get them if I did.
Speaker 1: there isn't a better option.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the graham cracker despite being really popular and coming in many different forms is really just sort of this bridge cookie in between The regular cookie and the gingersnap.
Speaker 0: right obviously a graham cracker.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have ginger and it has like cinnamon or whatever.
Speaker 0: But it's sort of like this area of cookie where he gets the spicy sweetness coming in because the cinnamon honey combo and Ginger snap is like.
Speaker 0: no, we're gonna make a spice cookie.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah I like me a gingersnap as long as it's still got some softness to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Snaps get hard then it's like a spice cookie.
Speaker 1: is all those things like we'd always make.
Speaker 1: you know The Christmas cookies with the shapes with spice.
Speaker 0: Yeah gingerbread man that same deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the windmill cookie.
Speaker 1: That was my favorite mass-manufactured cookie.
Speaker 1: as a kid was the windmill cookie.
Speaker 1: Mmm Cuz those things had those thin sliced almonds in them.
Speaker 0: So there's chips ahoy.
Speaker 0: and what's the other brand?
Speaker 1: I can't eat that shit.
Speaker 0: There's the other brand.
Speaker 0: What is?
Speaker 1: it doesn't matter I. Chocolate chip cookies in packages are just like I can't eat them.
Speaker 1: They taste like preservative to me like they taste like they're.
Speaker 1: they're soft still and my brain says this should not be soft.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just can't.
Speaker 0: there's like two major brands of you know, bagged cookie.
Speaker 0: that are right bad cookie.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's also, you know a bunch of other similar kind of things down there like the EL fudge.
Speaker 0: It's like the two little Keebler elves with a ship in between them.
Speaker 1: when I was a little kid I really liked those because there was no lady when we had block parties who would always set up a table.
Speaker 1: It's just tons and tons and tons of those things and I just stand there to fisting them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then I got a little older and my tongue probably revolt if I did that there's still a step up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they are.
Speaker 0: but then you go step up even further and now you're getting into Vienna finger territory Which Vienna finger is like a slightly differently shaped golden Oreo with little less sugar and a little more cake flavor.
Speaker 1: I feel like Vienna fingers.
Speaker 1: there was an era at RIT with the Vienna fingers.
Speaker 0: Vienna fingers are good.
Speaker 1: They were okay.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they live up anymore.
Speaker 0: No, this tastes Vienna finger flavor has never changed.
Speaker 0: as far as I can.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: I'm saying my taste might have gone beyond them.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: So then after that you start getting into like the hard mode, right?
Speaker 0: the hard mode is like chess men that come in a bag or School boys using the Milano's right?
Speaker 1: I like the school boys.
Speaker 1: the white chocolate.
Speaker 1: school boys are pretty right.
Speaker 0: These are.
Speaker 0: these are cookies are mass-manufactured But you only get a few at a time and they come in a little baggie or something and they're kind of fancy Except that they're not really fancy.
Speaker 0: get them anywhere.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I'll eat them all.
Speaker 1: so that's the problem.
Speaker 0: And then the highest level of store-bought cookie the malamar which might not even be a fucking cookie depending.
Speaker 1: I'm not a big fan of Malamar's.
Speaker 0: Malamar's cost five bucks for a reason.
Speaker 1: I just don't like it that much.
Speaker 0: It's basically a s'more.
Speaker 0: That's not warm It's like a packaged up s'more.
Speaker 0: you get a s'more whenever you want No campfire.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that is why it's five bucks to get a box of Malamar's the wok.
Speaker 1: Hey, that can't be.
Speaker 0: and it's more obviously a Malamar is not a replacement for a campfire s'more It is simply an alternative s'more variety.
Speaker 0: Right much in the same way that Something I can't come up with an example for right now.
Speaker 0: So there you have it.
Speaker 0: Yep, if Malamar's are on sale you buy them.
Speaker 0: if they're not you don't.
Speaker 1: One thing we can say though We're coming up on PAX and one of the things I really love about PAX is the cookie brigade because we were sitting there.
Speaker 0: they Brigade the finest the finest of cookies.
Speaker 1: You're like halfway through a game and everyone's pretty hungry just because you haven't gone out to eat yet And I'm gonna eat
Speaker 0: when this game's over, but it's only half over
Speaker 1: Yep, and then like you really want some food, but you can't stand up and suddenly someone behind you just says cookie Brigade
Speaker 0: It's like
Speaker 1: oh
Speaker 0: you have a delicious sugar that has been set on fire.
Speaker 0: I have a photograph of George, Washington.
Speaker 1: Yeah, shall we trade a lot of times?
Speaker 1: Here's ten bucks.
Speaker 1: Just let me grab a fistful of cookies.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna eat them all right now.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you could probably they better not let you have the whole bag He's not?
Speaker 0: rim could eat the whole bag and then what would they do?
Speaker 0: That's why usually I think like they get up on the stage and it packs and by guys.
Speaker 0: this year Cookie Brigade only brought in like ten bucks.
Speaker 0: the ten bucks that rim gave us before I had all the cookies They like.
Speaker 1: roll me out of the stage.
Speaker 1: I'm still eating the cookies.
Speaker 0: We all know we had gluten-free ones left over that he didn't eat, but no one wanted him.
Speaker 1: He's trying to eat him like now.
Speaker 0: There's only one person here who actually had 97 98 97.
Speaker 1: You know the real situation.
Speaker 1: they come up and like we raised $800,000 this year Just one guy gave us all this cash.
Speaker 1: He's eating all the cookies in the back right now.
Speaker 0: The final game of facts is rim.
Speaker 0: Eat cookie.
Speaker 1: How many will he eat?
Speaker 0: bet Whoever's closer without going over with you.
Speaker 0: guys don't understand.
Speaker 1: Not only do I like cookies, but I As soon as the show ends, I'm gonna run in cuz why I just got some cookies that are fresh.
Speaker 0: You ate one before the show.
Speaker 1: I ate two daddy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I ate one right when I came home.
Speaker 1: Do you eat cookie?
Speaker 0: I had to.
Speaker 0: I picked.
Speaker 1: I pulled out another one As I was walking over here.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Did you have you have a problem?
Speaker 1: except
Speaker 0: If I have cookies in my house usually I have to bring them to work to get them finished off because I don't control myself and eat a Ration of them per day if and some days I don't even any because it's it's too much I think
Speaker 1: the difference
Speaker 0: like at work today.
Speaker 0: There's a bag of Kit Kats, you know the mini ones.
Speaker 0: So I ate like, you know - so that's it You know slightly less than a full normal person.
Speaker 1: I can only eat about two of those.
Speaker 1: before I felt blarg and now I don't even eat a whole Snickers bar.
Speaker 0: And now when I get home I'm not gonna be eating any cookie or any kind of chocolate or dessert whatsoever.
Speaker 1: cuz I think the difference is just my Metabolism because I weigh the same that I've weighed for like 15 years.
Speaker 1: I weigh 155 pounds.
Speaker 1: It never deviates.
Speaker 0: I weigh about the same, you know different in the morning in the night, but you know, the range doesn't change.
Speaker 1: I am pretty much always hungry and And When I eat to film to do actually being full like if I eat to the point that I'm not hungry anymore That just gets me to my baseline.
Speaker 1: So I think it's just cuz I exercise a lot.
Speaker 1: I mean if you if you need motivation to be an athletic person, the only motivation you should need should be this I Rim as can be attested to by most of the people we know eat all the cookies I want all the time and I'm totally okay, and I'm not fat.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the thing is somebody is already fat.
Speaker 0: They have to go through a period of not only exercising and being hungry.
Speaker 0: I'm not eating all the cookies before they can reach the point where they have to continue the exercising But now can resume eating all the cookies.
Speaker 1: So if you're not fat if you're skinny and you like to eat cookies But you only eat a few because of self-control exercise like I do and you can eat all the cookies you want.
Speaker 0: Or Just don't eat all those cookies because even though you may not get fat Still all that sugar is probably not the best thing for you to be doing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but last time I went to the doctor They were like, wow, your blood is perfect.
Speaker 1: Like everything's great.
Speaker 1: Your cholesterol is like near the.
Speaker 0: did you eat cookies right before going to the Doctor the minute before?
Speaker 1: no because you have to fast so they can do the blood sugar thing.
Speaker 0: That's why they didn't see your cookie problem.
Speaker 0: if you would if they would have done that blood test the day before they would have pulled up and On the EKG the little line we're gonna do it and drawn a picture of a cookie and they'll be like up.
Speaker 1: They go to draw blood and cookie dough just coming out.
Speaker 0: me see problem here.
Speaker 0: See is for cancer.
Speaker 1: I watched a lot of Sesame Street and I feel like that's why I'm the way I am today.
Speaker 1: Cookie monster was my hero.
Speaker 0: My guys were all began with see count and cookie monster.
Speaker 0: Those are the guys.
Speaker 1: actually.
Speaker 1: My favorite character was Gordon.
Speaker 1: Okay, for whatever reason number two is cookie monster.
Speaker 0: three is probably wormy.
Speaker 1: three was actually Oscar the grouch because I felt like he told It like it was.
Speaker 0: I like wormy Oscar.
Speaker 1: I liked Oscar a lot.
Speaker 1: You know, I won green.
Speaker 0: Green is good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like that's a really big reason.
Speaker 1: Okay, you're asking for my kid motivations for kid desires and kid kid opinions like cookies and evil vampires.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then cute worms.
Speaker 1: All right, we talked about cookies.
Speaker 0: So I'm sure there will be much cookie discussion among other people, you know There's so many.
Speaker 0: I mean I could talk about cookies so much.
Speaker 0: I got out the rainbow cookies at the Italian bakery.
Speaker 0: You can talk about cookies from all sorts of different countries.
Speaker 0: There's one bad kind of cookie that I actually really like, you know You came or they fucking call it a biscuit and a cookie something different the black-and-white cookie like and white cookies.
Speaker 1: It's so much going on here, but the kind of cookie that's bad and I know it's bad, but I like it anyway.
Speaker 1: but it's how I try to avoid eating them are that like Store-bought kind of bakery cookie.
Speaker 1: That is just a sugar cookie, but it's covered Completely in thick multicolored hard frosting.
Speaker 0: I don't like the hard frosting no matter what it's on.
Speaker 1: Somehow for some reason I really like that kind of cookie eating.
Speaker 0: that is like eating the giant multicolored rainbow lollipop.
Speaker 0: No It's like.
Speaker 0: I feel that's not free.
Speaker 0: It doesn't seem like a thing that you eat.
Speaker 1: it seems like a prop I know but yet when I eat that cookie Part of me is saying this is wonderful and part of me is just trying to look away.
Speaker 0: No part of me even wants to eat that cookie.
Speaker 0: I can't even take one bite.
Speaker 1: You sure you're not just repressing it deep down.
Speaker 1: There's a little part of you.
Speaker 1: That's like, ah, no the heart.
Speaker 0: Now if you take a regular cookie and you put some actually creamy frosting on the regular cookie now you have a cake But then you go one step further.
Speaker 1: anyway Just take that cookie get another identical cookie put ice cream between the two cookies and now you have the full power.
Speaker 1: Yeah, ice cream sandwich is where it's at.
Speaker 0: Also that gif of Cookie Monster with the giant cookie That face that D face.
Speaker 1: alright guys either see you at PAX or we just saw you at PAX or You suck.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brand-okay for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.