Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, July 29th, 2015.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 1: We're talking about the old Vampire Hunter D OAV and Gundam The Origin, the manga.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I said OAV instead of OVA and I was going to correct myself.
Speaker 1: Like, oh right, because, you know, basically you can date an anime fan by if they say OAV or OVA.
Speaker 1: Because it used to be OAV and then...
Speaker 0: I just interchange, I don't care anymore.
Speaker 0: I don't even remember which one is more or more older.
Speaker 1: So the only reason it changed is that OAV started being used basically to refer to animated pornography.
Speaker 0: I don't, never heard of this.
Speaker 1: You really didn't know that?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: That's the main reason why they started calling them OVAs instead.
Speaker 0: I thought porn was just AV, like adult video.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but OAV was too close to AV, they sort of just combined...
Speaker 0: I never heard this story in my whole life.
Speaker 1: You really never heard that?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Never?
Speaker 1: We've even brought this up on panels before.
Speaker 0: I've never heard it.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but, Anime News Network still says OAV.
Speaker 1: So you can tell how old the people are who copy edit that stuff.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, it's summer.
Speaker 1: It's hot as balls out.
Speaker 1: Yay.
Speaker 1: Meaning it's hard for us to make content.
Speaker 0: that isn't... While I was waiting in the doctor's office on the TV, there was like a press conference with the mayor, like he has every day.
Speaker 0: And he was basically like, "It's way hot out.
Speaker 0: Check on your neighbors.
Speaker 0: Make sure they didn't die, especially if they're old or kids or sick or
Speaker 0: something.".
Speaker 1: I don't know any of my neighbors.
Speaker 0: "Drink water and stay
Speaker 0: inside.".
Speaker 1: Well, I saw even worse.
Speaker 1: So I grew up in Michigan, right?
Speaker 0: So I started thinking like, "Man, if I was mayor, I would get up there right
Speaker 0: now.".
Speaker 0: And I'd be like, "Hey, New York.
Speaker 1: It's hot.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Don't complain to me in the summer when you can't plow the street.
Speaker 0: You'd be wishing for this
Speaker 0: shit.".
Speaker 1: So even today, I walked outside of work, right?
Speaker 0: And the mayor's keeping the pools open until eight.
Speaker 0: I'd be like, "Dog, we're keeping the pools open until 8 AM, okay?
Speaker 0: Pools all night.
Speaker 0: Anyone who knows how to be a lifeguard, sign up.
Speaker 0: We'll pay you double.
Speaker 0: Work overnight.
Speaker 0: We're going to have some night pool.
Speaker 0: We're going to have some hot dog vendors rolling up.
Speaker 0: It's going to be all the most amazing.
Speaker 0: After midnight, we'll let you get drunk in the pool.
Speaker 0: If you drown, it's all on you.
Speaker 0: It's going to be good times, everybody.
Speaker 0: Night
Speaker 0: swim.".
Speaker 1: But even today, I was walking outside from my office.
Speaker 0: "If anyone's got a fire hydrant, you want us to make it into a sprinkler, just call me
Speaker 0: up?".
Speaker 1: "Well, you can do
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 0: "Fire
Speaker 0: department?".
Speaker 1: "You saw, they do that for
Speaker 1: real.".
Speaker 0: "I'm just saying, call 311.
Speaker 0: We'll hook you
Speaker 0: up.".
Speaker 1: "I'm actually very happy that they do that because when I was a kid, I had hacks mode for one thing.
Speaker 0: "You come by city hall, we got flavor ice for the
Speaker 0: kids.".
Speaker 1: "There's a fire hydrant in the easement past the sidewalk, right in front of our house, right?
Speaker 1: My dad was a fireman, so he could just open the fire
Speaker 1: hydrant.".
Speaker 0: "I mean, anyone with a wrench can open the fire
Speaker 0: hydrant.".
Speaker 1: "But he could open it, and no one would hassle us about
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 0: "I could open the one near my house, and no one will hassle me for a long
Speaker 0: time.".
Speaker 1: "They might hassle you sooner than you think, unless you have a spray cap on it of some kind.
Speaker 1: Because if you just open it, that water pressure drop is substantial and
Speaker 1: widespread.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah.".
Speaker 1: "So my dad had, and the fire department had a whole bunch of these things, but we just kept one at home.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like the ones we have in New York now, that have little holes in the top to make the arcs.
Speaker 1: It was basically a big pipe that came out and went up at an angle pretty big, and had wedges cut out of
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 0: "I'm sure if you go on eBay, you can buy all sorts of fun things to attach to the fire
Speaker 0: hydrant.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, but this one made a wall of water that blocked the street, and occasionally we would just set it up, and my dad would just call the fire department and be like, 'By the way, I'm doing
Speaker 1: this.'".
Speaker 0: "I think that's called a car
Speaker 0: wash.".
Speaker 0: "That's what that's called, you put one on each side of the
Speaker 0: street.".
Speaker 1: "So I was walking outside, though, today, and it was
Speaker 1: pleasant.".
Speaker 1: "It was basically perfect weather.
Speaker 1: But then I stepped into the shade, and I was like, 'Hey, it could be warmer, I'd be happier if it was a little
Speaker 1: warmer.'".
Speaker 0: "I mean, most of the heat comes from actually literally being in the sun, or things that are in the sun basically cooking, and then releasing heat
Speaker 0: upwards.".
Speaker 1: "Well, it only got to 92 today, so...".
Speaker 0: "Yeah, it's like, if I go in the, while I'm biking, if I go in the shade, it's like, 'Ooh, it's not hot at all in the
Speaker 0: shade.'.
Speaker 0: It's really literally only hot where the sun is, and a lot of places in New York City, you know, 'cause it's not like there's any big things casting shade, it's like, if you're under a tree, it's like, pretty much underneath a tree never gets sun, 'cause it's not gone from the side, it's not gone from the, you know, there's like, no way the sun can get in directly under the tree, so places that are shady are probably shady, like, most of the
Speaker 0: day.".
Speaker 1: "So Scott, on OAV OVA, like, I actually found the original forum discussion where I got that answer to start using in panels, but I figured, maybe that, you know, maybe that was an anecdote that was incorrect.
Speaker 1: Even the Anime News Network has a whole page dedicated to
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 0: "Okay.".
Speaker 1: "So, uh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm just, I'm surprised you don't remember
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 0: "Nope.".
Speaker 1: "We've literally, like, talked about that on panels more than
Speaker 1: once.".
Speaker 0: "Alright, so let's news.
Speaker 0: So, Otacon just happened, Gen Con is happening, but the big news from Otacon isn't necessarily anything that happened at Otacon, even though there are some exciting licenses and acquisitions and things that are going to be in
Speaker 0: English.".
Speaker 1: "There's actually going to be, like, a good round of anime in the US
Speaker 1: coming.".
Speaker 0: "Yeah, it's good stuff.
Speaker 0: But the most important thing is that Otacon's attendance went way down.
Speaker 0: Now you might think, well, that's unique to Otacon, Anime Boston's attendance went up, and that is correct, but Geneticon's attendance went
Speaker 0: down.".
Speaker 1: "And I have it on good authority that a lot of conventions lost a lot of people this
Speaker 1: year.".
Speaker 0: "That aren't gaming
Speaker 0: conventions.".
Speaker 1: "Yes, but not all conventions, which is very
Speaker 1: interesting.".
Speaker 0: "So, but, yeah, it seems like on most conventions, especially the anime types, attendance went down, but others went up.
Speaker 0: It's a strange year.
Speaker 0: And the attendance didn't go down a little bit.
Speaker 0: The attendance went down a
Speaker 0: lot.".
Speaker 0: "I think Otacon, the report I saw-" "I heard a rumored number of 25,000, which is lower than, like, the 2009 number, which is the last time we
Speaker 0: went.".
Speaker 1: "The number I heard was 6,000 fewer than-".
Speaker 0: "For a convention that only has 30-something thousand, that is a huge
Speaker 0: drop.".
Speaker 1: "Now, at the same time, remember, we're talking Otacon, one of the huge points of respect is that they count, basically, the real
Speaker 1: number.".
Speaker 0: "I use Otacon as, you know how in the comics industry they use Batman to figure out how much your comic is selling?
Speaker 0: It's like they'll tell you, 'Well, you sold 1.2 Batman's
Speaker 0: worth.'.
Speaker 0: Well, I basically use Otacon as the measurement, because they have the exact numbers for
Speaker 0: everything.".
Speaker 1: "Like, PAX is even smaller than Otacon, guys,
Speaker 1: attendance-wise.".
Speaker 0: "Depends on the PAX, but yeah, most
Speaker 0: PAXes.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, that is most
Speaker 1: PAXes.".
Speaker 0: "Anyway, but yeah, so, but I guess not now, though, because Otacon just shrank a whole
Speaker 0: bunch.".
Speaker 1: "Someone pointed out that this actually makes Otacon the third biggest anime convention now.
Speaker 1: Anime Central is bigger than
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: "Maybe.".
Speaker 1: "Maybe we should start going back to Anime
Speaker 1: Central.".
Speaker 0: "Yeah, go all the way over there, it's far
Speaker 0: away.".
Speaker 0: "I don't know, I feel-".
Speaker 0: "But it's a really easy place to fly
Speaker 0: to.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, the other thing is, I haven't been to Asa in a long time, and it was
Speaker 1: big.".
Speaker 0: "Is it really worth going?
Speaker 0: I mean, we go to Anime Boston, how's it gonna be any
Speaker 0: different?".
Speaker 1: "So, one, it was way big, like, back in 2002, 2003, when I was going.
Speaker 1: And two, I really feel bad about the fact that we write really good anime panels and do them at two cons every year, maybe three if we go to Zenkai
Speaker 1: Con.".
Speaker 0: "So you want to just take the things, you know, you do repeats, but if you go to more places-".
Speaker 1: "When I write, like, a gaming panel, I do it at two PAXes and every other con, but at the same time, we go to so many PAXes that I feel like I'm constantly writing at least one gaming panel, but yet, I have anime panels that I've literally only ever done
Speaker 1: once.".
Speaker 0: "Oh well.
Speaker 0: So anyway, B10 is way down, what are explanations for this?
Speaker 0: Well, one, it could be Otakon-specific issues, such as being in Baltimore, which is a troubled place
Speaker 0: lately.".
Speaker 1: "However, I don't think that's the
Speaker 1: cause.".
Speaker 0: "It could be overall economic woes affecting all
Speaker 0: conventions.".
Speaker 1: "I think that's the overall cause for all the
Speaker 1: drops.".
Speaker 0: "It could be that, you know, anime-specific issues, like, yeah, you know, people are still into anime, the young people, but the generation of the big generation, the Naruto Fullmetal Alchemist generation grew out of it, and the generation behind that is smaller, anime-wise, and like, this was the big year where that generation grew up, maybe?
Speaker 0: And they dropped out?
Speaker 0: Also, you know, even at conventions I go to, it's like the huge, huge things like Homestucks and whatnot, and Hetalia's, it's like, they're still there, but they're all small, there isn't currently, like, a thing that is the big
Speaker 0: thing.".
Speaker 1: "Well, at the same time, those kind of got replaced by other things, like, you saw those tweets, I've been slowly analyzing the data from
Speaker 1: KinetiCon.".
Speaker 0: "There isn't, still, there isn't one mega-fandom right now, the way there has been, sort of every year there's been at least one thing.
Speaker 0: that was the
Speaker 0: mega-fandom.".
Speaker 1: "That's kind of true, but at the same time, like, look at the numbers, like, Homestuck seemed really big, but it wasn't bigger than, like, Lodos War was at AnimeCons in the early
Speaker 1: 2000s.".
Speaker 0: "Percentage-wise, maybe, but total absolute numbers-wise, it's got to be way bigger than Lodos War in the
Speaker 0: U.S.".
Speaker 1: "Nah, at cons, hard to say,
Speaker 1: actually.".
Speaker 0: "You think Lodos War in the U.S.
Speaker 0: had more viewers than Homestuck has
Speaker 0: readers?".
Speaker 1: "I'm talking conventions only.
Speaker 1: The viewers, readers, consumers that go to
Speaker 1: conventions.".
Speaker 0: "You're saying the total number, you're saying the number of people that were, that would say they had Lodos War fans that went to a convention is equal to the number of people who went to a convention who would say they were a Homestuck
Speaker 0: fan?".
Speaker 1: "If you're comparing AnimeCons in the early 2000s to cons in the last few years, I actually think they'd be pretty
Speaker 1: close.".
Speaker 0: "The absolute number of human
Speaker 0: beings.".
Speaker 1: "I think
Speaker 1: so.".
Speaker 0: "I think the number of people who would call themselves Homestuck fans, even this year that went to conventions, is more than the total number of people that went to conventions back
Speaker 0: then.".
Speaker 1: "Homestuck panel attendance was precipitously down,
Speaker 1: however.".
Speaker 0: "That doesn't mean that the people wouldn't call themselves Homestuck
Speaker 0: fans.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, but at the same time, Lodos War was something that in the early 2000s, every goddamn anime fan had
Speaker 1: seen.".
Speaker 0: "Yes, all 200 people at the convention had seen Lodos
Speaker 0: War.".
Speaker 1: "Even back then, Otakon was pretty
Speaker 1: big.".
Speaker 0: "I'm just saying.
Speaker 1: Anyway.".
Speaker 1: "So, uh, I suspect, now, I'm privy to a little more information from other cons and things and there's some inside stuff, but one thing you guys gotta remember is that there are kind of like two fundamental classes of conventions in terms of the attendees, and this is something that hasn't ever really been talked about a lot.
Speaker 1: Most people talk about like, "Oh, well I kinda had this guest or that guest or whatever,".
Speaker 1: but some cons draw primarily people who are local to it physically, and some cons draw a big international or multi-state flying and driving in
Speaker 1: attendance.".
Speaker 0: "Well look, GenCon is happening right now.
Speaker 0: That draws people from all over, but if you go to GenCon and do a survey, right, I mean people come from other countries to go to GenCon, right?
Speaker 0: If you do a survey there, you will still find that most of the people at GenCon are from the Midwest.
Speaker 0: 'Cause even if you're the super tabletop gamer, the farther away you are, the less like you are to
Speaker 0: go.".
Speaker 1: "Oh yeah, from the Midwest, but I'm talking about-".
Speaker 0: "If you go to PAX Prime, most of the people there are from the Northwest, even though people come from Australia to go to PAX
Speaker 0: Prime.".
Speaker 1: "However, there's a pretty high- remember, they did that survey a while ago, there was a pretty high percentage of people who are not local coming in, like higher than
Speaker 0: other I'm saying is that you have cons that are like 90% local, like a Kineticon, and then you have cons that are like- even the most international cons are only like 50%
Speaker 0: local.".
Speaker 1: "No, but I'm talking more radius draw.
Speaker 1: Like there are a lot of cons that the vast majority of the attendees, it's not like 'oh they're from the Midwest' or 'they're from the state,' it's like 'they're within a 30 minute
Speaker 1: drive.'.
Speaker 1: Like they are not like further away in the state is not even coming.
Speaker 1: And those cons are highly dependent upon the local economy and really like the kinds of issues that you wouldn't think about.
Speaker 1: Like Kineticon, the results are actually public, but they had a survey that you could fill out and then you'd see some of the results.
Speaker 1: And from what I could gather, the primary thing that determined according to attendees whether or not they'd come seemed to be the ease of parking.
Speaker 1: And number two was like, could they stay in the hotel?
Speaker 1: Like programming and other things.
Speaker 1: And it's not just like Kineticon is the only one like that.
Speaker 0: People are looking at those things to decide whether to come.
Speaker 0: It's like they're going to Kineticon.
Speaker 0: If they're, you know, they're a nerd, they know Kineticon exists and they're close.
Speaker 0: It's like they want to go.
Speaker 0: They don't even look care which guest is coming.
Speaker 0: Or, you know, I mean, there are some people, there's like always one or two people every year who are like, "I'm here to see this
Speaker 0: person."
Speaker 0: And that's because they're a fan of that guest.
Speaker 0: They found out about the con and they decided to come to it.
Speaker 0: But that's very few people.
Speaker 1: But there's another factor to.
Speaker 1: the people who go to hyper local cons tend to not be as internet enabled, tend to tweet or smartphones as much.
Speaker 1: And usually because they're going to the hyper local con and that's their thing, they very rarely go to other conventions or go to conventions on a regular basis.
Speaker 1: That's the stuff I'd really like to see in a survey is for any given con, like how many other cons in a year does that person go to?
Speaker 0: Most people go to a con, that's their only con they go to.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I think the badges being more expensive, the economy in America being not great for the middle and lower middle class and the working poor combined.
Speaker 1: I think that is the primary cause of a drop in attendance in cons like Oticon.
Speaker 1: that also dropped primarily from a very local region.
Speaker 0: Well, you got to think, you know, economy wise also, right?
Speaker 0: If you are someone who doesn't have a lot of money, but you're a con goer, you're going you went and you're the con goer who's a big con goer went to many cons.
Speaker 0: You're now cutting out the lower con and go into the big con.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Then you would think, well, then shouldn't Oticon attendance go up and the other con, you know, attendance go down.
Speaker 0: But maybe at the same time, there's the other logic, which is, well, OK, you're a multi con goer.
Speaker 0: You don't have a lot of money this year.
Speaker 0: You cut out the big con and only go to the local one because it's cheaper.
Speaker 0: So there's a lot going on there.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, so many factors to figure out.
Speaker 1: There's also the fact that I think the average attendee of almost any con, except for the ones that are now hard to get into, just don't even really know much about the cons.
Speaker 1: I mean, I told this anecdote on Twitter, but I'm not lying.
Speaker 1: Person asked me straight up at a convention what a panel was.
Speaker 0: People asked us if the panels were free.
Speaker 0: And yeah, multiple people were like, we got to pay to go.
Speaker 0: I'm like, no, you paid to get in here.
Speaker 0: Everything else is free.
Speaker 0: It's like an amusement park and not like the carny.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, we'll see, like we'll wait for the full numbers and we'll wait for some more analysis and everything.
Speaker 1: But it'll be a very interesting thing that I'd like someone else to track because I'm going to forget.
Speaker 1: is for that, for that, like this year, 2015, it would be really interesting to see a list of significant fan cons that gained a lot of attendance and significant fan cons that lost a lot of it.
Speaker 0: We should take, you know, con attendance numbers, make sure they're all get the numbers that match up the same way and go year to year and then combine the cons together.
Speaker 0: And like make some sort of, you know, time lapse graph thingy.
Speaker 1: You know what I'd use?
Speaker 1: Remember that graph with the spheres to talk about first world, second world, third world stuff?
Speaker 0: You could do a lot of, you know, visualizations that would, you know, reveal an interesting information year over year con attendance.
Speaker 1: But on a side note, you know, Otacon, you know, despite the drastically lower attendance, hotels for next year went on sale.
Speaker 1: And I saw everyone on Twitter being like, oh, my God, the battle for Otacon hotel rooms.
Speaker 1: And I remember thinking back, never had to battle for Otacon hotel rooms.
Speaker 1: You only had to battle if you wanted to stay in like the tiny days in.
Speaker 0: That's everyone wants to stay in the days because it's like a hundred bucks a night because, A, it's really cheap, right?
Speaker 0: B, it's really crappy, but they don't seem to care.
Speaker 0: It's really cheap.
Speaker 0: It's really close.
Speaker 0: And if you're a cosplayer being that much closer and not having to walk two extra blocks is a big deal because it's a summer con heat outside.
Speaker 0: But I remember possibly rain.
Speaker 1: If you didn't want to be in the days in, you could wait weeks.
Speaker 0: You need a lot of money to not stay in the days.
Speaker 1: It's not that much.
Speaker 1: We stayed in the Renaissance.
Speaker 1: It wasn't that much money.
Speaker 0: It was twice as much.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: But however, if you forget, the days in was so is so we also.
Speaker 0: when we were poor, we stayed in that Renaissance with a lot of people.
Speaker 1: We did.
Speaker 1: But my point is that the days in has so few rooms available that using that as a price and saying another hotel is twice as expensive is literally worthless.
Speaker 1: because the vast majority of people who go to the con two hundred bucks a night is just what hotels cost.
Speaker 1: There's happened to be one really, really cheap hotel.
Speaker 1: It's nearby.
Speaker 0: You're getting your hundred extra dollars a night worth if you stay in a different hotel.
Speaker 0: But it was in their hotel attached to the convention center now.
Speaker 1: Well, there always was.
Speaker 1: But remember, they blocked it off that one year because they hated the Otacon people and they didn't even have a room block.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, not that one.
Speaker 0: The one the new one, the Hilton.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the one that's attack.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that they're way on the other side attached to the weird wing.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's there.
Speaker 0: Why not stay in that?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So everyone was tweeting about this this morning about how, like, oh, my God, the Otacon battle at five, at five, stay in that.
Speaker 1: But then they went on sale.
Speaker 1: So hours later, I clicked on the Otacon link and I was like, I wonder hours later in packs, you've got like 30 minutes of pretty much every hotel still had plenty of rooms.
Speaker 1: Only the days in was sold out and it was totally fine.
Speaker 1: Like I could have just booked a room.
Speaker 0: So, kids, seriously, don't whine like if you can't afford the not days in, don't go or do what we did.
Speaker 0: I mean, we see attendance is low.
Speaker 0: We're not trying to say if you're poor, you should be going.
Speaker 0: We're saying if you're poor, don't go.
Speaker 0: Like all the people who are poor didn't.
Speaker 1: We always went where we were poor.
Speaker 1: We just crammed.
Speaker 1: We get two rooms.
Speaker 0: Only if you're a college student, if you're not a college student anymore, it's not acceptable.
Speaker 1: We get two rooms adjoining in the Renaissance every year.
Speaker 1: So we'd have two bathrooms.
Speaker 0: You're an adult and you can't afford to go.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't be going now if I was if I was as poor as I was in college, because I save up, you can just go to PAX every other year or something like that instead of going to Otacon.
Speaker 1: What if you hate?
Speaker 1: what if you hate games in your primary interest in the world's anime?
Speaker 0: Why are you listening?
Speaker 1: Well, for the Wednesday night, of course, you're an awful person.
Speaker 0: I'd say the same thing about someone who would say they're only interested in games and they don't like animes.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but yeah, we we put seven people in one room, six people in the room next door, and that was the literal maximum loading capacity without disaster.
Speaker 0: Do you have a news or are you just going to talk about?
Speaker 0: that's the end?
Speaker 1: So Rick and Morty came back season two and I watched the first episode because it just came out.
Speaker 0: You're watching all these great shows because they're basically it's.
Speaker 1: there's been a huge renaissance for years now in a lot of really good American cartoons.
Speaker 1: So Rick and Morty, Scott would hate it, but he hates everything is like.
Speaker 1: season one was atypical and I didn't expect like I'd seen the first the pilot fighting this show.
Speaker 0: Huh?
Speaker 0: Are you fighting the show or is there a news?
Speaker 1: Sort of.
Speaker 1: Well, the news is it came back season two.
Speaker 1: OK, and the first episode just happened and you can just watch it for free on their website, like like.
Speaker 1: you don't have to like pirate it or anything.
Speaker 1: It's just there or get cable.
Speaker 1: No, you just watch it totally for free online.
Speaker 1: It's a full 24 minute episode of a show.
Speaker 1: But when I watched the pilot, I didn't expect I'd like it.
Speaker 1: I thought it was going to be basically like when South Park first came out, like, OK, this is just swearing.
Speaker 1: I don't think I need to watch the show, but it got really clever, really good.
Speaker 1: And actually, it's one of my like recent favorite comedy cartoons or just comedy shows in general.
Speaker 1: So my worry was many shows that are that good cannot sustain.
Speaker 1: And Rick and Morty had the benefit of having a very small number of very high quality episodes.
Speaker 1: And a new season just came out, just began.
Speaker 1: And episode one not only was great, it actually had a long.
Speaker 0: when you get an episode one of a new season, you had a long time to work on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it did something that I never didn't really expect you could do correctly in a television show.
Speaker 1: Basically, the plot of this episode involves multiple realities sort of splitting.
Speaker 1: So like the two possibilities happen.
Speaker 1: So the screen splits.
Speaker 0: I've never seen that before.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: So the screen splits and you see both happening at the same time.
Speaker 1: And then it splits again and it kind of splits and unsplits and things happen, but you get a full audio and video from both parallel universes or quadruple or whatever, all at the same time on screen.
Speaker 1: And somehow they totally pull it off.
Speaker 1: And it was actually kind of amazing.
Speaker 1: It was a fantastic episode of a show.
Speaker 1: No, it didn't.
Speaker 1: That's actually something the Simpsons literally never did.
Speaker 1: I just said, I know you did, but it's the one thing the Simpsons didn't do.
Speaker 1: I think there have been alternate reality episodes not showing you both at the same time in real time.
Speaker 0: Not that I've seen.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: And frankly, the show is as funny as always was.
Speaker 1: If you haven't watched Rick and Morty, watch any episode, but the pilot, because the pilot, it's like watching like if you want to sell someone on South Park, don't show.
Speaker 1: South Park is actually like that.
Speaker 1: Stick him in like season two or three.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing here.
Speaker 1: Just watch an episode of Rick and Morty.
Speaker 1: I really like that show and I think it actually might be my favorite comedy cartoon currently, as in something that's aired on TV any time in the last four or five years.
Speaker 1: So anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: Our good friend Judith has a blog stuff and fluff, cutest cooking.
Speaker 1: It's literally the cutest cooking.
Speaker 1: It's a cooking blog with recipes and stuffed animals and things.
Speaker 1: And I think we've mentioned it obliquely a few times, but I really want to make it a thing of the day because she just like started it back up after hiatus.
Speaker 0: Are you sure I didn't already make it a thing of the day?
Speaker 1: I don't know if you did in history, but the dish that is posted was pretty great.
Speaker 1: And when I saw this post, I remembered eating this dish because it was cooked in our apartment.
Speaker 1: And the background that you can't see in these pictures was our apartment.
Speaker 1: Seriously, this blog is good stuff.
Speaker 1: And if you're into cooking or cute stuff, I highly recommend it.
Speaker 0: So in New York, the subway is mad old, like 100 years old, and the equipment in the subway is mad old.
Speaker 0: And, you know, people talk about upgrading it and whatnot, but they don't really understand just how old.
Speaker 0: Well, the MTA made a video because basically they're trying to get money for their budget right now is a lot of issues.
Speaker 0: So in part of their trying to get money, they made this video showing just how old and busted they are because it's like, hey, the party is less old and busted than we are.
Speaker 0: And you're building a new one there.
Speaker 0: The trains are even older and busted.
Speaker 0: Or why don't you give the money to the trains instead, governor asshole?
Speaker 0: So here's a video.
Speaker 0: And even though this video is trying to do that, you know, in reality, this video doesn't even mention budgets or money or anything.
Speaker 0: It just sort of demonstrates, you know, the old technology showing you how old it is and the fact that we're still using it is amazing.
Speaker 0: And it also shows the new technology that is used only in like a few lines because it's all we can afford.
Speaker 0: CBTC.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it shows you how that works and how it's awesome or at least way more awesome than the old way of doing things.
Speaker 1: You know what, though?
Speaker 1: It's a concern of New York City.
Speaker 0: And almost no other cities in America, but it's still awesome to see old train switching stuff.
Speaker 1: It's awesome to see that technology that looks antiquated, even for a steampunk cosplay, is literally used day to day to make my commute happen.
Speaker 0: And it didn't work today because the end QR was having extensive delays due to signal malfunction.
Speaker 1: Oh, if only you took the seven.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 0: I walked over to the seven.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I take the seven every day.
Speaker 1: It's just great.
Speaker 0: I usually bike enough to worry about either one.
Speaker 0: And you know, I went to the doctor today.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: Thank you.
Speaker 0: Works almost every day.
Speaker 0: The one day it messes up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've got to know what.
Speaker 1: if I wait for seven from Greensboro Plaza rather than getting on an N or Q that has already arrived, I will reliably get to work fast.
Speaker 0: You're going way downtown.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got a job right near an NQ station and then move to an apartment right near an NQ station so wisely.
Speaker 1: And as a result, straight to work, actually, all I really need is once the T starts running, then the four or five will get slightly less crowded.
Speaker 0: I think there'll be an issue when the seven goes beyond Times Square, because then usually you go to Times Square to get in a seven and it's just sitting there waiting for you.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Or when it gets there, it empties out completely.
Speaker 1: Now you'll be waiting for those trains, getting people from the west side, except they're going to run on the same schedule and theoretically they can run and more trains because there's more track space and more stop.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll see.
Speaker 0: Also a long distance between once they finish the CVTC, because that's the line that's getting it.
Speaker 0: It should be more trains.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: In the moment, the book club book is still the wheel of time.
Speaker 0: It just keeps on turning its fantasy novel words in a book.
Speaker 1: I I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm increasingly frustrated with every child character for literally you've got a bunch of adults who are obviously trying to help you and you do nothing but but make each other promise to never tell an adult about any of the stupid bullshit you just did.
Speaker 1: Like, oh, oh, yeah, I just stole this dagger from this like evil demon guy.
Speaker 1: No biggie.
Speaker 1: Don't tell the adults.
Speaker 1: Oh, I just had this dream where something pricked me and an evil dude and a god and all this danger.
Speaker 1: And then I woke up and I actually had the.
Speaker 0: let's not tell the people who've saved my life multiple times.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Let's not trust any of these people, even though they saved our lives multiple times.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And let's also not trust each other.
Speaker 1: And like, I, I really don't like these kids.
Speaker 1: And now all of them have a plot thing.
Speaker 1: So I can't be like, well, at least I know two of them are going to die and only one of them matters.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I thought two of them were just hangers on.
Speaker 0: But no, then he made him real characters, which would be fine if they weren't just dumb shits.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I guess Perrin was that guy with the wolf guy.
Speaker 1: The wolf guy is probably the best one because he's he looks dumb but is actually super smart.
Speaker 0: I think main guy is the best one.
Speaker 0: His main guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but he also kind of hides stuff from people.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The other kid is the dumbest.
Speaker 0: He's the dumbest.
Speaker 0: He's the worst.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, if he would just die or something, you should come see us at PAX Prime.
Speaker 0: It's real soon.
Speaker 0: We're going to be our best convention on for nerds on the face of the earth.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You can still.
Speaker 1: I just checked.
Speaker 1: You can still at night tonight get hotels for Otacon.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, Pax Prime, you if you go and try to get a room at a hotel pretty much anywhere in near the convention center in Seattle, you can't even pay full price like there just aren't rooms.
Speaker 0: Well, I have because we are doing panels there.
Speaker 0: I have the emergency badge that I bought, which is actually four single day passes.
Speaker 0: Friday, Saturday, Sunday, Monday are available for sale.
Speaker 0: You could if you are someone who listening to this right now, that means you are someone who I will give preferential treatment and sell them to you at exactly face value.
Speaker 0: I'll even pay for the stamp to mail them to you or give them to you in person at the PAX.
Speaker 1: Oh, see my two emergency badges.
Speaker 1: I can't actually mailed anyone because there will call only.
Speaker 0: But yeah.
Speaker 0: If if I had to sell them on the Internet, I'm like eBay or something, I'm going to be marking them up and getting some profits.
Speaker 0: So, you know, if you want to go if you've got a place to stay or maybe you got an extra friend who's coming or, you know, someone who lives in the area, they don't need a place to stay because they live there, you know.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm giving one of my badges to our good friend Tracy because he totally helped me unfuck that one episode of gig nights that got fucked up.
Speaker 0: That is where that is a. if you do something for me, that is such so great in value as to equal that.
Speaker 0: Yes, I will also give you the except he only wanted the Sunday one.
Speaker 1: I was like, I'll give you all four.
Speaker 1: And he's like, that's the thing.
Speaker 0: It's like someone was like, I'll just take two from you.
Speaker 0: And it's like that's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: It's much easier for me to get rid of all four at once.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Facts.
Speaker 1: Facts is coming.
Speaker 1: Far future of gaming on Sunday, sports or games on Monday.
Speaker 1: And then I'm doing online story driven games on Wednesday in Portland.
Speaker 0: And after PAX, not before.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And as otherwise, Emily and I and a bunch of us will be at PAX dev just hanging out and we'll be playing tabletop games almost exclusively.
Speaker 1: Oh, wizard.
Speaker 1: I'm going to bring.
Speaker 1: I'm going to bring my poker chips, even though other people are bringing poker chips.
Speaker 1: Because we got to play wizard.
Speaker 0: I'm going to make a lot of videos of things, including like playing wizard and such.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm going to bring extra tripods and things, do some content creation at my Porto tripod.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I also have a Porto tripod.
Speaker 0: That's enough matter.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: Check us on the Internet.
Speaker 0: We're on all the places on the Internet.
Speaker 0: Come find us.
Speaker 0: So Vampire Hunter D, the original O.A.V I watch a sci fi channel or something.
Speaker 0: Noran, I think I might have watched also an anime club VHS subtitle, but that was like 15 years ago.
Speaker 0: So I don't remember very much at all.
Speaker 1: I have probably seen the original Vampire Hunter D O.A.V.
Speaker 1: from 1985, a hundred times.
Speaker 0: That's a lot of fucking time.
Speaker 1: However, ninety nine of those times I last millennium when my age was under 14.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 1: I mean, I first saw them on the side of it on the sci fi channel because my mom made me watch this movie and I actually wasn't super into it.
Speaker 1: But she kind of was like, oh, you got to watch it.
Speaker 1: It's like the Castlevania thing you like.
Speaker 1: And it was a transformative experience because I in fourth grade went from not knowing what anime was to trying to get fan subs.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So the first thing to know about Vampire Hunter D is the artwork is Yoshitaka Amano, who is the awesome.
Speaker 0: And he was mad young then, I assume.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because he's not super old now.
Speaker 0: He's just old.
Speaker 1: And it actually stays pretty true to his style.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I mean, this is the same dude who did the characters.
Speaker 0: So Final Fantasy six and other awesome things.
Speaker 0: This is like a big time important art person.
Speaker 0: You can tell his style because it's always swooshy and swirly and woofy.
Speaker 1: I was going to say long angular things around.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean, that also describes other people, right?
Speaker 0: He's his big thing is like the swirliness and like the mistiness.
Speaker 1: Look at those long point on the D hat and the long horn things coming out of his outfit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, triangles.
Speaker 1: So I watched this movie again once as an older person in like college ish.
Speaker 1: RIT ish time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably year 2000, I think.
Speaker 1: And it's interesting because, well, so the plot is D is fucking invincible.
Speaker 1: He's the son of Dracula.
Speaker 1: Yeah, spoilers.
Speaker 1: He's not a vampire.
Speaker 1: He's a dumpier or as a kid, as I thought from a vampire.
Speaker 0: Thing like vampire powers, but he's not a vampire.
Speaker 1: So when I was a kid, all I had to go on was the dub, which wasn't that bad as far as I can remember.
Speaker 1: But it sounded like they're saying Vampil.
Speaker 0: So I thought I think there are different dates on which dub or sub you get.
Speaker 0: I think it will say something different.
Speaker 1: He is a dumpier, but it sounded like Vampil.
Speaker 1: So for most of my childhood, I thought that vampire and Vampil were two different things.
Speaker 1: And I just used the word Vampil like, oh, yeah, you didn't know about Vampil's.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: I thought it was just a stupid thing where they were like, he's just actually a vampire.
Speaker 0: But it's like, I'll just change the word slightly and no one will know.
Speaker 0: I'm not Alucard.
Speaker 0: I'm Alucardo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll just change the word Dracula slightly.
Speaker 0: So you won't know.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like, you know, Clark Kent with the glasses.
Speaker 0: I thought that's what it was.
Speaker 0: I'm my first watching.
Speaker 1: So, you know, kind of review this movie.
Speaker 0: Then I remembered, oh, Japan made this.
Speaker 1: When I was a kid, a little kid and I watched this movie.
Speaker 1: All I remember really is that Dee was the coolest person I'd ever seen in a movie ever.
Speaker 1: The whole thing was awesome.
Speaker 1: The movie felt like it was three, four, five hours long.
Speaker 1: Like it felt like it just went on forever.
Speaker 1: I loved every second of it.
Speaker 1: I dressed up as Dee, kind of wanted to be Dee as a little kid.
Speaker 1: And I pretty much spent most of my childhood showing this to my friends who would then have.
Speaker 1: their parents would then call my parents, concernedly asking about this like violent cartoon that I had.
Speaker 1: Whenever it was my grandparents house, I would always be like, let's watch Vampire Hunter D. And my grandparents really did not like this movie.
Speaker 0: But watching it a little older, I watched Dumbo with my grandparents house.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 1: I also watched Dumbo.
Speaker 0: I pretty much watched Dumbo every time.
Speaker 1: But Dumbo and Vampire Hunter D as a kid were just interchangeable.
Speaker 1: And my brother was two and a half years younger than me.
Speaker 1: So he was in second grade.
Speaker 1: He loved it just as much.
Speaker 1: And we both turned out totally OK.
Speaker 0: But I would not agree with that.
Speaker 1: How did how did Vampire Hunter D mess me up?
Speaker 0: I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying that you're messed up.
Speaker 1: How so?
Speaker 1: How am I messed up?
Speaker 0: You are messed up in so many ways.
Speaker 0: You are the most messed up.
Speaker 1: I am the most messed up.
Speaker 1: I think we can name more messed up people.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah, you're not that guy, but you're messed up.
Speaker 0: How so?
Speaker 0: I was really messed up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let me count the ways.
Speaker 0: Let me count the ways.
Speaker 0: If Rym finds a noise that annoys you, he will make that noise repeatedly until you are so annoyed because he is not a good person.
Speaker 0: That is one way in which you are messed up.
Speaker 1: Two, that's just my superpower.
Speaker 0: You will live dangerously and risk death for stupid reasons.
Speaker 1: I love how you think it's dangerously to like bike 20 miles an hour in a separate separated bikeway to go skiing at all.
Speaker 1: Skiing is not that dangerous.
Speaker 0: Dangerous.
Speaker 1: Actually, it's not.
Speaker 1: Yes, no, it really isn't.
Speaker 0: Also lying a lot just about things.
Speaker 1: About what?
Speaker 1: What have I ever lied about?
Speaker 0: So many things.
Speaker 1: Like name one thing I've ever lied about.
Speaker 0: So much lying.
Speaker 1: OK, there's one thing that I didn't lie about, but Scott lied on my behalf.
Speaker 0: I never lied about anything ever.
Speaker 1: You were convinced and even argued with me that I had seen the second Matrix movie in the theater with you.
Speaker 1: When I, in fact, not only had not, but have to this day never seen that movie.
Speaker 0: Well, that is a good thing for you.
Speaker 0: Maybe that is if you.
Speaker 0: maybe if you watch it, though, it would cancel out your messed up and un-mess you up.
Speaker 0: But anyway, is that movie will mess you the fuck up as a kid?
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: I think that it's interesting from a kid perspective.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, watching Dragon Ball, like there's certain kinds of shows where you watch it and you're engaged in what seems like an epic struggle.
Speaker 1: But as an adult in college, when I watched it again, I realized something very profound about this movie that literally escaped my notice as a child, despite watching it like a hundred times.
Speaker 1: There is no struggle or conflict at all in this movie.
Speaker 0: The movie is.
Speaker 0: my vague memory is that this D he's awesome.
Speaker 0: His hand talks to him, which is the best part.
Speaker 1: The dub voice for his hand was actually pretty.
Speaker 0: I mean, just the fact that his hand talks to him is the best part.
Speaker 1: And his hand is kind of a dick.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Yes, the hand is the best character.
Speaker 0: The hand has more lines than anyone else, too.
Speaker 1: As a kid, I was obsessed with what the deal was with the hand.
Speaker 1: And of course, the movie doesn't tell you.
Speaker 0: He meets this girl somehow and he stays in her house.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: I don't know if he's guarding her.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't remember.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 0: And then Dracula lives in a castle nearby and he just lives in the girl's house for a while.
Speaker 0: I think there's a few lines.
Speaker 0: It's not actually Dracula.
Speaker 1: It's Count Magnus D. That's not Dracula.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: And you could say it's a Dracula.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: This is why I'm going by my memory, not the truth.
Speaker 0: And then it's just like a lot of time passes.
Speaker 0: And then he goes and kills Dracula.
Speaker 0: The end.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So she basically Count Magnus Lee wants this girl to be his next wife, because that's just what he does.
Speaker 1: And the vampires kind of just live in this horrible vampire world.
Speaker 1: And there's also like werewolf hunters.
Speaker 1: He just happens to be a vampire hunter and he has a robot horse.
Speaker 1: And it's like a nuclear.
Speaker 1: The robot horse.
Speaker 0: Not as cool as the talking hand, but still cool.
Speaker 1: The thing that resonated both as a kid and an adult for Vampire Hunter D is that it's one of those movies that does the thing very well.
Speaker 0: Not as good as Rau's horse.
Speaker 1: Like Cowboy Bebop also does.
Speaker 1: Similar style horse, though, in a lot of ways.
Speaker 0: It would definitely lose in a fight.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, of course it would.
Speaker 1: It's from Asher.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's just no.
Speaker 1: So is that it has this crazy setting with a whole bunch of stuff going on.
Speaker 1: And it that.
Speaker 1: but that stuff is not the plot.
Speaker 1: See, also Cowboy Bebop.
Speaker 1: That is one of the signs of a good where you have a good world and you have a story in that world.
Speaker 1: But the story doesn't have to be about that world resolving the world stuff.
Speaker 1: Just have it in the background, have it there.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so all this happens.
Speaker 1: She hires Vampire Hunter D to be your bodyguard because Count Magnus Lee is going to come back.
Speaker 1: He better and take her away and make her a vampire wife.
Speaker 1: Uh, D then just walks from challenge to challenge, trivially dispatching them, because literally he is just more powerful than everyone.
Speaker 1: The big plot at the end and to spoil it for you is that he just walks into Magnus Lee's castle to fuck him up.
Speaker 1: And Magnus Lee is like, oh, I have a thing that will stop you.
Speaker 1: And then he's just like, actually, no, I'm too powerful.
Speaker 1: That and just kills him.
Speaker 1: The end.
Speaker 1: Uh, like literally every fight is just D being like, I'm actually just more powerful than you and just killing whatever it is he's fighting.
Speaker 1: It's interesting to me that I did not notice that as a kid and only noticed it as an adult.
Speaker 1: I still think it's worth watching.
Speaker 0: When I was a kid, I thought He-Man was the best.
Speaker 1: So I just noticed Vampire Hunter D on Anime News Network under the category objectionable content.
Speaker 1: It has one word.
Speaker 1: Intense.
Speaker 1: This is a movie where D cuts people in half and the intricate details of the viscera spilling forth are drawn to a degree that is surprising.
Speaker 0: There's also a sexy shower scene.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which I didn't see as a kid because they cut that out of the sci-fi channel airing.
Speaker 1: So I didn't see it until I was much older, as in I was like 12 instead of nine.
Speaker 1: And I remember when they cut the shower scene out, it basically just went from D's, like she goes in to take a shower, D's sitting there being very uncomfortable and suddenly it's the next day and there's all this drama between the two of them
Speaker 0: and
Speaker 1: never really understood that.
Speaker 1: And then when I saw the shower scene, I was like, oh, OK, that makes sense now.
Speaker 1: I think this movie is actually pretty good from an anime movie perspective.
Speaker 0: I mean, you can watch it just to see the talking hand and the Yoshitaka Amano artwork.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like it's a set piece, it's 80 minutes long.
Speaker 0: And it's important anime history-wise, so if you care about anime, it's important to see it.
Speaker 1: Because remember, this was...
Speaker 0: It's not like a Satoshi Kon or an Akira level or a Miyazaki level or anything like that.
Speaker 1: It's unique because it's pretty different from most of the anime that a lot of people see.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot of other anime that's really like it.
Speaker 1: And a lot of the other anime in this sort of like OAV era is just garbage.
Speaker 1: This one actually has enough going on, despite a utterly ridiculously simplistic plot, that it's kind of worth watching.
Speaker 1: And it's also worth noting that it was the second anime to be shown in the sci-fi channel-like anime thing.
Speaker 1: that was literally the sole reason an entire generation of anime fans appeared in America.
Speaker 0: I think a generation of anime fans appeared in America also because of the syndication of Battleship Yamato, which was known as Star Blazers, and also Robotech.
Speaker 1: I did not say there were not other generations of anime fans.
Speaker 0: And also Toonami.
Speaker 1: But the thing that they showed right before this was Robot Carnival.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: I only caught the end of it because I tuned in to watch Vampire Hunter D.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so Gundam The Origin.
Speaker 0: I think I've talked about this in the show before.
Speaker 0: Maybe I even geek-bited it like in the opening part, but I've never made it the main bit.
Speaker 0: And Rym hasn't read it yet, but it's so good, it cannot be delayed any longer.
Speaker 0: It must be discussed, even if we're repeating it.
Speaker 1: I think, do I just need to borrow the earlier issues of it and just read it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's like, it cannot be delayed.
Speaker 0: Even if I'm repeating everything I've said before, which I feel like I might be, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It is worth it.
Speaker 0: So Gundam The Origin.
Speaker 0: What is Gundam The Origin?
Speaker 0: It is a manga that has been done more recently than the original Gundam.
Speaker 0: However, it is telling the story of the original Gundam.
Speaker 0: The original Gundam story that is in the novel and the original anime series.
Speaker 0: First Gundam, right?
Speaker 0: Gundam 78, Universal Century with Amuro and Char and Bright Noah and all the original Gundam story in manga form.
Speaker 0: Now, usually when something is redone in another medium later on, it's not as good as the original, right?
Speaker 0: You're not going to want to read like, you know, the Star Wars manga, the Star Wars manga.
Speaker 0: The Star Wars manga is a special thing.
Speaker 0: When I talk about like a straight redoing, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, as good as Lord of the Rings movie is, it's not Lord of the Rings book, right?
Speaker 0: As good as, you know, I mean, there's Star Wars novels that are literally just retellings of original Star Wars movie.
Speaker 1: I read the episode four novel, right?
Speaker 0: Not the same as episode four itself, right?
Speaker 0: It's not quite there.
Speaker 0: So usually it's like, you know, usually it's an anime adaptation of a manga.
Speaker 0: It's like you just go for the manga.
Speaker 0: You don't need to watch the anime adaptation of the manga, right?
Speaker 0: You can skip that.
Speaker 0: So you think, oh, it's a manga adaptation of this old, classic, amazing anime.
Speaker 0: that's super important, Gundam.
Speaker 0: Why would anyone give a shit?
Speaker 0: Well, is a rare case where the manga redo of a thing is the best possible version of the thing.
Speaker 0: It is the.
Speaker 0: if you want to know the story of the original Gundam, the first Gundam, this is the best version of that story in any medium, better than novel, better than the movie compilation movies, better than the anime series.
Speaker 1: Even with not having any music?
Speaker 0: Better than all those.
Speaker 0: It is the best telling of that story in any medium that has ever existed, right?
Speaker 0: So, first of all, the art is the greatest art that has ever existed for Gundam.
Speaker 1: Wow, you had you really you brought that back around because I was about to be like Akira.
Speaker 0: It is the best Gundam art, right?
Speaker 1: That is best at Gundam.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: The artist, right, is like always keep forgetting his name.
Speaker 0: It's Yasuhiko something, I think.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yoshikazu Yasuhiko.
Speaker 0: People I always just see, you know, Yasuhiko, whatever, right?
Speaker 0: This guy, this art is just like incredible.
Speaker 0: Somehow he's managed to keep the original designs of the characters and things, but also things are changed in ways like only a nerd would notice, like everything is still recognizable.
Speaker 0: Like if you look at, say, a Zaku, you look at it and say it's undeniably Zaku, you know, it's it's so iconic.
Speaker 0: But then if you actually line it up next to one from like the old anime series, it's like, wow, look at look at.
Speaker 0: The changes that were made here, but somehow for the better without losing any of, you know, the original design.
Speaker 0: that makes it what it is, you know, it's.
Speaker 0: it's to the point where it's like I bought.
Speaker 0: you can buy a Gundam model.
Speaker 0: It's a special Gundam, the origin model, as opposed to a original Gundam model.
Speaker 0: And you put them next to each other and it's like, oh, there are differences here.
Speaker 0: But if you looked at anyone on its own, only a nerd would be able to tell you which one was which.
Speaker 1: I think we saw a bunch of those nerds at that awesome Gundam panel at Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Probably those people would have recognized.
Speaker 0: The other thing is that not only does it tell the original Gundam story, but it makes some very small changes.
Speaker 0: But those changes are most are almost universally for the better.
Speaker 1: Universally century?
Speaker 0: No, they're just universally like good, positive, you know, small changes to like facts and they close some plot holes or, you know, provide clarity to things that used to be sort of vague and not 100 percent, you know, totally clear what happened.
Speaker 0: or, you know, really spend some more time on a character, you know, because it's a manga and they can do that.
Speaker 0: And they don't.
Speaker 0: they're not limited to the 30 minutes of air time you get in an anime or 20 something minutes.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know, you don't have this sort of like, oh, the character is there for two seconds.
Speaker 0: It's like, no, it's like full, you know, everything.
Speaker 0: Everything is as much time as it needs without getting too much time.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of color pages, which is kind of amazing.
Speaker 0: The color pages are like with the watercolor, the way it's amazing.
Speaker 1: I flipped through this thing like I haven't read it yet.
Speaker 1: I should.
Speaker 1: I'm going to.
Speaker 1: I'm going to take Scott's and read it.
Speaker 1: But I was flipping through it and Scott's not exaggerating.
Speaker 1: Like it is beautiful to behold.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like, is this an art book or is this a manga?
Speaker 0: It's like, whoa, what's going on here?
Speaker 0: And it doesn't skip over anything, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's a lot of volumes of this.
Speaker 0: It just keeps going and doesn't, you know, leave anything untouched.
Speaker 0: It is it is like a complete set, you know, as you're not missing anything.
Speaker 0: The way a compilation movie will sort of gloss over the less important things, you know, and focus only on the important part of the story is just like, no, the full story.
Speaker 1: I've heard other people, not just me, analogize it to that evangelical manga in the sense that I haven't read evangelical manga.
Speaker 0: So I don't know.
Speaker 1: I read the first chunk of it.
Speaker 1: And I would describe it a lot of the ways you've described this, that it takes Ava, the anime, and it just kind of moves at a slower narrative pace so that it doesn't gloss over anything.
Speaker 0: It doesn't feel like Gun of the Origin moves slow.
Speaker 0: It feels like it moves exactly right.
Speaker 1: Like cover all the bases and keep, you know, I guess like it doesn't skip things that were skipped in the anime and would definitely be skipped in the compilation.
Speaker 1: And it also like it fills in a lot of details.
Speaker 1: Like you see a little more like why was Kaji doing what he was doing and what was this person up to at this time?
Speaker 1: So it makes sense later when some other things happen.
Speaker 0: The other thing that it does is, you know, it adds in without changing anything, stories that were just not told in the original.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like you learn there's like this whole chapters of like history of Char and from way back.
Speaker 0: And it like it's sort of like the true story of what happened there.
Speaker 0: But that was never really included in a lot of the previous tellings of the story.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know, the most important characters, their back story is getting revealed and fully fleshed out, whereas before it was sort of known or not given screen time at all or, you know, skipped over or who knows what.
Speaker 0: But now you're getting the full story in regards to those sorts of things that wasn't there before.
Speaker 0: So that's real important because if you watch like original Gundam anime, you're not going to know that at all because it wasn't touched on.
Speaker 0: But here it's completely explained in full detail, 100 percent.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, this is if you even if you are a person who's like, oh, like robots and whatever.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, because it's a manga, you don't really have that robot fight sort of action scene where it's like, you know, they're just.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's still there where the people are talking while they're fighting and robots, but it's not like.
Speaker 0: there's pages and pages of just robots shooting each other and nothing going on.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like when there's a battle, it's like the battle really just serves as illustrations.
Speaker 0: And, you know, this the speech bubbles and text, the dialog that people are saying is on top of it.
Speaker 0: So you're not getting this sort of same thing happens in the anime where it's like talk, boom, fight slash talk.
Speaker 0: It's it's simultaneous.
Speaker 0: So even if you're like, oh, robot battles are boring.
Speaker 0: It's like, well, here you're just looking at illustrations while the plot continues.
Speaker 1: It's almost like the human drama and the horror of war is the story of Gundam and not the robots themselves.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: But I mean, there are a lot of people who are like anti robot, you know, it's like, well, now you can get the story of Gundam with basically skipping over robot, but not if you care about robot, though, you're not missing out at all because they're still fully illustrated robot
Speaker 1: battles
Speaker 0: and details about robots.
Speaker 0: And they talk about like, oh, improving the thing with this fire in the low and greens or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All that.
Speaker 0: Well, there's no long.
Speaker 1: I know that's in Gundam.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but, you know, all the military fanboy stuff is there, too.
Speaker 0: But it's like it'll be like, you know, the captain will give some orders and then that's it.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not like they dwell on anything for too long.
Speaker 0: You know, everything is just so perfectly given the right amount of panels and time and everything.
Speaker 0: It's just so good.
Speaker 0: It's like you don't really need any other Gundam if you read this manga.
Speaker 0: And the translation is I can't.
Speaker 0: I can't compare it to the Japanese, obviously.
Speaker 0: But as far as I can tell, it's like I have no desire to you know, it doesn't feel like anything was like confusing or mistranslated or worded.
Speaker 0: Strangely, it's like it feels like it was written in native English, as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: There's like, you know, it's not like this, you know, especially in a sci fi story like this takes place in a future in space.
Speaker 0: You know, you don't get sort of the Japanese culture entering into it in the way you would in something like, I don't know, what's a very Japanese, even Yamato to a degree.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: But I mean, like a school anime.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Where the facts of Japanese school life enter into it.
Speaker 0: You know, that doesn't even come into play.
Speaker 1: I sure do like donuts.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Little triangle shaped donuts.
Speaker 0: So if you're an anime person at all, which you probably are, if you're listening to this and you don't know Gundam, well, it's important to know this is the way to find out is to read this manga.
Speaker 0: And if you are a Gundam fan or robot fan of any kind, mecha fan and you haven't read this, what the hell?
Speaker 1: And seriously, even if you don't like like the like Scott said, the anti robot bias is real.
Speaker 1: I mean, as Gaflone is a giant robot anime.
Speaker 0: Also, if you're just a person who likes comics, this is like.
Speaker 0: so almost this is like the second tier of comic greatness of all time.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like you got the Tezuka and the eyes of the world and then you got this like right underneath.
Speaker 0: Like I didn't think like something, you know, Gundam, like I always had Gundam is like, you know, it's always solid.
Speaker 0: It's always there for you.
Speaker 0: I like it.
Speaker 0: I'm not, you know, ridiculous fan of it, but I really like it a lot.
Speaker 0: But I never thought of it as like the top tier, you know, just super important historically and whatnot.
Speaker 0: But this this is like somehow, you know, this franchise that is so much properties built around it is somehow one thing in that franchise is at the top tiers.
Speaker 0: You can't miss that.
Speaker 1: It's right up there with my Rattata.
Speaker 0: Rattata is the finest Rattata.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So I guess the moral is read Gundam The Origin and watch Vampire Hunter D.
Speaker 0: I think you should read Gundam The Origin and maybe watch Vampire Hunter D.
Speaker 1: If you've never seen Vampire Hunter D, I would watch it.
Speaker 1: It's not that long.
Speaker 0: If you're sitting at home and you got a Vampire Hunter D DVD next to a Gundam The Origin volume, you should be reading that manga first.
Speaker 1: Well, just do both.
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 0: I've got time for that.
Speaker 1: You've got an hour to listen to a podcast.
Speaker 0: You're probably biking to work or driving to work while listening to this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would not be biking to work and listening to a podcast.
Speaker 1: I don't do that.
Speaker 1: That's that'll kill you.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, no, I can't.
Speaker 1: I can't.
Speaker 1: I'll tell the anecdote after we stop the show.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.