Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, September 9th, 2015.
Speaker 1: I'm Rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is The Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: We're back from PAX and we're talking about One Punch Man.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we missed a lot of shows and we're gonna miss a bunch more because I'm gonna be in Singapore and Australia for like the next three weeks.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know, there was a PAX was a week early this year.
Speaker 0: And then there's Labor Day because PAX wasn't on Labor Day as usual.
Speaker 1: And we celebrate Labor Day by not laboring, so we didn't do any Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: No, why would I do that?
Speaker 0: when I could lay in the park and dick around, right?
Speaker 1: I ran in a race, though, and among the old men category, I was the second fastest old man.
Speaker 0: Second fastest old man?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Who was the faster old man than you?
Speaker 1: The faster old man beat me by like two minutes, so there was no chance.
Speaker 1: Who is this old man?
Speaker 1: So, the funny thing is, because they break it down by basically 10-year age groups once you get into your 20s, and what gives me hope is that the top three times for these 5K and 10K races for old men, not that much worse than the times for younger men.
Speaker 0: So, I feel like- But yours was two minutes.
Speaker 0: How many younger men beat you?
Speaker 1: I was sixth overall among everyone, even like- How many people were in this thing?
Speaker 0: Seven?
Speaker 1: Like 380.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, the only people who beat me were 20-somethings and 130-something who have hot bods and actually train.
Speaker 1: Emily did really well, too.
Speaker 1: We're both pretty fast.
Speaker 0: Did you get some sort of medal?
Speaker 1: So, yes.
Speaker 1: I got a trophy.
Speaker 1: It's made out of Lucite, and it's in the other room.
Speaker 1: I also have this trophy from last time.
Speaker 1: So, I don't run races that often, like maybe once a year, and I kind of wanted to win this one, at least among the old man 30s age group.
Speaker 1: So, I ran real hard, and my time was like 19, 59, almost exactly 20 minutes.
Speaker 0: We were like,
Speaker 0: "Pah!".
Speaker 1: So, I ran hard, and so at the end- Could you have run harder?
Speaker 1: I don't think so, actually.
Speaker 1: I think I ran as hard as I could have run on that day.
Speaker 1: But I ran over the finish line, walked over to some bushes, and immediately vomited into those bushes.
Speaker 0: Oh, you suck.
Speaker 1: Which, I mean, that happens if you push too hard, especially in a foot race.
Speaker 1: That's just something that happens.
Speaker 1: Marathon runners shit themselves.
Speaker 0: You also have a blarging problem.
Speaker 1: My body's go-to.
Speaker 1: My body, like if there's a conference inside of my body, like, "Hey, something's going on.
Speaker 1: Man, what should we do about
Speaker 1: it?".
Speaker 0: Also, if you do something that makes you bargle, that's a sign you shouldn't do that thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but running, I'll live longer if I run.
Speaker 0: Not if you bargle.
Speaker 1: And maybe you shouldn't push that hard without draining your body.
Speaker 0: Not if you bargle your body out.
Speaker 1: Might have been the Red Bull.
Speaker 1: I chugged before the race, too.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: I think that's cheating.
Speaker 0: They didn't test for that Red Bull?
Speaker 1: What next?
Speaker 1: So I run over to the finish line, I walk over to the bushes, I just vomit, and then I turn around, and I'm feeling good, like I'm smiling, and there's a kid standing right there.
Speaker 1: And he's looking at me, and he looks up at me, because he just saw me projectile vomit in some bushes, and just goes,
Speaker 1: "Wooooow.".
Speaker 1: Pretty much that made my day.
Speaker 0: Okay, maybe just next time you see a kid, stick your finger down your throat and bargle.
Speaker 1: You know, vomiting is actually pretty funny.
Speaker 0: Uh, you can do all the vomiting.
Speaker 1: If someone else is doing it.
Speaker 1: Somewhere near me, and I can't smell it.
Speaker 0: I am not doing any vomiting.
Speaker 0: I read something recently that there might be like disease transmission from like vomit particles in the air.
Speaker 1: I could easily believe that.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna avoid vomit.
Speaker 1: I read a similar article talking about how air dryers in public bathrooms are just spreading pee and fecal coliform all over.
Speaker 0: Well, at least they're not on my hands.
Speaker 0: Spread it all over the ground.
Speaker 1: Get it in the lungs and other people's hands.
Speaker 0: Yeah, blast it off of my hands onto the wall.
Speaker 1: So yeah, we're pretty much back for a little while, and then I'll disappear to Australia for a while.
Speaker 1: As long as I don't die mountain biking in Singapore, or mountain biking in Australia.
Speaker 0: Poison snake.
Speaker 0: Poison spider.
Speaker 1: Actually, I was reading about this place.
Speaker 1: It's like this semi-abandoned island.
Speaker 0: So even more poison snakes.
Speaker 1: Uh, nope.
Speaker 1: Snakes are not a problem there.
Speaker 1: The problem is very poisonous lizards.
Speaker 0: It's close enough.
Speaker 0: I mean, not snakes, other poisonous lizards.
Speaker 1: The website was like, if a lizard is blocking the bike path, do not antagonize it.
Speaker 1: Just choose another path, and it'll eventually go somewhere else.
Speaker 0: How big is this lizard that you can't just bike over it?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Or bike really past fast it.
Speaker 1: I guess I'll find out.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna go to this island on Saturday, because while I'm there, as I am- Saturday is the no lizard day?
Speaker 0: Is the day the lizard's taking the day off from poisoning people to death?
Speaker 1: Well, Thursday I gotta go to a convention and give a panel.
Speaker 0: How many people have died from lizard on this island?
Speaker 1: Not many, as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: The island's pretty safe.
Speaker 0: How many people have gone to hospital through the lizard on this island?
Speaker 1: I think more people have gone to hospital from the mountain biking part than the lizard part.
Speaker 0: Well, but if you get a double whammy, you fall off the mountain bike, there's a lizard!
Speaker 0: Well, that's what would happen in any comedy movie ever.
Speaker 1: That is one thing, at least with skiing, that while I am not as good as skier, I don't think- Yes, if you fall off ski, there are only poisonous lizards.
Speaker 0: There will just be a polar bear there, and a yeti.
Speaker 1: Not a polar bear, but probably a grizzly bear.
Speaker 0: I mean, the yeti comes 100% of the time, every time.
Speaker 0: But if you never stop- No matter what, if you ski long enough, the yeti will come.
Speaker 1: But if you never stop, and never slow down, and never fuck up, you won't actually catch you.
Speaker 0: Bumbles bounce you.
Speaker 1: So yeah, you got any news, or a Geek Byte perhaps, now that we're back and we're talking about anime, manga, comics, and the like?
Speaker 0: Well, there isn't a lot of comics news lately, probably because the newer Comic-Con is like in a few weeks.
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 0: But there is some sort of comics news, it's just releases, but there's some very important releases of things right now.
Speaker 0: It is currently Wednesday, you're probably listening to this on at least Thursday.
Speaker 0: That is Wednesday, September 9th.
Speaker 1: I know who listens the night we put these things up, because of who posts in the forum and tweets at me about stuff.
Speaker 0: There must be at least more people who are lurking and do that, but yeah, what's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Anyway, today, in the comic book store, there are comics on the shelf that were not there yesterday.
Speaker 0: Unless you have a comic book store that puts things up early, but they definitely weren't there Monday.
Speaker 0: And those things are, as follows, Saga Volume 5.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, I'm behind on Saga.
Speaker 0: Which, if you read the trade paperbacks, that's new to you, if you read the individual issues, you've read these already, obviously.
Speaker 0: And also, Descender #1, well, Volume 1, which, same deal.
Speaker 0: Descender is, oh my god, it's by Jeff Lemire, one of our favorite people.
Speaker 1: Jeff Lemire is definitely up there.
Speaker 1: Jason and the like.
Speaker 0: It's about this kid who's a robot in space, what else do you need to know?
Speaker 0: The art, OMG.
Speaker 0: So, go to the comic book store, if you didn't go there already.
Speaker 0: Oh, and not there yet, but you can pre-order it now.
Speaker 0: The subject of this episode, the man who punches only one time, per bad guy.
Speaker 0: The one punch man.
Speaker 1: He might kick a few times.
Speaker 1: Shove more than once on many occasions.
Speaker 0: He pretty much just punches people once and that's it.
Speaker 0: That manga, which has been only available by Scanlation in the US, is going to be legally available in like a month or two.
Speaker 1: Eagle.
Speaker 0: Yes, you can buy it at the store instead of reading it online and you can pre-order that now.
Speaker 0: I think they're putting out two volumes in one month, so it's going to be one of those deals where it's like, if you think, oh man, but I've already, I read a whole bunch of the manga online and then stopped when they were fighting a fisherman.
Speaker 0: That seems to be usually when I stop reading a Shonen Jump manga.
Speaker 1: Except for his slayers, that's when you start reading.
Speaker 0: Now, two volumes a month, they're going to catch right the hell up to Japan and we're going to be good to go.
Speaker 0: You can just stop reading the illegal stuff now.
Speaker 0: You'll get a much better translation and printing in the legit ones.
Speaker 1: I noticed kind of randomly, I was poking around on YouTube, that a ton of those old late 80s and 90s OAVs that were mostly, like they were on the sci-fi channel just occasionally with those streamlined dubs, they're pretty much all on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Just the whole movie is in super high quality.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean anything that was subtitled at some point but isn't popular and no one's going to go checking on the license or anything is totally on YouTube.
Speaker 0: You'd also be surprised how much stuff is legally on YouTube.
Speaker 0: There's a Gundam info YouTube channel that has so many legal Gundams on it that you can watch.
Speaker 1: So I watched some Vampire Hunter D like, "Oh right, that
Speaker 1: thing!".
Speaker 1: and I was reminiscing over those streamlined dubs of all these things.
Speaker 1: And then I clicked on 8 Men After like, "Hey, check this out, 8 Men After.
Speaker 1: It's
Speaker 1: Robocop.".
Speaker 0: Why do you have time to watch this?
Speaker 1: It's not long.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So we start watching it like a little bit like, "Okay, right, old
Speaker 1: OAVs."
Speaker 1: And we make fun of it and then instead of turning it off, we kind of just kept watching it because we kind of missed those old dumb 90s OAVs.
Speaker 0: If you didn't have nostalgia for it though, would it be any good at all?
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: It holds up way better than I would have expected.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not He-Man.
Speaker 1: It's other than the fact that the girl keeps wearing that Band-Aid on her head and she seems pretty dumb and she keeps saying the same thing over again.
Speaker 1: And also the streamlined dub being a streamlined dub.
Speaker 1: It was good enough and engaging enough to where we kind of just kept watching it.
Speaker 0: But you got to remember, right?
Speaker 0: These animes that were on the 90s, we were watching them as like teenagers or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: The old guys of anime who we see at the anime con sometimes who were like way older than us, like 50s, 60s, they were our age or they were adults when those things were on Sci-Fi Channel in the 90s and they were watching them, enjoying them.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So we're that age now.
Speaker 0: It's not like He-Man where we only watched it when we were three years old and that's why we liked it, you know?
Speaker 0: Well, you know what it is?
Speaker 1: It's that these OAVs, they have alternatingly great and terrible animation and there's just this certain like they have to finish their whole story quickly.
Speaker 1: So they're kind of like a movie, but they're usually based on things that would have been or were a manga or a TV show.
Speaker 1: So they have to kind of compress the action together.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I might do a show on 8-Man After if I get Scott to watch it.
Speaker 1: Have you ever seen it?
Speaker 0: Uh, no.
Speaker 1: Do you know what it's about?
Speaker 0: Uh, the 8th Man.
Speaker 1: Do you know who the 8th Man is?
Speaker 0: Not the 7th Man.
Speaker 1: Tobor the 8th Man?
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 0: Tobor.
Speaker 0: It's an acronym of robot.
Speaker 1: Oh, aducardo.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: And he's some sort of hero.
Speaker 0: He fights bad guys, punches them, eats them with robot powers.
Speaker 1: 8-Man After is an OAV movie that basically takes place long after 8-Man's death.
Speaker 1: And I'm not going to say it's particularly good.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to hold it out on any anime.
Speaker 1: that like everyone must see.
Speaker 1: It's better than you might think.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty much straight up Robocop story.
Speaker 1: With some roided up cyborgs playing American football.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Is MD Geist among them?
Speaker 0: He knows how to play American football.
Speaker 1: That would be the mashup I would do like my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: But the other thing I've been watching with Emily is Bojack Horseman.
Speaker 1: That animated show with, you know, the guy with the horse head that you see everywhere on Netflix.
Speaker 0: I don't have Netflix anymore, but I saw this because people said it.
Speaker 0: so I googled it and I saw a horseman.
Speaker 0: And the first thing I thought was, well, all those people wearing a horse mask are now cosplaying something specific and not just a horseman.
Speaker 1: They're only cosplaying Bojack Horseman if the rest of their body looks like a frumpy 50 year old.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: So Bojack, I like I saw ads for it because and I normally came up with this thing.
Speaker 1: So I normally don't really notice ads.
Speaker 1: However, when I was biking home every day early in the summer, they had hired an entire brick wall along that bike path and it was a picture of Bojack.
Speaker 0: Oh, that brick.
Speaker 0: I know the brick wall you're talking about where they always put like really high resolution advertisements painted on.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So one day I was biking home and there's a horse head.
Speaker 0: I always wonder how they do that.
Speaker 0: I like to be there when they put the ad out.
Speaker 1: They're doing one right now.
Speaker 1: You know how they do it?
Speaker 0: They print it out, they stick it up against the wall and hit it with a flamethrower?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: There's literally seven people just like sitting around on a giant scaffold just painting it by hand.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They're really good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like I stopped and watched them for a little bit.
Speaker 1: If they're still there later in the week, maybe I'll stop.
Speaker 0: What are they painting now?
Speaker 1: Looks like a football, sports ball thing.
Speaker 0: Oh, OK.
Speaker 1: But I might stop and give them a card.
Speaker 0: It is the season.
Speaker 1: It'd be interesting to interview someone like that.
Speaker 1: So you paint ads by hand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I get paid a ton of money.
Speaker 0: You can't do this.
Speaker 1: You know, we do do a joint show.
Speaker 1: We also get our friend, the chalk artist.
Speaker 0: Now, see, I wonder the people who own the building that's getting painted on, how much are they making?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Should we buy a building just to be in one of those places?
Speaker 0: You mean like the thing in the middle of Times Square that's basically an empty building?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Just like that, actually.
Speaker 0: It has like a Walgreens in the bottom and that's it?
Speaker 1: We buy a building.
Speaker 1: It's actually our banana stand.
Speaker 1: But on the outside, we make money by selling ads on it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the ad was a reverse centaur, basically, laying on its back in a sexy George Costanza style pose.
Speaker 1: And it just said, hey there.
Speaker 1: And I remember I biked past it and I actually stopped, went back and took a picture of it and tweeted it at Adam.
Speaker 1: Just kind of randomly because I was kind of taken aback by it.
Speaker 1: Only relatively recently did I actually go see what the hell that thing was and watch it.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: If you haven't watched it, it's not what you'd expect it to be.
Speaker 0: Isn't it just one of those Adult Swim shows, right?
Speaker 1: It doesn't act, feel, sound.
Speaker 1: It is in no way like those shows.
Speaker 0: The picture looks like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I expected it to be that kind of humor.
Speaker 0: Is it on Adult Swim?
Speaker 1: It's just on Netflix.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's a Netflix only?
Speaker 1: It is a Netflix original.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 0: But the deal is that if you- Is that the first animated Netflix original?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I actually really don't know.
Speaker 1: Are the other ones all live action?
Speaker 1: All the ones I liked and watched were live action.
Speaker 1: It might be.
Speaker 1: It's an American animated sitcom, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: It doesn't say here in a trivial reading of Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the show is actually a pretty hard to watch, brutal human drama that just happens to be animated and just happens to have about half the characters have horse heads and owl heads and things.
Speaker 0: Ooh, owl heads.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually the owl girl, Wanda, is pretty much the best character.
Speaker 0: I like owls.
Speaker 1: You would really like this character.
Speaker 1: Ooh.
Speaker 1: I got to show you Wanda.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: The thing about Wanda, well, I'm not going to say anything about the show.
Speaker 1: That's not Wanda.
Speaker 0: None of those are the Wanda you're talking about because none of them are owls.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: There's Wanda.
Speaker 0: Oh, she's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So the show is about a washed up actor and how fucked up he is and how fucked up his life is.
Speaker 1: And about 10% of the show is also jokes about the fact that half the people are animals.
Speaker 1: Like Bojack gets kind of messed up if he eats too much cotton candy.
Speaker 1: Like give a real horse cotton candy and they'll flip out.
Speaker 0: Shouldn't a real horse not eat cotton candy?
Speaker 1: Yeah, real horses should not eat cotton candy.
Speaker 0: I mean, animals shouldn't eat sugar in general.
Speaker 0: Humans get a good idea.
Speaker 1: Let me just say, if a real horse gets near a cotton candy machine, there's going to be some trouble.
Speaker 1: But it's about like a 90s TV star who's now rich and washed up.
Speaker 1: And it's just this really depressing and real human drama.
Speaker 1: And I really like it more than I expected to the point that I'm pretty much marathoning it as fast as I can.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I already got a second season.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't know if you'd like it, but if you don't like it, Scott, it won't be because it's like Archer or all those other kinds of shows we like.
Speaker 1: It's going to be a different kind of not liking from any not liking that you've had up to this point.
Speaker 0: It can go to the bottom of the queue somewhere.
Speaker 1: You should watch a few episodes at some point.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't put it at the top of the queue, though.
Speaker 0: I mean, the queue is getting pretty deep.
Speaker 1: If you're not Scott Rubin, however, watch some Bojack.
Speaker 1: The only caveat is that it might be a little too real for you and it might be a little too close to home.
Speaker 0: Yes, the Owl Girl is too close to home.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: Someone made this the Antonio Maria da Silva M's films YouTube account.
Speaker 1: It got like fifteen million, five million, ten million more views or whatever since when I first found it.
Speaker 0: But it only has three million total views, not even.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It seems like it's posted on a bunch of other YouTube channels now.
Speaker 1: So I'm trying to figure out who originally made it.
Speaker 1: But it's an amazing compositing mashup of like every movie ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like fifty different movies and characters from them all in the same nightclub.
Speaker 1: And you pretty much just have to watch it.
Speaker 1: It's like ten minutes long.
Speaker 1: It's kind of insane that someone made this.
Speaker 0: Someone really had nothing to do.
Speaker 0: I mean, the core was really, really, really good with video editing.
Speaker 1: The characters range from Star Wars Episode One to multiple Tom Cruises from different movies to Al Pacino to Blade to Arnold from Terminator One.
Speaker 1: Scarface is in there.
Speaker 1: In fact, Scarface is a major character in the plot that unfolds.
Speaker 0: There's a plot?
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually.
Speaker 0: OK, I couldn't tell if there was a plot.
Speaker 0: There is a plot.
Speaker 0: A mashup for the sake of mashing up.
Speaker 1: A gunfight breaks out and shit goes down.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: You just have to watch this thing.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: So it might have been a thing of the day previously, the Senpai Club.
Speaker 0: So if you don't know, if you didn't pay attention last time, it was probably a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Scott's a big fan of Senpai Club.
Speaker 0: There's this people.
Speaker 0: I think it's like, you know, this couple.
Speaker 0: I think they're a couple.
Speaker 1: Oh, here's the picture that was that was on the ad of BoJack.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: And they make, you know, just cute anime for YouTube.
Speaker 0: that, you know, in their spare time, I assume it doesn't seem like they're getting paid for it.
Speaker 0: And their studio is named Make Babies.
Speaker 0: Make Babbie dot ES.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Get it?
Speaker 0: The spelling.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: And they make the cut.
Speaker 0: They think they're currently making this called Senpai Club, which is like the best.
Speaker 0: And it's pretty much like this parody of anime in general, like school anime.
Speaker 0: And, you know, like making fun of the girl running to school with toast in her mouth.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or like the triangle headed be shown in.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So the latest episode, however.
Speaker 0: Well, part one of episode three.
Speaker 0: The opener is like in the old school anime 70s, 80s anime style.
Speaker 0: And they put a lot of work into it.
Speaker 0: And it's it's incredible.
Speaker 0: So you need to see it if you haven't been paying attention.
Speaker 1: It's one of the better.
Speaker 0: Even more.
Speaker 0: Like, even if you don't want to watch all of Senpai Club, if you know anything about anime and old anime, just watch this, you know, start of episode three, part one.
Speaker 1: You do have to know a little bit about anime.
Speaker 1: If you haven't seen a lot of anime, you're probably.
Speaker 0: It's a parody of anime.
Speaker 0: If you don't know anime, what sense will it make?
Speaker 1: It's like trying to watch Excel Saga if you've never seen anime.
Speaker 1: In the moment, the Book Club book was the Wheel of Time.
Speaker 1: Book one, a fantasy book, the novel.
Speaker 0: But we're going to do episode on it like tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, it'll go up.
Speaker 1: Who knows when we're going to try to put up episodes while I'm overseas.
Speaker 0: We finished reading it.
Speaker 0: We're going to record as many episodes as we can before it gets on a plane.
Speaker 0: And that will be one of the episodes you record before it goes on a plane.
Speaker 1: The only things I have to say about it at a time is that I'd recommend reading it if you never read it.
Speaker 0: If you like fantasy novel, this is fantasy now.
Speaker 1: It is so fantasy novel.
Speaker 1: It is a series of Chekhov swords that then fire within a few chapters.
Speaker 1: And there's a few more Chekhov swords that have not fired yet.
Speaker 0: And then there are eight more books, none of which were written by Chekhov.
Speaker 1: They're not the best books in the world, but I will say this.
Speaker 1: I'm about halfway through the second book now.
Speaker 0: Three quarters of the way through the third book.
Speaker 1: I bought the third book.
Speaker 0: Really big books.
Speaker 0: They don't really go by very slowly at all.
Speaker 1: I bought the third book.
Speaker 1: I'll probably read it on my travel and we'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: The Kindle versions are just as the same price as the paperback versions.
Speaker 0: Of course, you could go RMAT, right?
Speaker 0: But they're DRM free Kindle books, so whatever.
Speaker 0: If it was DRM'd, I probably wouldn't buy the Kindle version, but Amazon points.
Speaker 1: And we were at the Penny Arcade Expo.
Speaker 1: Videos and things will come.
Speaker 1: In the meantime, I burned through some of the queue.
Speaker 1: So I uploaded a video we made at PAX South in San Antonio.
Speaker 1: When Scott and I had some time to kill, we were bored.
Speaker 1: And we were already all rigged up with our equipment to go through the expo hall.
Speaker 0: It came out worse than I remember, but also better than I remember.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: The worst actually made it better.
Speaker 1: It was like this good mix of us laughing at our own jokes and attempting to put this thing together.
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 1: The concept was sound.
Speaker 1: And I think what says it all is that I actually laughed when I was watching it while I was trying to edit this thing together.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: This was all Scott's idea.
Speaker 1: Just saying.
Speaker 0: We had nothing to do.
Speaker 1: We could have played games.
Speaker 0: We did.
Speaker 0: We played as many games as we possibly could play.
Speaker 1: And we're going to be at MAGFest.
Speaker 1: But if you didn't get your hotel for MAGFest, we warned you.
Speaker 1: You're fucked now.
Speaker 0: Wait, I didn't get a hotel for MAGFest.
Speaker 1: I assume you're in with us and Phil and everybody and J.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: I'll double check to make sure.
Speaker 1: I said we were all in.
Speaker 1: If not, you're fucked.
Speaker 0: Oh, well.
Speaker 0: And we're going.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: MAGFest is now going to be just as hard to go to as PAX East, I think.
Speaker 1: So we're previewing this because we only got to see one episode that had blatantly incorrect made-up subtitles.
Speaker 1: I'm getting the disclaimer out now.
Speaker 1: Do not watch it until it comes out legit.
Speaker 1: If you watch it early...
Speaker 0: This anime is coming out early October.
Speaker 0: It's highly anticipated.
Speaker 0: There are many trailers and teasers on YouTube and such that you can watch.
Speaker 0: But they streamed the first episode on NicoNicoLive as a preview.
Speaker 0: Of course, people captured that and poorly subtitled it and it's low-res.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're watching.
Speaker 1: and Emily just started translating because the subtitles were...
Speaker 0: And Emily's like, "That subtitle's
Speaker 0: wrong.".
Speaker 0: And it was super wrong.
Speaker 1: At one point, a guy's like, "It will make you the strongest in the
Speaker 1: world.".
Speaker 1: Emily's like...
Speaker 0: He said that it tastes like strawberry drink.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And it's like, "Oh, it's not even
Speaker 1: close."
Speaker 1: Where the subtitle just says "IDK" because whoever did it couldn't actually translate.
Speaker 0: Right, so it's going to be on a legal streaming site, I'm sure, because it's super licensed.
Speaker 0: It's going to be a big hit.
Speaker 0: But this is the One Punch Man.
Speaker 0: One Punch Man was getting so much talking and on Twitter that I had to check it out.
Speaker 0: I read a whole bunch of the manga maybe about a year ago.
Speaker 1: So, Scott, what is One Punch Man about?
Speaker 0: So, there's this guy.
Speaker 0: And he was just like a normal, totally normal dude.
Speaker 1: And then he got bit by a radioactive spider or something?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: And he couldn't get a job.
Speaker 0: And he was sort of dismayed with life or whatever.
Speaker 0: So he said, "You know what?
Speaker 0: I'm just going to be a hero for
Speaker 0: fun.".
Speaker 0: So he decides to become a hero.
Speaker 0: And to train to be a hero every day, he does 100 push-ups every day.
Speaker 0: 100 push-ups and 100 sit-ups and 100 squats.
Speaker 0: And he runs 10K every single day.
Speaker 1: I could do that if I didn't have a job.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he didn't have a job.
Speaker 0: So he did that every single day.
Speaker 1: So if I quit my job and do that, can I kill anyone in one punch?
Speaker 0: He trained so hard that all his hair fell out and his head became super shiny.
Speaker 0: Deal breaker.
Speaker 0: And he became so powerful that any bad guy he punches goes down in one punch.
Speaker 0: His one punch is so ridiculously strong that he is now One Punch Man.
Speaker 1: Now that there is an animated television series of One Punch Man.
Speaker 0: I mean, it was already popular.
Speaker 0: Now it's going to be double popular with everyone.
Speaker 0: I saw maybe one cosplay of it in the past year or two.
Speaker 0: You're going to see so many punchmans.
Speaker 1: I have to redact/update a bunch of panels and lectures we've done for the past decade.
Speaker 1: Because for a long time, I have said, and so has Scott, that the greatest punch in the history of anime is Big O.
Speaker 0: The One Punch Man has pretty much taken over.
Speaker 0: I mean, it combines pretty much the best elements.
Speaker 0: This is sort of like the be-all end-all of anime, right?
Speaker 1: Wasn't that Kill La Kill?
Speaker 0: Well, no.
Speaker 0: Kill La Kill saved anime.
Speaker 0: It's already been saved, which is why One Punch Man can exist, right?
Speaker 0: In the saved anime universe.
Speaker 0: It has the ridiculousness and action scenes of the Kill La Kill, right?
Speaker 0: It has the crazy visual stylings and random crazy characters of a Space Dandy kind of situation.
Speaker 1: Well, it's directed by the person who directed Space Dandy.
Speaker 0: How about that?
Speaker 0: It brings in the punch and the epicness of violence of, say, a Big O, or a Fist of the North Star.
Speaker 1: Well, it brings in not just the epic violence and the punch, but the viscera and gore of the 90s.
Speaker 1: I mean, dude pulls an entire crab out of his body by the eyeball.
Speaker 0: And then it brings in the shounen-ness of the Dragon Ball, right?
Speaker 0: All together into this one, like, the be-all end-all singularity of shounen action manga anime that ever must exist.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to make any more, right?
Speaker 0: It's like One Piece, right?
Speaker 0: It's got the One Piece in there, too.
Speaker 0: It's Madhouse.
Speaker 1: The opening theme is Jam Project.
Speaker 1: It's a who's who in a lot of ways.
Speaker 0: It is the shounen anime of all time.
Speaker 0: And its first episode is even, like, half out yet.
Speaker 1: This is the kind of anime that when I was going to anime cons when I was younger, I'd actually be like, "Oh my god, there's a new anime!
Speaker 1: I'm gonna watch the
Speaker 1: screening!".
Speaker 1: It's the kind of thing that I expect to see at an anime con with the screening, and a whole bunch of people go to see it, and a bunch of cosplay, people getting really into it.
Speaker 1: Bald guys, your day has come.
Speaker 0: So I've read the manga, so I know some things that weren't in the first episode.
Speaker 0: the rhythm doesn't know.
Speaker 0: For example, there's a sidekick, and...
Speaker 1: Why would you kick?
Speaker 0: No, there's a character who's a sidekick who's awesome.
Speaker 0: He's like a cyborg, and he actually knows about being a hero.
Speaker 0: And there's an organization that manages all heroes on Earth, and the heroes have different grades and levels.
Speaker 0: So they're trying to level out to be higher grade heroes to get more monies or whatever.
Speaker 0: There's this whole structure that gets involved and stuff, but really, you just want to see him punch something one time.
Speaker 1: The opening song's name is "Set Fire to the Furious
Speaker 1: Fist."
Speaker 1: I think it's already on fire.
Speaker 0: But, you know, it's so... You know, it's like, Kenshiro knows that when he punches someone, they're gonna explode, right?
Speaker 1: But he punches him, like, a hundred times!
Speaker 0: Right, and so does One Punch Man.
Speaker 0: One Punch Man is sort of like, "Eh, punch.
Speaker 0: Phew.
Speaker 0: Whatever.".
Speaker 1: He also doesn't wait.
Speaker 1: Kenshiro will sort of wait, and, like, fight his way through a bunch of minions.
Speaker 1: This guy's just like, "Straight to the boss.
Speaker 0: Punch
Speaker 0: him.".
Speaker 0: His name is Saitama, and it's like, he wants to save the world.
Speaker 0: He doesn't want the world to die, but he doesn't care too much, whereas Kenshiro will be like, "Use these ten seconds to think about your
Speaker 0: sins.".
Speaker 0: You know?
Speaker 0: That kind of shit.
Speaker 0: He doesn't do that, right?
Speaker 0: Maybe he should.
Speaker 0: Maybe he will eventually.
Speaker 1: But the show's got just the crazy animation, like what we saw with "Kill la
Speaker 1: Kill."
Speaker 1: This is really bendy, squashy, weirdy.
Speaker 1: Like, when he jumps and punches, you see his whole torso, like, tarred, and the fist, like, bends into the punch.
Speaker 1: It looks great.
Speaker 0: They have to capture, even in highly pixelated stream rips, right?
Speaker 0: It looks great, so the real one probably looks even better.
Speaker 0: But the manga, you know, I think actually, compared to the first episode, I think the manga actually does a better job of, like, conveying the epicness of punching something one time, right?
Speaker 0: And it's mostly because the bad guys start escalating, you know?
Speaker 0: And it's like he punches, you know, what, in episode one of the anime, he punched Crablante once.
Speaker 0: Well, and he didn't actually even punch Crablante, or he killed him using a different method.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pulling his entire viscera system out of his body through his eye socket.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but he punched quite a, you know, that giant guy once.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: He punched some other guys once, right?
Speaker 0: But when he starts punching, like, the real bad guys once, and you start seeing, like, you know, they start, when all the other heroes start showing up and all these other characters, you sort of get.
Speaker 0: the relativity aspect of it comes into play, where it's, like, the most powerful hero on Earth is, like, you know, Superman, basically, is, like, having a tough time, and then One Punch Man punches that bad guy once.
Speaker 1: Well, it's got this nice idea of escalation, which a lot of, like, the indie comics and the kinds of things we like, like, if you see enough tropes and you see enough stories, you start to get to the point where you want to see, like, the culmination of that kind of story.
Speaker 1: Like, this is the culmination of the superhero story.
Speaker 1: What if you had the literally invincible, all-powerful, well, at least all-powerful in terms of beating bad guys guy?
Speaker 0: Like, push it all the way to the end and see what kind of story you have.
Speaker 0: Right, but to make it interesting, right, it's interesting because of the character that he is, right, is while he's super powerful, punch everyone once and they die, you know, it's, like, he's really sort of bored.
Speaker 0: Like, he wants a super awesome fight to be an awesome hero and have fun with it, but, like, he's not having fun with it.
Speaker 0: He just punches everyone once and it's over.
Speaker 0: And he's like, "Oh, God, this is so
Speaker 0: boring.".
Speaker 0: Right, and it's, like, he escaped the life of, you know, looking for a job.
Speaker 0: He gave up on that because it sucks so much.
Speaker 0: Now he's got this hero job and it sucks just as much because he's so good at it.
Speaker 1: But, meanwhile, like, D in Vampire Hunter D.
Speaker 0: I can really relate to that.
Speaker 0: Like, at work, I type everything once and then it's boring.
Speaker 1: One type man.
Speaker 0: I'm one type man.
Speaker 1: Touch the keyboard once, the problem's solved.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much what I do.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But, like, D, because I watched some old Vampire Hunter D again recently.
Speaker 1: There's a midnight screening of it at a local theater, too.
Speaker 1: He is just as, like, it's the same as one punch man, except it's, like, one sword slash man.
Speaker 1: He just wins every fight automatically because he's Alucard.
Speaker 0: But Alucard doesn't have the same personality.
Speaker 1: Well, no, D has no personality and gives zero fucks about anything.
Speaker 1: He just wins.
Speaker 1: Every fight is, "Oh, D, I've beaten you.
Speaker 1: Nope.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's.
Speaker 0: no, that's another thing, is that there's no suspense of, you know, is usually when there's a fighting story, right?
Speaker 1: Well, like, initial D. At the end, like, we talked about this when we reviewed it.
Speaker 1: Even in episode 25, when you know he's gonna win because he wins every fucking race, Itsuki's like, "I don't think he's gonna win it this
Speaker 1: time.".
Speaker 1: And you're like, "Well, what if he doesn't?
Speaker 1: I mean, that car is real
Speaker 1: fast.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's no suspense in one punch man if Saitama is gonna get hurt or injured or die.
Speaker 0: It's like, you just accept the fact that he's invincible.
Speaker 0: Like, he doesn't, you know, once you see him get, like, ridiculously, like, punched a zillion times and, like, he's unharmed, like, not even a scratch, it's like, "Oh,
Speaker 0: okay.".
Speaker 0: And you don't even, like, you're never concerned that anything, like, Kenshiro sometimes is like, "Oh, shit, is he gonna lose to this guy?
Speaker 0: He's actually really
Speaker 0: powerful?".
Speaker 0: And he gets hurt.
Speaker 0: I mean, he's got those seven scars in his chest for a reason, right?
Speaker 1: The Shonen fighting trope is to make the character actually invincible but continue to escalate to trick you into doubting for a second that he's gonna make it.
Speaker 1: But then he makes it in the end anyway.
Speaker 0: There's no question that he's gonna make it, right?
Speaker 0: It's just, a lot of the suspense is like, "When is he gonna punch him?
Speaker 0: Is he gonna punch him?
Speaker 0: Is this guy so strong that the punch won't
Speaker 0: work?".
Speaker 0: You're never worried about Saitama being hurt.
Speaker 1: So it skips, like, every trope of a Shonen show.
Speaker 0: Well, but there's also other characters such as the awesome cyborg sidekick who can get hurt, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like, "Oh, are those people gonna get hurt?
Speaker 0: Is he gonna save them in
Speaker 0: time?".
Speaker 0: You know, those sorts of things are still coming to play a little bit.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, I like how it's city A and then everyone moved to city B because city A got destroyed in a fight.
Speaker 0: It just doesn't hold back, right?
Speaker 0: It just, you know, it doesn't even bother trying to hide, like, the Shonen structure, right?
Speaker 0: By making it, you know, in Dragon Ball, they're like power level 9000, right?
Speaker 0: They're trying to hide it a little bit, right?
Speaker 0: One Punch Man doesn't even try to hide it.
Speaker 0: They're like, "Let us form a structure of Shonen leveling up that we will now, is easily translated into video games, but is a parody because we're making it so
Speaker 0: explicit.".
Speaker 1: It's almost a deconstruction.
Speaker 0: But it's not.
Speaker 0: It is the perfect construction.
Speaker 0: It is when, you know, you can't deconstruct something by being the same.
Speaker 1: Well, one could say the struggle is everything but the battle.
Speaker 0: By making the perfect example of a thing, you are not deconstructing that thing.
Speaker 0: You are simply constructing the best possible example of that thing.
Speaker 1: It's not perfect because the perfect example does all those other tropes and goes through the cycle of doubt and belief and doubt and belief.
Speaker 1: This is, it's going beyond the cycle.
Speaker 1: It's going past all that to all the other stuff.
Speaker 0: There comes a point where you can't tell the difference between parody and the real thing, and that is what One Punch Man is.
Speaker 0: It is at the pinnacle of it.
Speaker 0: You cannot possibly go any higher onto the top of Mount Everest when the pointy bit is in your asshole.
Speaker 0: That is the end of the line.
Speaker 1: That pointy bit is where either the best or the worst media are.
Speaker 0: This is the best one.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: But, you know, the worst one could be right alongside it because two people can be on the point at the same time if they can stand on, like, one atom of pointiness on their toe or something.
Speaker 1: But then you get into quantum physics and causality.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if you care anything about anime at all, even if you don't care about anime, and maybe you've thought about all those other anime we've mentioned, you don't need to watch all those.
Speaker 0: Just watch/read One Punch Man, and you will not need to see any other punches, watch any other shounen animes, or read any of the shounen mangas.
Speaker 0: This is the one.
Speaker 0: We don't need anyone to make any more.
Speaker 0: If you're writing one right now, just throw it in the garbage.
Speaker 0: Work on some shoujo or something.
Speaker 0: In fact, make the shoujo, like, One Kiss Girl or something.
Speaker 0: You know, because I want to read that.
Speaker 1: I would read that.
Speaker 1: I would watch that.
Speaker 0: And then I want to see the mashup, One Kiss Girl, One Punch Man.
Speaker 1: I looked.
Speaker 1: No one has drawn fanart of One Punch Man and Big O with the second punch, tier two punch.
Speaker 0: At least you haven't found such fanart.
Speaker 1: I just searched for, like, five minutes and couldn't find it.
Speaker 0: Well, searching Japanese.
Speaker 1: But seriously, while you should watch this show, just wait for it to be out legit, because-- It'll be out legit so soon.
Speaker 0: The non-legit version-- Next month is going to be the month of One Punch Man comes to America and punches every anime fan right in the junk, whatever kind of junk you got.
Speaker 0: It's getting punched.
Speaker 1: When he punches that one subterranean-- And it's only going to take once.
Speaker 1: He definitely punches him right in the dick.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Like, right in the dick.
Speaker 0: I mean, why not?
Speaker 0: If you didn't punch him right in the dick, that show would be a slight step lower on the Mount Everest.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, hopefully we'll have a bunch of Ginkgoz episodes up.
Speaker 1: We're going to trickle them out to you.
Speaker 1: We're going to record as many as we can before I fly.
Speaker 1: And starting in October, we'll actually be back in town doing our normal stuff.
Speaker 1: And we're going to start ramping up video production of things.
Speaker 1: So stay tuned.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: Uh... You're not as loud as you were before.
Speaker 1: Bop.
Speaker 0: Eh.
Speaker 0: Might be even too quiet.
Speaker 0: Bop.
Speaker 0: Fart.
Speaker 0: Poop.
Speaker 0: Poop fart.