Speaker 1: It's probably Thursday September 17th 2015.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: I might be in Singapore or Australia or something, but we recorded a bunch of shows ahead of time and tonight We're talking about on the geek nights book club the first book of the wheel of time.
Speaker 0: It is the eye of the world by Robert Jordan Fantasy book the novel part one part one.
Speaker 0: Let's do this, but first Things of the day.
Speaker 0: you can't do news recording a show in the past.
Speaker 0: cuz who knows what's happened today?
Speaker 0: We don't know.
Speaker 1: cuz we're in the past, but it's the lounge so we could talk about anything.
Speaker 1: commentary.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so my thing of the day is this guy longboarding down a really steep road Which isn't really that exciting except for the fact that I think this is a world record speed of longboarding.
Speaker 1: It's not going away fast.
Speaker 0: It's not world record.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really freaking matter.
Speaker 0: He's going like 70 miles an hour with no helmet on a longboard with no brakes down a road.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the road is smooth But I mean one rock in the road and he could boom bump tumble tree dead and that does not happen Which makes this video awesome?
Speaker 0: The coolest thing I think is like he's got this stance practice for when he's going straight.
Speaker 0: It's like he's got these perfect balance going on and he's also got these gauntlet kind of gloves on his hands.
Speaker 0: I think he has discs of metal or some kind of material so that when he has to make a sharp turn He can lean and actually put his hand on the ground and to stabilize himself without you know You got a glove on.
Speaker 0: that wouldn't even suffice, right?
Speaker 0: He needs this Like hockey gloves.
Speaker 1: You just wear right through him.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: So there you go.
Speaker 1: So this is a clay video that is about 10 minutes worth of just footage some natural some staged or recreated Just because you know old-timey equipment of the New York City subway.
Speaker 0: in 1949 they shot this with film cameras like black-and-white films spinning through a loop, right?
Speaker 1: What's amazing is that the only things that are different between then and today?
Speaker 1: 2015 are one the accents to the conductor's.
Speaker 0: you can still hear those accents in some parts.
Speaker 1: Not not quite as as New York is.
Speaker 1: this they're.
Speaker 1: they're kind of surprising.
Speaker 1: Yes The doors are deadly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they should be more dead.
Speaker 1: Yep, and there's tokens.
Speaker 0: Tokens.
Speaker 0: you never saw the tokens.
Speaker 0: I never used you ever use the token to go through a toll.
Speaker 1: No Yeah on the on the Garden State Park read throw change into the bucket.
Speaker 0: No the token you would go to the.
Speaker 0: what you would do is you would either if you went through like the toll every day Cuz you were commuting you would buy that and have them mail you the tokens like in rolls like you would get quarters in a roll.
Speaker 0: you get tokens in a roll and you'd pay like a fee monthly or whatever.
Speaker 0: but Or you would drive up to the toll booth and want and you would buy Tokens.
Speaker 0: and then if you buy like a roll of tokens for like 20 bucks or whatever and then every time you got to a Toll you throw in one token into the thing and then it would just you go through the toll.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the amazing thing isn't just that this video is, you know, cool.
Speaker 1: but if you click on this video You're gonna get a bunch of recommended videos on YouTube and it is pretty much nothing but similar Amazing footage of old and new subway stuff.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I've been doing a lot of subway stuff recently because New York actually Just recently for the first time In pretty much all modern history actually expanded the subway system and added a new stop.
Speaker 1: Whoa Yeah, it's we can go on in a few days.
Speaker 1: We can ride there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw the map in the subway car had already updated with the stop.
Speaker 0: I didn't know if the train was going there yet because I was at.
Speaker 0: I was at Times Square and the seven train is, you know still said last stop.
Speaker 0: So I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: but in Grand Central the sign says the name of Hudson Yards.
Speaker 0: now It says the Hudson Yards bound seven just in time to go to the New York Comic Con.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm not gonna go to.
Speaker 1: nope They didn't want my panel.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, yep New York Comic Con a con so big and amazing that despite the fact that I can literally take the subway to it for free Next to my house.
Speaker 0: I would go, you know a few years ago.
Speaker 0: We went just to see Like, you know screenings of films and things that happened to be there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we went to see Makoto Shinkai, right?
Speaker 0: But they aren't having that now.
Speaker 1: So no It's literally it's the only.
Speaker 1: it's the things I hate about cons.
Speaker 1: It's a giant Expo Hall a place with no no food to eat and A huge line.
Speaker 0: Maybe the Hudson Yards stop will create food to eat.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should open up a foodery near there as the Bellas.
Speaker 0: perhaps You know, you need to buy out some old like auto shop that's over there.
Speaker 1: You need to take the de Bellas formula to make the de Bellas truck.
Speaker 1: It's just a giant Winnebago and you pull it up outside of events and do the de Bellas thing.
Speaker 0: There is a submarine sandwich Italian.
Speaker 1: Do they make like ten subs a minute?
Speaker 0: I don't know how many they make but sometimes they're near my work and I haven't even bothered to go try them out.
Speaker 0: because if they Back way back when I worked at that stupid day Do not have a much enough people in a line outside of them to bet if they made ten subs a minute They would have no people outside.
Speaker 1: I mean I could make us an entire sub in about 30 seconds.
Speaker 1: Well, you can train everybody.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I'll count the money now.
Speaker 1: We gotta get the guy who trained me The master Time a of subs the book.
Speaker 1: a book is.
Speaker 1: well, we're done.
Speaker 1: now I'm gonna pick a new book club book Which is tough because I'm pretty much pick something that you're gonna read in Singapore.
Speaker 1: But I'm gonna read the next Wheel of Time books.
Speaker 1: Oops.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll just do book two of the Wheel of Time.
Speaker 1: Let's not do that, uh, maybe I'll pick the next our Scott back your book because there's a date now supposedly how good we're gonna Do this book club in 2025?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see when the date is.
Speaker 1: There's like there's no pre-order yet on Amazon.
Speaker 0: So Wheel of Time.
Speaker 0: I chose this book on the basis that the Wheel of Time is one of those ridiculously famous fantasy series just like Lord of the Rings and The Games of Thrones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's one of those things where if like if you go to an anime con and you're like cowboy bebop What's that?
Speaker 0: And all the other people are like what you've never seen cowboy bebop, you know, they're like certain You know, there's like sci-fi series like, you know foundation.
Speaker 0: And what's another good one, you know the culture series Even that's more recent.
Speaker 0: in the fantasy sci-fi nerd section of the bookstore There are certain book series that are just there.
Speaker 0: They're perennial.
Speaker 0: They're always, you know, they're a thing and being a nerd I feel like I should you know know at least some about all of these things because they're so important nerderies.
Speaker 0: But Wheel of Time while it's had many RPGs made out of it and things of that nature It hasn't had TV series or movies or anything like that to bring it into the greater pop culture.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I think most people don't know what the hell this is at all.
Speaker 0: But nerds you see those books and it's like you.
Speaker 0: even if you haven't read it you at least know That is one of the big fantasy novel series.
Speaker 1: So I knew about them because of all things there was when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: There was the museum replicas magazine where you could like or catalog where you could order swords And I didn't have money luckily, so I never bought any.
Speaker 1: but the best sword they had was called the heron blade.
Speaker 0: Oh, and it talked about like yeah, not as good as the heron spear.
Speaker 0: What's up with herons and weapons and fantasy series?
Speaker 1: Would suspect that the heron spear was perhaps inspired by the heron blade.
Speaker 0: you think so?
Speaker 1: I do think so.
Speaker 1: maybe the problem I the the main reason I'm really kind of invested in these books now the Wheel of Time and why I think was a good Book club choice for you to pick is that you didn't think that when I picked it originally.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't because Super at least you admit that I was not enthusiastic about reading however many million pages that that's exactly what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: I discovered these books because I spent a lot of time in the nerd section of the borders and the Barnes and Nobles in my Day as it.
Speaker 0: you know when I was younger before Amazon existed especially Sam and I'd see them and I knew that they were a fantasy series called Wheel of Time and that the books were ginormous and That made me not want to read them.
Speaker 0: like it makes me not want to read Ulysses like I saw those Piers Anthony books.
Speaker 1: I was like nope just not gonna not open in those.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean I knew people who read them and they would say things to me about them that weren't exactly.
Speaker 0: You know, they didn't say they were bad, but they wouldn't give a strong recommendation such as you must read these.
Speaker 0: Oh my god They're amazing.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be real with you guys because of that.
Speaker 0: I didn't ever bother to read them.
Speaker 1: my friends I trust and listeners and fans that I trust or at least seem intelligent and seem like worldly and well-read Basically say yeah, they're pretty good.
Speaker 1: They're okay.
Speaker 1: Or like they said they're pretty good.
Speaker 1: I really like them and they have a lot of like personal investment.
Speaker 1: But they wouldn't pretend they're like the greatest fantasy books ever.
Speaker 0: and but it turns out, you know There's a lot of people, you know nerds who have read them.
Speaker 0: people just don't discuss novels as much as they discuss other things.
Speaker 0: So but once you start talking about it It's like oh you start seeing who's read them and suddenly people have a lot to say and so far almost everyone's read them.
Speaker 0: So a lot of people not everybody by quite a lot.
Speaker 1: I bring them up in casual conversations.
Speaker 0: I remember in college Alex and Greg read them.
Speaker 0: Alex had like the hardcovers.
Speaker 0: They were Jay.
Speaker 0: No, they were even scarier looking.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like when we we all read the Prince of Nothing and basically our entire friend group would do nothing But talk about the Prince of Nothing for like a couple years.
Speaker 0: So the series goes on for many many books and then Robert Jordan sadly passed away some years ago Not too long ago, and then but unlike someone else finished the series I was like Ian M banks in the culture.
Speaker 1: He Robert Jordan basically had a protege like a person who could finish the series In a set in a way that would be satisfying and feel can.
Speaker 0: I haven't read that far obviously But I haven't heard anyone say that, you know, don't read those.
Speaker 0: They just sort of like accept those as like the real end of the series Even though there's two authors and they don't seem to have a problem with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: but we're only talking about book one today.
Speaker 0: So if you've listened to our you know Usually when we do regular Ignite episodes and we say the book club book is we sort of make some small Comments about what we read recently in that book.
Speaker 0: and You know the two main things that we pointed out in those times were number one.
Speaker 0: This is fantasy novel like.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's because the only like.
Speaker 1: I've read a lot of fantasy, but I've basically read two classes of fantasy.
Speaker 1: Three.
Speaker 1: I've read the classic like Tolkien.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well token is more the poetic kind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's about you know, it's.
Speaker 0: it's not just about the story It's also about the flowery prose and you know And the world-building and the consistency and there's a lot going on there.
Speaker 1: right I've read garbage.
Speaker 0: I haven't read as much garbage.
Speaker 0: I've read.
Speaker 0: I haven't read none, but I've read much less garbage than you.
Speaker 1: I read basically every forgotten realms book from when I was in high school and earlier Except I never read the drizz door in books because they looked really bad.
Speaker 0: Even when I was a kid the closest thing to garbage that I read was which I don't think is garbage Actually, I kind of liked it was Fred Saver Hagen series.
Speaker 0: Oh, there was like the books of swords and each book was about a different ridiculously powerful awesome sword.
Speaker 0: No that existed in this fantasy world.
Speaker 0: They never finished that series, but I really liked it.
Speaker 1: I read one six of the books I would want one Dragon Lance book and it was so garbage that I never read another one.
Speaker 1: I started reading Piers Anthony Dragons gold serpent silver chimera.
Speaker 0: That sounds like garbage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that book is like 900 bajillion pages long and it was so bad I literally more than halfway through just said you know what no and closed it and never opened it again.
Speaker 0: So the other kind of fantasy novel is like, you know, the prince of nothing kind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're actually some.
Speaker 0: it's actually, you know, real.
Speaker 0: let it quote quote real literature, right?
Speaker 0: I know it's a no true Scotsman, but you know what I'm saying?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's but it happens to be in a setting that can be considered.
Speaker 0: puts it in a fantasy section of the bookstore.
Speaker 0: There might be people with magical powers.
Speaker 0: There's some sort of map in the book.
Speaker 1: It may be based in some of those days of true people.
Speaker 0: It's a historical kind of you know.
Speaker 0: It's set in something that's like a historical earth where you know There's medieval or Roman or some Roman or medieval like society.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the difference.
Speaker 1: like a Tolkien is Here is a fantasy world and a story.
Speaker 0: It isn't particular Overarching allegory, yeah, there are swords and or sorcerers in the story like Some kind the Hobbit is about the Hobbit.
Speaker 1: Yes, and then the ring and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: The prince of nothing is about solipsism and philosophy.
Speaker 0: exactly.
Speaker 0: So the.
Speaker 1: yeah, I'm used to like super gritty Deconstructive dark like horrible fantasy and I'm used to garbage fantasy and I'm used to Tolkien and this is like Straight fantasy.
Speaker 0: it is literally like the It's.
Speaker 0: it's weird in a way in that.
Speaker 0: It's like wow, there's nothing this book is doing.
Speaker 0: that is like Different or you know like standing out in any way from what you expect fantasy to be.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's some sort of magic system that is you know, sort of mysterious.
Speaker 0: and you know, how do the world works mystery?
Speaker 0: That's in every fantasy novel ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a guy with an awesome sword who rises up from being like peasant up to Ridiculously important amazing powerful character who changes history.
Speaker 1: Yeah Bloods of ancient kings like battles from distant past.
Speaker 0: a map in the book multiple maps in the book.
Speaker 0: It's like every you know single trope that is there.
Speaker 0: that is a stereotype of fantasy novels is in this book.
Speaker 0: Everything plays out exactly as you expect, you know, there's people coming from off the map.
Speaker 0: that whoo What's what's going on over there?
Speaker 0: right, you know, it's like every single trope is there.
Speaker 1: I mean, they're everyone.
Speaker 0: every single last fantasy trope is there but they're all executed Solidly, I mean look at our party like the original party.
Speaker 1: We've got the bard who is just straight up a bard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've got the fighter paladin guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've got the wizard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who is like a mega wizard?
Speaker 0: She's got.
Speaker 0: all the wizards are mega.
Speaker 1: She's got magic items and an artifact.
Speaker 1: Sure We've got the kid with the magic sword who's also a mage with destiny.
Speaker 1: We've got dagger kid who's the thief and wolf kid.
Speaker 1: wolf kid who is a werewolf the blacksmith?
Speaker 1: Who is also an axe wielder?
Speaker 0: Yes, it's like someone made the D&D party, right?
Speaker 0: So this book doesn't have any you know, social allegories or anything like that.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have.
Speaker 0: poet has a little tiny bit of poetry, but not anywhere near Lord of the Rings level, right?
Speaker 1: If you try to treat it if you try to treat the poetry and the poetics of these books seriously That's not a good time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what you're looking for.
Speaker 0: Look elsewhere, right?
Speaker 0: And if that bothers you well, it's not enough of it in here to bother you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just like.
Speaker 0: really it's just a fantasy story.
Speaker 1: it's Competently presented not expertly written but very well and competently written.
Speaker 1: nothing bothers me about the prose or the writing, you know, it tells its story effectively.
Speaker 1: and What's really interesting to me is it reminds me actually a lot of Dumas in The sense that this the pace of the writing and the pace of things happening is pretty much the steady Never-ending slog forward.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like the.
Speaker 0: the rate of time passing as you read words Doesn't seem to change very much at all.
Speaker 0: They don't time skip anything.
Speaker 0: It's not like up three months later.
Speaker 0: That doesn't happen.
Speaker 1: It pretty much just skips sleeping and pooping.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it skips between the different groups of people as parties split up and rejoin and converge and diverge constantly.
Speaker 0: But it's sort of it just it's like okay.
Speaker 0: Here's what these people did this day.
Speaker 0: Here's what these people did this day next day.
Speaker 0: Here's what these people did and it describes, you know It goes into great detail about individual about small things like.
Speaker 0: they'll go into say A stable and it'll take the time to like list all the horses that are in the stable and describe them.
Speaker 1: and It's the way D&D like Dungeon Master Notes about the story go right.
Speaker 0: every single in it takes care to mention the name of the inn.
Speaker 0: What logo is on the sign of the inn?
Speaker 0: you enter the common room every single in that he enters.
Speaker 0: they describe who's in the?
Speaker 0: Common room, you know how big it is.
Speaker 0: Who's the innkeeper?
Speaker 0: I've read like 20 different inns already.
Speaker 1: They're all distinct and you kind of like we were talking about.
Speaker 0: they all matter, right?
Speaker 1: Like when they when the kids get to bear lot who's performing in the inn?
Speaker 0: if anyone what kind of people are?
Speaker 0: is it a?
Speaker 0: Drunken in a partying in
Speaker 1: they went to the bed
Speaker 0: There'll be hold there'll be like Pages where they go around town looking at all the inns to pick one to sleep in but
Speaker 1: then they end up sleeping in the one With the innkeeper tries to murder them and rob them.
Speaker 0: right, you know, but that's how it goes.
Speaker 1: Yeah But also but they accept.
Speaker 1: there's what I noticed I was flipping back through at the end of the last book.
Speaker 1: The one area where this actually fails is kind of a flaw in the books is that when there are intense action scenes, sometimes they're written that same way and A few times like the last few battles in the first book They're written so abstractly that you can't actually follow what happened.
Speaker 1: I agree with that like Flames from the sword and the check clashing of the whatever and it just sort of Describes a bunch of verbs and nouns in a row and then the battles.
Speaker 0: it felt a lot like a try gun manga battle scene.
Speaker 1: It was the opposite of and then they stepped into the circle inscribed by his sword.
Speaker 1: Yes, exactly That's some prints of nothing right there, right?
Speaker 0: But but other than that it kind of I think part of that's intentional too, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz that I mean I can tell you the battle scenes like the second book very similar You know, you don't really figure out exactly what's going on and in sort I think they don't want you to know a hundred percent exactly what's going on in a literal end of Evangelion kind of partly
Speaker 1: because then like fantasy combat doesn't really work because people get in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you made a movie you could you could do, you know actually cool action scenes But that's not what this is about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the combat that like the fights in the book It's like they just they sort of just describe it enough that they can lead you into the consequences of the battle happening.
Speaker 1: Which is the important part, you know it reads like a D&D combat encounter like they were fighting and he was fighting with him and she was fighting with him and Then it was over and the sidewalk this guy got stabbed.
Speaker 0: He's wounded.
Speaker 0: that guy, you know disappeared that one's dead.
Speaker 0: You know that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: They're also.
Speaker 1: it's a very Unsurprising and unchallenging book which might just be because we're old and jaded and we've read a lot of books and seen a lot for being so big.
Speaker 1: I read this really fast and Literally, nothing comes as a surprise everything whatsoever.
Speaker 1: everything is foreshadowed adequately and obviously Like you see the check-offs gone.
Speaker 0: it fires the check-offs gun.
Speaker 0: it fires the check-ups gun.
Speaker 0: It holds on another check-ups Gum comes out and fires in the first check.
Speaker 1: I'm going fires and the ones that don't fire fire immediately in the next book Like a fire later, but and it does this throw a little man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know I mean we only talking about book one.
Speaker 0: But let me tell you book two the first chapter of book two might as well could easily be.
Speaker 0: It's exactly the next chapter.
Speaker 0: after you end a book one You can just stick all these books together because I'm in book three now.
Speaker 0: I can tell you it happened twice so far.
Speaker 0: you could just put the book side by side and cut them anywhere you like To separate the books and it wouldn't really make a big difference.
Speaker 0: the only I think the only reason they chose like those spots to end one book and start another.
Speaker 0: because it's like after the culmination and Denoma epilogue after one of the more major battle at a conflict resolution parts That's when they cut the book off and start the next one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then it builds up and then there's the next major battle with the big bad guy.
Speaker 1: But like you learn about the ice today.
Speaker 1: and then as said I yeah I think I don't know how to say it.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it's ice.
Speaker 0: I don't know how to pronounce anything But my brain my brain is always says as said I took my brain a minute to read a guinea and not just say Mine says a Gwen in my brain.
Speaker 1: It's a guinea.
Speaker 0: I think who knows?
Speaker 0: How about how?
Speaker 0: about Neneve?
Speaker 0: At least Elaine is easy.
Speaker 0: Yeah It could be wrong.
Speaker 1: It's Rand.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: I hope it's Rand.
Speaker 1: better be random.
Speaker 1: It's Ron.
Speaker 1: I hope he dies.
Speaker 1: So Ruby Ron I Can watch that movie again.
Speaker 1: sure I Did not like any of those boys for three quarters.
Speaker 1: that book Rand was okay But he was a little Shinji, but Matt just they're all kind of Shinji.
Speaker 0: Rand is the motion G But he is bad wasn't that Shinji?
Speaker 1: Matt was just stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like Matt was the dumb one Matt almost got them killed so many times.
Speaker 1: I expected him to die expected him and parent to both.
Speaker 0: I think I think part of the reason there is that way is because they want to show you them like how quickly they grew Up, and they're constantly doing things like wow just like a year ago.
Speaker 0: They were in.
Speaker 0: yeah, you know they were in their peasants.
Speaker 0: They're being stupid.
Speaker 0: And it does work.
Speaker 1: cuz like in the second book you start to read or even the end of the first book and they're like Kind of competent adventurers, and then you're ridiculously confident in book three like not many chapters back like in book three.
Speaker 0: They're powerful you know leveled up dudes, but like it mentioned everybody every character.
Speaker 1: you learn about the ice today And it mentions later like well What if you met a whatever aja and then you learn about there's colors of aja?
Speaker 1: And you start.
Speaker 0: I thought at first I thought the red aja was like a person and that some of the a said I followed The red aja, but yup, it's like.
Speaker 0: no They're just in a group called the red.
Speaker 1: that is a trope of fantasy books.
Speaker 1: use a proper noun in context without explanation Yeah, then later use it in context again to clarify what type of thing it is.
Speaker 1: then later Reveal one of them.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: later you learn like what one of them is But there's still a lot of mysteries.
Speaker 1: the second you know that's at the end of the first book.
Speaker 1: There's no more explanation for that.
Speaker 1: immediately the second book.
Speaker 1: It's like it goes through this whole Build up, and then it just tells you what color a bunch of the characters are wearing and then you're like oh
Speaker 0: Yeah Another trope this book has is a thing will happen right and you the reader will learn an important piece of information and so will Some character right will learn that same information and then for many chapters You see what happens as that information does or does not spread to other characters.
Speaker 0: Yeah Which is actually cool because you and then that in books and then another thing Happens or another thing is learned.
Speaker 0: So it's like all that time all those pages are really taken up by other characters learning After you've learned something and the effects of that and then that somehow You know sort of dragging everyone into the next happening which creates more learning and more information coming out and then Process repeats itself over and over.
Speaker 0: like at one point there were like I think like the beginning of book three.
Speaker 0: It's like all the chapters are like everyone learning what happened at the end of book two and even now I just the chapter.
Speaker 0: I just read it was a Character was introduced somewhere in the middle of book three and they just learned what happened at the end of book two and it's like oops Someone slipped.
Speaker 1: now that would be really annoying except it kind of works because like you pointed out It doesn't retell the story like a lot of bad authors would do.
Speaker 1: instead It just focuses on the reaction and the consequences of that person learning that thing.
Speaker 1: Yep But at the same time because if we're talking about the first book here.
Speaker 1: Fucking Rand and Matt and Perrin would all independently learn really important stuff and not tell anyone.
Speaker 0: and up in book one There's a lot more not telling.
Speaker 0: because Matt the not telling enables these slower spreading of the information and the World is after you and the winner is in your dream and this wizard is protecting you and the Wizard about it.
Speaker 1: the Wizards protecting you specifically said Repeatedly if you have any weird dreams tell me it's what they don't and they don't trust her either.
Speaker 1: But then they won't.
Speaker 1: then they tell the bard and the barge like trust the bard?
Speaker 1: No They don't.
Speaker 0: only later because they're forced to because they trust the bard way more than the wizard.
Speaker 1: well toward the end Pretty sure he's not dead.
Speaker 0: No, he's not of course not Pretty much.
Speaker 0: I mean like Characters don't die.
Speaker 0: main characters don't seem to die easily and that way they can keep going away and coming back, right?
Speaker 0: And so far I don't think any major characters like been completely Removed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can't.
Speaker 0: I mean like even characters that are minor characters.
Speaker 0: It's like they bother to name someone you they're coming back like that captain of that ship.
Speaker 0: Oh, I like him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the pirate guy.
Speaker 0: He's a character.
Speaker 0: He's real.
Speaker 0: He comes.
Speaker 0: He's not a major character Obviously, but you know, he was a mid to minor character in the book.
Speaker 0: And yeah, you see him again.
Speaker 0: I are when light it makes you and the thing is.
Speaker 0: then later on You see other characters who are similarly minor and you have to assume while they're gonna come back again, aren't they?
Speaker 0: It's like yeah They probably will our place.
Speaker 1: are they gonna be like in book?
Speaker 1: 7 like go back to Berlon and stay at one of those ends again.
Speaker 0: There's only so much map to cover.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're gonna have to.
Speaker 0: you know, they can go off the map a little bit I assume.
Speaker 0: but yeah so much you can do.
Speaker 1: but like the like So many these little pieces like that like things are mentioned offhand and they seem to always come in at some point.
Speaker 1: Like if you if it mentions a place you're like, I wonder what's going on over there.
Speaker 1: Well something comes out of there soon enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah very much sooner than you expect right, you know Usually the things that are off the edge of the map in most fantasy series like our hawk wings all legendary armies that went over the sea.
Speaker 0: It's like they take a long time for those things to like.
Speaker 0: you've got to be in a later book to get to that.
Speaker 0: the Serious shit.
Speaker 0: It's like no it comes pretty quickly.
Speaker 0: It's like it escalates more rapidly than you would think for having so many pages and moving at a steady pace.
Speaker 0: Another thing it has a trope in this book that bothers me because I was hoping this would be the one to break that trope.
Speaker 0: That is I've talked about this before many times.
Speaker 1: You just want to read the stupid Silmarillion.
Speaker 1: Those stories are terrible.
Speaker 0: I've read Silmarillion, but someone is not exactly what I want, but there's a chapter early in the book where Moraine talks about the great king and the great hawk wing and all that.
Speaker 0: No, not archer hawk wing, but manetho.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay, right.
Speaker 1: She's obviously in Iran.
Speaker 0: she talks about basically these are peasants who live in a place called the two rivers and The two rivers used to be man of Theron.
Speaker 0: and she talks about what man of Theron was and it was basically the fucking Awesomest Kingdom with the baddest ass kings and the baddest ask.
Speaker 1: we really want to read that.
Speaker 0: Baddest ass heroes like Agamemnon and Achilles.
Speaker 0: level of awesomeness right like the baddest asses of the bravest and the goodest and So good, and that's what you want to read and I don't get to know.
Speaker 0: all I get is one chapter about those guys and then Vague hints.
Speaker 0: It's like why I want to read the book where the badass king of man of Theron is the main character of the book.
Speaker 0: You know and then the end of the book can be because clearly man of Theron is not there anymore, right?
Speaker 0: The end of the book is the fall of man of Theron and it has a bad ending.
Speaker 0: bad guy wins the end.
Speaker 0: That's the book.
Speaker 1: I want to read okay, and Like get up in your fanfiction Right the wheel of time book zero.
Speaker 0: There is a wheel of time book zero.
Speaker 0: I have to figure out where in this.
Speaker 0: I have to figure out when it was published so I know when to read it.
Speaker 1: God, damn it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm just gonna keep reading them in order based on whatever.
Speaker 1: like Amazon says I'm not even gonna Scroll down to see the.
Speaker 0: All the books are spoilers for Obvious Chekhov's guns.
Speaker 1: I mean the dragon reborn chapter 3.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, they're talking about New.
Speaker 0: so book zero is new.
Speaker 0: spring right which tells you nothing and it was published when I got.
Speaker 1: there's 14 of these things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: So 2000 it was published in January 2004.
Speaker 0: I have a rule.
Speaker 0: scroll down.
Speaker 1: I'm saying I have a rule that solves this the rule that I have followed because it worked with the Horatio.
Speaker 1: books go down.
Speaker 1: I always have books in order of publication.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So after book 10 read book zero.
Speaker 0: then read 11 12 13 14.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: So what do you write?
Speaker 0: 679 10 0 11 12 13 14?
Speaker 0: That's the order.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's only set 20 years before the events of the first novel.
Speaker 0: Oh, so it's not gonna tell me about the Great King of Man of Therin.
Speaker 1: No, that was.
Speaker 0: but it will tell me about Rand's dad maybe Tim Tam and we'll figure out what Rand's.
Speaker 0: you know That kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah with his hair and blade Yeah, where that hair and his Outlander wife, yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah deals.
Speaker 1: it's almost like Just.
Speaker 1: it is really amazing how and I keep saying this unsurprising these books are.
Speaker 1: they follow a thread that is so Directly blazed through a plot that is so obvious.
Speaker 1: and yet at the same time you guys want to keep reading.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you poke it around like alright, these guys are coming.
Speaker 0: I wonder what their deal and it's the way the thing is.
Speaker 0: I think the reason it seems so obvious is that they tell you the reader Something right and they tell it to you in such a way that you being smart a reader Right.
Speaker 0: You don't need to be that smart.
Speaker 0: you get that information and you know it.
Speaker 0: you're like, I know this fact now, but They wrote it in such a way that it leaves a little bit of doubt in your mind Even though it was so obviously just told to you.
Speaker 0: and then later They tell you that same fact again in a way that a hundred percent confirms that the thing you thought was right to begin with.
Speaker 0: They never do the opposite.
Speaker 0: Maybe they will later on like at the end who knows.
Speaker 0: so basically confirming the thing they hinted at being true is indeed true.
Speaker 0: You're suspicious.
Speaker 0: 99% confidence level is actually 100% confidence level.
Speaker 0: So it makes it seem as if it was obvious when really it's like.
Speaker 0: no You were supposed to be the first time.
Speaker 0: they told you a hundred percent sure.
Speaker 1: Well, here's an example of how that all plays together everything we said.
Speaker 1: So there's a point early on where Maureen I think is the one who explains to other people That a woman who has the ability to use magic if she isn't found by the eyes today and trained she'll get these sicknesses Mm-hmm, and then she'll be fine.
Speaker 0: And then as soon as she says that you're like, well all these main character girls are magical.
Speaker 0: Yep, you just know it immediately like I bet that yeah, they're probably on that.
Speaker 0: and then yes, they are.
Speaker 1: but then Well later, uh Iguana is like fuck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll be a wizard.
Speaker 1: fuck this nonsense to River's bull.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I like her.
Speaker 1: Yeah Meanwhile the wisdom In a minute is like I'm not no wizard fuck wizards.
Speaker 1: But then when she learns about the sickness thing, she's like I got sick as a kill.
Speaker 1: Fuck.
Speaker 1: Fuck me.
Speaker 1: Oh, no But then later you get a flashback where Matt is like, yeah ran got really sick while we were traveling.
Speaker 1: It was kind of weird.
Speaker 1: now that came out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: And of course Randy's the dragon reborn Of course as the per the title of book three and all the foreshadowing of book one.
Speaker 0: But who do you think is a dragon reborn?
Speaker 0: Hmm Rand?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like oh, there's a cat There's someone named.
Speaker 0: I mean That's actually the bet.
Speaker 0: the one thing that's another thing this book does that I love is chapter one and actually the same chapter one that the prince of nothing has.
Speaker 0: It's that chapter one of Not the main characters.
Speaker 0: another time another place Something else right.
Speaker 0: and the chapter one of this book is lose Theron the real dragon, right?
Speaker 0: Definitely the dragon.
Speaker 1: Yep in his end insanity, right?
Speaker 0: He's called lose Theron kinslayer.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: well because after he you know, basically the murdered everyone he'd ever known.
Speaker 0: So if you if you if you didn't yeah, this is all in book one if you didn't read book one What the fuck you doing?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: so lose Theron.
Speaker 0: He's the dragon, right?
Speaker 0: He's a ridiculously powerful magical dude, right and he's the awesomest most powerful dude.
Speaker 0: and the bad guy Chetan, oh, I shouldn't say his name.
Speaker 0: Yeah Book two One time and shit goes down like immediately Balsam on the bad guy Satan right the dark.
Speaker 1: Yeah, literally based on Satan like go read.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's the bad guy Right.
Speaker 0: he and all the other magical dudes and ladies of that time the eight in right of his age They beat the bad guy and in so doing so imprisoned him in the mountain of doom the stereotypical mountain of doom Right, which is called shale ghoul or whatever all the bad guys.
Speaker 0: It's Mountain Doom.
Speaker 1: Come on It's all go got her off.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It's the bad place.
Speaker 0: You know, it's it's always named doom.
Speaker 0: They imprisoned him there and in doing so right they sealed him up.
Speaker 0: They couldn't kill him.
Speaker 0: they sealed him up in this mountain and that was like a plus move, but The bad guys last move his last move before being imprisoned is the backstroke of the West in one sense.
Speaker 1: Yes the backstroke Well, they call it a backstroke like four times.
Speaker 0: Sure He breaks is the breaking of the world right in where people they paint half of the the gendered magic Which the magic is gendered into the male half and the female half.
Speaker 0: so the bad guy Poisons.
Speaker 0: he basically puts his icky darkness all over.
Speaker 0: the man half of the magic.
Speaker 1: So now the touch the man half.
Speaker 1: to touch it you have to go through all of his bad guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you have to like.
Speaker 0: there's like a film of nasty oil on This pool of man magic.
Speaker 0: the lady magic is fine.
Speaker 0: If you try to use the man magic you have to sort of go through the icky muck that's floating on top.
Speaker 0: But and it slowly drives you insane and bad and whatnot.
Speaker 0: So all these magic dudes including lose Theron kin slayer the awesome You know dragon go insane and ruin the world and destroy all the kingdoms and fuck everything up.
Speaker 0: And that's why he's kin slayer because he killed all of his kin.
Speaker 1: Yeah chapter one and the whole book is all this precursor stuff of like the angry like.
Speaker 1: yeah This is just something we could just make all the time.
Speaker 0: so much Mysterious precursor shit from the age of legends which I think is even older than like mana Theron and lose Theron and all that It's like in a lock Lamora.
Speaker 1: like what's that crystal thing?
Speaker 0: Same same deal.
Speaker 0: There's some precursor stuff from people who are even better than the people were dealing.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 1: there's the place They mentioned like it's a cool place then match like why don't we go fucking loot it and the guys like Anyone who goes anywhere near there just suddenly dies.
Speaker 1: No one knows why.
Speaker 0: don't do that.
Speaker 1: I Feel like that place is gonna come up at some point though.
Speaker 1: Every other place comes up at some point.
Speaker 0: Yep there's also a lot of like shit.
Speaker 1: our leg off seems to be almost as dangerous as the bad bad and It's a different bad.
Speaker 1: What was that?
Speaker 1: That was the.
Speaker 1: that was the evil that man-made themselves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's also like the ways.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah with the the black wind, but it's when I think about the first book like unlike other fantasy books It's like they'll have like a few of those tropes and then their main story.
Speaker 1: This book is just everything.
Speaker 1: just everything's crammed into there.
Speaker 1: The ways would be like a big deal in any other Fanny series here.
Speaker 1: They just go in there once.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 0: it's such.
Speaker 0: it's like they just fill the fantasy world with every single fantasy thing.
Speaker 0: It's like he's got the heron blade Right and you think that's the Excalibur.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, it is.
Speaker 0: It is like the Excalibur.
Speaker 0: There's also Kalindor, which is the other.
Speaker 0: it's like the other Excalibur.
Speaker 0: It's like they're just magic shit Just coming the fuck out of everything.
Speaker 0: It's like every single place has some crazy shit going that's dagger could destroy the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's like every time you think that like, okay, we're just gonna resolve the stuff We have.
Speaker 0: they bring in more.
Speaker 0: It's like up new character new kind of bad Book one.
Speaker 1: they find the fucking horn and everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that was that's kind of crazy, right?
Speaker 1: They talk so much about this horn the seal and everything and then okay green man's dead found the horn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just like this is book one and there's like this legendary horn.
Speaker 0: the horn is actually way awesome.
Speaker 0: I love the horns like the horn in Ultima, right?
Speaker 0: It's like this is it's a horn?
Speaker 0: So just like a brass horn like it, you know It's a it's you know.
Speaker 0: They say you blow in one end it goes in a circle and then and then all the dead heroes of all past ages come To fight for you, right?
Speaker 0: so you blow the horn and like the ghost of Artur Hawkwing and like all the legends of legends just show up and Fight for you much like Lord of the Rings.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's already a deal with the ghost to come and fight for him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they'll follow whoever blows the horn and there's also some debate.
Speaker 0: and Lord of the Rings They'll follow whoever has a Narsil the sword of the king.
Speaker 1: of course hither - there's also some debate as to what the blowing the horn actually specifically does.
Speaker 0: The horn does very specifically because you know what spoilers that horn getting blown.
Speaker 0: Yo, they don't Fuck.
Speaker 0: three.
Speaker 0: I'm not telling you but The book does not hold back cuz I'm a little pissed off.
Speaker 1: in book two They just put it in the closet like they just put it in like a normal closet like good job guys.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, they can't let anyone know.
Speaker 0: Remember the people from Italy everyone else do.
Speaker 0: a great hunt from the horn has begun.
Speaker 0: There are people going all over the place looking for the horn the Amarillo new Iglemar knew they knew you can't.
Speaker 0: you can't blow it thinking of glory or sell a salvation.
Speaker 0: You have to blow it thinking of Only salvation.
Speaker 0: right only salvation not glory.
Speaker 0: blow it thinking of glory.
Speaker 1: It's bad news You know, I also noticed there's a few points where Maureen specifically hides information from land because it might make him feel bad.
Speaker 0: Remember as said I always have to tell the truth So she doesn't see.
Speaker 0: basically just avoid saying things and I every time and as said I talks You have to read it like you're fucking giving a wish to a genie to make you know, cuz like they can't lie.
Speaker 0: So, you know, they're telling the truth.
Speaker 0: You got to make sure like, okay, so Is that actually true?
Speaker 0: You know, where's the other people?
Speaker 0: you don't have to examine what they're saying nearly as much.
Speaker 0: But as said I has dialogue.
Speaker 0: It's like well fuck me after read this like half as fast just to make sure cuz I know they're not lying.
Speaker 0: So they're probably weaseling or neglecting to say certain things.
Speaker 1: So The fact that the magic is gendered and that is like a core part of this world Doesn't bother me enough to make a deal about it?
Speaker 0: I don't think it's.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't think you can accuse these books of being sexist.
Speaker 1: No, actually because it passes the Bechdel test like all the not only does it pass the Bechdel test But it hits the Bechdel test out of the park.
Speaker 0: The ladies are like mad powerful and they take care of their own shit and they're They're not just as main characters.
Speaker 0: If not more main characters than you know, it is.
Speaker 0: they're Tevarin yeah, and in fact because the The dude magic is poisoned pretty much all the powerful people are ladies and they're doing all the important shit.
Speaker 0: But then not all the powerful ladies are wizards like there's very few awesome dudes and they're kind of lame.
Speaker 1: But it's definitely like.
Speaker 1: there's definitely a feminist female empowerment like aspect of these books which I like and It's just pretty you know egalitarian.
Speaker 0: like there's strong and weak people of all genders.
Speaker 1: But it focuses a lot fantasy races like in the early chapters on heavily balancing and making it clear that like the women's circle is Actually just as powerful as the town count.
Speaker 1: It's more powerful than That's what the impression you get.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I guess I'd say that it has strong female Protagonists that are not strong female protagonists.
Speaker 0: Actually, they're not proper noun strong female.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's actually no protectionist There's just this protagonist of every kind of shape and size.
Speaker 0: Yeah You know.
Speaker 0: The one one thing though is that and it comes to bad guys.
Speaker 0: There seems to be I am even there seems Yes, but there seems to be one female bad guy at least one In of the extremely powerful ones, yeah that are legendary.
Speaker 0: there's like one is the token woman bad guy And then the rest are all dudes.
Speaker 1: I have a worrying Prediction about that one because it's outside of the first book and I can't necessarily like I don't want to spoil anything.
Speaker 0: Yes, it's exactly what you think because like I said before yeah, if you're 90% sure about something you should be a hundred.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sure about it.
Speaker 1: Yes, it worries me that that is going to be that characters like Ideal or core and I worry it'll be a tiny bit problematic.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, I'll mention after the show sure cuz you know, that's I learn about.
Speaker 0: you learn about that shit in like the middle of Book two right anyway, but yet so, you know book one for you know Something that started out as peasants right at the end of but you think it's gonna take a long time before the epic shit.
Speaker 1: No, they're like seventh eighth level D&D characters.
Speaker 0: But like at the end of book one just somehow With despite having the steady pacing they managed to get from.
Speaker 0: it's like when they're when the party gets split and they're trying to Cross the world from west to east.
Speaker 0: it's like that part sort of feels like it's right.
Speaker 0: and then before you know it It's like they're up fighting the big bad guy up at like the edge of the world.
Speaker 0: We're like the trial, you know at the wall.
Speaker 0: You know the stereotypical like l5r wall where the bad guys are on the other side and they marched through the gate and they go Into the.
Speaker 0: you know the evil, you know waste of the world of lights And they find the magic horn and shit and like the green man is there and everything.
Speaker 0: and it's like, whoa They really got to the super powerful shit right away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then book two just keeps going up.
Speaker 1: It's just an upward slant.
Speaker 0: It does not stop.
Speaker 1: They're gonna be 20th level by like the fourth book.
Speaker 1: I'd bet maybe a third.
Speaker 1: It goes way faster than you but what epic they Epic level like so fast.
Speaker 0: I don't even know what's gonna have.
Speaker 0: I can't even imagine how epic he gets a book five six seven.
Speaker 1: at the end One punch man comes down.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's basically one punch man versus one punch man.
Speaker 1: already as far as I can tell If nothing else what I can say is I'm digging these books enough to keep reading.
Speaker 0: I mean if you're a nerd you're gonna like fantasy novel and this has.
Speaker 0: there's a reason you like fantasy novel is because of those Tropes, it's like when you come across one that doesn't follow the tropes that like it stands out as being unique and whatever.
Speaker 0: but how often do you see one that has all the tropes and It just executes them all solidly and it just you have so much, you know, it's like it just never runs out.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, here's more of that thing that you like.
Speaker 0: We already know you like.
Speaker 0: why would you why would we mess with it?
Speaker 0: We know it's the thing you like.
Speaker 0: Here's more of it.
Speaker 0: here have some more perfectly serviceable delicious steak.
Speaker 0: Yes Oh, you want some more steak?
Speaker 0: Well good.
Speaker 0: There are 20 more giant books just like it.
Speaker 1: so like if Lord of the Rings is like the fancy expensive restaurant that you just go to occasionally because it is like super good and Prince of nothing is like the weird place that you kind of like.
Speaker 1: but you don't either that the foreign food with like The food's weird.
Speaker 1: It makes you sick sometimes.
Speaker 1: Sure And Forgotten realms is McDonald's.
Speaker 1: Yes, then these books are like Chipotle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is a little better than Chipotle Chipotle with the eso Fritas.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like it's not quite cafe Maya.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, you know, it's like you eat there a few times a week and it's totally serviceable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: yeah, do I want to eat there?
Speaker 0: Yes, I would like to eat there.
Speaker 0: Would I say it is my favorite restaurant?
Speaker 0: No, is it the restaurant I go to most?
Speaker 0: No, but I go there a lot.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz there's a lot of words a lot of pages.
Speaker 1: Yeah And how many lunches do you eat?
Speaker 1: You only you can only stray so far from your office in New York.
Speaker 0: So I think the lesson to learn here is when you see something I mean, I've learned this lesson already, which is why I made this which is why I made this decision, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I keep hearing about this thing called fist of the North Star.
Speaker 0: I should probably go and see what that is, huh?
Speaker 0: So this wheel of time thing that is a thing I know about as a nerd But I've never read it or looked into it in any way whatsoever?
Speaker 0: Maybe you should.
Speaker 0: is there's a nerdy thing you've heard of right?
Speaker 0: Like I saw I've met some people like it packs.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, I've never played any Castlevania's.
Speaker 0: it's like you've heard of it though.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe you should check that the fuck out.
Speaker 0: So think about the nerdy things that are out there that are popular among nerds.
Speaker 0: You know that you know exist but haven't checked out.
Speaker 0: and make a list and check them all the fuck out in order Like if you'd help it.
Speaker 0: if you need help putting them in order ask me and I'll put them in order for like.
Speaker 1: I don't Like Game of Thrones.
Speaker 0: No, I don't.
Speaker 0: I checked it out.
Speaker 0: I did check it out.
Speaker 1: I know it's deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like Evangelion a lot of you hate Evangelion.
Speaker 1: You're wrong, but that's a fine opinion to have.
Speaker 0: but some of you know, even jellying is a thing and you haven't checked it.
Speaker 0: But at least check it.
Speaker 0: check it.
Speaker 0: people here about it.
Speaker 1: I mean we Evangelion's not as old as the wheel.
Speaker 1: It's well depending will the time started being written.
Speaker 0: what like 84 90s I think came out in the 90s?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if you're a nerd check all the nerd things.
Speaker 0: and because you know They're probably good and nerds will like them like you and if they're bad then you can know bad.
Speaker 0: You could have stopped a middle way through this book.
Speaker 0: It was awful.
Speaker 1: Well, we had to finish it for the book club, but I wouldn't have read the second book.
Speaker 1: No And if something's really really bad and all the nerds like it Well now you can call him out on it cuz you've read it, you know Isn't that the best thing?
Speaker 0: when you say all you nerds what's that garbage you're all watching?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like that Anna Twitter discussion the other day about code gears where they're all like, yeah, that show is really shit guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah guys.
Speaker 0: or just now and we said yeah, you people game of Thrones is garbage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, it's not garbage.
Speaker 0: Just I don't know I'm not it's so.
Speaker 0: it's basically like because it's not really.
Speaker 0: it has dragons and stuff, but it's not fantasy novel It's like but also it just happens to be in a medieval ish setting which
Speaker 1: is it's gritty political Philosophical deep-feeling fantasy for people who've never read the prince of nothing or anything like that Maybe like they've never encountered challenging fantasy before.
Speaker 1: so they see Game of Thrones like who.
Speaker 1: this is the adult stuff.
Speaker 1: None of that.
Speaker 0: Tell them about Game of Thrones the same way.
Speaker 0: I feel about Star Trek where it's actually a different thing.
Speaker 0: It's like it.
Speaker 0: look, you know Game of Thrones looks like fantasy and Star Trek, you know Looks like sci-fi cuz in space.
Speaker 0: but Star Trek is actually just like a soap opera like days of our lives But it happens to be wearing spacesuits in a spaceship.
Speaker 1: So nerds like I'd say tea tea the originally OS the original series is More like actual sci-fi.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, it's more like Flash Gordon style But yeah, but I mean, you know the ones that are more recent are they see I could write.
Speaker 0: whereas Game of Thrones It's like okay It looks like a fantasy novel because they have swords and dragons and shit, but that's not what it is at all, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's not.
Speaker 0: it's more like Sopranos.
Speaker 0: It just happens to have you know Swords and so I hate to say this.
Speaker 1: The writing like the act like the mechanical aspects of the writing like the diction the grammar the word choice all that stuff.
Speaker 1: It's a little bit better than a Rothfuss but not that much better.
Speaker 0: which book Patrick Rothfuss, no, I mean which one are you saying is better but not that much better.
Speaker 1: I think Wheel of Time is a little bit better.
Speaker 1: Okay, but not that much.
Speaker 0: I thought you might as well have a game of thrones.
Speaker 1: I think they're both written at about the same level of like Execution in terms of writing writing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's serviceable.
Speaker 0: The content is again.
Speaker 0: It gets it done.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like, you know, I love like.
Speaker 0: if I had to grade that aspect, I'd be like BV - yeah Like one full step above Hunger Games.
Speaker 1: and even then Hunger Games definitely more better than I said one full step There aren't that many steps.
Speaker 0: but Even then like that kind of writing was serviceable because the story I think the thing it really lacks is You know, there's only a few like sayings that you can cling to.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we quote the prince of nothing.
Speaker 0: Where's your prince of nothing?
Speaker 0: You can like a trackless step shortest path.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: Whereas in Wheel of Time is like what about the glitters?
Speaker 1: is like everything.
Speaker 1: So you like you quote Lord of the Rings you quote prince of nothing.
Speaker 1: You don't quote Forgotten Realms.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't quote the Wheel of Time.
Speaker 0: no, it's not too much quoting to be done.
Speaker 1: And and honestly like it doesn't come up that often but when there is prose and poetry and prophecy in the Wheel of Time.
Speaker 0: It's I know not great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like there's a lot of songs people sing.
Speaker 0: I they keep going on and on about how in every town They're all singing the same songs with different words and different names.
Speaker 0: So something horrible happened and when I read those lyrics to some of the songs I can't put them to a tune at all.
Speaker 1: I can put them to tunes because of the diction.
Speaker 1: Like one of the songs they keep singing is doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 1: that song, you know, that's.
Speaker 1: oh, it's okay That song over.
Speaker 1: It's all folk songs.
Speaker 1: Like I guess just for music theory.
Speaker 1: Like I picked those things out, but You're better off not being able to put them to tunes like for real.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at least the Lord of the Rings like you read those books and those songs are Memorable and good.
Speaker 0: It's also kind of annoying sometimes when they repeat things like that.
Speaker 0: It's like yes We know that in every town they sing the same songs with different lyrics and the songs go by different names.
Speaker 0: You don't need to keep saying we get every Kids every in that you go to.
Speaker 1: we don't need kids and you're seeing the wide world for the first time.
Speaker 1: And oh these people seem just like us even in book three.
Speaker 0: They went to an inn and there was a lady singing in the end and they pointed out like oh It was a song he knew but it went by.
Speaker 0: Dude, I don't know what song it was.
Speaker 0: But even in book three, they still going on about this the wind runs through the willows.
Speaker 0: That's the one.
Speaker 0: yes, I think that's the number one song.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a few more that Don't dig deep.
Speaker 0: I'm not digging anywhere in those territories.
Speaker 0: Alright, I think that's the wheels of times to go round and round in the willows.
Speaker 1: I Will pick a book club book after my trip because I'm pretty much gonna keep reading the wheel of time during my trip Hmm.
Speaker 1: So also I got to think about what book I want to pick.
Speaker 1: I got a few ideas, but I want to consider.
Speaker 1: I want to see if maybe there's a hot new book I'm ignoring instead of going to something old.
Speaker 0: try to pick have a reason for picking like I did.
Speaker 1: Oh, I always have a reason like a very specific for everything.
Speaker 0: I think I like that one.
Speaker 0: There's a pretty cover.
Speaker 1: a Cover could convince me if it was good enough.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.