Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, June 9th, 2015.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I am the Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is The Geek Knights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we're talking about The Time Crisis 5.
Speaker 0: Mm-mm-mm.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: You best watch yourselves, 'cause I have a new toy.
Speaker 1: I have a teleprompter.
Speaker 1: - Okay.
Speaker 1: - And I'm gonna make use of it.
Speaker 0: Alright, you do that.
Speaker 1: I remember way back when I made that Five Nights at Freddy's, like, why this game is scary, like, video essay.
Speaker 1: It was a real pain in the ass to make that thing, because it's not like a lecture where Scott and I just talk, you know, to an audience, and then the video is just of that event.
Speaker 1: This is more like, I need, there's a bunch of things I need to say, and then I need to interleave that together with a whole bunch of video of, like, gameplay and things.
Speaker 1: So I needed, like, all these art assets together, and then I can make the thing.
Speaker 1: Which meant I had to write a script, or else I'd have to have a video thing set up and wear the same shirt, or have the same shirt and lighting and everything available, like, every day for weeks.
Speaker 1: So I had to, like, write this stupid script, and set this giant thing up, and then sit there for, like, an hour, saying all my things.
Speaker 1: If I'd had a teleprompter, that would have been a lot faster.
Speaker 1: I am not good at memorizing paragraphs of text, and then saying them into a camera.
Speaker 0: So, just ad lib it.
Speaker 0: What do you need to read the exact text for?
Speaker 1: I didn't even really read the exact text so much, but I had to make sure I said all the things, and the more I had to, like, go back and look at, you know, what points do I have to make, and did I say them all?
Speaker 1: Because if I miss a point, and I stop doing the video, I'm fucked, and I gotta go back and do this video over again.
Speaker 0: Just say all the things one at a time and edit the video.
Speaker 1: No, it took me weeks to edit that video.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna leave the video shit set up to video myself for weeks.
Speaker 1: Ideally, you have all the video done.
Speaker 0: The other part is all the parts in the video, see, what you do is you say each thing one at a time, right?
Speaker 0: And obviously, if you just cut those things together, right back to back, it's gonna look funny when you obviously cut.
Speaker 1: Oh no, I did that, believe me.
Speaker 1: Every time I cut...
Speaker 0: You switch between you, voiceover, you, voiceover, you, voiceover, you, voiceover.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: Every time I cut... That's the secret.
Speaker 1: But I did need video in my face.
Speaker 0: Now that you know that trick, and you watch people's videos on YouTube, you won't be able to unsee that trick.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: However, the funniest thing is, I've seen some cut points on our panels where, like, I change camera angle or something, but we just look like we did a cut, because, like, you move your head really funny suddenly, when really we didn't, so...
Speaker 0: You're supposed to edit those parts out to make them voiceover, so it doesn't look like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But no, the teleprompter will be useful generally for, like, more complicated projects that we want to do, so stay tuned for more complicated projects.
Speaker 0: It's good for when you've written something for someone else to say, and they just read it.
Speaker 0: Their only job is to appear on screen.
Speaker 1: It's also good when you're doing...
Speaker 0: "Hey, I'm hiring you to be in this commercial for me, pretty person.
Speaker 0: You know, you are beautiful on the camera.
Speaker 0: Read
Speaker 0: this.".
Speaker 1: It's also good for, like, if we were doing... Like, we have to do a Patreon video, so if we're making, like, a video that is just us saying our very specific thing with a very specific time limit, and we want it to be all one take.
Speaker 0: It's also good for mass production of video, like, make a thank you video for these hundred people.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Just cue up the teleprompter.
Speaker 0: stand there.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Read, read, read, read, read.
Speaker 1: Now, what I don't have yet, but I could do it now, because I have the physical teleprompter, is the dynamic thing where I could have someone else feeding me stuff from off-screen.
Speaker 1: So, I'm gonna play around.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna use this thing to the maximum extent.
Speaker 0: It's best if you could see, like, comments on there.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like, what I want to do is have... Ideally, I might make an app, because now all I have to do is display, you know, stuff in an app.
Speaker 1: It'll just work.
Speaker 1: So, I could display, like, the comments from a Twitch stream while I'm videoing my face, while I'm playing the game much easier than putting an overlay on the game.
Speaker 0: You don't need an app for that.
Speaker 0: You can use the Twitch app to do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, because the Twitch app isn't reversed.
Speaker 0: It has... Oh, but it has chat-only mode.
Speaker 1: Yes, but it's not reversed.
Speaker 0: It's a teleprompter.
Speaker 0: Well, I can read in reverse, so not a problem.
Speaker 1: You... I defy you to read non-reversed text.
Speaker 0: Let me just turn my iPad upside down.
Speaker 0: Oh, wait.
Speaker 0: It corrected itself.
Speaker 1: So, in other, like, actual stuff I've been doing, game-wise, I bought a Wacom tablet, and I've been playing a lot of Civ 5.
Speaker 0: You're using the Civ 5... Your Wacom tablet for Civ 5?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that works real nice.
Speaker 0: Does it really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Way nice.
Speaker 1: At least, way better than the Lenovo touchpad.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes.
Speaker 0: That is... Good God.
Speaker 0: Good God.
Speaker 1: So, if any of you are interested in a big Civ 5 game, I've done all the research, and I've almost done testing all the shit, and I'm trying to start a, like, for-real, semi-long-form, pit-boss Civ 5 game.
Speaker 0: It's all you.
Speaker 1: We'll see how that goes.
Speaker 1: I think it'll be fun.
Speaker 1: You got any video game news?
Speaker 0: So, this is big news, at least it seemed big, based on the clamor I saw on the internet, that people are so excited that Capcom announced Mega Man Legacy Collection.
Speaker 0: So, what's happening is basically this new company that sort of is marketing themselves is we want to be the criterion collection for video games.
Speaker 0: We're gonna re-release all the old video games, you know, remastered, HD, Perfect Edition, with all sorts of added features, like, they're including, you know, a museum with all the old artwork, and high-res, and...
Speaker 1: Noble goal.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean, this isn't a bad thing at all, right?
Speaker 0: But I'm like, okay, first of all, they're making it HD, but it doesn't, like, they're not redrawing it, they're just directly scaling it to HD.
Speaker 0: It's like, well, my emulator does that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only thing... And they're acting like, oh, it's a big re-release.
Speaker 0: It's like, dudes, I already have Mega Man Collection and Mega Man X Collection for the GameCube, and it has Mega Men 1 through 8, not Mega Men 1 through 6.
Speaker 1: Also, the other thing is, the only thing that would make this worthwhile, for real, would be if it was guaranteed to be NES accurate, because the problem with emulators is that they're not 100% accurate.
Speaker 1: Like, the game's a little different.
Speaker 0: Don't need it to be so.
Speaker 0: The differences are so small that if you care about that difference, you can go fuck yourself.
Speaker 1: It depends on the game, at least from a museum standpoint.
Speaker 1: Like, if you're looking at preservation...
Speaker 0: But, I mean, we have plenty of Mega Man cartridges.
Speaker 0: There is no shortage of any Mega Man game on its original format.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but without that, I already have all these games on emulator.
Speaker 0: Right, but it's weird that people are so excited about this.
Speaker 0: It's like, you don't know about emulators.
Speaker 0: You don't... I mean, these games are even in Virtual Console, you can get them.
Speaker 0: It's like, why was this made into the big deal, news-wise, marketing-wise, when really, it's like, uh...
Speaker 1: So, you say that...
Speaker 0: Every Mega Man person fucking can already be in these games 100 times.
Speaker 1: Almost no one I know who knows about things said anything about this.
Speaker 1: This... All I saw was other people's retweets of the press release stuff.
Speaker 0: This filled my feeds for, like, half a day.
Speaker 0: What kind of feed do you have?
Speaker 0: Apparently Mega Man related.
Speaker 1: You've got the internet figured out that Mega Man's a jam?
Speaker 0: I guess maybe.
Speaker 1: Here, leaderboards, challenges, replays.
Speaker 1: If that's global and works well, that's actually pretty good.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's nice, but it's like, is it really enough to spend 15 bucks on games that you already have beaten?
Speaker 1: It depends.
Speaker 0: And played, and can already play anytime you want?
Speaker 1: You know, someone made a point on Twitter today that people like us, pretty much every genre of video games came into existence while we were alive and gaming from nothing.
Speaker 0: Well, before, at the original video games, when video games started, there were no genres.
Speaker 0: Every game was its own genre.
Speaker 0: What genre is Dig Dug?
Speaker 0: What genre is...
Speaker 1: A Digger, because Dig Dug 2.
Speaker 0: What genre is Mule?
Speaker 1: Mule is a resource allocation and bidding game.
Speaker 1: I would classify Mule the same way I classify board game.
Speaker 0: Right, it's like, what genre is...
Speaker 1: Pac-Man?
Speaker 1: Hubert.
Speaker 1: Hubert?
Speaker 1: Not actually a good game.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying it's... I'm just saying what genre is it?
Speaker 0: You know, games didn't have...
Speaker 1: Tile puzzler.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying, games didn't necessarily have genres.
Speaker 1: Real-time tile puzzler.
Speaker 0: Yeah, games didn't have genres.
Speaker 0: It was later on that genres came into existence, like NES days.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying, if you are young now, never played on a NES, like a kid who's growing up right now, not talking yet, when they're a little older, this is probably the best way for them to play all those old MegaMans.
Speaker 1: The question will be, will they ever want to?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, I just watched, you know, those YouTube channels that are like, old people react, babies react.
Speaker 1: Oh, kids react to NES games?
Speaker 1: I can summarize every one of them.
Speaker 1: This game's bullshit and hard, fuck it.
Speaker 0: Well, they just did Teens React Contra and they had them co-op.
Speaker 1: Oh, I watched that.
Speaker 0: And they were... It's like, you know, on one hand, I always feel bad, like, man, young kids are so much better at video games than me with their reflexes and their whatnots.
Speaker 0: It's like, wow, they are garbage at Contra.
Speaker 0: Now, to be fair, it was bullshit that they didn't give them the instruction manual first.
Speaker 1: I was like, I looked at that instruction manual.
Speaker 0: They spent a good amount of time, like, how do I drop down?
Speaker 0: How do I do this?
Speaker 0: It's like, you're supposed to read the fucking manual.
Speaker 1: You know, it's Contra.
Speaker 1: If you sit there when the game starts and mash the buttons, you literally figure out the entire game.
Speaker 0: They did eventually figure things out.
Speaker 0: But for example, they didn't know that you could shoot the mechanical turrets.
Speaker 0: They just tried to dodge them.
Speaker 0: They didn't know the water is safe.
Speaker 0: They didn't know the water ended at one point.
Speaker 0: They didn't know, like, they didn't know all these things that you could figure out.
Speaker 0: if you have, some of them you could figure out if you had the instruction manual.
Speaker 1: But you can also figure them out by playing a little.
Speaker 1: I've noticed that, you know what?
Speaker 1: That might be the same reason why even a lot of young people and just general people also suck at computers and everything else.
Speaker 0: They don't read manuals?
Speaker 1: No, fuck that.
Speaker 1: They don't even try to do anything.
Speaker 1: Like, they don't attempt things.
Speaker 1: They don't say, huh, I wonder what that is.
Speaker 1: Like, when I was a kid and I got a new game and there was a pit, jump in it just to see what happened.
Speaker 1: Like, I would just try stuff.
Speaker 1: I didn't need the Mega Man, Mega Man, Mega Man.
Speaker 0: Some of the kids tried stuff and some of them didn't.
Speaker 0: But they were all so garbage at Contra.
Speaker 0: It's like, man, I can't beat Contra without Konami Code or whatever.
Speaker 1: Here's the question, Scott.
Speaker 0: I can get way farther than those kids.
Speaker 0: None of them got past level one.
Speaker 1: Without Konami Code, are you confident right now that if we both played Contra, you would get past level one?
Speaker 0: Yeah, 100% confidence.
Speaker 1: Would you bet money on it?
Speaker 0: I would bet a moderate amount of money.
Speaker 1: You want to do a live challenge of.
Speaker 1: we each play Contra, one chance, no Konami Code.
Speaker 1: Whoever gets further wins with a pot.
Speaker 0: Further?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: I'm not betting on further than someone else.
Speaker 1: No, just me.
Speaker 0: I'm betting that I can beat level one.
Speaker 1: You're afraid that you're not as good as me.
Speaker 0: I can only do something that is guaranteed, which is that I can beat level one and possibly even level two.
Speaker 1: I'm dubious that you would beat one.
Speaker 1: There's no way you'd beat level two right now.
Speaker 1: When's the last time you played Contra?
Speaker 0: The upstrolling one?
Speaker 1: Oh man, I know how to do that.
Speaker 1: When was the last time you beat Contra?
Speaker 0: A while ago.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it's got leaderboards, which is cool, but at the same time, I don't know enough people who will care about the leaderboards enough.
Speaker 0: $15 for games you already have.
Speaker 1: $15 for games?
Speaker 1: It's not a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: It's got a database of enemy lists and stuff, so I guess it replaces the existing Wikia.
Speaker 0: The Mega Man Wiki is now crying.
Speaker 1: And they've got a museum of a whole bunch of pictures of things.
Speaker 0: I guess I can throw out my Mega Man 25th anniversary edition.
Speaker 1: I mean, there is a place for this.
Speaker 1: I don't take quite the div views Scott takes on it, but at the same time, I didn't see a big press blitz like you did, so.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 1: I did not run afoul of this.
Speaker 1: This is something that I knew was coming and I thought, oh, that's cool.
Speaker 1: I didn't think about it anymore.
Speaker 0: It's not bad.
Speaker 0: I thought there was a disproportionate response for what it was.
Speaker 0: I saw all this Mega Man hype and I was like, oh, Mega Man hype, what's this?
Speaker 0: And I'm like, oh, that's it?
Speaker 1: Look how balkanized the internet is.
Speaker 1: You and I are actually even in different ghettos of the internet.
Speaker 1: Apparently, you live in Mega Man town and I live in next door to Mega Man town.
Speaker 0: Bionic Commando town.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if there's Bionic Commando news, I'm all the fuck over that.
Speaker 0: It's okay.
Speaker 1: Even though Bionic Commando Rearm 2 is kind of garbagey.
Speaker 0: What is your news?
Speaker 1: So there is an article here that I don't think you even need to read, but the IGDA did a big satisfaction study and everything.
Speaker 1: And what they discovered is that developers in the video game industry, 50% of them earn less than 50K.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 0: Like you think that video games is like What games are they developing that they're making so little money?
Speaker 0: If you have like your developer, specifically, you know how to program and write code?
Speaker 1: You can make 80K in New York and finance overnight.
Speaker 0: Are the people that we're talking about here?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about like artists.
Speaker 1: We're talking about developers.
Speaker 0: Or testers.
Speaker 0: Developers.
Speaker 0: So somebody who knows how to code is working on a video game and only making 50K.
Speaker 0: If you know how to code, it doesn't matter what kind of code you know how.
Speaker 0: If you can actually code, you can make way more than 50K in any major city in the country.
Speaker 1: So anyway, there's a whole bunch of links here that are really fascinating.
Speaker 1: But the biggest takeaway seems to be that developers are leaving the industry at a higher rate.
Speaker 0: So they don't need the advice that we just gave them.
Speaker 0: They already figured it out.
Speaker 1: The churn rate in video games, which we all assumed was high, is way higher than we even assumed.
Speaker 0: How much did you assume?
Speaker 0: Because I assumed a lot.
Speaker 1: Well, at the same time, I know people who are highly stressed and way underpaid who continue to work in the video game industry.
Speaker 0: I do know such people.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: But the biggest takeaway is that the thing that is driving people out isn't even the money.
Speaker 1: It's the stress and the long hours and all the corporate bullshit.
Speaker 0: Stop doing that bullshit.
Speaker 1: So yeah, my continued dream of make a video game company that makes cool games.
Speaker 1: And if you make more money than you expect, instead of doing profits, just use that to make your lives better and don't try to be like a AAA profitable.
Speaker 0: If you're going to work in video games, only work for Valve, because you know what?
Speaker 0: Valve just releases games and they're done.
Speaker 0: They don't push to get them out in a certain time or any bullshit.
Speaker 1: I do know for a fact that some of the people who work for Blizzard, at least, are really happy and have good jobs.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm sure that someone at every company, no matter, you know, you think of the most evil company you can think of, the most, you know, someone at Time Warner fucking loves their job.
Speaker 0: Someone that, you know.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: In Nazi Germany, the SS, they fucking love their jobs.
Speaker 1: The regular German army, not so much.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying.
Speaker 1: I'm just, I'm trying to believe, yesterday I was reading this paper talking about, it was like this weird World War II thing about how the German army recognized pretty early, the Third Reich did.
Speaker 1: They recognized pretty early on that the average soldier, if they encountered the death camp stuff, could not deal with it and started going insane and suicides like crazy stuff.
Speaker 1: So they found that the SS people were way more into it and it's just an interesting study about how they tried to mitigate the damage that being literally the worst humans in history did to the people who were actually doing the work.
Speaker 1: So I'm glad all this discussion about stress in the video game industry went straight to Nazis, but this developer satisfaction survey is amazing.
Speaker 1: And seriously, if you work in video games and you work in video games because you're passionate about games and your job is stressful bullshit of working 80 hours a week for a company that doesn't care, either quit or find people who are like you, and just form your own game studio.
Speaker 1: I guarantee you'll do way better.
Speaker 0: Make a union.
Speaker 0: They can't stop you.
Speaker 1: Laws.
Speaker 1: Except because of the high churn rate, they can.
Speaker 1: They'll just fire you.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 0: The other option was quit, so at least try to make a union first.
Speaker 0: Worst case, you get fired, which is even better than quitting because then you get unemployment.
Speaker 1: But seriously, the only truly happy video game people I know are people who work for cool people, not just want to make money people, and full stop, that's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: Everyone else is the exception, the unicorn.
Speaker 1: Things of the day.
Speaker 1: So this is a fascinating article.
Speaker 1: Apparently satyrs or satyrs, depending on where you live.
Speaker 0: You mean a man with goat legs?
Speaker 1: Man with goat legs.
Speaker 1: And I guess, I don't know if what cultures have a female equivalent.
Speaker 0: I've never seen one.
Speaker 0: The Witcher has that.
Speaker 0: Maybe Fantasia, but that's more like... Those are satyrs, kind of.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: But yeah, the Witcher too.
Speaker 1: There's that one girl.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about Witcher.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: I just know it's a Polish video game.
Speaker 1: There is a... Anyway, you know the Mr.
Speaker 1: Mashant's wife, the sexy Lamia?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There's an equivalent satyr woman, witch person in a Witcher game.
Speaker 0: When did you play Witcher?
Speaker 1: I just know about video games.
Speaker 0: You just know about Witcher?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: How witchy are you?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was Dave and Joel.
Speaker 1: That's how I know this.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 1: My brain was stretching back.
Speaker 0: That's the game they would play that you wouldn't play.
Speaker 1: I was stretching back in my brain like, "Wait, are you dreaming?
Speaker 1: "How do you know this?
Speaker 1: "Is this real?
Speaker 1: "Do you have
Speaker 1: Witcher?"?
Speaker 1: "How did you get
Speaker 1: here?".
Speaker 1: But apparently satyrs, or satyrs, won't eat soup.
Speaker 1: And this is a theme in woodcuts, in carvings, in paintings.
Speaker 0: From ancient times.
Speaker 1: 1600s.
Speaker 1: So all these old images of satyrs, you'll see them sitting at a table and a peasant's eating soup like, "Check this shit
Speaker 1: out.".
Speaker 1: And satyrs are like, "Oh, fuck
Speaker 1: no.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, that satyr's too good for soup.
Speaker 1: Or the peasant reveals some soup and the satyr just faints.
Speaker 0: If someone's an artist, a good enough artist, to make art like that, you should draw a satyr in Japan being like, "Fuck no
Speaker 0: ramen.".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But also he's like, "Hell
Speaker 0: no.".
Speaker 0: And they're eating pho.
Speaker 1: It's interesting seeing this painting from 1730.
Speaker 1: And then there's another painting from 1680 and 1615.
Speaker 1: And they all show the satyr leaving by the fact that the stool he's sitting on is being knocked over.
Speaker 0: Why are the satyrs always so buff?
Speaker 1: They historically are buff.
Speaker 1: They're supposed to be super hot.
Speaker 0: I guess that's from not eating soup.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll stop eating soup.
Speaker 0: But wait, chicken soup too good.
Speaker 1: So this article explains why satyrs are so fucked up by soup.
Speaker 0: How did this person research this?
Speaker 0: What library had this information?
Speaker 1: Here, I'll read it.
Speaker 1: So satyrs, or hybrid beings who are part human and part goat, are famed for their love of wine and body behavior.
Speaker 1: Marcantonio Riamondi's Bacchanal in 1510, derived from ancient sarcophagus bass relief and displaying a lot of drunken followers of Dionysus, is characteristic of the type of activity associated with satyrs.
Speaker 1: However, as the number of printed examples reveal, a bowl of soup placed before a satyr elicits some surprisingly sober conduct.
Speaker 1: So I'm not going to spoil it.
Speaker 1: Fucking go read this article.
Speaker 1: It's pretty great.
Speaker 1: And the answer is actually pretty simple and pretty funny.
Speaker 0: So this guy on YouTube, he's got a YouTube account with over 140,000 subscribers.
Speaker 0: His name is Styro Pyro.
Speaker 1: That's a good name already.
Speaker 0: His latest video has almost three and a half million views.
Speaker 0: It is my homemade 40 watt laser shotgun.
Speaker 1: Wait,
Speaker 1: 40? 40
Speaker 1: watts.
Speaker 0: Like a light bulb 40 watts.
Speaker 1: I've witnessed a five watt laser before and that shit was not cool.
Speaker 0: Imagine all the photons coming out of a 40 watt light bulb, which is bright enough that when you look at it, it hurts.
Speaker 0: But instead of being spread all over the goddamn room, they're all aimed at one spot like bam.
Speaker 1: So I actually have seen this video.
Speaker 1: The best part about it is that when he turns it on, his camera goes, Oh, fuck no.
Speaker 1: And really has a hard time recovering from how bright it is.
Speaker 0: And he, you know, he shoots a bunch of balloons and set stuff on fire and whatever.
Speaker 0: he does exactly what you should do.
Speaker 0: The way it works is he's got a whole bunch of lasers and he shoots them all at a lens that focuses them at one point.
Speaker 0: This guy has also in the past made a six watt laser sword and many other projects that will get a lot of YouTube views.
Speaker 1: I look forward to seeing the video where this kid talks about why he lost his eye.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's pretty much the I don't know.
Speaker 0: He's not that much of a kid.
Speaker 0: He seems younger than us, though.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this guy is the expert at making dangerous things that get a lot of views on YouTube.
Speaker 0: So give him your views.
Speaker 1: So in the moment, the Book Club book is Scott's Choice and I disavow the selection.
Speaker 1: It is the Eye of Zawado, also known as the first book of the Wheel of Time by Robert Jordan.
Speaker 1: Known so because it goes on and on and on and on until I start foaming at the mouth and falling over.
Speaker 0: I started reading book one.
Speaker 0: I'm about 100 pages in and it's a fantasy novel.
Speaker 1: I'm going to London next week and I plan to read most of it on the plane.
Speaker 0: It's a fantasy novel.
Speaker 0: If you're a nerd and you like fantasy novels, this is one of them.
Speaker 1: So gut read better or worse than the Rothfussian offerings.
Speaker 1: You've only read the first Rothfuss.
Speaker 0: I mean, I killer quality wise.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, I guess ignoring the content, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, the content is more generic, whereas the Rothfussian is more modernish despite having its issues of being, you know, Superman and whatnot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know, this is a more of a classic plot, but I guess it's more well done in writing wise.
Speaker 1: Just curious what I'm getting into here.
Speaker 1: I'm still everyone I talk to.
Speaker 0: It's like perhaps Robert Jordan was a better writer than Rothfuss, but he wrote about something that is more, you know, the content is more typical and not surprising.
Speaker 0: It's just a fantasy adventure.
Speaker 1: And there's a lot of things are now ranging from, oh man, those books aren't that good too.
Speaker 1: Now you got to read like the seventh book.
Speaker 1: The early ones aren't that good.
Speaker 0: Mixed response all over.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And also the response of man, I don't like fantasy novels.
Speaker 0: It's like, why are you listening to geek nights?
Speaker 0: Are you a nerd or what?
Speaker 0: Cyberpunk only, maybe.
Speaker 0: I mean, I mean, it's real hard to not just really only two kinds of books that nerds read the sci fi's and the fantasy.
Speaker 0: They put them in the same section of the bookstore just for you.
Speaker 0: Reading only half of those seems kind of weird.
Speaker 1: You're real lucky.
Speaker 1: We don't just make the book club.
Speaker 1: Every prince of nothing chat.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, they're usually fantasy and sci fi are also in the same section because they're usually the same thing.
Speaker 0: You just replace dragon with like computer virus and replace sword with laser sword.
Speaker 1: And it's the same thing.
Speaker 0: So otherwise we have no convention appearances until Connecticut, which is actually surprisingly soon.
Speaker 1: Connecticut is in about a month in July in Hartford, Connecticut at the Connecticut Convention Center.
Speaker 1: It is not worth flying to, but it is definitely worth driving to.
Speaker 0: If you can get to it in a car, and you're a nerd, which you are if you're listening to this, you should go to it.
Speaker 0: Also, June 20th is the Philadelphia Netrunner Regional Championship.
Speaker 0: I'm going to live stream from there if their Internet doesn't suck.
Speaker 1: I may or may not tag along.
Speaker 0: You should come to make my life easier.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could, but at the same time, I could do something else.
Speaker 0: You would be in this game store all day until the late night in Philadelphia.
Speaker 1: Unless it's a burning con.
Speaker 1: Pretty much any other like game store event.
Speaker 1: After about four hours, I want to be outside.
Speaker 0: You can stand outside the store.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can walk around Philadelphia.
Speaker 0: You can play Netrunner.
Speaker 0: You can entertain the people with all the who are going to be many viewers, probably hundreds.
Speaker 1: So we were in Wildwood, New Jersey last weekend.
Speaker 1: We've talked about it at length on the show many times in the past, but one thing that happened over the years is we pretty much started going at the peak of arcades.
Speaker 0: And then every year it was only the peak DDR.
Speaker 0: It wasn't the peak of arcades.
Speaker 0: The peak of arcades was Street Fighter 2, Mortal Kombat 2 era.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: In the United States, at least.
Speaker 1: The peak of arcades at the shore.
Speaker 0: The peak of arcades DDR wise.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but also the shore had its...
Speaker 0: Police 911.
Speaker 1: Hokuto no Ken.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying there was a time at the shore where they had Street Fighter 2, Mortal Kombat 2 at NBA Jam.
Speaker 1: No, but that was a different time, you understand.
Speaker 0: And just the peak of arcades at the shore with DDR was when we went.
Speaker 1: So over the years it declined and declined and declined until one year, last year, there was literally not a single arcade machine worth touching on the entire boardwalk.
Speaker 0: Unless you really want to play a rigged crane.
Speaker 1: But now there's a retro pinball museum that you can play awesome old mechanical pinball machines.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a handful of good arcade machines on that boardwalk.
Speaker 1: With one exception, they're all in one arcade.
Speaker 1: So while we were walking around looking for something to do, we bumped into Time Crisis 5, which just came out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was like, whoa, I didn't even know.
Speaker 0: this just came out because I mean, how would you even know?
Speaker 1: Well, because when was the last Time Crisis game?
Speaker 0: Right, it was actually in 2006.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I looked to make sure.
Speaker 0: Time Crisis 4 was in 2006.
Speaker 1: On July 4th, 2006.
Speaker 0: In other words, when there were less than one year of Geek Nights episodes recorded.
Speaker 1: We did a show called Arcade Games colon Dance Dance Revolution House of the Dead 4 Time Crisis 4.
Speaker 0: This is Time Crisis 5.
Speaker 0: It came out nine years after Time Crisis 4.
Speaker 0: There've been nine years without an arcade Time Crisis game.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow, our things of the day back then were a guy lighting 45,000 bottle rockets at the same time.
Speaker 0: I remember that one.
Speaker 1: And the dog wielding a Roman candle.
Speaker 1: And something about WG ad doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: The page is gone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway.
Speaker 0: OK, so Time Crisis is a really interesting game, right?
Speaker 0: Because I mean, gun games are some of the oldest arcade games, even in like pre-video game.
Speaker 0: A lot of arcade machines were shooting gallery.
Speaker 1: It was like a big wooden like bolt action rifle on a stick shooting mechanical targets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they used various very clever methods of figuring out if your aim was accurate or not.
Speaker 0: And those methods worked or did not work to various degrees.
Speaker 0: But, you know, arcade, the gun games have always been a staple of the arcade, because even though you had the Zapper at home with your NES, it only worked so well and a mechanism to make it work better was not something you could have in your house.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, lethal enforcers work pretty well on the SNES.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: What did you use, a super scope?
Speaker 1: Oh, it came with guns.
Speaker 0: Oh, it came with guns?
Speaker 1: It came with plastic guns.
Speaker 1: That's all right.
Speaker 1: Like big revolver looking things.
Speaker 0: But I mean, especially when CRTs died and we had the LCD screens, it was even harder to make gun games.
Speaker 0: that, you know, for home.
Speaker 0: And, you know, buying guns that all in every game used a different method and the arcades just kept getting fancier at a rate.
Speaker 0: So even today, right?
Speaker 0: The arcade gun game is still vastly superior to anything you can have at your home, unless you buy an arcade machine.
Speaker 0: And really it started with sort of lethal enforcers, but it moved on to, you know, area 51 sort of reignited that.
Speaker 0: And time crisis really just sort of blew them all out of the water and became sort of the king of the arcade gun game.
Speaker 0: And nothing is really tried to stand up to it since, other than more time crisis.
Speaker 1: Here, there was actually the, that gun was a standard gun.
Speaker 1: It was the Konami justifier.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 1: And it worked with lethal enforcers, lethal enforcers too.
Speaker 1: Oh, on the, on other systems that worked with a bunch of shit, but on the SNES in 92, it literally only ever worked.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So time crisis, the big revolution reason time crisis was such a big deal is because time tries has introduced the pedal, right?
Speaker 0: Not only were you shooting at the screen, you're also stepping on this thing.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And when you stepped on it and you, you would basically pop up and be able to shoot guys.
Speaker 0: And when you let go, your guy would hide and also instantly reload the gun.
Speaker 0: So it combined the reloading with the hiding, which makes sense.
Speaker 0: Cause you hide and reload.
Speaker 0: You don't want to reload with your head sticking out, but also the height.
Speaker 1: That was just fine.
Speaker 1: And operation Wolf.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Uh, but it also, you know, the, the aspect of hiding also added this sort of extra element to the game of the dodging.
Speaker 0: You could see bullets or rockets coming at you and dodge them by ducking and then pop out and shoot the bad guy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And all these games were just rail shooters, right?
Speaker 0: You don't control your movement.
Speaker 0: You basically just had to kill all the guys on the screen.
Speaker 0: Get served.
Speaker 0: Don't die.
Speaker 0: Get to the next screen.
Speaker 0: Before that, all the gun games would be the more like a duck con or.
Speaker 1: Well, like legal enforcers, there was the child's pop out and you shoot him.
Speaker 1: And then there was like operation Wolf, like the machine gun, a bunch of shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well that was Terminator two arcade, right?
Speaker 0: We got a bunch of shit, but that wasn't actually a gun.
Speaker 0: It was actually a joystick that looked like a gun, right?
Speaker 0: So you felt like you were aiming at the screen, but really they just mapped the position of the joystick to positions on the screen.
Speaker 0: The gun was attached to the top of the thing.
Speaker 0: You couldn't pick up the gun and aim anywhere you wanted.
Speaker 1: Now nicely.
Speaker 1: That didn't really matter in terms of playing.
Speaker 0: Also the time crisis guns added a few other things.
Speaker 1: The force feedback, which is gone now.
Speaker 1: Well, it's still force feedback, but they've removed the actual physical, you know, clicking of that was when I first picked up a time crisis gun and that big bolt at the top would move.
Speaker 1: That was the shit.
Speaker 0: It was, it was kind of awesome.
Speaker 0: Uh, they, you know, it's not there now.
Speaker 0: and time crisis five, at least the machine we played, but that really set time crisis apart.
Speaker 0: It got you to put quarters in just to play with that.
Speaker 0: Cause it was fun to play with that.
Speaker 0: Even if you sucked also the shooting in time crisis, the way it worked, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I still don't actually know specifically what method they're using to make the gun work.
Speaker 0: The gun is ridiculously accurate, or at least it feels ridiculously accurate.
Speaker 0: Like you never have a situation where you shoot and the bullet goes off somewhere else, or it doesn't hit the screen or whatever.
Speaker 0: Like you can have that happen even in games like area 51 and whatnot.
Speaker 0: That'll happen sometimes.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So time crisis five in terms of plot.
Speaker 1: I have fuck.
Speaker 1: If I know I've never cared.
Speaker 1: I skip every cut scene.
Speaker 1: As far as I know, time crisis is.
Speaker 1: there's a couple of pretty guys and you shoot things and the enemies are in.
Speaker 0: There's always an insane boss who has a huge, huge army consisting of ridiculous mechanical deadly contraptions and lots and lots of really boring foot soldiers and henchmen.
Speaker 0: And they're drat.
Speaker 0: They're chasing you through a dangerous, dangerous world of industrial shit.
Speaker 0: And that crazy boss guys just keeps taunting you until eventually you murder him and have an even crazier boss in the next level.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So time versus five, the shit gets got going on.
Speaker 1: Is that daddy two pedals?
Speaker 0: Daddy two.
Speaker 0: So it's like, what can they possibly do for time crisis five that didn't already do in games like crisis zone with the submachine gun or time crisis for they already added co-op and time crisis too.
Speaker 0: They like, they advanced so quickly.
Speaker 0: They got ahead of themselves.
Speaker 0: It took them nine years to come up with a way to advance this game.
Speaker 0: And all they could do is two pedals.
Speaker 0: And it's like two pedals.
Speaker 0: that really isn't that big a leap, but it's actually kind of awesome.
Speaker 1: Cause basically when you put your foot on a pedal, you stand up in that spot.
Speaker 1: If you let go, you're ducking.
Speaker 1: Put your foot up on the other pedal, you run around and come up on the other side of some bitches.
Speaker 0: So basically there's for any screen that you're on, there's two places you can stand and you can safely move between the two positions.
Speaker 1: And as a result, it'd be dangerous.
Speaker 1: Cause if Scott moves to one spot and I moved to another spot, like off to the side, we could shoot each other.
Speaker 1: I can see him over there.
Speaker 0: Well, that happens in time crisis too.
Speaker 1: Also, but now it's active depending upon me.
Speaker 0: Now there's like decisions that you make.
Speaker 0: Like if you coordinate with the other person, you can perhaps avoid any risk of that by always positioning yourselves in a certain way, but it actually kind of makes the game easier because when you appear and start shooting, all the bad guys will turn towards you and start shooting at you as they do.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They're not dumb.
Speaker 0: You switch to the other position.
Speaker 0: They're still aiming where they were originally.
Speaker 1: Usually occasionally when we got to this one smart guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I come around and there's a guy like in the back with a worst gun covering his friends.
Speaker 1: I can be like, Oh shit and duck immediately.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But you and you pop up in the other position, you pretty much all the bad guys are still gonna be facing.
Speaker 0: You're going to shoot them from their side and flank them.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So you just keep switching back and forth and you're pretty much almost always flanking all the bad guys and hitting them without being hit very much at all.
Speaker 0: It really makes it kind of easy in a way, but it encourages you to keep switching between the two pedals pretty much constantly.
Speaker 0: But there's sometimes you don't want to switch.
Speaker 1: Of course, we only got to the first main boss.
Speaker 1: We don't know how easy it remains.
Speaker 0: I wasn't going to put that many quarters in there, but they do a lot of other interesting stuff with the pedals.
Speaker 0: Like that first main boss is a rotating flame turret thing.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So not only do you want to rotate to get to the right side of it based on its position, but you need to use that rotation to sort of duck under the flame thing.
Speaker 0: And if you do it wrong, that flame could just hit you in the head.
Speaker 0: If you pop up, say on the right pedal, when it's coming at you, you got to be able to see it coming at you, duck on the right, move to the left to get under it, and then pop out again where it's safe.
Speaker 0: So they incorporated a lot of, you know, the bosses and other elements in the environment really integrate well with the two pedal system.
Speaker 1: And it just felt like the slickest time crisis to date.
Speaker 1: Like it was just fun, good.
Speaker 1: Like it's a perfect example of a great arcade gun game.
Speaker 0: Another thing that makes time crisis really stand out from other arcade gun games, especially say House of the Dead is the big screen.
Speaker 0: You never see time crisis with a tiny screen.
Speaker 0: Even time crisis one had the big screen.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And the screens on this one are huge.
Speaker 0: And you're sort of far away from that screen.
Speaker 0: So it actually, you know, there is a lot of aiming shooting going on with House of the Dead is like a little screen usually.
Speaker 0: And you're like next to it and up close and going like, yeah, even police 911 is a tiny little screen.
Speaker 0: It's like the gun games is one case where it's like, yeah, a bigger TV actually matters.
Speaker 0: A whole crap ton goes in this more area to shoot at.
Speaker 0: that makes aiming like sort of matter with a tiny screen.
Speaker 0: It's like you're just moving the gun like a little tiny bit.
Speaker 0: And it's like, whatever, right?
Speaker 0: When you're moving the gun, like shoot a guy in the way left, shoot a guy in the way, right?
Speaker 0: That's like more the physical action starts to get into it.
Speaker 0: It's, you know, that's what makes a gun game good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So the co-op and ever like playing together was really fun.
Speaker 1: And we actually died like basically within a few seconds of each other.
Speaker 1: Like I died finally.
Speaker 1: And then the boss comes in and Scott died.
Speaker 1: That was it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But, uh, it has a pretty good competitive co-op thing in that there's some screens and some events where you both have a task.
Speaker 1: Like one, there's one boss guy jumps on a pulley and starts like escaping and you get all these targets to shoot.
Speaker 1: And I shot the targets faster.
Speaker 1: So at the end of gave me a huge point bonus and it was like, yeah, you beat your friend.
Speaker 0: I mean, time crisis too is the first time of the co-op, but really it was, you, it was just, Hey, let's make the game easier because now there's two people shooting the bad guys.
Speaker 0: Even though if you didn't have a co-op friend, there was an AI that shot the bad guys poorly.
Speaker 0: Uh, really all that did is sort of let you beat the game with your friend and you could compare scores, but no one gave a shit about score.
Speaker 0: You just cared about seeing the end of the game and then ever playing it again.
Speaker 0: In this, that the, uh, the actual, it says on the screen to win, lose.
Speaker 0: It actually tells you we, the word win and the word lose.
Speaker 0: And somehow that makes you care and makes you want to do better than your friend.
Speaker 1: A lot.
Speaker 1: I started taking a lot of risks to kill more guys than Scott faster.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: It paid off.
Speaker 1: I won every screen.
Speaker 0: I didn't really care.
Speaker 0: I just wanted to try to beat the game.
Speaker 0: still, even though the fact is the first time I said win, lose, I was like, well, I didn't know that was going to happen.
Speaker 1: So the interesting thing that's kind of sad is that it prevents one mode of gameplay that I used to do occasionally at older time crises, holding both guns and playing both sides.
Speaker 0: I mean, you can not do it.
Speaker 1: The pedals are physically too far apart.
Speaker 0: Time crisis too, right?
Speaker 0: Time crisis one, there was only one gun in one screen.
Speaker 0: Time crisis two, you could do it because they were kind of close enough to each other that you could step on both pedals and sort of shoot the left screen, shoot the right screen, shoot the left screen, shoot the right screen.
Speaker 0: I think I don't know if crisis zone.
Speaker 0: I don't remember that being two player with the submachine gun, but there were some other arcade games that had submachine guns that weren't time crisis where you could hold both submachine guns, one per hand, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But yeah, time crisis five.
Speaker 0: The screens are so big and the guns with the two pedals are so far apart.
Speaker 0: You can't possibly play both sides at once.
Speaker 0: You know, you no matter how much you can split your legs, you can't hit the left pedal on the left one and the right pedal on the right one at the same time and still shoot and still hold both guns.
Speaker 0: Maybe if you were a satyr, maybe if you have, uh, four people, two people can control pedals and two people can have guns or one person in a, both guns and then two people on the pedals.
Speaker 0: Or I don't know, maybe you could just, you know, rig some sort of, if you have it in your house, you can just like connect like extra pedals that are right near you and you can have all four, all four pedals right in front of you with two guns and one screen.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, you couldn't have one screen because the two screens are going to be different.
Speaker 1: Well, honestly, in the modern era, like I don't see gun games really coming back on consoles or in houses.
Speaker 0: Just no one's going to shell out, you know, with an LCD TV, it's very hard to get the system to work.
Speaker 0: You're going to need like extra stuff.
Speaker 0: People already don't got tired of buying plastic guitars and DDR pads.
Speaker 0: No one's buying guns for how few gun games there are.
Speaker 0: Who's paying for this, right?
Speaker 0: Nobody.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So I don't think this is even going to make an arcade resurgence.
Speaker 1: Like I'm surprised.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's probably a big deal in Japan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I am shocked that there is the time crisis five machine on the East coast of the United States.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Let alone in Wildwood, New Jersey, randomly surrounded by a literal sea of shit and cranes.
Speaker 1: I mean, the arcade it's in is nothing but garbage and cranes.
Speaker 0: Dude, the Yahtzee machine was so bad.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: I thought I was going to play actual Yahtzee.
Speaker 0: It's like, Nope.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: Other than time crisis five, the only good games in the arcades anywhere were all those pinball games in the one place.
Speaker 0: Old pinball.
Speaker 1: The old DDR supernova machine.
Speaker 0: There wasn't even a good air hockey.
Speaker 0: There was bad air hockey.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All the good air hockey's are gone.
Speaker 1: That last photon table is gone.
Speaker 0: Now they just had the one that goes ding on the side, which is garbage.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I watched some people playing it.
Speaker 0: Might as well not even play air hockey.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Just give up.
Speaker 0: But yeah, time crisis, you know, is this game with like this long history that somehow just by being in, you know, time crisis one and two, especially just by being in every arcade, you know, any nerd that went to an arcade between the years of like 2000, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess time crisis one, 96, 96.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So I think area 51 was nice.
Speaker 0: So anyone who went to an arcade in the nineties up through the two thousands and he was a nerd in that era.
Speaker 0: You can't not know time crisis.
Speaker 0: It's like, I don't know if there's anyone who's like a time crisis fan.
Speaker 0: I've never met such a person, but it's just like a staple.
Speaker 0: And there's like NBA jam is a staple.
Speaker 1: Like when I thought arcade, I thought like, yeah, there's the fighting games.
Speaker 1: There's the time crisis machine.
Speaker 0: There's the DDR machines in USA cruise in the world.
Speaker 0: That's a staple.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There's certain games like Ridge Racer was always hanging out somewhere.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And you know, Marvel, Marvel vs.
Speaker 0: Capcom was a staple, but that's sort of brought it home.
Speaker 0: A lot of those fighting games racer.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Those, a lot of those games are able to bring it home, but the ones that weren't, you know, it's like they sort of disappeared and never came back.
Speaker 0: But here we go.
Speaker 0: Time crisis five coming back for whatever reason.
Speaker 1: So I guess what I'll say is when I go back to Wildwood later in the summer, I might, cause it's only 50 cents to continue.
Speaker 1: I think I just want to beat it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If I have enough quarter, maybe I can find my laundry quarters that don't need anymore.
Speaker 0: Cause I now have a car.
Speaker 1: Let's just bring a bag of quarters and be like that guy who was doing this, preventing us from playing earlier.
Speaker 0: We'll just find a day with bad weather.
Speaker 0: And if there's a bad weather day, just go to the time crisis machine and beat it.
Speaker 0: Cause it never takes that long to beat time crisis.
Speaker 0: Now the thing is they fuck you because like the final boss will just keep killing you.
Speaker 0: Cause it is an arcade machine.
Speaker 1: You're not going to give up at the final boss.
Speaker 1: You're not just like, well, that's my last quarter.
Speaker 0: It's just like X-Men arcade machine.
Speaker 0: Magneto kills you so many times.
Speaker 0: You know, he just cheats like bullshit and then eventually, but you put enough money to beat him.
Speaker 0: And then that's the, you know, the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But it's worth it to see some ending that you'll pretty much, I don't know.
Speaker 0: if you know, you can see this ending on YouTube.
Speaker 0: You're proud.
Speaker 0: I want to say you can't cause you can see anything on YouTube.
Speaker 1: We kept skipping that.
Speaker 1: Like all there were going, there was like something about a briefcase.
Speaker 0: Well, and there's always something about a briefcase.
Speaker 0: That's how time crisis is.
Speaker 1: And there's that Robert Baxter guy who came, who appeared, who was yelling the whole time.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess he's in older time crises.
Speaker 0: So yep.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: The plots of time crisis is really, really don't research those on the.
Speaker 0: That's not good for you.
Speaker 0: That's really bad for your health.
Speaker 0: Really bad.
Speaker 1: Three months prior to the events of the game, a VSSC auditor was murdered.
Speaker 0: The one thing that really bothers me though, is that it's called time crisis.
Speaker 0: People don't know this because in time crisis one, you're actually traveling in time.
Speaker 0: Isn't the first level like a medieval castle that you're in?
Speaker 1: or I don't even remember.
Speaker 1: I was never like, I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: in time crisis one, the first level is like a medieval castle and like your dudes with guns going through history to stop these bad guys or something.
Speaker 0: And, uh, in the other time, starting in time crisis two, there's no more time travel.
Speaker 1: I don't know if there's any time travel.
Speaker 0: I remember a medieval.
Speaker 1: I think it's called time crisis because there's a countdown timer that you are fighting.
Speaker 0: Why are you in a medieval castle in time crisis one?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 0: Is it a plot of time crisis?
Speaker 1: involves an attempted coup in the fictional Republic of Circea.
Speaker 1: For a millennium, the Garo family ruled Circea with an iron fist.
Speaker 1: in 1995, the VSSC, the international intelligence agency sent William McPherson who successfully toppled the Garo regime and became the first democratically elected president.
Speaker 1: The last remaining member of the Garo family.
Speaker 1: God damn, there's a lot.
Speaker 1: There is no mention of time travel.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: I don't think there's time travel.
Speaker 1: I think you're just making that up.
Speaker 0: The first level though is definitely a medieval castle.
Speaker 0: So I must have falsely interpreted that when I was young in the 90s playing that, that I was a guy with a gun.
Speaker 1: I think that's just the family's incest for the Garo family's ancestral home.
Speaker 0: Like, yeah, it was a present time castle.
Speaker 0: I falsely interpreted what was going on.
Speaker 0: There's any time travel because as a wise man said, don't pay attention to the plot of time crisis.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think we're done here.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a creative comments attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Are you ready to dance?
Speaker 0: Loosen up and get ready to groove.
Speaker 1: I need your love in every way and I feel this every day cause I have too many tears with falling in love again.
Speaker 1: Now I am walking around in this side of the town.
Speaker 1: I just can't hide away.
Speaker 1: How can I look in your eyes when I feel like you died?
Speaker 0: I have to run away.
Speaker 0: I'm falling in love again.
Speaker 0: And I'm falling in love again.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: This is it.