Speaker 0: It's Monday, December 14th, 2015.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is geek nights tonight the death of QA or not?
Speaker 1: really Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Scott witnessed me on the glory road as I died.
Speaker 0: history.
Speaker 0: Well, actually no, I did not die historic I just won the race.
Speaker 0: Scott died historic in last place.
Speaker 0: Congratulations on winning the 50% random game the game that was a skill game until you lost.
Speaker 1: It's a 50% random game 50% skill and 50% luck.
Speaker 1: if you you can make poor decisions and lose it very easily.
Speaker 1: You can also just be unlucky and lose.
Speaker 0: Well, it's got a more complex push your luck in the sense that odds making matters a lot.
Speaker 1: And so in the second half of the final app I pushed it as hard as I could because that was my time to go but you were already behind because of poor decisions earlier.
Speaker 1: I didn't make a poor decision.
Speaker 0: I held back and took the safest possible risks the entire time and then I had all the resources I needed to just floor it For the entire end of the race.
Speaker 1: Listen, that's how things sometimes go in the world of racing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was kind of cheating.
Speaker 0: I mean I saw f1 on that course.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what I knew.
Speaker 0: you know what I knew from what I saw.
Speaker 0: they slowed down a lot at the two corners And then they sped up again as fast as they could.
Speaker 1: it's true for every race ever of cars.
Speaker 1: That is true any kind.
Speaker 1: when you have to turn you must slow.
Speaker 0: the X part of that track is pretty cool Like the course in Singapore because it's basically an X with two pretty much 90 degree turns right at the same spot.
Speaker 0: So like full out like there are hard turns, but there's also like some crazy long like where'd you cane like things on the other side?
Speaker 0: But yeah, so playing some games over the weekend games are playing a lot more games now that it's cold and can't bike to wait.
Speaker 0: It's not cold.
Speaker 0: It's spring.
Speaker 0: Yesterday wasn't yesterday the hottest yesterday in New York City history.
Speaker 1: I'll take it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if it would stay like this here, but isn't people all upset about global warming.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I welcome it.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, the world's gonna be destroyed or whatever.
Speaker 1: It's gonna suck.
Speaker 1: That sucks.
Speaker 1: I don't like that but what I do like is at least none of that will happen in my lifetime and In my lifetime New York will become tropical hopefully or more tropical.
Speaker 1: Hey, I'll make my life way way better.
Speaker 0: problem a lot of standing water and stuff in New York.
Speaker 0: if it gets much more tropical Malaria might come here.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 0: a New York with malaria is cannot a great place to be.
Speaker 0: yellow fever get some cholera hanging out.
Speaker 1: I don't think I'm gonna get malaria even if malaria comes to New York.
Speaker 0: Malaria if malaria comes to New York, you'll probably get it.
Speaker 0: because you bike around all the time You can't go to Rockaway anymore.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: That's where the mosquitoes are all gonna be by that a bobo bo bridge Alright, so then you'll get malaria and you automatically get it.
Speaker 0: You'll get it.
Speaker 0: mosquitoes bite you if you're hanging outside.
Speaker 1: I also just constantly take prevention medicines.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those drugs suck.
Speaker 0: There's a reason why when I travel despite the fact that I'm going to some malaria areas I don't take it and I just don't fucking go outside.
Speaker 1: Well, listen Bill Gates is already putting mad money towards the malaria in Africa, you know, so if malaria starts spreading to the rest of the world Definitely people are gonna start putting a lot of money to fixing that shit real fast.
Speaker 1: Yeah Also, wouldn't that be a crazy good sci-fi story?
Speaker 1: if like, you know right now humans dominate the world But in some distant future.
Speaker 1: malaria is like the number one species on earth Because it just kills everything.
Speaker 0: Uh, I don't think malaria specifically would become the biggest species on earth.
Speaker 0: It'd be more malaria than anything else, but it wouldn't have any places to live.
Speaker 0: left mosquitoes.
Speaker 0: But it needs all.
Speaker 0: it doesn't just go from mosquito to mosquito.
Speaker 0: They'd eat each other.
Speaker 0: It goes mosquito to human to mosquito.
Speaker 0: mosquitoes can't eat mosquitoes yet unless the ape learns to kill the ape.
Speaker 0: so in actual news We talked about this a bit because it was coming for a long time but it actually happened.
Speaker 0: the FAA regulations start in a week on drones if your drone weighs more if you're in the United States and your drone weighs more if you're in the United States and You have a drone that you can control.
Speaker 0: So like model rockets don't count unless your model rocket has a guidance system that you control from the ground.
Speaker 0: Then and it weighs more than 250 grams.
Speaker 0: So point five pounds meaning every drone worth a damn.
Speaker 0: You must register it by law on an FAA website the same way you register for like a ham radio.
Speaker 1: These are tests needed.
Speaker 0: No, you have to register it as yours like serial number and everything.
Speaker 0: So if it does anything shady, they can come to your house and be like, yo, dude Oh, that's not too bad.
Speaker 1: It's not even like a driver's license.
Speaker 1: It's that's way easy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, go to a website and fill it out and push submit and you're good.
Speaker 0: It costs five dollars.
Speaker 1: But oh, no, you can afford a drone, but you don't have five extra dollars.
Speaker 0: But for the first month because this is new regulation registration is free.
Speaker 1: Oh Even better.
Speaker 0: you spent your last dollar on the drone and you're still good and you only have to register it before you fly It the first time.
Speaker 1: so you keep your drone in the closet until the spring because it's winter.
Speaker 1: You could just register in the spring, but then you got to pay five bucks.
Speaker 0: This is just.
Speaker 0: this is the Minimal regulation.
Speaker 0: I think it's fine.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have no problems with.
Speaker 1: no problems with this.
Speaker 1: now you had to register a car.
Speaker 1: This is way easier than that and it you know And probably should be way more should probably have to take a test to make sure you know how to fly this stupid drone.
Speaker 0: Yep But I honestly feel like this is a good thing because one if we need to Insurrect against the government and we're using drones to do that.
Speaker 0: We're just not registering them anymore dirt.
Speaker 0: And Also, that's the situation where some of the other stuff we'll talk about tonight has to go on.
Speaker 0: but also right now I think more people use drones not maliciously but just stupidly.
Speaker 1: Then I see a lot of film production crews and TV production crews using drones to get aerial shots And I think that is the current You know most practical and prominent use of drone.
Speaker 0: But a lot of those uses are actually kind of illegal because of the no commercial use clauses for a lot of drone use in a lot of places.
Speaker 0: But this specific regulation I think is fine And apparently they piggybacked on the old regulation for radio-controlled propeller driven airplanes.
Speaker 1: Oh, that sounds good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that those things While they are deaf, I'd rather be hit by the drone me to the airplane.
Speaker 0: I've flown those things.
Speaker 0: There are real airplanes with gas engines.
Speaker 0: They're just tiny but they're not light.
Speaker 1: Why don't we make a drone with a gas engine?
Speaker 1: That's not lights.
Speaker 0: pretty sure people have.
Speaker 0: I mean I've seen remote controlled ones of those where there's a camera feedback and you're just flying a real plane Sitting on the ground.
Speaker 0: don't crash it.
Speaker 0: So, yeah Some other news going on.
Speaker 0: So this is just a little bit but there's a town in North Carolina.
Speaker 0: So basically the south bad place the South's north.
Speaker 0: Yes in the US and in the town of Woodland, North Carolina The citizens of that town did not want a solar plant to happen in their town.
Speaker 1: Well who was?
Speaker 1: who wanted to put a solar plant in their town?
Speaker 0: some company and apparently there already are two solar plants in The vicinity and a company wanted to put another one there are they like a power?
Speaker 0: the power company or I don't know It's private.
Speaker 1: Oh, they wanted to power like their own building like they had it.
Speaker 1: They had their own office building.
Speaker 0: They want a private company could generate power and put it on the grid.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't know about North Carolina regulations.
Speaker 1: Sure, but do you get you get paid for doing that?
Speaker 0: So the council not only rejected the proposal.
Speaker 1: So this is the town council.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay, but voted on a complete moratorium on all solar farms henceforth, right?
Speaker 1: They're probably just all anti not believe in global warming.
Speaker 1: southern nut job.
Speaker 0: one person in the town.
Speaker 1: What part of this is news?
Speaker 0: So one person in the town who was at the student at the student council at the council meeting?
Speaker 1: They break the the South Shell.
Speaker 0: very what do you what do you think?
Speaker 0: There are the reasons that people at the meeting might have said they didn't want this solar B's in the south.
Speaker 1: They're stupid.
Speaker 1: They're probably believing.
Speaker 0: like what reason do you think one of those nimby's would say out loud?
Speaker 1: That they you know, they don't believe in global warming.
Speaker 1: solar power is dangerous.
Speaker 0: you were an order of magnitude off So I gotta get crazier.
Speaker 0: So some of the reasons were cancer the solar.
Speaker 0: well cancer was one of them.
Speaker 0: Okay, they can't tell me these things don't cause cancer.
Speaker 1: Sure Cuz we know we can tell you a coal my coal power plant does cause cancer.
Speaker 0: solar panels would suck up the solar energy going Into the town so plants wouldn't do as well and we wouldn't get as much sunlight Alright, so I mean obviously these are the crazies coming to the town council But the only reasons go to town council.
Speaker 1: the people on the town council are slightly less crazy while still being stupid.
Speaker 1: and southern.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh it would bright.
Speaker 0: It might block photosynthesis for nearby farms.
Speaker 1: That is not true.
Speaker 0: That was a big thing.
Speaker 0: one person complained that they've already surrounded her farm in solar plants and it lowered her property values.
Speaker 0: But a reporter went and checked and there aren't solar plants near her property as far as they can tell.
Speaker 1: and what about her property values?
Speaker 1: Have they gone up or down?
Speaker 0: Uh, it's North Carolina.
Speaker 1: So nothing's worth anything anyway.
Speaker 0: Okay, we might be applying a urbano centric and North centric view to this.
Speaker 1: that is but that is also a factual view.
Speaker 1: There's nothing wrong with being a something centric view if that view is also founded in truth.
Speaker 1: Oh and the other truth centric view also have was the urbano centric.
Speaker 0: They were afraid that if you build solar plants young people won't want to live there anymore.
Speaker 1: I don't think young people care about what kind of power plants are there.
Speaker 1: Also young people don't want to live in North Carolina.
Speaker 0: No matter what power plant you have I don't think there's anything you can do to keep young people there except Entrench them in such poverty and ignorance that they do not know they can escape.
Speaker 1: you can get young people to live there by Stop being a nimby and let awesome things be in your town like a roller coaster and an arcade And a business that isn't backwards and by you moving away from the town Like that.
Speaker 0: tell you what if a small town like that could give me a job that pays even half what I make now With reasonable hours and has another equivalent employer.
Speaker 0: so I could quit.
Speaker 0: It's not a company town.
Speaker 1: build a train and Ikea.
Speaker 0: I can commute without a car.
Speaker 0: I can see a 70 millimeter Panavision movie.
Speaker 1: build a bunch of bike lanes.
Speaker 0: So I can see Hateful Aid on opening night in its real format.
Speaker 0: There's bike lanes everywhere.
Speaker 0: I can see the Opera.
Speaker 0: if I want.
Speaker 1: I can just walk in and see the screen.
Speaker 0: I'd say there's an arcade but there really aren't arcades here, so I can't really hold them to that.
Speaker 0: There aren't roller coasters here either, so I can't complain about that.
Speaker 1: I can go to the game shop any night of the week, and there's like eight people playing netrunner.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, there's got to be at least eight people in the town who play netrunner.
Speaker 1: Well, no not eight people in town who play netrunner.
Speaker 1: when you go to the meetup There's usually around eight people which means is way more than eight people who play.
Speaker 0: so damage control for the town Argued that the actual reason they voted no was that the two previous solar projects did not benefit the town in the way that they expected.
Speaker 0: but at the same time I cannot find evidence that it hurt the town in any way because they bought the land and The land is not worth that much anyway.
Speaker 0: and further even if that is the reason the town council says they voted this way The opinions expressed by the townspeople are opinions by real voters who not only vote in America But are so politically active that they go to town council meetings.
Speaker 0: people like me and Scott don't go to town council.
Speaker 1: Well, that's that's how politics works.
Speaker 1: if you go to a town council meeting It's because you have no job and you have nothing else to do.
Speaker 1: if you have no job and nothing else to do is because you're dumb or Old and you don't know things.
Speaker 1: if you know things you have a job and a life And you don't have time to go to town council meeting.
Speaker 0: no not necessarily.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of people who know things therefore ours.
Speaker 1: We should change it and to make it just like it was in the 1700s.
Speaker 1: We don't need to be like.
Speaker 1: only property owners can vote.
Speaker 1: it should be.
Speaker 1: only people with jobs and brains can vote.
Speaker 0: ah But there are a lot of people with brains who can't get jobs And there's a lot of people who are disenfranchised not being because they don't have access to brain and beginning services.
Speaker 1: Obviously, I was not Right.
Speaker 0: that was just a crazy Sticks again thing about this is when tech issues like this come up in small town meet like I've tried to go to beacon town Council.
Speaker 0: well beacons a city, but you actually ever go to it.
Speaker 0: I went twice.
Speaker 0: whoa you know what it was.
Speaker 0: It was nothing, but inane bullshit that I couldn't affect and actually didn't care about because it literally didn't matter.
Speaker 1: Nothing wasn't a solar panel for you to comment on.
Speaker 0: there was not a solar panel for me to comment on.
Speaker 1: Okay, why wasn't there a representative from the company that wanted to build it at the meeting?
Speaker 0: Uh, I think you know say and I assume they had some sort of musical where they did their both sides.
Speaker 0: And then there was a dramatic Person saying no, that's not true.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: That's not true.
Speaker 0: There's the dramatic debate about evolution.
Speaker 0: at some point William Jennings Bryan got up and gave his speech.
Speaker 0: Oh what that was.
Speaker 0: that was the plan.
Speaker 1: you should be able to sue.
Speaker 0: that was inherit the win not this town council meeting.
Speaker 1: There should be a way to sue at like the next higher level of government of the lower level of government for making a decision Based on false information.
Speaker 0: Hey, County.
Speaker 0: This city is so dumb you need to overstep them.
Speaker 0: Yes, some states have mechanisms for that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: for the federal government You should be able to go to any town wraps around Just a circle.
Speaker 1: Yes, if you go to your mayor and the mayor against some scientists say the federal government, you know did Did something wrong based on false information?
Speaker 1: So they have to undo.
Speaker 0: so Tor has some problems like Tor is you don't say pretty well one.
Speaker 0: it's used primarily by child porn and drug traffickers, but Tor also is Really easily compromised in that the NSA probably runs a lot of the.
Speaker 1: Tor knows I mean, it's so popular and everyone knows it that it's sort of like.
Speaker 1: yeah, it gets the job done But it's not super perfectly getting the job done in a mathematically Guaranteed locked in way.
Speaker 0: so researchers at MIT Have actually created a real alternative and it echoes some of the things that waste did which was we've talked about waste on geek nights A bunch of times we're kind of waste fan.
Speaker 1: I mean Tor and waste are not really alike at all.
Speaker 0: Well, they serve a lot of similar purposes though It's just one.
Speaker 0: what one was an application that offered like chat and all this stuff built in and one is just an anonymized Browse the web and communicate thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you can probably guess what parts of waste this appropriated by its name because the name is vuvuzela.
Speaker 1: Vuvuzela, so it's loud and annoying and you want to punch whoever's got one.
Speaker 0: Ah, I imagine the net with these switches.
Speaker 1: anyone who uses this needs a kickin.
Speaker 0: I imagine the network admins and places that use this will feel that way about them much like I feel about vuvuzelas.
Speaker 0: But the interesting thing is you should read MIT's paper.
Speaker 0: I will link to it directly because in our list can the listener understand this paper?
Speaker 0: So the threat model the as in this is the threat that vuvuzela is designed to avert.
Speaker 1: what threat are they averting?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna quote this because this is real important.
Speaker 0: This is why this is better than Tor and why anonymized Data transfer and anonymized communication is real important.
Speaker 0: So before the threat model what this is designed for on a high level Is that metadata is gathered about.
Speaker 0: you like Scott went to this website and emailed these ten people with this frequency by person.
Speaker 1: So even if we don't have the even if we encrypt all this information, right?
Speaker 1: So the data is encrypted.
Speaker 1: people can still see that X IP made a TCP IP connection to that IP These frequencies and sent this much data across the wire.
Speaker 1: So if I you know, you can pretty much tell even if I'm using encryption, you know Time Warner can look at my traffic rates and which direction the traffic is going in and say he's using bit torrent for something.
Speaker 0: Yep, probably most likely even if all of our chats are encrypted the NSA could figure out.
Speaker 0: Raymond Scott know each other.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they see a whole bunch of download and then they suddenly they see all the download stops and there's a stream of upload.
Speaker 1: They're like, well that was a bit torrent transfer of this about this size probably a movie.
Speaker 0: Joey Jojo emailed this one address a bunch of times on a regular basis Those emails but that address is of a mental health clinic that primarily treats her and you can start and either Joey Jojo or somebody knows needs help with the mental health clinic.
Speaker 0: So the truth suit statements that justify this thing that MIT did are one.
Speaker 0: officials of the NSA stated that if you have enough metadata, you don't really need content.
Speaker 0: true and Separately quote we kill people based on metadata.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: So here's the threat model that they are attempting to circumvent but recently I'm quoting now.
Speaker 0: But rusilla's design assumes that the adversary that controls all but one of the vuvuzela servers Users do not need to know which one Control an arbitrary number of vuvuzela clients meaning possibly every client
Speaker 1: or possibly one client,
Speaker 0: but yours And can monitor block delay or inject traffic on any network link.
Speaker 0: That is a bigger threat model than I have ever considered in anything I have ever thought.
Speaker 0: so.
Speaker 1: in other words the NSA could set up this entire Network where every single node on the network every server and every client is just trying to spy on anyone who tries to use this Thing.
Speaker 1: Yep Scott knows you come in and you start up one server and you add it to the network and you know for sure that one Server is yours that it is not compromised by the NSA.
Speaker 1: It is running the true vuvuzela code that is not compromised and you spin up your vuvuzela client.
Speaker 1: You can communicate securely without them.
Speaker 1: No Any of those the entire rest of the network knowing jack shit about what you're doing.
Speaker 0: So in a sense the NSA is probably going to run most of the nodes on this network.
Speaker 1: So me and rim can set up one server connect to each other and even if the NSA runs every other server and client on The whole network we can communicate in absolute perfect secrecy.
Speaker 0: I've heard the term.
Speaker 0: this is solipsistic security in the sense that I can only know myself, right?
Speaker 0: Yep, I know my node.
Speaker 0: So I'm good.
Speaker 0: I only need to know about one and the one I control counts.
Speaker 0: That's crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah They also is now and all those evil ones will just be helping you out.
Speaker 0: so in this situation two users communicating through vuvuzela should have their communications protected if their two clients and Any server are in compromise.
Speaker 0: We also assume that the server's public keys are known to all users.
Speaker 1: That's what public keys?
Speaker 1: yes, they're public.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you could come up with models where people share public.
Speaker 1: It's anyway, right better generate your public key.
Speaker 0: Well, though because they can still compromise the only other assumption is that the users have a separate mechanism to pre-share Each other's keys or at least discover who is on the other side of the key.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, I mean you could still share the keys over the network But then you'd be giving away metadata of Scott and rim shared keys.
Speaker 1: Yes, so Scott and I would trade like a USB stick once and then we're good we're good or some other website just has a bunch of keys and You go to that website and just search for someone and download their key.
Speaker 0: It works based on think of like cold war spies.
Speaker 0: So you have drop boxes that are bit their mailboxes, but they function like dead drops.
Speaker 0: So I put a message in a mailbox.
Speaker 0: My client puts that message there at some point between now and like 50 seconds from now.
Speaker 0: But I'm also putting messages of randomly encrypted data into a random set of other drop boxes and basically, it's like all.
Speaker 0: communication is two ships passing in the night and there's an infinite number of magic ships filled with bullshit.
Speaker 0: and There's no mathematical way to determine bullshit from actual shit.
Speaker 0: And you can have it.
Speaker 1: and how does the person I'm trying to send the message to get the shit?
Speaker 0: You can read the paper for that.
Speaker 0: But basically because we know our keys We know we've our clients basically know which drop box to get the data from.
Speaker 1: but no and no one else does.
Speaker 0: No one else knows that we are communicating and there's too many other ships.
Speaker 1: They can't find our ship.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: They were looking.
Speaker 0: so this is the kind of shit you need to do if you want to make a real secure communication of real secure networks and MIT is building this one.
Speaker 1: So is there actually software you can get?
Speaker 1: GitHub or something.
Speaker 0: So researchers created it.
Speaker 0: I believe they're running it in MIT right now.
Speaker 1: So you have to code it from the paper to use it today.
Speaker 0: Yes, or meet one of these people at MIT.
Speaker 0: Follow this project if you care about the things that Tor is good at because this will do it better and I doubt it will be back doored.
Speaker 0: so uber but for blank basically means we're gonna disrupt a market by getting rid of all the regulations, not having employees.
Speaker 1: We're gonna set up a company that ignores all laws and just do evil things But be so convenient to the customer that we make a lot of money and then try to fight to keep our business around.
Speaker 0: Never mind that a real- see uber, see FanDuel, see DraftKings.
Speaker 0: Yep Never mind that a real company could have the same- AirBnB.
Speaker 0: Like regular taxis in New York could have the same user interface as uber and Just they'd cost a little more than uber and people would still make you know actual livable money kind of.
Speaker 0: but I digress.
Speaker 0: gigster wants to be uber of Software development.
Speaker 1: Well, that's a little more difficult because unlike say driving a car from A to B. It's a little harder to.
Speaker 1: it's not just pay I'm done It's.
Speaker 1: you know, there's a lot of stuff that goes into software development.
Speaker 0: So apparently I sign up and I send you my idea.
Speaker 0: Gigster then passes on to developers who sign up.
Speaker 1: There's so many implementation details.
Speaker 1: This is why you need like a company if you were working together every day to build the software.
Speaker 0: Yeah, gigster will apparently make put a team together and have them Design it and then send back a functioning app for a flat fee.
Speaker 1: But what about my input other than the idea?
Speaker 1: Can I write a full spec?
Speaker 1: How much spec do I write?
Speaker 1: Well, you know, there's so much going on there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I gotta revise the spec after we see what can be implemented.
Speaker 0: I feel like No level of spec is going to make this work very well and this the sole purpose of this Nonsense.
Speaker 0: business is To for a VC type person.
Speaker 1: and if you can write good software, you're not working for gigster You have a job.
Speaker 1: so it's like you're only getting shitty developers of this, right?
Speaker 0: Or you're getting people who are between work and just want to get paid.
Speaker 0: You know, you're probably gonna get mostly people who are currently in college Or also gonna submit the code they write for you to whatever their projects are inside of the college.
Speaker 1: You're not getting someone you want.
Speaker 0: Yeah So apparently gigster will own the code to the app it designs for you And it leases the software to you with a license.
Speaker 1: It's not good.
Speaker 1: So suppose I'll pay someone else to make something for them.
Speaker 1: It's like no, I'm paying you to make it for me.
Speaker 0: I don't know if this company is trying to steal money from VCs or if they're trying to be a conduit for VCs to have their money stolen by other VC like I. I can't imagine any legitimate use for this Other than in a utopian world economy where everyone has enough money to eat and people only do this for fun.
Speaker 1: I mean, I want to say this is gonna fail because I'm 90% sure it will.
Speaker 1: just I'm surprised hasn't failed already.
Speaker 0: But it was easy.
Speaker 1: people are just so dumb and have so much money.
Speaker 1: Maybe they'll know.
Speaker 0: simultaneously There are probably developers who don't live in cities, but need work.
Speaker 0: I don't know because there's not a lot of coding jobs outside of cities.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this The trend of Ubering business models worries me, but I'm amazed.
Speaker 0: you see such a crass like Gigster is the kind of thing I would make up as a joke in like Robocop as a movie and the fact that it's an article come true.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel like too many onion articles.
Speaker 0: Oh, here's another onion article that came true.
Speaker 0: Phillips pushed a firmware update to their light bulbs that locks out third-party light bulbs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this this is line of light bulbs you can gather LED light bulbs and the controllers, right and You can use like this.
Speaker 1: There's open wireless networking protocol.
Speaker 1: got Zigbee.
Speaker 1: I've used it.
Speaker 1: It's been around for a long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's only pot.
Speaker 1: It's not something that's like a consumer thing, right?
Speaker 1: It's it's mostly a. you know, when you're making products you would use it, right but And you can use it to like communicate with the light bulbs like, you know Turn them on and off when you're not home or change of colors or you know all kinds of stuff, right?
Speaker 1: You communicate with the light bulbs of an app, but I would love to have an app.
Speaker 0: There's just a map.
Speaker 0: my house just control the light bulb.
Speaker 1: It can sort of do stuff like that because I don't have light switches everywhere.
Speaker 0: I want them.
Speaker 1: But anyway anyway, so There they changed it to where you have to use their light bulbs or their approved light bulbs with it in the late if you Update your software.
Speaker 1: You can't just use whatever light bulb you want.
Speaker 1: You got to use their bulbs and it's just like what the fuck and you know.
Speaker 1: on the one hand It's like it's easy to understand why they did this.
Speaker 1: a they want you to buy their light bulbs.
Speaker 1: they make more money.
Speaker 1: but be they're worried that if you put some shitty light bulb in there and it somehow explodes or causes other Damage because they're not you know accounting for every conceivable possible light bulb you might use in their software.
Speaker 1: So they don't want to get sued So they're it's.
Speaker 1: they're also preventing litigation but also being evil with the DRM not letting use whatever the hell light bulb you want.
Speaker 0: But I feel like the middle of the road should be that Unlike like light bulbs that aren't up to spec if they cause a problem you void your warranty.
Speaker 1: Yeah, most people do and you can't sue us and you agree.
Speaker 1: not, you know, it's like that's that's him I don't know.
Speaker 0: which can also in some ways BBS because of the whole like right to repair your own car thing Sure, like should be legally be allowed to let a non licensed Porsche mechanic Mechanic eyes your Porsche.
Speaker 1: I probably wouldn't if I had a Porsche but You might want to and I feel like shouldn't it be required that you give me the diagrams and technically Specs of anything that I buy ever enough to where I could make any repair necessary?
Speaker 1: I'm
Speaker 0: this all Disappearing because we are some of the last people who grew up in an era like literally where when I bought my when we got Our first computer it came with this multi hundred page book that had pin outs Voltage diagrams and schematics of all the chips on the computer.
Speaker 0: I bought a stereo that came with all that my mixer has that now and I bought that like Not that many years ago, but mixers are where they all have schematics are with.
Speaker 0: is this that just disappearing?
Speaker 1: hmm I think it's already disappeared.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean people these days they buy an iPad.
Speaker 0: you never open it true But while that's disappearing, I guess will Modern young nerds like young Millennials the generation after them see this as a bad thing Recognize that it's happening be afraid of it They don't even know anything about.
Speaker 0: do they want control of their devices or have they given that up entirely?
Speaker 1: Even know that it's an option?
Speaker 0: is it okay that they don't know that it's not.
Speaker 1: no But they don't.
Speaker 1: no one knows.
Speaker 1: even old no one knows except nerds.
Speaker 1: nerds only.
Speaker 0: no But the stereotype of a nerd is increasingly becoming someone who consumes technology, but does not know anything about it.
Speaker 1: No, not a lot of people know.
Speaker 0: a lot of our nerds do back into the distance pull out Vuvuzela and live in our own darknet for the rest of time and then die out.
Speaker 1: I hope so.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: Do you have a thing of the day?
Speaker 0: So apparently?
Speaker 1: There's a fancier filler refrigerator you can buy from Samsung and this refrigerator has like a screen on the front and That screen can actually do some sort of cool things.
Speaker 1: if you're just so ridiculously wealthy You could buy a refrigerator with a screen on the front And the most useful of those things is to display your calendar right the fuck there on your fridge where normally you'd look for it Right except now it's a digital calendar.
Speaker 1: so you can get your Google Calendar synced up with it And you'll see all your good, you know, that's really freaking cool.
Speaker 0: That'd be extra great cuz.
Speaker 0: I'd make a sub calendar in Google of like what I'm gonna cook on different days and just be sitting Right there with the recipe and you could get reminders like from the fridge.
Speaker 1: So you stand in the kitchen and just be like hey, I gotta remember, you know, we were eating breakfast this morning You know anyway, so I know the milk is bad, right?
Speaker 1: It's it's kind of cool.
Speaker 1: It's really expensive and probably would never buy this but you know if you're you know, it's it's okay.
Speaker 1: apparently Google changed their API about how Google Calendar works And of course you can't just like a smart TV or so-called smart TV.
Speaker 1: Nobody's making software updates to the Samsung fridge, right?
Speaker 1: Just like Android phones.
Speaker 1: No one's making software updates for those.
Speaker 0: Oh the title of you the title of the thing you're linking to it's not an iPhone Right, so it's not iOS.
Speaker 1: or they keep updating it or it's not Windows or they keep updating it, right?
Speaker 1: They don't update this thing.
Speaker 1: So There's this thread in the Google Calendar help forum that says can't sign into Google Calendar on my Samsung refrigerator and it's really long because I guess a lot of people have this refrigerator and They can no longer sign into Google Calendar on it.
Speaker 1: And so now it's sort of like they paid a whole bunch of money for a refrigerator That no longer does the thing that they paid all that money for.
Speaker 1: You could have probably saved a bunch of money just by getting an old tablet and like taping it to the front of your refrigerator Something with updatable or open source software on it and you would have been better off.
Speaker 0: This is why you should never buy a smart TV.
Speaker 0: never buy any device that has a computer in it.
Speaker 0: That's not a computer if you expect that computer to do generic.
Speaker 1: I mean don't buy some weirdo, you know side.
Speaker 1: you have to buy mainstream bits things that are supported.
Speaker 0: But here's the thing.
Speaker 0: a Samsung refrigerator seems pretty mainstream like a Samsung phone.
Speaker 0: Samsung phones don't get updates necessarily.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean smart TV like my TV is not a if it's not a Google device Microsoft device or an Apple device.
Speaker 1: I pretty much can't trust that it's gonna get updates.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just can't sign into Google Calendar on my Samsung.
Speaker 0: It looks like Samsung's response is eat a bag of dicks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't care you bought our refrigerator.
Speaker 1: We're doing this.
Speaker 0: response is tell Samsung to eat a bag of dicks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we you're supposed to update your software.
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: Wow this I'm surprised.
Speaker 1: Nobody's just flashed the refrigerator the Linux or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because desktop Linux came so far Refrigerator Linux is even further.
Speaker 1: you can run doom on it.
Speaker 1: that refrigerator definitely runs doom.
Speaker 1: I bet even doom to Guarantee you could be a doom on that refrigerator.
Speaker 1: That'll be a pretty even quake one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Ran quick one in software mode.
Speaker 1: if you can run Google Calendar, you might be able to run quake one.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day This is a video got internet cuz it can access Google Calendar You.
Speaker 0: So actually what I really want to see is I want the fridge to head to figure out what's in it and Order groceries.
Speaker 1: for me and within our lives that'll happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, RF IDs, but then we won't be able to update the firm.
Speaker 1: No, even just computer imaging like the self-driving car can drive.
Speaker 1: There's no reason a camera inside the fridge won't be able to tell milk from orange.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I mean that Vivino amp I use.
Speaker 0: I take a picture of a wine label without not even like a barcode, right?
Speaker 0: Tell me what that wine is just before.
Speaker 1: a bunch of can't little tiny shitty cameras inside your fridge and a database and eventually You know, it'll it'll be good.
Speaker 0: I wanted to email and be like yo dawg You put that leftover mac and cheese in there a week ago that shit.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like sailed.
Speaker 1: I mean you're at the grocery store and you'd be like do I need sour cream?
Speaker 1: and it will go.
Speaker 1: ding I see a sour cream in your fridge.
Speaker 1: the date on that sour cream is last month.
Speaker 0: Why would I do?
Speaker 0: Store, it's just good.
Speaker 0: The fridge is just ordering from fresh direct without my intervention.
Speaker 0: That's what happened.
Speaker 1: That would be even better.
Speaker 0: and when I come home it did.
Speaker 0: there's a sour cream already delivered and I take it and I go.
Speaker 0: why did it order sour cream?
Speaker 1: and I know the fridge has access to your Google Calendar and knows and you'll be out of town.
Speaker 1: It doesn't order the sour cream.
Speaker 0: Yep and there's an expired sour cream in the fridge and there's a red light pointing at it in the fridge telling me that that's the One to get rid of.
Speaker 1: no I reach in the fridge and start and I grab it and it'll say throw that shit out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just yells at me Don't eat that.
Speaker 0: So our friend showed it this over the weekend.
Speaker 0: We're having a party.
Speaker 0: It's called afterglow light suit segment.
Speaker 0: It is just this crazy amazing video of two dudes wearing these custom-made suits covered in LEDs skiing down a mountain at night.
Speaker 0: okay, this is crazy awesome to watch and as my follow-up thing of the day here is a longer video of How they made this crazy video with all this lighting down a mountain And it looked like it was really really hard to make this thing.
Speaker 1: the pride sponsors They did corporate variety.
Speaker 0: They had huge sponsors and I find out that I did not say who the sponsors are.
Speaker 0: So that was ad dollars well spent dudes.
Speaker 1: Fuck you sponsors.
Speaker 0: Yeah These videos are super amazing though in the moment new book clubs coming soon old book club was the wheel of time.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be live at Pac South.
Speaker 0: We have three Three panels at Pac South then mag fest then mag fast where we have fucking like seven panels Jesus.
Speaker 1: then there's like an anime Boston and a PAX East.
Speaker 1: after that I don't know what the order is.
Speaker 0: We have to have at least four panels or we don't get our business.
Speaker 0: at anime Boston We'll say thank icon will be coming up at some point.
Speaker 0: I assume Scott's skipping it but I'll be doing four panels.
Speaker 0: have to say you should come.
Speaker 0: I already put in our four panels.
Speaker 0: so we'll say I Enjoy zenkai Khan, but here's what I'm gonna do because you see small cons, but we don't need to see other panels.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna do our panels.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna eat Amish food like all day on Saturday.
Speaker 0: I'm not even going on Friday going Friday night Amish food all day Saturday Sunday I'm gonna play board games and get drunk in that bar by the by on Main Street.
Speaker 1: Why don't we just go home on Sunday?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna stick around perhaps.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna leave like Sunday.
Speaker 0: early evening is my plan.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we The Amtrak goes to the con.
Speaker 0: That's the only reason I go.
Speaker 1: that's it's true, but it still sucks.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but yeah, if you live near zenkai Khan, you should just go like you can drive there.
Speaker 1: I mean no matter how shitty the con is if it's that close to you and thank icons pretty good Like if you live in a place like that, you're not getting a lot of nerdery.
Speaker 0: Thank icon is like 10 derpy cons worth of entertainment.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Yes, not even joking.
Speaker 0: That's true but we were doing Atari game design designing game rules on Saturday and Sunday both at 1 p.m.
Speaker 0: And also on Saturday in the evening Early evening.
Speaker 0: as soon as I have more details, I will tell you there was a third panel.
Speaker 0: Scott's not on it.
Speaker 0: He's gonna go play games like a smart person.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'll be on this panel and you want to see this panel I can't promise we'll video it either and I'm pretty sure Because the person running the panel is a full order of magnitude more famous than we.
Speaker 0: are panels gonna fail.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's weird because on one hand that person told us that like we would be overqualified to be on the panel But on the other hand that person is so much more well-known than we are That well known and qualified are not necessarily the same thing exactly.
Speaker 0: But I feel like they're also qualified.
Speaker 0: but it should be a good panel.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah So Yahoo, at least the story that the tech media is saying is that Yahoo doesn't have QA Anymore and it's awesome and everything's better.
Speaker 0: now that they're quote coding with no net.
Speaker 0: That's kind of not true.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean it Basically, usually when you make software on a team, right?
Speaker 1: You'll have a developer and they'll write some code and then they got a hand that share that code with other people.
Speaker 1: But before you do that You know you double and triple check your code to make sure you're not sharing code this garbage.
Speaker 1: because if you share garbage code With someone they like hey that shit.
Speaker 1: You just sent me that patch.
Speaker 1: It just doesn't work.
Speaker 1: Did you even run this?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you just wrote it and didn't even do anything.
Speaker 1: What the fuck's wrong like?
Speaker 0: if I write a script to give to someone else to run I at least run it once on my own.
Speaker 0: Like okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it worked right.
Speaker 1: you make sure it works.
Speaker 1: And then you'll have QA people who are not developers.
Speaker 1: Double triple quadruple quintuple check it in every possible conceivable way.
Speaker 1: And why do you do this?
Speaker 1: Why doesn't the developer just do this?
Speaker 1: And the reason the developer doesn't just do this is because the developer could be writing code.
Speaker 1: The QA person doesn't have the skills and knowledge to write code.
Speaker 1: if they did they'd be a developer instead.
Speaker 0: pretty much So.
Speaker 1: this way the developer can develop more and then the QA person will find all the bugs do work that the Developer could do.
Speaker 1: but now the developer can focus on developing.
Speaker 1: the QA person can find the bugs.
Speaker 1: Then once they report those bugs It won't take the developer much work to fix them because the QA person Investigated them so thoroughly and this way you get to be much more efficient everywhere.
Speaker 1: so the trend over the past bunch of years has been this idea of Test-driven development or at least lots of testing which is where you write Automated you get the computer to do the tests for you.
Speaker 1: So instead instead of or in addition to having QA people manually check over all the code and run all the programs You have computer programs that check the computer program.
Speaker 0: now again This both of these just like the thing of you know QA people testing Unit tests or test driven development in the right situation is the right thing.
Speaker 0: Like if you have code that say is taking a huge set of structured like XML data like gigabytes of nonsense XML Transforming it into some other kind of data and calculating things.
Speaker 0: You don't want humans like plugging that data through and then like double-checking math or anything.
Speaker 0: You want an application that puts the data in to the code as a black box See the data that came out and it knows what the answer should be and then checks to see if the answer that should come.
Speaker 1: Testing is is a perfectly valid and important and useful thing, you know, there are a lot of different methodologies Places to test right and you should use tests often if not in many places, right and it's just so useful.
Speaker 1: think about it's like you write some code and Now you run it you make sure it works and then you run the tests and it's test in there for all sorts of things And all you do is say run tests and you wait and it'll check and be like, hey, you know what?
Speaker 1: Yeah, your code worked whatever it did the thing you thought it was gonna do.
Speaker 1: but you actually Reintroduced this bug that someone introduced a long time ago.
Speaker 1: and because they wrote a test for the time They made that bug we were able to automatically find out with no one having to do any work Additional work that your new code makes that bug happen again.
Speaker 1: So before you share the code fix that bug and make sure these tests pass
Speaker 0: now that sort of regression testing is probably the best Use case for test driven, but you
Speaker 1: also, you know write a new test for you the new code You just wrote especially if maybe the code you just wrote is a bug fix in and of itself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if anyone you know and then for the future if anyone makes that bug happen and so on and that's a good thing To do it doesn't you know hurt?
Speaker 1: but What Yahoo is doing is basically saying?
Speaker 1: Hey, that's pretty much all we need.
Speaker 1: We don't need the QA people, right?
Speaker 0: That's a bad idea and the way they just at least the way this article describes what they're doing.
Speaker 0: What they're describing are unit tests in a test driven environment But they're describing it like it's this like an amazing paradigm shift like most large software development companies Do both right?
Speaker 0: So that's this is not novel, right?
Speaker 1: So the thing that bothers me here That's obviously a problem is the point of having the QA people.
Speaker 1: is the developers can spend less time Doing the QA part and just develop.
Speaker 1: if you make the developers do QA You have one person doing two jobs.
Speaker 1: Are you paying?
Speaker 1: did you give all those QA salaries to the developers and other developers doing QA's work?
Speaker 1: No, but you gave yeah, you gave him twice as much work probably and it's like yeah as much even if you're testing is so Good is not as good as QA.
Speaker 1: No, did you give any people find shit that tests don't find all the time.
Speaker 0: Yep now there's this separate problem because one of the things that at least Yahoo pointed out was that What they found just sort of analyzing their internal stuff is that the human QA process?
Speaker 0: Was injecting a lot of human error that QA would what I'm reading between the lines that because I see this You know in all the work that I've done a lot of times QA is Introducing work where they're finding issues that aren't really issues due to either them misunderstanding what the code should do Them finding issues that are technically problems But that don't actually affect users or that don't affect the things in material ways.
Speaker 0: And then there isn't a good process for someone to say don't fix that
Speaker 1: or mark is don't fix
Speaker 0: yeah, but I find a lot of companies do not have a rigorous methodology for doing that or they don't have people who have the ability to say those things or Developers who are looking for low-hanging fruit because they don't want to be doing the real work.
Speaker 0: We'll fix a million shitty little bugs Because they don't have the management watching them and telling them no only work on this one.
Speaker 1: The other thing is that in my experience as a programmer, right?
Speaker 1: I don't write tests usually because the code I write isn't medical devices and isn't factory machines and isn't space shuttles.
Speaker 1: So it's not really that big a deal if there's a bug in production.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, no Someone's picture is offset by a few pixels.
Speaker 0: I feel like I was actually in the same boat Like nothing Yahoo does is mission-critical, right?
Speaker 1: So in that case, it's like you're unless your bug is so catastrophic.
Speaker 1: It's like do you even need to test it all?
Speaker 1: do you even eat QA people?
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, you'll feel if you run the code yourself, you know, and you make sure it works It's gonna be 99% good.
Speaker 1: and all those in line unless you're really bad developers and all the ad the but it'll be bugs in Production but big whoop you'll just fucking fix them later.
Speaker 1: You see Twitter is basically down with the fail whale for like its first two years of existence.
Speaker 1: And no, it didn't fuck them over at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so who really gives a shit now?
Speaker 1: really bad important.
Speaker 0: there is a big difference between package software development like here is our Application that we sell that you run on computers or on servers version 4.8.11 versus here is a website that we are hosting and iterating on develop.
Speaker 0: because say I push some code and it fucks up a Website I can just revert it back that night To the previous version because the previous version or that
Speaker 1: minute
Speaker 0: Yeah, the previous version of the code right before I push that other code can't be worse than what just broke catastrophically.
Speaker 0: Yeah at worst the old bug is still there, but if I ship software on a refrigerator.
Speaker 1: It's got to be right.
Speaker 0: so there no one can update that refrigerator, but my worry is that.
Speaker 0: but like, you know Because of the nature of my work.
Speaker 0: I kind of have to use LinkedIn.
Speaker 0: And so I see things people post on LinkedIn and there's a lot of people who are Bandying this.
Speaker 0: Yahoo got rid of QA around as a good idea in Places where it is not a good idea to save money by not having QA people this firewall.
Speaker 0: Yep I also feel like people don't know the difference between Quality assurance as a process versus QA.
Speaker 0: as you've got people testing code.
Speaker 0: QA is a process.
Speaker 0: It's not just a checkbox.
Speaker 1: You also have to make a value a cost-benefit analysis, right?
Speaker 1: So if you're writing something that's not a space shuttle software or refrigerator software.
Speaker 1: Yep What would the cost to you to be of the bugs that go through?
Speaker 1: Get through versus the cost of hiring QA people.
Speaker 0: Let's say geek nights, right?
Speaker 0: We don't have a QA.
Speaker 0: per you know the QA is Scott updates the website and I bitch if it breaks, right?
Speaker 1: Okay, and it's not a big deal.
Speaker 1: So now think about it.
Speaker 0: guys is down for a day.
Speaker 0: How much money do we lose Scott?
Speaker 1: zero?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Here's the other cost-benefit analysis.
Speaker 1: Let's say you have a developer and they can just write code check it a little bit and put it up.
Speaker 1: You have another developer who has to write unit tests for everything.
Speaker 1: You're losing the efficiency on the developer who has to write all the unit test.
Speaker 0: He's 40% slower.
Speaker 1: and because now he's gonna spend all these time writing these goddamn tests The QA person would have been writing and if you can read from Scott's Verbal language they're like read between the lines.
Speaker 0: developers hate that shit.
Speaker 1: They'll probably quit if there's a lot of them who drank the Kool-Aid, but I yeah.
Speaker 0: But I know a lot of developers who would quit if they had to do QA.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if you told me I had to write unit tests for things that weren't important.
Speaker 1: It's like no.
Speaker 1: Sorry.
Speaker 1: See ya Yeah, but so now if a developer has to write all these goddamn tests, they're gonna be so much slower at working.
Speaker 1: Someone's gonna be like no no no the increase their efficiency because the find the bugs and whatever.
Speaker 1: but we don't care about the bugs You already determined.
Speaker 1: the cost-benefit analysis is such that the bugs getting through is not the end of the world.
Speaker 1: But now how much you're how much development.
Speaker 1: you could have had two new features instead of unit tests for the one feature you had.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: so is it more worth it to you to have three new features or one super rock-solid feature?
Speaker 1: now You have to make that sort of decision.
Speaker 1: all right, so I guess Yahoo has decided that they want You know fewer things done more rock-solidly But actually less rock-solidly than they were before.
Speaker 0: because now QA people just the tests Yeah, so I have more like my experience.
Speaker 0: You know my job almost every job I've had has been like the mission-critical.
Speaker 0: people might die crazy bullshit and package software and all this stuff.
Speaker 0: and in my experience the best QA processes involve dedicated QA.
Speaker 0: But basically the people doing the QA are also developers.
Speaker 1: But then couldn't they be developing aren't you?
Speaker 0: so we already have all the developers we need to develop forward.
Speaker 1: But if somebody could be a developer you could develop other things.
Speaker 1: It's like you don't.
Speaker 1: why would you use a person who cool has developed skills to do QA work?
Speaker 1: That's like because that's like if I hired a NASA engineer who could make a space shuttle to fix my car.
Speaker 1: It's like I could be having them making a space shuttle its wasted resource.
Speaker 0: No Because if it's mission-critical.
Speaker 1: I made my toilet out of gold when I made it out of.
Speaker 0: here's a hypothetical example from a Job I had before couple jobs before the job I have now.
Speaker 0: So let's say you've got some pretty mission-critical software like.
Speaker 1: it's not people will die But it's like a lot of people will lose a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like big deal if shit goes south in the software that is going to be deployed It's important enough that you should test it.
Speaker 0: So you have to.
Speaker 1: it's not just a website.
Speaker 0: you have a real crack development team like serious people working together making the software.
Speaker 0: It needs to be tested.
Speaker 0: the testing is complex if you hire people who are QA Specialists, but are not developers at all.
Speaker 0: They're generally not capable of writing the kinds of tools You need to test that efficiently and they end up.
Speaker 0: the developers end up needing to write the testing tools for them to use.
Speaker 0: If the developers were writing the testing tool if we had developers who are doing the QA They would want to do the job quicker.
Speaker 0: They would write the testing tool to be completely automated to not have to do the work.
Speaker 1: I think that's really the best way to go.
Speaker 1: It's like The developers who are making the software, right?
Speaker 1: They don't make them test too much because then you'll get less software.
Speaker 1: have someone else whose only job it is To write tests because they'll get really good at it.
Speaker 1: They'll be able to write more tests than you know.
Speaker 1: Then like the three developers code that they're testing but that person can't be like.
Speaker 1: if my job is only to test code I can test the code of like five developers and I'm just one And Right.
Speaker 1: I could write the test and do the testing and do everything all at once and you'd get the rock solidness But you also would get the efficiency at the same time.
Speaker 0: Yeah And this does discount UAT and all those other kinds of things.
Speaker 0: We're just talking about QA like the basic babies.
Speaker 1: first Make sure it doesn't crash at a QA.
Speaker 1: make sure the number that one plus one comes out is two and not as five.
Speaker 0: But you know to get to your point the specific problem is so you get you know upon upgrade.
Speaker 0: fatal error at startup.
Speaker 0: Application fails.
Speaker 0: Here's the log.
Speaker 0: Here's the error.
Speaker 0: That's not that useful because now the developer still has to do all the work and test them to figure it out.
Speaker 0: I'd rather have a QA person who knows the code enough to say well it failed in that class.
Speaker 0: Let me look at the code and see if I can figure out what the problem is.
Speaker 0: Right, if you have a person say yo dog no pointer exception your serialization is fucked.
Speaker 1: You could even make so if that person could even be good enough just to fix bugs like you have their job is just there Developer.
Speaker 1: they're just only a bug fixer and not a feature maker.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of times you will work on open source projects.
Speaker 1: All they do is fix other people's bugs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they don't write any new stuff.
Speaker 1: They just go to an open source project They find bugs they fix them and they submit their patches to fix them.
Speaker 0: So if you're crazy mission-critical like, you know, and when I was in the hospital like people might die mission-critical Cross-development you have a you have two teams developing two things.
Speaker 0: Then when you get to the point of like it's stable and ready for testing you swap Projects and now their job is to write the tools and test the other person's stuff.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That is what you do if people will die.
Speaker 1: Yep I don't think that's done and you also check it like many more than one time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, check it so many times Yeah, but that that's when you go, you know people like to make fun of like.
Speaker 0: not necessarily add but like the waterfall model or like Methodologies of software development all methodologies is stupid if you're doing mission-critical stuff like people will die.
Speaker 0: Having a defined methodology just means it is very well defined.
Speaker 0: what is tested where and when.
Speaker 0: you can very quickly converge on failure And you can very quickly identify where something got fucked.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but you don't need that.
Speaker 0: if you're running Yahoo Games It's okay.
Speaker 1: Yahoo Games is broken.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, someone shot the moon in hearts and didn't get the right score.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I'd be real mad.
Speaker 0: But yeah, who doesn't make any money for me anyway, so This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and tonight's patrons are in the order of the amount of money that they give us on a monthly basis.
Speaker 0: Nicholas Brandau Rebecca Dunn James David white Christian coons Jess mechanical mind testing.
Speaker 0: one Two three Phil Ulrich Amanda Doucette Renee from New Zealand Robert Lee Ryan parent drew Openlander rare Lavelle Brian Sidroni Rochelle, Monta, Nona Finn Eric Silveraad rim eats poop kinetic man William Eisen rose Erin Cerise Chris midkiff Chris Knox flame dark fire Samuel Cordery Daniel Redman Chris Haddad Doug Snyder Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: So I haven't put this information on the actual site yet.
Speaker 0: I kind of hinted at it on Twitter and a little bit in the forum, but It's not officially announced yet, so I'm burying it down here for people who actually listen to the end of the show.
Speaker 0: But so you know that third panel I was talking about.
Speaker 0: it's just me It's not Scott because Scott we do our usual lectures But occasionally I will be asked to join someone else's panel Just because I go to dev and I actually respond when people email me and Scott's kind of surly and you know how the deal Is.
Speaker 0: but so I'm going to be on very likely This is like 90 something percent confirmed at Pac South other than Atari game design and designing game rules an unnamed panel on horror in games With Chris Straub.
Speaker 0: He's the person moderating it and I'm just a panelist and some other people at least one other person.
Speaker 0: I won't name any names other than that yet because I can't necessarily confirm them, but it'll be Saturday at 5 30 p.m in a panel room to be determined.
Speaker 0: so 1 p.m.
Speaker 0: On Saturday 1 p.m.
Speaker 0: On Sunday and a 5 30 p.m.
Speaker 0: On Saturday is the horror panel.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I'll be able to video it and get it out to you guys.
Speaker 0: Apparently, I'm an expert on horror games.
Speaker 0: now It seems like this came mostly out of that.
Speaker 0: five nights at Freddy's video I did and some other stuff and I kind of realized scarily that I actually am up on the current state of contemporary short horror fiction and I'm actually Pseudopod and other sources, so I think it's actually me a good panel.
Speaker 0: So I suggest you line up for it because Chris is way more famous than we are.
Speaker 0: So our panels don't always fill all the way, but I suspect this one will.
Speaker 0: and now I leave you with the thing That Scott will never hear literally the opposite of Zen Some sort of sound.
Speaker 0: if you're clever you can figure out where these things come from I feel like only Chris Reimer is betting a thousand in terms of actually finding them.
Speaker 1: I ain't got no time for nobody.
Speaker 1: My style is rich, dope, fat, and rich.
Speaker 1: We'll make a cake today that looks rich.
Speaker 1: Crack, crack, crack the egg into the bowl.
Speaker 0: M-I-X the flour into the bowl.
Speaker 1: M-I-X the flour into the bowl.
Speaker 1: Crack, crack, crack the egg into the bowl.
Speaker 0: Baking a cake Yes, means you gotta try.
Speaker 1: I'm doing this for years, but don't ask me why.
Speaker 1: Butter, butter, butter joins the bowl.
Speaker 0: Butter, butter, butter joins the bowl.
Speaker 1: We're making us a cake that you've never seen before.
Speaker 0: We're making us a cake that you've never seen before.
Speaker 0: Heat up the oven, now we're on a roll.
Speaker 1: We'll heat up the oven, now we're on a roll.
Speaker 1: We'll make a cake that you've never seen before.
Speaker 0: I put birds and words in the flower's room in the ticky, ticky, ticky, ticky, ticky room Clap clap, clap clap, clap clap.
Speaker 0: Let's say you're in the ticky room Clap clap, clap clap, clap clap Clap.
Speaker 0: you're in the ticky room.
Speaker 0: Welcome to our tropical hideaway.
Speaker 0: You love me, people, you.
Speaker 1: If we weren't in the show starting right away, we'd be in the audience too.
Speaker 0: In the ticky, ticky, ticky, ticky, ticky, ticky room.
Speaker 1: In the ticky, ticky, ticky, ticky, ticky room All the birds and words in the flower's room.
Speaker 1: In the ticky, ticky, ticky, ticky room.