Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, July 21st, 2015.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We're talking about party games specifically Jackbox games.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: I would have tried to make a joke about like yeah, you don't know Jack, but I don't know anyone.
Speaker 1: I don't think I've ever known anyone named Jack In my entire life.
Speaker 0: I did camp counselor was named Jack one really yeah Maybe maybe my roommate and I had a co-worker named Jack that roommate at RIT.
Speaker 1: I never knew his name might have been Jack.
Speaker 1: I don't really know.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: don't ask me about your roommate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just don't ask me about my roommate.
Speaker 1: People always think it's weird that I never knew the dude's name.
Speaker 1: We never talked to each other.
Speaker 1: We just sat back to back and that was.
Speaker 1: that was it.
Speaker 1: Our only interaction was once he said yes something happened to your fridge when that wine bottle exploded in it.
Speaker 0: I Beat a. I beat a Porsche 911 in a race today on my bike.
Speaker 0: oh Yeah, I know that sounds impossible But there was a lot of traffic in his way and I can get through Emily and I beat the seven train on Sunday.
Speaker 0: It's not hard either.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we biked to flushing and yeah, we can bike to flushing way faster than the seven goes to flushing.
Speaker 1: It's a nice bike though, there's basically a bike path that goes almost straight there the whole way.
Speaker 0: yeah pretty much.
Speaker 1: We also found a secret path back that I never used before.
Speaker 1: Okay, yeah, cuz I said I wouldn't talk about the commute But I can talk about this.
Speaker 1: so instead of going on the one side of Citi Field We went like on the backside by all that weird car repair districts you mean Willits Point yeah that whole area there, and you went along the water.
Speaker 1: No So there's a. it looks like you're gonna get on the freeway and get the more you bike.
Speaker 1: that way You're like.
Speaker 1: this is just taking me onto the freeway.
Speaker 1: I'm going on the freeway and now it's telling me to go into a parking lot.
Speaker 1: And then actually on the freeway by the movie theater no There's a little hidden bike path that I never would have even known was there And it's kind of creepy and isolated and like at this weird place.
Speaker 1: I only found it because I had Google Glass on and I was like glass.
Speaker 1: take me home And it told me a bikeway, and I kind of followed it despite my better judgment saying this doesn't seem right But it totally was right.
Speaker 0: this goes along the water to the West.
Speaker 1: No, that's not.
Speaker 0: I don't know where the hell you're talking about you.
Speaker 1: on a map It's not long because you get to the normal bike path right after all that.
Speaker 1: But there's just one little like shunt.
Speaker 1: it goes through a weird place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Didn't expect you to.
Speaker 1: I just found a cool path.
Speaker 0: How do I doubt the coolness of your path?
Speaker 1: it was pretty cool, uh-huh, I was very pleased with this path.
Speaker 1: sure I Can't talk about anything else related to biking.
Speaker 1: Thanks to my promise.
Speaker 0: Is there any gaming news that has a ton of gaming news?
Speaker 0: Way too much gaming news if you haven't done a show in a long time.
Speaker 1: We actually I think wasn't our last show a gaming show.
Speaker 0: that was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I was like right before kinetic on.
Speaker 1: it wasn't that long ago still yeah, so we were at kinetic on and There's a bunch of gaming news.
Speaker 1: so first off.
Speaker 1: There is the Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: that happened that we haven't talked about it all yet.
Speaker 0: Shenmue 3 Full and I never played Shenmue 1 or 2. so why would I?
Speaker 0: These games on like the Sega Saturn or the Dreamcast or whatever there isn't or a PlayStation.
Speaker 0: They were on systems I didn't have and couldn't play.
Speaker 1: these games are those games that a lot of people I knew knew people who were really into them But I never really knew anyone who was really into them.
Speaker 1: and the best way I can describe them is you know how?
Speaker 1: in modern?
Speaker 1: Pokemon games there's a mill.
Speaker 1: you just wander around and do a bunch of million things that don't really matter at all.
Speaker 1: Imagine that times a hundred.
Speaker 0: yeah everything ever read about this game would simultaneously be like whoa.
Speaker 0: That's so cool like you can do everything.
Speaker 0: It's like real-life simulator almost, but then it's like oh There's no reason to do everything It's just a time waster.
Speaker 0: you might as well be rune factory for.
Speaker 1: well in fact there.
Speaker 1: Well rune factory 4 has the dating element.
Speaker 0: It has dating and farming and monster killing and all the things yeah as every possible thing.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a.
Speaker 0: that's all there is in life right?
Speaker 1: remember that old old old penny arcade comic about those games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: So what's interesting is that this was the definition of an old?
Speaker 1: Popular franchise that it just sort of disappeared that was definitely niche Not actually that widely played or that why I had so much critical Acclaims and the people who did get into it and didn't enjoy it.
Speaker 1: It was like the best thing for much like Sonic the fans Sonic the Hedgehog erotic fiction.
Speaker 1: It's one of those things where there's a small, but extremely vocal and dedicated fan base.
Speaker 1: So yeah the Kickstarter happened, and it raised like over six million dollars.
Speaker 0: That's about right.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: well What's interesting to me the the the point about this is that a lot of people were saying we're complaining That the game raised so much money and a lot of other people seem to have really overblown expectations about the game like because it raised such a huge amount that the game is gonna be like the fully realized vision of Wander around and randomly do stuff in convenience stores.
Speaker 0: the game six million dollars isn't a lot of money.
Speaker 1: No, okay for a budget for a game like this.
Speaker 0: Maybe if they had 30 million it would be that you need more than that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this game's not going to be the second coming of Jesus Or I guess the first coming is Jesus never existed, but I digress.
Speaker 1: But it is very interesting to me that This kind of property was remembered enough by people dedicated enough to our 70,000 people collectively pledged Six million dollars.
Speaker 0: Can you emulate this thing?
Speaker 0: I'm curious to go and play the old ones.
Speaker 0: Should we do it see what the reality is?
Speaker 1: should we just play these games?
Speaker 0: It's not possible to emulate them.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna do it.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna buy a Dreamcast or some shit.
Speaker 1: I'll bet you can get one on eBay real cheap Whatever.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it.
Speaker 1: No, I mean we might have a Dreamcast.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna have one laying around.
Speaker 0: you have a Dreamcast just laying around.
Speaker 0: No, you don't.
Speaker 1: I have someone we know probably has one that someone you know, but you don't.
Speaker 1: yeah, I'll have that pile of any s's.
Speaker 1: I'll trade someone.
Speaker 1: Actually, one of the any s's has a low serial number and apparently people who really care about this too much Care about their what.
Speaker 1: which of the 11?
Speaker 1: Versions of the chip or the board in an any s you have?
Speaker 0: well One of those is my any s and one of them is I think your brothers or something.
Speaker 1: Well, and there was the third one that we gave away to someone.
Speaker 1: I forget when but that was the one that we won When I won.
Speaker 1: right right.
Speaker 1: so come turn him.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: So the one I think your original any s is the one that got given away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we have the duck hunt one that we won and we we we we I won Sure.
Speaker 0: and then my original any s from when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: So mine is probably the old.
Speaker 0: mine came with a red gun though.
Speaker 0: So it can't be red guns.
Speaker 0: Not the old one can't be old if it has the red gun.
Speaker 1: the difference between them is actually useful if you're a collector Like it actually is.
Speaker 0: what's the difference?
Speaker 1: the earliest boards have no lockout at all?
Speaker 1: So every tangen bootleg bullshit cartridge will totally work fine.
Speaker 0: Mine worked with tangen Tetris.
Speaker 0: Yeah with micro machines I never tried my and those Bible games never tried Bible games but we definitely were able to play tangen Tetris on that any s. cuz it happened.
Speaker 1: so as Versions came out the last versions of the any s actually locked out.
Speaker 1: top loader everything You mean top loader know the lat of the original any s the top loader even diff.
Speaker 1: No, the top loader had a different board.
Speaker 0: Okay, but the top loader was the last any s.
Speaker 1: Yes, but it was also a different iteration of the any s. it was a different sku.
Speaker 1: It wasn't just a different board.
Speaker 0: inside of the same sku my cousin had top loader.
Speaker 1: Yeah I Remember when the top loader came out.
Speaker 1: I couldn't understand why anyone didn't already have an any s.
Speaker 0: Yeah Either.
Speaker 0: and now it's like man.
Speaker 0: I wish had a top loader so much more reliable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so what this gives me?
Speaker 1: Hope.
Speaker 1: I'm now waiting for the radish skull and devil.
Speaker 0: doll Kickstarter make it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just make it and hope that the guy who made radish skull and devil now sees it And decides that he's actually gonna make it.
Speaker 1: I don't think he owns the copyright though.
Speaker 1: Remember all that complicated story of why they didn't own thing.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I don't think he does.
Speaker 1: That's why the rest of it didn't get made.
Speaker 1: That was like a promotional thing.
Speaker 0: So that's your news.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be a psychonauts.
Speaker 1: I'm waiting for that to get remade.
Speaker 1: All those games all those weird things gives me.
Speaker 1: Hope that maybe in a far future They'll be an advanced Wars Kickstarter Rampart Kickstarter Rampart Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: We just make rampart.
Speaker 1: just fucking remake it.
Speaker 1: kaboom - yeah electric boogaloo bombaloo You got any news.
Speaker 0: There's so much gaming news going on I can't even Touch but I just want to pick this gaming news since I have the most to say about it Even though there's probably more important.
Speaker 0: gaming news is out there.
Speaker 0: Yep So I guess ESWC stands for eSports world championship or European something world championship.
Speaker 1: I actually can't keep all the league straight in my head anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, look it up ever.
Speaker 1: I don't
Speaker 0: know but You know, it was a eSports championship of some kind and There was counter-strike played there and this guy on team Nehillum or Nylem or whatever named Simpis S-E-M-P-H-I-S is doing this interview about what happened there and He just comes out and admits that his whole team was on Adderall the whole time
Speaker 1: which like that's actually pretty common.
Speaker 0: I mean if there's such high stakes and you want to win and there's no rule against it and there's no drug test Why wouldn't you?
Speaker 1: Yep, that's why we have drug testing in professional sports, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know, this is something that you know, this is yet another example of something we've been talking about for years That actually came to be or is actually now in the spotlight and it's like, yep, look how smart we are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it's interesting because you know, actually one of our packs panel to talk about about a moment But we are doing a panel sports or games talking about games and sports and the overlap A moment of that panel discussing this rather this topic.
Speaker 1: Yes, and it'll be really interesting because we're seeing gaming and professional gaming go through all the same sort of learning curves as professional sports and interestingly very few of the leagues seem to be Actively looking at like the NFL like what do they do?
Speaker 1: Why don't we just do that?
Speaker 0: I mean and you know and you think about okay So the big eSports leagues might do something about this eventually or maybe they won't.
Speaker 0: maybe It's like well if you want to win eSports, you're gonna take Adderall, right?
Speaker 0: Otherwise, how are you gonna compete?
Speaker 0: Yeah But what does this say for like your local Street Fighter tournament at your college, right?
Speaker 0: One guy takes Adderall and wins well at the same.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess the difference is do you know some?
Speaker 0: or and as time goes on you think Adderall is gonna be like the only Drug, right?
Speaker 0: There's gonna be some crazy shit out there.
Speaker 0: You can take it's like I.
Speaker 1: you know, I run like dumpy local races and I'll you know win a trophy or whatever.
Speaker 1: But if I wanted to really what if I just started using strychnine to win those races?
Speaker 0: Well, they'll kill you also.
Speaker 1: No strychnine was actually so, you know how we should all have a race walking Cuz it's a terrible sport.
Speaker 0: There's drugs and racewalk.
Speaker 1: race walking might be the first sport that people use performance enhancing drugs in.
Speaker 1: Wow Yeah, they would dope themselves up on strychnine and all sorts of stuff just to keep it going just to keep walking keep walking.
Speaker 0: But that doesn't.
Speaker 0: how could that help?
Speaker 1: it does.
Speaker 1: it keeps you awake.
Speaker 1: it's they would use.
Speaker 0: Sleeping is what makes you lose.
Speaker 1: Well, so in the old days race walking was more of a endurance challenge.
Speaker 1: It was just whoever goes the longest.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 1: days and days and days and days and days The sports.
Speaker 1: they fucked up history and it's still a terrible sport.
Speaker 0: But if you needed one more reason to hate it, but I mean take for example, right like the netrunner world champion, Dan Yeah, he's an okay guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah ish right ish.
Speaker 0: He's okay.
Speaker 0: He's not like a bad person and he's really fucking good at netrunner.
Speaker 0: But it's like we're at the Philly regionals.
Speaker 0: It is his local store and he's just like vaping in you know, because the store doesn't stop him.
Speaker 0: It's his store.
Speaker 0: They don't care.
Speaker 0: so I can't say anything about it.
Speaker 0: if the store allows it All right, may or may not and it's like state be illegal I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know about the laws or anything, but in terms of the fairness of this tournament I mean, it's just a small time.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a netrunner regional, but I mean a netrunner regional might as well be like, you know In terms of all the gaming sports tournaments in the world, that's pretty low bar, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's probably even smaller than your local 5k race or whatever You know, and it's it.
Speaker 0: he's taking drugs.
Speaker 0: Is it helping him?
Speaker 0: I mean part of the tournament is that you got to play seven rounds in netrunner and then elimination rounds You know and last the whole day and keep concentrating and stay on your a-game the whole time from 11 a.m To like 11 midnight midnight.
Speaker 1: So here's there's the question that that will Right.
Speaker 1: when should he be?
Speaker 0: even if you made him go outside is he still is that easy allowed to do that?
Speaker 1: When and why did the NHL and the NFL and Major League Baseball and all these things crack down on start testing for drugs in sports?
Speaker 1: Was it not partially because the government started getting involved and poking his nose and saying I do something?
Speaker 1: I don't think the government is capable of even understanding that video games Played professionally are a thing for at least 20 more years.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you know if the it's because the big big professional sports in the US are regulated in some ways by the government?
Speaker 1: Yes, partly because of the money and the infrastructure and also, you know The government just had a vested interest for various reasons.
Speaker 0: plus when you know, and the the sports leagues buy into this, right?
Speaker 0: You know, there's all the controversies about like, you know, the local people buying stadiums for the teams.
Speaker 0: It's like well sure It's like.
Speaker 0: we probably shouldn't be doing that definitely shouldn't be.
Speaker 0: but if we are Suddenly right there the sports leagues are allowing all that sort of government interference to come in.
Speaker 0: It's like well, we bought you a stadium which means now we can get fuck you over.
Speaker 1: But I I don't think there will be any such pressure from the government unless the story and the narrative become.
Speaker 1: Kids are doping themselves up in these video game tournaments.
Speaker 1: But I suspect the reaction will be banning video game tournaments not regulating them like we regulate the NFL.
Speaker 0: But I mean, you know, the other thing is like why even ban this right?
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: Just allow it.
Speaker 1: well, you make the same argument about football right and the answer is it fucks you up and Maybe we shouldn't encourage football.
Speaker 0: fucks you up drugs or no drugs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the drugs do not help.
Speaker 0: So use baseball as your example instead.
Speaker 1: Okay or tennis.
Speaker 0: Yeah tennis great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why not allow it in tennis?
Speaker 1: Well, because those drugs do have hired increase like increased chances of death.
Speaker 0: Let's say someone invented a performance enhancing drug that Didn't really hurt you that much.
Speaker 0: I mean is Adderall really gonna shorten your life that much?
Speaker 1: really maybe you don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm not a pharmacologist.
Speaker 0: It's not like you're not like you're on crack or meth.
Speaker 1: It's more the question of do you want sports to go down that road?
Speaker 1: because then everyone in that sport Will have to go down that road to compete.
Speaker 1: and if that is the case and there are adverse effects You're probably causing a net harm to society for no tangible benefit.
Speaker 0: It's also creates this barrier to entry where like someone like me I can't.
Speaker 0: if you know everyone in the whole who plays this game is taking this drug and I don't want to take that drug Then I can't compete in that sport.
Speaker 0: That's like an unfair barrier to entry.
Speaker 0: Imagine if you want to go get a job, right?
Speaker 0: Remember sports.
Speaker 1: All right, Scott.
Speaker 0: I'll turn around To go get a job.
Speaker 0: and they're like if you want this job, you must snort some cocaine.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, you can't have this job.
Speaker 0: That's basically what they're saying.
Speaker 1: I'll play the devil's advocate.
Speaker 1: back at you I got a kind of real example.
Speaker 0: that is sports or a job.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so For my job I pretty much have to be able to drink alcohol.
Speaker 1: with people like.
Speaker 1: I can Drink less and actually I have more than one dump drinks out in bushes.
Speaker 1: but if I didn't drink alcohol and didn't hide that fact a lot of people would like it would be difficult for me to do Business because that's just how that world is.
Speaker 1: So you couldn't do my job.
Speaker 1: This is the barrier to the same barrier to entry.
Speaker 1: Is that okay?
Speaker 0: Probably not.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right Here's another example.
Speaker 1: There is a barrier to entry to baseball in that you have to be super strong and you have to be willing to work out a Bunch, are you willing to do pull-ups every day?
Speaker 1: or is that a barrier to entry?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean that's the thing is right.
Speaker 0: It's like genetics Gattaca, right?
Speaker 0: I mean there are certain things that are you know, do you have the skills for the job?
Speaker 0: It's like oh you can't be a programmer unless you have programming skills.
Speaker 1: What if one of those skills is willing to take Adderall, right?
Speaker 0: You know willing and you know able are different right?
Speaker 1: Well, you're able.
Speaker 1: you just aren't willing.
Speaker 0: That's you know, there's a lot of questions there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are a lot of questions.
Speaker 1: Maybe this is gonna be a fascinating panel We're running at packs.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this is just.
Speaker 0: you know, this is just the first instance I've seen of just someone coming out and admitting what everyone already knew.
Speaker 1: Well, they do they admit it but not for Adderall.
Speaker 1: It was always one step below that.
Speaker 1: It was like the energy drinks in the caffeine and the guarana and all that shit.
Speaker 1: This is like a step up.
Speaker 1: right, you know There's cocaine and amphetamines going on - you know every there.
Speaker 0: anything that can help anyone is being used.
Speaker 1: But at the same time I get the impression a lot of things that don't help or in fact Actively hurt are being used as well.
Speaker 1: I don't think marijuana really makes you better at counter-strike.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, I doubt it does.
Speaker 0: Yeah But you know, it would be interesting right for like a you know, especially for things like, you know Due to his vaping right is a mild stimulant like, you know regular old e-cigs really gonna help you that much?
Speaker 0: Maybe not right, but if there's such a serious competition and say somebody is you know Like addicted to that and your answer to that is like anyone who's competing during the course of the tournament.
Speaker 0: We're gonna lock you in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the reverse barrier to entry of up.
Speaker 1: Sorry, you're addicted to cigarettes So now you can't compete in eSports, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you're you know, that's part of the thing right.
Speaker 0: when you go black dynamite I'm addicted to steroids and cocaine like when you're in the Olympics, right?
Speaker 0: Not only do they test you but it's like they're.
Speaker 0: you know, they're keeping you in that Olympic village and shit.
Speaker 0: You can't go screwing around Inside the village, you know, so there's another similar story sex.
Speaker 0: Apparently Olympic Village is so much sex going on.
Speaker 0: So because it's all hot people from around the world who are relatively young and also I thought I was gonna bring that up.
Speaker 1: I was gonna I was gonna make that's like the sex fiesta of the world.
Speaker 0: is the Olympic Village?
Speaker 1: Make an oblique reference to that and then turn it into a joke.
Speaker 1: and you were just like, oh, yeah You know, it's a sex village.
Speaker 0: It is pretty much everything.
Speaker 0: I've heard is the Olympic Village is like the sexiest place.
Speaker 1: so at Evo 2015 fighting game tournament happening Street Fighter 4 dudes controller broke in the middle of it and The story around this is pretty interesting, but it's a finals.
Speaker 0: First of all, it's a big deal.
Speaker 1: This is a big deal, but you can read the story.
Speaker 1: We don't report news on geek nights.
Speaker 1: We just comment on it.
Speaker 1: What we want I want to talk about is that the rules that they had they had rules about this about what to do with The right, you know Evo is like a legit thing that's been going on for a long time.
Speaker 0: It's like they're not amateur hour when it comes to this kind of situation.
Speaker 1: So here are the rules on equipment failure in a tournament at Evo.
Speaker 0: Okay reporting equipment failure I mean the fact that they have these rules shows it's not amateur hour.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean and like.
Speaker 1: this is another example of this area this arena this Genre of gaming is maturing.
Speaker 1: video game hardware has the tendency to break down during tournaments.
Speaker 1: buttons or joysticks will occasionally break down in the middle of a match leaving a Player on the broken side at a significant disadvantage.
Speaker 1: The following rules will be used in the event of a break breakdown one in the event of an equipment player Failure.
Speaker 1: the player has the out there a lot of typos in this.
Speaker 1: I apologize.
Speaker 1: the player has the option to stop the game in progress and obtain a replacement.
Speaker 1: if The game is stopped in progress the reporting player must forfeit the current rounds.
Speaker 1: New equipment must immediately be available.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sure the pros are bringing multiple joy.
Speaker 1: It doesn't say who is responsible for that.
Speaker 1: That's something the end of the NHL pros are the pros.
Speaker 1: They're not showing up with one fight I know but I'm saying the NHL rules have things like the sticks are provided in this Capacity the pucks.
Speaker 0: your equipment manager takes care of it But it's all in the rules.
Speaker 0: if you're if you're so pro at Street Fighter that that is your job Because that's how good you have to be to make it to these finals.
Speaker 0: and at Evo You've got probably a person who's carrying a joysticks around.
Speaker 1: But what it's just.
Speaker 1: it's interesting to point out that this equivalent section in ice hockey rules is like four times longer.
Speaker 1: sure New equipment must be immediately available.
Speaker 1: if replacement equipment cannot be obtained in a timely manner you lose.
Speaker 1: the player must continue to play on their current equipment or Forfeit the match.
Speaker 0: Well, if your thing is just completely broken doesn't do anything.
Speaker 1: You're just gonna lose The entire match not around.
Speaker 1: sure once replacement equipment is obtained the player is given the rest of that round to configure their buttons and test the new equipment if The player gains an undue advantage by doing so Exempli a gratis charging an abundance of super meter.
Speaker 1: They must forfeit that game.
Speaker 1: Mmm that rule is good, but has too much ambiguity.
Speaker 1: It says charging an abundance of super meters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let me charge a little bit.
Speaker 0: It's if you charge any super meter at all.
Speaker 0: Why is that fair?
Speaker 1: Yeah, now maybe charge it a little bit is kind of like stepping a little bit past the base.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, just push it a little bit kind of like in hockey Like yeah, if you drop your stick Well, fuck you.
Speaker 1: like you can try to pick it up.
Speaker 1: If you break your stick, well, you gotta go get a new one.
Speaker 1: You don't get another person on the ice while you're doing that.
Speaker 1: So Oh a player may opt to switch out equipment between games with no penalty.
Speaker 1: Yeah This occurs.
Speaker 1: the player will be given ample time to configure his buttons before the game begins.
Speaker 1: Not super fan of the gendered language, even though that's technically correct, but whatever whatever.
Speaker 0: but yeah.
Speaker 0: So they but they have a rule for the situation and the situation happened.
Speaker 0: So they followed the rule, right?
Speaker 1: Yep, they followed the rule and the story is that apparently The players thought that the fact that he had to forfeit was kind of bullshit.
Speaker 1: So they agreed to alternate procedures among themselves.
Speaker 0: So while that's I mean on paper, that's kind of cool, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, okay That's at.
Speaker 0: the thing that actually happened is probably a more satisfying thing, right?
Speaker 0: Someone didn't just get an automatic loss They actually played it out.
Speaker 0: They even like Right and they really restarted the thing.
Speaker 0: They let the timer run down to where the timer was when the breakage happened and they punched each other just enough to have as Much damage done to them as it was when the thing happened.
Speaker 0: so it's like they picked up where they left off which is kind of much more satisfying for the Spectators and for the fairness of who wins right.
Speaker 0: if you just get an automatic loss because your controller broke That's kind of disappointing and not cool.
Speaker 0: So what happened was cooler, but You can't just have two players Deciding to use a different rule.
Speaker 0: You can't be like at the Super Bowl.
Speaker 0: at the start of the Super Bowl both coaches come out and they're like,
Speaker 1: yeah Ref,
Speaker 0: we both decided that during this Super Bowl touchdowns will be worth five points instead of the usual
Speaker 1: but at the same time Because these are eSports unlike human sports with just humans bumping into each other There are.
Speaker 1: there is a lot more capacity for rolling things back and doing alternate procedures.
Speaker 1: So that kind of interaction could be one of the hallmarks of some eSports in the future.
Speaker 0: that it yeah That would be a good thing, right?
Speaker 0: I mean the fact that you can Like at a football game.
Speaker 0: sometimes if there's like it's hard to roll back more than one play To redo something if something was mess.
Speaker 1: imagine I'm not saying the same but imagine an advanced wars tournament.
Speaker 1: You could theoretically roll back in turns if you needed to write like the net runner tournament.
Speaker 0: I was at some.
Speaker 0: something that happens a lot is Someone will like Accidentally leave their cards behind in the previous game and it'll get shuffled into their previous opponents deck and then they'll play a new game And then in the next round and missing some cards.
Speaker 0: and that's why you count your cards for every round to make sure you have Them all and you don't have any extras.
Speaker 0: and if you do have extras then you give them back, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like I've had seen people play games Missing cards in their deck and you know, we don't have rules yet because the company that makes netrunner sucks at this.
Speaker 0: But I've seen some judges say yeah You'll just have to replay that game since the game you played with while missing cards doesn't count and you just roll it back.
Speaker 0: But you know in eSports the rolling back is much more possible Than in say baseball where you'd have to keep fans there for another two hours if you rolled back to say the fourth inning.
Speaker 0: You know, you can roll back.
Speaker 0: You can say up that last Street Fighter match didn't count.
Speaker 0: play it again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this matters a lot.
Speaker 1: Remember the Omega.
Speaker 0: you can say this Starcraft match fucked up at one minute.
Speaker 0: It's all recorded digitally.
Speaker 0: We'll just read roll the replay back to the one-minute mark.
Speaker 0: Ready set go.
Speaker 1: Remember the Omega thon finale at PAX East.
Speaker 1: that was the Nintendo World Championships redone and how the games failed Like more than halfway through the first go.
Speaker 1: so they had to start over and do it again.
Speaker 1: The team that was winning the first time was winning because they knew how to play fucking Mario one Yeah, the other team didn't.
Speaker 1: but because the other team Basically got that practice round and then they had to start over.
Speaker 1: the other team was able to win.
Speaker 1: They would definitely not have won if they'd played the original match all the way through But the original match was fouled by an equipment failure.
Speaker 1: Mmm, so these issues.
Speaker 0: While there are many more ways to roll back but in a professional competition Learning something from the practice match isn't gonna make a big difference.
Speaker 0: Yeah unless what it could.
Speaker 0: right if you're playing Street Fighter and Practice match and someone revealed their hidden card that they had been saving for the finals And then that match gets undone and they have to redo it again.
Speaker 0: But now, you know, they're hidden card.
Speaker 0: They better have another hidden card.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, yeah, or even what about just situations like What is the test of skill you'd always talk about in an ortho game?
Speaker 1: What is the thing that you're ostensibly testing?
Speaker 1: the omega-thon is ostensibly testing a combination of your skillet games and your knowledge of games.
Speaker 1: So now that the people who had more knowledge of Mario 1 lost that Advantage because that knowledge was given to the other team in the restart anyway, eSports are both simpler and easier in the sense that you can do clever things with the rules and you can buck all the traditions that constrain a Lot of sports,
Speaker 0: but even though even the most pro level ones still are not Mature yet in terms of you know, I mean they're getting there rapidly.
Speaker 0: Evo is probably the top tier if there is a tier But it's still not as good as it needs to be yet.
Speaker 1: Also final note this stuff is gonna be big business down the road.
Speaker 1: So it's already big high school kids looking for careers in the future.
Speaker 1: eSports eSports stuff is actually a valid career path, right?
Speaker 1: I mean like team managers You're basically all the jobs that like baseball and football have.
Speaker 0: you could be the equipment manager for someone who's really good at Starcraft And you're all like getting keyboards and mice and polishing them and shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could be the commentator You could be the ref you could be the commissioner.
Speaker 0: Yeah, boo.
Speaker 0: And then they'll be talking about you.
Speaker 0: I'll be booing you.
Speaker 0: They'll be talking about you on ESPN, you know You could be the the trophy polisher, right?
Speaker 0: It's your job to manage.
Speaker 1: the Starcraft Hall of Fame is the one that the biggest thing that eSports lack is a Stanley Cup equivalent.
Speaker 1: Make it yeah There's got to be an.
Speaker 0: make an overall eSports championship and make a trophy for it and then manage it in a Stanley Cup fashion.
Speaker 1: Well, you know we could do.
Speaker 1: we could do it the way they have to.
Speaker 0: they have to compete in the FPS the RTS the fighting game the turn-based strategy game of some sort boxing the actual sport and also the The What the classic arcade style game.
Speaker 1: so, you know we should do oh and pinball.
Speaker 1: the easy way to do that because you don't we don't have we don't own an NHL is You know, the Stanley Cup was a challenge cup for a long time.
Speaker 1: You make it a challenge cup You just officiate it and you set it up the way the Stanley Cup was.
Speaker 0: So we just we just award it to the best eSports person in North America.
Speaker 1: every start using our own discretion Yes to start and then we basically just manage the rules of When and how it can be.
Speaker 0: we should go to the same place that Lord Stanley got the Stanley Cup from and buy a new Cup.
Speaker 0: Oh, so I'm sure a silver cup is expensive but affordable, especially if it's gonna last so long.
Speaker 0: It's probably worth it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what can a silver cup be?
Speaker 0: a few thousand dollars?
Speaker 0: Might even only be hundreds of dollars.
Speaker 1: silver isn't what we have to make the original that we keep ourselves for the museum piece.
Speaker 0: No, you know you get the use like the Stanley Cup.
Speaker 0: They used that first one for quite a while until it got big.
Speaker 0: then they did something.
Speaker 0: then they made more.
Speaker 0: If it never becomes big, why would he buy two cups?
Speaker 0: One failed cup we can have so anyway.
Speaker 1: things of the day Crash bandicoot games were not that good.
Speaker 0: Like they're not There's 3d platform ease.
Speaker 0: I never cared.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've never really.
Speaker 1: they're very few of those games that I like Pretty much.
Speaker 0: you played Mario 64 and you really like it.
Speaker 0: you can play Mario Sunshines or galaxies and whatever.
Speaker 0: and then what do you need more of those for?
Speaker 1: but crash bandicoot exists and Very recently as in days ago their cutscenes That were for the first game Animated ones that were never actually used that had surfaced Occasionally and people seem to think they were from a an aborted cartoon.
Speaker 1: But no, these were just lost cutscenes that weren't included in the game and Someone found them got permission from the producer of the game and put them on YouTube days ago.
Speaker 0: I like.
Speaker 0: I don't know Really it much about crash bandicoot at all But like the big very beginning of this looks very familiar Like.
Speaker 0: I feel like I've seen that background before.
Speaker 1: yeah, because that stuff is in the game.
Speaker 0: I never played the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well you might have bumped into.
Speaker 0: I feel like I've seen that guy.
Speaker 0: Those some of those characters are vaguely familiar, but the background is really familiar.
Speaker 0: I feel like this is reusing animation cells or backgrounds from something else that I've seen before Because I definitely haven't seen this before.
Speaker 0: that's not possible, right?
Speaker 1: So so, uh, yeah, you're really into furry adjacent properties like Sonic.
Speaker 1: Here's the beach here of that a never before seen footage.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 0: so, you know, we love to talk on geek nights about.
Speaker 0: You know shit like making guns with your 3d printer, yeah, we do.
Speaker 0: here's a dude.
Speaker 0: I don't know who this is or what they do.
Speaker 1: the feds do because there's been a lot of Talk to him.
Speaker 0: They got it.
Speaker 0: They got a gun a real gun like a handgun the kind that can kill somebody.
Speaker 0: They attached it with a stick To a drone with propellers on it and he arranged it such that it would fly Fire the gun and then the recoil would sort of push into the drone but the drone wouldn't crash or anything.
Speaker 1: drone is surprisingly capable of handling that recoil and it can shoot.
Speaker 0: so You can just fly this drone and then shoot someone with it.
Speaker 0: It's possible.
Speaker 0: Welcome to the year 2015.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I posit that within a year or two Someone's gonna be murdered in the u.s.
Speaker 1: By another civilian with a drone.
Speaker 0: I don't say a year or two I say five years because someone who is smart enough and capable of setting up the gun on drone is Someone who is smart enough to have a job and have a good life and be whatnot.
Speaker 1: Engineers were evil the world would collapse such that they won't be murdering anybody.
Speaker 1: But what if Someone like defense distributed got a little cough going on there Lingering for like days decides to make the 3d printed gun that Automatically works that connects to your 3d printed drone?
Speaker 0: You have to be you have to.
Speaker 0: it won't happen until this is so accessible until the self kitty.
Speaker 0: once Florida man can do this then there will be a big problem.
Speaker 0: but until then it's just gonna be this awesome thing that we can talk about academically.
Speaker 1: cuz I'm gonna say if I if I were Like evil or there was someone I really needed to kill a drone like that Just fly up to their window and shoot them through their window and that would be the end of it.
Speaker 0: if there was something I really needed to kill I would pay someone to run them over with their car in New York City.
Speaker 0: cuz You basically don't get punished for that at all.
Speaker 0: It's an accident.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but why would I want to kill someone in New York?
Speaker 0: Maybe they're visiting.
Speaker 0: it's possible.
Speaker 1: It is possible, you know evil dictator visiting the UN Something like that in a moment.
Speaker 1: The book club book is still not water ship down.
Speaker 1: Scott did upset to update the website.
Speaker 1: It is the wheel of time the eye of the world the first book.
Speaker 1: I'm about Bob little over halfway through it.
Speaker 0: I'm a little over 25% through.
Speaker 0: I read them yesterday.
Speaker 1: They're not on the second boat.
Speaker 1: Are they?
Speaker 0: they're not in the second boat.
Speaker 0: They are in the city that they got to.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh my god, it's a city.
Speaker 1: You mean like barrel out of the share line, whatever.
Speaker 1: They're not in the city city or the city city city.
Speaker 0: No, they're the first the first city they've ever seen.
Speaker 0: bear land.
Speaker 1: Okay, you've.
Speaker 1: uh This is gonna be another situation where I finished the book and then like a year later we do the show.
Speaker 0: this book is big.
Speaker 0: Yo, yeah, and it's not that I don't I read slow.
Speaker 0: I'm actually read way fast.
Speaker 0: I just don't.
Speaker 0: I go home and I watch something else instead of reading.
Speaker 0: I've been reading but what I've been to my new thing is that since my iPad died actually You know, I used to when I go to bed I would you know iPad until I went to sleep.
Speaker 0: But now since my iPad is gone and not getting a new one till it comes out Hopefully iPad Pro comes out and that's not just a rumor You know, I've been reading only books and comics before going to bed instead of Ipad.
Speaker 1: Oh books say yeah books like that book.
Speaker 0: Yeah that book.
Speaker 1: Okay, as long as you're reading that book already yesterday because I'm not that excited about finishing this book.
Speaker 1: So I don't want to be in a situation where I have to wait.
Speaker 0: You can just read any book you want while waiting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the problem is well with some of these books.
Speaker 1: if I read a bunch of books I'll forget.
Speaker 0: my nuanced points Shows how that tells people that the book may be forgettable or unforgettable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but also like the prince of nothing like I got to read it again Run a regular basis to be able to talk about it.
Speaker 1: Apparently, why not?
Speaker 1: So other than that, we're going to be at PAX Prime 2015 Every year.
Speaker 0: we keep thinking they're not gonna accept our panel, but they always do.
Speaker 0: Thank you.
Speaker 0: Thank you packs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the best your favorite con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the number one convention on earth for nerds PAX Prime.
Speaker 1: So on Sunday August 30th at 1 p.m.
Speaker 1: In the Sphinx theater We are we are actually moderating a proper panel the far future of gaming.
Speaker 0: This is rims idea.
Speaker 0: Yep, I stole it from someone else.
Speaker 0: He stole from a forgotten master.
Speaker 1: I actually know I stole it from myself because I ran the same thing at mag fest two years ago.
Speaker 0: But you stole that from those y plus 30 people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's not a Saying that you stole that.
Speaker 1: it's like saying yeah Lord of the Rings They just stole that from the idea of a fanciful story.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's not it's going to be me and Scott.
Speaker 0: Luke Crane the community manager for games at kick people confirmed Yeah, they positively said yes, they're gonna be there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're gonna be on the panel.
Speaker 1: Scott I've had I've been talking to them for months about this.
Speaker 1: You just you're.
Speaker 1: you're never involved in these conversations.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I have a conversation about a panel like this every year.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It just packs didn't accept them for a while Partly because the P part of the people I wanted on them would bail or fail or whatever.
Speaker 1: So finally, I only asked people that I know would be pro.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So Luke crane, you know burning wheel starter definite pro cat small super pro UX and game designer at Brooklyn game.
Speaker 0: Marie the most pro.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she still work at SoundCloud.
Speaker 1: Also, you think so.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she's so awesome.
Speaker 1: Josephine food the lead game producer date night.
Speaker 1: Oh also a good friend of ours also futurist.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and Emily Compton.
Speaker 1: You may know her from old episodes of geek night getting Emily a free badge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also she does work in the gaming industry super legit.
Speaker 0: So totally count.
Speaker 0: and thus it's not just.
Speaker 1: we actually have people Representing a wide range of games and game design, right?
Speaker 0: You've got us two jerks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got.
Speaker 0: indie RPG also works at Kickstarter Luke.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: You've got like academic UX and game design.
Speaker 0: Right that small.
Speaker 0: this is like the most Variety panel we try.
Speaker 0: I guess the only thing we're missing would be Andrew with his VR ness.
Speaker 1: I tried to get someone from oculus on this panel because that would have been the only thing we didn't have The closes we've got.
Speaker 0: I guess you also don't have triple-a game developer.
Speaker 0: We don't need them.
Speaker 1: Uh, I would like to have one of them.
Speaker 1: I can think of two people either one of which would be great But due to corporate reasons, they probably couldn't be on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, that's probably the same reason Andrew isn't on either.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no Andrew is also just afraid of saying something stupid.
Speaker 1: I think.
Speaker 0: hey well, you know after his uh his juice incident And then on Monday August 31st at 4 p.m.
Speaker 1: In the Sphinx theater again Remus Scott panel.
Speaker 0: Yes sports are games That's right.
Speaker 0: Don't be disrespecting the sports just cuz you're at packs.
Speaker 0: Yes, many self-described gamers will issue games like football or ice hockey or booze ball But you should not issue them.
Speaker 0: sports are games and we're gonna give you the smackdown if you try to Disports like the most perfect game on earth with just tennis and if you actually live on the west coast as opposed to you know Most of the people just fly to packs after packs.
Speaker 1: September 2nd in Portland I'm giving a lecture on story games game design and UX at kai-fu.
Speaker 1: So if you want to go see me like sure.
Speaker 0: if ooh, what the hell is that kai-fu?
Speaker 0: It sounds like a martial art computer human interaction forum of Oregon.
Speaker 0: It's an organ specific.
Speaker 0: It's like I guess there is a lot of software development going on in Oregon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's an academic.
Speaker 1: So I'm Mike Sellecker the guy who runs packs dev.
Speaker 1: He's lecturing like the week before me.
Speaker 0: I think oh this thing happens more than once this.
Speaker 1: well, this is a lecture series.
Speaker 1: I so every week a like someone from the game industry who has something really interesting to say is in this lecture series.
Speaker 0: Oh, so it's not a convention.
Speaker 1: It's a once a week deal about yes until it ends It's like a limited engagement.
Speaker 0: So is it like at a school or something?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so look Emily treat went before me like silica.
Speaker 1: These are all game designers game.
Speaker 0: Is there anyone I know?
Speaker 1: You probably know you probably know some of these people but don't recognize their names.
Speaker 0: Some of the little weird silhouette things look familiar.
Speaker 0: Is there a little silhouette for you?
Speaker 1: There is a little silhouette for me.
Speaker 0: Where is it right there?
Speaker 0: That's not.
Speaker 0: someone said that's okay.
Speaker 1: Someone said that it makes me look like pendulette a little bit like a young pendulette.
Speaker 0: pendullette lost mad weight.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, he did.
Speaker 1: Also, he's leaving Vegas to tour somewhere else.
Speaker 0: Well, he's just here.
Speaker 0: He's coming to Broadway.
Speaker 0: They've done that before.
Speaker 0: That's not the first time they've been.
Speaker 1: I wonder if they'll go back to Vegas cuz they're the venue they were at.
Speaker 0: I don't think they're leaving Vegas.
Speaker 0: They're just temporarily doing a Broadway show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that show in Vegas I don't think ever ends.
Speaker 1: the thing is Contract.
Speaker 1: if I were them like that resort like the place they play live in Vegas.
Speaker 1: I know but the place they perform Kind of Crappy and old-school compared to modern Vegas isn't every place they in Vegas like that.
Speaker 1: No, all the places on the new like main strip are Super modern kind of scary how well-designed they are and the place that pen and tell her at just feels really dumpy in like early 90s styling Whatever.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, so I will be doing that lecture on September 2nd, and you should totally come see it.
Speaker 1: We will likely a video of it.
Speaker 1: And for once I'll have other people professionally doing all the video.
Speaker 1: You'll get the can we go are there?
Speaker 0: how?
Speaker 0: when did this thing start?
Speaker 0: this start already?
Speaker 1: Yes, we go for well are there?
Speaker 0: can we put the link so I can watch the already happen talks?
Speaker 1: I will link to this and we'll go from there.
Speaker 1: All right, so we had a 4th of July party and We as always were playing a bunch of games with a bunch of friends at it.
Speaker 1: When you have a lot of friends over there aren't a lot of games that a lot of people can play except party games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the old, you know apples to apples cards against humanity comes out.
Speaker 1: Yep, and you know what those games have to play.
Speaker 0: spot it.
Speaker 1: But the our go-to our go-to for this party that worked out real well was mount your friends a gift from the hitman heart That has gotten a lot of play and I'm
Speaker 0: I don't feel like I'm good at that game But every time I play it I do really fucking well.
Speaker 0: you do really fucking well, but in the end and he doesn't matter I'm pretty good.
Speaker 0: I won.
Speaker 1: I won that one that one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was the biggest one we'd ever played.
Speaker 0: one previous ones.
Speaker 1: Do you have one previous ones?
Speaker 1: I will give you that you were good at this game.
Speaker 1: And it's not the duck hunt.
Speaker 0: It's like assembly programming.
Speaker 0: It's like in my mind.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the fuck I'm doing.
Speaker 1: But when I go to do it somehow it's like oh It's interesting seeing which of our friends are good at it Which of our friends are not because it's not the people you'd expect be good or not good at it.
Speaker 0: No, it's like someone to be like the master of fighting games.
Speaker 0: It's like whoa, they're so good at video games and you play mount your friends and it's like dirt.
Speaker 1: But then so Conrad and Joe were like, whoa, you should install jackbox games.
Speaker 1: I was like what like you don't know jack like those old games shit from the 90s.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he was like, yeah There's a thing on steam just install it.
Speaker 0: So rim you'd never played any of these ever before.
Speaker 1: I've always known about you don't know jack and I just never gave a shit because I Had my fill of party trivia quizy kinds of games Like when I was a little kid and in high school when these were popular.
Speaker 1: I was in quiz ball I had I was doing that like in a
Speaker 0: Thing with you don't know Jack is I played it in the 90s and we would sit around someone's computer Right with with like a 14-inch monitor and we all you everyone have like a button on the keyboard that's their button for ringing in or whatever and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: and Even though it was sort of like it was like a really trivia party game.
Speaker 0: But the things that made it kind of more awesome were that it wasn't just straight-up trivia like Trivial Pursuit.
Speaker 0: It was clever trivia and really interesting trivia.
Speaker 0: so even though if you weren't winning or whatever you were either learning or Being fascinated and it wasn't really a lot of internet in those days if there was any at all as AOL days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, you know, it's like you could you know a cat picture like oh my god Not that I had cat pictures in it and You know, it was sudden.
Speaker 0: you could play in that party atmosphere.
Speaker 0: But also this the polish of the game itself graphics and sound wise with the narrator with his cover.
Speaker 0: I think they have the same narrators even since the old days even in this new one.
Speaker 0: I think it's the same person It sounds the same.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's like just the way they talk and you know The whole presentation of it really makes you feel like you're on a professional game.
Speaker 0: show it.
Speaker 0: You know if you can't actually go on the Family Feud, but if you can get your whole family to play You don't know jack game together You're basically you feel like you're on the real double.
Speaker 0: dare something at home?
Speaker 1: double dare can't do so Way back to kind of frame all of this.
Speaker 1: why we're talking about this?
Speaker 1: is We?
Speaker 1: what we had said was that the GameCube was like the height of Nintendo's Interesting innovation in that they had that Game Boy link cable.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and that they underused.
Speaker 0: Yes They only use everything that they've invented except the only things they haven't underused are the concept of a portable console the touchscreen the analog stick and The two screens of the DS.
Speaker 0: that's the only things they haven't underused.
Speaker 0: everything else they've invented They've underused so I guess also the button and the d-pad.
Speaker 1: that was that was an idea that they never capitalized on other than Final Fantasy crystal chronicles and Or swords and for source and verse and pac-man verse three only three games three kinds.
Speaker 1: quite a right So they never.
Speaker 1: you know, the DS should be able to connect to the Wii and do that But it just fucking doesn't.
Speaker 1: and they've never done any of this.
Speaker 0: and I gave up even just make fucking poker where it's Texas Hold them on the TV is the table and in your 3ds in your hand.
Speaker 0: You can see your hand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's even just that just straight-up poker that any card game You're bugging, you know, the concert just but user.
Speaker 1: the concept of everyone having their own screen That they can see is a killer app for like Thousands of game ideas.
Speaker 0: Yep, and there's all these game ideas are completely untapped.
Speaker 0: so I've known for a while being a you know programmer that is technologically feasible to either have a server running somewhere a web server is you could use it not web server also or Something running on an HD PC doesn't really matter and then Everyone on their phone or laptop or tablet Connecting such that you could do the same kind of game where on your TV communal screen is one thing and on everyone's individual device is their personal hidden information and you can make games like this, but I've never seen anyone do it or Do it well Until now.
Speaker 1: Yep So we've seen people do like SMS or whatever.
Speaker 1: This thing just fucking worked to the to a point that I was pretty intoxicated because it was a big party.
Speaker 1: So I like install this game I'm gonna play it and I just sort of hit go and not only did it just work But it just worked requiring eight people to individually go to their phone and do a bunch of shit, right?
Speaker 0: So Technologically, it's I'm pretty sure this is how it works is you run the application.
Speaker 0: It's actually a local Windows app.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a game right in Steam But you can actually just run the app on someone's phone to get it from the App Store or something.
Speaker 0: So you run this app.
Speaker 0: the app connects to the server.
Speaker 0: that's in the cloud somewhere, right?
Speaker 0: So you have really, you know, and it's connecting with like this one API.
Speaker 0: So it gets the information that needs to be public Meanwhile on the server in the cloud.
Speaker 0: So like when they're when this game could disappear one day if they take their server down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because my steam server my steam game will go to the server and say I need a new game Right, and then the server gives it like here's the code for your game right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah so you go on your phone and go to the website and You type in the code and then it knows aha this person typed in this code.
Speaker 0: They belong to this game And so that's how everyone joins the game as they type in the shared code.
Speaker 1: But we're even everyone communicates with this server.
Speaker 0: that synchronizes everyone and uses web sockets Yep to communicate with all your devices.
Speaker 1: that is key because it's web sockets.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much just live like you're just connected to a web socket is basically a way to trick a web browser.
Speaker 0: Not trick it but the way to make a web browser have a TCP IP connection.
Speaker 0: You can just send data across arbitrarily.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, you can just play quake over a web socket.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 1: Yep So it's what got me was that it just worked.
Speaker 1: It was super responsive Like way like real-time like I put in an answer and the screens immediately makes the noise or whatever.
Speaker 1: like it was.
Speaker 0: it was fast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like it worked it helped that everyone was on the same Wi-Fi with files But I wasn't.
Speaker 1: most people were not connected to the wire.
Speaker 0: You're using your phone phone.
Speaker 1: I was using my phone phone.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow.
Speaker 1: Also, we had just changed the Wi-Fi password because the router had just caught fire.
Speaker 1: So a lot of people were not connected to the Wi-Fi didn't matter.
Speaker 1: totally worked fine.
Speaker 0: I was on the Wi-Fi.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it was really amazing.
Speaker 1: and Basically, if you have friends who come over and everyone people have smartphones or literally any device with a web browser Yeah, any tablet will work.
Speaker 1: fine.
Speaker 1: anything with a web browser that has an internet connection It has to be a web browser that does support web sockets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think someone had an old phone and it actually said on their screen Sorry, your browser doesn't support website, but I don't think you can use like the 3ds browser.
Speaker 0: There is also a 3ds has a web browser.
Speaker 1: There's also an app.
Speaker 1: So I think you could use the app even.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I saw the app in the App Store.
Speaker 0: I think you can use the app to actually run the game.
Speaker 0: So you could like install the app on an iPad use the iPad as the communal device and then everyone sits around the iPad with their phones.
Speaker 0: Or you can use the video out from the iPad to the TV or who knows what right?
Speaker 0: Or send the screen of the iPad to the TV with an Apple TV.
Speaker 1: So the games it has.
Speaker 1: it doesn't have a lot in it, but it has only play.
Speaker 0: so we browse through the games.
Speaker 0: But we only played two of them that were recommended and that supported eight players.
Speaker 0: Some of the other ones don't support so it's got regular old You don't know Jack?
Speaker 1: the same thing that's existed since I was a little kid up to four players.
Speaker 1: The three that are two that are up to eight players Which is like the sweet spot for this game because eight people is a good number of people to play a game at a party Like this.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Fibbage, which is the lion game.
Speaker 0: So as we played that one
Speaker 1: Drawful which is
Speaker 0: played
Speaker 1: on a dictionary basically
Speaker 0: that too
Speaker 1: and then word spud, which is basically just the match game
Speaker 0: Mmm,
Speaker 1: and then the last one which takes up to a hundred players looks like a light version of the fibbage one lice water, okay, it's a bit because you know.
Speaker 1: Realistically, yeah, these games could have large numbers of players.
Speaker 1: practically, you've got to Minimize the interaction and minimize how much the game blocks on someone not taking their turn quickly.
Speaker 1: That's why only one of the game supports 100 players.
Speaker 0: So fibbage.
Speaker 0: the way fibbage works is it shows a sentence on the screen?
Speaker 0: Like with a question or a sentence with a blank in it or whatever and everyone lies and makes up an answer.
Speaker 0: you make up an answer that you want people to Believe is the right answer But you don't want it to be the right answer.
Speaker 0: It has to be a false answer.
Speaker 0: then after everyone has submitted their false answers By the way, if you type in the right answer, it will tell you that you're right and make you type something else.
Speaker 0: Then it will show all of the answers that people submitted as well as the real answer.
Speaker 0: Protip.
Speaker 1: if you can't spell you're never gonna win this game.
Speaker 1: Do you have to?
Speaker 0: so so from the get-go regardless of being clever and I'm coming up with something good to type in.
Speaker 0: You want to a type something in in a way that looks like the way the game would phrase the answer Right and spell it properly and punctuate it the way the game does so it fits in with the other answer.
Speaker 0: Is it like if you use camel case or you know?
Speaker 0: Do something weird or use a word that probably the game wouldn't use?
Speaker 0: it sort of stands out and people like that's obviously not The right answer.
Speaker 0: so then you choose which answer.
Speaker 0: once they're all displayed you choose which one you think is the correct answer.
Speaker 0: You might know the correct answer because you typed it in in the first place.
Speaker 0: But yeah, just choose that one.
Speaker 0: Anyone who chooses the right answer gets a bunch of points and Anyone who has their false answer chosen by someone else gets a bunch of points.
Speaker 0: yep, straight-up party game and then you get score and then you just keep doing this and the points increase and the questions get crazier and Then someone wins.
Speaker 1: Yep, and then the draw.
Speaker 1: the one is basically just Pictionary like.
Speaker 0: So it tells you to you know, tell one person to draw something So you draw it and then people try to guess what it is Right, it seemed yeah, but everyone's kind of drawn a picture and it comes down to.
Speaker 1: People can't draw like no one can draw.
Speaker 1: None of our friends can draw especially not on your iPhone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like even the artist.
Speaker 0: and it doesn't doesn't let you erase either.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so even the artists who normally like in a real-world Pictionary situation would be great.
Speaker 1: They were severely Constrained by the way this you get one color.
Speaker 0: Everyone has their own color to draw in.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the things it gives you to draw I had the worst possible.
Speaker 0: I the first like the concept of hope.
Speaker 0: the first thing it told me to draw was family values.
Speaker 0: And it's just like are you fucking kidding?
Speaker 0: How am I supposed to draw family values?
Speaker 0: if you said family matters I go to draw on an Urkel But you said family values what the hell am I supposed to do?
Speaker 1: So the moral of all this I mean we don't need to review party games in depth is that this thing is Really legit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the technology aspect of it is really what makes it happen.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a party game.
Speaker 0: It's a good party game.
Speaker 0: You could you know, you could have this party game going on.
Speaker 0: Just you know, even without any technology.
Speaker 0: but having the Technology just made it so much easier for people to jump in if we brought this.
Speaker 0: if he busted this out like as a board You know, it would be like an e-poop you cat.
Speaker 0: only some people go to it and some people don't.
Speaker 0: the fact that it's on The TV it grabs the center of attention.
Speaker 0: People are sitting around on their phones.
Speaker 0: Suddenly you're sitting around on your phones together.
Speaker 0: that really brings everyone in no problem.
Speaker 1: And the thing is it's the barest minimum effort once the technology is there.
Speaker 0: the technology is there.
Speaker 0: I just I just learned how to do a really good pattern for writing a web socket Application the other day.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's a really great video.
Speaker 0: It's awesome.
Speaker 0: So I can make these.
Speaker 0: but here's I just need someone to do the front-end part to make it look nice.
Speaker 1: The game design part of this like these games are so great The barest effort was put into the game design side.
Speaker 1: That's not even the hard part.
Speaker 1: it amazes me that no one's really done this until now, so What I say to you out there Give up on Nintendo.
Speaker 1: They have had the technology to do this on Nintendo consoles since the GameCube era.
Speaker 1: They have squandered that they will never make use of multiple screens That all that multiple people are holding.
Speaker 1: ignore Nintendo.
Speaker 1: give up on them.
Speaker 1: I mean Smash Brothers doesn't even work that well in local multiplayer.
Speaker 0: You just make wizard with this.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah We should just make to prove the tech that we can make the technology happen as well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe we should just as a proof of concept.
Speaker 1: and then all we have to do is sit down and design.
Speaker 1: You know you do.
Speaker 1: you design like ten games that are at least as designed as fibbage and drawful and BAM.
Speaker 1: You've just made something amazing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we try to make wizard for this.
Speaker 1: Yeah We should license that art.
Speaker 0: I'll just scan them in and use them and then in our in our proof of concept.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just to make it work.
Speaker 0: and then you know If anyone wants to make it look nice, they can just replace all those.
Speaker 1: So I'm sorry Nintendo It's just you.
Speaker 1: this was you were here.
Speaker 1: You had this and you never let it be what it was born to be.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.