Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, June 17th, 2015.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I am still sky and this is still geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We're still talking about Ore Monogatari my love story.
Speaker 0: I guess just my story.
Speaker 0: We don't know enough Japanese to really understand.
Speaker 0: I guess it's implied that part.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So this past weekend a lot of our for, you know, we only really go to one anime con.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah really one anime con.
Speaker 0: we go to anime Boston.
Speaker 1: We went to anime next to once many many years ago, and that was it.
Speaker 1: You know, it was worth going.
Speaker 0: That's where we saw rent our own sorry in Taro there.
Speaker 1: You know, it was a good time.
Speaker 0: We went with like katsu.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we went with katsu for the most part.
Speaker 1: It's like we saw rent our.
Speaker 1: we walked around the dealers room And then we were like, oh, there's really nothing else for it was a you know You know what that was.
Speaker 1: you can go back and listen to the geek nights.
Speaker 1: or we talked about it.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: It was that was the last time I went to an anime con.
Speaker 1: Didn't we do a panel there?
Speaker 0: No, no where we weren't guests like.
Speaker 0: we just went to an anime con right for fun.
Speaker 0: We don't do that We haven't done.
Speaker 0: this is the last time.
Speaker 1: so anime next is still going and it's pretty good anime con.
Speaker 1: It's never been really awful.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I hear why worried.
Speaker 0: I heard that the panel rooms are pretty small.
Speaker 1: I don't think it really concentrates on panels too much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a typical anime con, but it gets it done.
Speaker 0: So all our friends were there this past weekend, so I got to see that Twitter stream, but you know, we were doing other stuff.
Speaker 0: but now There's some news.
Speaker 0: I didn't know until.
Speaker 1: Anime next is making a change that might lure me back into their foal for 2016.
Speaker 0: You can pre-register now.
Speaker 1: Good job.
Speaker 1: All right, you're already doing a good job.
Speaker 0: if you pre-register in the next week.
Speaker 0: This week it's 40 bucks for a weekend pass.
Speaker 1: That's cheap.
Speaker 0: But the news is that anime next 2016 is in Atlantic City.
Speaker 1: It's moving.
Speaker 1: It was in North Jersey.
Speaker 1: now It's going further away from where I live Closer to the beach and it's a summer con or at least late spring con.
Speaker 1: It's in June.
Speaker 0: If anime next we're in Atlantic City last weekend I would have been there and I would have spent about a third of my time at the con and the rest just at the Beach.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean Atlantic City for people don't know used to be a big fucking deal now.
Speaker 1: Or you could fly easily to Vegas now It's not as much of a deal and it's sort of.
Speaker 1: a lot of the hotels and casinos are closing and it's bad times in Atlantic City, but that I guess means the Convention Center space is cheaper to rent because no one wants to be in there.
Speaker 0: Now we kept thinking which means anime cons can move on in.
Speaker 0: There's a big Convention Center actually in a Wildwood.
Speaker 1: It's not as big as the Atlantic City.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, but big enough.
Speaker 1: We were thinking enough for a small con.
Speaker 1: by no by no.
Speaker 1: by is definitely big enough for a small con.
Speaker 0: But here's the big difference.
Speaker 0: You need a car to get to Wildwood.
Speaker 0: You can take trains from New York to get to Atlantic City.
Speaker 0: That's true, uh, I think I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: we'll submit some panels for anime next 2016.
Speaker 0: Maybe we will.
Speaker 0: I'm Kind of feeling this because imagine if anime Boston was the same as it was this year except every second We were bored in between like all our fun stuff.
Speaker 1: go to the beach.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we were just laying on the beach and cosplays on the beach.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my photos on the beach that guy who was dressed up as beach episode.
Speaker 1: or if they're smart outdoor anime screening on the beach.
Speaker 1: If they're smart get on that.
Speaker 1: yep, so, uh, yeah, oh but and when you need to stop to eat Atlantic City eats I mean, there's still good restaurants there.
Speaker 1: There's still casinos there.
Speaker 1: casinos have restaurants.
Speaker 1: In fact, those places plenty of fucking hotels cuz that means some of them are closed, but this casinos this hotels Yeah, so I and most of the kids can't go to the casinos.
Speaker 1: It's not we might.
Speaker 0: we might double the number of anime cons we perform at every year starting next year.
Speaker 1: Maybe good, you know, but Otakon Vegas, I don't know what did.
Speaker 1: was that just as successful?
Speaker 1: I think the difference is that Vegas there's no beach.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would.
Speaker 0: just the desert is if If I fly to this I'll spend some time in the con like doing our panels and like walk around the dealers room once rock on the artist alley ones Maybe like see a couple of panels.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, I'm gonna be on the beach.
Speaker 0: I'll even take a couple extra days off and just stay on the beach.
Speaker 0: It's a bathing suit.
Speaker 0: Yeah But Vegas I would pretty much just.
Speaker 0: all all you do in Vegas is eat food and go to shows.
Speaker 0: Yep Anyway, not that I mind that but anyway good job.
Speaker 0: So next I can take a train dad to Atlantic City.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can't take a train to Vegas.
Speaker 0: that's worth taking.
Speaker 1: All right, so in my news, this isn't really.
Speaker 1: this is sort of news I guess but today.
Speaker 1: well not today actually today.
Speaker 1: But today we're recording.
Speaker 0: this rim is in London.
Speaker 1: right now as you're listening to this is in London But as we're recording this is Monday, June 15th, even though this is the 17th episode.
Speaker 0: You've broken the illusion.
Speaker 1: I know I don't like illusions.
Speaker 1: I don't like lying.
Speaker 1: So on Monday, June 15th, it was is was the 30th anniversary of Studio Ghibli which is crazy because I'm older than that.
Speaker 1: I was three years old when they founded that studio.
Speaker 1: That's 30 years old now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's pretty significant.
Speaker 0: Do you remember a time before?
Speaker 0: Studio Ghibli existed.
Speaker 1: I was three but Pepperidge Farm is much older than me.
Speaker 1: So it remembers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, think about all the animes the Studio Ghibli is made and now are they stopping or not?
Speaker 1: We don't even know But that was the you know, you could almost say like, ah, that was the life of Studio Ghibli.
Speaker 1: There's an important time since this.
Speaker 1: really I don't know if there's much to link to for this.
Speaker 1: I think there was on the 25th anniversary Which I guess is a more round significant number than 30. in some ways they had like a anniversary concert.
Speaker 1: So you can just pretend that that's the 30th anniversary concert.
Speaker 1: Nah, I think it's on YouTube maybe or something if I remember because I remember watching it once maybe a few years ago Probably five years ago.
Speaker 0: so in other news if you think that the war on people like being afraid of comic books was one a long time ago when the Comics Code kind of disappeared and Like people are more modern and civil There's comic book.
Speaker 1: You clearly don't read the comic legal defense funds.
Speaker 0: We'd like to remind you that Terrible people are still out there.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna explain this and they do this pretty much in a daily basis.
Speaker 1: Yeah basically You have extra money that you don't need.
Speaker 1: Consider giving it to the comic book legal defense fund because when someone comes to put you in jail Because you happen to have a hentai manga which oh by the way that has happened The conflict legal defense fund are the lawyers that will come and keep you out of jail.
Speaker 0: They have done this Yes, so basically this story however is extra special because of the complainant in this case All right.
Speaker 0: So a school the teacher for study had some required reading and because the class Was about this sort of thing.
Speaker 0: They had to read comic book class.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to look for the name goes Michelle assigned as reading in class before.
Speaker 1: so it was.
Speaker 1: They assigned the movie for watching.
Speaker 0: so it was an English class and they had to read Persepolis fun home.
Speaker 0: why the last man Sandman?
Speaker 1: So basically a bunch of like eyebrow comics that are mostly on my shelf.
Speaker 0: a student and her parents.
Speaker 1: I think all but one of those is on my shelf and the reason Sandman isn't because I read someone else's copy.
Speaker 0: Yep, so a student and her parents complained to the school and are Extremely unhappy that their child has to read pornography In her English class, I'd like to point out their child is 20.
Speaker 0: This is a college.
Speaker 1: Yeah Okay.
Speaker 1: So first of all, none of those are pornography not even close.
Speaker 0: There's a better quote.
Speaker 1: They do all contain our rated material, especially Sandman.
Speaker 0: if you can't deal with our rated material You don't deserve you should not even be in college and it's definitely a probe.
Speaker 1: All of those are definitely 100% age-appropriate highbrow and educational.
Speaker 1: those are like lit like junior senior high school appropriate I mean sure, but they're there of high literary merit and worthy of any college course.
Speaker 0: She was quote apparently aware that the specific focus of the class was graphic novels But she told the newspaper that quote.
Speaker 0: I expected Batman and Robin not pornography.
Speaker 1: Okay, first of all, have you read any fucking Batman and Robin?
Speaker 1: Because you know if you see some like DC cheesecake characters going on in there you want to see some Catwoman action.
Speaker 1: You're going to be rather upset And you don't know what pornography is because that's way more pornography than any of those things.
Speaker 1: now granted It's not.
Speaker 1: I'm saying I'm not saying Batman is pornography.
Speaker 1: I'm saying it's closer to it than Sandman.
Speaker 0: So reading between the lines here.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure this girl and her family I'll bet she was homeschooled or something and I'm sort of like ultra-christian Probably and I think there's some helicopter mom going on probably all rolled in together Definitely.
Speaker 0: Yeah so I Don't know what else to say.
Speaker 0: this article speaks for itself and it would be funny if it wasn't so sad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you care about comic books at all the CVLDF is something you should pay attention to.
Speaker 1: They're pretty much at like every comic-con you ever go to and they're usually like selling sign shit that authors Donated to that they could sell for lots of money to you know, and they're also just accepting donations.
Speaker 1: So you should do that Yeah, or one day when you get arrested for having a comic book for having pornography Batman and Robin right you'll be wishing the CVLDF was there.
Speaker 1: and when they ain't because you didn't give them five bucks You know, don't complain to me.
Speaker 1: I told you five dollars.
Speaker 1: I told you Also, you can get like cool stickers and they have lots of cool stuff They like.
Speaker 1: every year.
Speaker 0: they put out freedom comics Yeah, and their logo and everything is just great to like.
Speaker 0: they're just a great.
Speaker 1: or they put a nice sticker on your laptop.
Speaker 0: It's like look people listen to Monday gig nights.
Speaker 0: They're really big into the EFF.
Speaker 0: If you listen to Wednesday gig nights, these are this is your EFF, right?
Speaker 0: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: so, you know anime Boston doesn't have its rave dance.
Speaker 0: It's gone forever basically, and I just think that was nothing but a positive thing
Speaker 1: not a problem for me,
Speaker 0: so if anime cons specifically Continue to persist in this idea that they need to have an anime rave that they call a dance for legal reasons Why can't it at least be like this video?
Speaker 1: So this is our actual rave.
Speaker 1: I think in Japan a while ago.
Speaker 1: I don't know how long ago But 2015 electro X.
Speaker 0: I guess.
Speaker 1: I guess it was recent But there was a vine of this and also a YouTube video of it spreading around.
Speaker 1: they're playing a pretty recent you know trance hit song called ping-pong and There's a bunch of pikachu's dancing.
Speaker 1: It's amazing.
Speaker 0: This is what every.
Speaker 0: this is what anime con dances should look sound and feel like like actual raves and not pretend kid raves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel like a lot of the kids who go to anime counter raves though Would just pee their pants if they went to an adult rave.
Speaker 1: Yeah You don't have any how many like half the people there on X or whatever.
Speaker 1: It's so crazy
Speaker 0: to me though because when we went to anime cons like in the early 2000s the dances was basically like they'd be playing sort of dancy remixes of just like anime openers and people would just be kind of Poorly dancing to them and everyone was having fun And then it increasingly smelled worse and worse and worse as the years went on.
Speaker 1: So this dude he made is really nothing special to this.
Speaker 1: It's not really the greatest thing of the day, but he made the bicycle from Akira, which is not Akira's bicycle It's Kaneda's bicycle Motorcycle not bicycle.
Speaker 1: Yeah He made it out of Lego which I'm sure has been done before But he did it to a greater extent than anyone has done before.
Speaker 1: it is more accurate more detailed more functional more music in his YouTube video.
Speaker 1: So if the bicycle motorcycle from Akira made out of Lego and actually rolling around with remote control Interests you here is a YouTube video of the best of that You're probably gonna see.
Speaker 1: or you know I mean if someone tops this guy who even really cares at that point.
Speaker 0: There you go in the moment.
Speaker 0: The book club book is the wheel of time.
Speaker 0: We've somehow spent our whole lives having not read it a very popular and prominent nerdy book series.
Speaker 1: We have not read any books from it ever.
Speaker 1: Let's read the first one so that we can call ourselves Leonard's yep, and we're going to the talk about it when we finish it.
Speaker 1: nerd cred plus plus good or bad.
Speaker 0: Yep Also, we got some new videos up.
Speaker 0: You should be following both mine and Scott's YouTube channels because they give two different flavors of later all the kind of tangential to geek night stuff we do.
Speaker 1: on Saturday, I'm gonna live stream the Net runner regional championships from Philadelphia and and less than a month July 9th 10th 11th 12th in Connecticut.
Speaker 0: Hartford is Connecticut.
Speaker 1: if you can get to Hartford Connecticut without the use of an airplane in a reasonable amount of time You and you're a nerd which you are.
Speaker 1: if you're listening to this You and you don't have anything more important to do like I don't know a wedding or family obligation or who knows what?
Speaker 1: You should be at Connecticut, it's not sold out.
Speaker 1: you can buy a ticket and go badge membership, whatever you want to call it.
Speaker 0: Yep, Connecticut is pretty badass and it is unlike a lot of things that say they are that Actually and everything come no matter what your nerdery is.
Speaker 1: Connecticut's got it covered.
Speaker 1: if you're an anime fan You will have shit to do all weekend.
Speaker 1: if you're into gaming you'll have shit to do all weekend.
Speaker 1: if you're into whatever the fuck It is you're in the I don't know George Takei.
Speaker 1: if you're into Star Trek sci-fi Music Like literature like authors and if you're into more than one of those things you will have more Than things that you want to do.
Speaker 1: then you can do in the weekend.
Speaker 1: Yeah, come to the kinetic on.
Speaker 0: so We're watching a pretty new anime and is from a current season.
Speaker 0: It's not like it's still.
Speaker 1: I found out about the show when we put together our panel for anime Boston And what do we say about it?
Speaker 0: We said in judge anime by its cover.
Speaker 0: We reviewed it based on one screenshot Yep, and a paragraph of text and I had a positive expectation based upon those things.
Speaker 0: So now we watched enough of it to confirm three episodes.
Speaker 0: I've watched more than that.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm gonna watch more than that when I get home.
Speaker 1: That's all you need to know.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna watch all of it.
Speaker 0: In fact episode 12 like just went up.
Speaker 1: a good thing.
Speaker 1: I pay for crunchyroll.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah, it's on crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: by the way, I was sold on this just from the picture of the protag.
Speaker 1: Sold on this from the picture and also believe it or not, right?
Speaker 1: I was sold on it from the picture.
Speaker 1: I was gonna watch it at some point But it got pushed up in the queue because of all places I saw on places like boing boing Things like this getting posted outside the anime community.
Speaker 1: There was interest in this show.
Speaker 0: Oh some some internet people that I follow that many of you don't follow.
Speaker 0: They've been tweeting a lot of really fucked up fan art and internet about this show.
Speaker 1: So it's called or a Monogatari and we already sort of discussed the name and the opener of the show But as far as I know already is like mine or me or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Monogatari is story or a side story or you know.
Speaker 1: That's always used for like in the in the titles of things pretty often like Shin Megami something something Monogatari And it's sort of like the side story.
Speaker 1: So this is basically my story as far as I know.
Speaker 1: in my limited Japanese language knowledge I don't know why the translated title suddenly has the word love in it.
Speaker 0: The love must be implied.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we would ask Emily and bring her on the show, but she's not home.
Speaker 1: She's not home that so we don't know.
Speaker 1: But that's kind of weird.
Speaker 1: But I guess it's fine because if it's just my story you wouldn't have any idea what the show is about.
Speaker 1: by saying love story You know, it's a romance and you know what it is.
Speaker 0: This show is not our favorite kind of anime because our favorite kind of anime is ghost in the show, of course But it's a good.
Speaker 0: it's a good kind of anime that we like because I mean you guys like we watched a lot of Nana Like a lot of it.
Speaker 0: We really like here is Greenwood.
Speaker 0: We like really kind of show Joey fun stuff, but they have to have something going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah Too many of them are just the typical.
Speaker 1: what you expect?
Speaker 1: kind of thing either their way perverted or their way fantasy Fulfillment or you know, there's something wrong with a lot of romance shows out there and mangas.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty rare that you come across one.
Speaker 1: That is both a there's nothing wrong with it in terms of being horrible or scary or freaky or whatever and B it is not just Stereotypical.
Speaker 1: follow the usual expected plot line.
Speaker 1: So it's boring.
Speaker 0: and this show is that because basically to sell it to you before we even talk about what it really is about.
Speaker 0: It has a typical like these people should date but there are misunderstandings and they don't date.
Speaker 1: So it's not love Hina where they go the whole season without getting together.
Speaker 0: Basically that plot gets resolved Immediately and then the show just keeps going.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so good Takeo is just a monster.
Speaker 1: He's not actually a monster But he is a huge dude like.
Speaker 1: he's way tall and way strong and he will fuck you up like gigantic.
Speaker 1: If he was a boxer, he would be a super heavyweight if he was only a freshman in high school.
Speaker 0: He was in silver spoon.
Speaker 0: He's bigger than those cows.
Speaker 1: Like he is a gigantic powerful ogre of a man Plus because anime or manga they can draw him really really big.
Speaker 0: Yeah, his best friend is this super hot boshonen guy that all the girls love.
Speaker 0: He's a cool dude, and there's this tiny adorable girl who has a crush on him Inexplicably.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So cuz he saved her and now she noticed him and he's a good dude.
Speaker 0: So he spent his whole life having girls ignore him and go after his friend.
Speaker 0: His friend wants nothing to do with these vapid girls always going after him.
Speaker 1: But there's an interesting reason why.
Speaker 0: yeah stuff very interesting reason why and this girl also Obviously has some secrets and like there's stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they know nothing about this girl other than that.
Speaker 1: She's into the main character and she's legit adorable.
Speaker 1: Yep in the opener There's you know, but it's not like she's not weird and she's a little weird but not no, no But she's not weird in a sort of like, you know, lowly con kind of way.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, she's not like a Right, she's not a moe blob and it's he's not cheesecake and like, you know in a pervert kind of way.
Speaker 1: it's like the character design is totally just like Anime cute but normal person and she likes to bake.
Speaker 0: they also draw a really like cute little just well Like.
Speaker 0: there's in the opener There's a scene where she's like sitting on this little like cushion and she's making a really good particularly notable face.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but she's generally like chill.
Speaker 1: It's not like, you know, there's no scary creepy stuff going on whatsoever.
Speaker 0: But I mean the way the show kind of goes.
Speaker 0: cuz you know in the first three episodes I'll spoil a little bit they they're dating by the end of that.
Speaker 0: So the show kind of sets you up like the the misunderstanding of he's the big guys like, oh, he's so dumb.
Speaker 0: There's no way she likes me.
Speaker 1: She obviously likes my hot be showed in friend.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna cheerlead them.
Speaker 0: I've resigned myself to my fate as an ogre.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna make their relationship happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's it, right?
Speaker 1: So there's this fairy tale of the ogre and good anime like utana always have a fairy tale as they're backing, right?
Speaker 1: So this has the fairy tale of the red ogre in the blue ogre Which is a metaphor for the story of the show and that's a pretty good fable right there.
Speaker 1: I like that fable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it keeps coming up especially in episode 4 with the fire Have to get to episode 4 tonight.
Speaker 0: So yeah It gets to the point where like it gets just to that Bianca Tomahome like insufferable point of oh my god you tours So-dumb and then the show just kind of looks you in the eye and says no no No, that's not what the show is about.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell this show is about Horrible disaster happens every episode but this big dude can save the day.
Speaker 0: Yes, he's huge.
Speaker 0: He makes a project a co save in episode 4.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean it's like this.
Speaker 1: it's like even though it's primarily about this romance and relationship and these characters Right because it's about this big dude they could bring in this extra action aspect, right?
Speaker 1: And I think that's really why the show is appealing is that it's got Sutton for everybody no matter what you are No matter what you into what you're looking for.
Speaker 1: It's in this show somewhere even though it's primarily a romance show, right?
Speaker 0: Well, cuz it's multi-dimensional like one thing.
Speaker 1: maybe a perverted guy who likes moe stuff and I just said this doesn't have it But it's like.
Speaker 1: well the girls still cute, right?
Speaker 1: You'll still be into her cakes and shit.
Speaker 0: But like you like that camaraderie kind of show after the initial setup it kind of zooms out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the big guy has a whole bunch of other friends and they're all totally in the show.
Speaker 0: and the girl Yeah, she has her own set of friends.
Speaker 0: in the fourth episode the plots like well, I guess we're dating now.
Speaker 0: Alright, you should meet a bunch of my friends.
Speaker 1: Yep And like all these characters got all kinds of school action.
Speaker 1: if you're into school action If you're maybe the kind of girl who likes to watch free or the kind of guy who likes to watch free or whatever you Are and you like to watch free cuz there's hot guys in it.
Speaker 1: There's hot guys in this showing guys Showing guys way awesome.
Speaker 1: You could be into him.
Speaker 0: I like him.
Speaker 0: I'll also be into.
Speaker 1: you could be in if you're into yaoi's you could.
Speaker 1: there's a bromance between the main guy and the shonen.
Speaker 1: You know, there is.
Speaker 1: yeah, so you could be into that too.
Speaker 1: You could get some shipping going on.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: There isn't.
Speaker 0: there is not cyber brain hacking.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: That's the one thing the show is lacking.
Speaker 1: There's.
Speaker 1: no It's got a touch of coma.
Speaker 1: has baking, you know, like baking the way that you know That one piece has pirates or the way that your pedal has bicycles, right?
Speaker 1: So you could be into the baking aspect like I am like, oh, these are the other Patisserie something.
Speaker 1: so when she makes that cake Salé, yeah, right exactly You know, this show has something going on But the mainly kind of anime.
Speaker 0: the reason this show is getting attention.
Speaker 0: one is madhouse.
Speaker 1: So dog car is so good at making anime.
Speaker 0: Yep, you do It's just.
Speaker 0: it's a show and we say this a lot about good shows where you look at it and you think okay I see where this is getting.
Speaker 0: as soon as you say that it turns 90 degrees and you can't predict where it's going.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean episode 2.
Speaker 1: I was like how much longer is this guy gonna be dumb?
Speaker 1: and then he stopped being dumb.
Speaker 1: if he would Has kept being dumb to the end of episode 3 I would have been done with the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but because they got together it's like well, this is a real show.
Speaker 0: now the way they get together I'm not even gonna spoil it is great.
Speaker 1: So good Souda, there's the because he's so big right you can add in like these amazing animations and visual He's always like the steam coming out of his nose, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they're always utilizing like, you know The character isn't in the environment to do sort of like actual like powerful animation Even though it's just you know, like the show - you know
Speaker 0: what it reminds me of a lot actually is here is Greenwood
Speaker 1: A little bit like the comedy plus the something for everyone plus the romance.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus the school Yeah, and the like zoomed out cast of characters cast of morons.
Speaker 0: You gotta have the cast of morons.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean or is that sir has that to the extreme?
Speaker 1: And I definitely think it is the same genre as the here's as the here's Greenwood and there aren't often things in that very specific Category.
Speaker 0: Yeah Honey and clover a little bit a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right But yeah, I should finish.
Speaker 0: I never read all the manga of.
Speaker 0: here is Greenwood.
Speaker 0: I own it all I just haven't.
Speaker 0: I only read like that first five.
Speaker 1: I haven't either.
Speaker 0: just watch that show again.
Speaker 0: I think we reviewed it on geek nights at least very important show that is we're the no-brand heroes chair.
Speaker 0: Anyone who out there who listens to geek nights remembers here is Greenwood.
Speaker 0: I'm curious.
Speaker 0: a lot of people Well, who I think people who have listened to us since we reviewed it have I'm sure plenty of people know it.
Speaker 0: I'm curious Let me know Posting the forum about here's Greenwood.
Speaker 1: Is there anything else to say about my story?
Speaker 0: No, just if you you know If you want to watch what other anime you're watching this season.
Speaker 1: this season doesn't seem at least right now in the summer season.
Speaker 0: There does not seem to get in dice case not out yet Is it?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: but there doesn't seem to be anything blowing the doors off in Madoka style right now.
Speaker 1: So this is the show because you missed the last round with yuri bear and we're still waiting for Some yo pedal movie and you're also Wolf boy movie that I'm invested in right?
Speaker 1: So there's really no enemies to watch right now.
Speaker 1: So watch this.
Speaker 0: Well, if you didn't watch Yuri Kuma are actually I mean if Scott doesn't watch it soon Emily and I are just gonna do a show on it.
Speaker 0: cuz it's it's good.
Speaker 1: What's your hurry?
Speaker 1: It's real good Big guy in his story.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I was trying to watch the first two episodes of Yuri bears.
Speaker 0: cuz I was like, alright I'll see what the deal is.
Speaker 0: and then the rest of that show was oh shit.
Speaker 0: When's the next episode Jesus?
Speaker 0: I need to say alright, but yeah I'm pretty much gonna power through this as fast as possible.
Speaker 0: the 12th episode just came out.
Speaker 0: I don't know how long it's actually gonna be.
Speaker 0: I think 24 episodes Which is a good number.
Speaker 0: That's like a full season.
Speaker 1: Not bad.
Speaker 1: It's on crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: So This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Speaker 1: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and in Discriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.