Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, January 20th, 2015.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, Kings Forge.
Speaker 0: We're Kings Forge things.
Speaker 1: And it's kinda okay.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: You know, a long time ago, Scott used to give me shit about how I didn't do Club Nintendo and how I just throw my Nintendo boxes away and I just didn't care.
Speaker 0: Well, that was free codes for me, whatev.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I mean, it was free stuff.
Speaker 0: Why wouldn't you get the free stuff?
Speaker 1: Yes, because now, later, older, wiser, do you want a bunch of plastic stuff?
Speaker 0: Well, in those days, you know, that was the days where I was so foolish as to spend money on useless plastic stuff.
Speaker 1: I used to have a lot of plastic useless stuff.
Speaker 0: Also, Club Nintendo in Japan gave away awesome, worthwhile- Well, they gave away that, what, the NES controller?
Speaker 1: at one time?
Speaker 0: That was the best thing they ever gave away was an SNES controller, a Super Famicom controller, full, real controller, but it was 100% wireless and it worked with a Wii as opposed to with any other system.
Speaker 1: I would have paid like 100 bucks for that.
Speaker 0: Well, you could pay like 70 bucks and get one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but like when it came out- Right, but if you had enough Club Nintendo points, which at the time that this came out, this was like, you know, I definitely would have had the points to get it if it was offered in the US.
Speaker 1: Well, because apparently everyone had a ton of points all the time, but we'll get to that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I mean, I bought, you know, between starting with the Game Boy Color, right, onward until the Wii, I bought a lot of Nintendo stuff.
Speaker 0: I bought the Game Boy Color when it came out, the DS when it came out, the GameCube when it came out, the Wii when it came out, and a lot of games, and I bought, you know, especially a lot of portable games, and those added up to a lot of points.
Speaker 0: But I didn't get shit for my points.
Speaker 0: I got like a calendar that I threw out and I got some washcloths I still use.
Speaker 0: Those aren't bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, the thing is, the problem with any program like this is always that- Yeah, nowadays you can get some virtual console games.
Speaker 0: Well, not for much longer, though.
Speaker 1: Yep, but the problem with all those things is that usually the thing that, you know, savvy people who sign up and try to min-max these systems want is just more games for free.
Speaker 0: Yes, well, you can get that now, sort of.
Speaker 1: But in providing that with any real economy, you just undermine yourself by getting less money from your most dedicated fans.
Speaker 1: They're gonna buy your shit anyway.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, that's why even now they're giving away games for free, but they're like virtual console games and no one's gonna buy, you know, aren't worth paying real money for, so it's like, oh, I can- 'Cause even though I don't want- I'm not- I'm done ever falling for the pay for virtual console game ever again, 'cause I can just emulate that shit.
Speaker 0: But it is nice to have, like, I got Wario 2 for free from Club Nintendo, and having Wario 2 just officially on the 3DS is a lot more convenient than, like, getting out the piracy card.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: You know, but not worth paying for, but nice that I got it for free.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't get me to buy more games just to get that, but it makes me feel good about buying the games I already bought.
Speaker 1: So meanwhile, on the wide internet, I saw lots of reports, now when I was looking into Club Nintendo, when I saw the news I'm about to bring up, that, oh wow, this happened today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, today.
Speaker 1: So, that a lot of people had saved up codes or purchases to, like, maintain their status, and they were treating this like air miles, like they were really into it.
Speaker 0: 'Cause the way it works is, even though you can spend your points and any time to just get something, your coins, if you have enough coins within a certain amount of time, you set a status.
Speaker 0: Like, I used to be at the top status, but since the, you know, Wii U and the...
Speaker 1: All the way up to Rattata?
Speaker 0: Yeah, top status.
Speaker 0: I think top is platinum status.
Speaker 0: So I was at the top status for a while until the Wii sort of ended and the Wii U came out and didn't buy a Wii U, and I didn't buy that many 3DS games, and so since then, my status has gone down.
Speaker 1: I realized I've only bought eight 3DS games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're at the top status, there's, like, just stuff that you just get that you can't get any other way.
Speaker 1: So here's what I think happened.
Speaker 1: 'Cause Nintendo canceled the program, it's done, spend all your points, they're all gonna get deleted.
Speaker 1: If you care about this thing, you probably already know.
Speaker 1: So that's not the interesting part.
Speaker 1: But I feel like what happened here on a high level...
Speaker 0: They're replacing it with something else yet to be determined.
Speaker 0: They are.
Speaker 0: Maybe it'll be better.
Speaker 0: Maybe they're actually gonna do the right thing and offer the same awesome stuff to every country.
Speaker 0: Or fuck over every country, even Japan.
Speaker 1: So I saw... I read an article about this, like someone kind of explaining in more detail the context and the corporate whatevers and everything.
Speaker 1: And the one thing that the articles all seem to point out is that Nintendo seems to have done this in response to their profit scare, because, you know, recently Nintendo's not been doing well.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: And suddenly Nintendo changes a bunch of stuff when they're not doing well.
Speaker 1: Most of those changes involve shutting things down or backing away from things, but I digress on that.
Speaker 1: The first comment on two of these articles was a different person both saying the same thing effectively, "What if I buy a game between now and when the new program starts up, I better get my fucking
Speaker 1: points.".
Speaker 1: They were really, really, really worried about that.
Speaker 1: So as much as I want to say loyalty programs are stupid, obviously people care about them enough to dedicate life cycle resources toward them.
Speaker 0: The most evil thing about the Club Nintendo that I think is that you could... Basically, not only did you buy a game, type in the code, get stuff, but you could fill out surveys.
Speaker 0: So it's like you did surveys about any game you bought, but there are also other additional surveys.
Speaker 0: And taking these things, you got even more points.
Speaker 0: So it's really Nintendo is basically giving you stuff in exchange for market research for free.
Speaker 0: It's very similar to the grocery store card where you get discounts if you swipe the card and they track your purchases all the time.
Speaker 1: And the only reason they do that is because by law, they're not allowed to use your credit card number to track.
Speaker 1: So I wonder if you could theoretically get away by using face recognition or fingerprint or something.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I digress there again too.
Speaker 1: So what I suspect happened really here is that Club Nintendo was one of those things they did in Japan because that's what Japanese companies seem to do.
Speaker 1: It seems like a lot of these consumer rewards programs in the domestic market in Japan exist primarily because you're expected to have a program like that.
Speaker 1: You're expected to have this sort of deferential behavior toward your customer.
Speaker 0: From what I've seen, there's all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 0: In Japan, there's just lots of ways to get stuff.
Speaker 0: Especially, you buy a manga, you send in the surveys, you can get stuff for sending in the surveys.
Speaker 0: There's contests.
Speaker 0: you can just enter.
Speaker 0: Send in stuff, win contests.
Speaker 0: There's people giving out free tissues on the street.
Speaker 1: When I started picking up Japanese anime magazines and things in the old days just because, "Hey, pretty
Speaker 1: pictures!"
Speaker 1: I noticed all those things in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's lots of ways to get stuff and they keep rewarding people with things.
Speaker 1: I wonder if there's a cultural difference.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm not Japanese.
Speaker 0: I mean, we have that culture here a little bit, but it seems like they have it a lot more.
Speaker 1: Well, I wonder if in Japan, the reason it wasn't a problem is that people, there was sort of this like, not everyone min-maxed it and went crazy on it.
Speaker 1: But I feel like in the US at least, the nerds I see who care about these kinds of programs care to an unhealthy degree and go way out of their way to maximize their haul.
Speaker 1: And I wonder if that wasn't the case in the domestic market.
Speaker 0: Well, there are kids who don't have a lot of stuff, so getting anything for free is amazing to them.
Speaker 0: These are the same people who are fighting tooth and nail for a t-shirt and hanging in the expo hall of PAX literally all day.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know what I should bring?
Speaker 1: Do you know how many Halo 4 t-shirts I have from PAXes?
Speaker 1: Because vendors will just give me shit, so I'm gonna bring it all with me and just give it away at our panel.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Pay to fly your junk to San Antonio.
Speaker 1: I'm paying to fly stuff out anyway because I think Delta's gonna charge us for our checked bags.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can just bring it to PAX East instead.
Speaker 1: It's the same hassle either way.
Speaker 0: Not necessarily.
Speaker 0: You can bring it to Connecticut.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I feel like I just want to get rid of it as quickly as possible.
Speaker 1: You know why?
Speaker 1: Because yesterday I was doing laundry because I got a bunch of... Right after PAX South I'm going on a ski trip, so I tried to get all my laundry done and set my life affairs in order likened unto what a dying man does.
Speaker 1: And I bumped into all those fucking shirts and I couldn't tell if they were clean or dirty or if they'd ever been washed.
Speaker 1: They were kind of wrinkly and I was like, "I don't want to fold them and put them somewhere and then forget about them again.
Speaker 1: I don't want to wash them.
Speaker 1: I'll just put them in my bag and take them to
Speaker 1: PAX.".
Speaker 1: So yeah, Club Nintendo's gone and I don't particularly personally care because I just threw away my game boxes.
Speaker 0: In other news, in the gaming lands, we talked a little while about GOG.com and the awesomeness of them bringing back the long lost TIE Fighter NX wing.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, problems with that.
Speaker 1: We'll review those, I think, in depth later.
Speaker 1: But I do want to mention, if you did not buy TIE Fighter or X-Wing yet, here is my review.
Speaker 1: Do not buy X-Wing.
Speaker 1: It is just the prototype for TIE Fighter and it actually kind of sucks.
Speaker 1: Do not buy the later release of TIE Fighter.
Speaker 0: Well, you don't.
Speaker 0: You get them both.
Speaker 0: There's no separation between the purchase.
Speaker 1: You could buy them separately, I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure you buy them both together.
Speaker 1: I think you bought them in that pack.
Speaker 0: It's just TIE Fighter.
Speaker 0: I don't think they offer like...
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure you can buy the two editions separately.
Speaker 0: No, it's ten bucks and you get TIE Fighter.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, there we go.
Speaker 1: I didn't remember because I just bought it and it was a while ago.
Speaker 0: It's ten bucks and you just get everything.
Speaker 1: Special edition and TIE Fighter are separate listed here.
Speaker 0: I paid ten bucks and I got both.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to navigate this side.
Speaker 1: Anyway, there is a 1994 edition and a 1998 edition.
Speaker 1: The 1998 edition is garbage and you should never play it.
Speaker 1: The actual good edition is the 1995 edition that they did not re-release.
Speaker 1: There is no way to get that edition.
Speaker 1: I guess you could pirate it and run it in DOSBox yourself.
Speaker 1: That might be better.
Speaker 1: So, here's the differences.
Speaker 1: The '94 edition did something that games did not do well again until Tribes II.
Speaker 1: It had dynamic music.
Speaker 1: It had scarily dynamic, widely divergent music because it was all mini.
Speaker 1: So, when a missile was homing in, the music would get more intense.
Speaker 1: When there's fighters around you, the music would change.
Speaker 1: It would play like little riffs and motifs like when you take something out and the goal is completed.
Speaker 0: The other one has a Redbook CD track and it just plays it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, '98 just plays really bad music pretty much constantly and never varies it.
Speaker 1: That alone is a reason to never play the new edition.
Speaker 1: The new edition uses a different flight model which just isn't as good and not as fun.
Speaker 1: It has these ugly textures in it and I guess they lost the original assets when they made that re-release because all the game menus and everything just look like shit.
Speaker 1: And all the cutscenes, the sound quality is bad and the aspect ratio is wrong.
Speaker 1: So, just play the original '94 edition or pirate the '95 CD edition.
Speaker 1: The only difference between '94 and '95 is that '94 is partially voice acted.
Speaker 1: '95, every single word has amazing voice acting.
Speaker 1: Every mission briefing, everything.
Speaker 1: And the '95 edition is 640x480 instead of 320x200.
Speaker 1: That's nice.
Speaker 0: So, GOG.com followed that up today by releasing six more Star Wars games.
Speaker 0: GOG.com Wave 2.
Speaker 0: Star Wars Battlefront 2, which I think is a game where you're like a storm trooper and you walk around hitting things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, never played that.
Speaker 0: I think that's what it is.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like screw that game.
Speaker 0: There's no point in playing that.
Speaker 0: Star Wars Knights of the Old Republic 2.
Speaker 0: People really fucking love Knights of the Old Republic a lot.
Speaker 0: I haven't played the second one, but I tried to play the first one.
Speaker 0: It is not good.
Speaker 1: I concur.
Speaker 0: It is a bad RPG that takes way too long to play and is completely uninteresting.
Speaker 0: I don't understand why these games are so ridiculous popular.
Speaker 0: I mean, whatevs.
Speaker 0: Star Wars Dark Forces, which is not that interesting because it's been on Steam for a long time.
Speaker 0: I have all those games on Steam.
Speaker 0: And those games are basically Doom, but Star Wars?
Speaker 0: And they're actually kind of fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're okay.
Speaker 0: It's like, oh, you know, you're a stormtrooper, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like Doom, FPS style.
Speaker 0: Maybe a little bit better than Doom.
Speaker 0: Star Wars Galactic Battleground Saga, I think is an RTS.
Speaker 0: Who cares?
Speaker 0: And X-Wing vs.
Speaker 0: TIE Fighter, X-Wing Alliance, the two missing pieces.
Speaker 1: So X-Wing vs.
Speaker 1: TIE Fighter was a noble experiment, but it was awful and unplayable.
Speaker 0: So when it came out, it was like, holy shit, are you kidding me?
Speaker 0: We had X-Wing, we had TIE Fighter.
Speaker 0: Now, finally, multiplayer, X-Wing vs.
Speaker 0: TIE Fighter, holy crap.
Speaker 1: X-Wing vs.
Speaker 1: TIE Fighter came out three or four years after TIE Fighter came out.
Speaker 0: I think it was '98 or '99.
Speaker 1: It was '97.
Speaker 0: It was '97?
Speaker 1: It was X-Wing vs.
Speaker 1: TIE Fighter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, '97.
Speaker 1: When X-Wing first came out in '93, the first thing every nerd thought was, "Oh my god, I just want to play this with another human
Speaker 1: being.".
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: And then X-Wing vs.
Speaker 1: TIE Fighter came out and was a disaster.
Speaker 1: Just didn't work.
Speaker 1: X-Wing Alliance...
Speaker 0: '99.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It was '99.
Speaker 1: X-Wing Alliance is way better than X-Wing vs.
Speaker 1: TIE Fighter.
Speaker 1: It's twice as fast as X-Wing and TIE Fighter and has a new flight model.
Speaker 1: that's actually pretty good.
Speaker 1: And has a really good story mode.
Speaker 1: It was a great game and I really, really liked it as a kid.
Speaker 0: X-Wing Alliance.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: X-Wing Alliance also had multiplayer.
Speaker 1: that I guess worked, but...
Speaker 0: Was the best multiplayer, but apparently it is not offered according... At least if you go to G.com and click on X-Wing Alliance and scroll down to the specs where it talks about the game, it says single player.
Speaker 0: It does not say multiplayer.
Speaker 0: So I assume that means... See, right there.
Speaker 0: Modes.
Speaker 0: So I assume that means the multiplayer mode has been removed or is non-functioning.
Speaker 1: I wonder if it just doesn't work.
Speaker 1: I don't even remember how it worked.
Speaker 1: I assume it's just manual IP addresses.
Speaker 0: GOG is working on some sort of technology.
Speaker 0: They're using the old Alienverse Predator FPS as their test game.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I remember that game.
Speaker 0: That's not a bad game.
Speaker 0: They're working on redeveloping game servers to get multiplayer working in good old games.
Speaker 0: And that once they get it working in that game and develop the tech, they might be able to get it working for games such as X-Wing Alliance or in a holy universe where there is a god, tribes two.
Speaker 1: Ah.
Speaker 1: My biggest fear now.
Speaker 1: Because I got a joystick and I've been playing this stuff and TIE Fighter is so good and I'm going to play X-Wing Alliance again because you're not like rebel, empire, whatever.
Speaker 1: You're just some guy with like a family and you fly a YT-3100.
Speaker 1: You know, basically the Millennium Falcon.
Speaker 0: Only crappier than the Millennium Falcon.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: And it's just like half life-ish.
Speaker 0: It doesn't do a Kessel Run in even one par say.
Speaker 1: It's like half life story mode.
Speaker 1: It's like, well, I got to protect my family from the pirates in the outer rim and what's all the fucking empires getting up in my grill.
Speaker 1: Eh, eh, these rebels are here.
Speaker 1: I wish they'd go away.
Speaker 1: I just want to do my whatevers.
Speaker 0: Why not just join the empire?
Speaker 0: Then everything will go well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think it has a branching story.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: I haven't played this game since middle school.
Speaker 0: I mean, if you're just a normal schmo and you don't actually care.
Speaker 1: High school.
Speaker 0: Like your life is going to be the same.
Speaker 0: either way, really, whether it's rebel or empire, you know, because you're just like farming happily and either side doesn't really give a shit, then why wouldn't you go with the empire?
Speaker 1: Yeah, why not just go with the Nazis?
Speaker 1: Because they're leaving you alone.
Speaker 0: Uh, what Nazi-ing did the empire do?
Speaker 1: They killed the entire planet.
Speaker 0: Uh, that was before this game.
Speaker 1: After this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, uh, when does this game occur, Scott?
Speaker 1: You don't know about it.
Speaker 1: When does this game?
Speaker 1: Everyone knows.
Speaker 1: How do you not know?
Speaker 0: Uh, you live in some podunk planet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one here is like, oh yeah, where's Alderaan?
Speaker 0: I don't fly around to other planets.
Speaker 1: So, actually, X-Wing Alliance takes place shortly after the battle of Hoth.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That's where it's set.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So there's no Thrawn?
Speaker 1: Uh, probably not.
Speaker 0: Wah-wah.
Speaker 0: Fail.
Speaker 1: My biggest fear is that there is going to be a legit new TIE fighter-ish Star Wars game, because Star Wars is bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, I'm playing these a little bit, but if that happens.
Speaker 1: Well, my fear is that that will happen.
Speaker 0: I'm not playing them enough to warrant the joystick purchase.
Speaker 1: And it will be a good game, but it will be designed for a controller and not for a flightstick and thus be bullshit.
Speaker 0: And it might have a toggle in the settings.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but like playing TIE fighter again, I was reminded of how different a game that's designed for a joystick feels compared to a game that's designed for a controller.
Speaker 1: Or for a mouse.
Speaker 1: And go joystick.
Speaker 1: Like, if I can't have that, you know what I really want?
Speaker 1: I want it to come with the console, like in that old mech game where I have little widgets and buttons to push.
Speaker 0: Why don't you be that guy who, as your crazy hobby, makes a replica of the inside of a TIE fighter in your house that works perfectly with the game 100%, including like adjusting the inputs and everything, and then bring it to PAX and bring it to Star Wars Celebration and show it off.
Speaker 1: If we quick ignite.
Speaker 0: And a link of your website showing all the photos and videos that we passed around on Reddit and you get a million hits and shares on Facebook.
Speaker 1: Starting after PAX South.
Speaker 1: Give me two or three years, I could probably have that together.
Speaker 0: Just do it in your spare time instead of, I don't know, rock climbing or some dumb skiing shit.
Speaker 0: Just get one of those things and do this instead.
Speaker 0: It's nerdier.
Speaker 1: Anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: TED Talks were amazing and then I kind of got sick of them because a lot of them were increasingly kind of woo woo or information sparse.
Speaker 0: Well the woo woo ones mostly leaked in in the TEDx's.
Speaker 0: that weren't very well.
Speaker 1: But even some TED Talks, they weren't woo woo in the.
Speaker 1: this is chiropractic or acupuncture, but they were woo woo in the.
Speaker 1: this is a really lofty vague idea that doesn't actually go anywhere, and you obviously paid a lot of money to be involved in all this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and also, people might learn things watching TED videos.
Speaker 0: I definitely learned things when I did watch them way back in the day.
Speaker 0: Kiki Bulba?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I learned Kiki Bulba.
Speaker 0: I learned a lot of things, but, you know, they seem to be acting like we're changing the world with these talks and videos and things, and they haven't changed shit as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: You'll learn more from a crash course than you will from TEDs.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Fun fact.
Speaker 1: Scott and I had a TEDx license we never used.
Speaker 1: We were going to run a TEDx and then we just didn't have time and we backed out like we were.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that was a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So this is a parody of every TED talk, and it's about the same thing that Seinfeld is about.
Speaker 0: If you see this, you don't need to see any other TED talks except for Kiki Bulba one.
Speaker 1: And I just want to point out that the top comment on this YouTube video is, and I quote, "This guy eats his own
Speaker 1: shit.".
Speaker 1: So watch this video.
Speaker 0: He probably says so himself.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So the AGDQ just ended, the Awesome Games Done Quick, the annual, well, recently ended, the annual spectacle celebration of speed running and also donating money to fight cancer and save the animals in Super Metroid, which is the right way to do it.
Speaker 0: It was actually kind of interesting because every year so far, Kill the Animals has won in the donations because people want to, you know, it's faster that way.
Speaker 0: So, you know, all these speed run.
Speaker 0: people like, "You got to kill the animals.
Speaker 0: You can't be saving them.
Speaker 0: That's
Speaker 0: slower.".
Speaker 0: At the very last second, well, Save the Animals is winning the whole time, but then Kill the Animals pulled ahead towards the end because everyone waits until Super Metroid is actually being played to start donating, including myself.
Speaker 0: At the very last possible second, some dude, we don't know who it is, donated like multiple tens of thousands to put Save the Animals over the line, and his donation message was just, "Get
Speaker 0: rekt.".
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: I got a second thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Ben Couture just tweeted this.
Speaker 1: It's a super cut of every user interface in the first Star Wars movie.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Episode four.
Speaker 1: Every TIE fighter X-wing interface.
Speaker 0: Well, you can use that when you're making your replica.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: That's your reference material.
Speaker 1: So, anyway, continue.
Speaker 0: So, at the AGDQ, there are many amazing things to see this year, but the most amazing of them all to me was Tetris the Grandmaster.
Speaker 0: So, I had known about Tetris the Grandmaster for a long time.
Speaker 0: It's basically this arcade Tetris version in Japan that you can get.
Speaker 0: that is ridiculously hard, and there are people who can play it, and they're amazing at Tetris.
Speaker 0: More amazing than anyone else.
Speaker 0: It's the hardest Tetris.
Speaker 0: Not until I watched this video did I truly understand everything that is to know about Tetris the Grandmaster.
Speaker 0: I mean, everything I knew was correct.
Speaker 0: It is the hardest, most crazy Tetris arcade game in Japan.
Speaker 0: It is far crazier than I could possibly imagine, and in this video we see what is almost definitely the best non-Japanese Tetris Grandmaster players demonstrate their skill as and explain to you all the things that I have learned.
Speaker 0: If you know or care about video games at all, I don't care if you don't like speed running, and yes, it is a speed run even though it's Tetris, and you'll understand if you watch it.
Speaker 0: You need to understand what Tetris the Grandmaster is all about because these people are simultaneously the saddest and the most glorious gamers I have ever seen.
Speaker 1: In the meta moment, we are going to be live at PacSouth this weekend on Sunday, January 25th at 4.30pm in the Armadillo Theater.
Speaker 1: We are presenting Bad Games.
Speaker 0: So bad.
Speaker 1: The baddest.
Speaker 1: And if we get set up early and let the audience in early, we're just going to play Outlaw until the panel starts.
Speaker 1: It's going to be a good time.
Speaker 0: Also known as Pretzel Cowboy.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: The book club book is Watership Down.
Speaker 1: It's a story about amazing rabbits on an amazing journey.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll read it on an airplane.
Speaker 1: Maybe you should.
Speaker 0: When you get to the cultist rabbits, I think you're- I've already selected the next book club book.
Speaker 1: I've selected the next next book club book.
Speaker 1: If yours is a bad book, however, I'm redirecting back toward Monsieur Dumas.
Speaker 0: I don't know if mine is bad.
Speaker 1: I don't know either, but I'm just saying Dumas is just hanging out.
Speaker 1: Just waiting in the wings.
Speaker 1: Just waiting for me to tag him in.
Speaker 1: Le Combe de Monte Cristo.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: And I started a new live streaming series and I'm going to keep improving on it.
Speaker 1: People always ask me, well no, one or two people have occasionally asked me how to be good at Advance Wars.
Speaker 1: So I'm putting together a series on how to be good at Advance Wars.
Speaker 0: And perhaps you can find all the other Advance Wars players and get them together and form a thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe we should.
Speaker 0: Advance Wars speed runs.
Speaker 0: You can go to AGDQ next year and do the run.
Speaker 1: So what I did, one of these videos, I played a small puzzle map against myself because the AI is just not good enough to be worth talking about to try to show two omniscient opponents fighting each other how the logic breaks down game wise.
Speaker 1: And the first comment in the live stream was- This guy sure likes playing with himself.
Speaker 1: No, that should have been.
Speaker 1: the first comment was, wow, it is amazing how intense this guy is against himself.
Speaker 1: He is really into this.
Speaker 1: And then I realized when I watched it after the fact to see how this dream went, I was playing as Blue and I'm like, so Blue's probably going to try, he's going to build a tank because that's the only thing he can do.
Speaker 1: So I got to build these mechs and do this thing and hopefully Blue won't go north.
Speaker 1: And then when I'm Blue, I'm like, so obviously I'm not going to build a tank because that asshole built those mechs.
Speaker 1: So instead I'm building the anti-air and I am going north because that's what he didn't expect.
Speaker 1: It was weird watching myself compartmentalize the two sides.
Speaker 1: It was kind of, it was actually weird watching me play after I made the video.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Like super weird.
Speaker 0: Other meta things that I can think of.
Speaker 1: We're going to be at PAX East presenting on Friday, March 6th.
Speaker 0: PAX East is ridiculously close to PAX Out.
Speaker 1: 4.30 PM and PAX OZ just happened.
Speaker 0: Anime Boston's also coming up.
Speaker 0: So is Zenkai Con.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: It's convention season has moved from summer to spring.
Speaker 1: See Genericon, I know you wanted us to come.
Speaker 1: This is why we can't come.
Speaker 1: We're sorry.
Speaker 0: It's also Netrunner's store championship season.
Speaker 0: If anyone cares.
Speaker 1: But on Friday, March 6th, also at 4.30 PM in the Bumblebee Theater, we are presenting what is losing at PAX East.
Speaker 1: Welcome to our panel and find out.
Speaker 0: It is living with the name of Rim.
Speaker 1: And it is not just.
Speaker 0: Your name is Rim and you're alive.
Speaker 0: My losing panel.
Speaker 1: I did a panel called Losing at PAX Australia and this is not that.
Speaker 0: You're an expert on the topic.
Speaker 0: Of course you should be doing that.
Speaker 1: I'm in fact an expert on losing for the only way to become a winner is to understand the loser.
Speaker 0: To be the loser.
Speaker 1: To defeat the loser, you must become the loser.
Speaker 1: That is where Juggalos came from.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: So we played a tabletop game.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I've played this game twice.
Speaker 1: I've played it once.
Speaker 0: It's enough.
Speaker 0: Alright, so what this game is King's Forge.
Speaker 0: It is made and designed by a person named Nick Sibicki.
Speaker 0: I think it was a kick-started game.
Speaker 0: It was published.
Speaker 1: Was it a kick-starter game?
Speaker 0: I think it was.
Speaker 1: Because in my experience, and I'm going to lay down some real sad, ugly truth right here.
Speaker 1: Games that are kick-started, that are tabletop games, tend to be fucking awful.
Speaker 1: It is very rare that they are not fucking awful.
Speaker 0: King's Forge was indeed kick-started.
Speaker 0: They had a buy game salute.
Speaker 0: They had a goal of $5,000 and they made $80,000.
Speaker 1: Guys, don't kick-start board games.
Speaker 0: Okay, so, King's Forge.
Speaker 0: What is King's Forge about?
Speaker 0: Basically, I really like the theme of this game.
Speaker 0: Everyone is some sort of smith or artisan, and the king wants goods.
Speaker 0: And you're forging goods for the king, and whoever forges enough goods first is the best.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter what you forge, it's just, do you forge stuff?
Speaker 1: Now, there's a limited set of things to be forged that the king will want, and it's Dominion style.
Speaker 1: Every time you play, you make basically a splay of, "This is what will be forged in this
Speaker 1: game.".
Speaker 0: There's like five things the king wants.
Speaker 0: If you can forge one of them first, you give it to the king.
Speaker 0: He's like, "Alright, I got the thing I
Speaker 0: want.".
Speaker 0: Even if someone else forges it, which they can't, there's no point.
Speaker 0: The king is like, "I already got one of those.
Speaker 0: Don't need
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: So, if you show up at the king's door some number of times, three times, four times first, then he's like, "Whoa, you've been forging a whole bunch of stuff for me.
Speaker 0: You're the awesomest.
Speaker 0: You
Speaker 0: win.".
Speaker 0: And that's how the game goes.
Speaker 0: So, mechanically, it's really very similar to Splendor, only random and bullshit.
Speaker 1: So, if you look at this game without reading the rules, you just look at what it looks like, you think it's going to be Yahtzee.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it's kind of cool physically as well.
Speaker 0: There's cards with awesome art of different items to make for the king.
Speaker 0: There's this cool area where you're working to build up your dice.
Speaker 0: All kinds of different colored dice.
Speaker 0: Tons of them.
Speaker 0: You get to roll them.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the multicolors of dice give you this really good feeling of, "Oh, fuck yeah, I got some red dice
Speaker 1: now.".
Speaker 0: It's all different.
Speaker 0: When you're choosing, you can choose a little plaque for your player.
Speaker 0: I always choose the green owl.
Speaker 0: Owl is an awesome animal, and green is the best color.
Speaker 0: But there's all these other choices, like purple dragon.
Speaker 0: There's all kinds of good stuff going on in this game.
Speaker 0: But, the bad part about this game is basically in the details.
Speaker 0: If they had just changed the details of this game a little bit, they could have made it polished and smooth and actually really, really good.
Speaker 0: But because, in the details, there are flaws that do not exist in a more tested and proven game like Splendor, what ends up happening is there's a huge advantage to the first player on the first turn.
Speaker 1: Most of the time.
Speaker 0: Most of the time.
Speaker 1: That will only not occur if basically only hard to forge things come out.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Also, there is a huge luck advantage in general.
Speaker 0: Not just the dice rolling, because you can sort of mitigate the dice rolling.
Speaker 0: You can't mitigate the like, well, these are the choices that are available to me on my turn.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: You actually have a very limited, like you have a limited, so basically there's some options that are always out there that you can just do if you want.
Speaker 1: Or, you can use one of the options that's flipped up.
Speaker 0: Right, right.
Speaker 0: Okay, so let me explain it better so people aren't completely lost.
Speaker 0: Everyone has a bunch of dice.
Speaker 0: Some black dice you start with.
Speaker 1: Yeah, boring dice, crap dice.
Speaker 0: But you can get better, you can basically, on your turn, you can, if you want to, do something which usually involves spending dice, either losing them permanently or for the turn, in order to get better dice that you only will be able to use on a future turn.
Speaker 1: So for example, give up three black dice this turn, and then for the next turn you get a green die.
Speaker 0: Yep, or give up a green die permanently, get a blue die starting next turn.
Speaker 0: Then at the end of your turn, any dice that haven't been used, you get to roll.
Speaker 0: And when you roll them, if you roll adequately enough to match the requirements listed in one of the king's items, then you forge that item.
Speaker 1: So like this item needs three red dice of five or higher, and four black dice of one or higher.
Speaker 0: Right, so you have to A, have enough dice to meet that, first of all, and B, roll them and get that result.
Speaker 0: So if you have enough red and black dice, you roll them, and one of the red die is too low, you missed it.
Speaker 0: You don't get to forge it this turn.
Speaker 1: And then it has this tie-breaking thing, so say I forge an object, and then when we get to Scott, he can forge the same object, and his dice on a one-to-one matchup are higher than my dice?
Speaker 0: Yeah, every single die I have has to be higher than yours.
Speaker 0: So even if, let's say, it's a very simple one, you need a red three, red at least three, black at least three.
Speaker 0: Rim rolls four four, red four, black four.
Speaker 0: I roll red six, black three.
Speaker 0: So I met the requirements, and in fact, if you add up my numbers, I actually have one higher than him.
Speaker 0: I have nine worth and eight worth, he has eight worth, and we've both met the requirements.
Speaker 0: But because both of my dice are not both higher than his, every single one has to be higher, I don't get it.
Speaker 0: He gets it because he went first.
Speaker 1: Yep, which is, that is fine.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Except, so there's a first mover advantage on taking items.
Speaker 1: There's a first mover advantage just in terms of the objects, like the actions you have available to you during the game.
Speaker 1: And the turn order only rotates clockwise based on the passing of the overdone anvil.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the anvil, it's like, the game has really good, I told you, construction of pieces.
Speaker 0: Whose turn of his marker is a big plastic anvil.
Speaker 0: I feel
Speaker 1: like the game was not play-tested enough to determine the fact that there are two forces giving advantage to the person who goes first in the overall game, and to the person who's currently going first, and because the number of things you need to forge to end and win the game, whoever goes first is likely to get the advantage more than other people.
Speaker 0: Usually at the beginning of the game, there is like an easy to forge item that pretty much anyone could forge on turn one just by rolling all their black die, and it's not many more or less valuable than any other item, but if there's only one or two of these things, the first or second player is almost guaranteed to get them, no matter what the other players try to do.
Speaker 0: So obviously the strategy for the other players is to give up on them, and spend that turn upgrading to get better items.
Speaker 0: The thing is, the other players can also spend their turn upgrading and still get those items, and they're just basically one item ahead the whole game, and it's very hard to out-compete them unless all of the items that appeared are difficult, and then everyone has to spend their turns building up and can't get anything easily.
Speaker 1: And because you basically get, at the end of the build-up phase, the one roll, sometimes you just get completely fucked, and the only real strategy is deciding, based on how far behind you are, how much you're willing to risk, in terms of, like, the game seems to come down to, well, Scott will win on his turn unless he rolls badly, so rather than taking a long-shot chance of being able to beat him in case he rolls well, I'm just going to spend this turn developing, bank on him failing,
Speaker 0: Because I have no other choice.
Speaker 0: There's no way to attack the other players, other than going before them.
Speaker 1: So, that's the other problem.
Speaker 1: There are a handful of things that let you attack other players.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's right.
Speaker 0: They're very tiny, though.
Speaker 1: Because there's so few of them, they just devastate individual players, primarily for spite and leaderkeeping and things like that.
Speaker 1: Like, they're very... either have those things be common or don't have them at all.
Speaker 1: I hate games where, like, oh, there's this one way you can attack that comes up sometimes.
Speaker 1: Either be an attacking game or don't be an attacking game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you look at other really well-designed games, say, Power Grid, one of the all-time great games of tabletop in general, it gives an advantage to the first player, sometimes, in the house buying, because you get the cheapest house spots first, because you get to go first.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then it mitigates it.
Speaker 0: But it mitigates it because in the auctions, it kind of sucks to go first.
Speaker 1: Well, look at Sellers of Catan.
Speaker 1: If you place your first settlement first, you get the best spot on the board.
Speaker 1: You place your second settlement last.
Speaker 1: The guy who places his first one last gets to place both at the same time, so he's guaranteed to get the spots he wants.
Speaker 1: And it's actually super balanced.
Speaker 0: All good games, you know, have some way to mitigate where going first is good sometimes and bad sometimes, and it moves in such a way, you know, that it's not... So in this game, just going first in the first turn of the game is a ginormous advantage, and going first in any given turn is a ginormous advantage on that given turn.
Speaker 0: So you just try to go first, and then you're going to be very easily winning this game.
Speaker 1: The rules are also a little bit obtuse.
Speaker 1: The terminology is pretty consistent, but not great.
Speaker 1: It took far longer to teach this game than it should have, for how complex this game actually is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's actually a really simple game to play, but learning it just took a long time, because for whatever reason, you know, the way the instructions are written, the way the cards are worded, those sorts of things.
Speaker 0: And all the sorts of, like, catchy situations.
Speaker 0: Like, it took a minute to explain, "I have a 6 and a 3, that's 9, that's higher than his 4 and
Speaker 0: 4.".
Speaker 0: But he met the requirement, he met it first, and I have to have both of my dice have to meet or exceed all of his.
Speaker 0: So, even if just one of my dice is lower, if every single other die I have exceeds his, if just one is lower, I can't take it away from him.
Speaker 1: You have such limited options, that you're only, you know, there's the fiddly, like, "Do I do this one thing or this other one
Speaker 1: thing?".
Speaker 1: But in general, your decisions come down to, "Do I invest in this turn, or the next
Speaker 1: turn?".
Speaker 0: And there's not going to be that many turns.
Speaker 1: You have no other choice.
Speaker 1: Invest now, or invest later.
Speaker 1: Everything else is pretty obvious and boring.
Speaker 0: The way Splendor mitigates a lot of this, is this, in this game, you get like, what, 4 items or something, and it's over, and that's it.
Speaker 0: In Splendor, it's like, you're buying cards like crazy.
Speaker 0: There's so many things to buy constantly coming out all the time.
Speaker 0: If King's Forge is like, "Forge a ton of items over 10 turns over forges the most wins," and you're forging quite crazy, then that can mitigate so much of the luck, because not everything is tied up, and like, one big item is it.
Speaker 0: It's like, oh, I'm forging a whole bunch of stuff, everyone's forging a whole bunch of stuff, and then it comes down to the smaller optimizations in your play, as opposed to the random chance, I got that one item by luck, I win.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the other problem I had was with the, you know, you get the semi-randomized set of actions that are going to be available, and that's the set for the whole game.
Speaker 1: So it has that dominion aspect of, the actual decision is, based on the set of actions that are going to be in this game, what is the clearest path to victory?
Speaker 1: However, because of your limited interaction with those things, and the way the turns work, you have no actual choice as to whether or not to follow that strategy.
Speaker 0: Right, you're sitting there looking, and it's like, well, there's the actions that are already available, that are always available, and one of them is clearly superior, that haven't been taken yet, and then here are the actions that are available at this moment that I can take.
Speaker 0: So you pick the best one, and you can't take anything else into account, and then as soon as you take one, if it's one of the temporary ones, you immediately physically take it, and another one is immediately revealed for the next player, that might be the best one, it just happened to appear on their turn, and if you hadn't taken one of the temporary ones, they wouldn't have seen that, the next person would have seen it, or someone, you know, but
Speaker 1: there's no way to know.
Speaker 1: Now meanwhile, another game that has a similar mechanical sort of, I don't want to say problem, but nuance, is Hansa Teutonica, because if you take a special plate, you have to put another one out, that the next player...
Speaker 0: But you can put it in a place where they can't get it easily, or it benefits you, and mitigate the fact that you have to put out this awesome plate, that you might...
Speaker 1: So you get a, you know what I call this?
Speaker 1: You get a boon, the awesome boon.
Speaker 0: You might have taken an extra office plate just to get a plate, and then you're forced to put out an extra action plate on the board that you really would have rather had, but now every other person is going to get a chance to go for that plate before you can even make a move
Speaker 1: on it.
Speaker 1: So if you choose to take the boon, the plate or an action that's one of the temporary cards that's out there, then you have to accept the bust of the next player, the person to your left, now has an advantage.
Speaker 1: You get a nudge after that in Hansa Teutonica.
Speaker 1: You can nudge that bust in a direction that's beneficial to you.
Speaker 1: In this game, you can't do that, and in this game, your only options are take a shitty action, or take one of the temp actions.
Speaker 1: You're always giving the next player.
Speaker 1: There's never a good tactical or strategic reason to take the bad action, the suboptimal one, just to prevent the player to your left from getting a better possible action.
Speaker 0: So on your turn, all you end up doing is taking the best possible action you can, and then everything else is completely up to luck.
Speaker 0: So there aren't really a lot of meaningful decisions.
Speaker 0: once you've figured this out, and it comes down to rolling dice and whose turn it is and what cards appear, and it gets pretty close to Candyland amongst smart people.
Speaker 1: Yep, so who is this game good for?
Speaker 1: If you're a gamer gamer, I really wouldn't buy this game.
Speaker 1: I would play it occasionally.
Speaker 0: Just get Splendor, and it's almost the same game without the bullshit.
Speaker 1: Now, because I already know how to play it, if someone else busted it out at a con and said, "Hey, you want to play
Speaker 1: it?".
Speaker 0: If I didn't have to pay for it, and I was curious, and I was a really big tabletop gamer, I would definitely play it at least once or twice to understand what we're talking about, because there are lessons to learn from this game.
Speaker 1: Yes, but if you're good at games, I mean, I would play Castles of Burgundy over this.
Speaker 0: This game can also have drama.
Speaker 0: If the luck ends up being in the dice rolling, it's possible there could be exciting drama in this game.
Speaker 0: It didn't happen when we played because people mitigated the luck as much as smart people do, but someone could theoretically just go big, just try to go for it, and end up getting like 66666 or something crazy or 111.
Speaker 0: That should have been an easy grab of that item, but I rolled a bunch of ones, and I didn't have any of the automatically turn my dice to six things.
Speaker 0: Which is fine.
Speaker 1: I mean, when the goalie scores in hockey, that's amazing.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But this game...
Speaker 0: It happens rarely.
Speaker 0: I played it twice, and that happened zero times.
Speaker 0: It was just theoretically always in the back of everyone's mind.
Speaker 0: It never actually happened.
Speaker 1: So in terms of the brain feel as a result, if I win or lose this game, those two feelings are not different.
Speaker 1: Because if I win, I feel like it was because of the luck and the randomness and the order of the cards, and if I lose, it's because of the exact same thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is one of those games I get frustrated playing, and it's like, I'm usually not frustrated playing a bad game or losing a good game.
Speaker 0: I'm frustrated when there's a potential for goodness that was taken away.
Speaker 1: You know how many times when the rules were being explained to us, me or Scott would be like, "Oh, and then you do X because that would be
Speaker 1: cool?".
Speaker 1: And then the guy's like, "Uh, no, actually, you just do
Speaker 1: Y.".
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: This game, if they had just playtested it more, worked on it harder, and didn't spend all their Kickstarter money on a fancy plastic anvil and high-quality pieces and high-quality arts and all the other things that actually were kind of good about this thing, if they had made the game better, then this could have been like even maybe even competing with Splendor because that dice part actually, you know, but they failed.
Speaker 1: So, something interesting.
Speaker 1: I went to BoardGameGeek just to see if there's any interesting notes about this.
Speaker 1: The top post about this game is, "Shill alert!
Speaker 1: The King's Forge 7.38 rating seems
Speaker 1: bogus.".
Speaker 0: So many fake 10 ratings.
Speaker 1: Quote, "I almost bought this game today, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, but then I came to look at the game comments before I pulled the trigger.
Speaker 1: I noticed that seven of the nine BGG users who gave King's Forge a 10 had no avatars or badges of any
Speaker 1: kind.".
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: "And appeared to be new
Speaker 1: accounts.".
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: "They had no comments and didn't blah, blah, blah, and then he posted a bunch of evidence and...".
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, people Kickstarting a game are very likely to, you know, my work is actually having the same thing.
Speaker 0: We have like apps in the App Store and it's like, "Should we go submit fake
Speaker 0: ratings?".
Speaker 0: And I'm like, "I'm
Speaker 0: not.".
Speaker 0: And I think it's, you know, do you just want to be dishonest and evil if you do it?
Speaker 1: "But if I made it, don't I think it's a great
Speaker 1: app?"
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 0: But it's like, go for it.
Speaker 0: Go submit your, you know, fake, you know, review that you want for your own app to try to boost it up in the App Store ratings.
Speaker 0: Instead of letting it live on its own merits.
Speaker 1: Just don't click on your own ads in YouTube or your account is going to be fucking shut down.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about that another time.
Speaker 0: At least the AdSense part of your account.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They'll still let you make videos.
Speaker 1: But I guess King's Forge reminds me so much of Ground Floor.
Speaker 1: In both games were Kickstarters with really high production values that obviously did not get a lot of playtesting.
Speaker 1: And the rules were written by people who obviously don't have a lot of experience with like the history of tabletop game rules as written by everyone else in the world.
Speaker 1: They make a lot of amateur mistakes.
Speaker 1: There's obvious flaws.
Speaker 1: There's usually like a fixed rule or errata that comes out pretty soon after the game.
Speaker 1: Like the thing that was in Ground Floor that was really broken was that advertising thing.
Speaker 1: That part of the game where you'd like put your, I forget exactly what it was called.
Speaker 0: No, I know exactly what you're talking about.
Speaker 1: Because it was designed so counterintuitively and so stupidly that players wanted to ignore it because it wasn't fun to deal with.
Speaker 1: But because the rest of the game was badly designed, it was actually the only thing that mattered.
Speaker 1: Ground Floor is very similar in that there's no way this game got a lot of playtesting.
Speaker 1: Or if it did, only amateur hour people playtested it.
Speaker 0: Right, my guess is that sort of what we're seeing here with a lot of the Kickstarted board games is there are people who play games, who are making tabletop games.
Speaker 0: And the things with video games is at least a barrier to entry to where you need to learn how to code or at least learn how to use Game Maker.
Speaker 0: You need to have some specialized knowledge to make a video game and it takes a while.
Speaker 0: So this barrier to entry where it's kind of hard to make a well-produced, completely bad video game.
Speaker 0: If you've completely produced and well-made a video game code and art-wise, you must know something kind of good.
Speaker 1: Well, we were just at an event at Microsoft where we got to demo a whole bunch of unreleased indie video and tabletop games.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: The unreleased didn't put a lot of time into these yet and far from polished video games were almost universally amazing.
Speaker 0: You could see unique things in there that if they just worked on them some more, they could turn into gold, like Nidhogg level gold.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, and I've got another ugly truth here, almost every tabletop game that is indie and unreleased that I've ever playtested or played or done a demo of with anyone has been awful.
Speaker 1: Almost every.
Speaker 1: There are exceptions.
Speaker 1: Like Jeremy's game he's working on is actually really good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no.
Speaker 0: Jeremy's game is better than any tabletop game I've demoed.
Speaker 1: Or like that weirdo Luke Crane when he made us play that tabletop game that one time at UberCon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that roleplaying game.
Speaker 1: Or then now the mouse swords game.
Speaker 1: Swords and strongholds.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's made by a real game maker.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: The barrier to entry of tabletop is low so a lot of tabletop games get kickstarted with really high production values.
Speaker 0: Well, also you don't need to be a good tabletop game to make a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Look at Munchkin.
Speaker 0: Munchkin is the king.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Cryptozoic is the king.
Speaker 0: That's what people are going for.
Speaker 0: They got $80,000 for their kickstarter no matter what.
Speaker 0: They have the money.
Speaker 1: If I were budgeting to make a tabletop game, it would be more than $80,000.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they asked for $5,000.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I were, this is me, the product manager, like all the other work I do in my life.
Speaker 1: If I were budgeting a company to make a game like Kings Forge and sell it for real, my budget would be about $120,000 to $150,000 minimum.
Speaker 0: Probably.
Speaker 1: So...
Speaker 0: You need at least just $60,000 to pay the salary of the game designer.
Speaker 1: Yes, a game designer.
Speaker 0: For a year.
Speaker 1: A dedicated game designer who is an experienced game designer.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That's half the money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then contracting out art and then extensive play testing.
Speaker 1: Play testing that takes longer than the game design, maybe.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one more.
Speaker 0: This actually reminds me of one more thing.
Speaker 0: So, in Netrunner, they have the draft, which is like you buy cards.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like in Magic Drafting.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You buy cards, you open them, you pass them around like Seven Wonders and then you play.
Speaker 0: So, they charge money for this and it's not the one, the official draft is not very good and it costs a lot of money to play.
Speaker 0: So, it's very hard to get people to do it.
Speaker 0: We did it once and that was sort of it, in New York at least.
Speaker 0: So, what some people do is they make a cube, which is the thing people have done in Magic where it's like make your own, you know, draft, you know, pile of cards and pass it around and everyone will draft out of that.
Speaker 0: And that way we don't have to pay money.
Speaker 0: We just take cards you already own, put them in a pile and we can have all the fun of drafting without whatever.
Speaker 0: And I was like, the guy's like, "Oh, yeah, my cards are all...".
Speaker 0: I get into a discussion with a dude.
Speaker 0: He's like, "Oh, you don't, why don't you want to play the
Speaker 0: cube?".
Speaker 0: And I'm like, "Dude, it's basically the same thing we're talking about here.
Speaker 0: It's a game made by a
Speaker 0: player.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay, Netrunner wasn't made by the player, but this cube is like, "How do you know your cube is balanced?
Speaker 0: What kind of rules you got for this
Speaker 0: cube?".
Speaker 0: He's like, "Oh, but it's been made by, you know, Magic players have been doing this for a long
Speaker 0: time.".
Speaker 0: It's like, "I don't care.
Speaker 0: You know, the card selection, how much have you play?
Speaker 0: tested this?
Speaker 0: You're basically asking me to be a play
Speaker 0: tester.".
Speaker 0: You know, but people really like doing it despite how crappy it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, guys... The same people that like King's Forge.
Speaker 1: We will play.
Speaker 1: test your game either if you're a close personal friend or for money.
Speaker 1: We're not going to play.
Speaker 1: test your game at a con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the guy brought his cube to the next Netrunner night.
Speaker 0: He's like, "Does anyone want to play my
Speaker 0: cube?".
Speaker 0: And it was like, "Nope.
Speaker 0: No one wanted to play his
Speaker 0: cube.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, we did that panel, How to Win at Games.
Speaker 1: Remember how we talked about how if you understand games truly well, you ruin most games for yourself?
Speaker 1: If you get good at games, you're going to sound exactly like us about the 90% of tabletop games you ever play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I told that guy the story of Tribes 2 that basically let the players get what they wanted and Counter-Strike, which didn't let the players get what they wanted.
Speaker 0: He still was not convinced.
Speaker 0: He was just so adamant about his cube.
Speaker 0: How his cube drafting was so great.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, his cube gate.
Speaker 1: You're denying him entry.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: Cube Ghazi.
Speaker 0: You can't say gate anymore.
Speaker 0: No gates allowed.
Speaker 0: It's all Ghazis now.
Speaker 0: Only Ghazis allowed.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.