Speaker 1: It's Monday, February 23rd, 2015.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem, and this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 1: Lenovo, and how you should never buy anything from them ever again.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, technology, you know, we're always advocates of how technology lets you, like, keep every conversation you ever have, and you can sort of search through and resolve arguments, and, you know, the internet doesn't forget.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm glad that we're living by the sword and dying by the exact same sword, because it turns out...
Speaker 0: I'm not dying.
Speaker 1: Well, you're losing 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: Big deal.
Speaker 1: Live by the $20.
Speaker 0: You don't have $20?
Speaker 0: You got a problem with monies?
Speaker 1: You gotta pay the poor man's bet, not the rich man's bet.
Speaker 1: So, back in 2012, in the... When was that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, ancient times.
Speaker 1: Quetzalcoatl never showed up, too.
Speaker 1: Waiting for him.
Speaker 1: We did a show, and we were talking about OSX and Mountain Lion and Gatekeeper and all that stuff, and Scott and I kind of doubled down on a position we took, and we made a bet.
Speaker 1: In fact, not only did we make a bet, but this is notable because Scott doesn't fucking ever make bets.
Speaker 1: Scott was so sure, and so was I, that what I bet was, and you're gonna see why this is gonna fail now, quoting myself.
Speaker 1: Well, first, Scott, I will bet money.
Speaker 1: Within three years, you won't be able to install non-App Store software on Apple computers.
Speaker 0: All right, well, I got the time frame wrong, but that has definitely been going in that direction, and give it some number of more years that I will not bet on.
Speaker 1: No, you're not gonna bet anymore.
Speaker 1: You're not as sure.
Speaker 0: But it is going to happen.
Speaker 0: It's coming.
Speaker 0: It's been happening since then, and it's happening more.
Speaker 1: So, my bet was, and I quote, "I will bet $100.
Speaker 1: that Scott is right with the qualifier that if Apple actually removes it, the option that lets you, like, sideload, but some hacker finds a supported way around it, I will still
Speaker 1: win.".
Speaker 1: So, if someone cracked or hacked or got around it, I didn't lose the bet.
Speaker 1: And I bet that in 2012, and there's some follow-up discussion where people are...
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at least today, if you buy a brand new MacBook Pro, you can install things on it, and Apple doesn't try to stop you.
Speaker 1: So, some days ago, not very long ago, someone tweeted at me, and they tweeted at me a screenshot.
Speaker 1: It was a screenshot of a notification on their phone reminding them that the deadline for the bet was coming up.
Speaker 1: And, yeah, we lost that bet, so I owe our friend George, like, $100, and Scott owes him, like, $20.
Speaker 0: This is why I don't bet a lot of money.
Speaker 0: And somewhat related to that, I've made a habit of, like, when I look things up on the internet that are from olden times, I look at, like, dates on Wikipedia of things.
Speaker 1: Trying to, like, match up, like, what happened when.
Speaker 0: Right, like, maybe I'll find a video game, right?
Speaker 0: And I'll see, I'll, like, look up some old video game, and I'll be like, you know, what was the release date for Super Metroid?
Speaker 0: Right, and then I'll see what it was, and then I go in my calendar, and I'll go to, like, the significant round number anniversary, like, 25th anniversary or something, and I'll put in, like, Super Metroid 20th anniversary on my Google calendar.
Speaker 0: And then, one day, that happens, and then you can tweet it or whatever, and people are like,
Speaker 0: "Whoa!"
Speaker 0: And no one else tweeted it.
Speaker 0: You're just you.
Speaker 1: So, a better way to go about that, why don't you just use, like, TweetDeck and schedule that shit?
Speaker 0: Uh, 'cause then, you got to, you know, let's say the 50th anniversary of something, right, that TweetDeck still has to be running then.
Speaker 1: Ah, true, true.
Speaker 1: It's, you know, it's easier to get a goo, you know, the goo, and you might not wanna Plus, what if, like, Hitler 3 rises on that same day, and the whole world is going crazy, and you're like, "Hey guys, the 50th anniversary of
Speaker 1: Mario!".
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Just find, whenever you look up something old, look at the date, and then find an anniversary and put it on your Google calendar, and it's interesting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 0: When you get the notification on that day, you'll be like, "Oh shit, that's blank years old?
Speaker 0: Fuck me.
Speaker 0: Fuck
Speaker 0: me.".
Speaker 1: It gets real bad with movies, especially when it's movies that I saw in the theater.
Speaker 1: That is a big differentiator for me being an old man.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we were, you know, never, never, ever.
Speaker 1: imply that we won't admit it when we're wrong.
Speaker 1: We made a prediction three years ago in technology, and we were fucking completely wrong.
Speaker 0: We were wrong on the time frame.
Speaker 0: I still think we'll be wrong on the fact.
Speaker 1: I don't think so anymore.
Speaker 1: I think the sideload options will remain indefinitely.
Speaker 1: I think that either Mac OS X will disappear entirely, or continue to be more locked down over time as it has been.
Speaker 1: Except it's opened up in a lot of ways.
Speaker 0: In what ways?
Speaker 1: Quote, "Instead of Dropbox having to do kernel hack stuff to change the icons to sync folders, Apple gave them an API they could use to change
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: "Apple let them use this feature in the same release that they launched CloudKit, which could be seen as a
Speaker 1: competitor.".
Speaker 1: I'm quoting Luke Burge in The Forum, where he basically argues vociferously against your assertion that they're locking down more as time goes on.
Speaker 1: There is the secondary issue where they're- Changing icons.
Speaker 0: Oh man, that's just so not locking down.
Speaker 1: There is the secondary.
Speaker 1: There's kind of two separate things.
Speaker 1: There's the, can you load applications that you wrote or that aren't in the app store or aren't approved or blessed?
Speaker 1: And then there's the, do they enforce apps that are in the app store to follow certain requirements?
Speaker 1: And on that side, the latter side, they're definitely going down that direction.
Speaker 0: Well, they've always been in that direction.
Speaker 1: I kind of feel like Android should go down that same direction.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't think you should enforce restrictions on people of like.
Speaker 0: how they- There's certain kinds of restrictions that are okay and certain kinds that aren't, right?
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: Apple, for example, will not let you make a porn app and put it in their app store.
Speaker 1: No, I think that's bad.
Speaker 0: Even if that porn app is absolutely in every way completely legal and there's a parental control or whatever the fuck you want or, you know, et cetera, they will not allow it.
Speaker 0: And they have often, you know, porn, you know, when you see it, Apple has often blocked, you know, and sometimes gone back on their blockage or denials.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: But not always.
Speaker 0: Apps that, you know, contain sexual content or violent content or whatever that is not actually porn or it's perhaps of an artistic or other, you know, worthwhile nature.
Speaker 0: And, you know, those sorts of things are not cool.
Speaker 0: to say you can't come in my app store because there's some boobies, you know, on this album cover.
Speaker 1: For example, there are things that you can do in Android apps that just fuck the battery.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: And I feel they are checking for the general.
Speaker 0: One thing I do agree is that if you're going to put something in an app store that's, you know, verified that somebody should, you know, like.
Speaker 0: I'm trusting that because it's the official app store.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's like you sort of as a person don't have the mental capacity to trust and distrust individual things.
Speaker 0: If I trust the app store, I have to trust everything in it.
Speaker 0: I can't like I know I do not trust download dot com or anything on it.
Speaker 0: I can't like, you know, if I have to then suddenly trust some things on download dot com and some and not others, that's a huge pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So if I'm going to trust the official Google Play store of apps or the official iOS store of apps, I need to know that none of those apps have malwares.
Speaker 0: None of them will like actively harm my device or ruin the performance.
Speaker 0: It's a list of quality issues that need to be addressed by who is ever approving what goes in there.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: And I'm really OK with those kinds of restrictions.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Some of them are OK.
Speaker 0: And so, you know, but if I want to install the make my phone explode app, I should be able to go and download it.
Speaker 1: What was that app that I found?
Speaker 1: I think I used it a long time ago, but use the accelerometer and the GPS.
Speaker 1: And the goal was throw your phone as hard as you can up and then catch it.
Speaker 1: And your high score is how high it got.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 1: But I don't think Apple is going to restrict or prevent people from unchecking that box that says, yeah, install some bullshit if I want.
Speaker 1: I think that's going to still be an option for the foreseeable future.
Speaker 0: Eventually.
Speaker 1: I don't think eventually ever.
Speaker 0: I think eventually.
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: I think at least in the Y plus 30.
Speaker 1: So, you know, 30 years ish.
Speaker 0: You're really stretching the time frame.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was 100 percent wrong and I fully accept that.
Speaker 0: I only got the time frame wrong.
Speaker 0: I believe.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: I only got the time frame wrong.
Speaker 0: I still believe, believe the end is nigh.
Speaker 0: I can't say when.
Speaker 1: So in other news, you know that Google acquired Waze and they kind of integrated that stuff.
Speaker 0: What did they acquire?
Speaker 1: Waze, Waze, Waze, Waze, Waze.
Speaker 1: You don't know about Waze?
Speaker 0: I don't know what the hell you're talking about.
Speaker 1: So Waze was an app that basically.
Speaker 0: How do you spell this?
Speaker 1: W A Z E.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: That's oh, are they trying to be cute like W A Y S. But they spelled it W A Z E but pronounce it the same.
Speaker 1: I guess it just pronounced ways like I never thought about it because basically it was an app you could use.
Speaker 0: And it would tell you about traffic and Google Maps tells you about traffic and navigation.
Speaker 1: So Google Maps used to do it kind of shittily.
Speaker 1: Google bought them.
Speaker 0: Google Maps does it really well.
Speaker 0: They've done it really well since Google Maps stopped sucking, which is like in its second year.
Speaker 1: See, now you say that, but actually Google Maps directions like live navigation was really bad at routing you around accidents and traffic.
Speaker 0: I know for about two years, Google Maps is garbage.
Speaker 0: And then it became good.
Speaker 1: You're talking about like 2003, like that kind of era.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I remember when it was brand new.
Speaker 0: You would we were like, fuck Google Maps.
Speaker 0: I mean, it looks better.
Speaker 0: But MapQuest actually tells you where the fuck to go.
Speaker 0: That was true.
Speaker 0: It doesn't send you down a one way street to die.
Speaker 1: That was in fact true.
Speaker 1: I didn't try.
Speaker 1: Google Maps was the worst.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: In about two years, they stopped sucking and beat MapQuest.
Speaker 0: And then people were like, what's MapQuest?
Speaker 0: And ever since then, Google Maps has been pretty much perfect compared to other competitors.
Speaker 0: There's been no reason to use anything else.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Except I drive a lot, you know, just like taking people places and kind of like the chauffeur at this point.
Speaker 1: And even though neither one of us owns a car, I just have the Zipcar.
Speaker 1: But Waze had way better like speed trap, alternate route.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: Trap info is somewhat illegal in some places.
Speaker 1: Those court cases pretty much always get overturned.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We won some free speech.
Speaker 1: We usually win those in the end.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 1: But basically, Waze had much better data.
Speaker 1: And what Waze would do that Google Maps didn't do for a long time was say you're driving and there's an accident like right now, it would.
Speaker 1: it would very likely be able to tell you, yo dog, get off the freeway the next exit or you're fucked.
Speaker 1: Like right then, like real time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So Google Maps, even today, it doesn't reroute.
Speaker 0: It's like you when you ask for the directions, it gets you a route and you choose that route and then it locks that route in and won't reroute.
Speaker 0: Now, you say that unless you go off the route, then it will reroute.
Speaker 1: This is what changed.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it works on iPhone, but at least on Android, if you're driving now what it does.
Speaker 0: I've never actually used the driving.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I use the walking in the bike.
Speaker 1: I've used the navigator one.
Speaker 1: Well, it does this for walking and everything, too.
Speaker 1: It'll always constantly be showing you just like on the map, gray offshoots like this is a juncture where you could take this all day.
Speaker 0: You can see the routes there because they're the same ones that were there when you asked.
Speaker 1: But it does.
Speaker 1: it live while you're navigating and it flags any route that is currently based on current right now data faster than the road you're on right now.
Speaker 1: So if an accident happens on like the freeway ahead of you, but it doesn't automatically switch you to that route, it just puts a little it pops up and says, yo, you want to you want to try this other route.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I've never seen that happen even one because it's only started happening.
Speaker 0: And I guess it would only be likely to happen driving because that's where traffic is.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: And it only started happening after they bought ways and ways was just really good at figuring out ways, ways.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's why I called that the Beatles.
Speaker 0: So Google bought ways and used it to make Google Maps better.
Speaker 1: So they finally integrated all that shit into Google Maps.
Speaker 1: And here's the problem.
Speaker 1: It's not a problem.
Speaker 1: It's a problem for people who suck.
Speaker 1: Tons of people, particularly in
Speaker 1: L.A.,
Speaker 1: are suing or otherwise super pissed because now there's a ton of traffic in their neighborhoods because Google Maps is telling people smart ways to get around traffic jams.
Speaker 1: So suddenly, like before, we're like I-84, which would be blocked because there's an accident on the bridge.
Speaker 1: Now, ways will tell everyone all the different ways to go.
Speaker 1: And as the ways around that start getting saturated, it finds other ways because it's using live data from all the other people driving.
Speaker 1: So people are super mad that roads that were once quiet, it turns out if you analyze the data, are the best way to get places.
Speaker 1: And people are making maximum efficient use of the existing roads, making traffic flow faster and pissing off NIMBYs.
Speaker 0: Well, listen, you have two choices.
Speaker 0: Number one, you can shut up or number two, we can knock your house down and put a train there.
Speaker 0: Those are your choices.
Speaker 0: No other choice is allowed.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, basically these complaints are ridiculous.
Speaker 1: You can never fault people for using available information and technology to make systems more efficient.
Speaker 0: I can find one fault, which is if and this is only if I don't know this has happened.
Speaker 0: If it routed someone down a private road, that person with the private road can complain.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: But if you own a private road, fuck you rich asshole.
Speaker 0: You can get a helicopter to work and you can get some earplugs because you're still goddamn rich of a private road.
Speaker 0: So go fuck yourself.
Speaker 0: If you complained about someone driving in a private road to avoid traffic, I don't see any problem drowning you.
Speaker 1: But it's amazing.
Speaker 1: Like people, these people who are mad about getting hit by the car is a quote from the article.
Speaker 1: When the people whose houses hug the narrow warren of streets paralleling the busiest urban freeway in America began to see bumper to bumper traffic crawling by their homes a year or so ago, they were baffled.
Speaker 1: Like no one had ever figured out there were shortcuts until now or a few people did.
Speaker 1: Suddenly those shortcuts are part of the road system.
Speaker 1: So the technology behind this is amazing.
Speaker 0: And it's I think you also could have made your roads not suck, but it's too late for that.
Speaker 0: So trains.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Live in New York.
Speaker 1: It's really the only place with trains.
Speaker 0: Don't live in L.A.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Why the fuck do you live there?
Speaker 1: There's a big reason why a lot of people ask me, you know, hey, would you consider moving out to somewhere in California to have a job?
Speaker 1: I was like, would I need to own a car?
Speaker 0: Is it?
Speaker 1: is it not?
Speaker 0: New York is the place you were asking me to live in the Empire State?
Speaker 1: What did I tell?
Speaker 1: I told one guy recently if I was willing to live, leave New York, I would have tried to work for Valve like a decade ago.
Speaker 0: Listen, if I was willing to leave New York, I saw the original job posting from Justin TV looking for the person to start Twitch.
Speaker 0: And it basically if you find that job posting and read it at the time, it was basically skills of Scott.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: I remember that because Scott said I could have applied to that job.
Speaker 1: I could really find the chat we had because you messaged me and you were like, check this out.
Speaker 0: I could have applied to that job and had a very good chance of getting that job if I was willing to go to California, which I wasn't then and I'm not now.
Speaker 1: I'm even less willing to do it now.
Speaker 0: So I think that's the last job posting I saw that I said, that is a job that I want.
Speaker 0: I have not seen such a job posting since then.
Speaker 1: So anyway, you got any news being Monday after a long hiatus?
Speaker 0: Well, since there was such a hiatus, he missed a very important news where the commissioner of the FCC was actually influenced by our deluge of comments.
Speaker 0: And it despite not actually revealing his full proposal, the summary of it is pretty much he's going in our favor and they're going to vote on it real soon.
Speaker 1: This is getting real complicated because net neutrality February 26.
Speaker 0: So three days.
Speaker 1: It's like the Democrats have this really wide and derpy range of opinions on this issue when really they don't have any opinions because I don't think any of them really understand it.
Speaker 1: Maybe Kristen Gillibrand has like almost an idea of what this issue is, but no one else understands what it is or why anyone cares about it.
Speaker 0: Well, what's his name?
Speaker 0: Wu, who ran for lieutenant governor.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, there's two who's to invented the term net neutrality.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are two or three people almost at the national stage who know about this stuff.
Speaker 1: But the Republican Party seems to have pretty much come down hard against net neutrality, right?
Speaker 0: Because it's against the people who are paying them money.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so as I said, I said commissioner, he is the chairman, right?
Speaker 0: The other people in the FCC are the commissioners.
Speaker 0: So it's like a chairman with like a little council of commissioners, right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So he is basically the one time in the past, my lifetime, the government has worked.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Well, government has appeared to almost work.
Speaker 1: Congress has already realized the government is going to shut down again over that immigration thing.
Speaker 1: Like we're already.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: But it appears that that government has almost democracy may work soon.
Speaker 0: The signs are it's like that clock that never rings.
Speaker 0: The hammer next to the bell is pulled back.
Speaker 0: It hasn't rung.
Speaker 0: We got three days quote.
Speaker 1: today.
Speaker 1: Wheeler has released a four page fact sheet about his proposal, which would reclassify broadband Internet under stricter and more utility like laws.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So the actual plan is three hundred and thirty two pages, but only eight of those pages contain the rules.
Speaker 0: The rest of it is just legal justifications and other bullshit that you don't need to actually read unless you're some lawyer or whatnot.
Speaker 0: But someone's job was to write that fucking thing.
Speaker 0: God bless them.
Speaker 0: So anyway, the Republican commissioners right who are pretty much going to lose this vote if it goes down in three days are basically like, let's delay.
Speaker 0: Let's delay.
Speaker 0: We got we got to delay.
Speaker 0: You haven't.
Speaker 0: Why haven't you released the full three hundred and thirty two page thing publicly?
Speaker 0: And why haven't let people comment on that?
Speaker 1: Now, part of the reason is because the Republicans are trying to delay it so that they can try to get Congress to pass a bunch of rules before the FCC can do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They're trying to get in and supersede and thus supersede anything the FCC wants to do itself.
Speaker 0: See, even if they do that, it may bite them in the ass if they act too quickly and write up some bill that is not, you know, carefully written.
Speaker 0: Because if you take powers away from the FCC, many other things that they do may get messed up in a way that they don't like.
Speaker 1: You know, it's interesting because parts of what the FCC does, I'm really against and parts of what it does.
Speaker 1: I'm really for.
Speaker 1: So making it more or less powerful kind of equally serves some of my interest in different ways.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the chairman Wheeler said we received more than four million comments in the past year.
Speaker 0: It's time to do something.
Speaker 0: That was in a tweet he wrote today.
Speaker 0: But he's pretty much like, yeah, you want to stop and have more comments.
Speaker 0: We had four million comments.
Speaker 0: We're just going to vote and you're going to vote the way I want, which is yes.
Speaker 0: And that would be good.
Speaker 1: We'll see though, because like I said, it's pretty much just a partisan issue with this right now.
Speaker 0: Could there be, you know, it is true though that while the summary of the rules changes is pretty much 100 percent what we want almost, I mean, 90 percent what we want.
Speaker 0: Can't really complain.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Uh, he hasn't released those eight pages of actual legal wording rules changes or the other 320 whatever pages of legal nonsense.
Speaker 0: Maybe they're lying to us and actually they're going to vote.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: And we're going to go, yay.
Speaker 0: And then we're going to see the actual rules and go, you lied to us.
Speaker 0: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: Government is just what we thought it was.
Speaker 1: That anti gerrymandering bill in New York that was actually just entrenching gerrymandering forever.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: That one.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: That a lot of people voted for.
Speaker 0: But at least there is more hope now that government will work correctly on one issue than ever before.
Speaker 0: Not since FDR.
Speaker 1: You know, it's interesting because it's an issue where despite the money that gets donated, the Republicans in particular who are nominally against net neutrality, they could let this one slide because their base cares much more about racist stuff than it does about network stuff.
Speaker 0: Ah, but the people who give them money, they could lose that money.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, if they have to give up something.
Speaker 0: But here's the thing I understand.
Speaker 0: It's like, OK, so I'm an evil congressperson and Comcast gives me money every year to run.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And I need that money or I won't get real.
Speaker 0: OK, so, uh, you know, I fight for Comcast.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And I vote in their favor and I, you know, try to write laws for them that don't get passed.
Speaker 0: And every year they give me more money.
Speaker 0: And then this happens and net neutrality happens.
Speaker 0: You know, I couldn't stop it from happening.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, they keep giving me money.
Speaker 0: I don't actually have to get any fucking results for them.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's not like they're going to stop giving me money.
Speaker 0: They might.
Speaker 0: If I vote and what if I vote for you, yes, net neutrality, I like it.
Speaker 0: You think you're going to stop giving me money?
Speaker 1: Probably.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: They just keep giving money to people.
Speaker 0: They don't stop.
Speaker 0: They got to give money to somebody.
Speaker 0: Interesting because the other congressman is going to say, no, I don't want to.
Speaker 1: But the ultra psycho conservatives on the Republican side, they are kind of safe because even if they lose a lot of their money streams, it's hard to displace them unless you come in further right than them.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot of room over there.
Speaker 1: Anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: I'm a big fan of like old futurism, like the visions of the future from the past.
Speaker 1: So this is a extensive, a huge collection of advertisements that from the Bone Aluminum and Brass Corporation from Detroit, from the forties, the nineteen forties.
Speaker 1: And the art is basically all like super high concept design of the future.
Speaker 1: I don't know enough about art to classify this more than just calling it futurism.
Speaker 1: I don't really know, but I really like it.
Speaker 1: And it reminds me a lot of that Italian futurism thing that we saw, except much more Akira-esque in some fashions.
Speaker 0: And apparently being aerodynamic means having motorcycles makes you Akira-esque.
Speaker 1: Well, that motorcycle is pretty Akira-esque, that one in particular.
Speaker 0: Any weird motorcycle is Akira-esque.
Speaker 1: To a degree, yes.
Speaker 0: You realize you could say that Akira is Bon-esque.
Speaker 0: Considering that it came much, much later.
Speaker 1: As long as Akira does not give you a Bon Air.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's anything in that movie or manga that should give any normal, not perverted person a Bon Air.
Speaker 1: I was about, yeah, you qualify that pretty harshly, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, there's someone who's going to get a Bon Air looking at like, I don't know, like a rock, right?
Speaker 0: So Rock King.
Speaker 0: That's for sure.
Speaker 1: Geodude.
Speaker 0: You know, he's got those.
Speaker 0: What's?
Speaker 0: I have the toy where the um, it's uh, what's it called?
Speaker 0: It's the toy where he turns into a rock, but he's actually a dude.
Speaker 1: No, that's just regular porn.
Speaker 0: No, there's a toy, Rock Master or something where he's, it's uh, maybe.
Speaker 0: No, I have the, um, I have the stupid toy.
Speaker 0: The what?
Speaker 0: I have the toy.
Speaker 0: Rock Master, this guy?
Speaker 0: No, I forget the name of it.
Speaker 0: It was something bots.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: What was it?
Speaker 0: What was the not transformers crappy bots?
Speaker 1: Well, there were several.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the one that actually had the word bots in it or something.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So that is my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Coolest thing I saw.
Speaker 0: Here's a video in my thing of the day, right?
Speaker 0: And this thing of the day actually much like geek nights happens to be creative commons licensed.
Speaker 0: They're using a attribution, no commercial share alike license.
Speaker 0: So the most restrictive possible one.
Speaker 0: But maybe, uh, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I just decided just now.
Speaker 0: maybe I'll try to find creative commons things of the day for a while.
Speaker 0: But anyway, make, make it a theme.
Speaker 0: This creative commons thing of the day, uh, is last episode.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: Which is very old.
Speaker 0: This is a video on Vimeo, uh, called dot, dot, dot.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, dot, dot, dot from Sandro Bocci who did the images and editing.
Speaker 0: The music is from Maurizio Morgan.
Speaker 0: I think it's Italian, perhaps.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to Mario Faggioli and some other people.
Speaker 0: Julia set collection.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So, uh, it's featuring, uh, proto Riester, linky, scolimia, fungi, trachea, philia, et cetera.
Speaker 0: Many strange sea creatures.
Speaker 0: That's what those are.
Speaker 0: And in this video they find the sea creatures.
Speaker 0: I can't tell if it's in an aquarium or the bottom of the sea.
Speaker 0: And they did, these are really, these are sea creatures that look really weird, but move really slow.
Speaker 0: They're not, you know, they're the kind of thing that sits still and doesn't do a lot.
Speaker 1: So specifically weird and slow is the niche, right?
Speaker 0: And they did a time-lapse video, so it looks like it's moving at normal speed.
Speaker 0: Uh, and they also did a high magnification.
Speaker 0: So now you can see, for example, a coral or a starfish moving pretty fast and that's not something you can usually see.
Speaker 0: Uh, I think they also, uh, I don't know if these colors are natural.
Speaker 0: They could be because sea creatures, the music is not natural.
Speaker 1: The music was, how do you know they're not making that music underwater?
Speaker 1: They just, they speed up.
Speaker 1: It's like that mouth silence.
Speaker 0: Did you notice just off camera?
Speaker 0: Sebastian is there.
Speaker 1: Did you notice in mouth silence, the Neil says, or everything, if you play it at a very high speed, it's got songs from the nineties back, like masked on top of it.
Speaker 0: Is that true?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Can you, do you have that?
Speaker 1: Not, not, not immediately at my fingertips.
Speaker 0: Can you like drag the MP3 into audition and play it at high speed?
Speaker 1: Yes, I can do that and I will edit it into the show.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: In the meta moment, we're going to be, not this weekend, but next weekend at the Penny Arcade Expo, right after the last Penny Arcade Expo.
Speaker 0: Weren't we just at a Penny Arcade Expo?
Speaker 1: Oh my God, there's, there's five packs a year if you count dev and we go to, well, at least one of us goes to all of them.
Speaker 0: We've been to all of them.
Speaker 0: We collectively have been to every pack since 2008.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Which means we missed four packs, four, five, six, and seven.
Speaker 1: And it's been a lot of God damn packs.
Speaker 0: If you count it, we've also missed necroomicon and I think we missed some devs.
Speaker 0: If you're counting those two, I skipped a dev.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, uh, So on Friday, March 6th at 4 30 PM in the bumblebee theater.
Speaker 0: Thanks for the great time slot and great theater.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We're going to be presenting what is losing?
Speaker 0: What is losing?
Speaker 0: It is the thing that rim does and the panel.
Speaker 1: You just dropped the mic.
Speaker 1: I stand on stage crying for 55 minutes.
Speaker 1: And then I suddenly go to Q and a yup.
Speaker 1: Oh, the book club book is still water ship down.
Speaker 1: Maybe you should update the website because Scott doesn't care about rabbits.
Speaker 0: I read some of that book yesterday.
Speaker 1: I need the affiliate link.
Speaker 1: Oh, I can't generate those myself.
Speaker 0: I could just, you could just ask me.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: I asked you many times.
Speaker 0: You did not ask me any times.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I read some of that book yesterday.
Speaker 0: The Kindle says that I am like 15% done.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 1: So did the rabbits get to, did they meet any other rabbits yet?
Speaker 0: They just met a rabbit who is weird.
Speaker 0: He was really nice, but he was also just like, Hey, come on by if you want.
Speaker 0: And it seemed kind of probably something shady.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Scott, those rabbits are cultist.
Speaker 1: You're going to be, you're going to really dig the, you know what is really thing about this book.
Speaker 0: And I'm probably should save this with the book club episode, but whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The rabbits, the main character, rabbits basically act the way it's like when you play RPG, a tabletop RPG, you basically don't trust anything.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They're like, right.
Speaker 0: And it's like, you're like, no, whatever it is we just encountered is bad.
Speaker 0: Oh, this is bad too.
Speaker 0: Everything is dangerous.
Speaker 1: Alex, our game master, you just introduced a new, new NPC.
Speaker 1: I'm going to assume that's a fucking demon in disguise and usually be right.
Speaker 0: So usually when you act like that, it's like people are like, that's so meta gaming.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's so bad.
Speaker 0: Uh, you know, but in this story here, these rabbits are acting just like that and they're not even RPG and they're just characters in the story.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There, you know what?
Speaker 1: It was very, I thought about that too.
Speaker 0: But that's what rabbits are like.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they are.
Speaker 1: You know, there's a term for that, but when a rabbit telescopes, it's when they like, there's something they want to check out.
Speaker 1: So they kind of lean their body, like they extend into a long tube, like just barely next to it, kind of poke it a little bit and then back away the fuck up and see what it did.
Speaker 1: It's all telescope in and back up and telescope in and back up.
Speaker 0: They also periscope.
Speaker 1: that they do.
Speaker 1: They periscope up and then look left and right.
Speaker 1: And then the air radar goes, and then go back in the grass.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's just like us playing D and D like everything we pumped into.
Speaker 0: We're like, meet this guy.
Speaker 0: He seems pretty nice.
Speaker 0: And they're like, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Can we trust this guy?
Speaker 0: We should dig a hole in the ground.
Speaker 0: It's not going to be safe with his brain.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is, I mean, Fiverr was right in the beginning.
Speaker 1: He's like, you're all going to fucking die.
Speaker 0: It's also mouse guard ask, or you could say that mouse guard is water ship down ask.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Well, mouse guard gives a little more tools in society.
Speaker 1: Water ship down is a little more like just rabbits.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like they're, they're rabbits.
Speaker 1: They have the same capabilities that rabbits have.
Speaker 0: They don't have swords.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They do meet a bird though.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So the only other thing, cause you know, it's been a while.
Speaker 1: We've we're on a long hiatus.
Speaker 1: We're back pretty much on our normal schedule, hopefully for the foreseeable future.
Speaker 1: I guess our thousandth episode happened at some point recently cause I was looking at the database round numbers.
Speaker 0: Who cares?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Uh, I still kind of want to do a like nth episode party in New York at some point and I'm still looking into that.
Speaker 1: It'll be like the thousand and 30th episode party.
Speaker 0: It's all you.
Speaker 1: But uh, I made a YouTube video that I'm going to tell you about right now.
Speaker 1: I did a dramatic reading of the worlds of power book Castlevania two.
Speaker 0: Haven't you been going on that for like three years?
Speaker 1: Uh, well no, I read it.
Speaker 1: I didn't and I didn't really do anything with it.
Speaker 1: So our friend Judith and did an animatic of the very first bit of that.
Speaker 0: Also, I'm better at dramatic reading than you.
Speaker 1: Uh, why don't we have dramatic reading off?
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Cause I point out, can I use any material I want?
Speaker 1: Uh, we should both use the same material.
Speaker 1: I think.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 1: For, so it's a, we can do a blind test.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: With strangers.
Speaker 1: Not so confident now, are you?
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: You're, you're really, you're gonna Scott, the source material I was working with, you know, how many times I edited out me laughing because I couldn't deal with it.
Speaker 1: So yeah, that video is on YouTube and it's pretty fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 1: So long, long time ago, uh, I bought a laptop and I got a weird Fujitsu like boutique power book.
Speaker 0: Well that's, so you got to go even earlier than that.
Speaker 0: Steve Pomeroy, who we knew in college, the trio thing he had or whatever.
Speaker 0: No, well he had a Fujitsu P series laptop, which is the tiniest watt, you know, super wide screen, high resolution laptop.
Speaker 0: And it was really expensive for Japan, but it was awesome in that it was tiny, had incredible battery life considering as the early two thousands, cause you could put two batteries in it, one in the CD rom slot.
Speaker 0: And despite being tiny and wide screen, like 10 inches plus, right?
Speaker 0: Uh, the resolution on that screen was way high pixel density for the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You guys don't understand, but like power books did not exist until relatively recently.
Speaker 1: The idea of a laptop that was small and powerful and had a long lasting battery, that shit didn't exist unless you imported something exotic, right?
Speaker 0: Well the one he had had a weirdo CPU, but the ones that we got were the same, basically the same model a few years later and ours had like Intel real CPUs in them, like core whatnots.
Speaker 0: So, but again, weird boutique laptop because it's something you had to get from Japan that was expensive and whatnot.
Speaker 1: So I had a lot of money for that fucking Fujitsu.
Speaker 0: It was like 2000, 2000 plus dollars, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But eventually even that amazing laptop was too slow and Fujitsu really didn't keep up with that product line very well.
Speaker 1: And also power books became a thing and Lenovo or you know, IBM, the X series think pads were pretty much like the only game in town.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean in terms of you want a laptop, this is before tablets were like, you know, they were just garbage in those days, right?
Speaker 0: Like viewsonic.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Don't be like, yeah, you should have bought a Microsoft service.
Speaker 1: Like, yeah, nothing like that existed back then.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We're talking, you know, we were probably bought these while we were doing geek nights.
Speaker 1: I'll look up exactly the day I bought mine.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, it's like, you know, I bought mine and I guess, you know, it was, it's a relatively small laptop, right?
Speaker 0: Like 12 inches.
Speaker 0: ish, right?
Speaker 0: I have one at work also, but full powerful.
Speaker 0: If you don't want to do anything other than 3d gaming, because it doesn't have much of a video card, it doesn't Intel, whatever.
Speaker 0: It does everything else.
Speaker 0: Full power, plenty of Ram, plenty of CPU, plenty of everything.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: So I bought my Fujitsu, Fujitsu P 8010 in 2008.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: That was one newer than mine.
Speaker 0: I think mine was like a P seventh.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That laptop.
Speaker 1: I still have it actually still works great.
Speaker 0: Mine was mine had some issues.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 0: I don't know what happened to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I think I gave it to someone.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I remember having issues cause it was the end.
Speaker 1: We needed a new laptop for panels.
Speaker 1: pretty much.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So yeah.
Speaker 1: Then you got the Lenovo X two 20.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: That's right at work.
Speaker 0: I have a two 30, which is a shitty touch pad, but as it still is the good keyboard.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well the thing is the Lenovo, they still have that two 20.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: And I bought the two 30 because the two one I have at work was old.
Speaker 0: And the two 30 was just like the current one already, already that two 20 was really the last good one.
Speaker 0: The touch pad, as I said in the two 30 sucked.
Speaker 0: And even beyond that, now the keyboard sucks and the touch pad sucks.
Speaker 1: See I don't know what the fuck your beef is with that keyboard.
Speaker 1: That keyboard's fine.
Speaker 0: Chiclet keyboards can suck my dick.
Speaker 1: The chiclet keyboard is fine.
Speaker 1: I can type on it just fine.
Speaker 0: What is wrong with it?
Speaker 0: I can type on it.
Speaker 0: Just like I can drive a Yugo or a Ford Fiesta or whatever.
Speaker 1: Also the touch pad on the X two 20 was no party.
Speaker 0: No, it was not great, but the two 30 is worse.
Speaker 1: The two 30 was a substantial drop further into the toilet.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: The MacBook Pro touch pad is still the best.
Speaker 1: To this day, but for the lack of multi-touch, that Fujitsu P8010 had, like that touch pad was a goddamn dream.
Speaker 0: It was a tiny touch pad, but actually it was really, really good for what it was in its day.
Speaker 1: It was so sensitive and so accurate.
Speaker 0: It's still not as good as the Mac one.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, the Mac one is special.
Speaker 1: I mean, like the idea of multi-touch didn't even exist back then.
Speaker 0: It's magic.
Speaker 0: Magic trackpad.
Speaker 1: It is magic.
Speaker 1: So for the longest time, if anyone said, "I need a laptop," what I would ask them is, "Do you care about money, speed, battery life, or
Speaker 1: size?".
Speaker 0: Do you really need a laptop?
Speaker 0: You can probably get away with an iPad these days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but money, speed, battery life, size.
Speaker 1: What one do you care about?
Speaker 1: And if the answer was everything except money, I would say get some crazy Japanese thing.
Speaker 1: And if the answer was everything, I would say get whatever the current Lenovo X2XX is.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's nice and small.
Speaker 0: It's powerful enough.
Speaker 0: You just can't play crazy games on it.
Speaker 1: But like my 230, it's got my 230.
Speaker 1: I play Civ V on it like all the time on airplanes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but try to play like something, you know.
Speaker 1: No, but Civ V works fine.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: That's what I need for my laptop.
Speaker 0: Now, the other thing is that ever since forever, even the '90s, this is an old problem, PCs have come with pre-installed garbage on them.
Speaker 0: And then, I've said this a million times, but I guess this is the show to say it again once and for all, the reputation of Windows is not a good reputation.
Speaker 0: Even people are not computer experts, and many who are hate Windows.
Speaker 1: Now, some of that is legitimate.
Speaker 1: I mean, old versions of Windows.
Speaker 0: Windows is not perfect by any means, but much of the bad reputation of Windows itself comes from the fact that most people who use Windows use Windows that came pre-installed on a computer with a bunch of garbage installed.
Speaker 0: And that if you use a clean Windows install from a disk that has not been modified or had any garbage added to it in any way, it is vastly superior.
Speaker 0: This has been true even since Windows 3.1 days.
Speaker 0: The computers had come with garbage that would ruin it, and you wouldn't get the real Windows experience, et cetera.
Speaker 1: Now, the benefit of Lenovo's was that they came with a comparatively small amount of garbage layer, and it was all like Lenovo-owned system configurator optimization garbage.
Speaker 0: I never, ever buy a computer that has pre-installed shit, and when I do, because a laptop, you had no choice, really.
Speaker 0: I would clean install the Windows.
Speaker 0: And even the Lenovo, though, you could get away without cleaning, installing the Windows because all they put on there, the only bullshit was like they replaced the Windows Wi-Fi thing with this other Wi-Fi thing.
Speaker 1: - Which you could just uninstall.
Speaker 0: - Right, and if you went to program settings, uninstall, and removed it, it actually removed, and the Windows Wi-Fi thing took over, and it worked just fine.
Speaker 0: So it's like, oh, this is actually not the worst.
Speaker 0: They didn't put like AOL icons.
Speaker 0: It was only like these system utilities things, and actually one of them was useful because the particular Wi-Fi thing that they, the card that's in there, at least on my Lenovo, Windows keeps popping up this thing occasionally when you connect to Wi-Fi where you have to click on yes, and one of the things that they pre-install is a patch to Windows that makes that dialogue not pop up.
Speaker 1: - You know that some engineer was like motherfucker, and he just wrote a patch.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, it's like a stop Intel Wi-Fi pop-up thing, and you can actually see it in the program settings as a thing to uninstall, and you can go to the Lenovo website and download it and install it.
Speaker 0: - I did, yeah.
Speaker 0: - In case, if you do a clean install of Windows, you can go get this thing and install it to make the pop-up stuff happening.
Speaker 1: - The one thing I left on my 230 was the battery management thing 'cause it did give me a lot more accessible options.
Speaker 0: - Sure, I still hate that it replaces the real Windows battery software, which is perfectly fine.
Speaker 1: - But at least it added functionality, and I did see side-by-side comparisons where if you use it, the battery lasts longer.
Speaker 0: - Sure, I mean, that's obviously definitely possible, but why did they have to do that?
Speaker 0: Why couldn't they just make a battery power driver and have it installed via Windows Update just like every other driver?
Speaker 1: - Yeah, well, no, I agree, but these are minor niggling issues.
Speaker 0: - Sure, compared to the other options, Dells, HPs, et cetera, the Lenovo ThinkPad was like a dream in terms of not having a bunch of garbage pre-installed.
Speaker 0: You could get away without clean installing the Windows if you wanted to, right?
Speaker 0: Now, I've always said, Microsoft, this is really your fault.
Speaker 0: What you should do is you should say, "Hey, look, Dell, look, HP, look whoever.
Speaker 0: "You wanna pre-install Windows.
Speaker 0: "and all these computers you're selling, right?
Speaker 0: "Otherwise, you're not gonna be able to sell 'em "'cause you don't have an OS.
Speaker 0: "You're gonna put Linux on there, ha ha
Speaker 0: ha.".
Speaker 0: So we sell you Windows licenses at a bulk discount 'cause your business is mad low margins.
Speaker 0: You need to have this discount on the Windows license.
Speaker 0: 'cause if you had to pay the full Windows license cost, man, you'd be as expensive as the Mac and your hardware is garbage compared to that.
Speaker 0: And you can't make better hardware 'cause you suck, so without our cheap Windows license, you're pretty much fucked.
Speaker 0: So here's the deal we're gonna make you.
Speaker 0: We'll continue to sell you the discount Windows license.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll even discount it further if you agree to not pre-install any software whatsoever and deliver only the clean Windows experience that we have designed.
Speaker 0: If you pre-install anything whatsoever, then either we're not gonna give you any contract.
Speaker 0: You can buy Windows licenses at full retail price.
Speaker 0: Go fuck yourself.
Speaker 0: And if Microsoft had done that years ago, the reputation of Windows today would be much, much better.
Speaker 0: And even now, if they did it, it's a bit late, but better late than never.
Speaker 0: They could do this today as soon as their current contracts expire.
Speaker 0: - But they don't and they won't.
Speaker 1: - They didn't back then, so the people who sell computers to make more and more money would bundle a bunch of crapware that they were paid to bundle.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, some of the crapware they put, like the Lenovo Wi-Fi thing, it's like no one's paying for that.
Speaker 0: I don't know why they, you know.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, no one would go to a store and say, "I would like to buy the Lenovo Power Manager for
Speaker 1: $5.".
Speaker 0: - Right, but some other stuff they put on there, such as like, you know, aha, install McAfee.
Speaker 0: (laughing) Right, you know, that stuff, McAfee paid the money, you know, to put it on there and that decreased the cost of the laptop, you know, which already has a-- - I would argue it didn't decrease the cost of the laptop.
Speaker 0: - Well, it already has a razor-thin margin, so it increased the margin, right, if you think about it that way.
Speaker 1: - So let's back up a little bit because there's one other piece of this puzzle before we get to what's going on here.
Speaker 1: So way back in 2005, when I still worked at IBM, IBM basically sold its PC business to Lenovo.
Speaker 0: - Right, IBM made computers for a lot, you know.
Speaker 1: - The best like business, I do things with computers, laptops, there were for a long time.
Speaker 0: - The IBM ThinkPad.
Speaker 0: - Yeah.
Speaker 0: - And, you know, they also made pretty good desktops and also, you know, we had an IBM desktop way back in the day.
Speaker 1: - So when that deal happened, I was super untrusting of Lenovo.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, I was like, whoa, they're selling this business off.
Speaker 0: Is the ThinkPad gonna die, right?
Speaker 1: - Yeah, they're selling it to some like dubious-looking Chinese company.
Speaker 0: - This company makes an important product that I wanna buy, and they're selling that product to some shady company I never heard of.
Speaker 0: Is that product now going to be ruined and I need to find something else to get instead?
Speaker 0: Is that what's going to happen here?
Speaker 0: I was very concerned, you know, even though IBM was still making, you know, giant servers that I'm never gonna buy.
Speaker 1: - So the fears I saw online in general were one, people were afraid that because it was a Chinese company, the hardware and the software and everything would be compromised for spy shit.
Speaker 1: And the other fear was that the hardware would just get shittier.
Speaker 0: - Right, well I mean, you know, there's racism against China, but there's also truth in some of that, right?
Speaker 1: - Yeah, there is, in fact.
Speaker 0: Although the third fear was that there would be no more good support.
Speaker 0: - What was that Chinese cell phone company that made actually super shady cell phones?
Speaker 1: - Oh yeah, I almost used that as my news.
Speaker 1: I've got it open in a tab here somewhere.
Speaker 0: - That was a year or two ago.
Speaker 0: I've seen ads for their phones on the subway at like Metro PCS, you can get those.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, well there was some recent news about that.
Speaker 1: - Really?
Speaker 1: - Yeah, but I didn't, it's on a tab somewhere here.
Speaker 0: - Anyway.
Speaker 1: - So that happened, and actually, I was really, I didn't, like I wouldn't buy any Lenovo stuff or IBM stuff until like a generation of products came out and people said, oh, like the new laptops are pretty much just as good as the old laptops.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, it's like, yeah, they pretty much just kept it going, they didn't fuck it up.
Speaker 0: Good job, Lenovo, you didn't fuck it up.
Speaker 1: - Yup.
Speaker 0: - At least not right away.
Speaker 1: Then Lenovo fucked it up, so what happened?
Speaker 0: - Just now they fucked it up.
Speaker 1: - They fucked it up in a way to where when this news first dropped, 'cause this is pretty recent news, I assumed it was false.
Speaker 0: - Yeah.
Speaker 1: - Because there were reports that Lenovo laptops had bundled malware that was injecting ads.
Speaker 0: - Right, I assumed that this was just like, you know, they were definitely bundling something 'cause they all bundle some bullshit, but that it was overblown and the truth was much, much tamer, as is often the case.
Speaker 1: - But no, it was underblown.
Speaker 0: - It was definitely underblown.
Speaker 1: - Lenovo was bundling something called Superfish, which is a fucking shady company to begin with.
Speaker 0: - So Superfish paid Lenovo money to put Superfish software pre-installed onto laptops and they did so for a period of time.
Speaker 1: - Yes, now details of what that relationship is are probably gonna come out in the court cases that are coming out of all of this.
Speaker 0: - Sure.
Speaker 1: - It appears that the State Department is interested, Microsoft has already added Superfish to their anti-virus definitions.
Speaker 0: - Really, the government could also take action on this and say, you guys can't sell things with shit pre-installed.
Speaker 1: - They may well, there's already at least one major lawsuit.
Speaker 0: - In fact, they could even say, if you're selling hardware, you can't have any software pre-installed, make it come separately on a disk.
Speaker 1: - On Saturday, the Department of Homeland Security made a big fucking deal about this thing, too.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, well, rightly so.
Speaker 1: - Yes, so this software, this Superfish thing, I'll explain it in terms that everyone will understand.
Speaker 0: - Right, so you turn on your brand new computer, you log into Windows for the first time and there's some Superfish thing, what the fuck is that?
Speaker 1: - So you wouldn't know it's there, you would never see it.
Speaker 0: - It's not in the system tray, I'm sorry, notification area.
Speaker 0: It's not in the program settings where I can uninstall it.
Speaker 0: There's no indication anywhere that I have this thing and can get rid of it like there is with the other software.
Speaker 1: - It's just malware and what it does, one, is it literally--.
Speaker 0: - And this wasn't something that somebody snuck in in the factory modifying the image that they were putting that was getting copied to all the drives.
Speaker 0: This was something someone paid to have put in that image and Lenovo said yes and put it there.
Speaker 1: - Yep, Mark Hopkins, who, I forget what his job is at the Lenovo, but he basically was the one who said, "We messed up with this and we're gonna roll it back.
Speaker 1: "and please stop being mad at
Speaker 1: us.".
Speaker 1: The funny thing is, at first, when this news first broke, they didn't say like, "Fuck Superfish, we fucked up, "we're sorry, we didn't
Speaker 1: know.".
Speaker 1: They basically said, "We're temporarily suspending "the rollout of Superfish until we address these
Speaker 1: concerns.".
Speaker 1: So already, fuck them, they were 100% in on this from the beginning.
Speaker 1: One, it literally injects ads into your web browsing.
Speaker 0: - So if I'm browsing the web, there's gonna be ads there.
Speaker 0: Is it gonna replace ads I normally see?
Speaker 1: - No, look at this screenshot.
Speaker 1: Went to Google, typed Intel 7260 AC.
Speaker 0: - So they're searching for a router to buy.
Speaker 1: - The top result is this store where you can buy it.
Speaker 1: that was injected by the malware and then the visual search results, which were also injected by the malware.
Speaker 0: - So it actually modified the Google search results page and added stuff to that page, even though, in addition to not replacing anything Google put there, but adding more shit.
Speaker 1: - Yes, it may have done more too.
Speaker 0: - So could not Google sue Superfish for doing this?
Speaker 1: - We'll see what happens, like I said.
Speaker 0: - 'Cause I'm pretty sure Google's way bigger than Superfish.
Speaker 1: - This went down really recently and the lawsuits are just beginning as of today.
Speaker 1: So it injected ads and spied on all your browsing behavior.
Speaker 1: It also included--.
Speaker 0: - Where did it send your browsing behavior, to Superfish?
Speaker 1: - Up here.
Speaker 1: so, yes.
Speaker 0: - Some Chinese server somewhere?
Speaker 1: - We're gonna find out.
Speaker 1: So it did more too.
Speaker 1: It injected a self-signed certificate and left a ready-made, man-in-the-middle SSL attack.
Speaker 1: So if you use one of these computers, you go to Gmail, Gmail has that lock, it's certified SSL, your communication's encrypted, through their certificate locally so they can spy on literally everything you do.
Speaker 0: - Oh, so I'm communicating with Gmail with just HTTP and not HTTPS?
Speaker 1: - Well basically they're using their own certificate so they can decrypt your communication.
Speaker 1: There's a man-in-the-middle attack.
Speaker 0: - Oh, so I'm communicating with Google with SSL but I'm not using the certificate that my computer would normally use, I'm using one that they made, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like if I'm making a phone call and I think I'm holding my phone but I'm actually calling their office first and then they're making the call to Google.
Speaker 0: And even though it's encrypted, they're decrypting everything.
Speaker 1: - So I try to call my bank.
Speaker 1: My phone actually calls Scott.
Speaker 1: Scott just passes me right through to Google and records the whole conversation.
Speaker 0: - I take two phones and hold one of them upside down.
Speaker 0: So he's talking to the bank.
Speaker 0: But I'm listening in, I got it next to my head.
Speaker 1: - In fact, here's a screenshot showing the certificate.
Speaker 1: I mean, this shit is just egregious.
Speaker 1: This is the kind of thing that spies would use.
Speaker 0: - So you think that you are doing perfectly safe web browsing 'cause you go to your bank's website, you go to Google, you read your Gmail, and that green lock is green, but that's because something has been added to your web browser in advance.
Speaker 1: - So even better.
Speaker 0: - Did they just add this to the IE that is part of the computer?
Speaker 0: If you install a Chrome separately, would it then--.
Speaker 1: - I saw some reports that Firefox at least did not use that key store, but I'm not 100% sure.
Speaker 0: - Oh, it adds it to a Windows key store that's shared between browsers?
Speaker 0: - Yeah, OS level.
Speaker 0: - So if you use a different browser or something, like, that doesn't use that, you might not be spied upon.
Speaker 1: I haven't, like, I don't have anything with supervision on it to poke at it.
Speaker 0: - But even still, any, you know, normal application that just uses, like--.
Speaker 1: - Yes, Microsoft Firefox is not affected, or does not appear to be affected by the man in the middle issue because it maintains its own certificate store, but the ads are still injected.
Speaker 0: - But the ads are still there 'cause it's basically looking at all outgoing HTTP traffic, probably on a lower level.
Speaker 1: - So listen to this shit-eating response.
Speaker 1: This is an official response from Lenovo.
Speaker 0: - Lenovo or Superfish?
Speaker 1: - Lenovo.
Speaker 0: - So who's Superfish?
Speaker 0: Where's this company?
Speaker 1: - This is the shady-ass company that provides this software.
Speaker 1: They're basically the bonsai buddy.
Speaker 0: - Right, but who are they?
Speaker 0: What have they said?
Speaker 1: - I believe they're an Israeli company.
Speaker 1: - Uh-huh, okay.
Speaker 1: - And I don't wanna talk a lot about what Superfish is because there's a lot of conflicting information as to who might really be behind this, and there's a lot of--.
Speaker 0: - Conspiracy nuts?
Speaker 1: - Yes, but at the same time, some of what they're saying actually pretty legitimate.
Speaker 1: I haven't done enough research.
Speaker 0: - It could be anyone, anyway.
Speaker 1: - Superfish is a private advertising company that develops various advertising, super generic company.
Speaker 0: - It's just an evil advertising company with no morals.
Speaker 1: Okay, continue.
Speaker 1: - But it was made by, okay, there's a bunch of information.
Speaker 1: It was made by this guy who graduated from Tel Aviv University.
Speaker 1: Multiple links computer science, computer surveillance industry.
Speaker 1: There's a weird chain of custody of--.
Speaker 0: - Is there a note on this Wikipedia page about needing, you know, change--.
Speaker 1: - No, there's citations for all these things.
Speaker 0: - Alrighty then.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, so anyway, I don't wanna get into that stuff, but the self-signed certificate's password was also discovered.
Speaker 1: So basically, there is a built-in vulnerability.
Speaker 1: I, myself, can sign shit using the same certificate that is built into your Lenovo computer.
Speaker 0: - So the certificate that was added to all these computers that shouldn't have been there, right, is an easily decrypted certificate because-- - The password is commodia.
Speaker 0: - The password is a stupid password that someone figured out and distributed.
Speaker 0: So anyone who knows that password, which is literally anyone who wants to, and has a copy of OpenSSL-- - So commodia is yet another shady company.
Speaker 1: - Oh.
Speaker 1: - Commodia, quote from another article, a company that brazenly calls one of its software development kits an SSL
Speaker 0: hijacker-- - So the password for the certificate used in the Superfish shitty software is the name of a shady company that does something similar and related, implying that the same people were behind both things.
Speaker 1: - So that shady-ass software is in a ton of other programs, it looks like, and is widely deployed as malware on the internet.
Speaker 0: - So people who, so basically what happens is--.
Speaker 1: - And most of those companies are Israeli.
Speaker 0: - So people wanna make a shitty malware and they wanna snoop HTTP traffic, including SSL traffic, so they buy commodia and put commodia in their software.
Speaker 0: Superfish is really a customer of commodia.
Speaker 0: They need, they're like, man, we gotta snoop on the SSL traffic, too, to get our ads in there.
Speaker 0: Let's pay commodia money for their thing that lets us snoop on the SSL traffic with the certificate.
Speaker 1: - So I suspect that at least one of the parties involved here was just greedy, and another party involved here is actively malicious, either on behalf of shady darknet hackers, whatever, or government spying, NSA, whatever.
Speaker 0: - Right, so not only is Superfish spying in all your shit, but because they're spying in all your shit, you've basically now have a big, wide-open back door for anyone who knows anything about computers to spy on your shit also.
Speaker 1: - So the response to this has been massive.
Speaker 1: Microsoft added it to their antivirus definitions basically immediately.
Speaker 1: The NSA, Homeland Security, everyone is going apeshit, there's lawsuits against Lenovo, and Lenovo's shit-eating statement, which is what I was getting back to, I gotta find my tab again, really gets to the crux of this.
Speaker 1: Quote, let's see, "Superfish was previously included "on some consumer notebook products.
Speaker 1: "shipped in a short window between September and December.
Speaker 1: "to help customers potentially discover "interesting products while
Speaker 1: shopping.".
Speaker 0: - That is what it does.
Speaker 1: - Yep, that is also one of the more shit-eating things I have ever read.
Speaker 0: - That's three months that they was in, okay.
Speaker 0: - Further quote.
Speaker 0: - How many laptops do they sell on those?
Speaker 0: At least it's not us.
Speaker 1: - Oh yeah, it's not us for sure.
Speaker 1: I don't trust that there isn't a vulnerability on my Lenovo, though.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, but it would be in the hardware or something, right?
Speaker 0: Because I clean installed the windows.
Speaker 1: - Quote, further quote.
Speaker 0: - Unless it's in the pop-up removing patch.
Speaker 0: - Yeah.
Speaker 1: We have thoroughly investigated this technology and do not find any evidence to submit substantiate security concerns.
Speaker 0: - Well, you have not researched it thoroughly enough because everyone else did.
Speaker 1: - But we know that users reacted to this issue with concern and so we have taken direct action to stop shipping any products with this software.
Speaker 0: We will continue doing what we do.
Speaker 0: - Well, actually, you said you stopped in December, but this is February already, so what happened in January?
Speaker 0: - Yeah, so--.
Speaker 0: - Why didn't you ship it in January?
Speaker 1: - Basically, here's the result.
Speaker 1: Never buy any Lenovo product again because that company cannot be trusted.
Speaker 0: This was a supreme breach.
Speaker 1: Either they are greedy and incompetent and let these other shitware companies and these spies get into their software or they're complicit in it.
Speaker 1: Either one is equally bad.
Speaker 0: - You need to never, ever, ever under any circumstance buy a computer that has anything except a clean OS installed.
Speaker 0: and Apple is actually, despite us saying things about the early part of the show, they're not perfect, but one thing Apple has always gotten right is they don't allow anyone to fuck with the software that's installed on the devices.
Speaker 0: That's a large reason that they also make the hardware.
Speaker 0: Way back in the day, way, way back, when Steve Jobs ran the original show, he was selling Apple products and then he got really mad when people were selling Macs that weren't made by Apple.
Speaker 0: There were Macs that were not made by Apple.
Speaker 0: It was just like PCs where anyone could make one and he was super pissed and he was like, "They shouldn't be allowed to do
Speaker 0: that.".
Speaker 0: And on the one hand, it's like, "Well, I sort of think they should be allowed to do
Speaker 0: Even today, I think people should be allowed to make a computer and just install OS on it, but he was correct in some ways in that even though I think that having different hardware is not really ruining the experience, at least compared to the one button mouse of the official Mac, someone fucking with the software and giving you something other than just the OS, putting other software in that you did not want, that should not be allowed pretty much ever.
Speaker 0: It's like if I go to the store and buy an Apple and I say, "I would like this Apple, please,".
Speaker 0: and they put a banana in my bag with the Apple, it's like, "What the fuck?
Speaker 0: I don't want the
Speaker 0: banana.".
Speaker 0: I mean, no, a free banana, I might not complain.
Speaker 0: I might want the free banana.
Speaker 1: Well, what if the banana has microchips in it?
Speaker 0: What if it's a poison?
Speaker 0: What if it's a bad old banana they're just trying to get rid of because they all turn brown?
Speaker 0: or a banana they can't sell because it's too green and it's going to go from green to brown because you know how bananas are?
Speaker 0: Or, you know, who knows what?
Speaker 1: But it's like-- You know, I do know how bananas are because I currently actually own too many bananas and every morning for two days-- I only have one left, I'll take some.
Speaker 1: You take some bananas because I looked at them this morning, I was like, "Whoa, those got way more yellow than they should be by
Speaker 1: today.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm going to make some banana bread.
Speaker 0: They were green yesterday.
Speaker 0: Today is National Banana Bread Day.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 0: Did you know that?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Now you did.
Speaker 1: I should use the banana bread.
Speaker 0: Go for it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, you should not be able to force upon someone something in addition to what they are buying from you, right?
Speaker 0: So, if I buy a copy of OS X or a copy of Windows, you should not be able to force or even attempt to trick me into taking additional things that I do not want.
Speaker 1: What if those things are now just part of the operating system?
Speaker 1: Like a web browser.
Speaker 0: We had a discussion about that.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 0: Right, but I mean, it should be clear that like, you know, what's included in the package, right?
Speaker 1: So Lenovo or Microsoft could-- Microsoft has a vested interest in not being party to this-- could just buy this super fish stuff and just, "Oh, it's our software.
Speaker 1: It's Lenovo's
Speaker 1: software.".
Speaker 0: That's the thing, but it's not.
Speaker 0: It's Microsoft's software.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's Lenovo's hardware.
Speaker 0: The real answer is-- But yeah, Apple, notice how you buy a MacBook.
Speaker 0: It's got OS X on it.
Speaker 0: You buy an iPhone.
Speaker 0: They don't let Verizon put shit on the iPhone.
Speaker 0: You buy it from Verizon, right?
Speaker 0: But the Android phones are full of garbage from the manufacturers and the carriers.
Speaker 1: This has been a problem for a long time, but it's never been this severe of a problem, at least not in a publicly identifiable way.
Speaker 1: The level of breach that this Lenovo vulnerability is, is to the point where you should literally burn all commercial ties with Lenovo and never, ever buy one of their products again.
Speaker 0: Now, wait, what if I'm from a company and I gotta buy computers for my employees and I gotta buy laptops, but every single company that makes laptops is pre-installing some kind of shit on there.
Speaker 1: I would still go with anyone but Lenovo because Lenovo didn't just install shit.
Speaker 1: They installed active malware.
Speaker 0: All right, so who am I going for?
Speaker 0: I don't know, Dell.
Speaker 0: Great, thanks.
Speaker 0: That's really good help.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 0: My employees will be so happy with their garbage laptops.
Speaker 1: Your employees don't even know, and anyone who knows is at a company where they just buy their own laptop with a corporate car.
Speaker 0: Luckily, the Microsoft Surface made by, at least, I don't know if it's, you know, Microsoft actually manufactures the hardware, but it doesn't seem like they pre-install any bullshit on there.
Speaker 0: It seems like it's just Windows 'cause it's the Microsoft Surface.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, you know what, too, I had to buy a bunch of computers for work, right, just 'cause the CTO was busy?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I use that iBuyPower, and it comes with, like, those PCs just come with a completely clean Windows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, iBuyPower is basically go on Newegg, design the computer with some more limited choices.
Speaker 0: And we'll build it.
Speaker 0: And they put it together for you to save you the trouble, but it's otherwise just like a computer you would've made, perhaps even better because the guy wiring it wired, like, 50 computers today.
Speaker 1: And if there is some sort of secret, nefarious vulnerability in it, it's at least secret and hidden, and no one knows about it.
Speaker 0: No one said anything, which means...
Speaker 1: This Lenovo thing is just like a disaster from every perspective.
Speaker 1: So you can't trust them because even if they're not evil, they're desperately incompetent.
Speaker 1: At least if Dell is doing something evil, they're competent enough to hide it.
Speaker 0: If we're gonna spend a thousand-plus dollars in a computer, you don't want one from someone so incompetent and/or evil.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And really, it's the statements Lenovo made is why I feel that way.
Speaker 1: Because the level of shit that was eaten...
Speaker 0: The statement they should've said was, "We installed Superfish on the computers during this time period because they paid us money to do so, and we admit we were
Speaker 0: incompetent.".
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Because you can't admit you're evil.
Speaker 1: If they had disavowed Superfish, day one.
Speaker 0: "We admit that we were incompetent and did not realize how horrible the software was.
Speaker 0: We did realize it eventually, and that's why we stopped allowing it in January.
Speaker 0: And we already have a patch in our website where you can go get a thing that will remove
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 1: But no, the fact that they said they evaluated it and thought it was fine and only recanted later when people proved they were lying.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You just admit the incompetence from the get-go, because otherwise you gotta admit the evil, which is not... You can't be doing that.
Speaker 1: So my X230 will be the last Lenovo product I will ever own.
Speaker 1: Luckily, I won't need another laptop for like five more years with the way we're going.
Speaker 0: Literally, all I need the laptop for these days is the few things, if I'm on the go, that a tablet cannot do.
Speaker 1: Here's what I do.
Speaker 1: One, typing a whole bunch of shit.
Speaker 1: That's what I use my laptop for.
Speaker 1: Two, actually editing video.
Speaker 0: I can actually... I have Premiere on my iPad, if I just need to get the iPad that has more storage space.
Speaker 0: I don't even need...
Speaker 1: Three, PlaySieve 5.
Speaker 0: I don't even need the laptop to do presentations because I bought the iPad to HDMI cable.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Will that work with VGA?
Speaker 0: No, but if there is a VGA, then I have a laptop.
Speaker 0: But there's no reason for me to get a new laptop.
Speaker 0: This one is going to be just fine for pretty much ever.
Speaker 0: And if I need to play a fancy game on it, which I never ever do, I can Steam stream.
Speaker 1: Well, you can't Steam stream on a plane.
Speaker 0: But I can Steam stream in my bed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 0: And I wouldn't want to Steam stream on a plane.
Speaker 0: I would not Steam stream on a plane.
Speaker 0: I would not Steam stream in the rain.
Speaker 0: Because then my laptop would go in the wetness.
Speaker 1: I think we're done here.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.