Speaker 1: It's Monday, November 30th, 2015.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm scared and this is geek nights tonight Talking about headphone jacks.
Speaker 0: This is rooms.
Speaker 1: I did TRS and all that biz.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So today, I'm you know my building is for elevators for work like the office just for like our elevator bank because it's a tall building and There's a lot of semi public businesses on it.
Speaker 1: So people use it off and on throughout the day.
Speaker 1: But today like 11 I went down and did some stuff and I go to take the elevator back up and there's a woman Standing there like waiting for the elevator, but she has not hit the button to go up.
Speaker 1: So fine, so I go and hit the button and then she turns me and says Excuse me, sir, and already I'm like, oh, why is she tell who's this person?
Speaker 1: Why are they talking to me?
Speaker 1: and she's like are you riding the elevator up?
Speaker 1: and I'm like, yes I'm riding this elevator up and she's like what floor are you going to?
Speaker 0: and I'm Part of me is thinking maybe why do I have to tell you where I'm going?
Speaker 1: maybe I should not respond because this is like crazy person.
Speaker 1: bells are going off, but well-dressed not a hobo like Yeah, yeah, but seriously there is it's New York.
Speaker 1: the reality is if someone reeks of urine and starts asking you stuff It's very yeah, but just cuz you don't speak of your it doesn't mean it doesn't mean oh, you don't pull the shields down.
Speaker 0: I'm not telling you where I'm going.
Speaker 1: You do not put the shields down just because someone doesn't reek of urine, but you might actually respond to the hail.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, I'm going up to the 16th floor and she's like, oh, okay.
Speaker 1: I'm going to 15.
Speaker 1: Can I ride with you?
Speaker 1: and I'm like, uh Guess.
Speaker 1: so the elevator comes and I get in and I wait for her to hit 15 and I hit 16 And then she starts explaining to me that she won't ride elevators alone because she's afraid to Okay, so instead I guess she waits for the first stranger who comes by and decides to get in the elevator with him.
Speaker 0: You don't have to ask you can just wait for them to go in the elevator.
Speaker 1: I think she was worried that what if she got in with me and I did?
Speaker 1: she kind of explained this and I went to A lower floor than her cuz then I would abandon her so she'd have to get off in the same floor I got off on but that would be weird.
Speaker 0: You could get over it and deal with.
Speaker 1: yeah I don't know what aspect because she's afraid of being alone in the elevator.
Speaker 1: So I joked.
Speaker 1: I was like, well, you know Elevators are pretty safe like once you're in if it's not like someone else can get in when they're between floors.
Speaker 1: and she's like You don't know that.
Speaker 1: and then I was like, yeah shields are back up.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like hers.
Speaker 1: it reminds me of.
Speaker 1: I learned that there are actually people who have it.
Speaker 1: There's an app for this too, but people have a job of hanging out.
Speaker 1: You know that bridge by the water gap down in Delaware that we used to take all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah I know that bridge.
Speaker 1: so there are people who are so afraid to ride in cars over that that they hire people to drive them Over that and they like sit in the back and cry.
Speaker 1: I guess Like that is the thing.
Speaker 1: There's a job.
Speaker 1: You can have a drive people's cars over that bridge for them every day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I wonder if I could get a job hanging around in my elevator Lobby riding the elevator with people as an escort.
Speaker 0: Uh What they should do is you just push the person the elevator and close the door Be like, uh, I guess you're free of elevators.
Speaker 0: There's a self-fulfilling Prophecy would have been funnier if you never would have said anything.
Speaker 0: you could have written the elevator normally like everyone else But because you were afraid.
Speaker 0: well now you're gonna have to suffer.
Speaker 1: you don't think about this too.
Speaker 1: It's just like.
Speaker 0: this is why you.
Speaker 0: it's just like with your annoying noises.
Speaker 0: It's like well now that we know that noise annoys you guess what's gonna happen?
Speaker 1: I think you learn one noise.
Speaker 1: that doesn't annoy me but This is why you were not a proper troll.
Speaker 1: This is why I am a schooled troll from the olden times and why I really feel bad about how this word has been denigrated Because a proper troll would have agreed to this woman's request.
Speaker 1: pushed five got into the elevator with her.
Speaker 1: No, not just gotten off hit 16.
Speaker 1: She hits 15. wait until the door is just about to close.
Speaker 1: Jump through it not tripping the sensor that would reopen the door So that she is suddenly trapped on her own without having been touched or shoved in any way.
Speaker 1: because if you shove her you were An asshole, but simply getting out of an elevator does not make one an asshole.
Speaker 1: that makes one a troll.
Speaker 0: Oh shit I forgot my coat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's even better if you make a polite excuse.
Speaker 1: So now she has no excuse.
Speaker 1: So yeah, that was my morning and I thought about this all day because that was it was the weirdest thing that's happened to me in some time.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: What weirder thing is I hope she was taking the elevator to like the psychologist office.
Speaker 1: There is one but it's on the 16th floor.
Speaker 0: Isn't that where she went?
Speaker 1: No, she went to the 15th floor.
Speaker 1: fuck if I know what's down there.
Speaker 1: It looks identical to my floor.
Speaker 0: So why doesn't she just use stairs?
Speaker 1: You can't take the stairs up in my building only down.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: because they're locked one way.
Speaker 1: Whoa.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can use the stairs my building all you want.
Speaker 1: I know I wish you could use the stairs in my building.
Speaker 0: I complained and the response I gotta take the stairs to the 16th floor.
Speaker 1: I talked to the super and I asked like hey Like could we set it up so we can take the stairs up during the day?
Speaker 1: and his response was to raise his eyes And look at me not respond and then look back down at his palate.
Speaker 1: So that was how far I got on that one.
Speaker 0: You should be like Alright, obviously there's some reason.
Speaker 0: you think that that's stupid.
Speaker 0: Can you please tell me that reason?
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I don't think he wanted me to talk to him.
Speaker 0: fine, I'm gonna go and talk to my.
Speaker 1: Go through, you know, the the building manager, but he basically is like there's no one above him I can talk to.
Speaker 0: he's collecting your rents.
Speaker 1: I'm actively but As great Scott get a building downtown.
Speaker 1: It's not like your fancy midtown.
Speaker 0: If I talk to the guy he's just like.
Speaker 0: hey, how's it going?
Speaker 1: So do you have any tech news?
Speaker 1: Anything to talk about in the first bit of the show this Monday?
Speaker 1: No, no nothing.
Speaker 0: We already did an episode that I don't give a shit and I'm find myself somehow even just a week later You've been giving less of a shit.
Speaker 0: All right, two weeks later.
Speaker 0: So there is no tech news.
Speaker 1: First things first.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking about building a new HTTP see.
Speaker 1: cuz my HTTP see is on its last legs I just upgraded mine to Windows 10.
Speaker 1: I did that a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Well, it just got the notification.
Speaker 0: I didn't do.
Speaker 0: I didn't push it, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I made it for the notification So and I had free time.
Speaker 0: finally on this, you know the weekend so Thanksgiving afterwards anyway.
Speaker 0: So, I mean it's kind of slow.
Speaker 0: It's only i3 and the.
Speaker 0: the low profile video card is weak So it can only play rocket league on like you have the GTX 460. no, it's an AMD whatever.
Speaker 0: I think it's actually 80.
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: It's it's whoa something cuz I have a low profile, but it's a GTX 460.
Speaker 1: Like it is a real video car.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's a real video card.
Speaker 0: It's just old.
Speaker 0: so I mean it can play rocket league on low settings, you know, it's fine.
Speaker 0: But uh, You know I don't do really too much 3d gaming on there and you can use the steam stream for all kinds of games with really fancy And it has no problem like power wise like playing HD videos or streaming HD videos or anything like that.
Speaker 0: The only slowness is the storage.
Speaker 0: it took a long time to upgrade to Windows 10 Yeah, and mine takes a long time to boot.
Speaker 0: SSDs are way cheap right now with the sales, especially I saw 250 something gigabyte SSDs for like 80 bucks or like 200 gig ones for like 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: It's like there's a new egg in Amazon.
Speaker 0: You can get.
Speaker 0: SSDs are way cheap right now.
Speaker 0: I saw 120 120 for $34.
Speaker 1: Yes, like I thought about buying one, but I'm like, you know what?
Speaker 0: Why spend any money?
Speaker 0: because it's still just it's still getting the job done.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that's exactly where I went to.
Speaker 0: because I because my problem is that it's like oh no It's a little bit slow when I have to read some files But usually it's reading files over the network and not over the and I'm not doing that.
Speaker 1: often the games I play on it all work fine is mostly emulation and like necro dancer and things like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's slow to reboot but I don't.
Speaker 0: You can still mount your friends like a die.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the booting is slow big deal Yeah, but lately it's a recent thing and I have not updated the driver.
Speaker 1: The video card will just crash and flip out.
Speaker 0: I think that's Nvidia driver because I'm my desktop.
Speaker 1: Oh, but this was a not Also happens.
Speaker 1: This was not happening before.
Speaker 0: there a recent driver update.
Speaker 0: with your Apply the driver update you switch from Windows 7 to Windows 10.
Speaker 1: Yeah But when I switched to Windows 10 this didn't happen for a long time and then it started happening Like I mean mine happens about once every month or two.
Speaker 0: There's a like Nvidia driver has crashed.
Speaker 0: I think it happened actually a couple weeks ago with some sieve.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I think I'm gonna dust it and reseat everything and see if that goes away.
Speaker 0: I was doing some research on dusting while looking also at the deals.
Speaker 0: Apparently, you know a lot of people like canned air is just poison chemicals.
Speaker 0: It's not actually compressed air and a can whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know that open the window when you use it.
Speaker 0: guys like yeah, but they're like no environment some hippie, whatever.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, well, what's your alternative?
Speaker 1: you're gonna buy a air compressor like just compressed air depending on how you do It could.
Speaker 1: it could introduce static issues.
Speaker 0: Sure, right?
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: is you don't use an air compressor you got it, right and they're like, this is product on Amazon.
Speaker 0: That's like the hurricane something or tornado or something like that.
Speaker 0: where it's like, yeah You just battery-powered it blow and it you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: Apparently if you read the reviews like it's a total it's a total bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: I go through about a can of air every two years.
Speaker 1: So I think that's okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just bought.
Speaker 0: I went on Amazon to buy the cans of air and you know what one can was $10.
Speaker 1: Let me guess.
Speaker 0: two cans was like $11 to pack was like 30.
Speaker 0: Oh, so I bought two one-pack Hahaha 20 which is deeper than the two-pack.
Speaker 1: So what I'm looking into now is There's two ways I can go.
Speaker 1: Basically.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna run this HD PC until it dies But I'm done with ATX.
Speaker 1: I'm either gonna get a micro ATX in the shoebox form factor instead of the VCR form factor Because the shoebox cases can have a full-size video card on a micro ATX Motherboard.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So I'm done with but if you just rotate that video card somehow 90 degrees You can't though because it's not like the old days.
Speaker 1: You could put like giant risers out of your motherboard and not affect performance like risers.
Speaker 1: fuck shit up now because things are fast.
Speaker 0: I think you know, there's a company ZOTAC that specializes in making small computers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they make some pretty good shoebox form factor But I think I might just buy like a complete system for them when the time comes.
Speaker 1: So the other thing I was looking at if I am confident that I can get away with not having take a look at the Next packs.
Speaker 1: They always have a booth Yeah but not having a real and video video card like if I'm if I'm comfortable that I can get away with like Even a core i7 on you just use the steam stream.
Speaker 0: It totally works.
Speaker 1: Yeah in that case I might get a core i5 or even it.
Speaker 1: like you can get a cheap i7.
Speaker 1: if you go with like lower numbers of cores And do the end the Intel onboard video and get a micro ITX and you get this tiny tiny tiny little thing.
Speaker 1: Because I don't really need the DVD playing capabilities anymore.
Speaker 1: So I don't which actually is the biggest thing other than the video card.
Speaker 1: So I might just make like the tiniest PC for my HD PC and be done with it.
Speaker 0: Let's just let me go to packs South as let's just check on the ZOTAC.
Speaker 1: Yeah Cuz if you're willing to go down the road of micro ITX The pre-built systems are probably better put together than anything.
Speaker 1: You're gonna build yourself at that point.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna do if you build it yourself?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm gonna buy a bunch of stuff from ZOTAC and put it in a box and we're clumsily than they do.
Speaker 1: Yep, exactly But the answer is not what.
Speaker 0: do they have any competitors?
Speaker 0: Like I just know them.
Speaker 0: I don't actually know if they're any good I just know of them, you know, they compete with bad solutions like roku's or smart TVs or Xboxes.
Speaker 0: so there has to be someone else to make small computer bits.
Speaker 1: because if you guys didn't realize there's a lot of YouTube videos and Content that just don't show up if you don't have a real HD PC Like stuff's just not there when you search.
Speaker 1: I've been doing research on that.
Speaker 1: So in other news Amazon, you know people a lot of people have been poo-pooing Amazon's drone delivery.
Speaker 1: But and you know Amazon had their little prototype.
Speaker 1: people like that's cute But it's fake and pretty much most industry people and normal people say that seems like something too far in the future.
Speaker 0: That won't happen.
Speaker 1: So Amazon are Driving cars and then Amazon was like, uh, yeah, we got one that works.
Speaker 1: Here it is.
Speaker 1: Here's video of it 15 mile range delivering real packages like for real autonomously.
Speaker 1: regulation is holding us back not technology.
Speaker 1: and Actually, it looks pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Are you within 15 miles of an Amazon warehouse?
Speaker 1: If I were Amazon, well 15 miles Scott hope it takes me.
Speaker 0: I'm like nine miles because I know there's an Amazon warehouse like in Jersey somewhere.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, that's a new egg warehouse.
Speaker 1: I'm whatever miles away from my office downtown.
Speaker 0: yeah, I'm like.
Speaker 1: so you could put platforms on top of like Four buildings in Queens and cover all the parts of Queens that matter?
Speaker 0: No, but I'm saying is that you need to have the has to start at the warehouse or the goods are?
Speaker 1: well No, you have that.
Speaker 1: you still have trucks delivering probably from the warehouses to like distribution centers.
Speaker 1: But instead of having that big-ass truck, you know go to a bunch of little trucks.
Speaker 1: The big-ass truck goes to a distribution center.
Speaker 1: that then goes to a whole bunch of little drones.
Speaker 0: So what do you do people throwing rocks at the drone?
Speaker 1: We'll solve that by just making it a crime.
Speaker 1: I Actually the rock problem.
Speaker 0: is there a way to trick the thing and to deliver?
Speaker 0: I see you got.
Speaker 0: you know, normally it's like Okay, it's got to land in my house.
Speaker 0: What if I'm not home?
Speaker 0: Is it ringing my doorbell?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, and you know what the the problem is.
Speaker 1: we could do a whole show on that.
Speaker 0: It's gonna land on my balcony.
Speaker 0: Is it gonna figure that out now?
Speaker 0: Can I help it figure that out?
Speaker 1: The problem is every time any tech blog is snowing any podcast any slash dot shithead talks about this topic.
Speaker 1: They'll ask questions like Scott's asking but they'll act like no one at Amazon ever thought of these things like yeah It's like they're like, oh I found this problem that you didn't already answer.
Speaker 0: I'll assume it's Unanswerable.
Speaker 0: there is no solution.
Speaker 0: I'm therefore this could never happen.
Speaker 1: I got this crazy idea for a horseless carriage but but what if?
Speaker 1: What if horses are still on the road?
Speaker 0: I mean it has a power from somewhere.
Speaker 0: Where does it get power from?
Speaker 1: Yeah, what did you think of that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, what do you it's like, you know feed it like a horse you feed.
Speaker 0: Hey, it's like.
Speaker 1: yeah, I invented the horseless carriage.
Speaker 1: I've figured all that stuff out.
Speaker 0: So there's no gas stations yet.
Speaker 0: How you gonna get that again out?
Speaker 0: in New York, there's only gas station around.
Speaker 1: yeah I'm confident that Amazon has people whose sole job is to sit there all day Thinking about all the things that could go wrong with delivery drones.
Speaker 1: That probably a fun job.
Speaker 1: Actually, just sit there and be like what is it?
Speaker 1: X happens?
Speaker 0: That's a fine job if I didn't have to sit there for more than 40 hours a week.
Speaker 1: Yeah So, uh, what other?
Speaker 1: oh, yeah, so this is a cool thing I'm just going through.
Speaker 1: all my tech news is garbage technique.
Speaker 1: formula E is a racing scene that pretty much no one except like super car nerds knows anything about or super nerd nerds, right?
Speaker 0: It's like the bet.
Speaker 0: basically, you know, there's Formula One which is the best and then the best But also problematic for everything is all.
Speaker 0: racing is problematic.
Speaker 0: But Formula E is like, alright fine We'll make another league, you know another racing, you know Championship.
Speaker 0: Yeah, where there's electric cars And basically instead of charging the batteries in the middle of the race you pull in and you jump the driver jumps out of the Car and jumps in the second already charged car.
Speaker 0: Otherwise the race wouldn't be long enough.
Speaker 1: now the problem with.
Speaker 1: well one of the problems with this all this kind of racing is that?
Speaker 1: You can't do a lot like there's a limiting factor in a lot of car racing.
Speaker 1: that's the human and the safety concerns.
Speaker 0: So Formula E was basically a lot of rules in Formula One that are pretty much like.
Speaker 0: you can't do this because you kill people.
Speaker 0: They're even thinking about making include, you know, it's open wheel, you know It's open wheel open cockpit racing
Speaker 1: and there's a lot of reasons for that for like competitiveness and whatever
Speaker 0: They're considering like closing the cockpit on Formula One cars for safety reasons like put a little glass dome over your head or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Formula E was just like, you know what?
Speaker 1: robot League Robot League.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: No more humans driving these cars.
Speaker 0: We'll let the cars drive themselves.
Speaker 1: Well, then so there I mean, we don't know the full time.
Speaker 0: He's not asking a bunch of stupid questions?
Speaker 1: I assume there's no answer for I Am excited for the idea of this show because then Formula One and other kinds of racing can showcase more like team tactics the human factors in the face of limitations.
Speaker 1: Formula E could go crazy.
Speaker 1: redline Nonsense, that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Like the cars could have guns on if we wanted to like that could tell you got to worry about the spectator safety still.
Speaker 1: Yeah they solve that in all the movies about this.
Speaker 0: that also if you put guns on the cars it stops being less about racing more about Yeah, bad fighting but more like.
Speaker 1: so.
Speaker 1: ground-effects cars like f1 cars could be way way faster And we made they were way fast.
Speaker 0: Yeah ground-effects cars not even ground effects.
Speaker 0: We used to have like v10s.
Speaker 1: These things could have all of that and Even better if it's AI versus AI.
Speaker 1: a lot of people only watch f1 For highlights to see when crazy shit happens.
Speaker 1: a bunch of AI's Reacting in real time in souped up dangerous electric cars.
Speaker 1: crazy shit might go down like on a minute by minute basis Like the AI might just do something stupid eventually, but the thing is right.
Speaker 0: like all sports You're gonna approach like, you know maximum efficiency pretty rapidly if there's enough investment and you're just gonna see every car achieving It's maximum, you know lap time.
Speaker 0: It's its shortest possible race time and whichever one is the shortest possible race time will win.
Speaker 1: However, I will say this if AI gets advanced enough to where every car on the road is Driving perfectly in there won't be a situation where the car that gets the pole and The qualifying won't also win the race.
Speaker 0: It got around the track fastest.
Speaker 0: It can continue to get around like.
Speaker 0: imagine this.
Speaker 1: so say two of the AI cars.
Speaker 1: I have perfect knowledge of the perfect line and the fastest speed but one of them is in front of the other one.
Speaker 0: How did it get there if the other one was faster to begin with?
Speaker 1: So yeah, how?
Speaker 1: how do you do anything in f1?
Speaker 1: I mean right now in f1 you have the qualifications So they might be off like a microsecond.
Speaker 0: human errors.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So maybe a IRS.
Speaker 1: if we get AI that is perfect at this and there are no differentiating factors between them You get really boring.
Speaker 0: But that also means we have solved a lot of really complicated problems solved how to make a car go around a track as fast as possible.
Speaker 1: if the AIs are so perfect that the competition is Meaningless and comes down to random factors in Formula E with a eyes down the road That means that self-driving cars are the literal reality of the entire rest of the world At least the industrialized world at least rich people in the industrialized world.
Speaker 1: Hmm, but I'm looking forward to what actually comes out of this.
Speaker 1: So stay tuned.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm gonna watch every race.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the cars that drive themselves.
Speaker 0: I'm watching every race every second.
Speaker 1: So I got one little thing here.
Speaker 1: Unicode, you know is the way you should be encoding text nowadays for a lot of reasons and Unicode has a lot of like smiley faces and things in it.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of characters in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because they've got so much space.
Speaker 0: They've already put all the human languages.
Speaker 0: So and emojis and emoticons are used by a lot of people.
Speaker 0: So why not put them in there?
Speaker 0: and they have been and it's been really helpful.
Speaker 1: Yeah It is really useful that I positive thing I can type an emoji on my Android phone and pretty much anyone.
Speaker 1: I send that message to on a phone a computer depending on their font anywhere in the world The symbol is transferred but not the graphic.
Speaker 1: So if Scott's on iPhone He's like angry cat guy looks a little bit different from my angry cat guy because the character is just defined as angry cat guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and your font determines what it actually looks like.
Speaker 1: So there's a consortia.
Speaker 0: all the normal letters.
Speaker 1: yeah, there is a consortia like Unicode is just like an example of a lot everything that is both good and overly bureaucratic with Technology standards.
Speaker 1: and there's a problem that has emerged that a lot of people never anticipated only recently.
Speaker 1: Companies like Nestle are trying to petition the consortium that decides what characters get.
Speaker 0: That's a good thing.
Speaker 0: The consortium isn't a commercial entity.
Speaker 1: Yeah with commercial interest to add their own trademarks and advertisements as Unicode characters.
Speaker 1: No, so Nestle wants a Kit Kat emoji.
Speaker 1: Taco Bell wants a Taco Bell taco emoji.
Speaker 1: Durex wants a condom.
Speaker 1: but supposedly well, I mean, I just want a generic condom.
Speaker 1: I do need.
Speaker 0: I'm okay with that Durex You're good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're good.
Speaker 0: But if Durex wanted a also Taco Bell, I think there's already a bell.
Speaker 0: so And if there's also a taco that's fine too.
Speaker 0: You can just go taco it followed by Bell.
Speaker 1: So here's my word Nestle.
Speaker 0: I think it's already a chocolate bar.
Speaker 0: So shove it.
Speaker 1: Here's my worry.
Speaker 1: if you think that most people are don't care enough about local politics get involved that People who have too much power are involved and are controlling local politics Less people care about this than you can imagine.
Speaker 0: the people who care about this are also the people who care about The clocks being one second off.
Speaker 1: more people know who Bernie Sanders and Lawrence Lessig are Combined.
Speaker 1: then even know that there's a Unicode consortium.
Speaker 1: You're a rare unicorn Scott.
Speaker 0: so my worry is there a unicorn emoji?
Speaker 1: that consortium could probably be taken over by shady commercial interests trivially if people actually tried and that's bad news.
Speaker 1: and even if it isn't if these Pollutes that space the can of worms that opens is beyond Comprehension we're gonna have to replace Unicode with something else.
Speaker 1: Let's say I send a message I tweet something with the emoji for I don't know coca-cola like a coke a can of coca-cola.
Speaker 1: But I say hey wanna Pepsi Coca-cola would have to send me a trademark.
Speaker 1: C and D or Risk losing their rights to the trademark.
Speaker 0: I make a font and there's one of the characters is letter a another one Is the letter B things which are not owned by anybody and the third one is and the third one is 2012, right?
Speaker 0: So I have to make when I'm making my font a graphic for Ron Paul 2012, but I decide to make it a poop.
Speaker 1: So, I think that is the solution.
Speaker 1: it'd be we'll keep an eye on this.
Speaker 1: believe me I'm one of the people who will know if this shit happens.
Speaker 1: if it happens I call on everyone who makes fonts everyone who supports you anyone who makes any emoji arts any emoji?
Speaker 1: That is a trademark Hans should always be interpreted as a middle finger Or a poop or a middle finger and a I think.
Speaker 1: but yeah poop is better because middle finger isn't culturally universal.
Speaker 1: Poops pretty you know.
Speaker 0: or a poop with a trademark that T.M.
Speaker 0: Or goatee.
Speaker 1: Oh Anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: what do you got for me?
Speaker 0: So, you know in Manhattan, it's not easy to get real estate.
Speaker 0: It's not even easy to rent even if it's commercial real estate.
Speaker 1: Well, it's got you.
Speaker 1: So guess what?
Speaker 1: Lakehole is gone can't couldn't afford the couldn't afford the rent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, $100 plus a table a head table restaurant.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a cook shortage I heard but that's a different story.
Speaker 0: Yeah But surprisingly in Manhattan, there's a lot of things that manage to stick around And seem to be unable to get pushed out despite the fact that rents go up and they're usually things that have some special way Of staying where they are.
Speaker 0: things like a church right as some special way to stay where it is.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's a landmark.
Speaker 0: Maybe someone just owns the property and it's not like renting.
Speaker 1: There's a great article about why Chinatown still exists Even though that real estate is worth like a hundred times what it's being used for.
Speaker 0: Yep Things like that.
Speaker 0: So, you know theaters.
Speaker 0: they stay, you know, like even though theaters are making money anyway.
Speaker 0: And one of the things that tends to stay or like museums But also these really like specialized in tiny museum type thing Always go around and you'd be like what the hell is that.
Speaker 0: and it's like this really tiny thing and it's like oh That's the Museum of gangsters.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it's this tiny little thing and somehow it you know, no one goes to it But it keeps that spot and it just stays there.
Speaker 0: So another thing related to the museums are these libraries like these very specific Libraries like you'll see them if you walk around just like Christian Science Library and I think that partially uses the church exception.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also Christian Science is bullshit.
Speaker 0: It's nothing to do with science.
Speaker 0: Yeah away from that.
Speaker 0: Not as bad as Scientology but bad.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's as bad as Seventh-day Adventist bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're better off just going to Catholic Church or whatever than going there.
Speaker 1: Why not the orthodoxy?
Speaker 0: sure you can go there, too.
Speaker 0: It's better better than Christian Science.
Speaker 1: Oh see man.
Speaker 0: Christian Science is all like don't take medicine.
Speaker 0: But anyway, you'll also see ones like.
Speaker 0: I think there's like a Swedish like Specific like library kind of thing.
Speaker 0: I saw ones, you know, you see stuff like that.
Speaker 0: but there's one I did not know about probably cuz I never walked past where it is and It is called the conjuring arts Resource Center.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: That sounds Lovecraftian.
Speaker 0: It is a library that contains 11,000 books about magic and its Allied arts.
Speaker 1: Whoa, if I if high school rim had found that place high school rim would have applied to work there.
Speaker 0: Right, so apparently that's there and Yeah, so I didn't know it was there.
Speaker 0: but if you need to study magic don't go to the regular library go to the magic specific library and you could learn some cups And balls or some son lady in half or worse.
Speaker 1: That is actually super awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah Usually, I don't know.
Speaker 0: sometimes these I don't know how this one works A lot of them work differently like sometimes you can go in and read all you want, but you can't take anything out.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you got to be a member to even walk in.
Speaker 0: so they're all you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah I guess you can go to their website and get some infos if you actually want to go there and you're in Manhattan and you Care about magic.
Speaker 1: I'm going there.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna learn there?
Speaker 0: I don't know magic.
Speaker 0: You're gonna learn magic.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna learn?
Speaker 0: I know magic magic missile.
Speaker 1: I Dude, can you hope you know how much damage 1d 4 plus 1 is on a human a level zero commoner?
Speaker 1: That's death for most people.
Speaker 0: All right, well they're not.
Speaker 0: they're not.
Speaker 0: obviously not letting you in.
Speaker 1: magic missile never misses either.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I have a quote to you for you But from an article about the video that is my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: quote the battery pack.
Speaker 1: living inside this thing is a literal pack of rechargeable double-a batteries soldered and taped together into an amalgam of electricity and regrets.
Speaker 0: So first of all, if you don't realize this already, you know when you get a battery pack.
Speaker 0: It's like batteries come in cells the same way that your double A's and your C's and your all your trip.
Speaker 1: I like you buy a little bit laptop battery.
Speaker 1: It'll say like this is the six cell Cell.
Speaker 0: take your laptop battery and open it up.
Speaker 1: Don't do that.
Speaker 1: Okay, don't actually open it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, but if you if you opened it up, you know It's in there a bunch of batteries all end-to-end.
Speaker 0: Yeah in rows and they look like normal batteries.
Speaker 0: They're just usually like solid color and full of lithium and yep, but they're like tested together.
Speaker 1: They're embedded in like usually some sort of like heavy usually some circuit board controlling them, right?
Speaker 0: You're not.
Speaker 0: it's not like when you put a double-a battery in your TV remote.
Speaker 0: The double-a battery is going right into your remote, but there is you.
Speaker 1: there's like a power.
Speaker 1: Well, there's there's something there.
Speaker 0: There's some sort of capacitor regulator kind of thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's not.
Speaker 0: when you have a battery pack Usually, you know, there's some sort of circuit board in between all those cells and your laptop right inside the battery.
Speaker 1: This is a dude who just does like teardowns like he'll take apart technology and be like, hey here's the thing and I'm gonna take it apart and tear it down and tell you how it worked.
Speaker 1: and He has these ones about like embedded computers and tablock tablet computers and whatever.
Speaker 1: But this video is kind of special.
Speaker 1: This is like a specialized tablet computer that was sold as a product for people to use in a professional setting.
Speaker 0: Yes, I mean we already know that like medical devices and medical can you know are like the worst the asinomad Infoview medical tablet computer.
Speaker 1: I guess it was used in hospitals for medical data and doctors and nurses and things and probably starting fires.
Speaker 1: Probably so he does his usual thing.
Speaker 1: Like he's opening this thing and he's like, oh, well, there's a board like this.
Speaker 1: There's a board like this and this video increasingly goes off the rails.
Speaker 0: I laughed so hard at work.
Speaker 1: It's like this is a dog's breakfast.
Speaker 1: is what we got in here like.
Speaker 1: he cannot believe What is going on in here and he finds?
Speaker 1: Bad cells like, you know the kinds of cell like, you know, those cells God was talking about.
Speaker 1: They kind of look like a regular like double-a battery, but they're not a regular double-a battery Like you.
Speaker 1: don't just put those in something now and he has soldered them together and wrapped tape around them Like jumbled in like laying on top of the motherboard.
Speaker 1: There's like two of them and then there's a third one like off somewhere else, but he keeps saying like oh, there's a battery pack There's a normal battery pack.
Speaker 1: and then this bullshit.
Speaker 1: and as he's getting deeper and deeper into this thing He starts getting more and more suspicious of that quote battery pack.
Speaker 1: and when he opens it This video is just great.
Speaker 1: This is also why.
Speaker 0: so keep in mind when you go to the hospital.
Speaker 0: This is the sort of equipment your life depends upon.
Speaker 1: Yep this is the kind of equipment that I used to have to deploy in hospitals, which is why I Quit that job and burned every bridge I had as I walked out the door.
Speaker 1: flip it everybody Burn it.
Speaker 0: This is gonna burn itself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all I did was leave in a cenomed tablet computer on the bridge.
Speaker 1: In the moment the book club book was the wheel of time.
Speaker 1: I just read the fifth book.
Speaker 0: I Started reading the fifth book and I haven't read any in a long time.
Speaker 0: You could probably listen to geek night's episodes and figure out when I started and stopped reading that fifth book.
Speaker 1: We'll start a new book club book.
Speaker 1: That isn't the wheel of time soon.
Speaker 1: I actually know what it's gonna be now.
Speaker 1: that book that we talked about on the last interview show we did.
Speaker 1: You remember that book?
Speaker 1: no sounded like a really good book.
Speaker 0: Okay, maybe I'm remembering a bit now with Joe with Joe food.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah that one.
Speaker 1: That's the book I'm gonna do.
Speaker 1: I think okay.
Speaker 1: So otherwise, we're gonna be at magfest on a bunch of panels.
Speaker 1: They're not public yet.
Speaker 0: I got to arrange all kinds of transportation.
Speaker 1: if you back us on patreon I posted a preview of the panels were likely to be on even though that's not otherwise generally public information.
Speaker 1: So there you go.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, we're probably gonna be back south.
Speaker 1: We're probably gonna be a pax east.
Speaker 1: We're probably gonna be an anime Boston.
Speaker 1: We're probably gonna be a kinetic on.
Speaker 1: I think that's far enough out.
Speaker 1: push in July packs prime packs prime.
Speaker 0: That's the convention schedule for next year.
Speaker 1: then magfest again pecks out or pecks ass.
Speaker 1: We're probably gonna do pecks ass.
Speaker 0: I was thinking about going to Essen next year.
Speaker 1: I won't do both.
Speaker 0: I can't afford that.
Speaker 0: You want to give me a bunch of money?
Speaker 1: No, why don't you patreon?
Speaker 0: you want to like quintuple your investment?
Speaker 0: Yeah, send me to Essen and packs ass.
Speaker 1: Oh and also for our Tuesday listeners David Peterson finally posted.
Speaker 1: we helped him and Lou Crane make a bunch of videos around the Mouse guard swords and strongholds board game the board game that the mice play in the mouse guard comics, right?
Speaker 0: So if you had any rules questions about those games We help produce some videos that explain every conceivable possible rule scenario.
Speaker 0: in case you don't want to read the rules You just watch these videos instead.
Speaker 1: There is one scenario.
Speaker 1: We do not describe.
Speaker 1: No, we knew because we I have the video where we all talked about the scenario and agreed that there's literally no reason to explain That scenario.
Speaker 1: Okay, the one where what if I need to put a mouse back on the board with my rescue?
Speaker 1: and There's literally because there are four strongholds blocking the other side.
Speaker 1: There is no legal place for me to put it.
Speaker 0: You're already in bad shape.
Speaker 1: Yeah So There are always rumors about what Apple's gonna do next and you know A lot of them are just complete BS unless you know where to look.
Speaker 1: but the most recent rumor is one that has been a perennial rumor with Apple that they're gonna remove the headphone jack from their blank and This yeah, everyone's acting like they never heard this story before.
Speaker 0: we heard this story like two years ago.
Speaker 0: This is not a new story.
Speaker 1: Yeah Didn't they?
Speaker 1: they actually put on a mini TRS jack on an iPod at one point?
Speaker 1: Like I remember that happening or something rumblings happening about that.
Speaker 0: I know I remember that ever.
Speaker 1: I mean iPods are ancient technology anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah iPods have always had the regular headphone home, but it's actually an interesting question because the TRS standard or at least the you know The headphone jack that as you know, it is called TRS.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well TRS is the you know tip ring shield sleeve.
Speaker 1: I've heard sleeve or shield in desert.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter It's.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: that's what it stands for because the plug has a tip Then this sort of black separator than a ring a metal ring Oh then another little separator and then the sleeve or the shield, right?
Speaker 0: And then so it's these three pieces of metal and when you shove it in the socket It connects in three places to your device.
Speaker 1: Right and it existed because that shape was actually really easy to make and be super reliable.
Speaker 1: Right was really easy to connect to a very simple cable, right?
Speaker 0: And the best thing about it is that the tip has like this indent in it.
Speaker 0: So in the inside of your hole, there's some little pushers that push inwards and when the tip makes it past the pushers They they lock in behind the tip keeping that headphone jack sort of in there.
Speaker 0: pretty good, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's not.
Speaker 0: you got to you know, apply some force to yank it out.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: and the contacts are not
Speaker 0: just like a loosey, you know, that's why when you put your headphones You know into the into the hole it goes click and then it clicks to come out is because the shape of the tip and these Little pushers on the inside
Speaker 1: and also the contacts are real big get a really good connection there Which is important because for audio purposes, that's analog information.
Speaker 1: It's not digital.
Speaker 1: There's no error correction, right?
Speaker 0: It's an analog audio signal.
Speaker 0: it can you know, it's already been amplified right to what it's gonna be.
Speaker 0: You just need to send it to some speakers and you can hear it, you know, so it's pretty much, you know What is the speaker?
Speaker 0: It's a magnet that just moves back and forth, you know pushing a thing to make the air move to make Sound that's the same as a model own just in the opposite action exactly.
Speaker 0: So if your speaker is got, you know, if someone's creating like a you know, I don't know a hundred Hertz tone You know.
Speaker 0: then if you look at that electric signal, what is it?
Speaker 0: It's an electric wave that's going at a hundred Hertz.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then you make a thing move at a hundred Hertz and then it makes that sound.
Speaker 0: That's how it works.
Speaker 0: So when you have the tip ring and sleeve the sleeve is ground because electricity Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the tip and ring are left and right because it's stereo Which is lossy.
Speaker 1: because the other way to use that kind of cable is a balanced connection where you're only sending one channel So it's mono.
Speaker 1: but it's actually so ethernet cables at least up through like hundred megabit They do pretty much the exact same thing.
Speaker 1: is what I'm about to describe.
Speaker 1: you send the same data over both.
Speaker 1: So the tip and the ring both have the same data, but you invert one of them, right?
Speaker 0: So when one says one the other one says zero.
Speaker 0: at the same time.
Speaker 1: It's more like because one says thirty eight point nine seven and the other one says forty one point four five because it's analog.
Speaker 0: Yes, yeah, but then at the other end because they're the exact opposite of each other, right?
Speaker 1: It's you can pretty much a hundred percent and detect any errors or mistakes Because say you add 20 to one spot because there was like a EMP went off somewhere like nukes are happening.
Speaker 1: an EMP went by and a plus 20 Got added to this one like microsecond in your signal at the other end You see there's a plus 20 on top of a signal on one end and there's also a plus 20 on the other end.
Speaker 0: So basically so something that started off is negative 2. positive 2 is now Neg, you know negative it's 18 and 22.
Speaker 1: So you're like, aha that must have been a - yeah Because if you take the two signals and overlay them on each other they turn into zero plus all the noise.
Speaker 1: So basically you get a track now That is just the noise and you can remove it.
Speaker 0: and that is why balanced audio cables are the best thing in the world But those don't devices on either end after you actually do that and you would need like tip ring ring ring sleeve.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why XLR cables.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing.
Speaker 1: It's just three pins instead of a tip and a ring Doing the exact same thing, but balanced audio is not used by any of you Unless you have a mixer and some audio.
Speaker 0: so and there's no reason to because really how much interference are you dealing with and walking?
Speaker 0: Around none.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't hear any difference using.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus you've got a short cable and some shitty headphones.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't really matter.
Speaker 1: that doesn't matter if you have fancy headphones.
Speaker 1: They don't.
Speaker 0: don't start believing some audiophile nonsense that you got to use balanced cables for your everyday audio listening.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're audio producing most of the time your devices don't support that anyway like you can.
Speaker 0: yeah So, you know, so it's an audiophile devices often don't support.
Speaker 1: So TRS is important though because there's some debate about this and I'm not going to weigh in on whether or not this Statement is correct, but a lot of people have posited that the TRS audio standard So that jack and that socket and that format of sending audio analog audio Might be the longest live technical Specification in consumer device history
Speaker 0: even old even older than like the phone jack.
Speaker 1: It is basically a phone jack.
Speaker 1: Before our modern rj11 phone jack existed.
Speaker 0: really it's older than rj11.
Speaker 1: Yeah Read the Wikipedia article on this is cut.
Speaker 1: It's not called TRS.
Speaker 1: TRS is a use of it.
Speaker 1: It's called phone jack.
Speaker 0: Oh Okay, that's news to me.
Speaker 0: Something else you may have noticed is that like newer headphones and newer phones and things in general.
Speaker 0: have Tip ring ring sleeves extra ring on there.
Speaker 1: There's some like T tip ring ring ring ring like.
Speaker 1: there's a lot.
Speaker 0: I've only seen two ring.
Speaker 0: I've never seen anything more than two ring.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure I've seen TRRS.
Speaker 0: I've only seen TR.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna look that up.
Speaker 1: I see TRS here.
Speaker 0: So TRS is basically an extra ring.
Speaker 0: and what do you do with that extra ring?
Speaker 0: They're not doing balanced audio because it's nonsense right?
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: There it is.
Speaker 1: There's TR.
Speaker 0: Okay, what they're doing with the second extra additional ring is first of all, it's fully backwards compatible with the one ring.
Speaker 0: Right, it's like if you take a tip ring ring sleeve headphone and put it in an old iPod that only supports tip ring sleeve.
Speaker 0: It's gonna play just fine because it's gonna line up with either ring and it doesn't give a shit.
Speaker 1: and it's elegant because the way It works in the modern era.
Speaker 1: I mean think if you've got a mono Device just because you have like like one speaker or something You can plug a mono cable into there and it'll just work.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be touching both halves of the stereo part and combining them, you know Well, there's a little more.
Speaker 0: nor maybe you'll only hear left or maybe you'll only hear right?
Speaker 1: I do not want to get into what happens there because actually with old devices you could kill yourself but Basically, it just works in the modern era.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 1: That's what you need to know.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the tip the extra ring there.
Speaker 0: that's how you that's how on your little fancy iPhone headphones like I have you've got a little microphone on there and you could push Buttons to like, you know Make the track go forward or play pause or make volume up and down.
Speaker 0: Is that so the extra ring is doing?
Speaker 0: the extra ring is going the opposite direction in your iPhones or your regular phones or Android?
Speaker 0: phones.
Speaker 0: That extra ring is not.
Speaker 0: they're not sending anything out on that ring unless you know.
Speaker 0: You know if you start talking to someone on the phone They'll just send that to the tip in the first ring because you're listening to it and your ears They don't need to use that right?
Speaker 0: The third ring is going the opposite way.
Speaker 0: it's a microphone and when you push like the volume up button, it's actually creating little sounds and Sending those sounds to the phone like you said something only you can't talk like a modem going To make it volume go up Right and then the phone hears that and goes aha I guess I'll make the volume go up.
Speaker 0: Someone said to turn the volume up on the microphone hole on the second ring.
Speaker 1: so Think about what this means.
Speaker 1: I can take the newest iPhone.
Speaker 1: I can take the first Walkman.
Speaker 0: I can plug any pair of Headphones that were news beats and plug them into the oldest Sony Walkman and I could take the headphones that came with that oldest Sony Walkman and plug them into the newest iPhone and they'll all work.
Speaker 1: That's a big deal because headphones might be like very well constructed like if you get good headphones, but they're dumb devices.
Speaker 1: They're just a Physical thing that responds to electricity.
Speaker 1: They're driven by the DAC in the device.
Speaker 1: The device was smart.
Speaker 1: the headphones were dumb, right?
Speaker 0: See in the olden days you didn't even need a DAC because like you have a cassette player with a Walkman The audio is already analog.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just reading the analog audio from the tape and playing it with the amplifier.
Speaker 0: Walkman does.
Speaker 0: it doesn't do anything else is the tape reader, but nowadays you got an mp3 player.
Speaker 0: You're converting those digital You know sounds into an analog sound and then sending that analog sound through an amplifier not the headphone hole But because we have that line of differentiation where the standard this TRS is used these quarter inch or eighth inch jacks.
Speaker 1: I think they're officially defined in millimeter terms.
Speaker 0: now Whatever.
Speaker 1: but or you get the two and a half millimeter that some like bullshit phones used to use my ti-86 head.
Speaker 1: I mean, well because they use that for data.
Speaker 0: I think the Xbox 360 headset uses a tiny one also.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've got adapters for the tiny one for my rig.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway, but because like because that standard it was almost like an abstraction layer in code.
Speaker 1: like because we've got that there.
Speaker 1: It's like an interface.
Speaker 1: Well, it is an interface Literally is an interface.
Speaker 1: So doesn't matter what's on the other side of it because the same thing comes out and every device that plays audio pretty much in the world Will work with this.
Speaker 1: headphones work everywhere.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: but The problem with it.
Speaker 1: as far as Apple has been concerned and they have been concerned about this They can't make their phone thinner.
Speaker 0: No, and they've made.
Speaker 1: it is too big And in fact Apple has been so obsessed with it made it thinner.
Speaker 0: They even push the camera out the back a little bit to make the phone thinner.
Speaker 1: But I found all these articles about patents and old work Apple has been doing for a long time To try to hack around to get a smaller version of these TRS eighth inch connectors Make the phone thinner and make you use a stupid adapter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they designed one.
Speaker 1: That's the same thing Except one side of it is cut flat.
Speaker 1: So it's like cut in two along the length just to make it thinner But otherwise work the same way and have one pusher on the top only Like.
Speaker 1: that's how obsessed they were with this and the rumor is that Apple is finally going to with the iPhone 7.
Speaker 1: Just force you to use Thunderbolt and that's where the audio comes out, right?
Speaker 0: So here's the issue here.
Speaker 0: the people were if you remember the older iPhones before they invented lightning cables.
Speaker 0: their lightning Thunderbolt is different.
Speaker 0: Yeah before they invented the lightning cable They had the dock connector, which is like this big wide rectangle kind of thing.
Speaker 0: That was only one, you know, and it had a million pins on it.
Speaker 0: The dock connector was actually really fancy in that there was a lot of things on those pins Including analog audio output.
Speaker 0: so like they also sent the analog audio out a few of those pins and that's why you could easily take an old iPod and Put it on a dock and they you know a dock with speakers and could just play music because it would.
Speaker 0: just you know There was like extra headphone hole.
Speaker 0: That was a weird shape on the bottom of it in addition to the one on the top.
Speaker 1: That's why that dock was cheap.
Speaker 0: The dock was stupid right as far as I'm aware.
Speaker 0: the lightning connector I could be wrong does not have analog audio output on it.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it's a digital only connector like a serial USB kind of connector.
Speaker 0: We could look that up.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'm wrong.
Speaker 0: I think you're right from what I mean means now if you have lightning headphones What used to happen was the phone would convert the digital sound into the analog signal.
Speaker 0: the amplifier would be in your phone.
Speaker 0: now By you're gonna have to buy an adapter.
Speaker 0: that isn't just some dumb shape changing metal connecting thing for there's gonna be a circuit in There's gonna be a digital to analog, you know processing device and Either the adapter or if your headphones have a lightning cable in your headphones.
Speaker 0: and now suddenly This is a whole different.
Speaker 0: Headphones are no longer to some a speaker with a wire coming out of it Like every speaker has been for the history of speakers.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: This is not a new problem.
Speaker 0: This has happened with serial ports The digital analog converter and possibly an amplifier in your headphones.
Speaker 1: Like a lot of devices if you need to just connect something to a computer to send and receive data Way easier and cheaper.
Speaker 0: and does this mean your head?
Speaker 0: does this mean your headphones need power to?
Speaker 0: yeah well, they're gonna get power from the lightning because you can get power from the lightning connector because that's how the The the pencil charges the pan charges off the lightning connector so you can definitely get power from it.
Speaker 1: So in the old days with devices you use serial ports because you can just send and receive data and Trivially implement that like in hardware.
Speaker 0: But the device that's using the serial port needed power from somewhere cuz serial ports didn't give power.
Speaker 0: This is why the USB they added power to USB.
Speaker 1: But for a small device if you want to use USB as your serial bus You've got to implement the fucking USB stack with a chip on your device.
Speaker 1: Yep serial You could just take a bunch of Nang gates in there if you really wanted to and go to town.
Speaker 0: You just needed a double-a batteries.
Speaker 1: Yeah But in terms of like you could you could implement the signaling stuff without having to implement a semi software stack of USB and get a UUID and all that nonsense or GUI do whatever whatever.
Speaker 1: so It would be interesting if Apple did this Because it would.
Speaker 0: you're gonna charge your arm and a leg for an adapter, which is their favorite thing to do.
Speaker 1: Well, it'll also start locking you in because as soon as you buy lightning headphones You can't go back to Android.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 0: Well, you buy your lightning headphones and you buy a $50 adapter to turn lightning into tip ring sleeve to use it with something Else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then if you don't buy lightning headphones You're gonna have to buy a $50 adapter to use regular headphones with iPhone 7.
Speaker 1: But it might be moot because I suspect most people are going toward Bluetooth if they have iPhones.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah I don't know why Apple doesn't just get rid of the connector entirely and say Bluetooth headphones everyone and make some fucking good ones.
Speaker 0: Cuz no one makes any good ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah Someone's gonna tell me that someone does make good ones and you're wrong cuz.
Speaker 0: I've tried a lot of them and they all have problems I still use.
Speaker 1: I actually stopped using the old animotics because they're just too fragile and now I just have some sure Isolation earbuds with a TRS connector on the end and they work great.
Speaker 1: But it's interesting because this dance has happened a few times.
Speaker 1: and with the serial port thing Serial ports are still around and a lot of things still use them because USB is inadequate even today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of switches a lot of routers a lot of embedded devices a lot of research devices.
Speaker 1: That's why even now you can buy a PCI Express Card that just has four serial ports sticking out of the bag.
Speaker 0: a fun thing to do.
Speaker 0: Just install Linux on a computer just any kind of Linux even Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: Oh, how many kids even know this.
Speaker 0: and if by default it's going to run a terminal Right device on the serial port Usually the first one if you take like a VT 100 or something some serial device or
Speaker 1: even just get an old Windows computer Or something and just connect to it with a normal
Speaker 0: mini-com.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, or you know any or even putty.
Speaker 0: you can probably do it, right?
Speaker 0: And just connect a cable to that serial port to a terminal either a virtual or hardware terminal and boop They you'll turn it on and there's a login.
Speaker 0: It'll be like, you know login username.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there it is.
Speaker 0: Just log it on the serial port.
Speaker 0: cuz back in the day, that's how computers worked.
Speaker 0: it you'd go to a school.
Speaker 0: There'd be one computer running Unix and there'd be a whole bunch of terminals.
Speaker 0: This and all those terminals had a serial cable connected to the computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they were terminals.
Speaker 1: They were not computers.
Speaker 1: There was not much going on.
Speaker 1: They could not do stuff on their own and you can do the same thing.
Speaker 0: You can take your computer and get a whole bunch of terminals plugged into it if you have enough serial connectors even use.
Speaker 0: you can even use USB to do this if you set it up and Everyone can use the same computer and all login is their own users.
Speaker 0: One person can when you SSH in.
Speaker 0: what do you think?
Speaker 0: It does.
Speaker 0: it creates a terminal on a device and sends it over the network.
Speaker 0: That's all it's doing.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know if this rumor is true or not.
Speaker 1: I give it pretty much 50/50 odds.
Speaker 0: I mean the last time it had either the rumor came about I said, yeah, that's believable Yeah, and now it's coming about again even stronger.
Speaker 0: so it's still believable.
Speaker 0: but what tends to happen with the Apple rumors is Most of them are actually Seem to be true that there aren't usually a lot of bullshit ones unless you read like really dumb websites, right and ones that are Seemingly wrong.
Speaker 0: like Apple didn't make a television.
Speaker 0: They just updated the Apple TV and stuff.
Speaker 0: They're usually right.
Speaker 0: eventually There's an is to die truth in there like Apple watch was a rumor for many years.
Speaker 0: And then what happened eventually?
Speaker 0: Apple watch there at the same time.
Speaker 1: By that logic there are rumors about pretty much every stupid thing.
Speaker 1: That doesn't happen.
Speaker 1: So wait, which ones I'm so people were talking about smartwatches 20 years ago.
Speaker 1: Sure, like I mean from the first iPhone there was probably some crack powders like there's gonna be an Apple watch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean Apple made a camera.
Speaker 0: There's a digital camera and it wasn't in any phone and whatsoever.
Speaker 0: It's a whole camera.
Speaker 0: Apple made printers Apple made all kinds of the people don't remember.
Speaker 1: but Basically, if you're a nerd or a geek like us if you don't know how headphone cables work I'd actually suggest read this Wikipedia article.
Speaker 0: Also, do you remember that?
Speaker 0: You know, they're big ones to the same tip ring sleeve, but quarter-inch but big.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a thing.
Speaker 1: In fact, not only is that a thing but that's still you still use.
Speaker 0: why not?
Speaker 1: Did you buy a good pair of headphones?
Speaker 1: That's all it comes with usually because well usually will come with the adapter also Yeah, but if you have a good pair of headphones like for real headphones You're probably plugging them into a for real device like an actual mixing console or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz there's no other reason to wear giant headphones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Always like you see those people who have like super giant amazing like $400 studio monitor.
Speaker 0: Well, I didn't sit there.
Speaker 1: iPhone Yeah with a little adapter and this time.
Speaker 1: Okay, let's take it out of the bottom of the iPhone listen to an mp3 or whatever.
Speaker 0: Like like.
Speaker 0: I'm sure that's so portable dude that must be so great.
Speaker 0: just carry around with you all day.
Speaker 1: your headphones are like Six times bigger than your phone.
Speaker 0: Might as well get the giant iPhone if you had the giant headphone.
Speaker 1: but seriously like if you're a kid who's never run into this stuff.
Speaker 1: like You can use serial ports and headphone jacks and TRS stuff to do a lot of stuff without writing any Software.
Speaker 1: like there's cool stuff down at the bottom of computing that no one knows about anymore except old people.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Speaker 1: music can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: The patrons tonight for this episode in order of the amount of money you're giving us are Nicholas Brando Rebecca Dunn James David White Christian Koontz Jess mechanical mind Renee from New Zealand Robert Lee Ryan Perrin drew Oppenlander rare Lavelle Brian Cedroni Rochelle, Montanona Finn Eric Silveraude rim eats poop Edgar Mendez William Eisen rose Aaron Sarris Chris midkiff Chris Knox flame dark fire Samuel Cordray Daniel Redman Chris a dad Doug Snyder Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: so Yeah, we had some trouble trying to figure out what to do the show on today.
Speaker 1: Scott did not want to talk about anything and he doesn't care about tech news.
Speaker 1: He refused to even pick newses.
Speaker 1: So I just picked four of the like 20 things I thought were worth talking about into the news and Then I convinced him to do the show on TRS and headphone jacks.
Speaker 1: Somehow he agreed to it, but he was like as your ideas stupid.
Speaker 1: We had like two minutes to talk about and yeah analyze the wave like I dumped it out.
Speaker 1: We talked about 50% of the time each.
Speaker 1: In fact Scott talked a little bit more than me in this episode.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, Scott says we can't do shows on things because there's nothing to say and if I trick him into doing it Then we do a show that would push an hour unless I actually cut him off.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know what we'll do.
Speaker 1: We're thinking about changing up the format.
Speaker 1: maybe for Mondays.
Speaker 1: We might start doing four to five news's and then a shorter main bit or Maybe we'll just do four news's and then whatever our longest news was going to be We'll talk about whatever generic topic can come out of that.
Speaker 1: If it means shorter shows fine.
Speaker 1: I actually think it'll be fine because Scott did fine and the show ended up in my opinion reasonably good.
Speaker 1: if any of you have complaints I tried to cut Scott off about the Minor details of exactly how TRS works in audio between balanced and unbalanced and which is what?
Speaker 1: no one actually needs to know that unless you're writing the spec modern equipment is not going to hurt you, but Generally don't plug headphones into microphone jacks.
Speaker 1: You might ruin the headphones because of the bias voltage or phantom power or whatever nonsense might be hidden in there.
Speaker 1: anyway I'm starting pre-production still on.
Speaker 1: he knows present sutana.
Speaker 1: I'll post some updates about that in the patreon soon.
Speaker 1: Scott still as far as I can tell does not listen to this nonsense and I now leave you your moment of literally the opposite of Zen - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
Speaker 0: - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
Speaker 1: -
Speaker 0: - -
Speaker 0: -
Speaker 1: -
Speaker 0: - -.