Speaker 0: It's Wednesday April 8th 2015.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: It's been a while since we've talked about anime con so anime Boston 2015 and Zenkai con The letter which is technically not an anime con if you listen to the people who want to say that to you.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: One of the weirdest things that I've ever done in my life is be in an airport, but not be flying anywhere.
Speaker 1: Why would you go to an airport?
Speaker 0: well?
Speaker 0: I had to go so I basically signed up for that like global entry thing cuz I fly around the world a lot like my Work was like yeah, it's free.
Speaker 0: We'll pay for it.
Speaker 0: Just go get it.
Speaker 0: Mostly, I'm doing it to get the TSA.
Speaker 1: I didn't think that I thought you could get checked at not an airport.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can.
Speaker 0: so I signed up, and I filled out all this forms and everything and then they were like all.
Speaker 0: right now You need an appointment in the next 30 days for us to like meet you in person and like check on your shit.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I go.
Speaker 0: no There's one at Bowling Green like right next to my office, and I click find next available appointment slot and June 28th.
Speaker 0: Okay, yeah, so then I was like yeah, can I get an earlier one somewhere else and if you go to JFK?
Speaker 0: There's an office there now, and I was able to get an appointment.
Speaker 0: like a few days There's no one wants to go there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you took the air train all the way there and back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically I took a half-day off work.
Speaker 0: I took the air train from work to there and went from there train from work subway to the air train from work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well yeah a train to the air train.
Speaker 1: Or you went to the South air train, so you know what's funny.
Speaker 0: from City Hall.
Speaker 0: It takes the same amount of time to take the e train to JFK Via air train as it does to take the a train.
Speaker 1: yep There are people who don't know.
Speaker 1: for people who don't know the e train goes way north and then goes south to the e train goes Furthest Queens through Manhattan Like forest Rockaway a true.
Speaker 0: No it ends the time actually.
Speaker 0: no it ends at World Trade Center, but the same tracks with the a train go all the way.
Speaker 1: A train is all the way to the bottom part.
Speaker 1: So it's like go.
Speaker 1: it's basically Imagine a circle and it's just as fast to go to the top half as the bottom half of the circle.
Speaker 1: So one thing I'd ever to fly as the crow flies.
Speaker 1: It should be way As the person as the rim drives Michigan right as though Scott bikes it would be so fast.
Speaker 0: I grew up in Michigan.
Speaker 0: So I think about distance.
Speaker 0: still like it's hard for me to not think That it takes about 80 percent of the number of miles a place is away in minutes to get there.
Speaker 0: So if a place is 10 miles away I assume it's gonna take me like eight to nine minutes to get there.
Speaker 0: But in New York City you know cuz it's Michigan you drive like 60 to 80 miles an hour Everywhere there's really no traffic, and there's a grid.
Speaker 0: so if there's traffic you just go somewhere else on the grid It's a grid here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a grid here, but now I've been in situations where I am Close enough to home that I can see Like the up the tower next to our apartment building.
Speaker 1: we took that Amtrak home from Boston.
Speaker 0: We just looked out the window.
Speaker 1: I saw my apartment And it went past my apartment And then it went around in a circle and then it went in a tunnel and it took me To a place that is 30 minutes away from my apartment.
Speaker 1: by train.
Speaker 0: I once sat and I could see the city building in Queens for a full hour stuck in traffic Just trying to get to that building.
Speaker 1: So yeah, New York, but the building the tallest of the buildings also has that effect.
Speaker 1: city buildings not that tall no But I mean it's way taller than buildings in the rest of the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is true.
Speaker 1: That would be the tallest building in town in most town.
Speaker 0: well like how we navigate in Boston.
Speaker 0: All we do.
Speaker 0: we got into the station we never been to before.
Speaker 0: we just looked around.
Speaker 0: we're like well There's the only tall building in Boston.
Speaker 0: go that way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the conventions at the tall building.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll go to it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the coolest thing was I will move on because I travel a lot for conventions.
Speaker 0: So I guess it's almost relevant to what we're talking about today.
Speaker 0: But the people that interviewed me and like did my background check were actual u.s.
Speaker 0: Customs and immigration people not like TSA people of course.
Speaker 0: good God does that just remind you of how?
Speaker 0: Professional chill and just generally cool people who work for the real parts of the government are Compared to the people who work with the TS the harder the job is to get the more awesome You have to be to get it.
Speaker 0: this guy sits me down, and he's like all right.
Speaker 0: I'm your passport.
Speaker 1: Are you a druggie?
Speaker 0: no?
Speaker 0: He just doesn't say anything.
Speaker 0: He's like hand me a passport, and then he's like he says nothing.
Speaker 0: he starts typing shit And then he's just looking.
Speaker 0: he's like looking through your background.
Speaker 0: I'm like okay, and he's like you ever done it like you ever done anything like really super bad, and I was like Like what constitutes bad?
Speaker 0: He's like.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm just making small chalk.
Speaker 0: the the thing already said you're fine So yeah, and then we started chatting.
Speaker 0: He's like so why signing up for this?
Speaker 0: your work paying for it?
Speaker 0: I'm like yep, and he's like yeah pretty much everyone who has this is either rich or their work pays for it and It was just a really much money could it be?
Speaker 0: it's a hundred bucks for five years.
Speaker 1: That's not that.
Speaker 0: it's actually not that expensive.
Speaker 1: I mean, but the thing is to make it worth it, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, it's a hassle to get it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's a hassle.
Speaker 0: you fly in and out of a real Airport Internationally at least a few times a year.
Speaker 1: It's not right the hassle of checking your passport at the airport takes a few minutes.
Speaker 0: this time It depends what.
Speaker 0: I've landed at JFK where the line for a citizen to get in was an hour, okay?
Speaker 1: So it takes an hour.
Speaker 1: So this had a long.
Speaker 1: did it take to go to JFK do this and then come?
Speaker 0: well I was doing it on work hours.
Speaker 0: So that was In fact, I just played a lot of nursery my hex sure, but I'm gonna say it takes for half your workday four hours.
Speaker 1: You have to fly four times to save time more.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking of this way paying a hundred bucks to save at least 40 minutes on the average return from overseas For five years and I fly overseas like 12 to 20 times a year.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: You have five years to do all the traveling.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I quit my job tomorrow, I've still got it for five years It's true.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so of course it's worth it and I didn't waste any of my personal time.
Speaker 0: I got home earlier than I normally do sure so it was awesome.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the actual like interview took three minutes plus they took my fingerprints and then even the guy was like Oh, do you like rock climb or boulder or something?
Speaker 0: I was like you can tell that from my fingerprints.
Speaker 0: and he was like we can pick out you guys and we can pick out people who work in hospitals.
Speaker 0: and I was like I used to work in hospitals and yeah Actually didn't have fingerprints for that whole time.
Speaker 0: and he was like, yeah That's actually a problem because people who work in hospitals don't have fingerprints usually.
Speaker 0: Yep, but the guy was just like super professional and chill it It's.
Speaker 0: it's so weird to interact with the government official who is so chill Because you very rarely interact with the professional government because you're working a hospital.
Speaker 1: you wash your hands like 10,000 times a day Yeah, but just like them like I cannot express to you how super chill this guy was.
Speaker 1: Wouldn't he be chill?
Speaker 0: because you kind of lose sight of that when you interact with like cops or the TSA people who are paid less More yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: or people who have jobs that actually matter like checking the actual passports is a real job Sure, but looking through my bags to see if I have more mousse than I'm supposed to have And making sure I took my shoes off So yeah, that's my story.
Speaker 1: Okay, so this weekend while we were anime Boston something happened something did happen something that we completely forgot about.
Speaker 1: it came by surprise.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the pones have returned.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh.
Speaker 0: So it's funny because one there's been a lot of quality animation both anime and just animation for the last year.
Speaker 0: So when ponies ended season four we didn't really miss it while it was gone because I had so much else to watch like.
Speaker 0: I mean Just counting animation.
Speaker 0: I've been watching Steven Universe Adventure Time Archer, uh Gumball and a bunch of anime.
Speaker 0: like Yurikuma came and went in that span.
Speaker 1: Your panel came and went in that span.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: so I come home and from anime boss I'm like, what should I do?
Speaker 0: and then I go on Twitter and I sell these pones.
Speaker 0: I'm like is pone back?
Speaker 0: Oh shit, and then I go and of course there's an hour special and you know what?
Speaker 0: Still shows pretty good still.
Speaker 1: It's not bad It was ponies in vergeron.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: We're watching the episode.
Speaker 0: We're like, so are these cult ponies?
Speaker 0: They might be communist ponies.
Speaker 1: as soon as I saw the equals cutie marks.
Speaker 1: I'm like pony vergeron.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there were noted.
Speaker 1: Did you see Harrison pony thon?
Speaker 0: You saw see the very clear like the wall reference.
Speaker 1: When was that?
Speaker 0: There's that where the when the ponies are marching the way they're set up and the cadence in the animation for a minute zooms in On their legs like the hammers.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: It was pretty good.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure they were like.
Speaker 0: I will put this in here.
Speaker 0: The show, you know season two is the best that show ever had to offer.
Speaker 0: season one's rather the second best.
Speaker 0: I think the show was on this slow upward trends from season three onward.
Speaker 0: I think three was the bottom.
Speaker 1: I'm still a season one fan the most right?
Speaker 0: I think one is like 1% less good than two.
Speaker 1: I mean Sonic Rainboom is the best episode and so was the one with the dragon.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I know his best episodes.
Speaker 0: I actually a lot of the rarity episode isn't my favorite.
Speaker 1: all the all every not to say that the other ones are bad.
Speaker 0: but season one had all the things I like about season five so far.
Speaker 1: the Overall, it's season four now right?
Speaker 1: five five.
Speaker 0: Whoa Scott.
Speaker 0: You lost track of pones.
Speaker 1: Well,
Speaker 0: so one thing I liked is that the plot of this season seems to be the magic mystery map is going to send them on a whole bunch of episodic adventures Confronting direct conflicts
Speaker 1: and you know, they don't have a stupid thing at the end of every episode They have to write in a journal or
Speaker 0: right now.
Speaker 0: They are the Knights of the Round Table.
Speaker 0: like that's it.
Speaker 0: They are the authority.
Speaker 0: like when they went to this place Twilight could have just nuked it or whatever.
Speaker 0: They didn't need to like go back to Celeste you and get help.
Speaker 0: Twilight is Basically, like I don't know a level 15 mage.
Speaker 0: at this point I guess right.
Speaker 1: the one problem though is it seemed like because Twilight is so powerful They didn't they good thing.
Speaker 1: They didn't cover up the fact that she was so powerful.
Speaker 1: She tried many times to just magic the problem away directly with magic powers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean she could have nuked all right, but They kept having basically until the end.
Speaker 1: They kept having things prevent her from succeeding edges magicking the problem away And then at the end they did let her magic the problem away.
Speaker 1: He's the most satisfying but what?
Speaker 1: how are they gonna keep?
Speaker 1: are they gonna keep making excuses in every episode or are they gonna keep?
Speaker 1: Having scenarios that magic can't solve?
Speaker 1: because I can't imagine many.
Speaker 0: the problem The only problems with this episode was that they should have resorted to violence way earlier Yeah, and they fell for like baby's first trap.
Speaker 1: Well, they're not gonna.
Speaker 1: they're gonna learn and not fall for them again.
Speaker 1: Second place they got to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I also like how the villain was basically just like a minor wizard.
Speaker 1: The villain was bad.
Speaker 0: It's like a minor wizard just started.
Speaker 0: a cult is basically Scientology Bergeron off in like the boonies.
Speaker 1: It's a Trixie kind of situation, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah Trixie would not be able to pull that off though.
Speaker 1: No, but I mean that that is a problem.
Speaker 1: right is that there are people who you know There are pones out there.
Speaker 1: all these people got magic this wizards fucking everywhere.
Speaker 1: one-third of the population as far as we know is Wizards.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so someone's got to keep that shit under control.
Speaker 0: Doesn't hurt to have another even you know, I wonder what the distribution actually is of pegasi unicorn earth.
Speaker 0: I think 33 we.
Speaker 0: you could figure that out by standing like background ponies.
Speaker 1: I mean it's tough, you know, if you go to clouds Dale's like a hundred percent Pegasus, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's only one day.
Speaker 0: look at how many shit bird in Ponyville is.
Speaker 1: clearly there's Pegasus's but there's not.
Speaker 1: It's not as not thirty.
Speaker 1: It's less than thirty.
Speaker 1: three percent pegasi or a minority.
Speaker 0: Oh evil, wasn't it notable that that's one of the few places where they intermingle.
Speaker 1: It's true the capital is mostly unicorns.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and everywhere else is mostly earth pones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Ponyville seemed to have you know, not thirty three percent.
Speaker 1: it had you know more regular pones, but this yeah, there's still plenty of unicorns and You know enough pegasi in Ponyville.
Speaker 0: But I'm enjoying the fact that it's the Knights of the Round Table going on constant adventures Probably spikes pretty much not gonna be around for a while.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm sure that'll tell them to go to.
Speaker 1: you know In like the later episodes it's gonna tell them to go to Ponyville like whoa.
Speaker 0: I was gonna tell them to go to Crystal Kingdom or tell them to go Keep taking them far enough away to where they cannot easily go back home.
Speaker 0: So they're kind of like the Horatio situation.
Speaker 0: The reason the Horatio hornblower stories work is because a ship captain in the British Empire Was basically the god of his ship and him and his officer just had to deal with whatever the fuck happened out there.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, you want to go back to Britain and get help or cannonballs.
Speaker 0: That's like a month or more journey Like you can't just leave.
Speaker 0: So that could force, you know, they have to deal with things with and if you try to just leave.
Speaker 0: There's Marines on the boat also Yeah, well also like no I'm saying like the ship tries to just leave to like go and get reinforcements or supplies.
Speaker 0: It'll be a few months before you get back.
Speaker 0: and what if they?
Speaker 0: I imagine actually if they'd left this town With violence in mind Jonestown would have happened before they got back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean there's already a rebellion happening right?
Speaker 0: Well, the rebellion was pretty much quashed.
Speaker 0: I mean they knew already that they're like they were set up.
Speaker 0: there were informants everywhere.
Speaker 1: I wonder if the evil pony What was her name?
Speaker 0: She's coming back.
Speaker 1: obviously I wonder if she offed any other pones who were betraying her the while before her.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'll bet her and Trixie team up at some point.
Speaker 1: It's the same voice actor.
Speaker 1: It's pretty similar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I hope they both.
Speaker 0: they team up at some point whatever or she goes off in mines Tyrak again or whatever.
Speaker 1: Who knows the other thing?
Speaker 0: I liked the Fluttershy was totally with this cult like from the beginning.
Speaker 0: Fluttershy's like, ooh, this is nice.
Speaker 1: She just doesn't like confrontation.
Speaker 0: No So, yeah, I'm The best.
Speaker 0: actually, you know what the best pony is going on right now is still the comics but Maybe I could read those if you would find the ones that I have here.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I gotta deal with that.
Speaker 0: So in other news one of our panels anime Boston was our annual judge anime by its cover.
Speaker 0: And I want to highlight there were a few shows in this thing that at least on a surface view Actually looked like they were worth checking out.
Speaker 1: These are summer anime chart shows that we saw that we thought hey We're gonna probably watch at least the first episode maybe more.
Speaker 0: and we learned some things because at anime Boston Multiple people came up to and said yeah, we saw your thing last year in the year before.
Speaker 0: you guys are pretty much always Right.
Speaker 0: So we're pretty much batting at that.
Speaker 0: Well, we're betting 990 because we fucked up on Sailor Moon crystal.
Speaker 1: Please tell us we're serious if we fucked up anything else, but we're only just a highlight.
Speaker 0: Akagami no Shiro Yuki.
Speaker 0: He may looks okay, maybe Alright looks like a fantasy story.
Speaker 0: It has some really good allegorical style and art up here and it's bones.
Speaker 0: Okay, uh, I gotta skip down because I remember the order we did.
Speaker 0: these in some of these shows look pretty pedo Durato, but there's already.
Speaker 1: there are two that I haven't watched.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's even more.
Speaker 0: watched a couple episodes.
Speaker 0: You know what it is.
Speaker 0: It's just more Durato.
Speaker 0: Right gakko gurashi Might look stupid, but it's basically like a zombie survival show and it's got a little bit of potential.
Speaker 1: I think Mm-hmm It's not a show that looks good.
Speaker 1: It's a show that could be good in sort of a. I Don't know like it's cool like a Monica kind of way where it's like the schoolgirls, but it's not about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like it could or it could be like a Nichijou type.
Speaker 0: You know those kinds of characters in a zombie survival world, which I could dig that.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean the girl with the shovel already is gonna give you some comedy no matter what.
Speaker 0: Gangsta just looks maybe good because it looks serious and not like other shows like If it's Amazing Mangalobes doing this that gachiman crowds inside.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't I have to see gachiman crowds first.
Speaker 0: No, the only reason I bring it up is we got to see what the fuck the deal is with this because I'm getting a Project blue cheeky you vibe from it.
Speaker 1: I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: I'm getting that vibe.
Speaker 0: I'll stand by that vibe.
Speaker 0: Bad Joe bad Joe bad Joe Bad show bad show.
Speaker 0: we were not positive about a lot of shows.
Speaker 0: Bad show bad show.
Speaker 0: actually that show no bad show.
Speaker 0: I think we're done.
Speaker 0: I think I mentioned all the shows that worth watching that our movie is gonna be good movies.
Speaker 0: Ushio and Tara is getting a remake.
Speaker 0: Mappa's doing it.
Speaker 0: No one in the audience knew what Ushio and Tara was.
Speaker 0: It was a pretty good manga and an okay anime adaptation from the 90s.
Speaker 0: I think this looks pretty good.
Speaker 0: cuz Ushio and Tara was the story of a kid.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's kind of like the Tenchi plot of a kid Finds this demon that was like sealed by his grandfather or whatever with this magic spear and the demons like if you free me I'm gonna fucking eat you and he's like.
Speaker 1: then why would you say that demon?
Speaker 1: You're basically asking not to be freed.
Speaker 0: rawr I'm a D. I'm a tiger demon rawr.
Speaker 0: They fucking eat you.
Speaker 0: He's just mad.
Speaker 0: and then this other demon comes and attacks the shrine and the demons like look if you free me Fight off that other monster.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna promise I won't eat you and the kids like.
Speaker 0: what the fucking choice do I have?
Speaker 0: so he frees him, but he keeps the spear Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So now him and the demon are kind of enemies, but he's got the spear and the demons a powerful demon.
Speaker 0: So they're against each other and they're both against the other demons and that's kind of what it's like.
Speaker 0: And I think this could be pretty good.
Speaker 1: But can't the demon just take the spear cuz demon stairs?
Speaker 0: the spear is actually really powerful.
Speaker 1: So it's like you can't even go near him when he's got the spear.
Speaker 1: Uh, doesn't he have to sleep at some point?
Speaker 0: watch your show share Considerings being remade and no one's seen it.
Speaker 0: Uh, I feel like we just everyone should watch it.
Speaker 0: I think knowing nothing about the original other than what I said, there's a lot of awesome movies coming in the summer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, particularly Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 0: that sin bad actually looks like it might be pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah Give me a Horace Prince of Sun vibe Seriously though.
Speaker 0: Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 0: when I saw that coca-cola kid a tie cuz Scott just wrote it out in English.
Speaker 0: That is that's one of the few complicated kanji words that I've ever recognized in my life.
Speaker 0: Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 0: you guys don't understand how much I like Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: so in Germany during the Wehrmacht You know the Third Reich World War two the Wehrmacht had a tank that was in many ways Technologically superior to pretty much any other tank in the world at that point.
Speaker 1: What was so great about it?
Speaker 0: The Tiger tank was just better.
Speaker 0: It was it was fast.
Speaker 0: It was super heavy.
Speaker 0: It was like a heavy tank Super crazy armored.
Speaker 0: It was basically Invulnerable to many lesser tanks.
Speaker 0: in a one-on-one kind of like confrontation You just roll onto the battlefield.
Speaker 1: if you're sitting inside of it You're perfectly safe and you can blow everyone else up now.
Speaker 0: There were many problems like yeah, the tiger tanks were amazing.
Speaker 0: Germany couldn't build that many of them let alone train enough crews for them and Because they were so technologically advanced they required a lot of complicated maintenance that became increasingly difficult as the war went on.
Speaker 0: So yeah, they had a few thousand like uber tanks.
Speaker 1: I was honored.
Speaker 0: America had Millions of shitty shirt will not millions but so many sherms like yeah, we lost ten in that battle But you lost your one Tiger tank.
Speaker 0: we came out ahead.
Speaker 1: I always wonder right what if Hitler was still Hitler but Minus the genocide part like he was just okay with all the people who lived in Germany and still tried to take over Europe.
Speaker 1: What about?
Speaker 0: basically one of the main reasons he reduced unemployment was by kicking all the Jews out of all their jobs and giving those Non-jews right, but he would just you know, employ the Jews give them jobs making tiger tanks just everyone in Germany.
Speaker 1: I don't care who you are.
Speaker 1: So you really gonna work together and be fascist, you know take over Europe.
Speaker 0: how many?
Speaker 0: Assassination attempts there were on Hitler by people who were like we want to be fascist Nazis But we need to cut down on the genocide and not invade Russia.
Speaker 0: There were so many attempts on his life.
Speaker 0: In fact, there was one dude who was like fuck it I'll suicide bombing because this shit's gotta end.
Speaker 0: So he put a chemical fuse for ten minutes In a bomb that he had on him met with Hitler.
Speaker 0: Hitler like called the meeting short and left early and he had to run to a bathroom and defuse the thing.
Speaker 0: The same bomb was then used to try to kill Hitler again.
Speaker 0: It was put on a plane with him, I guess and it just fucking didn't go off.
Speaker 1: All the alternate history like, you know, what's that guy who always writes the the Turtle dove right that guy?
Speaker 1: and also things like command and conquer red alert and you know These sorts of things are always like.
Speaker 1: what if Hitler got killed?
Speaker 1: What if this happened?
Speaker 1: What if that happened?
Speaker 1: the good news?
Speaker 1: I've never seen what would happen if Hitler was less evil because I guess no one wants to portray Hitler is less evil.
Speaker 1: But maybe you could just do the story as Hitler got killed.
Speaker 0: Hermann Gurne because right I've been reading a lot about world We're not.
Speaker 1: and Jew liking fascists ran Germany instead and they took over Europe.
Speaker 0: What's interesting though is so there's this two-sided view of the German military during the wehrmacht because on one hand They were like the troops that were like the stormtroopers were so technologically and tactically and just materially advanced compared to the armors they were fighting
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: The rest of the army was actually still like horse-drawn non mechanized Shittier than much of the rest of the world.
Speaker 0: So there's.
Speaker 0: it's a complication.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it's not.
Speaker 1: Anime otaku is usually military otaku.
Speaker 0: So that is true.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 0: What was that one show for summer?
Speaker 0: That's basically a member of the school.
Speaker 0: through and find it who is also an otaku Gets transported to a fantasy world got it Military guy right in the middle of the picture and he uses his fantasy and otaku and military knowledge combined to save the day.
Speaker 0: I Already give up on it.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: There it is gate.
Speaker 0: Jita J Tanochi nita kaku tata kek tata Kyra.
Speaker 0: some crazy Japanese fuck this show.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah So it's basic.
Speaker 0: if the tiger tank was notable for another reason the tiger done with military fanboy parts.
Speaker 0: This is my my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Oh, my thing of the day is this thing the tiger tank had possibly the best User manual ever written for anything into that point in the world.
Speaker 0: Yes It's in German the tiger feeble the tiger feeble or or tiger primer the tiger feeble Has cartoons in it.
Speaker 0: It has racy humor.
Speaker 0: It has.
Speaker 0: there's these characters and comics and poems.
Speaker 1: are they trying to copy Will Eisner's like service manuals?
Speaker 0: So basically the idea was that this thing had to act like they expected everyone who ran a tiger tank to actually fucking read This thing and know how to run the tiger tank.
Speaker 0: really well The tiger feeble is an amazing work to behold.
Speaker 0: watch check this shit out And if you're ever after write technical documentation kind of like how you know Network like the corporate or like sponsored type media like the Twitter accounts that succeed are the ones that are kind of real.
Speaker 0: and Like Sarah like funny and snarky and just.
Speaker 0: you know tell you like it is.
Speaker 0: The tiger feeble was that this shit is amazing and it was so successful That then later they made the Panther feeble for the Panther tanks and I'll like Many people who write about it make a point of saying this was actually written for Approved by the Wehrmacht.
Speaker 0: like this is official.
Speaker 0: It's amazing.
Speaker 1: If you like that sort of thing, you should check out preventative maintenance monthly, which is when Will Eisner was in the military.
Speaker 0: Oh, I think we made that a thing of the day at one point.
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: mean this, you know, Will Eisner basically made this monthly Effectively comic book magazine that told you how to prevent it, you know all about preventative maintenance of US military equipment during the war and It's prides, you know, that's not bad, but it's it's not as doesn't have a good name as the tiger feeble
Speaker 0: Tiger feeble, but it's
Speaker 1: but it's.
Speaker 1: you know, the tiger feeble is no Will Eisner There's a lot of naked ladies in it, too, which is you don't think Will Eisner ever drew a naked lady?
Speaker 0: No, I'm just saying the tiger feeble is pretty has a better name.
Speaker 1: Let's check the tiger feeble out So you got a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I do so, you know.
Speaker 1: We usually you know, we're not like big fans of like the violent real-world sports here, you know It's not like we're following the MMA's of the boxing or anything like that.
Speaker 0: But I guess I love out you.
Speaker 0: the unstated assumption is that hockey and spin football are not violent.
Speaker 1: not not.
Speaker 1: They're not just about violence, right?
Speaker 1: They just have violence.
Speaker 0: That's modern.
Speaker 0: Hockey is not about violence.
Speaker 1: That's correct It's true.
Speaker 1: an Olympic hockey is the best hockey which is very devoid of violence.
Speaker 0: But there was an era of hockey where violence anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Thanks, Philadelphia.
Speaker 1: But sometimes there is a notable Occurrence in the violent sports, you know, especially the MMA's and when there is it spreads around the internet To the eyeballs of people who can appreciate it, which is almost everybody.
Speaker 1: So this can be appreciated by everyone.
Speaker 1: Some 62 year old dude is in this MMA fight against a much younger individual.
Speaker 1: It doesn't seem like it's some sort of major big-time fight, but it's not small time.
Speaker 1: That's like a real-deal ring.
Speaker 1: Not some backyard junk place.
Speaker 1: There's real people watching.
Speaker 1: You know, this is like.
Speaker 1: You know, it's.
Speaker 1: it's almost like us at a convention panel compared to famous person at San Diego Comic Con.
Speaker 1: of that, you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so 62 year old dude fights much younger dude in MMA and I'm guessing you know What the result is.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, this wouldn't be a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: If the 62 year old dude just got the shit kicked out of him We wouldn't be discussing it because it would just be horrible.
Speaker 0: In the moment the booklet book is still watershed down It is a story about rabbits.
Speaker 0: also.
Speaker 0: You should totally check out our other show.
Speaker 0: geek nice presents shoujo kakumei you Tena.
Speaker 0: We did a panel at anime Boston where we talked about analyzing anime and we used do Tena as our example.
Speaker 0: It was crazy popular.
Speaker 0: the panel.
Speaker 0: Like I'm not like people really really liked.
Speaker 1: every panel is too popular.
Speaker 0: Yes, the one we did at midnight 30 had.
Speaker 1: I was hoping no one would show up so I can go to bed But they showed up.
Speaker 0: most of the panel was Scott every few minutes being like it's 1 30 with a fuck Are you still here?
Speaker 1: Jesus Christ I'm still feeling it from then.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I need to go to bed but all we did in this panel at the end was watch three and a half minutes of footage from utenna and Pause it periodically and point that only after every single line of dialogue.
Speaker 0: Yes, because the show is that thick We this show is.
Speaker 0: I was doing that for every single fucking episode of utenna and I the shows we're doing.
Speaker 0: this is a really Good thing we're doing.
Speaker 0: and if you have never won if you've never seen utenna and you listen to geek nights Wednesdays That's really I mean one of our friends just started watching utenna.
Speaker 0: what the recently?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and two if you've seen utenna so late to the party shows in the early 90s guys Yeah, next thing, you know, people are gonna be like Oh door die.
Speaker 0: So sauce and what's that?
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: And also, uh, a lot of people came up to us like enough people to wear like it's notable.
Speaker 0: Well a lot.
Speaker 0: so like maybe three or four people Pointedly said that they saw the panel We sent to anime Boston on that DVD when Pax anime Boston were the same weekend that one time They saw it at anime Boston.
Speaker 0: They finally met us in person.
Speaker 0: They wanted to thank us for showing them the way in terms of how shitty panels can be and how to not be that guy.
Speaker 0: So yeah, watch our shit on YouTube.
Speaker 0: We're fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: Also This weekend like that lack of humbleness.
Speaker 1: No Also this weekend is the mocha festival.
Speaker 1: it moved.
Speaker 1: It's not in the armory It's elsewhere in the city.
Speaker 1: go to their website to figure out where it is.
Speaker 0: We'll be there.
Speaker 1: We're gonna pick one of the two days and go.
Speaker 1: which day should we go?
Speaker 1: Saturday?
Speaker 0: We'll figure it out cuz Emily might have to do Sunday fill-in chair coming for the weekend to go to it.
Speaker 0: I don't know when we'll go.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll go one of the two days.
Speaker 0: We'll figure it out tonight.
Speaker 0: half the people are gonna go with us are coming home tonight for our GTR party.
Speaker 1: Sure I Don't know.
Speaker 1: Uh, the next convention is all the way at Canada con.
Speaker 1: So enjoy your warm weather summer spring thing.
Speaker 0: Oh my god convention season is over.
Speaker 1: Oh, ah At least for us there's plenty of conventions to go.
Speaker 0: Never thought I'd get to a point in a life where I said I want to go to conventions.
Speaker 1: There's plenty to go to.
Speaker 1: we just won't be there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we went to Zenkaikan and anime Boston.
Speaker 0: Well Scott had to skip Zenkaikan for sad reasons, but I went and Scott went to the previous Zenkaikan.
Speaker 0: So he's been there.
Speaker 0: He knows the drill, right?
Speaker 1: So I actually didn't want to go to the Zenkaikan because I really needed the weekend and it's like yeah No offense to Zenkaikan It's not.
Speaker 0: I mean we just don't bail on things that we've committed to.
Speaker 0: But I really wanted to be home that weekend for personal reasons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just didn't want to go to Zenkaikan, but you did end up going.
Speaker 1: Should did I if I could have gone?
Speaker 1: would I have wanted to go?
Speaker 0: you would had a good time.
Speaker 0: it was interesting because You know, we go to a lot of cons and there's kind of this, you know This is sort of a episode more for people who've listened to geek nights.
Speaker 0: a lot because we used to go to a lot of Anime cons very few gaming cons.
Speaker 1: There weren't that many gaming cons.
Speaker 1: The only gaming con that can't that we started going to his packs.
Speaker 0: it just happens to be that there's like four of them and we fucking loved anime cons and we went to a Lot of anime con most of them and the product.
Speaker 0: what happened was we went to one packs.
Speaker 0: We came home and we were like, wow, and I saw magfest almost all shit.
Speaker 0: and we went to magfest for like wow Yeah, anime cons and most gaming cons are shit.
Speaker 1: The big problem that anime cons have in general is not that they're bad It's that as so if you are not a person who can find something to enjoy and do During that whole weekend that you're there you spend a lot of time doing nothing Whereas at a gaming con you can always bail to tabletop.
Speaker 0: Yep So this is something that that have or other gaming areas PC.
Speaker 0: There's another factor Any con is fun if enough of your friends go and They're actually your super close friends that you would like hang around like late at night in your own hotel rooms with Mm-hmm, like your like friends.
Speaker 1: You don't even need the convention for that.
Speaker 0: So yeah, but it gives you context because the thing is here at a con means you all hang out and make messes But you're not in anyone's house for those messes.
Speaker 1: So consider, you know an artist's alley, right?
Speaker 1: Okay, so I go to a con by myself.
Speaker 1: I go the artist's alley.
Speaker 1: What can I do there?
Speaker 1: I can buy stuff and look at arts.
Speaker 1: if I have a person with me now, I can increase that.
Speaker 0: enjoy Scott.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, look at that art right there.
Speaker 0: like that.
Speaker 1: It's like a third person who saw the artist's alley without us.
Speaker 1: They all gonna come up to me later.
Speaker 1: Like did you see that thing?
Speaker 1: It's like no I missed that shit.
Speaker 1: I guess you better go back and look at it cuz he totally missed it.
Speaker 1: All right This thing I bought you this, you know.
Speaker 1: suddenly stuff sir more people you bring with you Multiplies the amount of enjoyment you can extract from a specific thing at a convention.
Speaker 0: So here's our side.
Speaker 1: as a limit to it.
Speaker 0: Obviously we went to a ton of anime cons.
Speaker 0: lot of our close friends went to anime cons.
Speaker 0: anime cons were a thing for us.
Speaker 0: We went to a Pax.
Speaker 0: we said holy fuck the next year we got a like.
Speaker 0: we got a bunch of our friends to go to a Pax and Then all our friends said wow fuck anime cons.
Speaker 0: and overnight Almost everyone we used to go to anime cons with started going to only Pax's and mag fests.
Speaker 0: They literally dropped Every anime convention that.
Speaker 0: these are people who'd gone to Otacon ten years in a row who suddenly just dropped it overnight Because they'd been to a Pax and a mag fest.
Speaker 0: Yep, and these people are super anime fans, too Like don't?
Speaker 1: they're watching anime all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah every season watching anime.
Speaker 0: They just don't go to anime cons.
Speaker 0: So now if I go to an anime con like we have friends there like an anime Boston we had like a bunch of like friends
Speaker 1: a lot of people there that we knew who they were and they knew us and we Ate together and hung out and spent time together.
Speaker 0: But our crew like the crew of people what with I've gone to cons for ten years with was not there.
Speaker 0: so All the time between hanging out with those friends like con friends and running our panels There's maybe two and a half hours of content total that are worthwhile to us Other than Mike Tool's stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah walk around the dealers room once.
Speaker 1: Mike Tool had two panels.
Speaker 1: He went to one of them.
Speaker 1: Yep Walk around the artists alley once walk around the convention once and Do our panels.
Speaker 0: but meanwhile Zenkai con the core crew went.
Speaker 1: Our core crew was there because some of them are running it.
Speaker 0: Yes So as a result, I spent most the con hanging around in bars and restaurants outside of the con with really close friends Just drinking and playing.
Speaker 1: There's nothing about Zenkai con itself.
Speaker 1: if we're talking to these people listening to the show They need to know about the convention.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the convention go to it if it's closed.
Speaker 0: if I if I could drive to it an hour I just go to it no matter what.
Speaker 1: that's true for almost any convention.
Speaker 0: Yes, and I'll probably go next year Cuz I actually really good time Partly because I gotta say about Zenkai con.
Speaker 1: Well anything notable happened there.
Speaker 1: Were there any notable panels events?
Speaker 0: I did not go to any event that I did not run.
Speaker 1: Okay, were there any notable like rooms?
Speaker 1: Like was the artist alley?
Speaker 0: good dealers room good like the artist alley was the same as last year.
Speaker 1: nice and tiny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like good, but good quality.
Speaker 1: increase the size of it.
Speaker 1: since last year Even though the convention grew.
Speaker 0: now cuz the space is pretty much the space they fill this convention center.
Speaker 0: Okay, but I mean the con was the same as what you experienced in every way you can think of.
Speaker 0: The only thing that was different at all is they had a room dedicated to Artemis which was just kind of cool.
Speaker 0: All right, a lot of conventions doing that days and there's fucking nowhere to eat food in Lancaster.
Speaker 1: True the same as last time.
Speaker 0: the worst thing is it was restaurant week there.
Speaker 0: So the few restaurants they had were full of townies townies And so we went off to this townie restaurant that was kept pretty far away from the con cuz we all heard Alright, if we go to a place is way far away from the con town only locals would eat there.
Speaker 0: How could it be full?
Speaker 0: we went there full?
Speaker 0: It wasn't that full.
Speaker 0: Oh disgusting.
Speaker 0: the owner Really didn't seem to want to let us into his restaurant Like he was really grumpy and surly.
Speaker 0: it was like kind of trying to passive-aggressively make us go away.
Speaker 1: Okay, and then as we want more money.
Speaker 0: So then as we walked out I saw a big sign and the sign said no cell phones.
Speaker 0: No cussing.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, I had a lot of cell phones and cussing.
Speaker 0: We were basically all standing there looking at our cell phones and cussing.
Speaker 0: Well, one of us is trying to negotiate like no we can split up into different tables, it's fine, dude Just like we'll just take those tables there.
Speaker 0: It's fine, dude it will sit down.
Speaker 0: or.
Speaker 0: And also I looked up at his beer menu and it pretty much consisted of like four bottle beers and like butt on tap.
Speaker 0: Okay, so, uh, yeah But here's the notable thing about zinc icon because this is all The things that are notable about zinc icon this year are the same things that were notable about anime Boston.
Speaker 0: the academic and For-real panels are having a huge uptick in terms of people going to see them.
Speaker 1: Okay, that's nice.
Speaker 0: You saw that anime Boston like Mike tool was like my 10 a.m Friday panel was full and we were like, yeah our like Mid-eleven at night panel on Friday is full like people are being turned away Like the panels that were actually good with good to good content full.
Speaker 0: Yep, and That has not been the case Previously at anime cons.
Speaker 0: for us like this is a trend now, right?
Speaker 1: So let's have anime Boston which I did go to.
Speaker 1: yeah It's an anime.
Speaker 1: Boston had problems talking about just the convention not our personal deal of going there without people.
Speaker 1: Yeah The convention itself the way I see it.
Speaker 1: It did an amazing job within horrible conditions.
Speaker 0: Yes, like Boston basically fucks anime Boston.
Speaker 1: like Boston is doing everything it can to hurt anime Boston.
Speaker 0: It's like the security thing is just as awful as it was before Alright, and it's very telling how much worse it is for AB than it is for packs because packs has the cloud to force Boston to back off a little bit.
Speaker 1: anime boss Oh can't force him to back off enough, but they back off more sure.
Speaker 1: But it's basically like not just the security but like just the conditions under which anime Boston is existing Right are just not good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like Boston prevents them from doing their dance.
Speaker 0: There was cops fucking Everywhere.
Speaker 1: Security checks at the door.
Speaker 0: the convention center staff this year.
Speaker 0: We're surly as fuck Mm-hmm, like like notably surly and let me tell you we have a high tolerance for surly convention center staff.
Speaker 1: Yep, the Sheraton hotel that is attached to anime boss.
Speaker 0: Fuck never stay there.
Speaker 1: They had a big problem.
Speaker 1: This is the elevators are a big problem.
Speaker 1: They couldn't even check people in as fast as they could.
Speaker 0: our and 45 minute way to check into your hotel Right now.
Speaker 1: that wasn't anime Boston's fun.
Speaker 0: None of these things are anime Boston's.
Speaker 1: basically within this framework of bad things happening around it Anime Boston itself is doing a great job of being anime Boston.
Speaker 1: They mostly anime content almost all anime content, even though there's some non right Every.
Speaker 1: there's just Pete tons and tons of people.
Speaker 1: It was probably the most crowded highest Attendance anime boss they've ever seen.
Speaker 0: the crowds were like really well-behaved like no weird shit was going on.
Speaker 0: Marco Polo was existent, but there's this great moment where I think was on Friday night.
Speaker 0: We heard somebody yell Marco and somebody else that shut the fuck up and then it was quiet Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And yeah, like the Marco Polo is not really that tolerated anymore and there's still a few punk kids, you know But not too many.
Speaker 1: the artists alley very high.
Speaker 1: I guess the art show is down, but that's your choice Boston's fault.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be really really real.
Speaker 0: there was almost nothing notable in the art show, but it's not anime Boston's.
Speaker 0: It's like saying oh you didn't have any good panels like at a con.
Speaker 0: it's like well what was submitted?
Speaker 1: Let's put some stuff in that art show next year.
Speaker 0: You're out of light.
Speaker 1: I'll just draw.
Speaker 0: you remember the rod of light?
Speaker 1: Yes, I'm just gonna draw like a spirit to me or something.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna draw a Baron, okay But yeah.
Speaker 1: So the one especially notable thing about anime Boston was it in the Sheraton Hotel on the fifth floor?
Speaker 1: Where the swimming pool is and the gym and other weird stuff.
Speaker 1: there were some rooms and they got these rooms.
Speaker 1: They basically got every room they possibly could in the area.
Speaker 0: Yeah This is like there are people's like regular hotel rooms and then there's these like low ceiling conference room, right?
Speaker 1: So they got these more rooms just to get more rooms and in those rooms they put Foundations of anime.
Speaker 1: is the foundations of anime area.
Speaker 1: This is in a hotel attached to the convention center on a weird fifth floor.
Speaker 1: That's hard to get to it hard to even know it exists.
Speaker 1: Yet we went up there to see what the deal was.
Speaker 1: because we had so much time We want to see every part of the convention place was rocking.
Speaker 1: It was full.
Speaker 1: There was a mythology and anime panel that was starting as we were leaving.
Speaker 1: that had any full line going all the way out And down the stairs and was a big problem.
Speaker 0: There was a guy who did a panel on like Gundam shorts.
Speaker 1: through the guys.
Speaker 1: There was a the panel on Gundam shorts.
Speaker 1: I get I've go to peek in and it looks like he's a that guy.
Speaker 1: But he's not.
Speaker 1: he's just the guy who's way into Gundam But it's totally normal and chill and he's showing these Gundam shorts that are all amazing many of which I hadn't seen.
Speaker 1: only one.
Speaker 0: What was he doing?
Speaker 0: He was he was explaining what their deal wasn't giving context.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I knew what he was talking.
Speaker 1: There are some Gundam fanboys in the crowd but most were not super fanboys and the room was mostly full in his weird area and It was pretty terrific.
Speaker 1: Yeah The other panel next door looked great too.
Speaker 0: Three years ago if you had told me this was going to exist in anime Boston I would have said that's a bad idea.
Speaker 0: one person will find this place This you like.
Speaker 0: I am so happy that people were up there and the people who were there It's kind of like it packs go over to the panel rooms.
Speaker 0: We're like game design stuff is going on Very different crowd from the kinds of people are in the expo hall and anime Boston.
Speaker 0: the kinds of people who are in this area Were our kinds of people you know me chill conversations.
Speaker 0: We have the strangers the likes of which I cannot have with strangers and other parts of anime cons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the hotels like little office He area was also there.
Speaker 1: so I was sitting in one of the office He chairs next to the rented computer that I wasn't using.
Speaker 1: yup And it's like this people hanging out there like eating lunch, and they had seen our panel and they were totally chill.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like oh hey you guys did that panel on that.
Speaker 0: that was super awesome.
Speaker 0: I just wanted to say I don't want to intrude, but you did a really good job, and they walked away, and I was like That's what happens at Pax's.
Speaker 0: that's happening at an anime con now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like anime Boston is like Totally rockin just within these bad conditions of stupid hotel and stupid Boston.
Speaker 0: yup And like seriously Go back.
Speaker 0: yeah our panels like filled standing room only people being turned away people Exceeding the fire code like going nuts.
Speaker 1: I think I want to go back and just do way more panels.
Speaker 0: I'll submit as many panels as you know because we have to do at least four because of the like.
Speaker 1: the panelists I'd submit like six or eight or something I would.
Speaker 1: I will do as long as long as a bunch of them are easy to do and they don't get scheduled for 1232 - I was fine with that because a lot of people is not fine with that because I didn't go to sleep.
Speaker 0: yeah Well, we didn't have any panels on Sunday if we get a 1230.
Speaker 1: if they'd given us the schedule earlier I could have gotten a later trip home and slept in and then wouldn't fine.
Speaker 0: We could have gotten a later trip home and slept in if we weren't just paranoid and gotten up way too fucking early on Sunday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean if we do eight panels.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's someone will be on Sunday, so we have to you know.
Speaker 0: So I've realized now I will continue to go to cons like Zank icon because my My core core friends will get drunk with me and hang out any convention no matter how shitty if you got friends there.
Speaker 0: Yes, okay, and I will continue to go to anime cons as because the the only problem is other than like Mike tools stuff And that floor five we didn't go to any panel content except the things.
Speaker 1: usually we go to the concert.
Speaker 1: But the concerts this year were Lisa who I don't know if she's good or not But she basically does anime theme songs, and they're not animes I know.
Speaker 1: so I didn't care and front a lot who I've seen six or seven time.
Speaker 0: I know I've seen front a lot so many times I think I made at this point.
Speaker 1: I may have seen MC front a lot more than any other musical act on earth.
Speaker 1: He just goes to all the same.
Speaker 0: I may have seen Paul and storm more times.
Speaker 0: technically.
Speaker 1: Maybe you did see them a time when front a lot was not there.
Speaker 0: yes And I have skipped front a lot in the past just because his concert was on the day I didn't want to go to a concert at a PAX.
Speaker 1: It would be tough to count.
Speaker 0: yeah Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Well can you add in the times that I saw front a lot like he is having a concert and I was there.
Speaker 1: But I didn't actually like stand at the concert like those CES right.
Speaker 1: No it wasn't CES.
Speaker 1: It was like it was like fake CES in the Javits.
Speaker 0: Oh, what was that called?
Speaker 0: I know what you're talking about that.
Speaker 1: yeah, and it's like I was just walking around looking at the booths and then leaving and I front a lot was just like they're doing his thing.
Speaker 1: This is before I ever went to PAX and Like six people were watching him.
Speaker 1: But he was.
Speaker 1: he was acting like it was a full crowd like he should like.
Speaker 1: yeah like you do cuz he's pro And I just saw him from afar, and I'm like is that front a lot.
Speaker 1: I guess it is wow that's sad.
Speaker 1: He's he's rapping to nobody.
Speaker 1: That's all right.
Speaker 1: I listened to him for like a minute and then kept walking.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the the only reason that we want to talk about these cons.
Speaker 0: Oh, here's the other weird thing We noticed and Scott you'll bag me up on this and I will say this is a hundred percent true for Zenkai Con 2 Fursuits like full-on.
Speaker 0: I am a furry with a capital S fursuit Way up like there is a trend.
Speaker 1: I mean I don't want you to.
Speaker 1: I don't want you to be imagining that It's like 25% fursuits right no But it is like usually when you go 120% increase in fursuits.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: usually when you go to a con like this like you go To magfest they'll be like two fursuits, and you see the same two going around.
Speaker 1: yeah You go to kinetic on.
Speaker 1: it's like five fursuits, and you see them because they stand out so much.
Speaker 1: There's a big.
Speaker 1: you see them, and then you can recognize them when you see them again.
Speaker 1: So it's very easy for anyone who goes to a convention for all the full weekend.
Speaker 1: if you move around and don't stay in one Spot.
Speaker 1: you have a pretty accurate count of unique fursuits.
Speaker 0: I think there were more than 40 at this anime, Boston.
Speaker 0: I know it was.
Speaker 1: it was a number that was quite significant to where I did not see like the same one twice very often And I was rarely in a place where I saw zero at a time.
Speaker 1: There was usually one like in every place.
Speaker 1: So I were.
Speaker 0: so what?
Speaker 0: this is what we wonder Why and we're not like.
Speaker 0: we're not saying like.
Speaker 0: I don't care like it's cool because the thing is the really high quality To the what I mean.
Speaker 1: a full body fursuit is rarely low quality.
Speaker 0: They were easy to make what they used to be rare to see.
Speaker 0: so I'm wondering.
Speaker 0: I have a few theories either.
Speaker 0: one furry cons are going the way of Sci-fi cons meeting the way of guy trying to blow up the con.
Speaker 0: yes Astronomicons meaning everyone there is 48 years or older obese and a pedophile.
Speaker 0: Maybe that is.
Speaker 0: so maybe young cool art kids are like they go to one Like people go to one sci-fi con and they go oh shit, and then they never go back.
Speaker 0: But they've got this fursuit.
Speaker 0: so they go to the anime con like maybe they're just going to anime cons now Maybe.
Speaker 0: so maybe those cons are just all exploding Disappearing collapsing.
Speaker 0: who knows?
Speaker 0: maybe young nerd kids just don't care about their nerder being out there anymore.
Speaker 1: I'm sure the listener is intelligent enough to speculate on the all possible reasons for an increase in freedom And we don't need to just tell them the speculations.
Speaker 1: They could make on their own.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm curious though I want you guys to tell us speculation.
Speaker 1: right I do.
Speaker 1: I want to hear speculations that I haven't thought of But also I want to hear some.
Speaker 1: you know anyone with knowledge of?
Speaker 1: I know there are people who listen to have furry knowledge is Furry-up, I need to know the furry weather report.
Speaker 0: yes because it's a red There's there's the tide is rising in the harbor right now on nerdery in Jen.
Speaker 1: I can see it's like.
Speaker 1: I can see that it's raining more now, but that doesn't tell me about tomorrow's weather.
Speaker 0: Yeah Right so look at it.
Speaker 0: So here's that there's the con weather report anime con weather report.
Speaker 0: anime Boston in content in particular, I can't say this about other anime cons has Consistently been getting better and better and better over everything.
Speaker 0: it has control over the anime Boston staff Every year.
Speaker 0: make things better and the con is on this upper trajectory.
Speaker 0: anime con attendees across the board are in an upper trajectory of being more interested in the Academic good content less interested in the bullshit even if they're not overall more interested.
Speaker 1: There are more people who are interested such that those Panels and things fill up or a very crowded and well attended because it's
Speaker 0: not just that everything was filling because we can't Peek in our heads in on all the other
Speaker 1: like there's a panel before us Which is a very nice well-done generic cosplay like how to be a cosplay business
Speaker 0: Pro yeah,
Speaker 1: but very poor attendance like
Speaker 0: 12 people are in the audience.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Basically universally most of the panels we looked in that weren't like Mike tool mostly empty Mm-hmm, but see.
Speaker 0: but yeah all the academic stuff super full.
Speaker 0: So rising tide there and furry is also a rising tide of the anime kind.
Speaker 1: and one more thing I want to say about anime Boston which differentiates it from other anime cons And they've always done this but they're doing it even more is every year They have a theme and they go all-in on that theme.
Speaker 0: and this Was so good the way they did the theme this year.
Speaker 1: the theme was such an excellent theme.
Speaker 1: It was mecha's verse kaiju.
Speaker 1: so they could integrate both at once.
Speaker 1: right it would have been easy to just be like mecha.
Speaker 0: But oh yeah, and their guests they had two of the Godzilla people right.
Speaker 1: so if you watch the original Gojira the very very first one from the olden days the guy who was in the Godzilla suit and also in the suit for like most of the movies that happened after that he was there and So was the main actor human guy right?
Speaker 1: You know he was also there.
Speaker 1: How am I supposed to remember these?
Speaker 0: I don't remember his name either.
Speaker 1: He if I when I'm his main human character from the original gods at Godzilla who was also in some other Godzilla movies.
Speaker 1: He was also there.
Speaker 0: He was wearing this amazing suit.
Speaker 1: He was like Japanese mr.. Hollywood.
Speaker 0: yes, and the first question his answer was basically all.
Speaker 0: it was all about Japan being nuked And the dangers that like the whole nuclear horror.
Speaker 0: It was just a great answer.
Speaker 0: also I think he's sexually attracted to Mothra like so am I.
Speaker 1: so we have something in kinda like.
Speaker 0: he was joking obviously But it was funny to see how he joked about Mothra and the audience laugh, and then he just kept Escalating the joke and he can't.
Speaker 0: he got to the point.
Speaker 0: We started doing it in English just to get.
Speaker 1: even a lot of people had their cameras out for this panel.
Speaker 1: I'm sure you could find video of it.
Speaker 0: It was pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah Autograph signing Distantly also does a good job of getting a good mix of guests.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean who would even think to get those people, but as soon as I realized that they were there I'm going to fucking see fucking went and stood in line Seeing that again.
Speaker 1: Uh so yeah.
Speaker 1: But you know they always decorate the hallways with the theme and they do all sorts of stuff with the theme and all of it Was really good.
Speaker 0: Yeah as usual, so hopefully we'll see you guys to anime Boston 2016 mm-hmm, and I'm hungry.
Speaker 0: I'm also super hungry.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website Front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: My baby you don't know how much I love you behind of you Cods always look the front to get to dream in future.
Speaker 0: My baby you don't know whether you'll be with the Nazi dance.
Speaker 0: It's lonely like a bird, but it's really feel like fun.
Speaker 0: I know I just don't fail with.
Speaker 0: it's okay.
Speaker 0: You can go to Everywhere.
Speaker 1: I've been my love Baby.