Speaker 1: let's do this.
Speaker 2: so I saw you did like a 60 70 mile bike to rock away this weekend.
Speaker 1: no biked everywhere.
Speaker 1: yeah nothing else to do.
Speaker 2: yeah because I ended up going to the shore Wildwood and while we were there our friends Chris and Anthony were there and we played that Kickstarter game Scoville.
Speaker 1: no based on peppers.
Speaker 2: yes you breed peppers and you cross breed them and there's different kinds of peppers.
Speaker 2: so I'm not gonna fully review it because Scott's got to play it all bunch and you gotta play it more but you should have to eat peppers to play the game.
Speaker 1: then it would be a good game right?
Speaker 2: that would be interesting.
Speaker 1: if the pepper you at the end of each turn whoever has the lowest number of points must eat one of their peppers or something like that.
Speaker 2: so the gist of it the way it works is that basically you plant peppers like you play.
Speaker 2: everyone plants a pepper like somewhere on the board and then to harvest you walk along the path.
Speaker 2: there's a shared space in the middle and you walk three spaces.
Speaker 2: I've seen mechanics like that and ever you crop but you don't walk like square to square.
Speaker 2: you walk along the edges of where the peppers are and you collect the pepper that would be bred by the peppers on either side of each space.
Speaker 2: so there's a ghost pepper next to a white pepper.
Speaker 2: then I think daddy gets two white peppers.
Speaker 2: or if there's a red pepper and a red pepper get two red peppers but a red and a green or a red and a blue I think makes a brown.
Speaker 2: there's like seven eight.
Speaker 2: now there's like ten or eleven different kinds of peppers mm-hmm and it was a pretty good game.
Speaker 2: I'm actually kind of into it.
Speaker 2: now I gotta play it again though we were kind of in a hurry to get on the road to beat the traffic back to New York because we played it on Sunday like right before we left mm-hmm.
Speaker 2: but I feel like this game might be up our alley and I might acquire a copy of it.
Speaker 1: you acquire all the stuff you want in your house.
Speaker 2: oh you're done buying board games.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be selling a lot of stuff.
Speaker 1: I need room.
Speaker 2: yeah thing is very few.
Speaker 2: the board games I own I'm kind of willing.
Speaker 2: the only game I still own that I'm willing to part with is Gloria Mundi because that game is kind of just bad like.
Speaker 1: really I have games that you know don't get played and I don't really care.
Speaker 2: do you own it?
Speaker 2: you know the clips right.
Speaker 1: I got an eclipse but I'll keep my clip.
Speaker 2: oh oh but when are you gonna play that again?
Speaker 1: I'll play it.
Speaker 2: when it was the last time you opened that eclipse I don't know.
Speaker 1: but you never know what an eclipse will happen.
Speaker 2: yeah we should just start playing some eclipse.
Speaker 1: but I got games like lahav and which is not a you know.
Speaker 1: okay like turning taxes like these are not bad games but I'm not gonna play them and they're taking up a lot of space relative.
Speaker 1: yeah you know what I realize.
Speaker 2: those are the kinds of games that I kind of would want to keep like I have Puerto Rico.
Speaker 1: I got T&E.
Speaker 2: I'm good but they're good games to own as like a collection of.
Speaker 2: like you have a board game night.
Speaker 2: you're like all right.
Speaker 2: here's it.
Speaker 2: here's the game you guys have never played.
Speaker 1: oh you want him then.
Speaker 2: but that sentiment only applied when I lived in a house.
Speaker 1: yeah you want you want those games now that I live in an apartment.
Speaker 2: no you want you want Gloria Mundi.
Speaker 2: no I will keep to call though.
Speaker 1: cuz oh wait Gloria Mundi which one's that?
Speaker 2: the one do you really don't remember?
Speaker 1: is that?
Speaker 1: is that the one with the god chasing you is the gods chasing you.
Speaker 1: oh you should play that.
Speaker 2: that game sucks though?
Speaker 1: no it doesn't.
Speaker 2: you don't remember playing it?
Speaker 1: don't remember?
Speaker 1: it was kind of fun.
Speaker 1: run away from the god.
Speaker 2: yeah there that was fun but the actual game just came down to you.
Speaker 2: always pay the god.
Speaker 1: well it wasn't.
Speaker 1: let's pay it again one more time as I can remember.
Speaker 2: I think the last time we played it was a New Year's party maybe but I forgot about those.
Speaker 2: I could get it out.
Speaker 2: we could play it again if we're.
Speaker 2: the thing is if we play it again and do a show on it we're also getting up.
Speaker 1: you did show in it like a hundred years ago.
Speaker 2: how about this though cuz you seem to have fonder memories of it than I do.
Speaker 2: let's bust out to call and Gloria Mundi.
Speaker 1: but it calls okay game.
Speaker 2: yeah let's play each once and then review them again.
Speaker 1: there's nothing wrong with the car.
Speaker 2: yeah but see like the last time I played to call was actually a long time ago I wonder what if my opinion will change you just having walk around digging up pyramids?
Speaker 2: yeah put your own machine gun guy on top of the one most valuable pyramid right.
Speaker 2: go after the tents.
Speaker 2: except no the tents are never good.
Speaker 1: I hope the volcano shows up at the good time for you.
Speaker 2: yeah.
Speaker 2: so uh yeah the main thing going on right now that's been going on for a while it's over now.
Speaker 2: yeah I guess it's completely over right?
Speaker 2: I yeah I'll get second.
Speaker 2: I guess that was the last day.
Speaker 2: yes as usual it's the miracle.
Speaker 2: we have enough energy to do blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 2: so yeah summer games done quick.
Speaker 2: the secret to summer games done quick is to watch them all on YouTube after the fact.
Speaker 2: so you don't get ads like you do in the twitch stream.
Speaker 1: I don't get ads in the twitch stream with my ad block.
Speaker 2: your ad block - actually I've never used ad block with twitch.
Speaker 2: does it just block the ad?
Speaker 1: I mean I'm using you block origin or micro block origin whatever you want to call it.
Speaker 1: but even when I used ad block plus I never see ads on YouTube or on twitch.
Speaker 2: I don't see on YouTube but I see the first ad on twitch.
Speaker 1: I don't see any ad on twitch unless I use like my phone or something.
Speaker 2: yeah and the twitch app yeah summer games done quick was a pretty good run this year.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean we already had a GDQ.
Speaker 1: right awesome games done quick.
Speaker 1: so they have two events summer games done quick.
Speaker 1: this year it was in like st.
Speaker 1: Paul Minnesota or something.
Speaker 1: but they got a surprising turnout of runners showing up to this thing not net runners speed runners who put on quite a display.
Speaker 1: they had four-way Super Metroid race which is always the highlight.
Speaker 1: the correct choice of save the animals was the winner.
Speaker 1: yeah as it was last time as well.
Speaker 1: for the Tetris.
Speaker 1: you know the grand master edition.
Speaker 1: you know they put the pretty good show on with that the last time.
Speaker 1: this time they brought over people from Japan.
Speaker 1: so they had like probably the best collection of Tetris players ever assembled in a single location.
Speaker 2: I was particularly enjoying the gauntlet one because I did not actually know as a kid.
Speaker 2: I bet gauntlet 2. it was the first one I got on the NES.
Speaker 2: I played gauntlet in the arcade and I got gauntlet 2 which is pretty much like the arcade on the NES.
Speaker 2: and then later I got gauntlet 1. and how this weird shit like a map and all the stuff I didn't get.
Speaker 2: I didn't know you could beat gauntlet 1.
Speaker 1: of course you can.
Speaker 1: no I didn't know you just like a lot of money to be gone.
Speaker 2: it's gonna - just goes on forever.
Speaker 2: but yeah gauntlet 1 the best part about the speed run is he starts going then he gets his password and he's like no no no stop the clock.
Speaker 2: we got to start over.
Speaker 2: my password started with an a. the game is unbeatable.
Speaker 2: yeah really there's a bug where if your password starts with an a then the game is unbeatable yep because you need to type in that code at the end yep and you won't be able to like it.
Speaker 2: just won't happen all right.
Speaker 1: other interesting runs that I saw during the weekend of awesomeness.
Speaker 1: obviously simply a night race is always a good show.
Speaker 1: yep all right you know it was pretty good - well I mean all the classics are at.
Speaker 1: the ones they have every single time are always good.
Speaker 1: that's why they have them every single time.
Speaker 1: right but there was a the majority way to.
Speaker 1: the majora's mass is crazy.
Speaker 1: the earthbound was pretty crazy.
Speaker 2: I'm going to watch the chrono trigger the Oregon Trail.
Speaker 1: they had an Apple to GS up ends.
Speaker 1: there was a super Noah's Ark 3d that didn't watch it but I want to.
Speaker 2: I don't know.
Speaker 2: that's just.
Speaker 2: it's just.
Speaker 2: I don't feel like see watching that one that feels like it won't be fun unless I keep very funny.
Speaker 1: a lot of the ones that like you're like I'm not sure if I want to watch this are very short and it's like oh it's only like five minutes.
Speaker 1: okay let's see what the deal is.
Speaker 2: oh yeah like the it wasn't this time it was a while ago but super pitfall is actually a great speedrun to watch even though super pitfalls an awful game because the guy is really really funny and he knows a lot about the game.
Speaker 1: yeah there was a crazy Pokemon blue situations going on.
Speaker 1: I have to watch those.
Speaker 1: still.
Speaker 1: there was oh the Taz bot.
Speaker 1: you know which is the tool?
Speaker 1: assisted speedrun yeah but it played Megaman one and did crazy glitches which is you know kind of interesting for about a minute.
Speaker 1: but the Ikaruga one.
Speaker 1: it basically gets the maximum achievable score to player Ikaruga.
Speaker 1: it's both players are being controlled by the bot.
Speaker 1: and I think the highlight this year was the chrono trigger at the end.
Speaker 1: but I haven't watched that either because it's four hours.
Speaker 1: I need to find four hours of time to set aside which is actually a lot less time than it would take for me to play chrono trigger again.
Speaker 2: oh god yeah.
Speaker 1: so I'm like oh I'll just watch this.
Speaker 1: and then I wanted to play chrono trigger again because I think it's a hundred percent chrono trigger 100% co-op runs.
Speaker 2: I guess they switched in and out.
Speaker 2: yeah I guess people you know well there was an incentive for a hundred percent so they didn't have to I guess but I guess more.
Speaker 1: I think I think basically the way it works is like that.
Speaker 1: one of theirs one of his sponsors is the Yeti which is the t-shirt site which isn't bad and the Yeti basically like matches donations that everyone's making you know and also sponsors.
Speaker 1: but what they do is they end up actually just sending in their donations just like everyone else does.
Speaker 1: only they're from the Yeti.
Speaker 1: so you know they'll be reading off donations and they always read the donations from the Yeti right because it's the big sponsor.
Speaker 1: so whenever they read the Yeti donations the Yeti always basically fills in every single incentive with the thousands of dollars you know donating.
Speaker 2: but yeah if you you know we talked.
Speaker 2: we mentioned this was coming a long time ago.
Speaker 2: then we didn't talk about it again.
Speaker 2: but just go watch all the stuff on YouTube.
Speaker 2: some of these are great.
Speaker 1: watching live does have a certain you know especially if you got people on Twitter who are talking about it.
Speaker 1: so luckily no one I follow on Twitter.
Speaker 1: the Twitch chat is worthless.
Speaker 2: the only one of these that anyone in my like follow group talked about on Twitter was the Chrono Trigger and I avoided spoilers.
Speaker 2: I don't know if they saved Magus or not.
Speaker 1: I don't know how it works either.
Speaker 1: they better.
Speaker 2: they better save Magus.
Speaker 2: fuck frog.
Speaker 1: what frog is my man?
Speaker 1: yeah but Magus is so much.
Speaker 1: so much sword with also Magus floats on the overworld.
Speaker 2: so make him your leader and like why would you ever do anything else?
Speaker 1: so much sword?
Speaker 2: so in other news remember that's old game.
Speaker 2: we did a show on this on geek nights like what six years ago longer.
Speaker 1: well see it's a very unique and high quality game that's been around for a long time and is you know managed to keep going despite you know yeah
Speaker 2: but there is the battle for Wesna
Speaker 1: was just like an open-source turn-based strategy game that has had of active community and has gradually improved over years and years and years
Speaker 2: or possibly gotten worse because the campaign's kept breaking.
Speaker 1: maybe but never played the campaigns.
Speaker 1: we really just played multiplayer.
Speaker 2: yeah well the game was it.
Speaker 2: it's interesting because this is one of the rare examples of a large game like a very large completely large that I'd say it's very large in terms of the framework.
Speaker 2: I mean it has a whole framework and its own scripting language just for making all those scenarios sure.
Speaker 2: yeah it also has like the backend and the netcode and a significant amount of moderately well-drawn art assets and poorly drawn hard assets.
Speaker 1: well it's an open-source game.
Speaker 1: what do you think the heart's gonna be like?
Speaker 2: but I'm hard-pressed to name larger open-source game projects.
Speaker 1: oh there was that FPS that was like a quake clone thingy.
Speaker 1: what was that thing called?
Speaker 1: I forget yeah there you go but was frozen frozen bubbles usually the example of open-source game right.
Speaker 1: so it was not this pretty great by comparison.
Speaker 2: but was not this having a problem?
Speaker 2: apparently there's no one left to write code for it.
Speaker 1: oh like the people are starting to quit now that it's been like a 20 year old.
Speaker 2: to quote the article the ship is sinking.
Speaker 1: the project is that but if someone wrote the ship is sinking that means someone's on the ship to write that it's.
Speaker 2: there are a few people on the ship but basically they need people with C++ Python and WML programming.
Speaker 1: well WML is the was not markup language.
Speaker 1: nobody knows the Wesnoth markup language unless they're already.
Speaker 1: it was not person.
Speaker 1: so you're gonna need people to learn the Wesnoth markup.
Speaker 1: if you
Speaker 2: are a punk kid and you want something to do to like
Speaker 1: and you like turn-based strategy games like Advance Wars only with fantasy themes
Speaker 2: yep this project is hurting for developers enough that you can probably have a lot of influence in a hurry
Speaker 1: on a game that a lot of people kind of care about.
Speaker 2: yeah but - uh I don't think it's gonna make it and has miners start.
Speaker 1: you don't think you think it's gonna be the end of Wesnoth.
Speaker 2: I think Wesnoth is not bloody.
Speaker 1: Foxton has come to be.
Speaker 2: Foxton is the final resting place of these sad souls okay so part of the problem I saw is that I was reading through it like slash shot which is not the most but slash does is the very Wesnoth.
Speaker 1: that's a place that was not.
Speaker 2: so it's interesting because a lot of accounts with way old numbers on slash shot like my people suddenly appeared suddenly talk about was not yeah and more than one of them was like.
Speaker 2: I tried to contribute but the developers are assholes and things.
Speaker 2: I believe that I believe that there seems to be an infinite amount of drama around this project.
Speaker 1: listen an open-source world.
Speaker 1: somehow assholes get shit done.
Speaker 1: look at Linux.
Speaker 2: yeah but I think the problem is that games like this really need like game design independently of the coding and the changes there.
Speaker 2: well it's not always had some design issues exactly but the people who were the best coders were also the ones who had a lot of the input over the design.
Speaker 1: you just code and you you set the design right.
Speaker 1: yeah there's no director.
Speaker 0: what you're describing right now is open source UX in general.
Speaker 2: I mean the gimp is totally fine right sure I haven't I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe the gimps improved now.
Speaker 1: I pay for real photoshop now so I don't know.
Speaker 2: I have real Photoshop and I work out of the gimp.
Speaker 2: so my workflow is do a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 2: why the fuck is this broken?
Speaker 2: flatten image continue working?
Speaker 2: why the fake leaf is broken flatten image continue going.
Speaker 2: I made a layer once and that ended my project.
Speaker 2: okay but uh I made a layer once Wesnoth just was never quite there and that that WML language kept changing with no backward compatibility and they kept changing gameplay stuff.
Speaker 2: so they had a lot of people who made a lot of.
Speaker 2: they change the language without changing the campaign or the coders change subtle gameplay things that broke the campaigns because oh yeah you can't win this one now because that dude just isn't strong enough.
Speaker 1: stuff like that.
Speaker 2: like there is no way to have dependencies on gameplay in scenarios and vice versa.
Speaker 2: there's no way to like snapshot or freeze like sets of game mechanics.
Speaker 2: so the project is such a big mess.
Speaker 2: that sure in my opinion unless they freeze that language and they freeze gameplay and design and focus only on fixing the code and bugs and issues for a while and have a stable platform for a while I don't think this thing's ever gonna get beyond where it is right now.
Speaker 1: well who knows I haven't played it in years and I wasn't really planning to play it again.
Speaker 2: yeah thing is as fun as it was.
Speaker 2: it was no advanced wars.
Speaker 1: no it wasn't.
Speaker 0: that wasn't Alex working on that.
Speaker 1: I mean he did it for a little bit back and when we were really playing it you know he made I think he made some sprites for it maybe and yeah I did some stuff.
Speaker 1: it was way back.
Speaker 2: yeah the part of the trouble is the game never got polished enough to be worth investing the time and being great at it partly because the gameplay kept changing.
Speaker 2: like I'm good at advanced wars I wouldn't be good at advanced wars like revision 809 build 7.
Speaker 1: yeah it's like every time there's new advances you had to relearn it anyway right?
Speaker 1: yeah it's constantly changing.
Speaker 1: it's difficult and you know what that's.
Speaker 1: why not?
Speaker 1: runner is awesome.
Speaker 2: but yeah I'll link to the slash down article because the comments is a lot of people who know a lot about Wes Knopf pretty much shedding light on things and linking to like old bugs they opened in 2008.
Speaker 1: let me show you my Ubuntu bug.
Speaker 2: so but anyway things of the day I want for you an AGD Q not an SDG Q. but this is a game that I was a kid I played and well I rented from blockbuster because it had really good box art and looked like it had good graphics and we my brother and I couldn't get out of like the first two screens and we did not get out of those things
Speaker 1: later once and couldn't get past the first two screens.
Speaker 2: yeah in the whole weekend and we took the game back.
Speaker 1: I mean I only spent about ten minutes on it and this game haunted me but not enough to go figure it out why this game haunts me because every time I go to a convention magfest packs anywhere and there's always that one booth selling the retro games.
Speaker 1: they've got a whole bunch of overpriced NES cartridges.
Speaker 1: yeah this game is 100% of the time always in the library and the selection available.
Speaker 2: so this is a speedrun of that game and a huge lingering chapter of my childhood unresolved hitherto has henceforth been resolved and I have closure.
Speaker 2: also the in this game pretty good kind of catchy yeah.
Speaker 1: so the SGD Q sort of you know always inspires you to try to be a speedrunner.
Speaker 1: yeah I opened up Mame and I wanted to play Tetris Grandmaster myself and I played it a bit and yeah I couldn't get past like level 100 something and that took me four minutes.
Speaker 1: meanwhile four minutes in those guys like at level 900 or whatever just takes practice 800 who knows.
Speaker 1: yeah obviously I don't think that there's any amount of practice I could put in that would get me at their level.
Speaker 1: I could be better obviously but not as good as them.
Speaker 1: so while I had my meme open I tried some other things.
Speaker 1: I played some Dodon Pachi and whatever and then I realized whoa I'm sitting here with my joystick playing all these arcade games.
Speaker 1: you know there's I can just play Street Fighter championship edition.
Speaker 1: it's just right here you know just like the old arcade days.
Speaker 1: so I opened it up.
Speaker 1: I start playing.
Speaker 1: you know my guy M bison.
Speaker 1: yeah and you know this is on arcade.
Speaker 1: hard mode.
Speaker 1: make you lose quarters mode and I get to review the fifth guy and I just can't win.
Speaker 1: and I was like what the fuck I used to be my that old.
Speaker 1: I can't even win.
Speaker 1: and it's like I take a round and then lose two rounds.
Speaker 1: some like let me go on the internet and find a video.
Speaker 1: you know a beating for you.
Speaker 1: maybe there's something I'm doing wrong and there was something to doing wrong I forgot.
Speaker 1: the thing in that game is that M bison middle kick basically just beats everything because it has so much as so much reach and it has some and it has enough strength.
Speaker 1: you can basically just middle kick your way through the game.
Speaker 2: yeah welcome back to my nightmares.
Speaker 1: but anyway while I was searching for like you know I want to see a video of someone beating were you like just like destroying him and Street Fighter championship in arcade.
Speaker 1: I found this video on YouTube.
Speaker 1: I know none of you have seen this because it has so few views.
Speaker 1: it is some dude just some dude who is reminiscing about playing this game and he's playing it and he beats for you.
Speaker 1: but the things he said it's like.
Speaker 1: this is like some glorious video that is completely hidden on the internet that no one knows.
Speaker 1: it has like maybe tens of you.
Speaker 2: it has 21 views and one like which I assume is you.
Speaker 1: yes that's my life.
Speaker 1: this video is worth watching.
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 1: what's up with this undiscovered guy?
Speaker 1: I didn't even look to see if it is the only other videos both posted on his own published recently but if he does I want to watch them.
Speaker 2: here are some random fights in Street Fighter 2 champion edition arcade.
Speaker 2: this is the classic fighting game this.
Speaker 2: well there's a lot of description here.
Speaker 2: here's my flicker here's my.
Speaker 2: alright I guess he's a photographer.
Speaker 1: yeah but whoever?
Speaker 1: I don't even know who this guy is but you just have to watch this and listen to him.
Speaker 2: Alexander's say and look here's a bunch of black and white pictures he took.
Speaker 0: Alexander you are in link is tinder.
Speaker 2: let's see flicker another photography another tiger.
Speaker 2: no no whatever.
Speaker 1: but we'll watch this after the show is over and you'll see the glory that this man has made.
Speaker 1: I mean this YouTube video.
Speaker 2: in the moment the booklet book is still fantasy book volume one.
Speaker 1: I've read much more of it.
Speaker 2: I'm you're probably ahead of me now because I left off when they were in the town after they landed from the ship being stupid again.
Speaker 1: yeah I'm a little after that.
Speaker 2: are they still being stupid?
Speaker 1: they left that town.
Speaker 2: are all the kids still alive?
Speaker 2: yeah I wish just one or two of them would not make it.
Speaker 1: I think the times are coming soon.
Speaker 1: man the wolf sent something.
Speaker 2: I just I suspect and I worry that the characters that like the least are the ones who are in the most pages of the wheel of.
Speaker 1: there are so many pages though I assume that they'll make newer characters who you may like or hate more or less.
Speaker 2: but I pretty much only like adults and hate children so far in these books.
Speaker 2: I don't know if that says anything about the books or about me.
Speaker 1: I have to agree with that anyway.
Speaker 2: also we are going to be live at PAX Prime on real packs.
Speaker 2: yeah the far future of one true gaming con.
Speaker 2: all roads lead to Rome room the mecca of nerds.
Speaker 2: yeah so Sunday far future of gaming.
Speaker 2: Monday sports our games which is getting increasingly topical what with the doping scandal in video game tournaments lately?
Speaker 2: and then on Wednesday in Portland I am giving a lecture not geek nights just me on UX in video games at Kifu in Portland the computer human interaction forum of Oregon.
Speaker 1: I'm sure so many people show up there.
Speaker 1: it sounds like such a hot place.
Speaker 2: a lot of people go to this thing like Mike Seliger lectured not too long ago and I know who that is bunch of packs that people were there.
Speaker 2: so okay apparently someone from packs dev knew us and saw me lecture at another packs and nominated me to be a lecturer here.
Speaker 2: so that's how that happened as far as I could tell.
Speaker 2: okay so yeah we got up.
Speaker 2: we got Conrad Kraling here in the studio if you didn't notice.
Speaker 0: oh yeah hi everybody my name is Conrad Kraling.
Speaker 1: Conrad you have been here before but I wonder how many people listening know who you are.
Speaker 2: it's been a while.
Speaker 1: maybe you should intro duct yourself.
Speaker 1: yeah save me the trouble.
Speaker 0: so hey everybody I'm Conrad Kraling.
Speaker 0: I've been on the show a couple times.
Speaker 0: you might remember me from my last appearance on this show where I gave a rough estimate as to the number of times that I've masturbated in my entire life.
Speaker 0: oh yeah the number has gone up.
Speaker 0: just let me quell any doubts.
Speaker 2: well the question is not how not whether or not it went up but what the diff is like.
Speaker 1: get a measure that why are we drenching to this territory?
Speaker 1: yes also I don't remember that at all.
Speaker 0: I remember it vividly yes so currently I'm working as the founder and lead engineer at my little visual novel company date night.
Speaker 2: oh that's that's a big step up from just working.
Speaker 0: yeah yeah it's not bad.
Speaker 0: you mentioned you mentioned that you were going to be live at at PAX.
Speaker 0: one of our people is actually going to be there our product manager Joe foo.
Speaker 2: in fact actually because Joe is on the panel I realized this is like the first time ever I've put together a PAX panel.
Speaker 2: that isn't five to six white dudes.
Speaker 2: there are three ladies and three men on this panel.
Speaker 2: I'm kind of amazed.
Speaker 0: I I mean I'm obviously very happy at date night.
Speaker 0: oh the the idea that we can put work by creators of color and and women forward is like a big part of our mission statement.
Speaker 0: it's it's a big part of what we want to do.
Speaker 0: so thank you so much for helping us to make that happen.
Speaker 2: thing is for here like before date night.
Speaker 2: oh I pretty much submitted panels with your name on them to conventions for years without telling you yeah I'm really sorry that I had such difficulty getting out there.
Speaker 0: I'm really excited about this year though even even just being in the audience and you know having somebody from date night to be on stage it's gonna be dope.
Speaker 0: I'm excited.
Speaker 1: we'll see how many people show up.
Speaker 2: I don't know it's that's the kind of provocative title that the problem is.
Speaker 1: so I've never had a PAX panel with a bad turnout though every time I think it's gonna be a bad turnout I get at least like 50% fillage.
Speaker 1: I know what we weren't?
Speaker 2: we like early morning on Sunday at one point it's usually a good time.
Speaker 2: yeah the only bad time I think is during the Omega thon itself.
Speaker 1: well our Mondays is you know they gave this to us last year to our panel Monday at the very end of the con.
Speaker 1: we gotta run to the Omega thon.
Speaker 1: it's like uh but I don't even know if I want to run this year.
Speaker 2: we could do our joke that we do every year of admonishing the people in the audience for seeing us instead of the.
Speaker 1: oh that's definitely gonna happen.
Speaker 1: yeah that is definitely gonna happen.
Speaker 2: so Conrad how's this thing going?
Speaker 2: I mean you're making dating games and I guess some of them actually came out.
Speaker 1: yeah do you make money doing that?
Speaker 0: yeah well uh you know obviously we ran the Star Fighter Eclipse Kickstarter which pulled in I believe a little over $150,000 a lot of money.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean it's not millions but that is way more monies than I have.
Speaker 0: yeah yeah it was.
Speaker 0: it was a rip-roaring start and you know we're still working on fulfillment for that game.
Speaker 0: in some ways we're doing the translations right now.
Speaker 0: we did.
Speaker 0: we did get the art book out as well as the soundtrack so we're really excited about that.
Speaker 0: the soundtrack is available on bank.
Speaker 1: how many languages are you translating the?
Speaker 0: so it's five.
Speaker 0: oh yeah it's five and and you know I actually just sent the contract out for our Russian translator.
Speaker 0: so yeah yeah yeah yeah it's actually a really big market for Starfighter.
Speaker 0: so yeah it was kind of a no-brainer for the for the project but yeah so that that actually shipped in May on date night.
Speaker 0: calm it's our first title on you know under our own power and on our own publishing platform.
Speaker 0: you just go to the website you play the game.
Speaker 0: there's like no downloads.
Speaker 0: you just buy it and play it it's.
Speaker 0: uh it worked even better like you know obviously like it's my company and like I made the game but it worked even better than like I had imagined like it was so cool being able to just go there and do it.
Speaker 0: we actually have another game coming out in early to mid-september called we know the devil.
Speaker 0: this is a collaboration work with a VB of the other publication zeal.
Speaker 0: we obviously were really excited about.
Speaker 0: I just implemented the UI for that.
Speaker 0: today it looks it looks dope.
Speaker 0: that's in collaboration with Mia Schwartz.
Speaker 0: she's doing the artwork and like you know me as a buddy of mine anyway.
Speaker 0: so I couldn't be more excited about that.
Speaker 0: and then next year February we've got hustle cat our next our next title about magical boys and girls working in the cat cafe.
Speaker 1: who doesn't like that?
Speaker 1: I mean if that had a full boyfriend pigeon dating came out right.
Speaker 1: I mean that's like ten times better.
Speaker 0: I'm actually gonna leak something.
Speaker 0: this will be a geek night's.
Speaker 2: exclusive people are listening and I know the listeners gonna appreciate this a lot.
Speaker 0: yeah I think so too.
Speaker 0: Audra Feruichi of Nemu Nemu is actually doing the cat sprites for us on hustle cat that just happened.
Speaker 0: she's doing the designs.
Speaker 0: I'm so excited.
Speaker 0: so these are definitely the most important.
Speaker 2: yeah right they've got to be real accurate or people are gonna be really mad.
Speaker 0: well they at least have to be real cute.
Speaker 0: that's really all I'm looking for is really accurate.
Speaker 0: but yeah we're actually in talks about doing a Kickstarter for that.
Speaker 0: we think we think we're gonna give crowdfunding a shot on that.
Speaker 1: so if the other one made 150 why wouldn't you do it again?
Speaker 0: yeah I will say that I think this is a an interesting new challenge for us because rather than being able to leverage an existing and let's face it really popular property like Hamlet machine starfighter we are kind of driving under our own power.
Speaker 0: now we kind of have to go in front of everybody and say this is an idea that we had.
Speaker 0: you know we can make games.
Speaker 0: we did it.
Speaker 0: you can go to the website and buy it.
Speaker 0: give us some money.
Speaker 0: we'll make another one of course.
Speaker 2: look how well that worked with like multiple Japanese game designers recent history who had a history of making good things and then just kind of struck out on their own for various reasons.
Speaker 0: yeah I couldn't imagine weird.
Speaker 0: it's like a bunch of news came out recently.
Speaker 0: anyway.
Speaker 2: yeah I was gonna talk about the news the revelations about all the game designers and composers who are literally being janitors for a certain game company.
Speaker 1: but I mean you know visual novels are hot lately right?
Speaker 1: you know I mean having a property to go along with.
Speaker 1: it seems to help.
Speaker 1: but if you look on Steam it's like that long live.
Speaker 1: the Queen game seems to have done really well.
Speaker 1: I mean I bought that right and there was that in New Year's.
Speaker 1: yeah it's like.
Speaker 1: you know there's definitely a market for any kind of visual novel regard in the US regardless of you know what's in it well and I think there's.
Speaker 0: there's actually the opportunity there I believe is is bigger than we expect.
Speaker 0: because I do think that the presentation the mode of presentation is accessible in a way that a lot of games maybe aren't.
Speaker 0: so even with bio where's efforts in Mass Effect 3 to allow you to bypass the action sequences and just get to the story?
Speaker 0: in the narrative you still had a lot of like let's face it relatively complicated controls for a certain set of users in a 3d space and in a 3d world.
Speaker 0: that was a barrier to entry to that narrative.
Speaker 0: and you know the price and the price?
Speaker 0: yeah you know.
Speaker 0: obviously like we don't have like GameStop we don't have EA we have.
Speaker 1: we have significantly lower overhead and the equipment that you need to play it right.
Speaker 1: you need either some kind of new ish console or a PC that doesn't suck yeah or a good PC and in our case like you can play your games on just like your phone right?
Speaker 0: yeah yeah it's it's all.
Speaker 0: it's all on the web.
Speaker 0: so it works with anything.
Speaker 0: above Andrew our Android 4.0 you've got iOS 8 and above.
Speaker 0: you know I actually have a Chromebook for testing and iPads probably really good to play it on.
Speaker 0: right it is actually.
Speaker 0: it looks beautiful.
Speaker 1: level resolution graphics?
Speaker 0: yeah oh yeah definitely we we actually bake two sets of assets for anything in the game one for high DPI displays and one for well yeah very nice.
Speaker 2: so it's interesting is that it these like the visual novels in general like they got really big but it seems like the ones that are getting the most traction.
Speaker 2: that people talk like hot tuba boyfriend is example.
Speaker 2: it's like the the ones that are almost a joke but like I played through that game it's not actually a great game it's just a great concept like.
Speaker 2: it's funny to know that it exists but it's not actually that fun to read it.
Speaker 0: so I have to admit something.
Speaker 0: I haven't played it yet.
Speaker 0: yeah so I will say I played it like a minute.
Speaker 0: it just came out on Vita which improves its odds like by about a thousand because the only time I ever get to play games now is when I'm a train or a bus or something.
Speaker 2: wait you have a Vita.
Speaker 0: yeah oh yeah I bought it to play danganronpa and persona for golden.
Speaker 0: so obviously like those are those are.
Speaker 0: they're a little more gamey.
Speaker 0: persona for definitely danganronpa pretty much.
Speaker 0: they're a little more gamey let's say.
Speaker 0: but at the same time they present this really strong narrative in a format that's really familiar to us.
Speaker 2: so hmm yeah well I remember like when I even like Emily and a lot of people I really want to play Mass Effect and all these games because the stories and then I really when I see them play Mass Effect 1 I'm just waiting for the.
Speaker 2: oh this game sucks.
Speaker 0: Mass Effect 1 was bad.
Speaker 0: yeah I think ably bad.
Speaker 0: yeah well I beat it.
Speaker 0: so I could not.
Speaker 2: I could not.
Speaker 2: I did not care enough about that game.
Speaker 2: I just I realized I could just watch the story on YouTube and it's not even that long.
Speaker 0: yeah and and you know I think I don't think you're the only person to say that and so it's interesting because you're coming at this from and I will use this term here you're kind of a hardcore gamer.
Speaker 0: yeah you know you know what you're doing you know how to use game pretty good.
Speaker 0: so imagine coming at it from a completely different perspective.
Speaker 2: I guess what I don't like are games that have like a really hard game component like this thing and then completely orthogonal to that.
Speaker 2: here's the story.
Speaker 2: that will continue and if you care about one or the other then they don't really intersect at all.
Speaker 0: yeah and and personally I think one of the strengths of what we're doing is is that you we have shed a lot of that.
Speaker 0: that baggage I think is the way that I'll put it.
Speaker 0: I mean we all played Mass Effect 1. we all remember driving the Mako or the Mako.
Speaker 0: that was not a fun part of that game.
Speaker 2: dice rolls for aiming and shooting in a third-person title please please of course I remember I even have life one like the vehicles weren't great actually.
Speaker 1: Half-Life 1 yeah I don't know.
Speaker 1: jeepathon was good time.
Speaker 2: jeepathon was good times.
Speaker 2: it was not good.
Speaker 1: so you're so you're dating out against.
Speaker 1: they're mostly sort of just.
Speaker 1: you know the straight-up.
Speaker 1: choose your own adventure path.
Speaker 1: you know there's not a lot of you know game going on at all.
Speaker 1: but I mean do you think you can do if you wanted like the more you know?
Speaker 2: simulation added to staff builder.
Speaker 1: yeah like like Tokimeki like a Tokimeki right you got to go to school.
Speaker 1: do I study?
Speaker 2: I'm just gunning for another Tokimeki game.
Speaker 1: I can't read the ones that exist.
Speaker 1: I need something.
Speaker 0: yeah there's.
Speaker 0: you know the.
Speaker 0: the system itself is very flexible.
Speaker 0: there's nothing stopping us from doing that.
Speaker 0: personally like I have spent my time in stat builders man I said I spent my time in the stat mines and so personally I I'm not as excited about that game mode.
Speaker 0: technically though there's nothing stopping us.
Speaker 0: and you know who knows if if a creator came to me and said I have this really great game it's a stat builder here here's the pitch and it was awesome I'd be like yeah definitely like.
Speaker 0: get on board let's let's build it but it's it's not something that I'm I would.
Speaker 0: I'm like fired up about.
Speaker 2: I guess design and QA is a lot harder like a lot of those I've played but later most like a lot longer ago like not anytime recently like especially like Tokimeki's and things like those simple dating games.
Speaker 2: there's like it's just a threshold of.
Speaker 2: did you get to a threshold to trigger this thing?
Speaker 2: so a lot of your decisions don't actually matter.
Speaker 1: I noticed that more with like long live the Queen.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: that's literally like.
Speaker 1: did you get this stat up to this percent by this day?
Speaker 1: if so this happens.
Speaker 1: otherwise this happens.
Speaker 1: so it's really just to choose your own adventure where the choices are obscured.
Speaker 1: but Tokimeki like it was a PlayStation 1 game but I mean this might just be my SNES game I mean but it really blew up on the PlayStation.
Speaker 1: I remember the technology at least back then being so insane like it could read you know the text-to-speech of your name?
Speaker 2: oh yeah in a PlayStation 1 you type your name in.
Speaker 1: I remember our name was right and it's just like.
Speaker 1: it seemed like it wasn't doing what long live the Queen.
Speaker 1: it even though it might have been under the hood.
Speaker 1: it seemed a lot more natural.
Speaker 1: you know in terms of like I went to school.
Speaker 1: you know it's like oh if you went to school more often then you would get better grades and you know the girl who cared about school would be more likely to go out with you.
Speaker 1: and as opposed to these things you know there were things that happen on specific days but there were so many days in the school year.
Speaker 1: you know as I think you know other games like think of it what long of the Queen's like 40 days long or something like that.
Speaker 1: 50 days and that's it.
Speaker 1: you know Tokimeki is three years of Japanese high school yeah plus summer.
Speaker 0: if I remember though there was a random component to that game.
Speaker 0: you could choose to study but you maybe it wasn't a success.
Speaker 1: I remember very whenever you chose one of the things it would be like you know like you would show the drawing and then like a circle or X like you succeeded or failed and being at the will of a random number generator.
Speaker 0: man there's nothing that's gonna turn me off from a game more quickly but it's a holding my breath like oh did he study right?
Speaker 0: this time you didn't.
Speaker 0: you did it bad.
Speaker 2: but imagine the counterpoint of not the door fortress of if the more emergent the gameplay is like if if the randomness causes unintended or unexpected or at least unexpected to the player things to happen.
Speaker 2: then there's this.
Speaker 2: it adds like this additional layer of discovery.
Speaker 2: it's more like an evolving story then.
Speaker 2: well I followed this path to the end.
Speaker 2: I'm gonna try to follow this other very specific path and see I'll totally get on board with that.
Speaker 0: but I think at least my experience when I played Toki memo on the SNES it was come on green hair girl come on.
Speaker 2: no I did track so bad that she doesn't like me anymore.
Speaker 0: how about you other green hair girl?
Speaker 0: you're in the library you want to go to the park.
Speaker 0: she didn't?
Speaker 0: she did not want to go to the park.
Speaker 1: better restart the game better restart.
Speaker 0: so when?
Speaker 0: when you talk about like emergent behavior like that I love that.
Speaker 0: but the failure state for me and Toki memo was kind of like.
Speaker 0: well I'm sitting alone.
Speaker 2: well I've been thinking about this a lot partly cuz that far future games pan like.
Speaker 2: I found the slides from when I did a similar thing at magfest and also we had all those panels up to our fortress.
Speaker 2: and there's like.
Speaker 2: there's this critical mass like this threshold where there's enough emergent behavior and bushiness to where it feels like discovery and the randomness feels like the effectively infinite content.
Speaker 2: but anything less than that feels like the game just fucked you and anything more than that feels like actual dwarf fortress.
Speaker 0: you can lean into it too.
Speaker 0: so Joe actually her one of her first games was a game jam game for a Valentine's Day and it was essentially you were.
Speaker 0: you paired up with with literally random women at a bar who had literally random backstories and said literally random things.
Speaker 0: when you broke up and some of the some of the dialogue we got out of that was heartbreaking.
Speaker 1: so how did so?
Speaker 1: did you wait?
Speaker 1: it was literally like you didn't fill a database with text.
Speaker 0: well we randomly choose yeah we filled the database with database with text.
Speaker 2: I guess she's not saying like I can pick fuck question exclamation point.
Speaker 0: no no but it would it would.
Speaker 0: you know?
Speaker 0: you would end up being paired with a woman.
Speaker 0: you would meet a woman at a bar who turned out to be like a puff of smoke and then the breakup line was she's gone like the wind.
Speaker 0: it's just like that was random but at the same time.
Speaker 2: so I noticed this like a few months ago.
Speaker 2: but explodes.
Speaker 2: them actually sign on happiness.
Speaker 2: they have a random.
Speaker 2: like you know every webcomic has a random comic right like click for a random one.
Speaker 2: theirs actually generates a random comic three panels.
Speaker 2: it is almost nothing but comedy gold.
Speaker 0: does it?
Speaker 0: does it do that from transcripts?
Speaker 2: well basically he looks like he made like thousands of individual panels and he just picks three of them.
Speaker 0: oh all right.
Speaker 2: yeah I love that and it seeds it.
Speaker 2: so you can actually go find one that you found before if it was actually like particularly know where they.
Speaker 1: hmm yeah that does seem to be a thing about visual novels.
Speaker 1: is that you know if you have the randomness the failure state does suck.
Speaker 1: cuz it's like I spent a lot of time on this and got nowhere.
Speaker 1: but you lose like the replay value.
Speaker 1: right like if I play a date night Oh game and I see every ending I'm sort of done.
Speaker 1: well if you read a book sure I guess that's the case.
Speaker 2: yes I was thinking about this a lot.
Speaker 2: they're like this.
Speaker 2: they're like this middle ground between just a book and like just a simulator like a door fortress.
Speaker 1: you can't end you can always play it again.
Speaker 1: well it's kind of you can play one time.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean yes you're you're absolutely right you know.
Speaker 0: and in the same way that some games well I think attempt to provide value by banking on the RNG and giving you this emergent gameplay.
Speaker 0: our games bank on the fact that there's a lot of words and pretty pictures and you're gonna look at them all at least I hope you do so.
Speaker 0: you know the so the so there's that I man.
Speaker 2: well think about the RNG like a game like FTL faster than light leans on that like that's the game.
Speaker 2: yeah and you get these like the end always sucks when you lose and usually you lose.
Speaker 2: but I definitely always because it's heavy on the gameplay the emergent stuff.
Speaker 2: it doesn't feel unsatisfying to die.
Speaker 2: but if you're playing a dating game and the emerge their RNG is just yeah no girls date you.
Speaker 2: that just feels really unsatisfying.
Speaker 2: it's not like there's a thousand different shadow gateways that you physically die because they didn't date you.
Speaker 2: then maybe it'd be interesting again.
Speaker 0: yeah wait I want to make this game like shadow shadow date.
Speaker 2: I would play the
Speaker 1: hell out of that
Speaker 0: smoking tinder torch
Speaker 1: torch.
Speaker 1: we go on girl.
Speaker 0: no no no don't do that.
Speaker 0: this race is coming on to you.
Speaker 0: wait hold up you're winning me over.
Speaker 2: so is that Zeno technically?
Speaker 2: or is that what is that ashy?
Speaker 2: so what is it like on a like personal level having like for real founded a game studio because the one thing Scott I have never done is actually given up on our day jobs to go after the things we care about.
Speaker 1: like I say I'm so risk-averse like I still work for rich people I would totally do that.
Speaker 1: you know many ideas I have but I am very afraid of being homeless.
Speaker 1: so it's not a thing that I do.
Speaker 0: well it's it's interesting.
Speaker 0: so towards the end of my college career I went to a. I promise this is relevant.
Speaker 0: I went to.
Speaker 2: I went to a private school.
Speaker 0: my family's financial situation changed.
Speaker 0: I basically got kicked out because I didn't have enough money and to stay in school.
Speaker 0: I subsidize that by doing freelance web development.
Speaker 0: so I've been doing freelance web development.
Speaker 0: so I was like yeah like 21 or 22 and then after I graduated I had all these professional contacts from doing it.
Speaker 1: so I could you also like work at AMD and stuff because you were way smarter than me.
Speaker 0: well yeah I did an internship there and I did pretty okay.
Speaker 0: but you know I once I graduated while a lot of people were getting these like w-2 yearly salaries I just kept doing freelance because I had all these professional contacts.
Speaker 0: so I got very used to this like invoice payment invoice payment cycle and feast and famine and it's sort of normalized risk for me in a way that I don't think it was normalized for a lot of people.
Speaker 0: so for me transitioning from my previous job which was like a normal w-2 salary position to date night oh which is you know it turns out owning a company and having a company is very different than being a freelancer because you don't get to invoice anybody.
Speaker 0: it is it is scary sometimes you know and and our co-founder Lindsay Woods of course is a full-time employee.
Speaker 0: so you know instead of you know just invoicing people I'm actually cutting paychecks.
Speaker 0: you're being invoiced yeah being actively invoiced and you know Joe Joe of course and Mike was on board.
Speaker 0: so these you know all of these things are happening and it's scary.
Speaker 0: but at the same time I think I'm well suited to it like to me.
Speaker 0: it's very exciting and and you guys have known me for a while you know that I've got that unfortunate personality situation where it's like I will invest like a hundred hours a week into something just because I didn't like the way this worked or because this needed to be just a little better before it launched.
Speaker 0: so the the confluence and the nexus of those two things I think were really really beneficial to me in that regard.
Speaker 0: it's been it's been nothing but a blast for me.
Speaker 2: so how about specifically doing it?
Speaker 2: is being in New York City a net positive or a net negative?
Speaker 2: in regard to this?
Speaker 0: this has been somewhat of a topic of discussion
Speaker 2: because
Speaker 1: I it's expensive but there's so much people's here and talents and monies but also costing monies
Speaker 0: you hit the nail right on the head is the the nexus of talent that's present in the immediate vicinity the a 10-mile radius that I can bike to like like at the drop of a hat the fact that I could literally say to Hamlet Machine of Starfighter hey well I'm gonna come up there we're gonna work tonight I'll just crash with you.
Speaker 0: that's cool that's fine.
Speaker 0: it wasn't like a big deal it wasn't this this big investment of time?
Speaker 0: when Lindsay Woods quit her job I was like hey just come work for me instead.
Speaker 2: like other than Joe everyone on that far future of gaming panel lives here.
Speaker 0: yeah yeah and you know we're.
Speaker 0: you know that that situation might be changing too.
Speaker 0: and so yeah this is the the nexus of talent present in New York.
Speaker 0: I. it's something I've been balancing very carefully recently.
Speaker 0: at this time I think it's fair to say that there is value in being in New York out stripping that of the kind of incredible cost of real estate.
Speaker 0: prices aren't going down here y'all.
Speaker 2: we're in some of the few remaining rent stabilized buildings here.
Speaker 0: yeah I just spent the last three weeks in Northern Virginia.
Speaker 0: so yeah yeah and it was.
Speaker 0: it was gorgeous.
Speaker 0: like I won't play.
Speaker 0: it was gorgeous but uh but at the moment I think it's it's safe to say that New York is is our home.
Speaker 0: this is where we were founded this is where our core is and it's it's where we're gonna be.
Speaker 2: cuz I ran into something interesting.
Speaker 2: so I went to a the kind of party that I'm usually not invited to.
Speaker 2: so I was basically at an event with like all the VCS like the investors like the top of that food chain and they were doing presentations.
Speaker 2: there's all this stuff.
Speaker 1: and what one percent evil people.
Speaker 2: yeah some of them might be listening you never know.
Speaker 2: but well just say that I was in one of these events and what I learned is that they look at New York as a place to start a company because all the smart people are here but they want the company to move to California.
Speaker 2: when they then want to pump it up get more investment and flip it wait it's obviously not for cost saving.
Speaker 2: it is actually in their perspective.
Speaker 2: they want to be out there because that's what they get more investment because salaries are lower.
Speaker 2: there's this they like.
Speaker 2: we used to always say and Dean as we had this perception that the difference between an East Coast and a West Coast startup is that in the East Coast I'll work for a startup if they pay me money but on the West Coast people will work for basically dreams and lottery tickets.
Speaker 2: equity yeah and the talented people in New York are a lot more like business oriented in terms of let's make the thing.
Speaker 2: so it seems like those people are actually better at getting things working quickly.
Speaker 2: but when they want to expand the company they can pay a lot of people in lottery tickets and actually cost a lot less money to like triple your headcount on the West Coast.
Speaker 2: because a lot of those people are kind of semi independently wealthy.
Speaker 2: they have money from the last company that was a lottery ticket.
Speaker 2: there there's.
Speaker 2: it was just a weird conversation to be having with all these really really really rich people.
Speaker 1: if they're so rich why aren't they on the beach?
Speaker 2: yeah as soon as I have enough money to be on the beach I'm either on the beach or making my own game studio.
Speaker 0: yeah hey if they're looking for investment opportunities man do I have some good news for them?
Speaker 0: that does surprise me I won't lie although I guess I shouldn't be that surprised.
Speaker 0: I've been kind of putting the feelers out for engineers out here.
Speaker 0: engineers out here are relatively hard to hire.
Speaker 0: that is has been my experience.
Speaker 2: oh everything's hard to hire like I. recruiters talk to me like direct and I basically tell him I work four days a week and you have to pay me a lot of money.
Speaker 1: how's that sound?
Speaker 0: yeah see welcome to New York.
Speaker 0: yeah but that's that's fair.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: I don't know where what our future holds in that regard at the moment but well there is.
Speaker 2: Emily told me about it.
Speaker 2: apparently there is a move for New York City might be the state - I'm not sure I could ask Emily about it but there might be a big like tax credit thing coming just for small semi-independent video game studios in New York.
Speaker 1: yeah but how about that?
Speaker 1: that startup NYC thing was bullshit so why would this not be?
Speaker 0: it was super bullshit by the way definitely bullshit right.
Speaker 1: so why wouldn't this also be bullshit?
Speaker 1: you never know you never know.
Speaker 2: I didn't write Emily told me about.
Speaker 2: I have not yet done any investigation into it.
Speaker 0: hmm yeah given given Albany oh man I'm from upstate New York so like let me get super mad right now.
Speaker 0: but yeah when it comes to Albany in New York State tax code it's just like all bets are off.
Speaker 0: that shit is out the window.
Speaker 2: the worst thing is our bar best.
Speaker 2: our last best hope for peace was Zephyr Teachout and now she's running that super PAC instead.
Speaker 2: I don't think she's gonna run for governor again.
Speaker 1: I don't think so anything.
Speaker 0: oh well well that will do.
Speaker 0: that will make me leave New York.
Speaker 1: let's talk about other games.
Speaker 2: yeah what have you been playing lately?
Speaker 2: anything well you played anything.
Speaker 0: I well I did just beat danganronpa one and two all right.
Speaker 0: so I mentioned this right have you got?
Speaker 0: are you guys familiar with this game at all?
Speaker 1: it's a title that I've heard of but I've never played it.
Speaker 2: yeah that that whole like the same thing with persona like those are games that I know about primarily from let's play is making fun of them.
Speaker 1: I know the names of them and I know sort of what they look like.
Speaker 0: I hate to be that that pitch guy who says oh it's like uber meets fresh direct.
Speaker 0: it is kind of like battle royale meets Phoenix Wright.
Speaker 0: so it's a Phoenix Wright high school murder simulator.
Speaker 0: with this most importantly it's got this incredibly bold visual style that how does it play?
Speaker 1: does it play like like like a 999?
Speaker 0: it actually plays more like a Phoenix right the yeah the the parallels actually go pretty deep.
Speaker 0: so there are murders and there are investigations and there are trials and the.
Speaker 0: there are actually more gamified elements in the trials than a Phoenix Wright.
Speaker 0: the first game I thought was significantly tighter.
Speaker 1: in this regard I have to do like a rhythm based objection.
Speaker 0: you are 100% correct.
Speaker 0: yes you do.
Speaker 0: that is that is absolutely correct.
Speaker 0: and and the you know my favorite of the mini games is the one where you have to drag comic panels into an incomplete comic to create the murder.
Speaker 1: that's actually pretty interesting.
Speaker 0: yeah yeah I thought the first game did a way better job like.
Speaker 1: it makes it still makes sense and you put it in the other orders but it's wrong.
Speaker 0: yeah yeah it'll.
Speaker 0: well it might not make sense so you could just put the wrong tile in the wrong space.
Speaker 1: yeah but you know it's not trivially easy if you're not cheating.
Speaker 2: Wow resurrection knife this isn't even a.
Speaker 0: but you know I really I love this style.
Speaker 0: the story of the first game really got me.
Speaker 0: I'm still like chewing through the second one.
Speaker 0: I will say that a lot of people I know really loved it.
Speaker 0: I'm still working on it.
Speaker 0: well you know I finished it but like I'm still kind of integrating it.
Speaker 0: so we'll see how I end up on that one.
Speaker 2: is that it?
Speaker 2: that's you that's your games.
Speaker 0: yeah I beat persona.
Speaker 0: I dabbled in Final Fantasy 14 briefly because there's an online one.
Speaker 0: yeah yeah there was this kind of like resurgence and I had this hot cat boy named cat face.
Speaker 0: yammer I mean yeah right like.
Speaker 0: come on I had the opportunity to be a hot cat boy so that that was.
Speaker 0: that was there for a bit but I I don't think I have the time right now to do MMOs.
Speaker 0: it turns out big surprise.
Speaker 2: yeah I think is I have almost invented free time and I would have time for MMOs.
Speaker 2: like I learned my lesson with the realm in 1997. man I played.
Speaker 1: I played more World of Warcraft than I probably should have back in college I'll say thankful to the muds of the 90s for protecting me from the 3d muds of the 2000s.
Speaker 2: now you didn't get your immunization.
Speaker 2: that's your problem.
Speaker 0: yeah that's true that's right.
Speaker 2: I saw World of Warcraft.
Speaker 2: I'm like ah I've been there.
Speaker 0: done that you guys are a little older than me right?
Speaker 1: no I saw a picture of you the other day.
Speaker 2: I was cleaning up my like photos and I have a picture of you from back in the air like an RIT like standing in the front of the anime club.
Speaker 2: you look like you're like six.
Speaker 1: is he wearing an orange safety cone?
Speaker 1: you were.
Speaker 2: yeah that was the orange safety code.
Speaker 1: I was wearing a Naruto costume.
Speaker 2: yep that was.
Speaker 2: that was that day.
Speaker 0: still one of my proudest stage moments man thank you.
Speaker 0: thank you for bringing that apparently alrighty.
Speaker 1: anime is still going strong too like I read yeah we saw those people at kinetic on and also anime Boston.
Speaker 1: so whoa hey well not not the old people from back in the day like the current RIT anime club came.
Speaker 2: there's a little like there's weird like genetic memory of us.
Speaker 0: that's that's amazing man.
Speaker 0: so you guys asked me what games I'm playing.
Speaker 0: I gave you.
Speaker 0: I gave you the good answer.
Speaker 0: now I have to give you the bad answer.
Speaker 0: oh alright so this one's a two-parter.
Speaker 0: okay I'm really sorry.
Speaker 0: fruits of gracias came out on steam.
Speaker 1: I don't know what that is.
Speaker 0: oh man Scott I have good news for you.
Speaker 0: it is a half a million word visual novel that was initially a.
Speaker 1: I guess I don't have to worry about the replay value.
Speaker 2: I tell fruits and it recommended that immediately before I typed of what's it about.
Speaker 0: so you play as the worst person in the world who rolls into this town and is obviously connected somehow with like the Japanese military and you're immediately arrested.
Speaker 0: and then you are sent to this school where there are only four other.
Speaker 0: you have four classmates all of whom are romance options and a principal.
Speaker 2: wait there's five girls on the corny or not?
Speaker 0: oh it's super.
Speaker 0: well not the steam version.
Speaker 0: oh is it five?
Speaker 0: did I get the number wrong?
Speaker 0: it is five.
Speaker 2: I say yeah this is an adult visual novel it is super adult but it has that many words in it.
Speaker 0: yeah yeah well it is.
Speaker 0: I mean I don't know.
Speaker 0: are you familiar with love love?
Speaker 2: no wait this many words.
Speaker 2: listen I feel like this is gonna be so.
Speaker 1: apparently you've done a. being a creator of visual novels.
Speaker 1: you seem to have done a lot of research on what is available out there.
Speaker 0: let me give it just an actual shout out right now to the writer of hustle cad Casey Van Hise for digging in to mov love.
Speaker 0: she got further in that game that I thought humanly possible.
Speaker 0: but if you like this the creator of attack on Titan actually went out of his way to say like hey I really I really loved mov love like it was a lot of that in that scenario that I really enjoyed.
Speaker 1: if you were not playing that and learning to draw better that would be because of it works for the body horror thing.
Speaker 2: but so my character design is some body horror here.
Speaker 0: oh man the mov love character designs are rough.
Speaker 2: let me tell you that reminds me of old savor marionette Jay crossed with like.
Speaker 2: I don't know MK are.
Speaker 1: I do always like the hairs that come forward like where there should be sideburns but they're long because she looks like that Tokimeki girl the one that you always know.
Speaker 1: I always like that.
Speaker 0: so so this game starts off as a normal high school romance simulator and it's a normal visual novel and there's two romance or five or four romance translated these things no one with hundreds of thousands of words.
Speaker 0: this is the one with hundreds of thousands of words.
Speaker 0: also this one also has it and this was a fan translation.
Speaker 0: so you you play this normal high school romance and then you beat it with these two romance options and then the game restarts into this ruined world where you're a mech pilot and all the women have to wear suits to show their boobies off and by that I mean there's glass panes on their boobies.
Speaker 1: well I didn't have the booby part.
Speaker 1: I definitely want to play the game where the world is ruined and you're a mech pilot.
Speaker 0: okay well so yeah no me too for what it's worth.
Speaker 0: we were like okay we just have to get through.
Speaker 0: it's called movlev.
Speaker 0: extra is the opening sequence and the movlev alternative the back half ruined world part and we were actually kind of excited about this because we were all reading attack on Titan at the time and Hajime Isayama was like yeah you know this was kind of an.
Speaker 0: I don't know if he said inspiration but he definitely mentioned the ruined world.
Speaker 0: okay yeah yeah.
Speaker 0: and so we were like yeah okay and then we started playing.
Speaker 0: it is like oh actually part of what Hajime Isayama?
Speaker 0: Is that his name?
Speaker 0: I might be screwing his name up.
Speaker 1: I'm so sorry.
Speaker 0: so part of what I think he took away from this was the intense jingoism and and like remilitarization of Japan and like you got it got mega uncomfortable in there for a second because this actually we were playing this right about the time when Mr.
Speaker 0: Isayama took all that heat for saying that stuff about Korea.
Speaker 1: yeah yeah so I mean aren't the otaku's who play these things in Japan usually also military fanboys?
Speaker 1: so isn't it?
Speaker 1: just like you know that's the audience.
Speaker 0: I mean there is a show now where young girls turn into battleships.
Speaker 0: so it's not.
Speaker 0: no I didn't.
Speaker 1: you see the airplane one - no yeah there's plenty of these things.
Speaker 0: I wanted to believe this was a new phenomenon.
Speaker 1: I mean I guess it's new relative to the history of the universe.
Speaker 2: I don't know what the first one was.
Speaker 1: that's a good quote.
Speaker 1: katsu would know.
Speaker 2: katsu would know.
Speaker 0: so this is mov love.
Speaker 0: and then the game I'm playing is fruits of Grisaia which smells weirdly like it.
Speaker 0: it's been.
Speaker 0: it's been rough guys.
Speaker 0: I okay more more geek nights exclusive some some deep insider tips.
Speaker 0: I run a Twitter by the handle fuck game tweets and I started taking screenshots of this game and putting them next to the steam review quotes.
Speaker 2: so my uh my one small anecdote is way back.
Speaker 2: I was with a bunch of like business contact people in.
Speaker 2: I was in Singapore at the time at a party on the roof of a fancy hotel and we're hanging out and people talking.
Speaker 2: no one gives a shit about the finance stuff.
Speaker 2: they're all asking about the video game stuff like oh my god you go to PAX like ah and we start talking about a pecs - look how much money you have.
Speaker 2: yeah go well but I was like you lecture packs get me a job in the game industry.
Speaker 2: I hate Wall Street like that's.
Speaker 2: you have so much money like making visual novels and there's a beat where I always pause because I expect these people to be like what's a visual novel.
Speaker 2: and I'm like already know what I'm gonna say.
Speaker 2: and the guy I'm talking to without skipping a beat doesn't say what's a visual novel.
Speaker 2: he says oh those Asian fuck games cool.
Speaker 0: and he was right about our first title.
Speaker 0: those boys in space are definitely just cramming.
Speaker 2: you know I like Starfighter but also I'm not just gonna say that relationship is not a hundred percent healthy like there's a little bit every every sexual encounter in Starfighter Eclipse is overtly consensual and we actually made sure of this in a copy editing pass.
Speaker 0: this was part of our copy editing process.
Speaker 0: yeah it was to make sure that every sexual encounter was explicitly consensual and I was just saying that.
Speaker 1: I'm guessing that's.
Speaker 1: are you saying that it's not the case?
Speaker 1: in love?
Speaker 0: I didn't play enough love love in.
Speaker 0: in there is at least a character that would definitely get you put into big-boy jail romancing.
Speaker 1: I mean I wasn't gonna play this but now I'm double not gonna play this.
Speaker 0: yeah no I had that problem.
Speaker 0: I played this overdrive game called the Edelweiss and I basically beat this game.
Speaker 0: I got all the roots except for the character who looked super young and I was like I can't finish this game.
Speaker 0: sorry bye that was the game.
Speaker 0: that was actually the game that I broke by trying to go the platonic route.
Speaker 0: oh yeah I didn't accept anybody's advances and then the game crashed.
Speaker 0: it just straight-up crashed and I reproduced the bug.
Speaker 2: you know if you open that bug ticket like they wouldn't understand.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that that might have been by their previous company groover.
Speaker 0: so hi what's up?
Speaker 0: I'm a font of visual novel knowledge.
Speaker 0: come at me.
Speaker 0: anyway I've been playing this game which has been really really sad.
Speaker 1: this you know though I can't fault you because one is legit research and two I mean if my job was to make these things I'd have to suffer through them.
Speaker 0: it raised a half a million dollars on Kickstarter.
Speaker 2: whoa yeah well uh we've played a lot of kick-started board games and all I will say is that sometimes I'll get an email.
Speaker 2: in fact recently we got an email from a pretty big name game developer who didn't like that.
Speaker 2: we'd played his game and talked about it.
Speaker 2: the way that we talked about it because we were kind of down on it.
Speaker 2: we played a lot of bad games.
Speaker 0: yeah what are they gonna do?
Speaker 0: like come to your house and be like hey stop talking about our game like yeah do that maybe make a better game next time.
Speaker 2: but lately the thing I've been watching a lot on YouTube is red suprays.
Speaker 2: you know about red supray?
Speaker 0: I mean it sounds like you're saying let's play but wrong.
Speaker 2: so what they do is they watch other people's let's plays and they just make fun of them and this concept sounds really mean-spirited.
Speaker 2: it kind of is.
Speaker 0: it sounds like it?
Speaker 2: yeah and yeah I learned a lot about what it means to be human watching those things the the best one ever is just titled Mario party of one.
Speaker 1: all right where they watch the guy play Mario party by himself.
Speaker 2: what are you doing in there Johnny?
Speaker 2: nothing just me and my four friends or my three friends.
Speaker 1: calm calm and calm.
Speaker 1: we're just having a having a big ol Mario party.
Speaker 2: and the worst part is the kid loses to the AI like kind of often you got too many stars.
Speaker 2: at one point princess peach like runs way past him with a mushroom and then he just like ah she's running away from me just like all the girls do and then he just gets quiet for like a minute.
Speaker 0: this guy's got to work on his radio voice.
Speaker 0: yeah no kidding.
Speaker 0: why does everybody around me keep dying?
Speaker 0: I hate this game.
Speaker 0: I don't want to remilitarize Japan.
Speaker 1: yeah so I'm military Japan to kill the people who made Mario Party.
Speaker 0: so I've been playing Grisaia which has been a slog.
Speaker 0: but guys I fell into the trap.
Speaker 0: I've been playing love live.
Speaker 0: I've been playing it.
Speaker 0: I've been playing it a lot it's it's been troublesome.
Speaker 2: you know at least you're not stagnating because I still only pretty much play like counter-strikes at five.
Speaker 1: I'm playing hearthstone and netrunner and I just started playing a cookie clicker variant call hi it was on steam yesterday.
Speaker 2: yeah it's a good reason.
Speaker 0: I saw people were all these people in my.
Speaker 1: it kept saying that like people were playing this game you know and my steam friends.
Speaker 1: and it was called like capitalist something.
Speaker 1: and I'm like what the hell is that?
Speaker 1: and I see it's free to play so I could play and it's just a cookie clicker candy box but it's really slick.
Speaker 1: so I'm like oh okay and it runs while like it's closed.
Speaker 1: it's refined heroin.
Speaker 0: yeah exactly so I'm just like oh what if I mean that is that is for what it's worth.
Speaker 0: refined heroin is how I would describe my time with a love life.
Speaker 0: they limit you have like it's.
Speaker 0: it's that classic concept that gets me every goddamn time.
Speaker 0: they give you a fixed amount of energy.
Speaker 0: they say you want to play a hard song.
Speaker 0: you got to provide 15 love points.
Speaker 0: yeah I only have 40. but man I'm so close to my next level.
Speaker 0: I paid a dollar.
Speaker 2: okay I'd say you didn't go past so far.
Speaker 1: I bought both hearthstone adventure expansions which cost a lot more than a dollar.
Speaker 0: I needed one love gem to collect my 11 rare card.
Speaker 0: I was like I'm not gonna wait.
Speaker 0: I could have I could guys I could have waited three hours.
Speaker 1: I mean it's it's surprising like how I've been hooked on so many of those over time but I've managed to just drop all of them.
Speaker 1: and like I played the one where you grow the molar fish oh I played that for like weeks and then one day I just lead it from my phone and then it was deleted from my memory.
Speaker 1: like I just didn't have any instinct to go and open it up or any memory of it or any care.
Speaker 0: that's exactly what happened to be at fallout shelter.
Speaker 1: exactly same thing with fallout shelter.
Speaker 1: and same thing with dragon coins which is the coin pushing machine.
Speaker 1: where then you also have they also fight like an RPG style.
Speaker 1: it's weird.
Speaker 2: yeah that game.
Speaker 2: well you show me that game and all I could saw the whole time.
Speaker 2: all I asked you was why are you playing this?
Speaker 2: I and then I just needed it and then I know the state fair and put quarters in that machine.
Speaker 2: it's the same thing.
Speaker 1: at least one of the state fair gives you money.
Speaker 1: this one tries to take your money and it gives you fake money in replacement.
Speaker 2: yeah so so more importantly are you?
Speaker 2: uh are you caught up on any animes?
Speaker 2: are you watching?
Speaker 1: see my time animes on Tuesday.
Speaker 0: okay so I mean me and Joe actually made sure to get nice and caught up.
Speaker 0: that was that was nice.
Speaker 2: yeah Scott doesn't watch again.
Speaker 2: I'm just trying to pressure him into watching it so we can do a show on.
Speaker 1: it's it.
Speaker 1: I downloaded it.
Speaker 2: I want to do like geek nights presents Steven Universe.
Speaker 1: well I've been sure.
Speaker 1: antenna first.
Speaker 0: I really enjoy it.
Speaker 0: uh as far as as far as anime we're watching gacham on crowds right now.
Speaker 1: I heard about.
Speaker 1: that looked interesting.
Speaker 2: we reviewed it already.
Speaker 1: do I need to watch any other gachamons any things?
Speaker 1: I've watched that.
Speaker 0: so I'm on the first season.
Speaker 1: and how does it know the one?
Speaker 1: how does it relate to the old gosh man with the bird people?
Speaker 0: that's very good.
Speaker 1: what is the connection I have?
Speaker 0: no I did not know.
Speaker 0: there was an original betraying somewhat my my.
Speaker 0: okay.
Speaker 0: so yeah we're watching gacham on crowds.
Speaker 0: that's been great.
Speaker 0: or a Monogatari is I think the sweetest yes ever been produced?
Speaker 2: that show gets so many points for the third episode.
Speaker 1: why don't you make the visual novel of that?
Speaker 0: I would man.
Speaker 0: hey put me in touch with somebody.
Speaker 0: let's go do it.
Speaker 1: who cares?
Speaker 1: if they try to stop you are they gonna do about it?
Speaker 0: see once you have a company these things become very.
Speaker 1: you just release that one on like BitTorrent no one knows.
Speaker 2: no one knows it was you?
Speaker 0: that's right and no one can pay.
Speaker 0: and then we don't eat.
Speaker 1: you can get donations you know.
Speaker 2: well you also make it a crypto Bitcoin.
Speaker 0: did I tell you guys I cashed out all my bitcoins for magic cards.
Speaker 0: what that's real?
Speaker 1: why would you get magic?
Speaker 1: wait bitcoins are like a new thing.
Speaker 1: that means you've played magic this recently.
Speaker 1: yeah why are you playing magic?
Speaker 2: wait did you buy them on Mount Gox?
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 0: okay legitimate question.
Speaker 0: no I bought them on Abu games.
Speaker 0: calm.
Speaker 0: the only retailer I could find basically it was during that massive crash that happened in like January.
Speaker 2: I believe they were crashing.
Speaker 0: yeah I I.
Speaker 1: so when did you get bitcoins?
Speaker 0: uh late last year.
Speaker 1: so recently yeah yeah by drugs.
Speaker 1: but why would you buy Bitcoin?
Speaker 0: I was legitimately just curious.
Speaker 1: so I just like how big lines work.
Speaker 0: there is a tale of woe here because I mined out to full goddamn bitcoins.
Speaker 0: you actually mind coins?
Speaker 0: straight up mind about a fair use GPU.
Speaker 2: yeah there was a time you could just mine coins that we consumer PC.
Speaker 0: oh there was a time you could do it.
Speaker 0: I never even try you.
Speaker 0: and then they're.
Speaker 0: they're gone now I don't know where they live and some kind of wallet who knows yeah in a wallet that I don't have access to and is lost.
Speaker 0: the problem with Bitcoin yeah one of the things right like.
Speaker 0: okay for real can we talk about the money supply of Bitcoin?
Speaker 0: super fast does the money supply continue to shrink like that is?
Speaker 0: dipshits like me lose their wallets?
Speaker 2: uh well yes but because they're so divisible it probably doesn't matter.
Speaker 2: I don't know like I don't think the inflation of them.
Speaker 2: I'm more worried about the integrity of the integrity of the Bitcoin chain over time.
Speaker 0: yeah okay thank you given.
Speaker 0: given like high-profile investments by like the Winklevoss twin yeah like.
Speaker 2: yeah.
Speaker 2: if someone has a controlling interest in the blockchain and they already might yep then they own Bitcoin yeah which is honestly like I had a couple there.
Speaker 0: I didn't have a couple.
Speaker 0: I had a couple and lost them.
Speaker 0: I had some shreds Bitcoin dust.
Speaker 0: I guess I turned him into magic cards and I'm done so.
Speaker 2: I'm on the committee in the FPL to basically figure out how to normalize Bitcoin and blockchain transactions in financial protocols.
Speaker 2: so like exchanges can like use them in stream how about you work on the confirmation time?
Speaker 0: somehow?
Speaker 0: how about you get in touch with mr.
Speaker 0: Satoshi?
Speaker 0: yeah see what he can do for you reducing that confirmation time.
Speaker 0: because if yeah sorry hey what's up?
Speaker 0: never mind I'm not gonna turn this in a Bitcoin.
Speaker 1: yes I guess we know it's not Conrad Satoshi cradling.
Speaker 2: he's planting a red herring here right now.
Speaker 0: okay so I understand how payments work.
Speaker 0: if I'm fucking piece of gum I can't wait 30 minutes to find out if I have the bitcoins for it.
Speaker 0: I need to be able to pay and leave the CBS.
Speaker 2: but you could do that to buy say illegal merchandise that's being shipped to you in a dead drop.
Speaker 1: yeah wait this is still Tuesday gaming.
Speaker 1: right you're just talking about magic cards.
Speaker 1: why are you playing magic?
Speaker 1: what?
Speaker 1: what's going on there?
Speaker 2: wait what magic is this?
Speaker 1: 1995?
Speaker 2: wait with these individual magic cards over these boxes very individuals wait what cars did you buy?
Speaker 1: much magic are you playing and what decks are you playing?
Speaker 0: okay so I unfortunately you know this is during a time when when I was doing some freelance work I had disposable income but I also had some like time.
Speaker 2: well you dispose of it?
Speaker 2: alright.
Speaker 0: well no I just supposed to bitcoins.
Speaker 0: it was very convenient.
Speaker 0: so I you know we were playing and and I got I got some some cards.
Speaker 0: I got them.
Speaker 0: I had a deck that was based around Zalgo zergo helm smasher namely because we were playing commander and I really like the suit.
Speaker 0: I wanted to run a goblin deck.
Speaker 0: he was an ogre.
Speaker 0: so I made this like like green and nasty except it was white red black.
Speaker 2: yeah that's too many colors for commander.
Speaker 0: you actually want a three color spread.
Speaker 0: three color spreads of commander are totally valid.
Speaker 1: okay Wow magic's changed a lot.
Speaker 0: yeah yeah rather than just doing the standard format where you have like 20 life and you know I forget what the optimal deck size is we never play.
Speaker 0: stand.
Speaker 2: back in my day in the old days 40 was the minimum.
Speaker 1: well yeah when I play back in the 90s it would in the.
Speaker 1: in the instruction book it said 40 was the minimum but at the tournament 60 was the minute.
Speaker 0: yeah correct right I believe you guys have the right of it.
Speaker 0: and again I'm betraying the fact that I don't play standard I only play commander.
Speaker 2: well we're betraying the fact that I stopped playing magic when fallen empires came out.
Speaker 0: hey listen I'm not gonna throw stone like.
Speaker 0: obviously I'm in a glass house right now just like you know.
Speaker 0: we got.
Speaker 0: we got really into it again and but but my interest has waned.
Speaker 0: I think I love net runner.
Speaker 0: don't don't get me wrong.
Speaker 0: I had the privilege of playing with some some fine folks a couple months ago and it was.
Speaker 0: it was a blast yeah.
Speaker 1: so why don't you play at all time?
Speaker 1: you got meetups on anymore.
Speaker 0: I turned.
Speaker 0: I turned bitcoins into magic.
Speaker 1: I turned magic money into magic cards and now I can't just turn the magic cards in an hour your cards and you'll be done or back into bitcoins.
Speaker 1: I guess that's that opens your options a lot wider - you can just turn me into drugs.
Speaker 1: yeah drugs drugs for drugs.
Speaker 2: wait is this?
Speaker 0: oh I'm going to jail now.
Speaker 1: nevermind I know Adderall's been a hot topic on this show and that's right.
Speaker 0: no white person has ever gone to jail for taking Adderall.
Speaker 2: no I saw the worst statistic.
Speaker 2: it basically said that like marijuana is legal for white people in New York State.
Speaker 1: yep pretty much.
Speaker 2: by the way the arrests have broken down.
Speaker 2: I believe you're white.
Speaker 2: you could just have all the weed you want.
Speaker 0: is it targeted?
Speaker 0: you can run.
Speaker 2: yes almost all of the enforcement of marijuana laws in New York City was during stop-and-frisk.
Speaker 0: oh go figure.
Speaker 2: yeah it turns out there weren't that many guns just guys with like half a roach in their bags of weed.
Speaker 0: yeah yeah cool good job New York.
Speaker 0: thanks Bill.
Speaker 2: yeah Bill actually Bill's shutting that down.
Speaker 2: thank Bill's actually doing his best job he can.
Speaker 2: the problem is bill doesn't actually decide anything.
Speaker 1: there's been less whoa.
Speaker 1: there's been less gaming on this Tuesday show percentage.
Speaker 1: I'm so sorry than any Tuesday show I have done.
Speaker 1: not that I disagree with anything.
Speaker 1: that was just because I don't how to lose money.
Speaker 0: a Bitcoin the counter curling story.
Speaker 1: Bitcoin is sort of a game a losing game game.
Speaker 2: yes the Winklevoss sorry I've actually give you if you played a crypt of the neck or dancer.
Speaker 0: I'm not familiar with this.
Speaker 2: now there's kind of a rhythm.
Speaker 1: is a rhythm roguelike but it's not too much rhythm I need.
Speaker 1: it needs more rhythm.
Speaker 2: it's way more rhythm.
Speaker 2: you just haven't played it.
Speaker 1: they added more rhythm.
Speaker 2: you pull its rhythm in that the the enemies have really complex patterns uh-huh.
Speaker 2: so it's a rhythm roguelike as in.
Speaker 2: move move move dig move potion spell move.
Speaker 2: I don't know what else.
Speaker 2: I can say you just play it.
Speaker 1: huh it rims really into that lately.
Speaker 0: it sounds fun.
Speaker 0: it sounds like a blast.
Speaker 0: I played a sneak beat.
Speaker 0: I believe it was called on iOS back in the day.
Speaker 0: that was fun.
Speaker 2: yeah we're not playing.
Speaker 0: love live now.
Speaker 0: so just bury me.
Speaker 1: I guess all right are we done here?
Speaker 2: I think we're done.
Speaker 2: it's been about an hour.
Speaker 1: okay yeah we're good.
Speaker 2: there's supposedly an excuse to trick Conrad and come into our house.
Speaker 2: we can hang out.
Speaker 1: I'm yeah I'm hungry.
Speaker 2: yeah I could cook some food.
Speaker 2: I got some shrimps.
Speaker 0: that'd be great.
Speaker 0: so so thank you guys.
Speaker 0: so much for having me on the show.
Speaker 1: I'll sell you.
Speaker 1: sell your things to anyone who's the five people listening.
Speaker 0: I really appreciate you taking the time I do schedule to talk to me.
Speaker 0: I you know I'm kind of curling date night.
Speaker 0: Oh calm just like it sounds you can play an 18-plus visual novel where boys just get into each other in this beautiful 80s sci-fi pastiche.
Speaker 0: we got a Kickstarter coming up probably sometime in September.
Speaker 0: we've got a game definitely coming out in September.
Speaker 0: we know the devil collaboration piece with zeal and a BB and Mia Schwartz.
Speaker 0: I love you.
Speaker 2: yeah oh yeah and come see us all at PAX.
Speaker 0: come see us all at PAX not me.
Speaker 0: I won't be there you're not going.
Speaker 0: I'll be there but I won't be there.
Speaker 0: you'll be on the panel be on the panel you'll be.
Speaker 2: you'll be maybe in the audience asking really really interesting questions.
Speaker 0: no I probably won't know.
Speaker 2: you're not gonna ask a question.
Speaker 2: no I think we're not gonna take questions.
Speaker 2: good this has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 2: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 2: remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.