Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, March 17th, 2015.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, the games of PAX East.
Speaker 1: 2015.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: God, we keep missing, like, weeks of shows at a time because, like, we get back from PAX and then I go overseas or some bullshit.
Speaker 1: And that happened again, so the last show we did was the games of PAX South.
Speaker 1: And I guess now it's time to talk about the games at PAX East because another PAX happened.
Speaker 0: There are no more PAXes until PAX Prime in September.
Speaker 0: In August, I guess, so it's a long time from now.
Speaker 1: Of course, in between, we've got ZenkaiCon, Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: But those are only on weekends.
Speaker 0: Those aren't overlapping any show days.
Speaker 0: True.
Speaker 1: But I'm going to London again next week, so...
Speaker 0: Well, other than you going somewhere, I see no reason why, barring something else crazy happening, that we won't have a lot of usual scheduled Geek Nights episodes.
Speaker 1: And the good news is...
Speaker 0: Between now and PAX Prime.
Speaker 1: And we'll talk about them at the moment, but we've got some stuff in the hopper that's not regular episodes.
Speaker 1: There's actually content on the way.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so, Potline Miami 2 came out.
Speaker 0: It sure did.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Have you played it yet?
Speaker 0: I bought it.
Speaker 0: I preordered it.
Speaker 0: Then I realized, like, a day after that you could install it, that I could install it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I also preordered it.
Speaker 1: I only knew that it came out because I was playing Civ V.
Speaker 0: I knew because I think someone tweeted about it, and I was like, "Oh, did that come out
Speaker 0: yet?".
Speaker 0: I opened up Steam and it said "Install" instead of, "This is coming out
Speaker 0: soon.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, on my flight home from London, I came back business class, so there was like a power jack on my seat and everything.
Speaker 1: So I played Civ V the whole way home, and I'm about halfway through a pretty good game, so I just kept playing it after I got home.
Speaker 1: And then I stopped the game to, like, take a break, and then that Steam news was up that you always ignore because it's just an annoying pop-up.
Speaker 0: I turned that off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I forgot.
Speaker 1: I just didn't think to, and it's like, "Hey, Hotline Miami
Speaker 1: 2.".
Speaker 1: And I was like, "Oh, right.
Speaker 1: All
Speaker 1: right.".
Speaker 1: I was going to play it, but I didn't.
Speaker 0: So Hotline Miami 2 is disappointingly not Hotline Miami 1.
Speaker 1: All I wanted was more Hotline Miami 1.
Speaker 0: It is, in a way, right?
Speaker 0: The music is there.
Speaker 0: It's pumping.
Speaker 0: It is pumping awesome music.
Speaker 0: But, despite it being pumping awesome music of a soundtrack that I will put and listen to on purpose outside of the game, it's that good.
Speaker 0: There is no individual song that stands out as so amazing like
Speaker 0: "Hydrogen.".
Speaker 1: I was about to say, there's no "Hydrogen"?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that song is not in there.
Speaker 1: Man, I work out to that song.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a good song.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so that's number one.
Speaker 0: Number two, the visual style of the game has been upgraded and is amazing times a billion.
Speaker 0: It's like '80s neon... I mean, it's the same as it was before, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I knew that...
Speaker 0: It's the same generic, you know, aesthetic.
Speaker 1: I did play it at a PAX.
Speaker 0: But it's so much more polished and cranked the fuck up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I saw it at a PAX.
Speaker 1: I played it at a PAX.
Speaker 0: I want to look at it all the time.
Speaker 0: It's so good looking.
Speaker 0: Even though it's still pixely.
Speaker 1: But, there's a big butt hanging over this.
Speaker 0: So the butt...
Speaker 1: Butt of Damocles.
Speaker 0: Is that the actual game, right, is mechanically mostly the same, right?
Speaker 0: You're still top down, walk around, hit things, knock a guy out, right?
Speaker 0: But it seems like there have been subtle changes to the mechanics.
Speaker 0: You know, like in the terms of the way the doors, you know, hit a little bit.
Speaker 0: It feels like they've been changed slightly.
Speaker 1: Now that would be fine, because some of that stuff is kind of broken.
Speaker 0: It feels like it's been sped up a little bit.
Speaker 1: That would be good too.
Speaker 0: But really, it's... you know how in the early... It's like they made these subtle changes, but somehow only subtly changing things has fundamentally changed what the game is about.
Speaker 0: Hotline Miami 1 is about puzzle solving.
Speaker 0: Like, okay, I can take all these guys out, but what order do I do it in?
Speaker 0: Do I have to do...
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'd be like door, door, shoot, back.
Speaker 0: Right, okay, there's a room with three guys in it.
Speaker 0: I can see that one guy is walking around in a circle.
Speaker 0: So I gotta open the door when he's next to the door.
Speaker 0: He has a baseball bat.
Speaker 0: I can immediately grab that and throw it at the guy with the gun before he shoots me.
Speaker 0: The other guy's a melee guy, so he's gonna rush at me.
Speaker 0: I can just punch him out.
Speaker 0: Then I can run over and get the gun and kill everyone, and that's how I'm gonna take this.
Speaker 0: And it's about, once you figure it out, pretty easy to execute in Hotline Miami 1.
Speaker 1: It's all about rhythm, beats, and of course, you know, the game did randomize a little bit, so it could have like 100% strategy, but it was good.
Speaker 1: It was like strategy plus tactical deviation when things don't go the way you planned.
Speaker 0: Later on, in the later levels of Hotline Miami 1, shit was balls hard, right?
Speaker 0: Where it's like, you know, you'd feel like, "Oh, that hurt really
Speaker 0: bad."
Speaker 0: Or, "Oh man, this is so frustrating.
Speaker 0: I can't do this even though I figured it
Speaker 0: out.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, there were one or two where I'd wait until like Arundo had a knife, and then I could do it, and I couldn't really unless I got that knife.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: So, Hotline Miami 2 is pretty much, instead of like having the same sort of, you know, curve from, you know, easy to hard, it just pretty much picks off where Hotline Miami 1 left off in terms of hard.
Speaker 1: Now, that I like.
Speaker 1: It's not good for the game or gamers as a whole, but it's good for me.
Speaker 1: It's like the problem when I play a new Advance Wars and the whole first half of the game is completely stupid.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 1: See, also, Metroidvanias.
Speaker 0: Sort of.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But, the other problem is that it's just sort of unfairly hard, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I saw like Mitchie D tweeted something to the effect of most of his deaths were off-screen gunshots.
Speaker 0: Yes, most of my deaths are off-screen gunshots.
Speaker 0: For example, it's like, there's a spot where it's like, okay, you can press shift and move the mouse around to see farther, but there's a limit to how far you can see.
Speaker 0: So, I can see like, okay, I'm going into a hallway.
Speaker 0: There's a guy patrolling.
Speaker 0: He comes near the door.
Speaker 0: I just have to open the door when he's near it.
Speaker 0: The hallway is otherwise empty.
Speaker 0: At the other end of the hallway, I can see that there's a window, right?
Speaker 0: But, I can't see farther than the window.
Speaker 0: So, there's nothing I can really do about that.
Speaker 0: So, I wait for the guy to come.
Speaker 0: I push the door down.
Speaker 0: I grab the guy's weapon, and then I try to go and seek cover.
Speaker 0: While I'm seeking cover, bullets come through that window.
Speaker 0: that was so far away, because now that I've moved like a very small amount, I've now moved to in range of that window, and this line of sight from this bad guy with a gun beyond that window, who has instant, basically all the bad guys are crazy fast and have perfect aimbots.
Speaker 1: See now, at least in one, there are a small number of places that were like that, but that was like a turret in Portal 2.
Speaker 0: This is like the beginning of the goddamn game.
Speaker 0: So far, every level has at least one or two bullshit spots, where you sort of just get killed by guys that are off-screen that you couldn't know about, and you can either go ridiculously slowly and still fail occasionally, or just go for it until eventually you manage to not get killed by some bullshit.
Speaker 1: This is actually kind of disappointing, because it's much like how Bionic Commando Rearmed was amazing, and then they made a sequel that just had that little jump hop, and they changed a few little mechanics, and the game just wasn't spiritually true to the thing I actually liked.
Speaker 1: See also, every WarioWare before or after the GameCube one.
Speaker 0: So I mean, it's not an awful game, it's still Hotline Miami, right?
Speaker 1: I'll still play it.
Speaker 0: It's just not as good as Hotline Miami 1, you know, it's not going, it's not gonna like, if it had, the thing is, if it had been as good, it would have like turned this into like an epic series of like, "Oh my god, where's Hotline Miami 3?
Speaker 0: Let's
Speaker 0: go.".
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: This shit is for reals, it's not gonna stop.
Speaker 1: Maybe they hit their sophomore slump.
Speaker 0: Right, like it would have been, you know, a new, you know, whole category, right?
Speaker 0: Like Zelda or Mario is a category.
Speaker 1: Well I mean, look at the longevity, of course it kind of petered out and stopped, of the Castlevania, Metroidvania games, like they died now, like they don't really come out anymore, but...
Speaker 0: They're not dead though, everyone wants them, just no one fucking makes them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're dead, see also all the kinds of games we like.
Speaker 0: Make Symphony of the Day or some shit, or...
Speaker 1: But, those games are all pretty much identical.
Speaker 0: Super Ridley, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and yet, I like the shit out of every one of them.
Speaker 1: So, I feel like unless you are like one of those like auteur game designers, and you have like this brilliant vision of like how to push a game in a different direction or a new direction, don't make a Zelda 2, just make Mario 3.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: So wait, what I said was don't make an okay game, make literally one of the greatest games ever made in the history of gaming.
Speaker 1: Just do that and you'll be fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the thing, is they made a sequel, right?
Speaker 0: And when you make a sequel to say Super Mario Brothers, your sequel is supposed to be Mario 3.
Speaker 0: Right, so the Hotline Miami 2 should have been the Hotline to Mario 3 to Mario 1, right?
Speaker 1: Or it could have been the Mario 2 Doki Doki Panic style, because that, or you know, the Zelda 2...
Speaker 0: Everyone would have just been like, wow, this is nothing like, you know...
Speaker 1: Yes, and everyone was like, wow, you know, in the US, Mario quote unquote 2 is nothing like Mario 1, and yet it still was a super popular game.
Speaker 0: It wasn't Mario 3.
Speaker 1: Well, Mario 3 didn't come out yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they both are in the canon of Mario and they're both great games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Doki Doki Panic is not a great game.
Speaker 0: It's a great game.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Play it again.
Speaker 1: Don't play the shitty remakes that turned it into baby mode.
Speaker 0: How about that Wart?
Speaker 0: Four minutes?
Speaker 0: Four minutes to beat Wart?
Speaker 1: Why are there four minutes left?
Speaker 1: I've been watching more Retsupreis, they're pretty good.
Speaker 1: They're okay, guys.
Speaker 1: So, the game that I played that's new...
Speaker 0: If you're going to play Hotline Miami 2 and you like... If you already played Hotline Miami 1 and beat it, and you're good, and you want to play Hotline Miami 2 because you haven't had enough, wait for the price to go down, because I think I paid like 15 bucks.
Speaker 0: Probably it's going to be $5 during the Steam of Sale.
Speaker 1: It sounds like if you haven't played Hotline Miami 1, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Just go play that.
Speaker 0: How come you didn't get that in the Steam of Sale?
Speaker 1: I mean, you might say, but Riven Scott...
Speaker 0: That game is still amazing.
Speaker 1: But Riven Scott, that game is uncomfortably violent, and the answer is yes, it is really uncomfortably violent.
Speaker 0: The new one, actually, when you first load it up, it says the sexual violence, do you want those scenes to not appear?
Speaker 0: Yes, no.
Speaker 1: You know, that's a good thing that they did, I think.
Speaker 1: Because there are people who otherwise couldn't play the game, or would play the game, and then have a bad time.
Speaker 1: So, it's a lot like X-Card.
Speaker 1: I wish more games did things like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not like we're going to remove this stuff entirely from the game.
Speaker 0: It's like... It's not like a movie where you can't choose, everyone has to watch the same movie, right?
Speaker 0: Why not let people customize the experience in that way?
Speaker 0: But also, why not let people customize the experience in ways that aren't related to sex, violence, disturbing, possibly offensive things?
Speaker 1: What, you mean like difficulty mode, like easy mode or good mode?
Speaker 0: Well, difficulty is one way.
Speaker 1: I mean, one, why not?
Speaker 1: Because adding options like that is a huge, huge investment from design and development.
Speaker 0: Did you hear?
Speaker 0: So, Blizzard is coming out with this Overwatch game, which is basically...
Speaker 1: I heard about Overwatch.
Speaker 0: It's basically their Team Fortress clone, and it's a Team Fortress clone, but made by Blizzard, so it's going to be super polished and whatever, right?
Speaker 1: Yep, they have to go in a slightly different direction.
Speaker 1: This seems to be...
Speaker 0: Blizzard's new thing seems to be, look at every genre of game that's popular and make the best, like, you know, super polished, with all our knowledge and skills, game in that genre.
Speaker 1: Which is interesting, because Valve also makes the super polished games.
Speaker 0: Valve and Blizzard are pretty much going head-to-head lately.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the fact that Valve and Blizzard have...
Speaker 0: In every category.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well both have...
Speaker 0: Dota versus Heroes of the Storm, right?
Speaker 0: Now you've got Overwatch versus TF2, it's on.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this game...
Speaker 1: If you want to do a good panel at a convention, and you want to beat us to the punch, compare the two headliners in each genre from these two companies from a design perspective.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the reason I thought of Overwatch just now is because there was a very ripe discussion about the FOV of the game, which is being locked in at, I think, less than 90.
Speaker 0: Well, fuck it.
Speaker 0: I think it was like 60 or 75 or something.
Speaker 1: Fuck it, never mind, not playing it.
Speaker 0: And you can't change that shit.
Speaker 1: I mean, come on, 120, guys.
Speaker 1: Like, we have wide monitors these days.
Speaker 0: But they, you know, they talked about why they decided to set it at that spot, because, you know...
Speaker 1: Well, Hitler can talk a lot about why he did what he did, too.
Speaker 0: They don't want people to have a competitive advantage.
Speaker 1: Because they're better.
Speaker 0: Because they don't get motion sick.
Speaker 1: I don't care about that aspect.
Speaker 0: They didn't want it to be a game about being able to see a super quick, clicky game, you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: Excuses for not making the game that everyone should make.
Speaker 1: The problem is, if they make the game that everyone should make, it becomes Quake 3.
Speaker 1: I mean, unless you...
Speaker 0: What's wrong with Quake 3?
Speaker 1: Have you played Quake 3 recently?
Speaker 0: I played Quake Live.
Speaker 1: It's not an old man's game.
Speaker 0: No, it is not.
Speaker 1: It is a young man's game.
Speaker 0: Overwatch is not an old man's game either, though.
Speaker 1: It's more of an old man's game.
Speaker 0: It is definitely more of an old man's game.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should play it.
Speaker 1: I mean, as much as I like to say, it's like saying, like, "Yeah, I really want to drive the, like, GTR.
Speaker 1: I want to drive the F1
Speaker 1: car.".
Speaker 1: But in reality, I don't actually want to drive the F1 car.
Speaker 0: If you sat in the F1 car, and you touched the gas pedal, you would die instantly.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: I want to say that I want the F1 car, but the reality is, I'm too old for that game.
Speaker 0: Like, if we just, you know, put you in the seat, and then a feather hit the gas pedal, you would die.
Speaker 1: So, I played Five Nights at Freddy's 3 because of peer pressure.
Speaker 1: I wasn't really going to play it like that.
Speaker 0: Five Nights at Freddy's is like your favorite thing.
Speaker 0: You're obsessed with it.
Speaker 0: You played one and two.
Speaker 0: I didn't play two.
Speaker 1: I thought you did.
Speaker 1: I had to watch a YouTube video.
Speaker 1: I know everything I need to know about two.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I am obsessed with one because, remember, most people, like even gamers, don't really know about that game, and people who aren't like the Scott-- I don't know.
Speaker 0: I heard about it from my coworkers, or I heard about it from you.
Speaker 0: People know about that game.
Speaker 0: You think that, but then like in Australia-- My sister even made a Let's Play video of that game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but like in Australia, like how many people have heard of this game, and one person raised their hand, and like none of our friends who aren't like listening to us and heard about it until I made them play it.
Speaker 1: But, so anyway, Five Nights at Freddy's 3, it came out suddenly.
Speaker 1: You know, the guy, Scott Cawthorne-- That guy is cranking him out.
Speaker 1: That guy knows what he's doing.
Speaker 1: So, it came out suddenly like, "Yo, guys, it's here.
Speaker 1: It's here.
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 1: Just buy
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: And I tweeted like, "Hey, should I play
Speaker 1: it?".
Speaker 1: And a bunch of people were like, "Fuck
Speaker 1: yeah.".
Speaker 1: So I made a Let's Play, and I played it.
Speaker 1: And to review it, because I know Scott doesn't really care, if you like these kinds of games, like a good horror experience, don't try to get good at them because they're stupid if you get good at them.
Speaker 1: They're experiences.
Speaker 1: Play them like a haunted house and be done with them.
Speaker 1: Play one, and then play three.
Speaker 1: I don't think two is actually probably that good of a game if you want that kind of experience.
Speaker 0: But won't you not know the story if you don't play two?
Speaker 1: Unless you really pay attention, you're not going to learn the story fully from playing the game.
Speaker 1: You're going to learn the story from playing the game and seeing Springtrap's death and all this stuff, and then you're going to go to some Wikia and just read what other people figured out because you've got to do some crazy bullshit to actually, actually find out what happened to those kids.
Speaker 1: The lore and the story is actually pretty good, but I think the reason I want to talk about the game, now that three came out, and I don't think he'll make a fourth one.
Speaker 1: I think he'll make a different kind of game after this.
Speaker 0: You don't know what he's thinking.
Speaker 1: I don't at all, but as a trilogy, it's kind of like Cowboy Bebop.
Speaker 1: There's a really contig--.
Speaker 1: Obviously, he made a pretty contiguous, defined story, but he doesn't just tell you the story.
Speaker 1: The story is just used as a consistent backdrop for the rest of the game.
Speaker 1: I like it when horror games do things like that, like an Eva style of, "I tell you what you need to know because I'm actually trying to make you experience
Speaker 1: X.".
Speaker 1: How we got there and who the Purple Man really is is not that important.
Speaker 1: The fact that he exists and there is a consistent-- Is the Purple Man in Five Guys at Freddy's?
Speaker 1: The Purple Man is basically-- So in three, there's the suit, right?
Speaker 1: There's the suit.
Speaker 1: There's only one suit, and it's in the place with you.
Speaker 1: And if it sees you, it just comes in and just kills you.
Speaker 1: But the story is basically to summarize and assume a lot that there's this guy who was luring little kids into a back room and just murdering them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, so there are at least two murderers between the two games.
Speaker 1: One of them was probably a pedophile.
Speaker 1: I think the suits got him.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so the suits, in the old days, there were golden suits that you could wear.
Speaker 1: And to wear them, you had to crank the spring thing, and it would pull back under tension all the AI animatronic bits, and then you could get into the suit.
Speaker 1: And they were prone to catastrophic failure, and they would just explode back into you and just crush your guts.
Speaker 1: So the dude killed all these kids, and then the ghost of the kids confronted him, scared him, and he put on the suit to try to get away from them, and then died in the suit and all this cool stuff.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the game, actually, in terms of horror, it does horror very well and in a much more polished fashion than Five Nights at Freddy's 1, but it does the same kinds of things.
Speaker 1: There's a door on the left that's open, and you have to look way to the right to pull out the camera to see what's going on.
Speaker 1: But behind the camera, you can see through this window into the hallway outside, and you'll see something walk by the window, and you're like, "Oh,
Speaker 1: fuck!".
Speaker 1: And you're trying to fumble out of the camera and look left and see if something's in the door.
Speaker 1: And in a stroke of genius, outside that door, all the time, is a mannequin of a busted Freddy.
Speaker 1: So you always turn and you see it there, and you know it's there, but every time you turn, you're like, "Whoa!
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: "Right.
Speaker 1: Thanks,
Speaker 1: Scott.".
Speaker 0: Hey, look at your right-hand screen.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Speaker 1: They're actually... Okay.
Speaker 0: No one can see this.
Speaker 1: Thanks, Wikia.
Speaker 1: I guess that's the puppet master carrying a dead child somewhere.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, if you like those kinds of games, play one and three.
Speaker 1: Two is more of a stress game instead of a horror game.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: I have a thing of the day that I practically guarantee none of you have seen unless you subscribe to my like stream on YouTube 'cause I just liked this video like a couple hours ago.
Speaker 1: So basically, this dude, Furious Paul, who only has like 100 subscribers, this video has less than 1,000 views, doesn't seem like super well-known yet.
Speaker 1: He seems to be one of those like play games quickly, be good at games guys.
Speaker 1: And he demonstrates an amazing glitch in Castlevania 2, the likes of which I have never seen before.
Speaker 1: Basically, you can get into a crazy glitched out area that is fully navigable and it is possible to traverse from that, which is an expansive giant area, back into the game.
Speaker 0: So it's similar to the Metroid 1 glitches where you get in the door and then jump up the side of the wall.
Speaker 1: It is, except there's way more traversable stuff in there for some reason.
Speaker 1: And at one point, he falls into what looks like an infinite loop and he's like, "Ah,
Speaker 1: alright.".
Speaker 1: And he's like, "I'm gonna see if this goes
Speaker 1: anywhere.".
Speaker 1: And he gets up and goes to the bathroom.
Speaker 1: No, it just keeps falling and falling and falling and falling and falling and falling and falling and bam, lands on a platform and then he just keeps going.
Speaker 1: This was pretty cool.
Speaker 1: And I'm gonna see what this guy's up to because I kind of like his Let's Play style.
Speaker 0: So I just learned about this dude.
Speaker 0: His name is Takanoyama.
Speaker 1: Takanoyama?
Speaker 0: He's a Czechoslovakian dude.
Speaker 0: But he was a sumo wrestler.
Speaker 0: His sumo name was Takanoyama.
Speaker 0: I don't know what his real name was.
Speaker 0: It was something else.
Speaker 0: And this dude did not look like a sumo wrestler because, I mean, he had his hair all sumo'd and he had the underwear or whatever.
Speaker 0: But he tried to become huge but he couldn't become huge even though he tried a whole lot.
Speaker 0: But he was like an awesome judo wrestling kind of dude.
Speaker 0: So it's not like he became the Yokozuna or anything.
Speaker 0: But he won enough to get into the top category a few times.
Speaker 1: So he's still a contender.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he was like in best 30 in the world at one point.
Speaker 0: And he sort of bounced around between the top level and the second highest level.
Speaker 0: And he did really well.
Speaker 0: But it's just awesome to see a dude who is not a humongous sumo wrestler basically throw humongous sumo wrestlers right out of the ring.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because all you gotta do is get that guy out of the ring however you do it.
Speaker 0: So if you look at his, you can see the truth of his career.
Speaker 0: This video makes him look amazing because only his highlight's real.
Speaker 0: Which is amazingly entertaining because you're seeing a non-huge dude throw around huge dudes.
Speaker 0: But if you look on Wikipedia about him, you can see his real record.
Speaker 0: Which is not bad, but it's not like he's the king of all time or anything.
Speaker 0: But still, really awesome video to watch to see a non-fat dude deal with giant fat dudes in an amazing way.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment, the book club book is...
Speaker 0: Sumo wrestling would be awesome if it wasn't corrupt and Yakuza shit.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: You could say that about a lot of things.
Speaker 1: The book club book is still Watership Down, the story of rabbits.
Speaker 0: Oh, I should do something about that.
Speaker 1: On an epic adventure.
Speaker 1: I've already picked my next book club book, so...
Speaker 0: I have too, but I have to finish this one.
Speaker 1: My next one is going to be The Forever War, so...
Speaker 0: What's that?
Speaker 1: Well, you'll find out because you're going to read it.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment, otherwise, we are going to be this coming weekend in...
Speaker 0: I thought it's the next weekend.
Speaker 1: Well, we're in a weekend right now.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're right.
Speaker 1: Because we're recording this show ahead, but not that far ahead.
Speaker 1: So next weekend...
Speaker 0: Which dates?
Speaker 1: The 27th... Well, the 28th and 29th...
Speaker 0: Of March.
Speaker 1: Of March.
Speaker 1: We are going to be in Lancaster, Pennsylvania.
Speaker 0: We're actually probably not going to be there on Friday till way late.
Speaker 0: Check Saturday and Sunday.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: At a convention called Zank icon.
Speaker 1: And we're doing not one, not two, not three, not five, but FOUR lectures.
Speaker 0: Five is right out.
Speaker 1: On Saturday, we're doing How to Win Every Game and Short Form Anime.
Speaker 1: So, like, Damek Adobezu type shit.
Speaker 1: And then on Sunday, we're doing Why No One Will Game With You and Anime Openers From Around the World.
Speaker 1: Completely revamped.
Speaker 1: I found some, like, Italian Lupin.
Speaker 1: that'll make you cry.
Speaker 0: Will it?
Speaker 1: It might.
Speaker 1: It's really bad.
Speaker 1: And we're going to be!
Speaker 1: The weekend immediately after that.
Speaker 1: In Boston.
Speaker 1: At Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Performing a bunch of panels, I assume.
Speaker 1: They haven't really finalized the schedule yet, so I can't say what or when.
Speaker 1: But none of our panels will be Friday morning because we're not actually getting there till Friday afternoon.
Speaker 0: Well, if they don't, then we just won't go.
Speaker 0: We'll just cancel our hotel room and not go.
Speaker 1: Well, all our panels are 9, 10, 11, and 12 a.m.
Speaker 1: And 12 p.m.
Speaker 1: on Friday.
Speaker 1: But I imagine we'll be doing, as we've done every year since we started this tradition, among other panels, judge anime by its cover, where we'll judge the coming season of anime entirely by its cover.
Speaker 1: However, I was already wrong about one, because based on its cover, Maria, the Virgin Witch, I thought was going to be a really bad show and is actually really funny and slayers-like.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the problem is-- But we're going to be talking about the next season, so don't worry about the ones you already messed up.
Speaker 1: Had we judged this season that I'm watching right now by that, there's one we might have been wrong on.
Speaker 0: I mean, we're not 100% perfect.
Speaker 1: Well, in the first, the inaugural one, we were wrong about one show, and that show was Sailor Moon Crystal.
Speaker 1: We thought it would be good.
Speaker 0: I didn't think it would be good.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's a recording of me of what I said, so I don't remember.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know why I said that?
Speaker 0: But I pretty much remember being skep.
Speaker 1: Well, we were skep because it hadn't come out yet.
Speaker 1: It had been delayed heavily.
Speaker 1: But I tweeted a while ago, I was like, "Hey, it's been a couple years.
Speaker 1: Were we wrong about any of
Speaker 1: these?".
Speaker 1: And two people said, "Feeling salty about Sailor
Speaker 1: Moon.".
Speaker 1: So I think we were wrong about that one.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, I assume we're going to be at PAX Prime.
Speaker 1: Start paying attention for hotels and badges and all that because they sell out faster than pretty much any con.
Speaker 0: PAX Prime badges and hotels go on sale really goddamn soon, perhaps this week.
Speaker 1: Yep, keep the eyes out.
Speaker 0: And visit us on the internet.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of places on the internet that you can find us.
Speaker 0: Your Twitters, your Facebooks, our official website, our official forum.
Speaker 0: Twitter is everywhere.
Speaker 1: Our forums have been smoking lately, too, and there's some amazing gamergates trying to argue their case.
Speaker 1: It's like a bunch of, I don't want to say rabbits in the lion's den.
Speaker 0: Our forum is not a place that a gamergate wants to go.
Speaker 0: That would be like someone with a sensitive nose going to the trash dump.
Speaker 1: It is interesting because they... I give those two gentlemen points for persistence.
Speaker 1: If nothing else.
Speaker 0: Well, they haven't actually said something absolutely horrible that we would have to ban them.
Speaker 0: They've just revealed that they're awful people.
Speaker 1: Still funny how none of those people have appeared at any conventions that we've been to.
Speaker 0: Fancy that.
Speaker 1: So we just were at a PAX, we're at another PAX, and it's time to talk about the games we played at PAX East.
Speaker 0: So despite this PAX East having to do panel and do enforcing and all kinds of stuff and play a bunch of wizard and games we've already played, I actually saw and played a lot of new games at this PAX.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And when I got home I was like, "Wow, I did play a bunch of new games at this PAX.
Speaker 0: There's a lot to talk
Speaker 0: about.".
Speaker 1: In fact, we're only going to talk about a subset of the games that stood out at this PAX.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So I think what we're doing is we're basically not talking about the games that stood out in a bad way.
Speaker 0: No, the bad games don't even get stuck in the memory to be talked about.
Speaker 0: And there's a lot of games that we saw that were good that were just repeats, right?
Speaker 0: Video ball.
Speaker 0: There you are again, video ball.
Speaker 0: I've played you for three PAXes in a row.
Speaker 0: Please get released already.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but basically I realized that I can tell now if a game is going to live up to its potential or not.
Speaker 1: immediately without even looking at the screen, just walk past its booth, if there are marketing type people aggressively selling you on it, Bad.
Speaker 1: It's guaranteed bad because the best games like video ball, the game is just selling itself and they're just standing there watching.
Speaker 0: There are also a lot of, especially in the indie games area, which is where all the things you have to pay attention to are because there's nothing to pay attention to in the big industry area at all.
Speaker 0: A lot of the games are starting to just look like rehash, whatever.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh, there's another pixelated, stylized Metroidvania game that's not as good as Super Metroid.
Speaker 0: Don't need to play that.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh, look, it's Ghetto Smash Brothers.
Speaker 0: Oh, look, it's another shmup.
Speaker 0: Okay, I'm done with that.
Speaker 1: Ooh, someone's trying to make a MOBA.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Indie MOBA.
Speaker 0: Here's another crappy iOS mobily game.
Speaker 1: It is amazing how many people buy a for real booth.
Speaker 1: Not an indie booth, but like a for real big money booth to show off their like 99 cent iOS game.
Speaker 1: Like, guys, those games are not that good.
Speaker 1: I can't imagine you get 10,000 sales because you're at PAX.
Speaker 0: There was a game that basically looked like Magical Drop and I was like, ooh, and it's like, no, it was way worse than any, I mean, it was a puzzle game.
Speaker 0: You could play it.
Speaker 0: It was way worse than pretty much any puzzle-y game that I had ever played.
Speaker 1: What really amazed me, though, was that Smash Brothers clone, because it was just like a really, really bad, like it looked like Smash Brothers if it was like a high school development team's project to make it for a quarter.
Speaker 1: Like, it was just not.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about the ones that stood out and weren't just rehash garbage.
Speaker 1: Uh, VA-11 Hall-A.
Speaker 0: In other words, Valhalla.
Speaker 1: Abandoned soberness, all ye who enter here.
Speaker 0: This game was amazing.
Speaker 0: So this game, I looked at it and I saw somewhat pixelated, really, really good anime art.
Speaker 0: I was already like, all right, you have my attention.
Speaker 0: I will see what your game is about.
Speaker 0: Then I saw that it was like all cyberpunk styling, anime arts, and I'm like, anime characters in cyberpunk world, I'm already going to now read every line of text that you have written anywhere in your booth and talk to you peoples, right?
Speaker 0: Then I found out even more amazing, positive information.
Speaker 0: This game is a cyberpunk bartending simulator.
Speaker 0: That is what it is.
Speaker 0: The way it works is very similar to another amazing game of our era.
Speaker 1: Papers, please.
Speaker 0: Papers, please.
Speaker 0: Instead of checking passports for validity, people come up to you because you're a bartender and you produce for them beverages of various natures by combining ingredients.
Speaker 0: Instead of a book telling you how to tell which passports are legit and not, there is a book of recipes and you have ingredients and you prepare the beverages and serve them to the people and they talk to you.
Speaker 0: So really what it is is a visual novel.
Speaker 0: Instead of just directly choosing your own adventure by making choices, you produce alcoholic beverages.
Speaker 0: that then guide the story.
Speaker 1: There's this likely underage girl who shows up and she's like, "Yeah, make me a drink.
Speaker 1: I'm old
Speaker 1: enough.".
Speaker 1: Then you look up the drink she ordered and the recipe is like a normal recipe.
Speaker 1: and then there's an optional ingredient which is some drug and you're not really sure what that drug does.
Speaker 0: You don't know anything.
Speaker 0: You learn by playing this over and over again.
Speaker 1: Do you put that in her drink because she ordered it or because it's optional?
Speaker 1: Do you leave it out or do you not make it for her because you think she's an underage punk?
Speaker 1: But then she glitches out like she might be a hologram anyway.
Speaker 0: It's cyberpunk world, right?
Speaker 1: It is the bar from Aitoru.
Speaker 1: Like 100%.
Speaker 1: It is basically that bar.
Speaker 0: I wonder if the giant Australian dude shows up.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I hope the giant Australian dude shows up.
Speaker 1: He is my second favorite character in that book.
Speaker 0: First favorite?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But yeah.
Speaker 0: So this game is amazing.
Speaker 0: I can't wait for it to come out.
Speaker 0: That's really all there is to say about it.
Speaker 0: It really also reminds me of a game we should talk about at some point that I played which is Long Live the Queen which is a visual novel where you guide the story not by making direct decisions.
Speaker 0: Well, sometimes you make direct decisions.
Speaker 0: But mostly you tell the queen what to learn.
Speaker 0: Like learn about cooking.
Speaker 1: Hey, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Someone's poisoning my food.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like today you should practice archery and you should practice learning history and then in your spare time you should play with your toys.
Speaker 0: And then based on her skills...
Speaker 1: It's a stat builder princess simulator.
Speaker 0: Based on what skills she builds up by choosing these things it ends up automatically doing the choose your own adventure.
Speaker 0: You don't know.
Speaker 0: on day five there's an archery test.
Speaker 0: So if you've practiced enough archery by day five the story goes this way and if you haven't the story goes another way.
Speaker 0: It's like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've played it a little.
Speaker 1: We played a bunch of it actually at New Year's at one point.
Speaker 1: People were playing it in the other room.
Speaker 1: The thing is the trailer for this game will sell you 100% on it alone.
Speaker 0: I'm really liking this trend lately of choose your own adventure but with indirect choosing by some game mechanic.
Speaker 0: I guess that started way back in the Tokimeki days but now is even more polished.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well visual novels are a wide genre.
Speaker 1: I mean there's stat builders.
Speaker 1: There's like just choice trees.
Speaker 1: There's all these different kinds of games.
Speaker 0: But this kind, this is the best one of this kind that I've seen.
Speaker 0: I'm all about this.
Speaker 0: Can't wait.
Speaker 1: Oh wow, the tagline from the actual website.
Speaker 1: Valhalla Cyberpunk Bartender Action is a booze-em-up about waifus, technology, and post-dystopia life.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's what it is.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm so into this.
Speaker 1: So we played this board game.
Speaker 1: Scott bought it.
Speaker 1: Well, it's a card game really.
Speaker 0: So it was on sale at the game salute booth and I had already played it earlier in the day with Matt.
Speaker 0: So I had played the game and it was on sale and it was a really tiny two-player game and I just sold my copy of Jambo to someone else.
Speaker 1: Jambo was not that good.
Speaker 0: Apparently Jambo is a game that is out of print and was in demand and someone said that.
Speaker 0: And I said, "Hey, I have Jambo.
Speaker 0: I've bought it once, played it a few times, and haven't played it since.
Speaker 0: Do you want
Speaker 0: it?".
Speaker 0: They said,
Speaker 0: "Yes.".
Speaker 0: So I mailed it to them in exchange for an Amazon gift certificate.
Speaker 1: Marles the Mushroom, a Brent Povis production.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so this game pretty much fits the same role as Jambo.
Speaker 0: It comes in that sort of Lost Cities, Jambo-sized little tiny box.
Speaker 0: It's 100% card-based and it's a two-player game.
Speaker 0: You can play pretty quickly, but it has a deep strategy to it or it's relatively deep, and it was on sale, so I picked it up.
Speaker 0: It was alright.
Speaker 0: I played it twice at PAX East.
Speaker 1: I played it once, I played it with Scott, it was alright.
Speaker 1: I can see it has that small problem that games like this have.
Speaker 1: Like, what was that?
Speaker 1: The games that are two-player, where in order to be a good game, you do have to know intuitively or count in your head how many of each card there are.
Speaker 1: You need to play the game a couple times.
Speaker 0: It is a game about card counting a bit.
Speaker 0: So the way it works...
Speaker 1: But if both players' card counted, then it is a game of looking the other person in the eye.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so basically the way it works is there's mushrooms in a circle, and you're basically both...
Speaker 1: Twilight Struggle, that's the game I was thinking of.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, both of the two players are walking around the circle, collecting mushrooms.
Speaker 0: You can only collect the mushrooms at your feet easily, right?
Speaker 0: Which are the ones that are next.
Speaker 0: And there are mushrooms farther away, but you need a stick to get to them.
Speaker 0: So when you collect mushrooms, they go in your hand, but you can only hold so many.
Speaker 0: If you get baskets, you can hold a few more.
Speaker 0: And if you collect enough mushrooms of the same kind, you can sell them or cook them.
Speaker 0: If you sell them, you can get sticks, which help you get better mushrooms.
Speaker 0: If you cook them in a pan, you get victory points.
Speaker 1: Sticks are more important than you think.
Speaker 0: Sticks are way important.
Speaker 0: So the thing is, for example, the morel, the most valuable mushroom, there's only three morel cards in the game.
Speaker 0: You need at least three of any particular mushroom card to cook it.
Speaker 0: If you collect all three morels and cook them, you get, like, 16 points.
Speaker 0: It's a ridiculous number of points.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, if you have...
Speaker 0: If you pick up two morels, the other guy just snipes the third one, then you just wasted your time picking up two morels.
Speaker 1: Well, no, because at the same time, you can take two or more of a type and convert it into sticks.
Speaker 0: Yes, if you take...
Speaker 1: But if you have just one morel, you're kind of fucked with that thing.
Speaker 0: Well, unless you just took it near the end to prevent the other guy from getting the third.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you take it early...
Speaker 0: Yeah, right?
Speaker 0: It clogs up your hand the whole game.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And there's some other stuff going on, like moon cards to get better fancy night mushrooms and other crazy stuff.
Speaker 1: It's a little hard to teach because they have two different ways of, like, laying out the board.
Speaker 1: Everyone who watched me and Scott play didn't understand how the, like, rotting movement was actually happening.
Speaker 0: The original rules say to put the mushrooms in a line, which conceptually makes the most sense because, you know, all the mushrooms are marching towards the decay pile in a straight line.
Speaker 0: It makes sense, but if you play that way, physically it's very demanding because you have to keep sliding the mushrooms over.
Speaker 0: Or, if you're playing at a table that's long enough, keep moving your chair to the side as the mushroom train moves, right?
Speaker 0: So, putting the mushrooms in a circle and using one of the spare sticks as a token indicating which part of the circle is the front and moving it around clockwise is much easier because now you have to move this one token, you have to move cards around.
Speaker 0: So, the circle way is better, but it's harder to understand if you've never played it before.
Speaker 1: So, actually, I think the best way, having played it now, is that I feel like you should teach with the line, and once someone gets it, just play with the circle.
Speaker 1: Because once you get the line, the circle makes perfect sense.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: But it was a pretty fun game.
Speaker 0: If you're looking for a two-player game that comes in a single box that is cheap and doesn't take long to play, that has some good replay value to it, get Smash Brothers.
Speaker 0: Get Lost Cities, because that's the greatest of all time.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: If you don't want to get that, you should probably just get Netrunner.
Speaker 0: And then maybe get Morels, or maybe Battle Line, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, Battle Line.
Speaker 0: This is about as good as Battle Line, I'd say.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it might.
Speaker 1: I can't.
Speaker 0: Notice two of those games are made by Rain or Kinesia, both Battle Line and Lost Cities.
Speaker 1: I suspect that Battle Line, in the end, is better than this game, but...
Speaker 0: Battle Line is probably slightly better than this game.
Speaker 1: You're right, slightly.
Speaker 1: I don't think by much.
Speaker 0: But Battle Line requires a bigger setup.
Speaker 0: It's a bigger game.
Speaker 0: This is tighter, physically speaking.
Speaker 1: It plays a lot quicker, too.
Speaker 0: So, again, if you need another two-player game, Morels is not a bad choice.
Speaker 0: It's not like some great, "Oh, my God, Lost Cities is the greatest
Speaker 0: game."
Speaker 0: But worthy of paying money for, especially on sale.
Speaker 1: So, guys, we've talked about it many times, but I cannot stress this enough.
Speaker 1: Video Ball... Video Ball!
Speaker 1: ...is the fucking, like, this is going to be the breakout game.
Speaker 1: I cannot stress this enough.
Speaker 0: Even if no one else Video Balls, we are going to Video Ball.
Speaker 1: In fact, we're hereby announcing that Scott and I have officially, as of today, formed the second professional Video Ball team.
Speaker 0: There might be others, but someone has already formed the first.
Speaker 0: I don't know how many there are, but we have also formed a pro Video Ball team.
Speaker 0: We are going to play Video Ball seriously, as a team, practicing and everything.
Speaker 1: The old gentleman with long hair and the old gentleman who is bald, a pair to be too old to play Video Ball.
Speaker 1: The young men are routing circles around them.
Speaker 1: It is a travesty.
Speaker 1: It is a disaster.
Speaker 0: But we will still be there.
Speaker 0: We will have, you know, awesome, like, you know, if we can't be actually good at winning, we're going to be serviceably good.
Speaker 1: We're going to be good at trash talk and making a ruckus is what we're going to be doing.
Speaker 0: We're going to have plenty of style and showmanship in our Video Balling, even if we do not win.
Speaker 1: My game name might be Jake the Snake.
Speaker 0: And maybe we'll win.
Speaker 0: Wouldn't that be the shit?
Speaker 1: I'm feeling Video Ball because there's been a big rise in the last few years.
Speaker 0: We just have to avoid the typical problem with rim and cob games of killing your friend.
Speaker 1: You mean the typical problem of we're doing fine and rivers at your ransom and Scott just keeps walking in front of me when I'm swinging a lead piper around.
Speaker 0: Oh, you walked into my constantly punching fist.
Speaker 0: That's like what a three-year-old's doing.
Speaker 1: I point out that when you and Adam played, you had similar troubles.
Speaker 1: When me and Adam played, no trouble.
Speaker 0: Video Ball is going to replace Mario Tennis.
Speaker 1: Mario Tennis is already dead.
Speaker 0: It's replacing the space formerly occupied by Mario Tennis.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: We were saying that for a while, but now that we have spoken at length with some of the team behind Video Ball, they know their shit.
Speaker 0: Video Ball developers know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: They know as much about games as we do, perhaps even more.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: They know as much about games broadly as we do, except in the narrow area of two-player direct competition video games.
Speaker 1: that are simple, they have untold depth.
Speaker 0: Usually when I go talk to someone at a PAX booth, a game developer or whatever, I'm picking apart the things that they are saying.
Speaker 0: When I went to hear what the Video Ball guy had to say, I learned.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, when he called us a secret?
Speaker 0: We were schooled by, I mean not that we were schooled like we were burned or anything, but we went to his school and reverently studied his ways.
Speaker 1: I now know a magic number that I won't share with you because it's his duty if he wants to share it or not, but there's a timing between when one thing happens in this game and another thing.
Speaker 1: And that timing is down to the sub-millisecond, the same timing as something that happens in another game, and that is a magic number.
Speaker 0: for how long you should wait.
Speaker 0: The fact that he would even say that that is a thing that is in the game proves to me how much they know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: They've even gone so far, for example, as to purposefully leave space around the playfield so that you can livestream Video Ball and still put your shit up on the screen in those spaces.
Speaker 0: That is how far that they have thought about the design of this game.
Speaker 1: When we asked them, "Hey, so when we have a professional team, where can we put our
Speaker 1: logo?".
Speaker 1: And he was like, "Actually, you put it right there.
Speaker 1: That's the place for the logos of the
Speaker 1: teams.".
Speaker 1: It was, oh, this game.
Speaker 0: Video Ball!
Speaker 1: It would be the best Pax Omegathon, it would be the best hanging out, it replaces Nidhogg as well.
Speaker 1: Nidhogg could have been this, except Nidhogg development stopped and the game is 100% dead.
Speaker 1: This will go where Nidhogg failed to go.
Speaker 0: We're gonna make it happen no matter what.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: If you all don't get on the Video Ball train with us, I'm riding it away into the sunset by myself.
Speaker 0: Even despite us entering into the pro...
Speaker 1: Scott, Video Ball NYC, we're forming the New York City Video Ball League.
Speaker 0: Sure, let's do it.
Speaker 0: We should also have, since you're playing it online, we should have the FRC ladder.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Is there a website that will just maintain ladders for you?
Speaker 0: The same way that Penny Arcade has a ping pong ladder.
Speaker 1: Is there a website that just maintains ladders for you?
Speaker 0: I don't know if Challenge supports it.
Speaker 1: I'll look into this.
Speaker 1: I don't want to make one, really.
Speaker 0: Me either.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, Video Ball.
Speaker 1: Wait until this fucking game comes out.
Speaker 1: Much like when My Little Pony came out.
Speaker 1: Once Video Ball is out, we're gonna be insufferable and talk about nothing but Video Ball.
Speaker 1: For, like, months.
Speaker 1: Also, New Ponies is coming out in, like, a month.
Speaker 0: I didn't know that.
Speaker 0: Oh, Gravity Falls has gone off the chain.
Speaker 1: So has Steven Universe, Scott.
Speaker 0: I only watched a few Steven Universes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Steven Universe.
Speaker 0: Like the one with the broken teleporters.
Speaker 0: Steven Universe.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna say the names of three properties now.
Speaker 1: And you're gonna wonder how the fuck I'm relating these to Steven Universe.
Speaker 1: Uh, Utena, which you can kinda get.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I already saw that part.
Speaker 1: Evangelion.
Speaker 1: Didn't see.
Speaker 1: And the Culture series.
Speaker 0: Saw the Culture part.
Speaker 1: Uh, no you didn't.
Speaker 1: You think you did.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, we're... Adventure Time has been, like, a game.
Speaker 1: Ace Forever.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, Gravity Falls and Steven Universe.
Speaker 1: There's talk.
Speaker 1: If we... Guys, if you gave us enough money to quit our jobs and do Geek Nights full-time, there would be Geek Nights Presents Gravity Falls.
Speaker 1: There would be Geek Nights Presents Video Ball.
Speaker 0: Send monies to me.
Speaker 0: We would need $210,000 a month.
Speaker 1: And we would do Geek Nights for you full-time.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Even a rich dude who's got a million dollars would be broke in five months.
Speaker 1: You know what's funny, though?
Speaker 1: You know, I was in London at this finance conference.
Speaker 0: Wait, don't you mean $210,000 a year?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so he'd be broke in five years, the rich guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so...
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 1: So, you know, you say that first number first, just in case.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But, uh, I met people when I was traveling at these conventions who make easily double what I make.
Speaker 1: And, uh, more than one of them asked me privately, multiple times, "How can they get into video
Speaker 1: games?".
Speaker 1: They would do almost anything to work in the video games industry.
Speaker 0: How much money do you have to throw around, double rich guy?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was like, "Really?
Speaker 1: Buy your way in?
Speaker 1: Or be a brilliant game designer?
Speaker 1: Or make half the money and work three times the
Speaker 1: hours?".
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, video ball.
Speaker 0: Give me the money.
Speaker 0: I will be the brilliant game designer.
Speaker 1: Two more little games.
Speaker 1: One more line.
Speaker 1: I'm already done with it.
Speaker 1: It's actually not that great as I played it.
Speaker 0: So, okay, so...
Speaker 1: It looks really good, though.
Speaker 0: The game is really, it's like, it's good.
Speaker 0: The problem is, is that unlike, say, Super Hexagon, you play Super Hexagon, and at first you start at Hexagon and it's balls hard, but eventually you get it, right?
Speaker 1: And then you're playing like...
Speaker 0: Then you're playing Hexagonist.
Speaker 0: And then you're playing, right?
Speaker 0: You know, you have this buildup of difficulty and speed.
Speaker 0: This game is just the same game every time, and even though your skills build up at the game and you get better at it, I never seem to get past, like, 120, 150 area.
Speaker 0: Like, I keep either dying early from bullshit, or, and I've practiced and I've gotten good at it, and it's like, yep, I'm in the groove, I know what's going on, and then just like, you know, you hit a ball and crash that was off-screen that you couldn't have avoided, and that's the limit.
Speaker 1: Even if they fix that, the problem with games like this, I think, is that any game where you're measuring, like, how far you get, if it doesn't have an ending because you won, maybe some score that shows your mastery along the way, or the difficulty literally does continue to escalate forever, so there is always a point where you're just not skilled enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's no changing in difficulty that I can really tell, other than the balls get big, the balls get, you know, things like that.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's just, you, it's just how long can you go?
Speaker 0: It's just straight endurance doing the same exact thing.
Speaker 1: This is why, while I respect in one sense, like, someone who has, like, the World Championship score in Asteroids or games like that, I also kind of don't, because games like that, once you get to a certain level of goodness...
Speaker 0: They don't get faster, they don't get harder, it's just how long can you do it?
Speaker 1: It's not even how long can you in some cases, how long are you willing to?
Speaker 1: I mean, Digdog, like...
Speaker 0: I'd love me some Digdog.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: So yeah, this game, I think what they should have done is they should have made it, you know, like, one of those ones where, you know, you get a little bit farther and it turns into clouds, and then you're in space, and that, you know, and that kind of thing, and also, like, earning, you know, it's a crappy game model, but it kind of works, where you get upgrades, and then the game changes as you go.
Speaker 1: It's basically, it's one of those games, like, really, again, it kind of worries and bothers me that so many people...
Speaker 0: But the music is so fucking pumping.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but so many people have games like this at PAX, like, just, this is a game you'll play for 20 minutes on your phone.
Speaker 0: This is the best of them.
Speaker 1: Yes, this is the best of them.
Speaker 0: And I still, I play it a little bit, like, if I just need to touch something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'll just go back to Nourishima Hexarch Super Hexagon, like, I don't... Yeah.
Speaker 1: And actually, you know what I started doing?
Speaker 0: It's not Super Hexagon.
Speaker 1: Carrying my old DS around again.
Speaker 0: To play?
Speaker 1: To play Advance Wars.
Speaker 1: 'Cause that's still... So, the last game that's new that we can play, a little quick game, we played Red 7.
Speaker 0: Red 7 is a lot like Flux-ish, where you sort of...
Speaker 1: It's Flux, but not stupid.
Speaker 0: Right, so it's a card game where you change the rules of the game as you play it.
Speaker 0: Here is the one thing about the game I can tell you that's amazing.
Speaker 0: On your turn, you can either, A, change the rule, B, change the cards that you have.
Speaker 0: So, obviously, the cards that you have are the ones that are affected by the rule.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're making like a poker hand.
Speaker 0: So, there'll be a rule that says, like, whoever has the highest card wins.
Speaker 0: So, the cards you have are what is judged by that rule, right?
Speaker 1: So, maybe I play a 7 and now I'm winning.
Speaker 1: Or maybe I change the rule to, like, whoever has the most even cards wins.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you can change the rule, you can add to your cards, thus changing, you know, how the rule affects you, or you can do both.
Speaker 0: And it's very hard to draw more cards.
Speaker 0: At the end of your turn, after changing the rule, changing your cards, or both, you need to be winning.
Speaker 0: As in, you are the number one first place sole possessor of winning.
Speaker 0: If you are not the sole possessor of first place, according to the judgment rule, at the end of your turn, then you have lost.
Speaker 1: You're done.
Speaker 0: If you have no way to make yourself the winner on your turn, you are completely eliminated from the game, the end, and the remaining players continue to use cards in their hand to win.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: I mean...
Speaker 0: That's the whole game, and that is amazing.
Speaker 1: There was an advanced mode we didn't know about and didn't play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're gonna have to play this a lot more, and once we get that advanced mode going, we'll probably be able to do a whole episode on this.
Speaker 0: But that mechanic in this game is genius.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you can make at least one or two more games with that mechanic without having to be played out.
Speaker 1: It is, it's pretty fun.
Speaker 1: It's not that great.
Speaker 1: It'll get played out, I think, pretty quickly.
Speaker 0: This isn't some thing that you can keep playing like Wizard.
Speaker 1: You know what it's like?
Speaker 1: You know where the place it serves in your game library?
Speaker 1: Right next to No Thanks.
Speaker 1: It's a quick game you play.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, this is definitely in the No Thanks territory.
Speaker 1: Yes, you bust it out while you're waiting for your food at a restaurant.
Speaker 0: Because it plays so quickly, because you get eliminated, and your starting hand is so small, and drawing cards is so difficult.
Speaker 0: If you do manage to draw a card, and I'm not gonna get into how you do that, that helps you a whole lot.
Speaker 0: That can make you survive a whole 'nother?
Speaker 0: turn.
Speaker 0: Because that card you draw is gonna give you a way to be winning on your turn, and then everyone else has to do it one more time before it gets back to you.
Speaker 1: It's also a Karl Chudick, so you can see why it's already at this pretty good level.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the Glory to Rome guy, right?
Speaker 1: There's another designer here.
Speaker 0: Is it the Glory to Rome guy?
Speaker 1: Yes, yes.
Speaker 1: But there's another guy, Chris Sizlik, who I don't know who that is, actually.
Speaker 1: Co-credited as designer.
Speaker 1: And I don't recognize any of the other games this person has done.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Adorable Pandering.
Speaker 0: I like that.
Speaker 1: It looks like an expansion to Innovation.
Speaker 0: Innovation's also the same guy.
Speaker 1: Rolling Ramparts?
Speaker 1: That sounds like a good name, but...
Speaker 0: Why don't we make Rampart the board game?
Speaker 1: This doesn't necessarily look good.
Speaker 0: No, I mean, why don't we make Rampart, real Rampart, the board game?
Speaker 1: You know what should've been that?
Speaker 1: Castellan.
Speaker 1: So yeah, we played a ton of games at PAX East, even though the games we played with our friends were mostly Netrunner, Hans and Teutonica, Wizard.
Speaker 0: Wizard.
Speaker 0: I played two Hans and Teutonica, two Wizards, two or three Netrunners.
Speaker 0: There was a lot going on there.
Speaker 0: I played some video balls.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, I just wanted to go play a video ball.
Speaker 1: We gotta get those guys.
Speaker 1: You know where video ball just needs to be?
Speaker 1: Everywhere.
Speaker 1: You know that couch at Magfest?
Speaker 1: It's just gotta be there 24/7.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we talked to these guys at length, and we'll have some video as soon as I... I have like a month-long backlog of video to edit for you guys, and I apologize for that, but I'm gonna put to the top of the queue the discussion we had with some of the video ball people at PAX.
Speaker 1: Because that was... You're getting some schooling.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.