Speaker 1: It's Tuesday August 18th 2015.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek guys tonight.
Speaker 1: Somehow we've never done a show on dance dance revolution.
Speaker 0: We sort of have.
Speaker 1: so here we go.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well in 2006 you were correct.
Speaker 1: We did a show where we reviewed games that we played on the Wildwood boardwalk.
Speaker 0: Actually saw two such shows in the in the archives there.
Speaker 1: now which one or the other one cuz that one I found we specifically reviewed time crisis for DDR supernova and some other game.
Speaker 0: there weren't.
Speaker 0: there were two in there But they were pretty much like.
Speaker 0: none of them were dedicated DDR shows where he talked about nothing, but DDR and I feel like There's much to say about DDR.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in fact we did a. we did a panel.
Speaker 1: I on DDR at a PAX a long time ago.
Speaker 1: It was one of our like, you know, we do three Mentioned.
Speaker 0: it wasn't about.
Speaker 1: well, it was games our mind control where we've talked about rhythm games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and as I recall when we did the panel I realized that I had like another hour's worth of stuff to say about DDR.
Speaker 1: Sure But yeah, so we're an amazing wedding in a giant ball.
Speaker 1: non-wedding law due to crazy Inside joke circumstances, but we're out in the woods in this giant house.
Speaker 1: That is pretty much the house from phantasmagoria.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 1: Well, here's what I'd say.
Speaker 1: They're
Speaker 0: much smaller than any sort of Resident Evil video game type house
Speaker 1: That is true but seventh
Speaker 0: guest maniac mansion type of the rooms
Speaker 1: that it had and the layout of those rooms and Several specific features are so deeply reminiscent of the stuff in phantasmagoria that when I saw them as a kid and as an adult watching that let's play of it.
Speaker 1: I Couldn't believe they'd exist.
Speaker 1: Like I couldn't imagine like a house that was physical and real that had a structure like that in them.
Speaker 0: Go to old houses yeah, but never.
Speaker 1: I never seen that giant fish radiator on top of the stove the the like heater in the upstairs or the What used to be a stage for what I presume was a bordello.
Speaker 1: that is now a linen cloth.
Speaker 0: you're just gonna presume the most awesome thing obviously, but This is because you I mean obviously you didn't live in a rural area Old houses like that before but there's a lot of old manor houses all over Detroit.
Speaker 0: if you go to summer camp Right every summer camp has like this sent the house at the center of it.
Speaker 0: That's like the camp's house right where like, you know the cafeteria is usually in there or this hall or whatever camp to halo had that offices those sorts of things right and Those center houses at summer camps are always that kind of house.
Speaker 1: It was mostly the stage because that was like there is a row.
Speaker 0: the no longer at stage.
Speaker 1: the stage with the weird like Unfitting wall in front of it to turn it into something else stage wasn't there anymore is just the wall with the door in it.
Speaker 1: Yep, but that exact thing is in phantasmagoria and there is a stage behind it and there's a murder machine back there.
Speaker 1: There wasn't a murder machine in this one.
Speaker 1: There was just a linen closet.
Speaker 0: So I also found the attic stairs behind that.
Speaker 1: but at this wedding we had a very important Group of people together.
Speaker 1: We had the original four people.
Speaker 1: That the four it was me Scott our friends Pete and Alex when we found team in our friends hot bull.
Speaker 0: Yep Scott is hot lion.
Speaker 1: Yeah bull is clearly superior because once again bull is the winner.
Speaker 0: archers King Archer didn't win The only one human second place only one with human intelligence the Archer.
Speaker 1: However, I think if you had just an archer versus just a bull and the Bulls goal was to fuck up the archer.
Speaker 1: I think the bull would win.
Speaker 0: dude people kill bulls without even the bow.
Speaker 0: They just stab the arrows right into the bow.
Speaker 1: You try that their hand Let's hand you.
Speaker 0: so if you got a bow, it's gonna be way easier because the bull even can't get even close to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I've seen like I've seen horrible videos of bullfights.
Speaker 1: They'll get like 15 hours into that bowl and this isn't even slowed down Because they didn't get.
Speaker 0: if you got a bow you can shoot the arrow so hard.
Speaker 0: it can go right through the skull in The brain.
Speaker 1: No, probably not.
Speaker 1: I actually are good at aiming with that kind of bow.
Speaker 1: Plus this is a Mesopotamish bull our bull and a Mesopotamish bow.
Speaker 0: That means the bow is mad weak compared to a Spanish one.
Speaker 0: But yeah to match the weakness of the bow.
Speaker 1: so it evens out Now that bull is probably just as badass as a modern bull who says Animals gonna be mad weak.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna eat like sure Mesopotamish bowls like modern corn and shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that Mesopotamish bull is probably fucking dangerous and that Mesopotamish bow is probably some BS.
Speaker 0: Also, I could just drown that motherfucker in the Tigris.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or the Euphrates But anyway, it's right there.
Speaker 1: I think we did a show on this but we you know how we found Tiggers and Euphrates and everything, but it remains after so many years to the point that it was forgotten and re-released recently.
Speaker 1: Tiggers and Euphrates might be our favorite.
Speaker 0: It just went out of print and then the license was bought by a different guy.
Speaker 1: It was pretty widely forgotten though.
Speaker 1: There was a lot of packs.
Speaker 0: The new printing is by the way worse than the old printing.
Speaker 1: It's better in a few ways and worse in the majority of ways, right?
Speaker 0: But I mean, it's still perfectly playable.
Speaker 1: Like it amazes me that you know I am very fickle in my taste in games and that I pretty much Will read the rules to a game and be done with it before I finish reading them.
Speaker 1: But Tiggers and Euphrates has somehow remained my favorite tabletop German style game ever and remain So to this day despite constant play, but we had the alumni together probably some of the most expert players of this game in the world and we played a game that
Speaker 0: we know
Speaker 1: that we haven't played in a long time and So sublime is the feeling of playing a game with three other people who have just as much experience expertise and knowledge as in a game as you and Literally just sitting down setting it up without saying a word and playing a super intense fast game.
Speaker 1: Game took like an hour and I won pretty pretty handily.
Speaker 0: You went on that with three tie breaks.
Speaker 1: Yes with Alex.
Speaker 0: That is not handily.
Speaker 0: Handily is like I have a wide margin.
Speaker 1: I was on the third tie break with Alex You and Pete not really contenders.
Speaker 0: I got into a really bad situation.
Speaker 0: you did where I was able to devastate opponents But I was and I was able to get my leaders back on the board.
Speaker 0: But the particular arrangement of my leaders back on the board put them in the kingdoms that did not have the matching monuments.
Speaker 0: I was not able.
Speaker 0: so while I was able to hold position I was not able to hold the correct position.
Speaker 0: You know, there was no way to move because you can't swap leaders and at the beginning of the game I had a fistful of red tiles.
Speaker 0: So I used it to my advantage and put pressure early and then later in the game I had no red tiles to speak of and I only internal conflicts were available.
Speaker 0: So that was partly because a lot there was a lot of my Catastrophes had already been spent because that's how I got into that position.
Speaker 1: in the first place was by early Attack, then it was interesting because it was a game where you see like three gigantic kingdoms with literally a one square channel separating them across half the board and There was a wall of catastrophes.
Speaker 1: at one point It was a great game But I'm pretty sure the only reason I won the sole reason is in that third round Where I did that internal conflict with five red tiles and took Pete's Kingdom.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much the leader that I put in that spot Did not move and sat there for literally the entire game was never contested and never in account.
Speaker 0: It wasn't possible for me to care anyone to contest that.
Speaker 0: yeah,
Speaker 1: cuz I walled it off so you couldn't even do an internal and No one want to do an external because it was by then like green points that pretty much won me the game that Single conflict in the beginning and the fact that no one
Speaker 0: You're discounting all the things that led up to your ability to make that conflict.
Speaker 1: Yeah in the third turn I had five red tiles in my hand, right?
Speaker 1: But you know how I had five red tiles in my hand.
Speaker 1: I started with four red tiles in my hand I played the bare minimum of them and then the next to turn the next turn I played two non red tiles.
Speaker 1: Basically, it was the fourth or fifth turn actually not the third turn.
Speaker 1: thinking back to the game anyway T&E is a great game.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: You got any gaming news?
Speaker 0: So this company?
Speaker 0: I read a news this morning about a company that just launched called fig.
Speaker 0: It's named after like some hall like Figueroa Hall or something.
Speaker 0: That's a place that people hang out after e3 for parties or eating or something.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure what the deal is But anyway, what this company does is basically Kickstarter for games Except you get to actually invest in the game somehow and actually get a return on your investment for reals.
Speaker 0: not just you mean you can still do the Kickstarter thing where you Back the game and get t-shirts or goodies or whatever like normal But you can also back and real invest for reals without having to be accredited or anything.
Speaker 1: So I am really excited if this works, but also it is a complicated thing to do legally.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this seems some kind of shady kind of whoa kind of what's going on here.
Speaker 1: it's a game changer.
Speaker 0: if it works though Sure much investigation has to be done into this.
Speaker 0: I would not give them even one penny until we are a hundred percent sure that this is legit and for reals, but Shortly after reading the news about the creation of this thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh, I learned something just now, you know how this works.
Speaker 0: There's a new law.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right the Obama thing the JOBS Act, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they made it.
Speaker 0: the what you need to do for accredited investing has changed.
Speaker 0: so That was what allowed us to exist.
Speaker 0: But anyway, a very important person announced shortly after these news articles went up that they are working there and that person is Heels who used to be the person who ran programming at PAX.
Speaker 1: I think I would describe his job as impresario of PAX.
Speaker 0: sure Well, not anymore.
Speaker 0: His job is now something something.
Speaker 0: We don't know at fig Yeah, so the fact that he is working there a person that we know a lends it some credibility and B means we can get a lot of information about this place because we know a person who works there.
Speaker 1: So we are Like we know people at oculus.
Speaker 1: They don't tell a shit.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you know, it doesn't matter Is that we're going to get the lowdown on this deal?
Speaker 0: So And also we know a lot about games.
Speaker 0: We if there's any legit.
Speaker 1: you don't realize.
Speaker 0: there are two possibilities fuck stop trade.
Speaker 0: Yeah possibility one This is a total bad thing.
Speaker 0: fuck them And we're gonna tell you is you won't get ruined by it or B. We're all gonna make money, bro Yeah, cuz uh, I actually kind of we will all work together to make money.
Speaker 1: I kind of recently liquidated all my Amazon and take to interactive stock just because they were way high and I figured might as well take some.
Speaker 0: I don't want to sell anything cuz I'd have to pay taxes up.
Speaker 1: So you got to do a wash - you got to sell something that you're losing money on and then buy it back at a low price later.
Speaker 1: Okay, so here's.
Speaker 1: so here's the example I own up.
Speaker 1: this is depending on where you live.
Speaker 1: This may or may not be illegal.
Speaker 1: It depends.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of.
Speaker 1: do not take stock advice from me.
Speaker 1: But theoretically what you can do in some situations is say I got stocks making a ton of money like it's up.
Speaker 0: You bought it at 50 and now it's $200, but I had another stock.
Speaker 1: I bought a 200. that's now at 50.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's so.
Speaker 0: sell them both Alright, so now I've got the same amount of money I started with and then buy back the stock that lost money the cheap one.
Speaker 0: That's at 50 now.
Speaker 1: So now you realized a big gain and a big loss and they cancel each other out.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 0: Well, okay.
Speaker 0: So why even if you're selling the one at 50 and then buying it right back why even do that?
Speaker 0: Why not just sell the big one and buy the cheap one?
Speaker 0: Why would you?
Speaker 0: why?
Speaker 0: what's the point of selling the cheap one and buying back the same exact shares you just sold?
Speaker 1: well because they're Two separate transactions you sell the big one and you have to pay taxes on that.
Speaker 1: Yes, but the way these taxes work is.
Speaker 1: you pay taxes on everything you gained - everything you lost that year.
Speaker 0: Oh, so if you sell the cheap one and buy it right back you still had losses because you sold.
Speaker 1: yes now Some places have laws.
Speaker 0: the problem is you you just didn't make any fucking money though Except you did.
Speaker 0: because now you have twice.
Speaker 1: you were gonna hold on you because this is assuming You were gonna hold on to that stock.
Speaker 1: that's down knowing that it's eventually gonna go back up.
Speaker 0: So now you have double the shares of the two or many more of the shares of the cheap one.
Speaker 1: You basically make all the money from the big stock that did well You are still gambling Hoping that the cheap one that is currently cheap goes back up and pretty much I only invest in things again.
Speaker 1: Do not take stock advice for me.
Speaker 1: I'm not there.
Speaker 1: all that stuff I pretty much only I'm like, I'm what you call a contra investor.
Speaker 1: I invest in things that have dropped for reasons that I think are stupid Like when there is that big breaks like when I made a lot of money like way back and like started investing.
Speaker 1: I bought Toyota when the stock collapsed after that like the accelerator scandal where like the cars would accelerate and kill people Because I was confident that was solely caused by old people in floor mats pretty much and turned out.
Speaker 1: I was right and the stock came back and I made a boatload of money.
Speaker 0: and then I invested all that money in Hasbro because Ponies or like the earnings of some company are down this quarter just because so the stock they didn't meet estimates of the stock market Punishes them.
Speaker 0: but it's like that company's doing just fine.
Speaker 0: In fact, they're doing great.
Speaker 0: They've got all these good business plans and there this product is gonna be very successful.
Speaker 1: I that they've talked about like oh take to a game company.
Speaker 0: I just went down because maybe the stock market in general went down and some bullshit financial nonsense got his good example.
Speaker 1: Oh take twos way down.
Speaker 1: Oh, look, no big games came out this year.
Speaker 1: What's come out next year?
Speaker 1: Oh the new Grand Theft Auto stock.
Speaker 1: people don't know shit about this by stock.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's worked out real.
Speaker 0: Well, you know you're buying it far enough in advance cuz you're going long-term.
Speaker 0: They're going short-term.
Speaker 0: They're only looking at what's like the next month.
Speaker 0: They don't want to hold anything for more than like a day.
Speaker 1: All right, so but yeah, basically Looking at this if this is legit and real I know a fuck ton more about games than I do about stocks.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: So Anyway, do you have any news?
Speaker 1: I have a minor news.
Speaker 1: So PAX is next weekend.
Speaker 0: It is and next week it is.
Speaker 1: ex-dev is Wednesday Thursday packs prime is Friday Saturday Sunday Monday We're gonna me and Emily gonna be at the whole shebang the packs not a packs the pack.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this isn't like fucking Ravenna.
Speaker 1: This is Rome.
Speaker 1: That's right and The full schedule is now on the website.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was.
Speaker 1: you know Everything everything.
Speaker 0: who is that keynote?
Speaker 1: The keynote is I actually have not had a chance to look at the schedule yet.
Speaker 1: Whoa, there's all this stuff scheduled before the keynote.
Speaker 1: We're okay.
Speaker 1: story time with Kim Swift of the game industry and Molly internet famous game developer gets lots of questions of what she does for a living how games are Made.
Speaker 1: why as creative storytime delves into the complexities of game development using commonly asked questions generic description and misconceptions about games.
Speaker 1: She's currently the senior game designer at Amazon game studio.
Speaker 0: Oh Amazon They're doing some weird stuff going on at Amazon game studio.
Speaker 0: I'd be interested to hear what's going on.
Speaker 1: I gotta look into that article.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna talk about this on the next Monday show.
Speaker 0: But that article about how Amazon works people to death Yeah, well Amazon's trying to do something similar with games that they do with like their original TV shows, right?
Speaker 1: yeah, which that's?
Speaker 1: that's also kind of a game changer, but The twitch boat is not the Google YouTube live streaming gaming boat, so I don't know what's going on.
Speaker 1: I don't know what's going on in this space Can't predict but I'm gonna talk about that more on Monday.
Speaker 1: mmm.
Speaker 1: a Monday not next Monday will be packs Things of the day.
Speaker 1: The audio of this is from a college humor skit, but a the ad the little animatic is from Steven Universe With the two combined.
Speaker 1: Scott wouldn't under appreciate it, but if you watch Steven Universe you will.
Speaker 0: I'll see you soon enough.
Speaker 1: It's pretty funny.
Speaker 1: It's that it's that don't touch my shit thing.
Speaker 1: remember like you You two can't are capable of not touching my shit, okay?
Speaker 1: It's an ode to a roommate from another roommate, but with Peridot a character you have not met yet.
Speaker 1: It's really funny.
Speaker 0: so this blog on on the website unseen 1964.net.
Speaker 0: they have a blog there, and there's one particular category of leaks.
Speaker 0: You can explore the whole blog if you want, but this website specializes in showing you unreleased beta never finished video games That you may or may not have even known wherever a thing and that is some hot shit right there.
Speaker 0: It is really fucking interesting some of them.
Speaker 0: You can even play like you know I mean this stuff in here like a dune ornithopter game for the GBA a Lufia game for the Genesis like they got.
Speaker 0: they're digging up crazy shit Thanks to developers who worked on these things saw them get cancelled And then you know still had materials and of now spilling them onto the web's.
Speaker 0: So and you know it's like most of these are not a big enough deal.
Speaker 0: It's like make the regular gaming news sites, but you come here, and it's like wow if you somebody knows about video games You're gonna care about this.
Speaker 0: I don't know why I didn't know about this earlier.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there is.
Speaker 1: they're already just flipping through this some interesting gems.
Speaker 0: Alright the meta moment PAX.
Speaker 1: we are going to be there on Man multiple days playing games, but we have two panels on.
Speaker 1: We're doing the far future of gaming and we are doing sports our games Extra topical especially now.
Speaker 1: what were these sports and doping and all this business that's going on?
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 1: Also the book club book is still fantasy book the novel part one of what.
Speaker 0: seven Nine of a lot.
Speaker 0: I'm done.
Speaker 1: I Do not know how many there are many okay?
Speaker 0: So uh the eye of the world.
Speaker 0: they just got it Jordan.
Speaker 1: I just got to the point where they just got to Kaelyn.
Speaker 0: I'm already almost done with Kaelyn.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, they just got there.
Speaker 1: uh knowing guys a little less annoying still kind of hope he dies but If he lives but just goes away, I'd also be okay with you mean guy who stole a dagger.
Speaker 1: yes dagger guy, okay?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean that dagger is obviously cursed like a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: that dagger is cursed.
Speaker 1: It's like every time they talk about him.
Speaker 0: It's not a secret.
Speaker 1: They pretty much tell you It's like just an asterisk next to his name.
Speaker 1: It's like he who carries the cursed dagger and he's gonna fucking stab someone with it suddenly.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile why didn't they keep that dagger?
Speaker 1: that the one assassin had the one that had like the flame blade?
Speaker 0: Maybe it's even more curse in the stable.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know seems like a powerful weapon.
Speaker 0: also didn't it set on fire or something?
Speaker 1: well the blade was hot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it does that all the time.
Speaker 1: Maybe they don't know that power were to turn it off or what?
Speaker 0: I don't know, but anyway That's the end of that.
Speaker 0: there's not really much to say because we're too preoccupied with packs and the meta times.
Speaker 0: So let us move on to you show.
Speaker 1: so on November 21st 1998 a momentous thing happened that I did not know about dance.
Speaker 1: dance revolution was released in Japan and We did not discover dance dance revolution until the year 2000.
Speaker 0: this is not entirely true.
Speaker 0: I knew that there was a game called dance dance revolution and perhaps 99 or even earlier 2000 and I knew that it was a game that involved dancing on four arrows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I think I'd heard of it And I thought it was.
Speaker 0: you know, not knowing anything other than that about it I thought it was stupid, but you know what?
Speaker 0: I thought like Pokemon was some stupid kids game before I ever played it.
Speaker 0: So, you know, yeah It's just like oh Nintendo's got a new franchise.
Speaker 0: It's some kids garbage.
Speaker 0: What have yep?
Speaker 1: So dance dance revolution was this thing that we kind of ignored.
Speaker 0: I was like in middle school or high school or something in the US like that.
Speaker 1: shit was not available.
Speaker 0: No well they did release a US dance machine that just said dance dance revolution on it.
Speaker 0: that had what was one player and Included a very limited crappy song selection.
Speaker 1: It had like 12 or something songs on it Did because licensing reasons and also I'm pretty sure that came out later and I never encountered it until 2001 when I went to Cedar Point and there was a single US mix dance dance revolution machine at the front of an arcade and I spent an entire evening playing it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So if you've never played DDR, it's that game with four arrows and you just dance to music on those four arrows.
Speaker 0: Now this seems really freaking stupid, right?
Speaker 0: A lot of people say things such as that's not real dancing, right?
Speaker 1: It's counter-strikes not real shooting, right?
Speaker 0: Exactly It also is just.
Speaker 0: you know at the time when it came out It's like so you step on the four arrows and it's just like what.
Speaker 1: and there had been.
Speaker 0: when I saw it I was like that is the dumbest thing I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: Why are you guys playing this?
Speaker 1: and there had been rhythm games before in various forms that I just always thought were stupid Like I'd always thought those kinds of games were stupid.
Speaker 1: They were just like mole whack-a-mole just music based whack-a-mole.
Speaker 1: They're always dumb.
Speaker 0: I mean the arcades always had the spider stomping game.
Speaker 0: What's the difference exactly?
Speaker 1: So and to cut the anecdote short We're at RIT and the anime club.
Speaker 1: in the gaming clubs like event There's like this overnight thing had set up.
Speaker 0: I don't think gaming club existed yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, did Our way, okay, not EGS.
Speaker 1: Okay, I came way later.
Speaker 1: In fact video games used to be mostly the purview of Our way, I thought it was Springfest or social night or whatever.
Speaker 1: It was one of those things remember we always.
Speaker 0: I think it was.
Speaker 0: it was a purely anime club Event because the anime club had purview over things that were Japanese including Japanese video games.
Speaker 0: So they had things such as card captor Sakura Tetris.
Speaker 1: Yeah But that that is also why when our wag had DDR the anime club would set the TV up for it.
Speaker 1: Sure, like weird.
Speaker 0: All right Because the people in the anime club were the people who owned modded or Japanese Playstations.
Speaker 1: Yep So they said at a time
Speaker 0: when the PlayStation new was brand fucking new and
Speaker 1: Scott and I were walking past it and we just kind of made fun of it and I thought it was stupid and kind of made fun of the people playing it and left and then Scott went and played a big D&D game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as I recall I was playing a big D&D and I decided well I'll play this thing Whatever cuz everyone was way into it and we were poo poo in it and rim went to play it.
Speaker 1: So fast forward like four hours Scott comes back from D&D I'm still playing it and I'm like Scott you gotta you gotta get over here And I'm like, I'm pretty sure that's the stupidest thing ever seen but I must not knock if I have not tried.
Speaker 1: I like four hours later me and Scott are both playing it and then I like I immediately got a Ps1 and modded it to play this game.
Speaker 1: I ordered pads and We didn't play in DDR ever since.
Speaker 0: so usually if people ask me What the best game period ever is, right?
Speaker 0: I usually say something like Super Metroid or Mega Man 2 or Zelda 1 or Zelda 3 And I don't know if I really want to change my Super Metroid answer But I'm leaning more and more Towards saying DDR.
Speaker 1: and what was that panel?
Speaker 1: at a PAX where the audience was like Adding and removing games from a top 10 like most important games ever list?
Speaker 0: yeah, and the smart guy made spy party added DDR to the list and me and rim were like And the rest of the audience was like what?
Speaker 0: right anyway.
Speaker 0: So let me talk about DDR as the best game ever because DDR The reason I think it might be the best game ever.
Speaker 0: Is that anything that you would say is a thing like think about the list of things that make a game good.
Speaker 0: DDR has all of them right.
Speaker 0: Super Metroid is not right one of the best games there is of all time.
Speaker 0: It's so high up the list It can't possibly be lower than top five on the list of anyone who's not a moron But it doesn't have everything Right, so, okay.
Speaker 0: No So let's think about the things that make a game really good.
Speaker 1: So competition you can have it.
Speaker 1: you can play against another person in some direct fashion.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Super Metroid has that with like a speedrun, but mostly not.
Speaker 0: so, you know DDR You compete against the person next to you can compete against them in many different ways.
Speaker 0: score Can you even beat this song that I beat on this difficulty level?
Speaker 0: No, you can't.
Speaker 0: Right grade maybe yeah style like.
Speaker 0: oh the people are cheering for me and not for you, right?
Speaker 1: There's that battle mode.
Speaker 1: that was kind of dumb.
Speaker 1: It was okay.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: So DDR has real competition.
Speaker 0: that like is legit.
Speaker 0: DDR also has Music and atmosphere and you know immersion and all the.
Speaker 0: you know that you think about it, you know games that have like stories.
Speaker 0: You know like half-life where you like get involved in it, right?
Speaker 0: Okay, so DDR doesn't have a narrative story.
Speaker 0: It has an even better story.
Speaker 0: DDR has a story in the way that NFL football or NHL ice hockey.
Speaker 1: has a story maybe rock band Sort of maybe right going up through the ranks as a rock star.
Speaker 0: It's like you get up on the DDR pad right and there's lights and there's sounds.
Speaker 0: right pumping Right, you feel like you're in the club, right?
Speaker 0: You get this whole immersion thing going on and then you get the story of.
Speaker 0: you know Rim was dancing that one time at the beach and those girls were asking him.
Speaker 0: You know those people behind were taking pictures or you know He beat the ridiculously hard song and the other person passed out.
Speaker 1: DDR is one of those games that people just playing it or you can draw a crowd.
Speaker 0: You went to that, you know that time that you went to You know that DJ eight ball pretended he was hurt In a crazy performance with involving the cane on the dancepad.
Speaker 1: We used to go searching for in the era before YouTube videos of DDR championships.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would download videos.
Speaker 1: Still have that video of DJ eight ball Right.
Speaker 0: So DDR has his story.
Speaker 0: It has.
Speaker 0: you know music obviously are you know, the the whole you know the.
Speaker 0: the Aesthetic aspect of it is full power.
Speaker 1: Well, so look at design, right?
Speaker 1: It's a rhythm game and These things were not well-designed up until this point like in fact, the original DDR was not well-designed.
Speaker 1: It took until the third or really the fourth or it was fourth mix because third still had flat arrows Exactly.
Speaker 0: fourth - sorry I mean they added features after the fourth mix, but they perfected the core of DDR in the fourth mix.
Speaker 0: That's where DDR became real.
Speaker 1: So the thing that matters the most is that there's a ranking system.
Speaker 1: Well two things.
Speaker 1: there is a ranking system a number of feet that is like a metric of how difficult the song is.
Speaker 1: Those numbers are one of the best designed ranking difficulty systems I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: because I can I could look at a DDR song and say that's a five that's a six Yeah And that it's like rock climbing or skiing like the grades are very well-defined and mean very specific things to an expert.
Speaker 1: So there's a very clear progression for a player and you always feel like you're progressing.
Speaker 1: And the upper end of that the upper limit of that is above 99% of players abilities.
Speaker 1: So you'll never hit the end.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Like there are very few people who can hit the end of DDR.
Speaker 1: So also but the other thing the design of the game itself the way it teaches you how to play.
Speaker 1: the arrows Have a color like they're cycling color But they cycle in time with the music through these colors so that they are You know yellowish or purplish or whatever color depending on whether or not they'll be on a quarter note eighth note sixteenth note Whatever when you're supposed to step on them, so it kind of trains your brain.
Speaker 1: So you play it a lot.
Speaker 1: your brain just sees arrows and your feet just move and there is literally no thought whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's it.
Speaker 0: There might be like a pattern.
Speaker 0: you're trying to figure out and you figure it out eventually and you do a little bit of conscious Thought and then once you've you know muscle memorized that you're done because DDR is also a sport.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right the first time I beat like a fast hard song and I did dropout.
Speaker 1: I fucking almost passed out Literally fell off the pad and collapsed and laid there heaving.
Speaker 0: you practice and you know You build your skills and your muscles and your muscle memory Right in the same way that you learn to throw a baseball or swim the breaststroke or anything like that.
Speaker 1: Yep Like people who are better than you and there's like this culture of no man dance it like dance that pattern like this.
Speaker 1: or now Yeah, like there's the point where you learn to twist your hips Instead of trying to step on all the things with the same foot.
Speaker 0: DDR has a community You know that has grown and shrunk over the years.
Speaker 0: But you know, it is it just naturally the way it is made.
Speaker 0: it builds a community.
Speaker 0: even just there could be a community around a single machine or as DDR as a whole or Even around like just aspects of DDR like they'll be the you know People who make you know notes in step mania for other songs that aren't official.
Speaker 0: There's a community for that is you know, there's a community for you know People who are trying to just you know compete and see who can do the hardest songs in the most perfect score.
Speaker 1: I used to hang out on the DDR freak forums and I was a regular poster as well.
Speaker 0: Yeah a community for people who build DDR pads because buying them kind of sucks, especially now.
Speaker 1: Well considering red octane is gone, which is the only people who make good DDR pads, right?
Speaker 0: DDR also has an important aspect which many other games do not have especially not competitive games Is that it offers the ability for self-expression.
Speaker 0: if you look at a game like, you know, minecraft and minecraft You can have self-expression right?
Speaker 0: You're creating this work of art.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot of competition in minecraft in magic the gathering you can have self-expression.
Speaker 0: You sort of make your deck as an expression of yourself any sort of customizable game.
Speaker 0: netrunner offers that to write the self-expression and the competition but they don't offer the sport.
Speaker 0: or You know the immersion with the sound pumping and the graphics and the in the crew, right?
Speaker 1: You know like those subtle moments where you turn your back on the screen and dancing facing the crowd and wink at some girl Who's watching like that's.
Speaker 1: that's fun stuff.
Speaker 0: DDR offers all the things at once.
Speaker 0: It is the only game that has ever done this that I know.
Speaker 1: we don't get back to your competition thing.
Speaker 1: This is a game where a beginner and an expert can play against each other on the same machine Side by side at the same time with no problem and totally.
Speaker 1: both have fun.
Speaker 1: because I think we talked about this in that packs Panel - if you get two scores when you dance.
Speaker 1: now some things have changed between all the versions.
Speaker 1: But say I'm doing a maniac song.
Speaker 1: it's someone we know hasn't played much is doing a basic song But we do the same song.
Speaker 1: we dance next to each other.
Speaker 1: I just have more arrows.
Speaker 0: you get a less score will be higher because your combos are probably bigger from having more arrows.
Speaker 1: But the letter grades are based on how well you do relative to that level, right?
Speaker 0: If they hit every arrow perfectly and you mess up a bit You'll probably get an A and they'll get an S and they'd be like I did better.
Speaker 0: It is a you know built-in handicap like bowling in golf.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the game puts prominent focus on the rent like the score relative to what you are attempting in your ability.
Speaker 1: But it also gives you the like absolute score where my score is multiple orders of magnitude above yours just because you know I had a lot more arrows to hit.
Speaker 0: and even for just something that's a rhythm game where you stomp on some plastic.
Speaker 0: right, it still has this sort of mystery and aura of secrets.
Speaker 0: and and you know Excitement that you get from like, you know, you play Zelda 1 and you find like, you know a secret.
Speaker 0: or You open up that eighth dungeon and the music is different.
Speaker 0: DDR has that too.
Speaker 0: even in the arcade songs unlock or There's different modes or if you hold down buttons You can open up the menu and get access to different settings.
Speaker 0: And
Speaker 1: you'd see this you just weird like when I go to a machine like when when I was when we were younger and there'd be the people like the community in the arcade and we do a song and then they get up there and Then like Scott said they like hold some buttons down and different shit would happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they get these weird menus.
Speaker 1: We didn't know what that was at the time.
Speaker 1: So we'd like watch them and then try and try to figure out what they were doing.
Speaker 0: It's like there's a lot, you know, you buy DDR at home and it's like who's that mysterious character when it still had characters?
Speaker 0: Boldo, right?
Speaker 0: It's like then you unlock the cowgirl and DDR fifth mix.
Speaker 0: It's like whoa.
Speaker 0: It's like crazy shit goes down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the game I feel like it's peak in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Was around like early first first half of two thousand two thousand two thousand five.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like two thousand two three was I think the biggest cuz.
Speaker 0: that's when because it started.
Speaker 0: Yep, pretty much Every hour after 2005 2006. that's when it was fading and around that time.
Speaker 0: It's about five years.
Speaker 0: ish.
Speaker 0: The thing is DDR was so big if you meet someone right and it's like people really aren't playing DDR a lot now.
Speaker 0: They still are but not a lot.
Speaker 0: but you bring DDR up and if there's a person who played it.
Speaker 0: I'm I'm constantly shocked about how often DDR will come up and a person that we didn't know play DDR be like Oh DDR yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, I played that.
Speaker 0: let's play right now.
Speaker 0: We've got it.
Speaker 0: Let's throw down.
Speaker 1: We have repeatedly busted out the pads and a bunch of strangers start playing DDR together.
Speaker 0: and people they still got it Just like a bicycle.
Speaker 0: They don't have a full power, but they can pedal they can get up the hill.
Speaker 1: Helps that.
Speaker 1: most of the music in DDR especially like fourth mix fifth mix six mix era is the kind of dance music I like anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I guess there are people who don't like that music.
Speaker 1: music is taste But well, then they can do.
Speaker 0: DDR has the kind of music that I will listen to even when not playing DDR.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that kind of like 90s dance pop like you're talking about best music in video games ever.
Speaker 0: It's like Mega Man 2 DDR.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Symphony of the Night is up there too.
Speaker 0: Sure, but it's pretty much Mega Man 2 DDR.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like the music in DDR is that good?
Speaker 0: I mean obviously it varies by which mix you're playing.
Speaker 0: right, you know It just keeps coming out with new mixes, but we played mostly in the fourth fourth plus fifth mix era.
Speaker 0: Yep, you know and I mean that doesn't mean that the other mixes are no good.
Speaker 0: We just haven't played them a total ton They but whenever I do go up to one and play it I can always find a good song in there.
Speaker 0: And I'm sure if I actually played those newer mixes a whole bunch I'd find a lot of good songs.
Speaker 1: only trouble is they change the foot ranking system in the newer mixes.
Speaker 0: Good you just got to get used to it, but I don't know it at all.
Speaker 0: I just have trouble just a matter of not knowing.
Speaker 0: it's not a matter of less quality.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, you can kind of tell what era someone came from by what they call the different difficulties.
Speaker 1: Because remember it was basic trick maniac and then light standard heavy and then they changed it again in the X series.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it's called anymore.
Speaker 1: There was oni mode for a while when we used to play at that bowling alley.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember the bowling at RIT that dodgy.
Speaker 1: I don't think anyone in that bowling alley liked the fact that we were there.
Speaker 1: bunch of young rowdy kids on a DDR machine surrounded by like sad 40 year olds on a league night went to that bowling alley for Bowling class as did I. I got pretty good at bowling when I took that class.
Speaker 1: just cuz I bowled every week Yeah, then after I stopped taking the class my score went back down to sub 100.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe if we live somewhere that at a combination laundromat bowling alley we could get better at bowling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I was I was doing like a 190 pretty like.
Speaker 1: on average I get about 180 190 without any trouble Which not great, but not terrible Wow, anyway, so yeah DDR.
Speaker 0: by any measure of things that make a game good DDR ranks very highly across the board whereas other amazing games Even if they rank amazingly, they don't do everything.
Speaker 0: DDR is like the all-encompassing game.
Speaker 0: It does it all.
Speaker 1: I know a lot about the internals of old systems like how they upgraded.
Speaker 1: like, you know The arcade machine would be upgraded version to version and then like there are different versions of the hardware and these laser discs you put In and all that.
Speaker 1: but you can read a website if you care about that stuff, but the important thing The pure and true form of this game is the arcade machine.
Speaker 1: all other forms while good are inferior in many many ways.
Speaker 1: Those pads of well-maintained in the arcade are so Perfectly sensitive like you can just stand on an arrow and shift your weight to get it to register at the right timing Like it's kind of nuts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how well it works.
Speaker 0: You know if you play at home I mean the railing you're not supposed to hold the railing.
Speaker 0: the railing is to keep you from falling off onto the people behind You watching you or perhaps to do a trick.
Speaker 0: Yes, or perhaps you fall off the bar trying to do a trick and while you should not hold on to it the lack Of its presence at your home is a deficiency.
Speaker 1: also like, you know Arcade is the best.
Speaker 1: the next step down is a custom or cobalt blue hard pad Which just aren't as sturdy like.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to see if I can buy can I?
Speaker 1: just I haven't thought about doing it Cuz they're heavy.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to buy an arcade pad replacement and use an Arduino or something to hook it up and use it With USB.
Speaker 0: you go for it.
Speaker 1: I've been thinking about doing that.
Speaker 1: That's a big project though because those things are huge like bigger than my cape the table in our kitchen.
Speaker 0: It's just really I've been looking for like, you know old DDR machines.
Speaker 0: It's not easy to find them.
Speaker 1: I found one like a couple months ago for about four or five thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: It was a fourth mix machine with.
Speaker 1: it looked like was in pretty good condition, too.
Speaker 1: But where am I gonna put it?
Speaker 1: Scott's house the other Scott?
Speaker 0: No, Johnson.
Speaker 1: Yes He hinted that he might be willing to host a DDR machine if we bought it.
Speaker 0: Maybe why don't we rent one for a party?
Speaker 1: I don't even know who I'd write.
Speaker 1: What do are those companies that will rent?
Speaker 1: arcade machines still exist?
Speaker 0: Well, whoever who lends them to kinetic on a magfest.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Well, I know one group that does but I think they're not easy to rent for like just us and just one machine.
Speaker 1: They like to bring the whole experience as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: I'm sure we can work something out.
Speaker 1: I made a hard DDR pad a long time ago Okay, and then I broke it and then I threw it away.
Speaker 1: but like I spent like a month building this thing It was kind of awesome.
Speaker 1: Like I learned a lot about electrical stuff I used the board from a soft pad that it died to actually make it because that was basically a PlayStation one controller with a bunch of things I could solder like wires into.
Speaker 0: You know, it's you know.
Speaker 0: If you think about the impact DDR had in its day right and on the lives of anyone who played it It might have been like the greatest life impacting game.
Speaker 0: it's like sure.
Speaker 0: I probably spent more hours playing I don't know.
Speaker 0: maybe counter-strike might be tied.
Speaker 0: who even knows at this point.
Speaker 0: Yeah and tribes with my tribes, but it's like DDR probably influenced and had a bigger effect on my life than any other game and I think a lot of people who were into DDR can Say the same thing.
Speaker 1: and partly because it's physical It's a different kind of skill from games like counter-strike.
Speaker 1: You can pretty much just start Physical but but the difference is you can like.
Speaker 1: when I started playing counter-strike again when go came out I was not good like not at all.
Speaker 1: I'm still not great, but I'm not terrible anymore.
Speaker 1: but you can't just pick up DDR and kind of remember how to play.
Speaker 1: then you're good to go again, I highly recommend like anyone buy The bootleg equivalent of the old red octane ignition pad the like inch thick foam core Whatever
Speaker 0: GDR pet you can get and you that's
Speaker 1: the thin plastic ones Require a lot of nuance to work properly and I found that people who play on those Have a lot of trouble when they try to play on the arcade or a better pad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, unless you do crazy things like we did where we literally duct tape them to the floor semi-permanently.
Speaker 0: There's also some DDR ish games that came out to this pump which is more popular in Korea I think which is the same thing as DDR.
Speaker 0: only instead of four arrows that are orthogonal It has five places to step one big one in the middle and four in the corners.
Speaker 0: It's not as good.
Speaker 0: It has a few good songs.
Speaker 0: It's just not as good as well.
Speaker 1: The difference is the.
Speaker 1: the format was actually probably better in a lot of ways for like dance moves in terms of the five arrows having one of the middle.
Speaker 1: well the four arrows plus the middle.
Speaker 1: but The people who made pump were not as good at making arrows that match the song and the pump songs were all kind of samey DDR at a wide variety and it took him a while like until fourth mix the arrows did not match.
Speaker 1: the song is very well No But from fourth mix on whoever it was he was designing those arrows had like they had come up with a Theoretical underpinning and the like.
Speaker 1: it's very telling when you play some fan made arrows Versus official ones.
Speaker 1: the official ones are professionally and expertly made.
Speaker 1: they fit the music so perfectly.
Speaker 1: It's kind of amazing.
Speaker 0: And then there was in the groove which was this weird thing where it was sort of a illegal bootleg deal.
Speaker 1: But imagine step mania on an arcade machine, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like it was.
Speaker 0: it was like they made this game was just a clone of DDR.
Speaker 0: They thought they could get away with it.
Speaker 0: I don't think they did But they had songs.
Speaker 0: they're like machine supremacy songs are in there.
Speaker 0: well cuz they Harmonics involved in this.
Speaker 0: I don't even remember.
Speaker 1: all I remember is when cuz that Wildwood there were a bunch of real DDR machines and a bunch of those and In my purely anecdotal experience the douchebag set of DDR players mostly played that and everyone cool play the real DDR machines.
Speaker 1: But those machines like they had harder modes and seemed to focus on like the super hardcore hit every arrow Like I'm going to master this game to the exclusion of all their game sets.
Speaker 1: And they kind of disappeared and they weren't as good in a lot of ways.
Speaker 0: now You got a real lot.
Speaker 0: people might not know but DDR is actually just one of a series of games Konami made.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my Metal Gear con I'm in the B money series be money stands for is short way of saying beat mania be money beat man.
Speaker 0: You know Japan likes to shorten things like that, right?
Speaker 0: so The first game in the be money series was beat mania.
Speaker 0: That's the game with the little turntable and the buttons, right?
Speaker 0: And then there were also many other games in the series like para para paradise The guitar one which got copied into a guitar freaks.
Speaker 0: Yeah was the guitar one that was then ripped off to make guitar hero.
Speaker 1: None of them are as good as DD at DDR.
Speaker 0: pretty much every regard of all of those games.
Speaker 0: You know pop and music whatever and there's a whole bunch of new ones now these days.
Speaker 0: They got fancy digital crazy things and whatnot.
Speaker 0: We wave your hands around and touch screens and they're all insane.
Speaker 1: Well, I feel like most rhythm games today turned into.
Speaker 1: here's a touchpad.
Speaker 0: make swiping motions right of all of the be money and be money style games.
Speaker 0: only.
Speaker 0: DDR is a revolution none of the other ones a Dance dance revolution.
Speaker 1: Yes, seriously, if you have never played DDR Ask your friends.
Speaker 1: if you're all gamers There's probably someone you know who's into DDR and just doesn't talk about it.
Speaker 0: Look for someone who was in high school or college in the early 2000s someone in their late 20s to mid 30s.
Speaker 1: They probably played DDR.
Speaker 1: And if you see him one in the arcade just play it like just go for it go nuts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, do not do not look at DDR and say man.
Speaker 0: That is stupid.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Just keep playing it.
Speaker 1: I was there.
Speaker 1: we said that we felt that we knew it was stupid.
Speaker 0: I know a lot.
Speaker 0: I even I still know some people who are like a verse, you know, they're like anti DDR.
Speaker 0: They don't you know, they're not into it.
Speaker 0: It's just just let it go.
Speaker 0: Just do it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I Kind of want to play some DDR now.
Speaker 0: I always want to play D here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Pat got you ready for packs.
Speaker 0: Maybe they'll be some DDR Ben.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: Like socials tragic illness made a smile While we Foxley unconscious on the barroom tile.
Speaker 1: we're talking so from Maine San Diego top saw Manningley and can say go can't refuse grotesquely swollen jaw Steve Sachs and is running with the law.
Speaker 1: We're talking home Ozzy and the straw.
Speaker 1: we're talking The.