Speaker 1: It's Wednesday January 14th 2015.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: Tom Moore's song of the sea.
Speaker 0: Oh, so I'm gonna see.
Speaker 1: you probably haven't been able to see it because you don't live in New York.
Speaker 0: Who do we suckies?
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: so sometimes you get into those YouTube ghettos where like you click on a video and you watch it and then all the Recommendations are the same thing like you've stumbled into a meme.
Speaker 1: Yeah an event her like the night.
Speaker 1: that do you do do do do do do?
Speaker 1: I don't remember what that's called me there But yeah, cuz I was looking for that the other day and I don't remember what that meme is called I'm sure but you know what.
Speaker 0: you would recommend that to you just for being.
Speaker 1: you see you'd think that but it didn't.
Speaker 1: it's too old.
Speaker 0: Just search for some related things and you'll find it.
Speaker 1: I found crackle sauce and all the blank sauces again, but I didn't find that thing.
Speaker 1: Okay, but so I clicked on a clip.
Speaker 1: that was a clip from The Critic because I saw it and I thought Does that thing have?
Speaker 0: Mmm, how many episodes does that show critic?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the critic not many only like two seasons, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, 94 95 and then I guess had some online stuff.
Speaker 1: So not that many episodes 23 total.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can watch that really easily.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I click on this clip.
Speaker 1: That was just a clip from The Critic and it was hilarious.
Speaker 1: And I remembered The Critic and I remembered watching it.
Speaker 1: and I did was the show that I just Literally forgotten about in the modern era.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that shit holds up.
Speaker 0: It's not forgotten about.
Speaker 0: other people remember it.
Speaker 1: I'm saying I had forgotten about it.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I so Emily comes in I'm like, hey Remember The Critic.
Speaker 1: and she was like, I never watched The Critic.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So I never watched the whole thing.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: I watched The Critic.
Speaker 0: I seen enough of it.
Speaker 1: I watched it as it aired on ABC.
Speaker 1: I was really into.
Speaker 1: I was really into like animation stuff in general.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah Why not?
Speaker 1: it was on like primetime.
Speaker 0: I watched enough of it.
Speaker 0: I mean, I was doing other stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean, I watched the original pre Simpsons Simpsons Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So The Critic boy Emily never seen it.
Speaker 1: So I go look for an episode and you don't even need to pirate it Because every single episode is just on YouTube with a bunch of views and no one seems to care.
Speaker 1: I don't think they're legit.
Speaker 1: They're mostly uploaded by I called The Critic fan.
Speaker 0: I Mean there's a legal.
Speaker 0: there's a Gundam channel that has legal Gundams on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's always hard to say though because remember the whole crunchyroll thing.
Speaker 0: This one's definitely legal.
Speaker 0: It's like Bandai's channel.
Speaker 1: so we started watching The Critic and I because I hadn't watched it since I was a little kid I Noticed things nowadays that I didn't notice back then of course.
Speaker 1: So in my opinion now, this is kind of like a geek bite of The Critic.
Speaker 1: having seen it again recently one It holds up real well.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, really funny.
Speaker 0: I could have predicted that but - It's basically the precursor to Family Guy.
Speaker 0: Well, no I mean so.
Speaker 1: no so the in terms of the style of animated comedy that The Critic has the critic was way ahead of its time.
Speaker 1: No other animated show Did the kind of humor that it did, you know the Family Guy thing of wow That's just like the time I whatever.
Speaker 1: and then it cuts to like a complete non sequitur.
Speaker 1: The Critic did that regularly.
Speaker 0: The Simpsons did that regularly.
Speaker 1: The Simpsons didn't do it that regularly.
Speaker 0: They did it enough, right?
Speaker 1: So when what season did The Simpsons do that?
Speaker 1: The Simpsons was a.
Speaker 0: I can find you Simpsons clips of this?
Speaker 1: Yes, I could do.
Speaker 1: what year were they from?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: But yeah, cuz this Scott was 1994 I was in middle school.
Speaker 0: What happened is right?
Speaker 0: The Simpsons was basically the first mainstream widely broadcast adult TV animation in the US and it was so big.
Speaker 1: well multiple critics say that this was the Precursor to Family Guy on Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: So fuck you, whatever.
Speaker 0: so From The Simpsons right because it was so successful.
Speaker 0: many many You know people tried to make animation for adults on US television and it eventually over the 90s You know was the biggest time of this was a golden era.
Speaker 0: Yes, the golden era was then because remember this shit was on primetime.
Speaker 0: All right, and that well This is still on prime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but back then a cartoon being primetime not Was originally on primetime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, you know.
Speaker 0: But now today it pretty much has gotten to the point where only Fox does it other than Adult Swim?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that's it, right?
Speaker 0: So Like none of the other networks even bother trying to compete in the animation realm for adults at night and all Saturday You know, I don't even try.
Speaker 1: here's a quote here of all the projects completed by XSNL players the critic was the most fully realized layers and heartwarming.
Speaker 1: it took its cues from Woody Allen movies Like Annie Holland Manhattan and offered up a style of random abstract humor that wouldn't be seen again on television until Family Guy So watching it Emily on you know, sort of Unpointedly without me saying anything said wow.
Speaker 1: This is like a good version of Family Guy.
Speaker 1: So that's why I was thinking about Family Guy.
Speaker 1: What's interesting though?
Speaker 1: Is that it makes a ridiculous number of pop culture references That I think would be lost on pretty much anyone who would watch this show again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it ends up working much like how?
Speaker 1: well because you know No, because I didn't even know a lot of the references because I don't know a lot of actors names now.
Speaker 1: So why would I have known them in the 90s?
Speaker 0: I know more 90s ones than yeah thousands ones, you know, like Arnold that's also 80s.
Speaker 1: But what I noticed is that the that stuff in the critic was a lot like that stuff in Bugs Bunny Cartoons in Merry Melodies.
Speaker 1: There are jokes there if you recognize the caricatures of famous people But if you don't the jokes hold up on their own anyway so it's fine and if you're smart you at least recognize that thing in the background is Obviously a caricature of someone famous from that era and you can infer something about them from the way they're handled.
Speaker 1: So the critic I don't know.
Speaker 1: I watched a bunch of it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna watch all of it again, and It's really interesting to see how many modern animated comedy shows Basically are taking a lot of cues from what was really pioneered at least in the u.s.
Speaker 1: With the critic which didn't like it didn't actually do that.
Speaker 1: Well didn't last that long.
Speaker 1: No, I also remember that John Lovitz existed.
Speaker 1: I kind of forgot about him.
Speaker 0: What is he doing?
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: Is he alive?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: All right, let's see born 1957 SNL.
Speaker 1: Wow his summary ends with Did SNL until 1990?
Speaker 1: and then it doesn't say anything else.
Speaker 0: Tire and go to the beach cuz good job, dude trying to find that out.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of it.
Speaker 1: Broadway.
Speaker 1: He does a podcast I guess.
Speaker 0: good job, dude.
Speaker 0: You deserve it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: He's a funny guy.
Speaker 1: but so while I was watching all those Critics something else came up in the recommendations.
Speaker 0: Duckman that's another 90s adult TV show.
Speaker 1: man is pretty fucking forgotten.
Speaker 1: So Duckman also almost holds up And I'm gonna talk about it separately because I'm gonna watch a bunch of it and then talk about Duckman.
Speaker 0: Duckman is somewhere in between the critic the tick and like our Lucas arts adventure games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there was an adventure game for duck man Oh was there which was supposed to be released in the US but the production company went bankrupt.
Speaker 1: it Eventually somehow got released in Germany and South Korea And nowhere else and it is one of the rarest PC adventure games ever published.
Speaker 0: sure you can download it.
Speaker 0: No problem.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I'm gonna look into that.
Speaker 1: But what I can say is that watching duck man I had forgotten about duck man, and I watched it like religiously when I was a little kid.
Speaker 1: So I started like unlocking memories in my brain as I watched this episode Like just what the deal was with this show And the two-headed son.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I also saw a lot of future family guy echoes.
Speaker 1: actually.
Speaker 1: So the older brother in family guy reminds me of the older brother and duck man.
Speaker 1: They'd even have the same kind of voice acting style the anyway, I'll talk about.
Speaker 0: if you look at old arts You see where new arts got their shit.
Speaker 0: But duck man, no one, you know, I was listening to this Beethoven and I was like, oh man I never seen.
Speaker 1: I've heard that music before recently At the record store on the radio, but watching duck man with Emily would never seen it before Was a series of what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Why does that kid have two heads?
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: where is this set?
Speaker 1: What is?
Speaker 1: who are these?
Speaker 0: Wow Wow Okay, didn't you start at the start of the beginning to understand a lot of just random fucking episode?
Speaker 0: yeah, that's not gonna work.
Speaker 0: That show doesn't work with the random episode.
Speaker 1: and then I remember the duck man was voiced by Jason Alexander Basically playing a fucked up version of George Costanza as a duck.
Speaker 0: Yes, that is correct.
Speaker 1: So yeah, that's.
Speaker 1: I've been watching a lot of animation lately, but not a lot of anime.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Well the big news lately is People are going nuts over the two-sentence rumor.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's.
Speaker 0: I don't think oh, it's legit.
Speaker 1: There is a I am DV page already.
Speaker 0: That means it's confirmed.
Speaker 1: I'm assuming this movie is already in theaters.
Speaker 0: Well the live-action Akira never happened Even though it could.
Speaker 1: live-action Ava never happened the four or five times there were rumors.
Speaker 0: live-action Cowboy bebop with Keanu Reeves never happened Thank the gods, but it appears that the live-action ghost in the shell for the 700th attempt is More likely to happen than any of those have ever been likely to happen.
Speaker 1: I still think the percent chance of this happening is between five and six, but there is a name of famous Action girl actor lady.
Speaker 0: Do you don't know who that is?
Speaker 1: Do you I mean, okay So we just talked about her before we started recording the show.
Speaker 1: She's I said her name.
Speaker 0: So the name is Scarlett Johansson because I can read it on IMDb and all I know about her Is that she is a famous actress?
Speaker 1: Suspect she was cast in this specifically because she plays Black Widow and she's a woman and that's it.
Speaker 0: So she is like Hollywood's current famous action actress person.
Speaker 0: So if you have an action part for a person who is not have a penis So this is the person that you hire.
Speaker 1: so should we talk about how we expect this will be bad or we should talk about All the meta reasons.
Speaker 0: Well Disney's doing it first of all right, so problem number one Despite the fact that the major is a robot the major is not white and Scarlett Johansson is Problem number one.
Speaker 1: wait, so so are you telling me that?
Speaker 1: The Pharaoh wasn't white Moses isn't white that You'll Brenner wasn't white not that you know about the remake right.
Speaker 0: you'll Brenner was not.
Speaker 0: I'm not talking about you'll Brenner I don't know any other day.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: You're gonna be real sad.
Speaker 0: They made another Ten Commandments that has white people in it.
Speaker 1: There's a movie.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about that separately the same.
Speaker 0: I mean not that you'll Brenner is Egyptian Not that Moses.
Speaker 0: I mean Chotland Heston is white and Moses was not.
Speaker 1: But you at least you guys got Exodus gods and kings.
Speaker 0: is This like the 300 of Ten Commandments, uh it seems to be.
Speaker 1: let's see so.
Speaker 1: Moses is played by Christian Bale All right, and yes, I leave it at that my Batman.
Speaker 0: Go all right look.
Speaker 1: Here's here's the cast.
Speaker 1: look white white white.
Speaker 0: Why not hire some Egyptian people?
Speaker 0: Any of them at least white Jews and I mean you could hire Israelis - wow I did not realize until just know.
Speaker 1: this was Directed by Ridley Scott.
Speaker 1: yeah Anyway So it is not Necessarily wrong to ignore race when casting.
Speaker 1: it just so happens that whenever they ignore race for casting It's always in favor of everybody being white.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why?
Speaker 0: well we know why at the major was black.
Speaker 0: We couldn't really say anything about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah But and it always happens to be right.
Speaker 0: It's like It's one.
Speaker 0: They've actually Hollywood seems to less often Whitewashed black people.
Speaker 0: not that it doesn't happen and it happens all the goddamn.
Speaker 0: yeah But it's like they whitewashed the Asian people slightly more that they do than the black people who are also whitewashed.
Speaker 1: So even we're.
Speaker 1: what I've noticed in general is that ignoring racism and all the other issues that are clustered around this whenever there's a movie like this that has like it is set in a country with a Specific culture and those sorts of things and they whitewash it usually it's a sign that is gonna be pretty shitty independent of any racism.
Speaker 0: yeah, well, okay, so Going based on the history of everything Hollywood has ever done ever and the fact that is Disney and etc.
Speaker 0: etc.
Speaker 0: Basically we can assume if the original Ghost in the Shell if we consider that to be the middle of the gray area flat gray Right eight eight eight eight eight eight eight
Speaker 1: right
Speaker 0: and we consider Ghost in the Shell 2 innocence to be black Zero zero zero zero zero zero zero zero.
Speaker 0: this is gonna be white.
Speaker 1: So the other thing is I've thought about this a lot.
Speaker 1: actually I have this idea that you know sanctuary the ma the Best manga.
Speaker 1: we recommend that you guys just can't ever read because it's been out of print forever.
Speaker 0: sure you can get it on the Internet.
Speaker 1: yeah, you can pirate it, but there's no legit way to get it printed.
Speaker 0: a spy kill rim and steal it from his house?
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: part of the problem Why you can't get it?
Speaker 1: cuz we talked about in geek nights a long time about every copy we saw in the Northeast.
Speaker 1: I have two and a half complete sets of it just because and our listeners from the old days probably bought all the rest of them.
Speaker 1: but You could do.
Speaker 1: there are two ways to adapt that.
Speaker 1: that would not be racist way.
Speaker 1: number one Adapted in America set in Japan with Japanese actors.
Speaker 1: that'd be fine.
Speaker 1: or Do a complete read adaptation and take that core story and rewrite it and set it like in the 80s in Chicago.
Speaker 1: That would also be okay because you're changing the setting and make you know you're you're localizing it.
Speaker 1: There's ways to do that, but if they may did the former option, and it was all white actors probably Probably at least unconsciously racist I have no confidence this is gonna come out.
Speaker 1: nor do I have any confidence that is going to be good and I really just want more Ghost in the Shell standalone complex.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: We're gonna.
Speaker 0: There's more Ghost in the Shell arise.
Speaker 1: We haven't seen I know and I'm just gonna wait until we can watch more of it in the theater like we did the other Ones I think those.
Speaker 0: finally we're approaching the point where all those Evangelion movies are done.
Speaker 0: we can watch those once.
Speaker 1: five dot five five five five five five five five or whatever comes out.
Speaker 1: We're just gonna marathon them all.
Speaker 0: the Evangelion Manga, I think is also done and oh shit son Viz has printed three in one volume.
Speaker 1: Did you ever read any of it?
Speaker 0: I read the start you can get.
Speaker 0: I think you can get all of it now in these three and one volumes from viz Cuz.
Speaker 1: that manga is really good.
Speaker 0: So and I think it's actually complete complete like you know what it's like.
Speaker 0: it is finished And there's not gonna be any.
Speaker 1: you know it's kind of like you keep talking about the Gundam manga.
Speaker 1: That's just like yeah, you wanted Exactly.
Speaker 0: oh by the way Gundam the origin.
Speaker 1: if you're not reading that Seriously yeah, I gotta read it.
Speaker 1: It's I Guess.
Speaker 1: well you got to read the book club book.
Speaker 0: yeah, so anyway.
Speaker 0: I got some brief news here The Emerald City comic-con probably the best still actually a comic-con on the west coast yep Which already is.
Speaker 1: there's not a lot of competition in that?
Speaker 0: It's definitely in fact you know of all the comic cons in the US that are still comic cons.
Speaker 0: It's up there.
Speaker 0: There's like the competition is like your heroes con.
Speaker 1: Yeah in North Carolina and I Mean unless you count things like mocha and SPX like that's.
Speaker 0: no we're talking about the mainstream comic cons Not the.
Speaker 0: yeah tea caps and whatnots.
Speaker 1: I mean you don't want to go to.
Speaker 1: What was that stupid convention?
Speaker 0: We went to and cuz I mean New York comic-con San Diego comic-con c2e2 all these Comic-cons that you know well.
Speaker 0: come no longer about comedy.
Speaker 1: use the new definition of comic-con which means generic pop culture Convention that you walk in and walk all the comic cons that are still comic cons.
Speaker 0: ECCC is like one of the top Three in the North America easily yep in fact.
Speaker 1: It's a comic-con I would go to if it weren't in Seattle and if I didn't already fly to Seattle once or twice a year for other conventions.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, like if ECCC were the weekend before or after packs I'd probably stick around and go to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 0: yeah, it's worth it.
Speaker 0: It's what kind of thing it's definitely worth it to go to for a day.
Speaker 1: well read pop known for Running the awful New York comic-con for running the okay, New York anime festival and then destroying it For somehow running the all the penny arcade expos and not destroying them Is now taking also the c2e2 also Star Wars yeah celebration celebration.
Speaker 1: from what I hear They do a good job with that one, but Star Wars celebration is basically a big expo kind of con.
Speaker 1: anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm good at that kind of con.
Speaker 1: Their bait read pop is basically good at running a certain kind of convention.
Speaker 0: It's just having to do like book expo.
Speaker 1: They do a lot of.
Speaker 0: they do a lot of.
Speaker 0: they do some wrestling con or something.
Speaker 1: just so happens that the kinds of Conventions they're good at running are the convention formats that I hate more than anything.
Speaker 1: so Read pop is taking over the Emerald City comic-con.
Speaker 0: They just bought it so the people who owned it sold it to them.
Speaker 1: Let's see here's the comics.
Speaker 0: was it?
Speaker 0: was it not for profit?
Speaker 1: Research this because it happened very recently like Dateline today.
Speaker 1: I was looking at this.
Speaker 1: Let's see read pop blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: Emerald City comic-con is now a part of read pop comics Alliance has confirmed that as part of the acquisition of ECCC The director John de Manacos and his staff will remain not just blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: who's gonna actually run the show?
Speaker 1: So that's the question.
Speaker 0: which individual human being?
Speaker 0: so I think Lance Fensterman runs in New York comic-con.
Speaker 0: I hope it's someone at read pop at least that's the last name that I heard.
Speaker 1: there are people at read pop that we know Who you can trust to be awesome, and there are people you can trust to fuck things up.
Speaker 1: not gonna name names I don't know which.
Speaker 1: who's dealing with this one, so we'll see.
Speaker 1: I hope this opinion I'm about to lay down doesn't anger anyone who's listening because we you know are go to PAX is all the time.
Speaker 1: in my Personal opinion the only reason read hasn't ruined the penny arcade expos is because PA Corp and the PA people and the Enforcers that were like there from the early days Actually make all the important decisions that matter and read does most of the logistics and all the other stuff.
Speaker 1: I Don't think that's the case with all these other cons.
Speaker 1: I don't think ECCC is gonna remain a good convention Mmm.
Speaker 1: That is my personal opinion.
Speaker 0: Maybe maybe that was yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean I hope I'm wrong and I hope that packs continues to remain awesome to throw everything but We'll see what happens with ECC.
Speaker 1: see see see see.
Speaker 0: I mean it is a big You know convention hall convention it is.
Speaker 0: it just happens to be a well done one.
Speaker 1: Just like Heroes con is yep So will they shift it more toward being pop culture New York comic-con SDCC style because it does have a large Percentage is comics because I don't mind generic con.
Speaker 1: what I hate is comic-con style generic.
Speaker 1: Can I like at least have like Dragon Con or kinetic on style generic con?
Speaker 1: Not to be confused with generic.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we ever talked about this on geek nights But Nina Paley has done a few awesome things on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Nina Paley's is awesome person.
Speaker 0: she makes animations and other arts and You might remember from back in the day because she was like big into the Creative Commons action.
Speaker 0: There's a video you almost probably have seen where it's like.
Speaker 0: it looks like an old Mickey Mouse cartoon in black and white and they're Singing a song like copying is not theft.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So she did that and then since then she's done a lot of other things and kick-started a movie.
Speaker 0: and you know She just keeps putting stuff out and she keeps being awesome.
Speaker 1: Yep, like she did see two things the blues Movie she kick-started and she's got another thing in the works.
Speaker 1: So my thing of the day is two of her videos because one they're kind of relevant to modern politics and two Perennially relevant.
Speaker 1: Yes perennial is in fact the perfect word to use there But two they both involve something amazing.
Speaker 1: So the kind of thing that I'm really into personified death.
Speaker 1: her personification of death is Possibly the best personification of death the world has ever seen.
Speaker 0: should it have a fight with birthday abacus death?
Speaker 1: Oh, they're pretty good deaths, but look at that death.
Speaker 0: She should have a fight.
Speaker 1: look at that death face right there.
Speaker 0: You have a fight with Adventure Time death.
Speaker 0: Adventure Time death is pretty good, too Like because Adventure Time death what I like about him is doesn't have a human skull.
Speaker 1: true true I got that rat skull thing going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah So you got a thing of the day?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, so her video video number one This land is mine.
Speaker 1: It is a history of the conflict in Israel and Palestine from caveman days through today Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And actually the cool thing about the video is if you go to her page She actually has a really long list of every single culture that's shown in the video and what their deal was Mm-hmm and to the death of the firstborn Egyptians.
Speaker 1: the witch will get stuck in your head and make you really depressed.
Speaker 0: Good thing it never actually happened.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: No, no, not.
Speaker 1: not the fact that Egyptians died in a mythical Christian past Because it's a mythical Jewish past.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a mythical past of a lot of people.
Speaker 1: Anyway, these are both really good Nita Paley's amazing, right?
Speaker 0: So rim you ever had to change a flat tire on your bike.
Speaker 1: I actually have never Since I switched away from mountain bikes changed a flat tire on my bike.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: We've had a flat tire.
Speaker 1: Uh No, no, not on my new bikes.
Speaker 1: I have not actually had a flat tire.
Speaker 0: Well, I got close.
Speaker 0: Well changing a flat tire sucks is doable, but it sucks and it's kind of hard.
Speaker 0: You got eat first.
Speaker 1: Well, it's gone.
Speaker 1: I want to tell you if it's a mountain bike.
Speaker 1: It doesn't suck.
Speaker 1: It takes two seconds.
Speaker 1: You can do.
Speaker 0: it is way easier with a mountain bike with big fat tires.
Speaker 0: So here's the process of changing a tire on a bicycle.
Speaker 0: first you got to pop the wheel off.
Speaker 0: that's way easy.
Speaker 0: Yep, then you got a little.
Speaker 1: this is the back tire.
Speaker 1: You gotta like get the chain.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: It's still easy.
Speaker 1: It adds another like 30 seconds, whatever.
Speaker 0: then you got to get the tire off the bike and you need specialized off the rim.
Speaker 0: So Mainly you just remove some air because it's flat.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it should have some air removed right and you use tire levers Which like you basically stick it in between the rim and the tire and sort of pop out the thing.
Speaker 0: and then you go whoosh In a circle and basically now the tire is only half on the rim.
Speaker 0: Then you grab the the tube that's broken and pull it out.
Speaker 0: Then you sort of partially inflate a new tube Stick it in, you know inside the tire nice, you know, make sure it doesn't like get crimped or anything.
Speaker 0: Then you got a wedge that tire back onto the rim, which is the hardest part.
Speaker 0: Then you got to reinflate it and make sure it's all 100% perfect and sealed and beautiful and everything Yep, and then you got to put the tire back on the bike.
Speaker 0: So this is even with tire even with the appropriate tools and everything.
Speaker 0: This is not a trivial thing to do With two hands as a human being.
Speaker 0: also then you have to reinflate it, which is really hard considering the fact that well It's super de-inflated.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well like in the old days, it's not like pumping it up like oh, I lost a little bit air.
Speaker 0: It's like oh it's empty.
Speaker 1: for most of my life.
Speaker 1: I lived in a house I could have the tools and equipment necessary to do bike maintenance.
Speaker 1: Now that I live in New York City I pay other people to do all my bike maintenance because it's such a pain in the ass if you don't have all that equipment.
Speaker 0: So in this video you will see a person.
Speaker 1: Oh, I just saw what this video is.
Speaker 0: You'll see a person who is among the class of people known as ultimate badasses.
Speaker 0: He has no arms, well, I guess he has some arm below the elbow Left but he doesn't have any hands.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 0: Look at that bicep Jesus and he doesn't have a right arm at all.
Speaker 0: But you don't need arms to ride a bicycle.
Speaker 1: But you might all right this guy's doing.
Speaker 1: he's doing it faster than I could do it.
Speaker 0: Let's in fast-forward.
Speaker 1: No, no This video is four minutes long.
Speaker 1: I could not do it in four minutes even in fast-forward.
Speaker 0: four minutes Right, but yeah, he changes a bike tire with basically one arm mostly using feet teeth He'd.
Speaker 0: the only advantage he has is that he doesn't have to pump because he has a can of a little compressed air cylinder thingy.
Speaker 1: That's what I would always carry with me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I should get one of those.
Speaker 0: Yeah, his tire lever is better than my tire lever because it attaches to the like, you know spoke in the middle of the Tire.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know what tire levers you bought.
Speaker 0: you bought the cheapest one on Amazon Yeah, the blue plastic one.
Speaker 0: three of them the one that everyone has.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, he's got the one that like attaches to the middle of the tire and goes whoosh in a circle real easily.
Speaker 0: That's the only advantage he's got.
Speaker 0: otherwise Super disadvantage.
Speaker 0: not having any goddamn arms Changes the tire way easier than I can do it.
Speaker 0: This is an amazing video and he needs to do this because basically he's like taking long ass bike trips You know all by himself.
Speaker 0: He's got to be able to change the tire.
Speaker 1: That is why I was into mountain biking where like if I had a problem fuck and I just like walk out or whatever Or I could just fix it trivially, but I didn't carry a lot of equipment with me.
Speaker 1: I don't do super long bike treks Unless it's some sort of organized event where there's like following maintenance cars and things just because I don't have patience for this stuff anymore.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Wow, this video is really amazing.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I'm saying it's good bike - well, I mean, it's got to go really far.
Speaker 1: Yeah So In the meta moment the book love book is still a water ship down the amazing story of a bunch of rabbits on an epic Adventure.
Speaker 1: and it's a really good book.
Speaker 0: sploosh water.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're reading it now.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Oh, I read just as my.
Speaker 0: I haven't read anything since we last did a pod.
Speaker 1: Oh, cuz water plays a big.
Speaker 0: you're the rather would hope so with the title.
Speaker 0: Not know that there would be water ships and something going down.
Speaker 1: Well, read you read your book.
Speaker 1: We are going to be actually very soon In San Antonio, Texas next week and on Sunday, January 25th at 4 30 p.m In the Armadillo theater right before the Omega ton fine ale we are going to be presenting Bad games at Pac South the inaugural back south.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, we have fuck all to do but play games.
Speaker 0: So come say hi and eat Texas food and not get shot by Texas Cowboys.
Speaker 1: and then not too long after that Friday March 6 at PAX East in Boston We are presenting at least one lecture at 4 30 p.m.
Speaker 1: In the bumblebee theater.
Speaker 1: What is losing?
Speaker 0: What is losing?
Speaker 1: Well come to our lecture and you'll find out.
Speaker 1: Yes, and also I've been thinking about this.
Speaker 1: I didn't ask Scott before the show.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of thinking maybe we should shift the show because it's been so long and Do the news at the end of the main vid at the beginning?
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 1: because our Listeners who are the listener who's excited about the show already is invested.
Speaker 1: He's gonna listen whatever.
Speaker 1: but whenever someone who isn't a your existing fan links to us for whatever reason they're like.
Speaker 1: Oh, they just reviewed that anime that I like and then it's 20 minutes of us bullshitting about biking and living in New York.
Speaker 0: But and also so that so they want to really listen to that review of that anime they like and now we're introducing them to Us.
Speaker 0: if they might just turn off after that review true and then not get to know us true But I thought of a very specific UX case on this.
Speaker 1: so say I'm the listener I just make two mp3s.
Speaker 1: then I yeah, I thought about that.
Speaker 0: we could do.
Speaker 0: we could do like news episode Main vid episode.
Speaker 1: I had thought about doing that and having separate RSS feeds for a long time.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should when we make two different geek night two different shows.
Speaker 0: geek nights Bullshit nice pure and geek.
Speaker 0: would anyone listen to geek nights?
Speaker 0: bullshit.
Speaker 0: Oh and people only listen to main big gig nights.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let us know.
Speaker 1: You know we've been doing this for almost ten.
Speaker 1: well Yeah, actually about ten years now
Speaker 0: you want to change the format on the tenth year Maybe
Speaker 1: and let's
Speaker 0: just close the whole thing at the tenth and
Speaker 1: we're thinking about doing a tenth anniversary Special at some point that might involve a party in New York City, so
Speaker 0: that's all you.
Speaker 0: yeah
Speaker 1: If you would Sometime like six ish months from now Come to New York City to see a live show and have a party somewhere with us to celebrate our the ridiculous Time that we've been doing this show the
Speaker 0: ridiculous waste of our lives then here It's
Speaker 1: just let me know because if people are interested.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna fucking kick-start it.
Speaker 1: so it doesn't cost me anything to kick-start that.
Speaker 1: Kickstarter is just pre-order for badges.
Speaker 0: I Just use Eventbrite also, and then just not and just give everyone refunds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could good Yeah, or I could kick-start it just because I found some venues.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's about it.
Speaker 1: I don't have any other meta, so We saw a movie movie that most of you can't see.
Speaker 0: what song to see?
Speaker 0: Okay So I make fun of Irish people.
Speaker 1: the one the one one of the many manifold benefits of living in New York City Is that we see pretty much?
Speaker 1: Every anime or animated feature that's available to be seen in a theater that we want to see That we're home that we're home to see exactly Like I missed Princess Kaguya cuz I was out of town for something.
Speaker 0: I think that'll be easy to see if you want to.
Speaker 1: yeah, it will be probably but I Remember where I was.
Speaker 0: I don't know where you were.
Speaker 0: so anyway Long ago.
Speaker 1: you may remember the secret of cals which was a really beautiful movie that we really really enjoyed.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure we reviewed it.
Speaker 1: Yep Tom Moore went on to now do Song of the sea which is about silkies.
Speaker 0: So if you don't know there is basically the secret of cals made by these people who were in Ireland.
Speaker 0: They're Irish All right, and it's sort of unusual to think of animation from Ireland.
Speaker 0: usually only think of animation from the United States Canada Japan sometimes France Sometimes Korea, and there aren't really a lot of other countries that are known for their Animated creations, I guess there's some old Russian animations that are interesting, but it's not like.
Speaker 0: oh man Have you seen that new?
Speaker 0: you know Belgian animation?
Speaker 0: Yeah, have you seen that new?
Speaker 0: Czechoslovakian animation movie.
Speaker 0: wow yeah, they don't really have big animation studios.
Speaker 1: You know in all these countries or in the times that they do they're very domestic or locally.
Speaker 0: yeah They're not making full-length.
Speaker 0: You know top production quality Motion pictures.
Speaker 0: right they may be making like a local.
Speaker 0: You know like Poland only TV show or Argentina only you know movie or whatever right?
Speaker 0: It's pretty rare.
Speaker 0: so in Ireland made secret of cals that was a big fucking deal.
Speaker 0: cuz like whoa Ireland made a 90 ish full-length.
Speaker 0: you know 90 ish minute full-length motion animated feature.
Speaker 0: that is top quality.
Speaker 1: Holy shit, I mean it was beautiful.
Speaker 1: It was drawn from like the aesthetic of old illuminations from like Christian manuscripts in the monasteries.
Speaker 1: It was nominated for best animated feature that year 2008 2009.
Speaker 0: So when they made secret of cals they didn't have mad moneys.
Speaker 1: I read that there were production issues, so I'm sure there was really good And I really liked it, but it had some pacing issues, and it's sort of meandered in the second half.
Speaker 1: But apparently part of that came out of them not necessarily having had enough money to finish it and a troubled production process.
Speaker 1: So now you know armed with.
Speaker 0: but because it because it was so good They got money.
Speaker 1: armed with money in the faith of other people and everything involved.
Speaker 1: Tom Moore went on to now direct song of the sea.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna see.
Speaker 1: we're not gonna spoil anything obviously other than it's about selkies.
Speaker 1: Oh, you don't say the old myths of Basically where seals?
Speaker 0: yeah, it's Irish people.
Speaker 1: You know in Ireland Dungeons & Dragons players know who selkies are.
Speaker 0: it's cold in Ireland and it's north And it's surrounded by water because an island and seals live there, so there's a lot of folk tales about People that turn into seals and back and those are called selkies.
Speaker 1: yep, so This review aside what I can say and I think Scott agrees this I think this was the best movie I saw in 2014.
Speaker 0: problem.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: I think it's the best.
Speaker 0: It's definitely the best movie I saw in 2014 that I hadn't seen before and came out in 2014.
Speaker 1: even of the movies I saw in 2014 that came out before 2014 I think it was the best movie I saw in 2014.
Speaker 0: think I saw a rear window at least once in 2014 for like the seventh or eighth time.
Speaker 0: I can't say that.
Speaker 0: yeah, I did not.
Speaker 0: I had to put more stipulations, but did I also rewatch seven samurai?
Speaker 0: It is possible.
Speaker 1: it far surpasses the Secret of Kells in terms of Production in terms of story and everything and the Secret of Kells was already super good.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah This is like saying yeah, this is way beyond Ava.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean it's like they went from really good - yeah now you got it right.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like wow that person's really fat.
Speaker 0: You know it's like they went in the Olympics.
Speaker 0: They came out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: They got like the silver medal.
Speaker 0: It's like whoa good job guys We never even heard of you before and you had the silver medal.
Speaker 0: That's crazy good.
Speaker 1: and the next year They're like yeah, we need a plan.
Speaker 0: the next year It's like they're across the finish line and no one else even started yet.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, okay.
Speaker 0: Good job You got it now.
Speaker 1: What's cool.
Speaker 1: Is that once again?
Speaker 1: It has a very much like Kells had this very sort of Two-dimensional flat aesthetic kind of based on the art that it was based.
Speaker 0: You can tell just by looking at it that it was made by the same people exactly.
Speaker 0: even if it wasn't about something Irish.
Speaker 1: It has a consistent and beautiful color palette and aesthetic that fits the story.
Speaker 1: It's telling so well.
Speaker 0: Yeah They pretty much took all the green Markers that they ran out of when they use secretive cows and they started using the blue markers because they had extra And also more importantly secretive cows told us.
Speaker 1: sort of Meandering and melancholy.
Speaker 1: story was almost I don't want to say it was slice of life because it did have like a hero's journey and all Aspects.
Speaker 1: but in a way it was just this look at an era and a setting and a place and a mindset.
Speaker 1: Song of the sea is not that it is a very very strong narrative that Simultaneously is a very strong like internally consistent allegory.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean It's pretty much this like direct adventure tale like just like most kids movies.
Speaker 0: are you know plot structure wise and if you're an adult?
Speaker 1: You know everything that's going to happen in this movie After the first five minutes, however, if you're an adult who's mostly used to Disney or American animated features You will find the end and the sort of message and moral of the story to be Deeply painfully melancholy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not like it.
Speaker 0: mean I consider it to be a happy ending, but it's not a happy.
Speaker 0: Aladdin marries jasmine ending.
Speaker 1: no, it is a happy in that was resolved to the best that it could be.
Speaker 1: The world is moving on to another stage in era.
Speaker 0: These problems that could be solved have been solved, but they have been solved in a way.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes I mean, what other kind of solution did you want?
Speaker 1: We'll talk a little bit about some of the.
Speaker 1: what actually if you already saw the movie?
Speaker 0: All right, so it's a quick plot summary, right?
Speaker 0: So there's a family happy Irish family.
Speaker 1: Well, not a happy family.
Speaker 0: They're happy at the beginning.
Speaker 0: Okay, okay They live on an island with a lighthouse with a lighthouse, which is pretty awesome, right?
Speaker 1: Just like Pete's dragon.
Speaker 0: Yeah Mom's a selkie, bro.
Speaker 1: Yeah Rope straight up.
Speaker 0: She's like this is and people are gonna be like us.
Speaker 0: No, it's like minute number one.
Speaker 0: Mom's a selkie, bro.
Speaker 0: Yep, right.
Speaker 1: So she now they have a boy who's just a normal boy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a son who's young and mom's pregnant with I guess a seal.
Speaker 1: Yes On the night that the young girl the sister is to be born the mother Essentially dies.
Speaker 0: she goes into the ocean because she's a seal and now the movie and all they have left is the daughter.
Speaker 1: So he actually begins effectively with a young boy who resents his younger sister for effectively killing his mom Which is actually a common tale both in literature and in real life.
Speaker 0: That is something that happens alright, so mom's gone she turned into a seal or died or whatever.
Speaker 0: and The sisters their brother doesn't like the sister there.
Speaker 0: He's way older.
Speaker 0: now This is like five.
Speaker 1: at least five years after this opening He resents her for the mother's death effectively.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And meanwhile the father's life is in shambles Again, because of the mother's death.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my wife turned into a seal and or and died and or disappeared.
Speaker 0: I'm upset.
Speaker 0: Yep, and then from mom was awesome because she was a selkie.
Speaker 0: It's like it's not just your wife.
Speaker 0: It's like you're a ridiculously awesome wife.
Speaker 1: This is both this.
Speaker 1: this is a tale of all of the major characters every single one of them Coming to terms with something.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm It's it's.
Speaker 1: it's a very rarely if I seen a movie that has such complete character arcs for every Character who has more than trivial speaking lines.
Speaker 1: Yep, who does not have a complete character arc?
Speaker 1: the dog?
Speaker 0: The bus drive the fairy dude.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I guess there's Before the movie.
Speaker 1: wait, the fairy dudes do have a complete arc because you get their arc through the past.
Speaker 1: I thought you're talking about the guy who drives the ferry not the fairies.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah fairy dude.
Speaker 0: Yeah fairy dude also, but also a hairdude.
Speaker 1: Yeah hairdo dude.
Speaker 1: I like hairdo hair dudes on the cover here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean he looks really cool.
Speaker 1: So yeah, but seriously if you even if you hate animation and hate movies You should coach there is literally no one.
Speaker 1: this movie is not for right.
Speaker 0: So basically after you know it fast forwards in time There's an adventure of traveling across land and encountering things and learning and advancing.
Speaker 1: and then the story Follows these characters and also follows basically the sweep of Irish myth.
Speaker 0: Yep, very people selkie beginning to end.
Speaker 0: also commentary and modern things Mm-hmm whatnot.
Speaker 1: So if I can't I cannot stress this enough.
Speaker 0: also beautiful animations and music.
Speaker 1: the soundtrack is great.
Speaker 1: The voice acting is super great.
Speaker 0: The characters have voices.
Speaker 1: Yeah You mean all but one the dog.
Speaker 1: he talks wolf.
Speaker 1: yeah I point out that owls.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I like the owls a lot too.
Speaker 1: I like their little jars About the other seals.
Speaker 0: the seals obviously kind of seals are definitely the best and I like how the seals look like.
Speaker 1: They're smiling by the way, they're drawn.
Speaker 1: I think that's a real.
Speaker 1: seals are like that - yes But the way they're drawn and the way they're presented double cute.
Speaker 1: They're bobbing.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I think triple cute.
Speaker 1: then is the young girl the selkie When she turns into a seal.
Speaker 1: spoilers, I guess.
Speaker 0: Oh my god Selkie's daughter is also a selkie, but you don't say then when she's a seal when she's wearing her up her selkie cape.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's pretty good.
Speaker 1: So go see the movie and you might as well stop listening right now.
Speaker 0: It might not be the easiest thing for you to see right now because it's like in theaters and weird places And there's a calendar.
Speaker 0: if you go search on Google You can see the calendar or linked rim could link to it and you'll see where it's playing in various countries and cities.
Speaker 0: But secret of Kells was on Netflix like very soon after we saw it.
Speaker 0: So I'm sure this will be on Netflix DVD everything etc.
Speaker 0: in relatively short order like months If not weeks exactly.
Speaker 1: so see it as soon as you can.
Speaker 1: and now I actually kind of want to talk about What actually happens in the movie for the few people who might have seen it or if they come back later?
Speaker 0: But okay.
Speaker 1: So spoilers past this point stop listening unless you saw the movie.
Speaker 0: and I would actually keep listening because it won't ruin the movie Because the movie is a hundred percent obvious to anyone intelligent.
Speaker 1: However, it will change your perception of the movie?
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: I think it will anyway.
Speaker 1: spoilers spoilers spoilers.
Speaker 0: It doesn't even have surprises Spoilers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you can go find the forum thread where everyone in the world argues with Scott about whether or not spoilers matter.
Speaker 1: They don't anyway, so I Really liked the fact that pretty much every one of you like the kid Does his adventure.
Speaker 1: but look at the back framing story the story of you know, the fairy?
Speaker 1: King, well the the giant guy who has turned to stone to take away his suffering and how he is obviously The young boy's father.
Speaker 1: Yep, and how the villain the baba yaga and her baba yaga hut equivalent the owl lady is Straight up the grandma and the movie even like
Speaker 0: lonely, you know when we went to see it Tom Moore was there and he said Basically, like that wasn't originally gonna be the grandma but then they changed it to make it that way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and like I think by making every single like conflict along the adventure path Into something that lined up with you know, their real lives and real problems.
Speaker 0: That was really interesting cuz like sometimes, you know, it's kind of similar to a spirited away Right in that you sort of encounter these different, you know monsters or even Alice in Wonderland, right?
Speaker 0: She's encountering these different things along the way Yeah, and they have sort of a metaphor for you know real problems and other things right on this adventure.
Speaker 0: But this one is like so direct without being overwrought at the giant.
Speaker 1: The giant was turned to stone by his mother to harden his heart So he would not suffer anymore mourning the loss of his dead lover.
Speaker 0: and that is a hundred percent what grandma is doing.
Speaker 1: grandma is Basically hardening the heart of the father whose life has become static because he can't get over the loss of his wife Mm-hmm, and he's holding basically the.
Speaker 1: the young boy is sort of stuck in the middle of all this and goes on his journey.
Speaker 1: but all of that because there's no way in the real world when Mom dies giving birth to younger daughter for that situation to be resolved Happily.
Speaker 1: or fairy tale like you can't just bring someone back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Recognizing that watching the movie and then realizing that the entire fairy adventure is a parallel to that The beginning of the movie tells you that this does not end with all those fairies turned to stone Being brought back to life.
Speaker 1: it ends with them all moving on.
Speaker 1: it ends with the end of the fairies.
Speaker 1: Yeah end of an era the.
Speaker 1: I said in the beginning we were reviewing.
Speaker 0: also Can I just say the fairies are totally bad?
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: the fairies that whole scene at the end where each stone fairy like turns back into a fairy person or fairy ghost.
Speaker 1: but All the different fairies they made and how they look at how that scene worked and that's one with the shield I guess every one of those fairy stones They didn't turn back to life like the ones who turned to stone didn't like come into bodies again.
Speaker 1: It was almost like their essence appeared that that animation that whole end sequence.
Speaker 1: I was choking back tears the entire time.
Speaker 1: It was like a certain sweep in near the end of Madoka Magica.
Speaker 0: that montage You could also think of it as a sweep at the end of Evangelion was a million crosses going.
Speaker 1: But like I said This is the sweep of the fairies of Irish myth to the end.
Speaker 1: the modern era has Disciplanted them.
Speaker 1: the the the fairy world came to terms with the fact that it is dead.
Speaker 1: The selkies came to terms with the fact that they are gone.
Speaker 1: The boy and his father come to terms with the fact that their mother is gone.
Speaker 0: Well his wife The mother's dad's mother still there.
Speaker 1: Yes mother I could have framed that better that sentence.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even even grandma right?
Speaker 0: It's like the whole time.
Speaker 0: grandma is just the bad person right?
Speaker 0: She wants him to move to the city.
Speaker 0: You know she's grumpy.
Speaker 0: She's not happy.
Speaker 0: You know I get you get the idea that maybe she used to be cool But she's not and I didn't think at all that grandma would turn good.
Speaker 0: I thought the happy ending would be just get away from grandma grandma.
Speaker 0: How much grandma keeps being a crab in the city?
Speaker 0: well?
Speaker 1: What was grandma's character arc?
Speaker 1: was it possibly that she recognized?
Speaker 1: How broken up the father was by it and realized that maybe she can't keep him static.
Speaker 1: She's trying to mold him into like this different type of father Yeah, and this different type of family, and I think she has to.
Speaker 0: she realizes that that couldn't work So she tries to do it herself.
Speaker 0: She's like oh, you can't raise these kids properly.
Speaker 0: You're all crazy You know.
Speaker 0: since you don't have a wife anymore I'm taking these kids away, and he's so turned to stone basically that he just lets it happen.
Speaker 0: He's like all right just go you know whatever.
Speaker 0: yep, and he stops being the awesome dad He used to be.
Speaker 0: but it's like.
Speaker 0: you know he was gonna become an awesome dad again But I didn't think grandma would be.
Speaker 0: you know it.
Speaker 0: I thought it would be one of those things where it's like sorry grandma.
Speaker 0: I'm an awesome dad again.
Speaker 1: BAM Like it was grandma's nice again - yeah, but in the very beginning like you you see the.
Speaker 1: you know the giant like he's physically there.
Speaker 1: that rock is just this giant fairy turned to stone from ancient times.
Speaker 1: yeah, and It would be very easy to expect that.
Speaker 1: in the end of the movie He wakes up and something you know that might cause things to happen.
Speaker 1: But instead he doesn't.
Speaker 1: you just see the birds being disturbed by his spirit leaving yep Deeply melancholy that is.
Speaker 1: I can't think of a better word to describe the end of this movie than melancholy.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 0: the only other thing I'd say is that for something called the song of the sea you know there's a lot of.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of metaphor of water going on right.
Speaker 0: the kid is afraid of going in the water He has to go in the well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know the sister who's a selkie.
Speaker 0: She's just like whatever.
Speaker 0: See I'm going in the water, but she's mute.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she can't speak or sing and The fairies are all held themselves in stasis because they need a selkie to sing them not to life But basically to death.
Speaker 0: yeah, and at the end You know he conquers his fear of the water to go down and get the selkie coat at the bottom of the ocean.
Speaker 1: He has a hundred percent like the archetypical hero's journey, right?
Speaker 0: But for even though there's all that water action going on It has surprisingly little sea.
Speaker 0: it's mostly a journey over land something that's called the song of the sea.
Speaker 0: There's a mean there is a song of the sea and but there really isn't a lot of sea.
Speaker 1: Well cuz they have to get back to the sea.
Speaker 1: yeah There's like a song to the sea.
Speaker 0: there's a sea at the beginning There's a sea near the end and there's a little bit of water in the middle But mostly land.
Speaker 0: and I was like I thought this was gonna have fishies And you know a little more a little mermaid action going on there wasn't.
Speaker 1: It was just and the story because of the allegory, and it's just.
Speaker 1: it's so well paced and so consistent beginning to end.
Speaker 1: I Really like this movie a lot.
Speaker 1: I'm hard-pressed to name better movies.
Speaker 1: I've seen in years I Mean I've seen movies that have come out in years.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen name a move.
Speaker 1: What was it?
Speaker 1: What is the best movie that came out?
Speaker 1: Before song of the sea?
Speaker 1: it doesn't have to be an.
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: a movie came out Princess Kaguya, I don't know.
Speaker 0: That's all.
Speaker 0: is that all I saw?
Speaker 0: yeah, there's nothing else worth seeing.
Speaker 0: it's all garbage superhero movies.
Speaker 1: I saw a lot of movies.
Speaker 1: There are good movies out there.
Speaker 1: Did you see snowpiercer?
Speaker 0: Actually, I just read it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would.
Speaker 1: I'm curious how close the movie is to the comic.
Speaker 0: well the movie.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine making a movie from those comics.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling it's different.
Speaker 1: Here's how I would describe snowpiercer the movie it is.
Speaker 1: It is like Robin Williams toys.
Speaker 0: The comic is not like that.
Speaker 1: okay That's interesting, but coupled with wool.
Speaker 1: It is wool the novel Written like toys with Robin Williams.
Speaker 0: There's a little bit of wool in there.
Speaker 1: It's wool and toys.
Speaker 0: It's some wool, but no toys and no toys.
Speaker 1: does anyone sing a song going over a bridge this bridge Action.
Speaker 1: is there a song that is sorry fine.
Speaker 1: Is there a sushi dinner?
Speaker 0: The there's.
Speaker 0: yeah, there's definitely eating.
Speaker 1: Do they eat sushi?
Speaker 0: I think so.
Speaker 0: in a normal Japanese sushi restaurant I think it's more like a train restaurant.
Speaker 1: Okay, okay anyway uh Yeah, I don't know what else I can really say because the movie speaks for itself And I have nothing but unabashed praise for it, which you guys have listened to us a long time.
Speaker 1: It is rare that we give unqualified praise to anything.
Speaker 0: I'm hungry.
Speaker 0: I'm also really go eat some seal.
Speaker 0: Let's not eat seal.
Speaker 0: It needs something.
Speaker 1: I don't want to eat any seal.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website At front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.