Speaker 0: It's Monday August 10th 2015.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: HTTP proxies and how they're often messing up your jam.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I've upgraded every computer I have except my old laptop to Windows 10.
Speaker 1: I have upgraded my laptop.
Speaker 1: I did that the Unlegit way because it never got a notification.
Speaker 1: it would have been that first because just waited.
Speaker 1: I did that first because there was nothing On that computer.
Speaker 1: I cared about it all so I could just erase it without worry.
Speaker 1: Then once the desktop got the notification and I learned all the deal that was going on I did that one.
Speaker 0: So you have what an x220 right?
Speaker 0: What's your laptop?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think my laptop's next to 20.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I have an x230 and a guy at work has an x240.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't even know they went that high.
Speaker 0: So the funny thing is the x240 is basically the same as my 230 just slightly shittier.
Speaker 1: So I mean I figure if once it goes above x220 just get shittier, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, the 230 is objectively superior to the 220.
Speaker 1: It has the shittier trackpad and keyboard.
Speaker 0: It's so much faster that the 220 is unusable - I can edit premiere video and like render it out in my laptop.
Speaker 1: I mean the one I have at work I think is the 230 and Keyboards are fine.
Speaker 1: I don't know why has the shitty trackpad not the shitty keyboard, but I don't use either one.
Speaker 0: So you're saying the trackpad is shitty and it is.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna say it's not but it's not shittier enough than the shitty x220s to be work.
Speaker 0: I mean Has ever had a good trackpad?
Speaker 0: like don't?
Speaker 0: okay?
Speaker 1: the x220 trackpad is Barely usable.
Speaker 1: the x2 the newer shittier one is unusable.
Speaker 0: So I was able to get it from unusable to almost usable by changing.
Speaker 1: some said, you know a good way to make it Really awesome by a Fujitsu laptop.
Speaker 1: No Buy a Mac Pro which has the real trackpad on it.
Speaker 0: the Fujitsu is like to this day because I have an old life book My first laptop.
Speaker 0: I spent like three grand on that thing a long time.
Speaker 1: Oh, those are like extra small and the days when the word Ultrabook didn't exist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like that laptop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those trackpads were good.
Speaker 1: They were better than the x220.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that thing actually had an amazing and so that life Wasn't.
Speaker 1: it was not amazing.
Speaker 1: It is not nearly an.
Speaker 0: actually I used it again recently because Emily brings it with her to like Kinetic on just for like presentations and stuff because that laptops actually fine.
Speaker 0: This is the old core to do.
Speaker 0: Oh that trackpad if you average all trackpads in the world today is One of the best.
Speaker 0: I would call it amazing.
Speaker 1: Are you counting?
Speaker 1: like, you know, you're just counting each kind of trackpad once, right?
Speaker 1: You're not counting every single Mac trackpad and averaging them all together because they've made a lot of them.
Speaker 1: They have the oldest ones weren't great Ever since they made the one giant trackpad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty much been incredible.
Speaker 1: I don't know how much you've used one.
Speaker 0: I've used them and that's why I said that is still.
Speaker 0: However, if you don't want to spend that much money on a laptop and you want something that's quite like as powerful for half the money Then the Fujitsu.
Speaker 1: I mean if your trackpad is your just your purchasing decision, right?
Speaker 1: That's kind of weird.
Speaker 0: Well at this point my purchasing decision is Computers aren't getting faster and my laptops fine, so I'm not gonna buy a laptop.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm doing.
Speaker 1: That's my also plan.
Speaker 0: Like I don't know what laptops will be like when I buy another laptop
Speaker 1: I just get an iPad and then you really won't use your laptop unless you really need a keyboard or to do a Presentation with something and even then you can get the VGA or HDMI output from an iPad.
Speaker 0: So yeah thing is what I use my laptop or the keyboard for the iPad.
Speaker 0: what I use my laptop for the most is Which an iPad does not do.
Speaker 0: number one actually is typing a bunch of shit.
Speaker 1: All right, you can get a keyboard.
Speaker 1: I can.
Speaker 0: number two is to five but I've had doesn't do that.
Speaker 1: Well, there you get some garbage sieve game instead.
Speaker 0: I'm hoping that well, we'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: the only game that you receive some Wesnoth and free sieve That'll be only real real game.
Speaker 1: that counts as a real game, right?
Speaker 1: And the no true Scotsman kind of way that you can get on iOS or iPad as hearthstone and that is a very random game.
Speaker 0: So yeah, that's not.
Speaker 0: that's not gonna scratch my I guess.
Speaker 1: now you can get a lot of board games.
Speaker 1: You can get TNE on there.
Speaker 0: None of those things are gonna scratch my sieve.
Speaker 1: five itch when I'm like business I mean, there's like some Master of Orion clones.
Speaker 1: But you know in terms of things you can actually get opponents for or whatever.
Speaker 1: There is no sieve five on iPad.
Speaker 0: yep, so but yeah, I've upgraded to Windows 10 everywhere and Everything has worked a hundred percent fine.
Speaker 0: But I noticed a lot of people we know have had a lot of problems with Windows 10 upgrades And the problems that reported to me are one VirtualBox the thing I talked about last week.
Speaker 0: Just use the latest unstable build and VirtualBox works fine.
Speaker 0: Adobe Creative Cloud won't work unless you have updated Creative Cloud sometime in the past like three or four months.
Speaker 1: So if you're not like didn't update their Creative Cloud They just installed it and it keeps saying hey update me update me.
Speaker 1: They keep saying no, dude.
Speaker 0: so I was googling to make sure like Audition and like my firewire chipset and the Mackie and all that nonsense would work in Windows 10 because you know, there's even odds and that stuff not working that well, I was worried and One of the first things I found with this dude who is like I've got audition 3 Will that work in Windows 10?
Speaker 0: and someone else is like there was a 3.
Speaker 1: Is that pre Adobe?
Speaker 1: because most of the things that that is what that is right after?
Speaker 0: Adobe bought the company that made cool edit and Renamed cool edit Audition.
Speaker 1: No, okay, but like most of the things out there like products from these big companies Microsoft Adobe, etc.
Speaker 1: We're actually products by other companies beforehand, right?
Speaker 1: Everyone says Adobe flash now.
Speaker 1: No remembers macromedia.
Speaker 0: I had macromedia action 3.0.
Speaker 1: Adobe bought macromedia and turned all their products into Adobe products and people don't remember macromedia unless they're old.
Speaker 0: in fact I had a class at RIT Microsoft Visio.
Speaker 1: that wasn't made by Microsoft is made by some other company.
Speaker 1: they bought and then renamed it.
Speaker 0: I remember pirating copies of director 7 and flash to do projects at RIT, right?
Speaker 1: It's like all this stuff was made by someone else and then these companies bought it incorporated it redid the UI.
Speaker 1: That's why even today you can see the ancestry of a lot of these long existing things You know like Adobe the only thing Adobe made as far as I know is fucking Photoshop and acrobat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think they made any of the stuff at all.
Speaker 1: I think they bought all of it.
Speaker 0: I think they might have even bought Premiere But a lot of weird stuff might not work.
Speaker 0: But like I saw a bunch of people were like I can't get fraps to work and I was like hot Why are you using fraps in 2015?
Speaker 0: Well, the thing with fraps straight is OBS does exactly what fraps does way better with less impact.
Speaker 1: Well fraps has a bad UI and so does OBS.
Speaker 1: They're even on that count.
Speaker 1: Yeah, fraps like I paid like what ten bucks or whatever it was Back in the day.
Speaker 1: that license is a forever license.
Speaker 1: I feel like you paid for it.
Speaker 1: I'll just keep using this.
Speaker 0: But what do you use it for?
Speaker 0: because OBS does the same thing.
Speaker 1: better, but OBS is also bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but better I just use neither one.
Speaker 1: That's my solution.
Speaker 0: Yeah You know, I use OBS for even when I'm at work and like I'm doing like I saw You know, I have a build of like our software or whatever and I click on it and notice something weird.
Speaker 0: I'll just video it and I'll just record the window and I'll just attach the ticket and be like, yeah That's a dumb interface.
Speaker 0: fix it.
Speaker 0: So, uh, oh so I haven't updated my laptop yet.
Speaker 1: It's the last one and I'm an updated my HTTP see it.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it cheap HTTP see actually is ready to update and I might do that tonight.
Speaker 0: I didn't get the notification on it yet But the laptop is Windows 7 is a loan over x230.
Speaker 0: my co-worker with the loan over x240 said he went to.
Speaker 0: he upgraded it And half the hardware drivers just didn't like install.
Speaker 0: and now his laptops.
Speaker 1: That's really interesting cuz I'm my x220.
Speaker 1: I did the full reset and when it fully reset and came back on I noticed like there's a whole bunch of Lenovo stuff like In there like oh, there's the Lenovo touchpad driver like already set up with everything But I there's the special Intel graphics thing.
Speaker 0: I think he also forced the update early So I did that as well on the laptop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so and you both had a little bit of weird problems that then eventually resolve themselves.
Speaker 1: The only weird problem I had is because I reset early, right?
Speaker 1: I think that the is the media creator tool which you used which you can use.
Speaker 1: you don't really need to.
Speaker 1: I never haven't actually Needed it yet, but I just did it because it's nice to be safe.
Speaker 0: I'm going to use it.
Speaker 1: lets you make a USB stick to boot off of right which you don't really need but it's nice to have.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna use that to reinstall cuz I got right here a new SSD.
Speaker 1: Well, you don't actually see you can reinstall without the USB stick.
Speaker 1: What you can do is on the light.
Speaker 1: I didn't know you could do that on the login screen or on just regular here For example.
Speaker 1: do it right now click on your own.
Speaker 1: don't do it right now.
Speaker 1: to record this show click on it when you go to either click on start and then you know power or on the Login screen click on power and hold shift and click reset.
Speaker 1: Don't just click reset.
Speaker 1: hold the shift key and press.
Speaker 1: click on the reset button in the menu there.
Speaker 1: It'll bring you to this special menu where you can basically click a button and say reset my computer delete all programs or Delete all programs and documents and settings and it's like two choices and it'll just do a full reset of Windows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I want a full reset.
Speaker 0: I want to install completely new on a different physical drive that currently is not in the computer.
Speaker 1: Uh, I think you can do that if you interrupt the thing at the right time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see I haven't.
Speaker 0: I haven't done that but I have that on a USB 3 PCI Express card here and with those combined, I think my core i7 920 is gonna make it another gear or two.
Speaker 1: All right, maybe that sounds good.
Speaker 0: Yeah I saw there was a slashdot thread and there people were talking about upgraded Windows 10 and There was one heading in that thread.
Speaker 0: that was someone being like I have a core i7 920 which is the processor I have.
Speaker 0: should I buy a new processor?
Speaker 0: Like is it worth it?
Speaker 1: I have never in my entire life taken a CPU out of a motherboard and put a better one.
Speaker 0: Well, you can't?
Speaker 0: you basically have to buy a new mother buy a new computer.
Speaker 0: Why I mean, I'm sure what I bought the socket that a 920 goes into does not exist anymore.
Speaker 1: No, I'm sure right, but I'm saying for example my computer.
Speaker 1: when I bought it I got like an i7 three and a half gigahertz.
Speaker 1: I think I could have I think what there was available a more expensive i7 that was slightly Insignificantly faster for hundreds more dollars that I could have bought for that same socket.
Speaker 1: I'm sure Chips of that make exist in the world today and I could acquire one.
Speaker 0: well the problem is every.
Speaker 1: I could Take the CPU out of my socket and put in a slightly faster one made for the same side.
Speaker 0: the cycle of computer upgrading is Long enough that by the time you think I could use a faster processor You're gonna buy a new motherboard.
Speaker 1: Anyway, pretty much.
Speaker 0: But oh, so all the responses were all these people coming out of the woodwork with low slash who were all like yeah, the core i7 920 was like the best fucking processor ever and There's really no reason to upgrade unless you're pegging your CPU all the time.
Speaker 1: You know, I pegged my CPU and code in the video.
Speaker 1: Yep, and even even then the GPUs helping out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the GPU cuz I'm in creative and this guy or the bottleneck.
Speaker 0: I got SSDs, so I'm good I do but I'm not all SSD.
Speaker 0: I had two SSD daddy - so the the utenna masters like the video for just like doing our show There that's like 80 gigabytes of shit.
Speaker 0: Just sitting there.
Speaker 0: Anyway whole bunch of tech news.
Speaker 0: I want to blow through real quick But I guess we could talk about Scott's tech news verse.
Speaker 1: It's sort of a big Mostly not tech news, but slightly tech.
Speaker 0: Oh just before the show you were like, it's tech news.
Speaker 0: You're trying to convince me.
Speaker 0: This is tech news.
Speaker 1: part of it is that's the part I want to mister.
Speaker 0: Business is not tech news.
Speaker 1: It's not so Google is like restructuring their business, which is business news in a big way, right?
Speaker 1: So they're basically changing instead of the company being Google.
Speaker 1: The company is now called alphabet and Google is one of the companies that is a subsidiary Along with others such as you know, Google, I guess what else do they make?
Speaker 0: Well, there's Google.
Speaker 0: Google fiber nest is definitely gonna be super nest, right?
Speaker 0: So basically, they're gonna have a holding company that owns a bunch of its semi-independent companies, right?
Speaker 1: So of course the Google part which is the search engine and the ads and stuff has got a new CEO because the former Google CEOs are now alphabet CEOs instead etc.
Speaker 1: So no one.
Speaker 1: that's all business news.
Speaker 1: No one cares.
Speaker 1: What's interesting is they chose the name alphabet, which is a really common fucking word and it fits their theme here.
Speaker 1: of you know, Google B and G and s B and N. but All the stuff that's named alphabet is already owned.
Speaker 1: all the accounts all the domains all the everything is already owned by someone Right, and it doesn't belong to Google.
Speaker 0: So the question will be one Alphabet as a company.
Speaker 0: What do they?
Speaker 0: what will they own the trademarks to specifically?
Speaker 0: and will they even have a website, right?
Speaker 1: But there's like are they gonna have to fight someone for the DNS on this?
Speaker 1: like it?
Speaker 0: but that's business news not tech news.
Speaker 1: No, it's not it's tech.
Speaker 0: How is that tech news?
Speaker 1: DNS is a technology.
Speaker 0: DNS is a technology.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 1: by that logic DNS battles are tech news.
Speaker 1: by that logic I can make literally anything a tech news, but the rest of it is not tech news is business.
Speaker 0: I mean tool use is technology that humans have learned.
Speaker 0: 40.
Speaker 1: stop being a pedant.
Speaker 0: or What's that quote from Silicon Valley?
Speaker 0: Dude?
Speaker 0: You're being a tool.
Speaker 0: I need you to be an asshole not a tool.
Speaker 0: Anyway the so my because this is kind of like new news.
Speaker 0: The best guess I have as to why this is happening is a big fuck you to Europe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, fuck you Europe.
Speaker 0: and I found a pretty good article that I have Castles and take everything else and shove it.
Speaker 0: So I skimmed this article.
Speaker 1: trees better be in those castles.
Speaker 1: No taking them out beforehand.
Speaker 0: I skimmed this article from a few days ago and It's on Bloomberg Business and you shall probably read it, but I didn't read it fully.
Speaker 0: It's way long But basically longer the more true it.
Speaker 0: Europe is at a hard-on for going after to destroy any American tech company that Basically competes with their completely non-existent local tech industry, especially the Google, right?
Speaker 1: So they're basically generally upset that like this company that sort of is super important everywhere in the world and really really affects Especially not only, you know their whole universe but specifically the European economy is an American company and they have almost no control over it and all their Extra super European regulations don't apply to like
Speaker 0: their bullshit right to be forgotten weird all these weird like Advertising things and the fact that they don't have freedom of speech and all this nonsense.
Speaker 0: So Google has been mostly giving them the finger and from what I gather Google gave China the superfinger way back.
Speaker 0: Google seemed to have had like come to some sort of a chord with them But apparently that deal broke down and that might be why this might have been their contingency plan Because this structure might make it a lot easier for Google to tell Europe to rightly go fuck itself.
Speaker 0: I Really do not want Europe to break Google up Nor do I want Europe to have really any control over the internet.
Speaker 1: Google should just say fuck you Europe You know what.
Speaker 1: if you don't like us fine, no Google for you.
Speaker 1: and then Europe will have to do whatever Google says and everything will be set right.
Speaker 1: and Google shouldn't have to.
Speaker 1: why even bother trying To like work through legal loopholes or other nonsense, right?
Speaker 1: It just make Europe change their law to be what you want it to be.
Speaker 1: So what do you do?
Speaker 0: Why are all the people you like have working for you?
Speaker 1: You know, you just give them a whisper whisper whisper, right?
Speaker 1: And you just stop you to.
Speaker 1: basically you keep paying those people.
Speaker 1: even right who cares?
Speaker 1: just cut off all Europe.
Speaker 1: No one can search and be like make the law exactly what we want or else.
Speaker 0: We're not turning search back Scott as much as I think that would be kind of funny, you know and awesome.
Speaker 0: You might be guilty of basically racketeering.
Speaker 1: So deal with it.
Speaker 1: What are you gonna do about it?
Speaker 0: Arrest your employees.
Speaker 1: Just you're gonna start arresting Google employees.
Speaker 1: They're good.
Speaker 1: They had nothing to do with it.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, but they can't get you.
Speaker 0: they'll Al Capone you you can't no one.
Speaker 1: Larry Page, what are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: You can never visit Europe.
Speaker 0: They'll arrest you.
Speaker 0: You'll never be able to see castles.
Speaker 1: They don't have any Google.
Speaker 1: fine Who's got the worst end of this stick, but they won't know how to find the castle without Google math.
Speaker 0: This is news.
Speaker 1: They want to find me without Google maps.
Speaker 0: That is still very emergent.
Speaker 0: So we will talk about this at length later.
Speaker 0: And normally we would just not talk about it.
Speaker 1: I'll go to Europe and they'll be like, they'll say cops go to the airport and arrest Larry Page.
Speaker 1: I can't get to the airport.
Speaker 1: I'm Google Maps.
Speaker 0: Yeah They're like wait, so where does Larry Page even live?
Speaker 0: they go to Google.
Speaker 1: ah Pages European castle address fuck.
Speaker 0: I imagine get Larry pages tweets.
Speaker 0: He's like, hey, I'm in and he named some city in like France.
Speaker 0: He's like, can you even find that city on Bing?
Speaker 1: The one cop who lives in the city comes knocking on the door and Larry's like wait don't arrest me I'll let you do two searches.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I need to search for something so good.
Speaker 0: but normally we don't talk about like brand like news that breaks like Pretty close to our dateline on geek nights, but this is actually pretty big.
Speaker 0: So we'll talk about it at length once the dust settles a little bit, but my money is on.
Speaker 0: This is a big fuck you to you.
Speaker 1: I don't think Google can win.
Speaker 1: anything can lose.
Speaker 1: Yeah in any fight with anybody.
Speaker 0: Well, they'll have the robots and the self-driving car.
Speaker 0: self-driving cars should start delivering poop Drones Dropping poop.
Speaker 0: So a bunch of little news is.
Speaker 0: there's two news is that I noticed that we're cut.
Speaker 0: They weren't related to each other But I think they're actually very closely related because I noticed in like stock stuff and just work that Pretty much all like Disney had a big drop and a lot of companies that I would generally like Disney have a big drop.
Speaker 1: They're basically owning pop culture.
Speaker 0: What I gathered is that the market going down the market the sector that got hit was anything that has a big interest in cable networks Television networks, of course, people are cutting the cord like crazy.
Speaker 0: So there are two newses.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Disney's got a lot of TV action.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they'll extricate themselves Because Disney will move to the internet Hasbro's moving to the.
Speaker 1: this is only good news because the faster this happens the faster they'll stream.
Speaker 0: so Basically us.
Speaker 0: there's an article here talking about how the cord cutting like we all knew was gonna happen.
Speaker 0: It was was happening.
Speaker 0: It was moving fast.
Speaker 1: A lot of people pay for cable cut the cord a long-ass time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a friend of ours.
Speaker 0: It was like a go message me.
Speaker 0: He's like, I thought you had cable and I was like, what the fuck?
Speaker 0: I haven't had cable in like two decades.
Speaker 1: I haven't had cable since 2000s been 15 years and I didn't watch cables.
Speaker 1: only my roommate my roommate watched soccer Cable and ball and I watched I think like maybe one show once I think I watched The Simpsons once so cord cutting accelerated relatively recently Faster than even people like us expected.
Speaker 0: there was like a huge jump.
Speaker 0: Well, what I think what it might be is that another wave of people Graduating and moving into college like remember we got the same number every year.
Speaker 1: It's a What do you mean wave?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so yeah, but so that the wave that just came in because remember we went to RIT like the cable come.
Speaker 1: So compared to last year, yeah those college graduates the ones this year a smaller percentage of them need television.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I think a smaller like the people coming into college are even like cable.
Speaker 0: Why would I even want Kate like?
Speaker 0: I think it's suddenly hit real hard.
Speaker 0: and the second Worst which I didn't even think about because it's just so sad pay-per-view still exists.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Basically it dropped down to negligible numbers.
Speaker 1: Well, because if there is a pay-per-view right it cost so much money.
Speaker 1: There's such a high incentive to just pirate that shit.
Speaker 1: So hardly anyone pay.
Speaker 1: even people who have cable are going on the internet to try to watch that shit.
Speaker 1: They don't want to pay 150 bucks to see some garbage boxing man.
Speaker 0: In fact, I think that box and it specifically Caused a lot of older people who never thought about piracy to ask the grandkids how to get to that pirate bay.
Speaker 1: And also, you know, even when there is something worth seeing like say a Ronda Rousey fight You can just see it the next day on YouTube.
Speaker 1: It's like a minute long.
Speaker 0: So at the same time there's another article.
Speaker 0: adblock usage just recently Skyrocketed lazy over the past 12 months.
Speaker 0: It went up 41 percent globally.
Speaker 1: pretty good.
Speaker 0: So like people are starting to use adblock rapidly.
Speaker 0: I think Advertising as a revenue stream between TV internet is gonna just like fucking good explode any day.
Speaker 0: good Alright bunch of other stuff.
Speaker 0: real quick.
Speaker 0: Scotland just banned genetically modified crops.
Speaker 1: Fuck you Scott.
Speaker 0: or literally no reason.
Speaker 0: and even the farmers are like, uh, you literally just destroyed our entire market.
Speaker 1: No, but no fancy.
Speaker 1: No, we had to get natural Disgusting potatoes that die immediately.
Speaker 1: We're not like what counts so counts.
Speaker 0: So, you know, it's even funnier.
Speaker 0: only Scotland did it not England.
Speaker 1: So basically all this Scottish money is gonna be going into England.
Speaker 1: People in Scotland eating disgusting vegetables.
Speaker 0: Genetically modified crops are because what did they?
Speaker 1: well, what did they write in their law?
Speaker 0: I didn't read the law because it's some horribly European law.
Speaker 1: It's probably just says like oh don't eat the current.
Speaker 0: I'm not even going to dignify that Scottish accent with a response.
Speaker 1: Hey lady play the bagpipes next to the corn as well this time.
Speaker 0: The reason so I'm gonna skip all these other tiny news is because we already got on for a while.
Speaker 0: The last one I want to talk about is this is super tech news.
Speaker 0: So, okay.
Speaker 0: I got to two actual tech news not business news.
Speaker 0: Like what Scott wants to talk about?
Speaker 0: There is a problem with Linux servers that is getting worse.
Speaker 0: We need for modern security and cryptography a lot of entropy like randomness.
Speaker 0: like if you know the difference between Dev random and dev you random you should.
Speaker 0: Dev random will block if it runs out of entropy.
Speaker 0: dev you random will give you some bullshit seated.
Speaker 0: Yep, so You refill dev random by basically reading entropy and there's a lot that we're not.
Speaker 0: that's a big topic We can't really talk about now.
Speaker 1: Talk to someone who knows about math.
Speaker 0: servers generate entropy But modern Linux servers for a variety of reasons don't generate enough entropy.
Speaker 1: So if you ask for too many random numbers too fast eventually the numbers you get either you won't get any more numbers or you won't get the numbers that are actually random enough anymore.
Speaker 1: and Then you'll be in big trouble security wise because like you start generating predictable keys or predictable encryption or who knows what.
Speaker 0: so we're not.
Speaker 1: We're generating less entropy and simultaneous or you just won't be able to send any more data.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we need the entropy way more for modern computing and security.
Speaker 1: So like a faster CPU helps but doesn't help enough.
Speaker 1: you really need like an Entropy source like a block of cesium or who knows why.
Speaker 0: well, you can buy cards that are entropy generator, right?
Speaker 1: You know what's in there fucking some radioactive thing this.
Speaker 0: well No, actually there's a lot.
Speaker 0: a lot of me use temperature dips like temperature deltas and stuff.
Speaker 1: Oh, I mean random that org uses like like atmospheric pressure.
Speaker 1: They have like a thing on their roof.
Speaker 1: That's like, you know, like barometers or something.
Speaker 1: It's pretty interesting quantus TRNG.
Speaker 0: I just googled the first one.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah here that Europe I googled it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's see.
Speaker 0: So I found a company check this out.
Speaker 0: It's a PCI Express card.
Speaker 0: what's on this random number generator?
Speaker 0: by exploiting a quantum optics process?
Speaker 1: There are many interesting sources of entropy in the universe, you know.
Speaker 1: Which is really kind of easy to find sources of entropy considering, you know, things are becoming more entropic all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah But you know the cooler your source of entropy is the more your sales will be.
Speaker 0: that that's true.
Speaker 1: I mean, would you rather buy the quantum optics random number generator or the atmospheric pressure random number generator?
Speaker 1: So I was cooler.
Speaker 0: if you're like a system administrator in a place that matters.
Speaker 0: It's worth it to you to make sure you know if like your company writes software that runs on those servers if They're abusing random when they could get away with you random because you don't want to you don't want to run you want to pump.
Speaker 1: I pretty much always use you random unless there's a problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah So I noticed one of my software things that uses random like.
Speaker 0: I noticed a thing that opened it and was drawing from it and I went to the developer and was like Why are we using that instead of you random?
Speaker 0: and he was like, huh?
Speaker 0: So I said change it to you random.
Speaker 0: And last but not least North Korea.
Speaker 1: But there's no technology there.
Speaker 1: They have a really bad internet and missiles that kind of suck and is switching to a new time zone that they just made up.
Speaker 1: Why do we even what?
Speaker 1: does it matter?
Speaker 1: Why does it even matter to us?
Speaker 1: What time it is in North Korea?
Speaker 0: So now at all Java has to have an update because Java has embedded time zone information.
Speaker 1: No, you don't need to update that because no one in North Korea uses Java.
Speaker 1: But well, no one in any outside of North Korea has any program that cares what time it is in North Korea.
Speaker 0: You might what if you were doing some sort of spy bullshit?
Speaker 0: and your spy bullshit thing keeps track of times and GMT.
Speaker 0: like it.
Speaker 1: The NSA can write a patch for themselves.
Speaker 1: They don't need us to work on this garbage.
Speaker 0: You're gonna write a pic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Java period like Java has embedded zone stuff.
Speaker 1: So everyone with a bunch who's got to do like I've got update to get new user times Whatever which this is your share zone info.
Speaker 0: So this actually fucked me not that long ago.
Speaker 1: Well, you've got your your trading stocks in North Korea.
Speaker 0: another group of Venezuela a similarly non-connected play.
Speaker 1: change your time zone.
Speaker 0: they changed their time zone shit, so daylight saving time happened at a different time and Basically a lot of people didn't like get the like update 70 whatever of jar JRE 7 and a bunch of shit stopped working.
Speaker 1: when they're just OS's time zone info.
Speaker 0: take care of that Except people never update that stuff.
Speaker 0: No, almost no one who runs Linux servers ever actually does like yum update all or whatever equivalent.
Speaker 1: I make sure my time zone is important.
Speaker 0: North Korea announced that it's winding his clocks back by a half hour.
Speaker 1: for what reason?
Speaker 1: they just want to be different and Be jerky.
Speaker 0: Yes, so they're now you GZ plus 830.
Speaker 0: Okay different from South Korea and Korea eight or nine.
Speaker 0: I don't know actually.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz my servers take care of that.
Speaker 0: Okay, and They're doing it to mark the 70th anniversary of the Korean Peninsula's liberation from Japan's Colonial rule.
Speaker 1: that's the way to have a celebration.
Speaker 1: change a time zone because you can't afford any other kind of celebration with actual like Confetti or beasts or anything.
Speaker 0: So two things.
Speaker 0: one change.
Speaker 0: I suspect that the political maneuver is they're trying to bully South Korea into.
Speaker 0: moving to South Korea can be like yes, we are committed to unification But at the same time South Korea is technologically savvy and is not stupid enough to so Pointlessly disrupt the job of people like me.
Speaker 1: everyone sleep an extra half-hour for no reason, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's the thing.
Speaker 0: if South Korea changed everyone in South Korea who's like me would be like and have to do some bullshit and no one else would care and - it doesn't affect anyone in North Korea.
Speaker 0: I don't think watches things of the day.
Speaker 0: So I did watch the last episode of The Daily Show.
Speaker 1: No, I'm sure I should watch that at some point.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Do you know what the premise is of the last episode?
Speaker 1: He has a premise.
Speaker 1: I thought it was just any old episode with some special.
Speaker 0: It actually isn't pretty much.
Speaker 0: they get every Everyone who's ever been a correspondent on the show even like Craig killed like everyone.
Speaker 0: Some of them just send a video.
Speaker 1: but like there's a montage of like does he still tell you what happened the news for that day?
Speaker 0: So the best part is there's a point where he starts crying and he cries so bad They cut the commercial and they cut it out.
Speaker 0: So he like.
Speaker 0: he lost it and had to like recollect himself.
Speaker 0: He's really and he got so choked up He actually couldn't say his final goodbye at the end.
Speaker 0: He was like And he leaves.
Speaker 1: he's a short little dream, man.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty good.
Speaker 1: I didn't want to go.
Speaker 1: you didn't have to go you could just kept doing it.
Speaker 0: I sadly think this might be effectively the end of The Daily Show is relevant independent of Trevor?
Speaker 0: No, it was a good job.
Speaker 1: people said that when Craig Kilborn left the show.
Speaker 1: I know I am reluctant to say the same now, but here's the thing.
Speaker 0: I Think the only thing.
Speaker 1: I am a person who learns from the past and also accuses people of not learning from the past.
Speaker 1: So I cannot refuse to learn from the past.
Speaker 0: I think the show's format is obsolete in the modern era and the slightly longer format of John Oliver's show is better for the purposes of this kind of thing.
Speaker 0: and I wonder if The Daily Show as a format will survive.
Speaker 0: I think either the format needs to change.
Speaker 1: Well what the format changed when it switched to Jon Stewart.
Speaker 1: it can change again.
Speaker 0: It actually didn't that much.
Speaker 0: they got rid of five questions because Craig Kilborn I guess owned that or something.
Speaker 1: Well, it was stupid anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was always really stupid.
Speaker 0: Actually.
Speaker 1: That's to say it's like letterman You can have your top ten list.
Speaker 1: No one gives a shit.
Speaker 0: I'll do top 11.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but The other thing is Comedy Central not doing so.
Speaker 0: well Television yeah, I think the infrastructure of The Daily Show might not survive and a show like it Produced out like Penn Jillette style on someone's own is gonna replace it at some point or something.
Speaker 0: I just I don't think the show format as it stands is gonna survive no matter how good.
Speaker 1: No, it's like a day or two after the last show.
Speaker 1: I guess last Friday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Coincidentally, right?
Speaker 1: I got out of work at three, but netrunner doesn't start until six.
Speaker 1: So what I'm doing is just like walking over to the river and laying in the grass for three hours.
Speaker 0: It's a good thing to do and then going to eat dinner and that's a real good thing to do.
Speaker 1: So but I happen to pass by Ye Daily Show studio Yeah, and there was some people with ladders like up in the awning And I was like, all right.
Speaker 0: I'm glad I saw The Daily Show a few times in person So I'm glad I got to do that.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I've seen enough Daily Show.
Speaker 0: It's really weird when you see it in person though Because the lighting is all like low and red and they do a weird process to make him look human.
Speaker 0: So, yeah My thing of the day is a time-lapse of the entire run of The Daily Show of Jon Stewart's face And it's actually pretty good.
Speaker 0: It's weird seeing how young he looked when he took over The Daily Show.
Speaker 1: go watch Jon Stewart.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: ah.
Speaker 0: so I just clicked on it like from the very beginning of The Daily Show with Jon Stewart and One of the first things I saw was Darth Maul.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's been a long time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those things happen.
Speaker 1: I mean go look at Jon Stewart on MTV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel like he was our generation's Johnny Carson.
Speaker 1: Maybe name someone else Mmm, if anyone else America doesn't have people like that, but there are other countries that have people like that.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, we had Johnny Carson.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean in this generation, right?
Speaker 1: There are other countries who have people who are like for that country on the Johnny Carson level or like literally everyone.
Speaker 0: Well, I just noticed something so that to keep Jon Stewart's face in the same spot There's a long arrow where the folk like the black ball the letterboxing on the left and bottom is Slowly growing as you see them like slowly moving where they point the camera.
Speaker 0: It's interesting.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I mean you can't play the camera the exact same spot every day Yeah, but there was a progression where it moved for a while and then starting about two-thirds of the way through it never moves again.
Speaker 1: Maybe they you know worked on their camera.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this is really cool to watch.
Speaker 1: Oh It's SD back then so we know the paintball in the airsoft.
Speaker 1: Those are respectable awesome activities of awesomeness that we simply don't have time money space effort.
Speaker 1: Airsoft is illegal in New York City City sure, but you know There's a lot of those awesome things in the nerd world that we would like to do and you simply as a nerd cannot do Everything right.
Speaker 1: you have to choose your battles, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah If you're gonna watch Evangelion for the third time and if you're gonna play some counter-strike and you're gonna record a podcast and you're gonna make a gun to You pretty much and gonna ride your bicycle around and you're gonna take photos of stuff You cannot also do airsoft and paintball.
Speaker 1: This is only so much in your life.
Speaker 1: So unless you're independently wealthy sure and you don't have to work.
Speaker 1: But anyway, even then you have to choose right?
Speaker 1: You just choose more things.
Speaker 1: There is a third thing besides paintball on airsoft that may be better than either of the other two and that thing is this I this YouTube video is pretty popular this week.
Speaker 1: It is basically airsoft slash paintball except archery.
Speaker 1: That's all you need to know.
Speaker 1: It also appears to have rules At least.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the actual rules are But watching the video you can make a really educated and intelligent guest unless you're a moron.
Speaker 1: It seems to be a lot more interesting and skill-based in addition to being archery instead of paint or airsoft.
Speaker 1: and the best part Is you don't have to like keep buying Ammo and shit.
Speaker 1: you buy a bow and it seems I can just use a normal fucking bow like just a recurve bow and you get this, you know arrows that won't kill people because they're all doofy on the end and You're all set.
Speaker 1: You don't need to like keep buying paintballs or pellets or whatever it is.
Speaker 1: So it's kind of if I was gonna do one of these if I became independently wealthy I would choose this one.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Have you ever have you done archery anytime in recent memory?
Speaker 1: I have done archery at every time I was ever at summer camp.
Speaker 1: I did extensive archeries.
Speaker 1: So in the moment also at RIT, I did our trees as well.
Speaker 0: I got.
Speaker 0: I got a reset.
Speaker 0: I was doing my micro machines thing.
Speaker 0: in the middle of the book of book is Fantasy book the novel the eye of the wildo.
Speaker 1: Yep I haven't found the eye yet or the world part, but I found all the other parts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I still want the one kid to die cuz I'm just bored with him.
Speaker 0: He's annoying and the wolf kids pretty chill and I wish he'd just be like, okay I guess I'm a little person just live with it.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's a Pax is really fucking soon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like in a few weeks if you are not at the packs the packs the packs prime of Seattle Who are you?
Speaker 0: So why the far future of gaming Monday sports our game packs is four days bitches.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Friday say Sunday Monday like packs, you know, it's not it's not even Labor Day this year.
Speaker 1: I forgot to take the Monday off.
Speaker 1: So I just did to add it today.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, I'm taking off because I'm flying up there Tuesday to go to packs dev Wednesday Thursday Then packs prime Friday Saturday Sunday Monday, then I'm going to Portland to lecture at kai-fu on Wednesday.
Speaker 0: I'm flying home to New York the next Thursday.
Speaker 1: I think I'm going in Wednesday and No, it's Friday Saturday Sunday Monday, right?
Speaker 1: I think I'm coming in Thursday and Going home on the Tuesday.
Speaker 0: Yeah good times.
Speaker 0: I'm feeling this packs like I like other packs is a lot gonna be a big packs.
Speaker 0: the packs prime is just the Pack.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go stand at that video ball booth and play video ball for a while.
Speaker 1: The balls pregnant me out soon.
Speaker 1: It might even they might even put it out at packs.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't put it past him.
Speaker 0: We got it.
Speaker 1: We got a former team thing is video balls got a lot of competition coming from rocket League.
Speaker 1: I know very similar kind of things only ones 3d.
Speaker 0: I feel like they'll end up being orthogonal for reasons We'll talk about on a Tuesday episode baby, but we'll video ball.
Speaker 1: get the audience.
Speaker 0: It'll get there.
Speaker 0: It'll get the good audience.
Speaker 0: It'll be like the people who watch f1 versus the people who watch NASCAR.
Speaker 1: Anyway That was weird.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what happened?
Speaker 1: I don't know my phone was having to be against this piece of metal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I heard that noise.
Speaker 0: I was about to stop the show and be like what's going on back.
Speaker 1: This is my phone, but it was just next to something that made worse noise than usual.
Speaker 0: All right HTTP proxies.
Speaker 1: So I had.
Speaker 1: I was just thinking about technologies and this one has come up a lot lately because you know I was installing lots of softwares and configuring lots of softwares with Windows 10 and various things and I kept seeing in pretty much every Software.
Speaker 1: there's always this configuration panel to set up HTTP proxy and it's something I never ever ever ever ever do.
Speaker 1: But it came to mind.
Speaker 1: I was thinking about show ideas and a G. proxies were on the mind and I'm like, you know what?
Speaker 1: Those do.
Speaker 1: well, not only could talk about HTTP proxies.
Speaker 1: You know about proxies in general all socks.
Speaker 0: You know socks.
Speaker 0: I know a lot of socks.
Speaker 1: I don't talk about that.
Speaker 0: We just even listen to the Wikipedia quote.
Speaker 0: socks also forwards arbitrary data after connection phase and is similar to an HTTP connected.
Speaker 1: But there's so much things involved in this one technology.
Speaker 1: I was like, hey, you know, we could do a whole show about this.
Speaker 1: So first of all, what is a proxy?
Speaker 1: So you have a server.
Speaker 1: the server is serving something.
Speaker 1: you then have a proxy server Just like you would have a proxy card.
Speaker 1: if you're playing Magic the Gathering where you just take a piece of cardboard and write down You know force of nature on it pretends to be the server in some sense.
Speaker 0: Yes, but sits in front of it exactly.
Speaker 1: So it's not totally replacing it, you know standing in It's sort of you want to talk to.
Speaker 1: I want to talk to this server that rims got his counter-strike server He's I. instead of talking directly to his counter-strike server I talked to this other server and that server then talks to the counter-strike server and then it forwards the communications between us.
Speaker 1: It's basically an intentional man-in-the-middle attack.
Speaker 1: when you think about it There is this other server between you and the server you actually want to talk to now.
Speaker 1: Obviously this can be used for a man-in-the-middle attack Which is really bad because then suddenly you type in google.com and you see porn.
Speaker 0: now It is often used as a man-in-the-middle attack in a. well Let's talk about HTTP proxies.
Speaker 1: right because that's an HTTP proxy specifically is a proxy Just like I talked about for the counter-strike server only for web servers.
Speaker 1: So you try to visit some website and instead of your get request going to the server that has that website It goes to some other server.
Speaker 1: that server may or may not get the website You know.
Speaker 1: forward your request along to the original website and then it'll send you a response.
Speaker 1: Maybe it'll send you the response to that web server sent back or it'll send you whatever the fuck it wants.
Speaker 1: So instead of browsing the actual web you're browsing the web as this proxy server wants you to see it.
Speaker 0: So for most of history when these existed they existed and they still exist.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but like when they existed in that history, they existed in one place at your school work place of business.
Speaker 0: It'd be sitting there Intercepting all your web traffic because they configured it in the browser And it would one be blocking porn sites and to logging everything you did.
Speaker 0: So you'd get in trouble later if you went to weird stuff.
Speaker 1: exactly so you said it.
Speaker 1: you set up a LAN and you have all these employees or students or whatever and You block.
Speaker 1: you set up the routers such.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're so yeah, most schools in the 90s didn't actually block.
Speaker 1: They just configured the bride when people weren't any good at this.
Speaker 1: But now if you're smart, you'll prevent people from directly accessing the internet from their computer.
Speaker 1: So any traffic that they want to send to the internet gets routed to this server.
Speaker 1: that's in your building and that server Usually is you know behaving nicely.
Speaker 1: you configured it to be a nice HTTP proxy where what it does is You know filtering if a request comes to it and it's what.
Speaker 1: for a domain that it doesn't like it Just won't honor your request and will send your response.
Speaker 1: It's like hey, no visiting that porn site But usually it'll send your request to Google get the response from Google send you the response sure, it'll log that you where you went and who went there and Such and such and also do some nice things like keeping a local cache.
Speaker 1: So the next person who makes the same request will get the same response without having to actually as Google again.
Speaker 0: Yep, so, you know in the old days like especially back when bandwidth was kind of limited If you had more than one nerd living in a house one of the nerd like especially at a university One nerd would be like hey guys I set up a squid proxy and everyone connect to it,
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: And that it actually saved you a lot of bandwidth and such and you could set you up When we live in our house, right?
Speaker 0: I go to slash dot.
Speaker 0: then you would hit five five on slash and it wasn't like websites are so dynamic.
Speaker 1: Then as they were now where every person's logged into Facebook and everyone's seeing something completely different.
Speaker 0: guys It was web 1.0 right web 2.0 didn't exist.
Speaker 1: So when I visited slash that when rim visited we saw pretty much the same thing and we just kept hitting f5 Like it wasn't.
Speaker 1: so these HTTP proxies are because most of the things you do with your computer Http, right?
Speaker 1: You're visiting websites doing web stuff.
Speaker 1: So an HTTP proxy can be used for great great good or great great evil and everywhere in between.
Speaker 1: There's so many things you can do with them.
Speaker 1: We probably won't even be able to touch on half of them in this show But caching for performance reasons is one of the good things that you can do with one of them.
Speaker 0: so one of the bad things they do is what companies can do is If you like HTTP.
Speaker 1: well thought SSL doesn't work through a web proxy natively Usually exactly because well, you could set one to just be like, okay someone's using SSL just let them go through.
Speaker 0: I could do that.
Speaker 0: or what some people do is Core and I've seen companies do this.
Speaker 0: People do this as well because they control the computer you use at work.
Speaker 0: They install a fake certificate to every major website like Google or whatever like a root like bullshit certificate Yeah, and then they run that on the proxy server and they take all your travel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm Google.
Speaker 1: Yeah, your browser thinks that it's using SSL because you're communicating with the proxy server.
Speaker 1: With encrypted SSL the proxy server is decrypting everything because you're using its certificate not the real Google certificate.
Speaker 1: So your browsers has a green light Google a-plus.
Speaker 1: It doesn't know.
Speaker 1: there's no way it can know that.
Speaker 1: that's not cool.
Speaker 1: and Now whoever's running the proxy server can see everything you're googling because they decrypted all your traffic and then they may or may not Pass that on to Google encrypted or unencrypted using the real certificate.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter because they've man-in-the-middle do and they see everything.
Speaker 0: and they can do this because they have root on your PC.
Speaker 0: And you probably wouldn't even know.
Speaker 0: and you can't even tell unless you inspect this HTTP proxy know what to look for.
Speaker 1: HTTP proxies these days Especially on the LAN are so fast that you if you put on appropriate hardware with appropriate network speeds You won't even know you're being proxy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like no one has to set this up in the browser anymore It's on the network level.
Speaker 0: You don't even know it's there.
Speaker 0: Yep, exactly You can inspect the hashes of the certificates, I guess and figure it out.
Speaker 0: But most people so I think a lot of people are probably listening to this at work tomorrow and they're like, oh Maybe I shouldn't be on this website.
Speaker 1: If you're if you maybe shouldn't be on that website at work, you maybe should be fired and deserve it.
Speaker 0: So, you know, well, you might be working for a company.
Speaker 0: that is weird Like I should be working for a different company every Monday at work.
Speaker 0: I read ogloff.
Speaker 0: But one I don't read ogloff at work.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: I Read.
Speaker 1: I watch YouTube at work.
Speaker 0: I read read it work I don't need to watch is I wouldn't read ogloff at work Like if someone was standing behind me looking at my monitor unless I was showing it to them.
Speaker 1: I don't read ogloff at work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I read.
Speaker 1: I might read another webcomic.
Speaker 0: I'm rude on my own PC.
Speaker 1: So yeah me too.
Speaker 1: But I'm you know, I still don't read ogloff at work.
Speaker 1: Yeah anyway Yeah, other things that you can do an HTTP proxy you can get fun, right?
Speaker 1: So there's lots of fun things that you can do which may or may not be evil.
Speaker 1: For example someone visited a website, you know, you pass along that request to the original website for a crew.
Speaker 1: calm You get a response of front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm.
Speaker 1: Now the proxy has to send a response back to the original users so their browser can render the page.
Speaker 0: Oh, look, let's flip all the images upside down because that's funny.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can modify the data that is coming back from the real web server in any way you want.
Speaker 1: Let's replace every image with cats.
Speaker 0: There is in fact a famous old story on slash top that I pretty sure was legit because people have done this.
Speaker 0: like it's not If you see a neighbor stealing your bandwidth because they're using your open like they cracked your web or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah old days make a proxy.
Speaker 0: just make all their images be upside down and they will never be able to troubleshoot that.
Speaker 1: You know the thing you do is you can make like all domains get reversed.
Speaker 1: So they'll have to type in like elgog.mock And you just you switch everything around all the time.
Speaker 1: Good stuff like that too.
Speaker 0: You can do pretty much anything that you can imagine if you're a bunch of nerds here in a house.
Speaker 0: Set up a proxy that blocks ads there.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's actually a really great way to do adblock because now you save the horsepower on your computer from doing it.
Speaker 1: You also block the ads not only in you know, cuz even if I use adblock for example on My computer then in that browser Chrome which has adblock installed I'm blocking the ads and my computer is doing the work of blocking those ads if I have an HD proxy set up.
Speaker 1: It's not only blocked in that browser.
Speaker 1: It's blocked in every browser.
Speaker 1: It's blocked in every can.
Speaker 1: every HTTP request on my entire network that goes to the internet has the ads removed from the response On your iPhone on your iPad on your Android device on devices that usually don't have adblock your Xbox, right?
Speaker 1: These are all making HTTP requests to get ads.
Speaker 1: You can block all those on the proxy level and all these devices Which usually you have no control over and are serving up ads won't have ads at least if they're on your land behind that proxy.
Speaker 1: Yep, and that is a real good.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: The best thing you can do with ads forget ads.
Speaker 0: you can block a malware Sure, why not?
Speaker 1: This is right.
Speaker 1: the malwares will often some of them use non HTTP, but most of them will be using HTTP requests.
Speaker 1: You know outgoing because they're trying to like tell some web server about your computer or who knows what.
Speaker 1: you just block all that You know.
Speaker 1: install some kind of filters or intelligent monitoring to see and be like, huh?
Speaker 1: Why are these HTTP requests being made?
Speaker 1: No, I'm not using any computer right now.
Speaker 1: What's going on?
Speaker 1: proxy do something about this done?
Speaker 0: so if you are malware.
Speaker 0: One of the common ways for malware to work is basically to proxy all your traffic that it can Through some dodgy server somewhere and steal all your info or just install a low Hd-proxy on your local machine.
Speaker 1: have your local machine use a proxy installed on itself.
Speaker 0: Yep, which is real easy to do.
Speaker 1: I mean most of the traffic that people are interested in is HTTP and most of the things we will do are Hdbs of proxying.
Speaker 1: that is the most useful and the most interesting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there's so many things go over HTTP that aren't just websites it's just.
Speaker 0: you can get really crazy now if you're in like enterprise or server like software side.
Speaker 0: a Problem often with these proxies is that they detect like malware and whatever and they throttle bandwidth and everything.
Speaker 0: so you might make an application or a web service or something that works great in your lab and Then you tell like the corporate sales or whatever people connect to it and stuff breaks in weird ways.
Speaker 1: Or it's a proxy might be caching it.
Speaker 0: It's really slow for some reason.
Speaker 0: It's like like the application connects like you can ping just fine But then when they connect to the HTTP port Like the one widget just doesn't load because the proxy is blocking some but not all of the HTTP track, right?
Speaker 1: You you carefully crafted this fancy JavaScript application and all right.
Speaker 1: But then the proxy modifies the HD the HTML the CSS or the JS that the client is actually receiving and our application doesn't work.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: it's not cleanly delivering to them what you gave out and if you don't understand how proxies work and all that This will be an infuriating problem because usually network issues are I can get to the host or not I can connect to the port or not.
Speaker 0: here you're connecting to the port but inside of that connection Individual little bits are being fucked up Real hard to troubleshoot.
Speaker 0: so you pretty much have to have this heuristic in your head of wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Is there a proxy been between my thing and you?
Speaker 1: right and it's basically because the person you'll be talking to is gonna be you And the customer who has this application who's just an employee at the other office.
Speaker 1: and meanwhile now the IT Department at the other office is now involved somehow even though they didn't need to be involved.
Speaker 1: now They are because their proxy server is interfering with this business.
Speaker 1: That's going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like oh god damn it you guys Why you gotta do this.
Speaker 0: one of the jobs I had at IBM a long time ago was setting up and maintaining Sox proxies through our OS to warp systems for like factory automation stuff.
Speaker 0: I Never really want to interact with that world again.
Speaker 0: Those are dark times.
Speaker 1: Well Sox is like a. isn't that a way to proxy like anything?
Speaker 0: Yes, it's a generic in the days before like modern ways of doing VPNs and things.
Speaker 0: that was like.
Speaker 0: you could just Proxy anything to anywhere with arbitrary rules.
Speaker 0: But you have to like install a Sox proxy on the local PC and set it up and it was complicated.
Speaker 1: Mmm, there's also the reverse proxy, which is usually used when you're the one who has the web server.
Speaker 1: So I set up a website and I got a whole.
Speaker 1: I want to make a whole bunch of web servers.
Speaker 1: All right, cuz I need.
Speaker 1: I have a lot of traffic I need to handle.
Speaker 1: so I mean instead of making one big server I make a whole bunch of little ones and then I set up a reverse proxy.
Speaker 1: So now when people make a request to my website, they don't go to any of these web servers.
Speaker 1: They go and connect to the reverse proxy Which is then we'll make the request to one of my hidden web servers that are hiding in my LAN and then it will cache Those responses going out.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of like now I've got an HE proxy on the server end and not on the user end and it's helping me out in the reverse direction.
Speaker 1: So that's why it's called a river channel, but it really does mostly the same thing.
Speaker 0: But think about this.
Speaker 1: then you can change your internal infrastructure completely arbitrarily and no one outside ever needs to know Yeah They're just making the same HTTP request to the same server load balancer whatever it is and everything that you do is behind it somewhere.
Speaker 1: and There you go.
Speaker 0: Now fancier people will use routers and network level devices to do that at the network level with extremely high performance and reliability.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of different things.
Speaker 1: you can do it depending, you know.
Speaker 1: But like for a lot of web like just just routing won't get you any caching, right?
Speaker 1: So it depends on what you want.
Speaker 1: You can also route to a whole bunch of different caches.
Speaker 1: You can set up all sorts of different architectures there with the reverse proxy.
Speaker 0: So yeah proxies, they're pretty interesting.
Speaker 1: There's a lot you can do is like you can have fun with.
Speaker 1: I recommend at your house is the the best thing you can do if you want to learn about these is to set one up for fun.
Speaker 1: and what you do is At your house, you got a wireless network.
Speaker 1: I bet you probably do set up a separate wireless network for your guests.
Speaker 1: most home routers that aren't garbage can do this Right.
Speaker 1: So like if you come to rims house, they'll be like geek guests and they'll be another one, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you come to my house same thing I got like four different wireless networks for different, you know one for me one for everyone else and then two on five gigahertz And two on the other one.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so on the guest.
Speaker 1: one set up a HTTP proxy.
Speaker 1: So anyone on that wireless LAN using that SSID all their HTTP traffic goes through the proxy.
Speaker 1: configure that proxy so that Anybody who's using that guest network all the images on any website they visit are replaced with cats dogs goatsy, whatever.
Speaker 1: And then invite some friends over and see how long it takes someone's like on their iPhone.
Speaker 1: They like what's the wireless password?
Speaker 1: Oh, you know.
Speaker 0: so think about how this will mess them up from like a user perspective.
Speaker 0: It won't mess up with their emails yeah, so like if they Email the link depending on how?
Speaker 1: well Yeah, it depends a lot but any HTTPS with IMG SRC any image requests that go over HTTP will return the wrong image.
Speaker 0: I think you'll have some high Larry is.
Speaker 0: some of your friends will be connected to the Wi-Fi.
Speaker 0: Some of them probably like know your password and are connected to the real one because they're better friends.
Speaker 0: So they can even be like it's fine on my phone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, look.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: See it's working just fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe you got the cat virus.
Speaker 0: I heard that's going around tell for 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: I'll fix it.
Speaker 1: a Good time will be had by all.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.