Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, May 12th, 2015.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight cordial minuets real money gambling.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, and we're finally actually for real back without any foreseeable Hiatuses for a long time.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're not gonna go on another business trip for like a week.
Speaker 1: Well now I actually.
Speaker 1: so my next trip that's any in any way substantial is Connecticut Wow, and then after that is Singapore Sydney packs prime packs dev that kai-fu lecture that I'm giving in Portland right after packs and London again, that's all in like August September.
Speaker 1: So we got some time.
Speaker 1: So geek nights is finally back and being back from Hong Kong Maybe Thursday.
Speaker 1: We should do a show on Hong Kong.
Speaker 1: I'll save it all Alex.
Speaker 1: I'll describe Hong Kong for 40 minutes.
Speaker 0: I've seen a lot of Hong Kong on YouTube and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: All I all I'll say now is that and also movies.
Speaker 1: if you have a stereo probably less accurate.
Speaker 1: Yeah if you have a stereotype of Hong Kong based primarily on like Asian cinema if you go to Hong Kong, you will know your way around and You'll feel like you're just in those movies.
Speaker 1: Hong Kong is so close to every stereotype I had about it that it was kind of shocking.
Speaker 1: I Fucking love Hong Kong.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 0: So yeah Marry it.
Speaker 1: Uh, so everyone's smart there went out of their way to remind me Yeah, but Hong Kong's ruined.
Speaker 1: China's gonna completely fuck it over.
Speaker 1: We're all like ready to leave as soon as they finally complete fucking it.
Speaker 1: Everyone there I talked to said something to the effect of I wish Britain had gone to war Rather than turn Hong Kong over to China.
Speaker 1: Wow, like people Really don't want China and most of these people are ethnically Chinese but culturally Hong Kong ease.
Speaker 1: Hong Kong.
Speaker 1: ease culture is closer to New York City culture than it is to mainland China culture Mmm, I get that feeling.
Speaker 1: in fact You know what.
Speaker 1: New York City culture is closer to Hong Kong than it is to like upstate New York culture Mmm, and and the most fucked up thing.
Speaker 1: So I was staying at this super sweet hotel like right in Lfk lkf.
Speaker 1: I keep saying lfk like It's lkf like one I can.
Speaker 1: Everyone I knew I met there who wasn't who didn't like grow up speaking a variant of Chinese Can't like.
Speaker 1: they know nouns, but they cannot speak Chinese.
Speaker 1: They have all tried for many many years to learn Cantonese and just can't speak it.
Speaker 1: But they know all the nouns mostly to rename places.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so I'm in this lkf area and There's awesome hotel.
Speaker 0: now you're saving this for Thursday.
Speaker 1: No, this is one little bit because you know the New York thing.
Speaker 1: so I'm walking like in the lobby like across there's like this glass door to the outside and I walked past it and I did what can only be described as a comedy movie like Overly dramatic over acted double-take.
Speaker 1: as I stop shake my head Walk backward and look out and sure enough I see the entrance to like the Prince Street and our station.
Speaker 1: There is this completely legit, New York City subway station sign complete with like the green like.
Speaker 1: You know that green painted and everything.
Speaker 0: Oh, is it like a bar?
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like the entrance to a bar and it's just there.
Speaker 1: my brain was fucked up by that the whole time I was there like every time I saw it.
Speaker 1: My brain was like, oh, I'll just take the subway.
Speaker 1: No, you can't take the subway.
Speaker 0: that bar will not take you to your house though, if you get drunk there your brain might go to your.
Speaker 1: But yeah, so I'll tell you about Hong Kong Coming up in the future.
Speaker 1: So in the news now that we're back from the head is the game.
Speaker 1: There's lots of gaming news.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna talk about Kojima or PT because we don't know enough about what's going on yet.
Speaker 1: We're waiting for the whole story to finish and then boom Yeah in fact The most interesting news I can find is that an insider made a YouTube video kind of talking about it and they made a DMCA Request to pull it down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so so interesting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is such drama.
Speaker 1: Wow, and this is in the backdrop.
Speaker 1: This is
Speaker 0: the most drama in video game ever
Speaker 1: and remember the backdrop of this crazy drama is multiple Famous and for real important Japanese gaming visionaries all in a relatively short span of time Quitting leaving or variously kick-starting and basically making the games they want to make
Speaker 0: more on that soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, uh, but I do want to point out this Kojima thing.
Speaker 0: This is going to be if you're not paying attention to this.
Speaker 0: This is epic gaming history news, right?
Speaker 0: Like there's certain things in gaming history that are big moments like, you know Square when square gave Nintendo the finger and put Final Fantasy on the PlayStation, right?
Speaker 0: Well think about how much the world changed like if you were making a timeline of video game.
Speaker 0: You know history, there would be many things on that timeline.
Speaker 0: Kojima fired by Konami is on the list of foot.
Speaker 0: You know things that would make it to the timeline that when it was zoomed way out We don't even 100% know.
Speaker 1: if you like we don't know.
Speaker 0: Pretty sure we're gonna find out which is why we're not going into any details until we're 100% sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, so I guess you got some news related to this related to this topic at least sure.
Speaker 0: So Koji Igarashi a Japanese game developing person who you may or may not have heard of he is a dude who has worked on many many Vania games all one of my favorite kinds of games.
Speaker 0: He's like the co-director on Symphony of the Night and then he's sort of like, you know It was the number one person pushing that genre and working on other games like that for many many years.
Speaker 0: so many of the things you like about those types of games are a result of this man's work, so Apparently, you know other the big game companies in Japan don't want to make those kind of games.
Speaker 0: But he recognizes that.
Speaker 0: hey people want to play these kind of games.
Speaker 0: So he's kick-starting one called blood-stained ritual of the night.
Speaker 0: man likes blood.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah It's already raised like seven hundred thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: I kicked it when it was still in like the hundreds.
Speaker 0: Yep, because I got brain.
Speaker 0: who's in charge?
Speaker 0: He's in charge of gaming.
Speaker 0: a Kickstarter tweeted it immediately as soon as it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and his tweet was so like I didn't realize what it was.
Speaker 0: He was just like.
Speaker 0: we want to know how.
Speaker 0: his tweet was whip whip whip link and I clicked on it.
Speaker 0: and I'm like Oh Castlevania.
Speaker 0: that explains the whipping.
Speaker 0: and then I watched the video and then while I was watching the video I gave them money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when I said I didn't even watch the video I scrolled down on the Kickstarter and I saw the concept art and I was like Oh So Sun is a Kickstarter but a miserable pile of rim spends 40 hours playing this game.
Speaker 1: Like a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: it's only 28 bucks to get a digital copy.
Speaker 1: 110 percents it in the upside-down castle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I gave 28 bucks just to get the game.
Speaker 1: That's what I gave.
Speaker 0: is I don't need physical good I don't need any of the garbage.
Speaker 1: one already backed it at the five thousand dollar level.
Speaker 0: Yeah, listen, even if you don't want to like play this game don't.
Speaker 0: if you don't want to play it don't kickstart it Right, but come and watch the video.
Speaker 0: It isn't one of the excellent Kickstarter videos of all time.
Speaker 0: It was the video was helped made by two-player productions who used to do videos or penny arcade I mean pretty much in my opinion like symphony the night number one Dawn of Sorrow number two.
Speaker 1: If anything's gonna dethrone one of those games, it's gonna be this.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't know could suck He might fuck it up, but I'm optimistic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but one thing that our good friend Daryl Surratt pointed out, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, wait, let me find is let me find his tweet.
Speaker 1: I think I know what's tweet you're about to say.
Speaker 1: cuz I favorited that tweet cuz I was gonna bring it up.
Speaker 0: Thing about Kickstarter is the big money demand isn't genre driven.
Speaker 0: It's previously established creator driven.
Speaker 1: Oh No, no, that's not true.
Speaker 1: A lot of bullshit gets a ton of money because it's purely genre driven.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 0: however, I do want he is true in the case of this one thing because If you look there have been a ton of Vanya like, you know Metroid Vanya genre indie games out in recent years.
Speaker 0: We go to PAX You see like ten of these things and they're all pretty mediocre.
Speaker 0: They're all kind of mad.
Speaker 0: That's why that they're not raking in big money on Kickstarter is not because of the.
Speaker 0: it's not the genre It's not the creator It's the quality.
Speaker 0: and it just so happens that someone who's made You know and being the producer director of so many of these is Gonna be able to deliver on the quality.
Speaker 0: if we people had the confidence That one of these crappy indie ones is gonna be any good It would also make a bunch of money.
Speaker 0: but without it's it.
Speaker 0: the creator doesn't you know, not necessarily.
Speaker 0: the fact that their name brings the money is that their name is a Somewhat insurance on the quality that brings the money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if it sucks, you've got a virtual boy Congratulations, you can bitch about it is gonna be hilarious.
Speaker 0: So that's how that's what's going on there?
Speaker 1: I'm like, I'm pretty invested in this game already.
Speaker 1: Problem is now I gotta wait for the game.
Speaker 1: I guess I did, you know, I'm so long Maybe I should just play all the DS ones again.
Speaker 1: I've probably forgotten them by this point.
Speaker 0: I still hadn't didn't beat those GBA ones.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Forgot all about those.
Speaker 0: It's quite a few.
Speaker 1: thing is I think a DS is just the best one because of how freaking long it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well longer the better.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean not.
Speaker 1: not often will I tolerate the like 80 hours of game but with a Vanya that's good.
Speaker 1: I'll tolerate a lot.
Speaker 1: I'll do a lot of things that I would not do Tonight again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they super Metroid again.
Speaker 0: Yeah again again again again.
Speaker 1: This is why with anime with video games with books with everything.
Speaker 1: It's real easy to like start watching.
Speaker 1: It's like start playing a modern indie game get about a couple hours in and say wow This kind of reminds me of half-life 2. why don't I just go play half-life 2 again?
Speaker 0: Sounds like a good idea.
Speaker 1: Actually, I started playing a half-life 2 again kind of recently just randomly why not?
Speaker 1: So in other news remember Freeman when good old games Recently released x-wing and high five.
Speaker 0: I think that's around the last time we did a geek night.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that was probably our news and that was huge news because x-wing whatever These are games that are in a genre that is truly dead and while x-wings not a game really like.
Speaker 1: to be honest high fighter Might have been what like not what it was one of the best PC games ever Made like that is.
Speaker 1: that is a fact that is not in dispute.
Speaker 1: Never forget that high fighter got the highest rating in what PC gamer.
Speaker 1: I think that was the magazine back Ever.
Speaker 0: his game ratings and magazines mean so much Yeah.
Speaker 1: But at the same time like they're in that upper echelon like people were really hesitant to give like the top ratings in case something Better came out the only game that beat it that dethroned.
Speaker 1: It was it re-released on CD.
Speaker 1: The only complaint we had about these do G packages Is that that re-release not the re re-release and not the original but the middle re-release on CD Was literally the best most perfect iterations of these games ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see people don't realize.
Speaker 0: see.
Speaker 0: nowadays when a game comes out.
Speaker 0: There's usually not Versions of the game anymore, right?
Speaker 0: The game gets patched.
Speaker 0: So you're always at the newest version.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one like counter-strike go, you know one eight and the patch differences aren't usually noticeable other than bug fixes except in fighting games.
Speaker 0: They change the rules and usually there's just DLCs adding stuff to a game.
Speaker 0: You don't get like Complete upgrades of games anymore unless they're old games getting HD remakes, right?
Speaker 0: Nintendo be like Wind Waker HD remake.
Speaker 1: but they took tie fire back in the day.
Speaker 0: The computer technology was advancing so quickly that even a game that was a year old like doom They just came out with doom again and then doom again again.
Speaker 0: It wasn't just like one cop You know, they kept re-releasing it and put making improvements to.
Speaker 0: especially there wasn't really internet then.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you couldn't download how I got doom.
Speaker 1: I was literally at a convention and for a dollar I bought a set of floppy disks that had doom Right, so you could get when they patched a game.
Speaker 0: How did they patch the game?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean you could send in to get floppies or something.
Speaker 0: But mostly it's just you didn't get the patch more than I said.
Speaker 0: you went and bought the game again.
Speaker 0: You would get a newer version than your friend who bought the game.
Speaker 0: a couple months ago.
Speaker 1: I got a floppy disk in the mail once.
Speaker 1: that was a patch to a fantasy empires.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like the copy of doom that I bought I got doom one on CD.
Speaker 0: now floppy.
Speaker 0: Whoa Young motherfucker had the extra episode CD and had the extra episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got that later, but CD Yeah, well because what happened is originally right?
Speaker 0: I got doom one just sort of copied from someone else on floppy.
Speaker 0: But then when I bought doom one It was already the extra episode edition with the episode for whatever.
Speaker 1: it was One of the first four serious games that I got and played a lot was actually xcom and I didn't know software piracy was A thing.
Speaker 1: a friend of mine was like, oh, yeah, I got a computer too.
Speaker 1: It's like a nerd guy I met at Space Camp.
Speaker 1: He was like, oh here.
Speaker 1: Here's some floppies.
Speaker 1: There's a game You should try it and it was just xcom with no instruction manual.
Speaker 1: Yeah Years later, I was like, oh that's a game you could buy in the store for money.
Speaker 0: Oh Star control - You needed that chart.
Speaker 1: Yeah Quest for glory - you need to that giant map.
Speaker 1: Yeah So the CD.
Speaker 1: so they really re-release tie fighter.
Speaker 1: They doubled the resolution of the renderer to 640 by 480.
Speaker 0: That is a Shit, that's huge.
Speaker 0: Fuck.
Speaker 0: That's way low res for these days, but it the difference is phenomenal between yeah, and they finish the voice acting.
Speaker 0: so Everything has voice acting and the music is the best.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's still the iMUSE system.
Speaker 1: So it's MIDI And it's dynamic like it changes.
Speaker 1: the only game that's done it as well.
Speaker 1: Yes as iMUSE was tribes 2 Like no games do it that well there They have like really simple cues.
Speaker 1: tribes would like change some of the loops depending on specific things that were going on Nearby.
Speaker 1: you iMUSE did.
Speaker 1: similar things like missiles are coming at you.
Speaker 1: the music get more and more intense.
Speaker 1: you feel like you're in Star Wars, so if you Regardless but no, I don't care if you play these games or not get this edition.
Speaker 1: There is literally no reason not to get.
Speaker 1: and you have five bucks.
Speaker 0: I mean, come on.
Speaker 0: Yeah You care about enough about video games that you're listening to this and you care enough about Star Wars because you're a nerd and if you Don't what the hell I can't high five.
Speaker 0: and you have five bucks because you can afford a device on which to listen to a Podcast.
Speaker 0: so you've got five bucks.
Speaker 1: buy this high fighter is one of the best games ever.
Speaker 0: Is it five bucks?
Speaker 0: How much is it?
Speaker 1: I don't know how much it is.
Speaker 1: It's also like it was the peak of a genre that died almost immediately after it Like it's a genre that is dead.
Speaker 1: And yet the peak of that genre is one of the best video games ever made.
Speaker 0: Looking up the price checking the price checking the price.
Speaker 1: So while you're checking the price I've been playing a lot of Civ 5 because I've been flying a lot and Modern airplanes.
Speaker 1: usually at least we're flying overseas.
Speaker 1: Just have holes.
Speaker 1: I can just plug my laptop in.
Speaker 1: so Kind of want to play Civ against humans and I figured out how to make pit boss go and I figured out all that shit.
Speaker 1: So if you guys want to play a big game of Civ 5 in the coming weeks I'm gonna try to do a few like let's play multiplayer for four hours just so everyone's kind of like getting pumped and getting into it.
Speaker 1: and then I'm probably going to start a Big for real pit boss game of Civ 5 and we you know with the may play by mail Like take your turn whatever and we'll just see where it goes.
Speaker 0: GOG's website is really bad on mobile.
Speaker 0: It like basically doesn't even work dude.
Speaker 0: I Would pay 40 bucks and there's a fancy new website - that's pretty shameful.
Speaker 1: I would pay 40 bucks if that's it's not 40 bucks It's way less than that, but I would pay 40 or 50 bucks for this game today.
Speaker 1: I paid like 74 60 at least when I bought it originally there Things of the day.
Speaker 1: So when I was a kid in high school in science Olympiad we had there's an event where you had you got points for like making a giant complex Rube Goldberg machine and For many years in a row.
Speaker 1: they changed the rules every year because we meaning my high school and middle school team Would look at the rules find a loophole and pull some like game breaking bullshit Get the first place.
Speaker 1: and then they changed the rules to specifically disallow the thing we did.
Speaker 1: like one year.
Speaker 0: It's like the TSA.
Speaker 1: Yep like originally like one of the rule it was just Every time you transfer between two types of energy and had like these broad categories of energy like chemical mechanical Electromagnetic like all these different things.
Speaker 1: So we made a Rube Goldberg machine and timing was the answer would like it had to finish in a precise amount of time Like two minutes and like raise a flag or ring a bell at another point along the way like one minute.
Speaker 1: So the first machine we made we made a mechanical clock with a pendulum that Ticked down exactly one minute and then exactly one more minute in parallel to a really fast and super complex Rube Goldberg machine that finished in like 30 seconds and Then just primed the clock to do its one minute and two minute.
Speaker 1: So we didn't have to do any timing for shit and our machine was a series of like 20.
Speaker 1: It was an electric motor connected to another electric motor connected to another another electric motor and our scoring chart was electrical to mechanical to electrical to mechanical to electrical to mechanical to electrical.
Speaker 1: mechanical.
Speaker 1: big old fucking battery at the end and We definitely broke every spirit of those rules to win that first place.
Speaker 1: There's a trend that continued year to year to year and when I was in high school Like senior year when I was a little older.
Speaker 1: I needed a reaction Where two clear chemicals would interact and become opaque By a like a laser sensor going through.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it had to be a chemical reaction.
Speaker 1: It couldn't be turbidity It couldn't be like.
Speaker 1: it had to be a chemical reaction.
Speaker 0: Well, you could always just find like some sort of acid or base and then pour in the stuff that turns pink in an acid Or base.
Speaker 1: no because that did so.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of reasons for that.
Speaker 1: It had to turn opaque not translucent.
Speaker 0: This turned sort of dark pink depending how much you know, but it was still translucent.
Speaker 1: It had to be opaque.
Speaker 0: you can have some starchy water and pour in some iodine.
Speaker 1: that is not the same kind of reaction Mmm, so what I remember like I was flipping through a chemistry books.
Speaker 1: I never took chemistry in high school.
Speaker 1: I took at the local community college.
Speaker 1: So I'm flipping through the high school chemistry book and then I kind of like I noticed the cover and I pull the book cover Off and the cover is a picture of two clear chemicals going into a beaker and turning a bright opaque yellow.
Speaker 1: So I there was no Google really that worked back then.
Speaker 1: so I was like trying to figure out what this reaction was.
Speaker 1: I couldn't figure it out.
Speaker 1: I wrote to the publisher like they never responded.
Speaker 1: So I went to the chemistry teacher.
Speaker 1: they even the college the college last resort chemistry teacher.
Speaker 1: Yes, I go to him because I didn't take chemistry like.
Speaker 1: I didn't know him.
Speaker 1: So I go to him and I'm like, so what is this reaction?
Speaker 1: He's like, I don't know But I'm gonna fucking find out.
Speaker 1: So he comes back to me like a month later and he'd figured it out.
Speaker 1: there are two reactions that do that and he couldn't find many other reactions that did it.
Speaker 1: and the two reactions are either a cadmium sulfide reaction cadmium sulfide is toxic as shit or a Lead chromate reaction.
Speaker 1: lead chromate is toxic as shit.
Speaker 0: It's lead.
Speaker 0: It's not know.
Speaker 1: the lead is the least of your worries.
Speaker 1: I'll link to this reaction, but Jesus.
Speaker 1: so I was like.
Speaker 1: so he's like.
Speaker 1: so why do you want to know?
Speaker 1: That's cool.
Speaker 1: and I was like.
Speaker 1: I explained that I needed it for the thing and he said oh awesome.
Speaker 1: and He gave me a card that I could use to go to the like the lab check out thing and I got all the stuff To do the lead chromate reaction and we totally used it in our thing Despite it being actually like pretty fucking toxic and dangerous.
Speaker 1: you drink it No, but you'd like inhaling it getting like it's not something to play around with.
Speaker 1: I'll link to it.
Speaker 1: So We did the thing and it worked.
Speaker 1: and then in the you know in the scoring the guy scoring us says Oh, so that reaction know what is the actual reaction?
Speaker 1: So I explained it to him and he says really I say yes, and he says you're disqualified You're not allowed to do something that dangerous here.
Speaker 1: This is like high school science Olympiad.
Speaker 1: Like what's wrong with you?
Speaker 1: Where did you even get this stuff?
Speaker 1: and My new my thing of the day is that just recently there's been a breakthrough.
Speaker 1: There is a new way to do this reaction.
Speaker 1: That is not toxic using bismuth vanadates.
Speaker 0: Okay, this video that sounds less scary.
Speaker 1: This video explains the know that involved and it's this guy.
Speaker 1: It's that awesome, sir.
Speaker 1: Palai a cough.
Speaker 1: Yeah our favorite guy.
Speaker 1: He explains it.
Speaker 1: He's like, it's pretty much not toxic like.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying you should eat it But if you had to choose between eating it or lead chromate you want to eat Have the lead chromate Rammel tea, so Anyway, I want.
Speaker 1: I was watching this video and then I remembered like this whole Odyssey of high school Olympiad.
Speaker 1: So I give you this video.
Speaker 1: enjoy it.
Speaker 1: and now you can turn two clear liquids into an opaque yellow pigment.
Speaker 0: Okay without getting cancer or dying or getting disqualified from the science Olympiad, yes.
Speaker 1: So you got a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: So here is some sort of town city council meeting somewhere, whatever.
Speaker 0: It seems like the mayor whoever the person in charge is gets up and goes to the bathroom and it's like the second in charge person She starts discussing but seems to be a legit issue and she's talking about MRSA.
Speaker 0: yeah, like, you know Bacteria that are resistant to antibiotics and how people they're starting to spread in their neighborhood.
Speaker 0: she knows people who are getting MRSA and other, you know, horrible C diff and whatnots and How they're gonna basically say hey federal government, you know They're gonna ask the federal government for money to help with this problem, right?
Speaker 0: Because it's a serious problem and it is and she's right.
Speaker 0: so.
Speaker 0: But that's not what the video is about.
Speaker 0: The video is about the guy who got up because he didn't need to listen to this part and he went to the bathroom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he left his microphone on.
Speaker 1: Oh, just like Homer Simpson.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that's all there is to it.
Speaker 1: I Think the best part about it is well She just starts losing it like in the middle of this very.
Speaker 0: she continues discussing her very serious issue, but she that.
Speaker 0: Also, it's funny that there's someone who's opposing her.
Speaker 0: It's like why would you oppose this?
Speaker 0: Do you want people to die?
Speaker 0: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm?
Speaker 1: Yeah I'll bet it was Republicans.
Speaker 0: Maybe I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know which side these people are on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's hard to say but I'm small town who gives a shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, small town politics the bathroom parts.
Speaker 1: The important part is the only thing worse than big-town politics.
Speaker 0: There's a few people in that meeting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's sad that there aren't more but at the same time I understand why there aren't more.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm not here How many are you going to?
Speaker 1: I try to go to a bunch of beacon?
Speaker 1: But the fucking old people in town always made him at like one o'clock on Wednesday.
Speaker 1: So people with jobs couldn't go.
Speaker 0: I was in the park once and someone comes up to me and is like Usually I'm just like giving them the New York ignore, but they're way pushy.
Speaker 0: Like where do you live?
Speaker 0: Where do you live?
Speaker 0: you live around here?
Speaker 0: And I'm like, no, I live in a story because I was like Greenpoint and they were like if you're lying to me I got to let you know that in that building right now is like a meeting discussing the participatory budgeting.
Speaker 0: You really gotta go.
Speaker 1: Oh someone like that grabbed Emily was like, oh you gotta fucking do this.
Speaker 1: And she was again like super scap like, uh-huh, but yeah that thing's legit.
Speaker 0: No, it's it's a real thing.
Speaker 0: That's like I don't have to go and sit in this boring meeting right now in a neighborhood.
Speaker 0: I don't live in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, get away from me.
Speaker 0: I told you no And then another person tried to push me.
Speaker 0: and I'm like.
Speaker 0: and I'm like when they said, you know I learned the lesson right there.
Speaker 0: Like do you live from here?
Speaker 0: And you're like.
Speaker 0: no, I'm from Connecticut.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm just like sprock is he - Of course that can fuck you in some places.
Speaker 0: second person was a lot less pushy though.
Speaker 1: In the meta moment, the booklet book is still water ship down.
Speaker 1: It's an epic story of rabbits.
Speaker 1: We don't have any conventions or anything until Connecticut.
Speaker 1: It's nice and chill now and relax.
Speaker 0: pegs badges are sold the fuck out So you had about an hour to get them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you had about 52 seconds to get good hotels or Saturday badges.
Speaker 1: Uh Yeah, and that's pretty much it like follow all our internet shit and now that tell the height of scissor done while it's sunny We're gonna be biking a lot.
Speaker 1: There's also gonna be a lot more geek nights content.
Speaker 1: I'm chewing through the backlog of video editing.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 1: So a Secret to win a fortune in games where numbers are foretold Cut with a scissor small slips of paper on each of which you should write a number.
Speaker 1: You should make as many numbers as you wish.
Speaker 1: put all of these slips in a large box such that the numbers are facing down.
Speaker 1: Take a spider first to trap it in a glass bottle for a half hour then smash it.
Speaker 1: Say me he prompts it.
Speaker 1: numero per de.
Speaker 1: so What did Kotaku?
Speaker 1: Kotaku described this as a mildly satanic video game that you can only play online with real money That's true.
Speaker 0: So Jason Rohrer a person we are a big fan of you may know him from such games as passage passage.
Speaker 0: Uh sleep is death which people don't know.
Speaker 0: sleep is death.
Speaker 0: is this two-player sort of RPG thing where one person Can take any action they want really and then the response is another person manually doing the pixels In response to whatever that person does.
Speaker 0: It's really amazing and overlooked.
Speaker 0: diamond trust of London castle doctrine Many other smart dude many other games and his current game that he's working on is cordial minuet Which I have been playing.
Speaker 0: we've talked about it before.
Speaker 0: we talked about in our pack South.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I started playing it too.
Speaker 0: We talked about I think a little bit before then But now it is officially released.
Speaker 0: a hundred percent Totally and I've been playing it for quite a while on and off.
Speaker 0: I have a very high yellow ranking, but I haven't made a lot of money because I don't take risks in big-money games.
Speaker 1: I haven't played it as much but I've been playing when I do play.
Speaker 1: I've been playing one to two orders of magnitude higher stakes than Scott Probably less games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've been betting ones of dollars.
Speaker 0: I've been betting ones of cents and tens of cents a Few times.
Speaker 0: one time I played a big dollar game like four or five bucks I lost and another time I played a big game for five bucks I won and I'm around $19 and change and I put in 20 bucks to start.
Speaker 0: so I'm down profit wise But my elo ranking is like six or eight plays or something.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot of games.
Speaker 0: They're just so low money They can't make up for my like losing that one one dollar game a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I put in 15 bucks.
Speaker 0: I'm at like 1380 right now I gotta play some games against rim where he bets like a couple bucks and then I can just get back up into the profit Zone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see though.
Speaker 1: What if I win right?
Speaker 0: So this game here is basically how this game works.
Speaker 0: Imagine if You're playing rock-paper-scissors But the rock-paper-scissors was not equal like rock 140 percent of the time and scissors was 20 percent of the time and paper was the other rest of the right.
Speaker 0: But not only that.
Speaker 0: there's a lot more than three choices.
Speaker 0: There's like 12 choices.
Speaker 0: Well, there's six choices really but you give one to you and one to your opponent and then you do it again one
Speaker 1: two
Speaker 0: of the remaining four choices and then the remaining two choices one for you and one for them and wherever the intersections are is the score and is a higher score wins and you bet after every move just like poker and You see who wins.
Speaker 0: you get the moneys and That's what this game is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is a game of perfect skill and Perfect arbitrary like it.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: it's a game where you Bang your brain against someone else and based on the combined decisions you to make one of you wins a bunch of money.
Speaker 1: You have to bet real money to real cash money you.
Speaker 0: there is no tutorial.
Speaker 0: There is no video that gives you tutorial.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, there's no playable you tutorial.
Speaker 0: There's a YouTube video tutorial and the way it works is you put real cash money in with your credit card.
Speaker 0: It goes into Jason roars bank account where it collects interest to who knows what right and he gives you digital money with which to Play the game which you can withdraw at any time of course into real money again, and then you play the game with the digital real money and When you create a game or join a game these the value of the game is already set.
Speaker 0: So you might see like someone wants to play a 10-cent game you click on it.
Speaker 0: You're now playing a 10-cent game.
Speaker 0: or you can say us you can say start a game and you can set the amount of money For the game equal to or less than the amount of money you have in the virtual bank.
Speaker 0: No, then both players go into that game with a hundred chips.
Speaker 0: You can leave the game.
Speaker 0: if you leave the game early you give the person the ante for the next game.
Speaker 0: Matt You know round you didn't play.
Speaker 0: So leaving means losing some amount of chips, but each chip is worth one 200th of the initial pot.
Speaker 0: so if you play a $2 game each chip is exactly one cent.
Speaker 0: Alright, and after eat the first round you're forced to bet one chip both players.
Speaker 0: So even if you both even if you fold immediately you lose that one chip.
Speaker 1: so then I pick a row for you and I pick a row for me and Then it reveals the wall row that the other person picked for you But not the row they picked for yourself for themselves, right?
Speaker 0: so I pick a row for them and they pick a row for me and And so I see the intersection of the row I picked for myself and the row they picked for me and I know the value that I have.
Speaker 0: it's some number on this grid This magic square.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we do it three times.
Speaker 1: So you basically you and them each score three boxes, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know which possibilities they have.
Speaker 0: it gets narrowed down over time But you're never a hundred percent sure until the very very end What their exact number is and along the way they play?
Speaker 0: Well, they can set it up such to where when you look at what possible numbers they could have They could have very high or they could have very low But all your values are sort of stuck in the middle.
Speaker 0: So, you know, so it's like they know whether they're beating you or not But you don't know.
Speaker 0: you just know that well 50/50 they're beating me to lose them I don't know.
Speaker 1: so in between every one of these after it's revealed how many points you got then you can Blind like simultaneously bet more money.
Speaker 0: So the betting is tricky, right?
Speaker 0: it's not like poker where it goes around.
Speaker 0: you bet without knowing what they're betting and Those chips that you bet go in well.
Speaker 1: Whoever bid less has to either match right other person bid or fold.
Speaker 0: But let's say I bid 10 and you bid 20. right you have an opportunity fold on 20 But I lose those 10 because I didn't get to see that you put in the 20 until my 10 were already taken away from Me.
Speaker 0: so now my choice is well put 10 more or fold as opposed to poker where it would be rim would put in 20.
Speaker 0: I would get the information.
Speaker 0: then my turn I fold.
Speaker 0: it's a simultaneous bet.
Speaker 1: so if you make it all the way to the end and neither player is folded then the last choice is you choose one of Your score box is to reveal to the other person, right?
Speaker 0: So once you get after that final reveal of that final number, right?
Speaker 0: Even though you're not choosing you already know your final score.
Speaker 0: I'm sure I know theirs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right that final reveal Sometimes doesn't matter based on the numbers that have been played.
Speaker 0: but that final reveal now You know, they're they have one of two possible scores and narrows it down that much before all betting is over.
Speaker 1: I have once or twice gotten someone to not fold and bid a bunch by revealing a surprisingly low number.
Speaker 0: Well, if someone reveals a low number, right it can't like it caps their max possible score obviously But you can see plainly if they reveal a low number and they have a high possible score left it's because they were hiding their big numbers.
Speaker 0: obviously right.
Speaker 0: if they reveal a high number and You look at their possible scores and there's a really low possibility It's like oh they revealed the high number to create this divergent appearance.
Speaker 1: So I get the impression That a lot of people who play this game at least at the very low stakes because there's another clever thing They don't know what's going on.
Speaker 1: The game has a really clever like score description UI element on the right.
Speaker 1: that sort of shows all the Mathematically possible numbers that your opponent could think you have that are possible in any fashion and it shows you Every possible score that the opponent could have based on the information you have.
Speaker 1: So basically it removes like a reasonable percentage of like the tedious calculation You'd have to do to be good at this.
Speaker 0: There are still some things you have to do though.
Speaker 0: It's like it does so much calculation for you, but there's still more right.
Speaker 1: the most boring calculations You can focus on the more interesting, right?
Speaker 0: so you can hover over numbers on the grid with your mouse and it will give you information if you know how to read It such as what would the possibilities be if this number will became yours Right.
Speaker 0: So it's like well if I got this number my score would be this and my opponent would see these possibilities, right?
Speaker 0: so you can sort of see a turn into the future what the possibilities are to help you decide what to pick and It's very very interesting that way because it's actually something people don't realize.
Speaker 0: this is like the first basic strategy of the game.
Speaker 0: It is possible and in fact it happens in a somewhat surprising percentage of the games I play in fact, I'd say maybe 25% of the rounds at in which before the final pick.
Speaker 0: So after the second reveal.
Speaker 0: if you look at the grid and study it You can easily figure out within.
Speaker 0: I can do it in about 20 seconds at this point, right?
Speaker 0: I can figure out Whether or not it is definitely a hundred percent guaranteed that I'll win or lose.
Speaker 0: It's like it's or after the second reveal.
Speaker 0: So the third picks haven't even been made but you can at that point oftentimes Determine with this board in this configuration no matter what pick they make and no matter what pick I make in the in the third pick I'm going to lose or I'm going to win no matter what.
Speaker 0: and at that point if you make that calculation and figure out it's One of those rounds you can either a fold immediately because you know, you've lost no matter what Yeah, or B just go all-in because they haven't realized it yet.
Speaker 0: Most likely Right, and if they know if they're as good as you they were gonna fold right.
Speaker 0: then anyway No matter what you bet.
Speaker 0: So what's?
Speaker 0: you might as well go all-in instead of 10 or 20?
Speaker 1: That's one thing I've noticed.
Speaker 0: and if they don't know any better Well, I mean, maybe you could have lured them in with a lower bet.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: in a higher stakes game if I just go all-in Most of the time my opponent folds very very quickly.
Speaker 0: Well, that's because they got a shitty score, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'll go all-in like semi-randomly and people almost always fold.
Speaker 0: Bluffing in this game is huge.
Speaker 0: Right because if you can get a bluff win You can get way out ahead of your opponent really fast because if you have the upper hand in chips You are in a very strong position to just take the rest of theirs Regardless of what gets picked.
Speaker 0: right because you can start raising on every round no matter what and if they don't have a good hand It's like they have to fold because if they go for it, they just lose everything they have left.
Speaker 0: They've only got like 20 chips left, right?
Speaker 0: They need to win on like an all-in to get back into the game.
Speaker 0: So we get the upper hand in chips.
Speaker 0: You can just bully your opponent a lot So that you know gives that kind of strong strategy there regardless of the picking that goes on.
Speaker 1: Yeah But in general like just playing this game it's Surprisingly addictive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because it's it gives you that and not because you want to win the real money.
Speaker 0: No, I'm paying for ten cents.
Speaker 0: I don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: Game theory game like this.
Speaker 0: There is nothing in my mind that has like a fit.
Speaker 0: like you go into a casino and you pull a slot machine which can be Addictive to even the smartest person and it's like.
Speaker 0: but that's because you have in your mind this fantasy of like ooh This jackpot might come out But this time I know there's no fantasy of a jackpot coming out.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to do like a poor man's minimax in my head Like I'm trying to like.
Speaker 1: do that, you know, which cup should I some people.
Speaker 0: some people use spreadsheets.
Speaker 0: Some people wrote their own client apps even right just like because it's just an open It's you can.
Speaker 0: there's no copyright in the code, right?
Speaker 0: Everything's on the server.
Speaker 0: It's like you can just write your own client.
Speaker 0: You can just look at the all the source.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever Jason say we asked him something like packs Like.
Speaker 1: does he care if people like try to write bots to solve it with game theory?
Speaker 1: There was a lot Yeah, and he's like, yeah, I still make a cut like I don't care go nuts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the thing.
Speaker 0: So every round of the game so you go into a game against someone and as long as no one leaves You're playing until one person holds all the remaining chips.
Speaker 0: now each round that you play when the pot pays out Jason roar takes one chip.
Speaker 0: So if you takes if you're playing like really going against someone and he goes deep into the game round after round after round And no one's won yet He's taking more and more chips away out of that game and he's happy times.
Speaker 0: He's getting more money's right like imagine if you're playing a big-time game thousands of dollars.
Speaker 0: Each one of those chips is only one two hundredth.
Speaker 0: So if you play a two thousand dollar game.
Speaker 0: each chip is like ten bucks But at the same time he's making ten bucks every round and also the ante increases every round.
Speaker 0: So I play against rim.
Speaker 0: we play a grid.
Speaker 0: right we have to.
Speaker 0: we must ante one chip.
Speaker 0: We can obviously go all in right away It doesn't matter but we're putting in at least one chip each.
Speaker 0: Then the next round two then the next three then four then five.
Speaker 0: so the deeper you get in You can't play Conservatively because you're basically forced to bet.
Speaker 0: like is the 20th round against this guy have to put in 20 chips, right?
Speaker 0: So it gets really rough if you're just like if you fall behind a little bit and start playing conservatively just to hold on folding a lot.
Speaker 0: cuz eventually it's Like well, I got I got the one on the first go fold.
Speaker 0: I just lost like 20 chips.
Speaker 0: Fuck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right It's like you have to play aggressively and really go after your opponent no matter how many.
Speaker 0: but you've got going on But it's hard to do.
Speaker 0: Like I said before when you have low chips You can't go after someone who's betting a lot because you're basically staking it all in that one game suddenly Whoa, random aside looks like a bull bus exploded.
Speaker 1: No It was the way to Boston - it's the one we would usually take.
Speaker 0: no look at that.
Speaker 1: It literally just exploded.
Speaker 0: Wow Bam was people on it.
Speaker 1: I think they ran off the bus.
Speaker 1: I can't tell what's going on.
Speaker 0: Whoa Wow, and I was so safe.
Speaker 1: Oh, look at that.
Speaker 0: I was having such good times on this safe bolt bus, but maybe you want this to be you.
Speaker 0: Maybe I should stop taking the boat bus Amtrak's not that much more expensive.
Speaker 0: That's the first accident bolt buses ever had.
Speaker 1: I think they've had a couple more.
Speaker 0: I don't know but that's.
Speaker 1: I was stuck on a bolt bus.
Speaker 0: It wasn't.
Speaker 0: it wasn't like a crash accident, right?
Speaker 0: It was just the bus.
Speaker 0: I thought those are well maintained.
Speaker 0: I guess I've been lied.
Speaker 1: I don't think any coach buses are well maintained.
Speaker 0: So said ah First comment.
Speaker 1: Yeah fun.
Speaker 1: Well still looks bad.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that was an aside.
Speaker 1: that's a New York decide right because we use the bolt bus to go to Pax's.
Speaker 0: So now, you know the rim just reads the Internet's while he's doing the show here.
Speaker 0: Yeah So there's a lot of other things going on in this game, right?
Speaker 0: So the theme of the game is sort of like this dark underground like satanic Like you've been invited into a secret society because you secret gambling day, you know things.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I mean like we talked about in our pack show.
Speaker 1: his booth at Pax was like this gypsy like mystery gambling day.
Speaker 0: That's a racist word.
Speaker 0: racist.
Speaker 1: Look like a gypsy cap.
Speaker 1: It was cool.
Speaker 0: Gypsy's a race.
Speaker 1: It should be like a Romani time Yeah, but I don't want to impose this satanic gambling game upon the actual Romani people.
Speaker 0: That's why but it's just.
Speaker 0: the tent was in their stylings But it was actually a tent in the style of the fortune teller from Laura linked to the past.
Speaker 1: But inside it was like this cyberpunk dystopia with these like raw Lzd monitors with like ribbon cables coming out of them to play the game on.
Speaker 0: Yep This is the style of the game accounts for live is the boring like minesweeper grid?
Speaker 0: You wouldn't really be wanting to play this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the games like it had and you know, he's made You know the gong that we do a lot of lectures about like game design and UX and all these things.
Speaker 1: Jason Rohrer is one of the few people on earth where I have really nothing bad at all to say about any of his works
Speaker 0: And all his works are like completely new and ingenious and fresh But like any other thing that came before that all the
Speaker 1: things that I make tired complaints about with other games Like he's got that shit down flawlessly like
Speaker 0: simple
Speaker 1: little things.
Speaker 1: Like he uses the metaphor of like paper in the game, right?
Speaker 1: Like it's a piece of parchment and you put ink on it.
Speaker 1: like green ink shows the air Like the place you took and red ink shows the other persons and the ink never goes away.
Speaker 1: Like it doesn't preview.
Speaker 1: showing you ink when you're making your decision you move a marker outside the board.
Speaker 1: ink is permanent on the paper.
Speaker 1: Yep little things like that.
Speaker 1: the UI and the UX are so Consistent and just so well thought out in these very nuanced ways.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about some basic strategies.
Speaker 0: So the most basic strategy there is is to give your opponent the row that has the lowest possible Number.
Speaker 0: basically keep their score down, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know the maximum score they could have.
Speaker 0: meanwhile pick for yourself either.
Speaker 0: You can figure out your opponent's behavior and therefore, you know They're gonna pick the shittiest row for you.
Speaker 0: So pick the highest number of the shitty thing.
Speaker 1: you already went one step beyond your first heuristic, right?
Speaker 0: or?
Speaker 0: Just pick a row with high variance.
Speaker 0: if you pick a row with high variance You're mathematically speaking because all the rows and columns add up to the same number.
Speaker 0: It's a magic square, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so You can sort of pick a row with high variance and it's like you might get a really low score.
Speaker 0: You might get a really high score, but your opponent sees both possibilities because you picked a row with high variance.
Speaker 0: So the result of that is you're keeping your opponent's score down.
Speaker 0: So they don't have a big number to be confident with that.
Speaker 0: They're gonna beat you.
Speaker 0: and when they look at your possibilities It's like well could be big could be small.
Speaker 0: You might have six you might have a hundred.
Speaker 0: They don't freaking know right?
Speaker 0: it's like sort of a coin toss for them which makes them nervous.
Speaker 0: and Then you can convince them with your betting.
Speaker 0: if you are being contained by your opponent sort of into this middle-of-the-road score It's like well you might win with that if they were really if you can force them into a really shitty score But you don't have the.
Speaker 0: how do you have the confidence to bet when they could have a really high score and they're betting big?
Speaker 0: It's like oh, what do you do?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that's the most basic of strategies.
Speaker 0: There are other strategies.
Speaker 0: For example, let's say you see a row and that row has like 36 and 34 and it like these two big numbers like those are 36 is the biggest number on the grid, right?
Speaker 0: It's a six by six grid one to 36.
Speaker 0: You don't want them to get the 36.
Speaker 0: They're probably gonna win with that unless you give them two really crappy numbers to go with it.
Speaker 0: But because it has the 36 and another over 30 number that row the rest of the numbers are gonna be really shitty.
Speaker 0: So it's like well if they pick this row, you know I'd give them this row if they pick randomly they have a four out of six chance of getting something really really shitty Right.
Speaker 0: So I'll give them that and maybe they'll get lucky and get the one of the two that are over 30 But most likely four out of six chance.
Speaker 0: They're gonna get a really bad number.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if they're stuck with that well You know, I'm probably gonna.
Speaker 0: they're breaking a fold right away.
Speaker 0: No If I bet a little bit or who knows where right.
Speaker 0: so you can give them that kind of row Bet and if they see you or they bet also you can be pretty sure they got one of those 30s unless they're really really smart Betting it up when they've got a shitty number course.
Speaker 1: Then you use that.
Speaker 1: if you assume that they got like the 30 then you know that they can't use that row again.
Speaker 1: Yeah in the next two rounds Dale.
Speaker 0: So you they pick a row.
Speaker 0: They've eliminated all these other possibilities from the game.
Speaker 0: So, you know you give them this row and the good number in that row is 36, right?
Speaker 0: And they let's say you're pretty sure they got the 36.
Speaker 0: Well, if you're pretty sure about that then you know that in this these other numbers across the board They can't get those on the second pick.
Speaker 0: and you see that they've eliminated by picking the 36.
Speaker 0: They've eliminated like the 28 from this other choice.
Speaker 0: It's like well I'll give you that row that no longer has a 28 in it because the rest of the numbers in aren't that great.
Speaker 0: And then they also they give you a row.
Speaker 0: so they give you a row and now it's like well They gave me that row which means they didn't take it for themselves.
Speaker 0: So they can't possibly have any of those numbers and they've eliminated the 30 from that one.
Speaker 0: So I'll give them that one that no longer has a 30 in it and has a really shitty numbers remaining.
Speaker 1: Now I found that a lot of one of the strategies I use in low stakes games It seems highly effective is I kind of assume my opponent's dumb and has a pretty simple strategy.
Speaker 1: So I move quickly and The first round I assume that they're gonna do something dumb Like they.
Speaker 1: they're going for the 36, you know, these look really like there's like the really simplest heuristics baby mode.
Speaker 1: so assuming someone's dumb and doing that I Maximize the harm to them by making that choice.
Speaker 1: and then it's immediately obvious if that works in the first round then I play super Aggressively and super fast and bit a lot and I just kind of bowl them over and win
Speaker 0: a lot of the game is Figuring out because if you just try to play randomly rock-paper-scissors wise right that is not going to work Right in rock-paper-scissors.
Speaker 0: You want to play randomly?
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: because all three choices are equally power.
Speaker 1: You do still want to play randomly, but you want to play with a mixed strategy.
Speaker 0: You want to play like not all strategies in this game are equally powerful, right?
Speaker 0: There's a really strong rock and sort of a weaker scissor and a ball.
Speaker 1: choices are not even so what you.
Speaker 1: so a mixed strategy would be.
Speaker 1: like 60% of the time I'm going to you know not choose the row with the 36 because reasons I'm gonna use this other kind of row in my first pick.
Speaker 1: Yeah Or like 20% of the time I'll choose a low variance row in the first round because the board is different.
Speaker 0: the actual Variance numbers change round to round.
Speaker 0: that is sometimes boards are just unfavorable to one or the other player.
Speaker 0: But you can.
Speaker 0: sometimes you can look at a board from turn one and be like, oh wow I can just totally corral them in no matter what they pick right.
Speaker 0: It's like in order for them to beat these picks They would have to make that pick.
Speaker 0: but then picks two and three they're hosed.
Speaker 0: So and if they don't pick that on turn one, they're hosed.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this board is just good for me.
Speaker 0: I'll just bet it way up on the first pick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like sometimes what I'll do is if there's a row that has very little variance is all like middle-of-the-road numbers.
Speaker 1: Sometimes what I'll do is I'll give that to myself on the first round because they can't basically like they can't
Speaker 0: hurt me Hose you out on the first round
Speaker 1: and then the Choices like making my choice and doing my calculation of the next two rounds super easy at that point because I have there's so few decisions left to make.
Speaker 1: so I can think of it in terms of Two row choices high score low score like these positions and I can sort of based on their behavior figure out like oh They tend to when they're behind do this kind of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's all about you know, figuring because your opponent is always a human being right?
Speaker 0: They have some sort of logic.
Speaker 0: You can always also think what would I do if I were them?
Speaker 0: and there's there are situations where it's not just poison cup because the math Unbalances the poison cup.
Speaker 0: It's like wow, they would be stupid to make this pick because they just lose if they make that pick.
Speaker 0: So really they're only making one of these two choices.
Speaker 0: Which one would I make if I was them based on their past behavior in previous rounds?
Speaker 0: Which one are they likely to pick?
Speaker 0: Oh, look if I pick this row that's kind of hoses them on either of those two choices.
Speaker 0: I have to pick that one and I'll get this one and then it usually turns out that you're right and You'll see that the other players can also do this to you.
Speaker 0: You'll often see like in the last round, you know when there's only like two, you know There's only like two numbers two columns left because there's only two things to pick.
Speaker 0: you'll see like there'll be one row.
Speaker 0: But there's only two shitty numbers available and it's like they're gonna give me that one, aren't they?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna get a shitty number now no matter what right right and yes Nine times out of ten that shitty row that only had two shitty numbers left goes to you and it didn't matter what you pick.
Speaker 0: However, if they don't do that like if they do well The only way they wouldn't do that is if that had given themselves that row already in one of the earlier two picks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if they're a good player They haven't.
Speaker 0: they knew.
Speaker 0: that's how it was gonna work.
Speaker 0: and those other two numbers that you've taken in that row They know those are already beneath what I was getting.
Speaker 1: that I can tell it makes like an obviously dumb decision.
Speaker 1: more than once They're a keeper and I saw I'm playing this game to the end.
Speaker 0: It's all about figuring out your opponent's behavior in those early rounds.
Speaker 0: It's always full advantage.
Speaker 1: smart in the early round no matter
Speaker 0: how smart you are There is some pattern to your behavior in some strategy because if you don't have any kind of strategy if you play Super randomly you will just lose to someone who plays sort of the greatest win percentage chance rose.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you there's you can just play the best chance of winning rose Against a random bot and you will come out on top like money-wise 60% or something like that.
Speaker 0: So you cannot just play randomly.
Speaker 0: you have to have some sort of.
Speaker 0: you have to at least Play best odds of winning choices if no other kind of choice.
Speaker 0: But if you play best odds of winning and your opponent knows you always play best odds of winning they can just destroy you.
Speaker 0: You have to mix it up and therefore it forces you to do Poison cup with math.
Speaker 0: add it on to it.
Speaker 0: Not just straight poison cup.
Speaker 1: So it's super fun and you should probably put just not mean think put like five bucks in.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to spend a lot of money.
Speaker 0: You can play penny games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right think think of that five bucks as that's what you paid for the game, right and just don't lose all your money And just try it out.
Speaker 0: It's if you have problems with gambling.
Speaker 0: There are places you can call for that.
Speaker 0: It's an Interesting like.
Speaker 0: it's not a variance.
Speaker 1: There aren't other games like it?
Speaker 1: No that's for sure and I'm curious if anyone is going to put any like Game theory math behind it to try to come up with an optimal play strategy.
Speaker 0: Also, it's really I just came out now.
Speaker 0: It's hot now.
Speaker 0: There's like a launch contest.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: if you're gonna play it play it now because this is the kind of game that could easily not Have any players after some amount of time.
Speaker 1: also, you know poker.
Speaker 1: if poker gets really popular like one month because there's a big thing On TV, that's when you want to play a bunch of poker because a whole bunch of noobs are playing poker.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna get some money out of them.
Speaker 1: You don't want to play poker when the only people in the room are all wearing sunglasses and are obviously poker pros.
Speaker 1: Just just leave.
Speaker 0: Yeah also the forum for this game.
Speaker 0: You need to go there if you're playing it more than just once to see what it is.
Speaker 0: Go and sign up for the forum for this game and read the threads.
Speaker 0: There is important informations in there to learn a lot of things.
Speaker 0: Many things need to be learned from those forums many discussions leaderboards all sorts of stuff That if you want to make any sort of winning strategy You need to go check that out and see what other people are talking about.
Speaker 1: and in a closing note blood-stained ritual of the night raised 70,000 more dollars since we mentioned it on the show earlier, you know, I've been watching this tally count up.
Speaker 0: I mean people pay a lot of money just for an original copy of Symphony of the Night on a disc.
Speaker 0: Why wouldn't they pay 28 bucks for a digital copy of modern?
Speaker 0: Probably a lot of people as good game at high levels - well, you know, they really like.
Speaker 1: I mean eight people gave him two grand.
Speaker 0: What do you get for two grand?
Speaker 1: What do you get for two?
Speaker 1: for two grand you get the game?
Speaker 0: I hope runic forging.
Speaker 1: I guess that's the name of that thing.
Speaker 1: Okay, collaborate with the development team to create an in-game weapon.
Speaker 1: All right, that's cool.
Speaker 1: That'd be cool.
Speaker 1: I would make some like bullshit little stabby dagger.
Speaker 0: I would make See what like throwing weapons because they don't get used enough, but I'd make it throwing up and it's actually used a lot.
Speaker 1: Well, like in Dawn of Sorrow my my go-to as soon as I got all the good weapons I'd always have cuz you know the two hands I'd have the slowest Most fucking damage like the giant axe and my other weapon is the fastest weakest weapon.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: what I would do is I would make a bow and arrow or crossbow that could actually be fired rapidly in all eight Directions, but was only mid was strong enough to matter but not ridiculously strong.
Speaker 0: So you'd be better off using an unwieldy weapon for just damage.
Speaker 0: So but it would really be good to use in a lot of those rooms or bad guys come from all sorts of directions if you have skills because you can Actually hit them as opposed to trying to like dodge out of the way so you could hit him with your clumsy sword.
Speaker 0: That's what I would do like a metal blade basically.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you and your metal blade.
Speaker 1: metal blade was way OP.
Speaker 0: That's the point.
Speaker 0: Yeah less powerful than metal blade though, but still with the directions and the control.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.