Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, December 16th, 2015.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: Miyazaki's castle in the sky, Lapita that we somehow never reviewed in all these years.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: There was a time not that long ago when new episodes of attack on Titan were coming and I was kind of pumped to see the next one because I really wanted to know what all the secrets were like.
Speaker 0: I really the show was not that great.
Speaker 1: There's a terrible secret of space.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I really what's in the castle with the king?
Speaker 0: I really needed to know the answers to all those secrets and I kept watching the show and I and it had.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: The show's not bad like the air like the flying around and the plot.
Speaker 1: I read a lot of the manga.
Speaker 1: I have a lot of the manga and they reveal these secrets and It's like there aren't a lot of secrets left But they don't tell you like about that fucking door house or whatever with the guy's dad.
Speaker 1: It's like they don't tell you the real secret.
Speaker 1: It's like geez.
Speaker 1: What the hell?
Speaker 1: I don't understand.
Speaker 1: So I doesn't make a lot of sense.
Speaker 0: I went out there and I found Summaries and I read every possible spoiler of attack on Titan that could possibly be found.
Speaker 1: it really Peters out a lot.
Speaker 1: Ah Based on everything I know about they don't keep up the mystery of the secret of space.
Speaker 0: very well If the rate of things being revealed from the first anime is an indication The entirety of what I know that happens after the anime will take about nine years to make it out in anime form.
Speaker 0: I Also knowing what the answers are like I just don't care anymore.
Speaker 1: I never care.
Speaker 0: If a new attack on Titan anime happens.
Speaker 0: I might watch it eventually but I'm not gonna watch it until it's all out.
Speaker 1: Anyone wants a whole lot of volumes of attack on Titan manga.
Speaker 1: I have them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't read the mom I couldn't.
Speaker 0: the manga was not great.
Speaker 0: I would rather just read a Wikipedia or like a Wikipedia page that tells me the plot then read the manga It's like in order.
Speaker 0: one anime is best to Wikia.
Speaker 0: three the manga For your annoying friend who knows more about it because they read the manga and you didn't.
Speaker 1: also There's a whole bunch of spin-off mangas about like one or two volumes each one to see what the deal was all bad, but seriously, I'm not gonna spoil it for you guys, but The things you don't know.
Speaker 0: there's some things that you probably think are gonna be really cool.
Speaker 0: They are not that cool Fact some of them pretty dumb.
Speaker 1: the dumb king really, you know The secret of what it's like cuz the king is like this mysterious character.
Speaker 1: Like who is the king?
Speaker 1: How did they become king?
Speaker 1: and it right the truth of who the king is and whatnot.
Speaker 1: that pretty much was like the final straw.
Speaker 0: I guess what really bothers me in retrospect is that there are things that happen in the show that based on the world You are presented with Everyone who witnessed those events should treat that like the most damning crazy revelation in history.
Speaker 0: It'd be like if Bigfoot literally just crashed through our window and said hello.
Speaker 0: right now Like that's how people should be reacting.
Speaker 0: and yet almost no one reacts to those events in the show at all.
Speaker 0: So it's hard to gauge what the actual plot is Or the history or anything unless you just read spoilers or know it all.
Speaker 0: I just kind of petered out on that.
Speaker 1: show Doesn't have a lot of staying power.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 1: You never did.
Speaker 0: we said that from the beginning Yep, and now it's kind of confirmed at least for me now that I know everything.
Speaker 0: it was confirmed.
Speaker 0: So it's it's Wednesday got any news.
Speaker 1: Yes, so Faku your boys the masters of American hentai good dudes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they they are going to launch a Kickstarter and this Kickstarter is Because they want to license and publish in English some mangas some hentai mangas.
Speaker 1: All right, including La blue girl the most famous hentai Perhaps the one that most anime fans have not actually seen.
Speaker 1: but everyone talked about demon beast invasion Which I know nothing about but has a cool name Adventure kid, which doesn't have a cool name.
Speaker 1: It might makes me think of an adventure island with the kid on the skateboard.
Speaker 0: I was about to say that sounds like I'm pretty sure it's hentai.
Speaker 1: Yep, and most importantly Took a doji legend of the overfeed the number one Violent.
Speaker 0: I feel like that anime bad anime.
Speaker 1: So the manga was published in six volumes by CPM a long time ago like ten years ago But apparently it was censored and things were removed.
Speaker 1: Fak is gonna give the uncut full real-deal legit release that does not exist in English in a legal way currently.
Speaker 0: It is weird how pervasive the legend of the overfeed is in American and British Anime fan culture like most people I know have not actually seen it but Everyone has heard of it.
Speaker 0: It's the default joke answer when anyone asks anyone.
Speaker 0: Hey, what anime should I show my mom?
Speaker 1: apocalypse zero.
Speaker 1: But they're actually working like they're legit like they're working together with Toshio Maeda Who's the guy who made legend of the overfeed?
Speaker 1: So this isn't like, you know some unofficial deal.
Speaker 1: This is like the most legit that it can be.
Speaker 1: So when this Kickstarter appears I might even kick.
Speaker 1: I haven't read or watched a hentai and like Ever I have some.
Speaker 0: maybe I have a bunch of the old Steve Bennett stuff that was given to me at a convention long ago.
Speaker 1: But it's like, you know, I'll buy a copy of legend of the overfeed in English Piece of anime history.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 0: He's a manga history, I guess nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: actually in Japan if Anyone particularly remembers legend of the overfeed Imagine not.
Speaker 0: I feel like it's.
Speaker 0: maybe I could be wrong But I imagine not because I know like there's a bunch of British anime fans way back told us that basically in the UK That was a lot of people from our generation like their introduction to anime and anime was like Japanese porn.
Speaker 1: Cartoons just happened to be like the first tent I had that someone brought over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we had like a lotos war is not really that good But that was one of the first anime on TV.
Speaker 0: It might have been the first anime on DVD in the US.
Speaker 0: So a lot of people buy.
Speaker 1: I think the first anime DVD was if I'm not mistaken the legend not Lodos war OVA DVD.
Speaker 0: I'm almost certain that is the case because I remember being a kid Trying to convince my parents to buy one of the like eight hundred to a thousand dollar DVD players that were fancy and new Because I saw that the box set of lotos war was like 90 bucks on DVD And that shit was way more than 90 bucks if you bought all those VHS.
Speaker 1: I remember all those VHS tapes like all the red VHS tapes that were lined up in a big row of lotos TV and like Every even even you know, not nerdy stores and it was just like whoa.
Speaker 1: What is that?
Speaker 1: It's some fantasy anime thing.
Speaker 1: Well, I can't afford all that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm a high school kid.
Speaker 0: a lot of anime I would have watched younger than I didn't because I saw how many VHS tapes there were at 2499 a pop for two to four episodes.
Speaker 0: so in less Exciting news Funimation all-around good anime company Apparently has found a sinking ship and is desperately swimming out toward it to make camp.
Speaker 0: For whatever reason Funimation is launching an anime focused cable TV network.
Speaker 1: But we already had.
Speaker 1: they already tried the anime network and it failed.
Speaker 1: and they came an on-demand Network, which I don't even know why.
Speaker 1: who still watches that?
Speaker 0: or anime network in today?
Speaker 1: It's making some kind of money because it still exists.
Speaker 0: It's a 480i resolution video on-demand service that basically I can't imagine.
Speaker 1: anyone who would use the anime network Unless they don't have internet must be making more money than it cost to run it.
Speaker 1: So cuz it still exists, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but why would you go back and try to do the full network again?
Speaker 0: I mean anime itself.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's a self-sustaining ecosystem of pure anime like anime fans.
Speaker 0: This is for you and only you are.
Speaker 1: they gonna like just show anime or they also gonna produce new shows that are anime Related.
Speaker 0: looks like they're just gonna license anime.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell they're not gonna make shows like quote from a tonight Or quote from the seat Mike the COO of Funimation anime world order TV.
Speaker 0: We're committed to making it easy to discover and connect with anime and our new cable channel will provide the best in anime entertainment that Fans have come to expect I mean to Nami can't even sustain can only sustain like a little bit of anime each week.
Speaker 0: This will not make it easy to discover and connect with anime because Hulu already exists let alone crunchyroll.
Speaker 1: So and also I guess if you're somewhere with the TV on and you're flipping through the channels You'll be able to put on this and it will be less bad than what the young people don't pay for cable anymore And they're not good this Anime to old people.
Speaker 0: but they won't because old people won't go to the anime network.
Speaker 0: The only way to get people who don't already know about Hulu and crunchyroll to be able to see anime is to put anime on The networks they already watch.
Speaker 1: I mean the Hasbro channel with the ponies couldn't even hold, you know hold Yeah, the hub did not succeed either.
Speaker 1: So why would this succeed?
Speaker 0: I know if I was gonna do this What are they thinking?
Speaker 0: I would make and a cartoon network that actually showed nothing but cartoons.
Speaker 1: I would.
Speaker 0: that's what I would do.
Speaker 0: it would that we would have the pony all the Hasbro type stuff and Anime and other animation and I'd hire like anime world order and make them just do a fucking morning show about animation.
Speaker 0: I hire a bunch of Warner Brothers shit.
Speaker 1: if I had Disney everything I've had a TV network.
Speaker 1: I would run it like a completely normal TV network.
Speaker 1: only my news would be real fucking news.
Speaker 1: You know all the people that all the personalities that appeared on my network would you know give people the real deal not some bullshit.
Speaker 1: You know watered down for TV nonsense and I'd show what I thought were the best shows being produced that I could get Regardless of whether they were what country they were from or you know what type of show.
Speaker 0: that's just what amazes me Like what.
Speaker 0: there's so many things wrong with this one.
Speaker 0: It's cable TV, which is dying like.
Speaker 0: we almost talked about that on Monday, but we didn't because it's so obvious.
Speaker 0: So they're going to a sinking medium.
Speaker 1: I don't know what like what is there?
Speaker 1: did they say what their strategy is?
Speaker 0: No, okay Renewed focus on delivering fans the best selection of anime content in the market.
Speaker 0: Okay, I mean, yeah, I guess you'll have the best selection of anime in the cable TV market.
Speaker 0: Sure go nuts, but so but it's bad.
Speaker 0: It's weird because they're going to network like well network cable TV, but it's also weird because it's anime exclusive Which defeats any of the benefits you get from being on network cable TV?
Speaker 0: So Whatever.
Speaker 0: I just I don't understand how the anime industry even exists in America.
Speaker 1: Sometimes they should spend their money like just on PR so that they get the same amount of coverage You know equal to their popularity in you know, the regular existing media.
Speaker 1: Yeah Just hire PR people with that money.
Speaker 1: don't hire
Speaker 0: PR people and get like shows that have mass appeal like just show redline On a network that shows other crazy movies like show aliens and then redline
Speaker 1: just market You know paint that money from marketing some market to people who aren't anime fans to grow the pie.
Speaker 0: So yeah, this is just kind of weird.
Speaker 0: They haven't even announced any details.
Speaker 0: funimation plans to announce further details on the funimation channels relaunch soon So I guess we'll be able to say more then.
Speaker 0: even worse You know what?
Speaker 0: This article says that what they said quote.
Speaker 0: while we finalize the new channel for launch next year I encourage viewers to subscribe to our streaming service now at funimation comm.
Speaker 0: so Why would I subscribe to one if I had the other?
Speaker 1: Why would you have cable if you have it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, why would I have cable full stop if you have internet?
Speaker 0: Okay, so interestingly enough just because I'm on there could be a place on where you can.
Speaker 0: you can't get really fast internet But you can still get cable comic book calm which is where I'm gonna link to for this because that's just the article I had.
Speaker 0: There's four comments on the article.
Speaker 0: The first one is broadcast one piece and I'll subscribe.
Speaker 0: Okay, the next one is I wish there'd be a network devoted to comic book programming.
Speaker 0: Okay, the third one is an ass spam ad.
Speaker 0: All right, and the fourth one is Saying what we just said.
Speaker 0: Okay, and also said something about to Nami.
Speaker 0: prove that no one cares of watching anime on TV.
Speaker 1: Well that says more about the Community of comic book calm than it says about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, yep Oh the guy who wants us to brought them to broadcast one piece has a luffy avatar in his Count that he made on comic book calm to respond to articles like this one.
Speaker 0: Who runs comic book calm?
Speaker 1: Someone who got a really good domain name and is just trying to me.
Speaker 0: I'm just like I know it's much money with.
Speaker 0: so it's got TV movies comics games.
Speaker 1: It's just a generic content scrapie site.
Speaker 1: It's probably not where that article came from.
Speaker 1: It's yeah original content.
Speaker 0: This is just interesting Whatever.
Speaker 1: It's interesting.
Speaker 1: There's a content scrapie site.
Speaker 1: Welcome to internet.
Speaker 1: There's like 10 million of them.
Speaker 0: There's fascinating.
Speaker 0: It's like when you explore a rundown city somewhere in the middle of Detroit like yeah, you know, there's rundown cities.
Speaker 0: But it's interesting to actually walk down some alleys and see what's back there.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: As you know I generally take a dim view of the sort of hyper live streams that people do about video games the whole markiplier or whatever.
Speaker 0: but This live stream is actually worth watching.
Speaker 0: So this is a dude in Japan.
Speaker 0: It's a Japanese guy who just live streams minecraft stuff in the usual fashion.
Speaker 0: But this particular video is him kind of.
Speaker 0: as an aside.
Speaker 0: he has this weird sort of like permanent match lighter that is not a use is trying to use it and over the course of these 11 minutes and 42 seconds he manages to start multiple fires and Burn his entire house down.
Speaker 0: Live on the internet.
Speaker 1: don't smoke kids.
Speaker 0: What makes this particularly funny but also tragic is the way that this happens because he had like Seven opportunities to prevent this from occurring and there is a beautiful moment When he starts a fire.
Speaker 0: in the process of trying to put that fire out He starts a second fire behind himself that he does not notice.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, he has this plug-in I guess where anyone who messages him from his live stream this Hatsune Miku sounding voice will read the message out loud.
Speaker 0: so The at one point the fire starts behind him and then you hear this anime will go.
Speaker 0: Wha?
Speaker 0: I Suggest you watch the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Don't skip ahead It's not.
Speaker 1: if it wasn't for the vocaloid reading the chat out loud Video wouldn't be any good But I'd really watch the whole thing because you will.
Speaker 0: there are many Chekhov's guns just waiting to fire Like the fact that he never tips the ashes out of his cigarette.
Speaker 0: so the ashes are getting longer and longer and longer the whole time and The video is just depressing and amazing and everything all together at once.
Speaker 1: All right, so I'm sure everyone saw this on the internet the other day.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I just let you know in case you missed it.
Speaker 1: You're living under a rock.
Speaker 1: So id software, you know, they made Wolfenstein 3d then doom then quake then garbage.
Speaker 1: You know, there was John Carmack and John Romero the two John's right the important dudes who you know There's a lot of other important people there, but mostly the important dudes Those are the most well-known people.
Speaker 1: - yeah, and before they made the Wolfenstein 3d They made another game called commander keen and commander keen Was notable because it was just an MS-DOS platforming game and it's pretty good the series if you ever want to play it.
Speaker 0: It was often installed on like PCs in schools so you could kind of just play it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it was one of the first if not the first PC game that had full all directions smooth scrolling.
Speaker 1: now That's a big deal because on those primitive.
Speaker 1: Well now we consider them primitive.
Speaker 1: on those old computers even like 386 is Scrolling smoothly.
Speaker 1: It was not an easy thing to do.
Speaker 1: even on the NES Which was sort of designed for it was sort of tricky to do.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: the Atari I don't think even could do it.
Speaker 1: I guess pitfall right.
Speaker 1: people didn't scroll one screen at a time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't even scroll but anyway.
Speaker 1: So apparently before they made commander keen, you know, but they had developed the smooth scrolling already.
Speaker 1: They sent to Nintendo a demo they made when they weren't even called id software.
Speaker 1: yet They were called ideas from the deep which I guess became id later for ideas deep, you know Whatever They made a demo.
Speaker 1: It was pretty much just a direct copy of Mario 3 as best they could for the PC and they send it to Nintendo.
Speaker 1: We're like, hey, let us make a PC version of Mario 3 and Nintendo's like, yeah We're not interested in putting Nintendo games in anything but Nintendo Which shows you how far game at least game wise the console NES was ahead of PC.
Speaker 1: Of course NES couldn't do anything else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the NES was ahead of every Entertainment system in the world when it came out right even though it came out contemporarily to the Atari 7800.
Speaker 1: also consider that you know the mario 3. in the cartridge There was a lot more advanced chips than we're in say the mario 1 cartridge.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 1: But anyway the So here he released just the other day in honor of the anniversary of something Um Commander Kean's 25th anniversary.
Speaker 1: He uploaded video footage of that mario 3 that they made all those years ago.
Speaker 1: So it's like a historic, you know video of game, you know, very important game history video here for you to watch.
Speaker 0: you know, there's gonna be already.
Speaker 0: there will be a future when kids will go to a museum because their parents make them and In the museum be one of those corners.
Speaker 0: They play it like a short film on a loop and that film will be this game and a little history of like.
Speaker 1: Nintendo was a company that made game and the big NES Comparison next to it showing you how the MS-DOS computer was so primitive compared to the what the NES could do But also explaining the reasons.
Speaker 1: and you know, the NES couldn't couldn't run Mac or your -.
Speaker 0: yeah Yes, any s could kind of share.
Speaker 0: yeah In the moment book club to be determined.
Speaker 0: The old book club is the wheel of time.
Speaker 0: We have two panels about three panels that pack south two of which we can announce Atari game design designing game rules.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be at magfest.
Speaker 0: I'm like seven panels and everything else is coming up after the holidays.
Speaker 1: I actually remember having some Capcom games for DOS back in the day Super Street Fighter 2 and also Megaman X And they were both super legit.
Speaker 1: Like just the same as the real deal.
Speaker 0: I remember in elementary school 486 in elementary school having a Megaman that ran on the PC at the school that someone had installed But it didn't work very well.
Speaker 1: No one can make a man X for DOS was basically totally legit.
Speaker 1: Megaman X as far as I remember now.
Speaker 0: So every year the IFC shows pretty much all the the Ghibli movies Just on in a movie theater in New York City.
Speaker 1: That's what you get when you live in New York City.
Speaker 0: So every year every year we pick like two or three of them.
Speaker 0: Just go see him because why not?
Speaker 0: It's great to see these movies.
Speaker 1: No, I haven't.
Speaker 1: I didn't see.
Speaker 1: I mean I didn't do it last year.
Speaker 1: I haven't done it before ever.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've seen I've seen new ones.
Speaker 1: when they come out.
Speaker 0: I'd I do it every year.
Speaker 0: You don't always come with me.
Speaker 1: What did you see last year?
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: No, I think we went to see my.
Speaker 0: we saw Mononoke again.
Speaker 0: Okay, because I really like that one.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I saw the news story that this is happening and I and then I realized you know what?
Speaker 1: Haven't seen love to in like.
Speaker 1: I saw it once and I hardly remember it.
Speaker 1: All I remembered was there's a castle in the sky is a cool robot as a magic girl with a necklace with a Jimmy there's some mining town there's a kid who's the main character and There's the bad pirate people who are also funny and good pirate people.
Speaker 1: and that's all I remembered and that was all accurate.
Speaker 1: but Upon watching it again, which we did yesterday.
Speaker 1: I forgot 90% of this movie So I'm real glad I watched it again to remember that other 90%.
Speaker 0: I remembered pretty much everything that happens in the movie But what I did not remember was how much backstory there was told purely in the backgrounds of the movie.
Speaker 0: Like that I did not remember this movie
Speaker 1: and the very opening credits of the movie There's basically these background images that don't really move They're just backgrounds behind the credits and they tell you the whole history of like humanity in this world of LAPTA and what happened and how?
Speaker 1: They polluted the earth and then they to escape the polluted earth.
Speaker 1: with their advanced industrial technology they made floating cities in the sky like covering the whole earth and floating cities and buildings and then They am play gods and all the dollars happened, right?
Speaker 1: All of them were destroyed and they had to return to the earth.
Speaker 1: But the pollution was mostly gone, but not completely by then because you don't see like, you know Super many trees on the ground.
Speaker 0: you see some well, you know, it might not necessarily be that they're also in a mining area.
Speaker 0: It is equally easy to say that that was just a class stratification of society built up the god People with their empire living up in the sky with the technology War and me and play God and the city's crashed down and try gun style.
Speaker 1: people have to rebuild society but it's been 700 years and people have basically forgotten about that that there ever was this sky society.
Speaker 1: and You know, it's almost.
Speaker 1: it's a legend, right?
Speaker 1: It's like a myth that like oh, yeah is a floating city.
Speaker 1: Haha, not really.
Speaker 1: No only a few people believe in that most people don't.
Speaker 0: So in terms of the movie itself though, I mean, it's a 1986 Ghibli I have a feeling 1986 looks better than most animes from 1990 to 2000.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this movie is beautiful and holds up what.
Speaker 0: the only thing that does not hold up having watched it again in the theater Soundtrack is not great.
Speaker 1: You don't like the soundtrack.
Speaker 0: I like half the soundtrack.
Speaker 1: So the thing with the soundtrack is that it's you know, it's the same as Joe Hisaishi.
Speaker 1: Whatever who does all the Ghibli?
Speaker 1: Yeah, most the vast majority of the Ghibli music, right?
Speaker 1: And you know, it's really catchy.
Speaker 1: some of the songs I should the main song But the thing is is that for better or worse it really Seems like Nobuo Matsu did the music.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like it's real.
Speaker 1: the plot.
Speaker 1: Also, it's very fun.
Speaker 1: Like you could it's almost like they took a Final Fantasy plot You know really squished it down to fit in 90 minutes and took out a lot of like the side characters and stuff.
Speaker 1: and You know, just put it on the screen and it a lot of the music and scenes feel like Final Fantasy.
Speaker 1: very much more specific criticism like that bad guy is basically kefka and The girl is like, you know, what's her face from the magic girl you meet at the beginning?
Speaker 0: You don't remember any of those characters names.
Speaker 0: Do you?
Speaker 1: well, I'd rename them all Tara.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the girls basically Tara You know, whatever.
Speaker 0: so my specific issue is that half the soundtrack is orchestral or vocal or normal instruments and sounds like a score like a musical score and the other half is Synthesizers going doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo.
Speaker 1: I kind of like that sound but yes, it's not the better It's a lower quality sound.
Speaker 1: now I can make an argument and it's that's why it's also contributes to the Final Fantasy sounding nature of it.
Speaker 0: I can make an argument as to why the soundtrack has this very stark dichotomy because the Soundscape kind of does something similar, but I cannot say that Joe hishaishi Did that on purpose.
Speaker 0: the argument I would make if I was in like AP video and film and was trying to write a short essay on it is that all the motifs around the precursor technology and Lop to itself and the triant like all that stuff is refined and elegant and uses normal instruments and is normal orchestral music.
Speaker 0: all the fighting and Industrial and like current society sounds are all those sort of grading synthesizer unrefined Sort of like not there yet like they're unrefined and raw and industrializing.
Speaker 0: That's the best I could come up with.
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: wasn't paying attention to know if that's actually true or
Speaker 0: soundtrack is very rough When like the normal people are fighting and doing their thing and the soundtrack is very smooth only went and smooth and elegant only either when Lop is coming up or When the spirit of humanity and the like very simple non confrontational background scenes are happening.
Speaker 1: I don't know if that's true or not.
Speaker 1: I had to like watch it again and like with notes to figure that out.
Speaker 0: all the machines make very odd Sounds as well Like the sounds that the machine like the flying machines make are.
Speaker 0: just you have to watch the movie like they're.
Speaker 0: they're odd sound effects.
Speaker 0: yeah, of course the wind rises does something very similar.
Speaker 0: the sounds that the planes make are very Very weird as I think we talked about when we did the review of that movie.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean in general it's still a really great jibbly movie.
Speaker 1: You know the plot isn't complicated and it's really straightforward and but I really love you know Terrible secret of space like is there a lot of it?
Speaker 1: obviously there is.
Speaker 1: they're gonna go there.
Speaker 1: Oh, they went there, but like it's not one of those things were like they go there at the end and they leave it being mysterious.
Speaker 1: It's like they get there and then they spend a lot of time there before the movies over and you pretty much learn everything There is to learn about it.
Speaker 1: You know, they reveal the full secret of space.
Speaker 1: They show you everything.
Speaker 0: The movie has a very epic feel to it And I think part of that is because it is a full two hours plus But I mean it as the only.
Speaker 1: that's sort of weird though because it escalates too quickly, right?
Speaker 1: It's like girl falls out of the sky meets the main character kid And then it just takes off like through the roof and it the progression is a little bit Exponential
Speaker 0: I think to
Speaker 1: the point where it's a little hard to believe suddenly like really that quickly you're see.
Speaker 0: I would make a counter-argument that the the story of La Pita and I think the movie is Moderately unique because there aren't that many films that do this to the extent that La Pita did anime or otherwise.
Speaker 0: There is a huge epic like Tolkien.
Speaker 0: ask volumes of this giant multi-generational Wheel of Time nonsense epic story and That whole story is told to you through Individual things that you see in the background of this movie Like little bits like the miners are all mining in this place in the beginning and then as the camera zooms back you realize that Hey They're in the middle of all these Abandoned mines from the old days like all the.
Speaker 0: all these buildings are abandoned These are old mines.
Speaker 0: and then you get the impression Oh, they're mining there because they assume these old mines had something in them and they can't find anything.
Speaker 0: There's nothing valuable.
Speaker 0: so they don't understand why these mines are there.
Speaker 0: But then you learn from the old dude that there is stuff there.
Speaker 0: The volisite is everywhere.
Speaker 1: They just don't recognize it or know how to use it exactly.
Speaker 1: even people back in the olden days though Who weren't La Pita might have known what it was and didn't know how to you know.
Speaker 0: And if you just watch in the background you see like civilization is like Clinging to the edges of all these old abandoned things and sort of even after 700 years.
Speaker 1: They've figured out a bunch, right?
Speaker 1: They can fly again and they do all it but they haven't figured out Nearly close to everything that used to exist.
Speaker 1: and that's always the best.
Speaker 1: the fantasy world where is the existing freaker zero?
Speaker 0: It's like the lock Lamora thing Which is especially highlighted when they get to La Pita.
Speaker 0: and then there's the scenes in the end where the weapon systems get activated and then it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like a player of games where yes, the lot the La Putin technology is So far beyond.
Speaker 1: I mean it takes down that battlecruiser in like the battle So is presented as like the biggest scariest most dangerous thing that the you know, existing human society is Military technology.
Speaker 1: and it isn't even like.
Speaker 1: it's not even like a contest.
Speaker 1: It's just like robots boom done.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like and you know there isn't even Suspense as to whether it's gonna be a contest because the power of lava is so great.
Speaker 0: He drops the nuke and he's like, oh, yeah, I can nuke too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the one robot that they captured That's like broken that wakes up and oh that destroys like the whole castle.
Speaker 1: It's missing a hand and a foot and it destroys the entire castle on its own.
Speaker 0: and it's barely even trying And you know holding back in a lot of media of having like really seeing that tech disconnect right there.
Speaker 0: But that is the client like the pinnacle of this huge story That's just told through little background bits little things.
Speaker 0: The main character the girl says little Insights you get from old people in the books and the sky and the guy who should be king and all that nonsense.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the actual story of the movie Starts in media res kind of like giant robo.
Speaker 0: I mean.
Speaker 0: it starts with the girl was already kidnapped and you don't know who the bad guys are and then there's a chase and All that stuff happens right away.
Speaker 0: So it starts in the middle of that epic story and it basically shows you the end of that epic story Like the very end when the last castle in the sky falls down.
Speaker 1: Spoilers, I guess What else is there to say about this besides?
Speaker 1: yeah, you should watch it.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm curious actually in the forum like how many of you you know your anime fans I assume if you listen to geek knives, but If you guys actually seen this movie, yeah I don't want.
Speaker 1: it's not the best jibbly movie But it's like the.
Speaker 1: I think in terms of bestness to least watchness the thing has like the worst ratio easily.
Speaker 0: I mean my opinion of this movie now that I've seen it again recently is a way higher than it was before.
Speaker 1: I remember really loving the hell out of it before.
Speaker 1: so my opinion my opinion level didn't really change.
Speaker 1: I just forgot most of what happened in it.
Speaker 0: But if you never like it like trust me when you watch this movie Pay more.
Speaker 1: you really need anyone to sell you this.
Speaker 0: No I'm just saying pay more attention to the backgrounds than the action because the backgrounds tell this really interesting story.
Speaker 0: But in terms of the action I This movie does something that Ghibli's did in the old days.
Speaker 0: They don't seem to do as much now, but it has this sort of like really light-hearted Like all in good fun violence.
Speaker 1: Well, okay.
Speaker 1: So in the early part of the movie There's tons and tons of crazy action going on that lots of violence.
Speaker 1: the main character the kid almost dies.
Speaker 1: The opening scene is violent.
Speaker 1: this girl just falls off of you know Skyship and airship right and there's all kinds of guns and shooting right away But not as you know.
Speaker 1: These pirates come and board the airship trying to kidnap her and steal the Jimmy firing cannons at each other.
Speaker 1: He's the evil men in black or she or you assume her evil men in black as they kidnapped the girl to begin with.
Speaker 1: They're shooting at the pirates.
Speaker 1: You're not sure which ones are good or bad, but the girls trying to escape everyone.
Speaker 1: So you figure they're both bad right and they're shooting at each other, but no one gets hurt or dies.
Speaker 1: Really it's you know in not in a permanent way and the movie continues to sort of keep that thing going.
Speaker 1: where people are like Do you know is avoiding what would normally be certain death?
Speaker 0: Like you know kid almost falls off a cliff just because he's fucking around like a time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like Looney Tunes level We're like they're on a train.
Speaker 1: It's going really fast.
Speaker 1: The train tracks are collapsing right behind the train, but they're not falling You know, they almost fall off things like ten times.
Speaker 1: they managed to grab on Realistically and survive like a whole bunch of times like no one's getting hurt.
Speaker 1: No one's dying.
Speaker 1: There's tons of fighting going on.
Speaker 1: the best fight whole town breaks out into a huge brawl when the pirate Take turns.
Speaker 0: punching each other in the stomach is one of my favorite scenes in this movie.
Speaker 1: It's such a good scene.
Speaker 0: I should make a gif out of that.
Speaker 1: like no one no one gets permanently injured or dead or anything from any of this.
Speaker 0: and then Later in the movie suddenly, they're like they stop and they're like, well people are dying now But they animate it the same way except before They'd show like GI Joe like literally every soldier running out of a thing before it blows up.
Speaker 0: and then at the end of the movie they show Everyone died.
Speaker 1: Well, I just like boop.
Speaker 1: well I think what it is that if I'm not mistaken, you know all the only violence that kills people is Violence from lava to technology.
Speaker 1: I don't think human technology kills anyone in this movie, right?
Speaker 0: Well that violence of the lava technology it also.
Speaker 0: it follows the men in sunglasses.
Speaker 0: the men in black there's like like there.
Speaker 0: there's a certain level of Humanity in the normal people in the town and in the pirates but there isn't humanity in the men in black.
Speaker 0: one of them's a labootin or whatever and the other ones are just toadies.
Speaker 0: but The when they're involved there is real danger.
Speaker 0: There's like this cold risk of death this other alien thing that is not present in the rest of society.
Speaker 0: They can.
Speaker 1: they're apparently important enough to boss the army around and mess with the army.
Speaker 1: But and the army is way powerful, but the army is also portrayed as being way stupid because their general is like a doof.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that guy is pretty doofy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course They'd probably better off it.
Speaker 0: He had won than if the other guy had won.
Speaker 1: He was just looting.
Speaker 1: He wasn't.
Speaker 0: I Mean you're an anime fan.
Speaker 0: If you haven't seen this movie, you should a hundred percent go see it.
Speaker 1: I mean what pseudo Ghibli movie is not must-see anime.
Speaker 1: Ah Ocean why don't we do Studio Ghibli ranking?
Speaker 0: we should just sit down.
Speaker 0: We'll both sit and try now do right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let me pull up the list.
Speaker 0: All right, we both got the list up.
Speaker 0: So I've seen almost all of these.
Speaker 1: I mean, we're mostly covering the major ones, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, we don't.
Speaker 1: I guess I haven't seen only yesterday.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 1: This is the first one.
Speaker 1: It was the first one Love.
Speaker 1: it is the first Studio Ghibli full-length.
Speaker 0: I was like only yesterday.
Speaker 0: Is it the first one?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah It's the first one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least on the list of films.
Speaker 1: It's the first one.
Speaker 0: I like La Pita a lot.
Speaker 1: It's way up.
Speaker 0: It's hard to say though because I would have ranked La Pita much lower based on having seen it once a long time ago.
Speaker 0: But now that I just saw it, I don't think it might.
Speaker 1: it's ranking is changing But I noticed a lot of things.
Speaker 0: I probably would have put it below Kiki's before but now I put it Significantly above Kiki's.
Speaker 0: but I have not seen Kiki's in a long time either.
Speaker 1: I seen Kiki's recently enough to remember.
Speaker 1: I think it might be equal that they're probably next to each other.
Speaker 0: It's hard to say because Scott, you know precursor technology is my jam to a deep degree.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm just evaluating the quality of the movie not my personal taste.
Speaker 0: So quality from like a cinematic like movie structure Spirited away might have to just win.
Speaker 1: that way is definitely I mean easy number one spirited away Is it if you're going from a purely like technical storytelling as an easy number one for me?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've seen it the most.
Speaker 0: also, you know, the wind rises has.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen that one.
Speaker 0: I enjoyed deeply because it is so different from every other Miyazaki movie and is a very uncomfortable movie to watch very uncomfortable.
Speaker 0: Earthsea has to be the bottom.
Speaker 1: Earthsea is the bottom.
Speaker 0: That movie was so awful.
Speaker 1: So Spirited Away is number one.
Speaker 1: Number two is a tough fight between Whisper of the Heart and Grave of the Fireflies.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I like Whispers of the Heart a lot.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's necessarily the greatest movie.
Speaker 0: I like it a lot for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 0: Whisper of the Heart is so good But I also really like Porco Rosso despite the fact that it is flawed in a lot of ways Right.
Speaker 1: I mean, I like Porco Rosso a lot But that's gonna be a little bit lower than some of these other ones.
Speaker 0: Why though?
Speaker 0: because quality chart from a like does rim like it.
Speaker 0: it might be higher But from a like.
Speaker 0: Porco Rosso's story has a few issues and leaves a few threads not Sufficiently tied off in my.
Speaker 1: well, it doesn't make it a worse movie or anything.
Speaker 1: I might actually put Mononoke number two, though Mononoke's Mononoke is in the mix and in like the three slot with the castle in the sky.
Speaker 0: Mononoke also has the complex narrative.
Speaker 1: The Totoro and the Kiki.
Speaker 0: Multiple characters and multiple sort of like competing factions that are all good and bad Simultaneously.
Speaker 0: like it's there is no.
Speaker 0: those are good guys.
Speaker 0: These are bad guys.
Speaker 1: Lapida, Totoro, Kiki and Mononoke are like this four Fecta that are like all really equal And it's hard to separate them and they're all in like the three slot area.
Speaker 1: I would put.
Speaker 1: those are like the solid.
Speaker 1: what you expect from Ghibli movie You know Totally good way awesome, but I can't really find any way to like put one above the other.
Speaker 0: I think I put Wind Rises and Grave of the Fireflies in the same category.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean they're you know more serious subject matter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean Grave of the Fireflies is so good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've seen Wind Rises.
Speaker 0: Wind Rises is also very good, but it's artistic in a different way.
Speaker 0: Mmm, you need to see it and then we could talk about that more.
Speaker 0: The cat returns is just fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cat returns isn't that good.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not bad It's good, but it's not.
Speaker 1: it's not at the level of the foursome I just mentioned.
Speaker 0: would you put the cat returns at the same level as like Ponyo or Arrietty?
Speaker 1: I Think it might be just slightly under those just due to production value and such.
Speaker 0: Nah, you know, but Arrietty had way high production values and was good but flawed in a lot of ways.
Speaker 1: Ponyo Arrietty, you know house moving castle pretty similar.
Speaker 0: house moving castle might be a little bit better Yeah, but at the same time house moving castle ignoring books or any other media about it Not necessarily the best narrative.
Speaker 1: No, I think Porco Rosso goes in between the four-factor and the Ponyos and the Earthseas Right.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like right under the four-factor and then I Guess what's what are we missing here?
Speaker 0: So I have not seen Kaguya unfortunately, so I can't.
Speaker 1: Kaguya is really good.
Speaker 1: It might be better than the Arriettys and the Ponyos But underneath the Porco Rosso's I need to see it because everyone's going nuts about it.
Speaker 0: But I saw song of the sea.
Speaker 1: the problem with princess Kaguya is that it's so good But the pacing of it is a bit slow towards the second half and it drags a bit and that really brings the whole thing down.
Speaker 1: But you know the art and the story is so good.
Speaker 0: You know what from a filmmaking perspective I think when Marnie was there actually needs to be pretty high on the list because that might be like tied with the Porco Rosso's.
Speaker 0: when Marnie was there set a really interesting level of tension and it but it wasn't like a Hitchcock movie tension, but I like it.
Speaker 0: I had this sense of dread throughout a lot of the movie because It misdirects you in a lot of ways as to what it's actually about.
Speaker 1: And I also had a slight pacing issue of slowness, but not as bad as Kaguya did.
Speaker 0: Well the slowness and Marnie I think is also intentional to heighten the tension where you can't quite figure out what's going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I would definitely put Marnie above, you know, the the castle the Ponyo the Ariete.
Speaker 0: yeah, I just Marnie was just a very well-constructed movie and Seeing it to the end.
Speaker 0: It reminds me of a lot of the old great just live-action movies I like from the 40s and 50s.
Speaker 1: I didn't see Poppy Hill.
Speaker 1: I Didn't see Ocean waves.
Speaker 0: I saw Poppy Hill.
Speaker 0: Poppy Hill was pretty good, but it wasn't great.
Speaker 1: I enjoyed it.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen my neighbors.
Speaker 0: the Yamada's Poppy Hill was.
Speaker 0: It has this moment where you think oh, that's the twist.
Speaker 0: Okay, and then oh, that's not the twist double twist.
Speaker 1: And you think are there any that I didn't see only yesterday?
Speaker 1: Is there anything else we didn't comment on?
Speaker 1: There's just about all of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah So yeah, yeah, if you haven't seen Lava to go see it I mean pretty much every I mean even though you know, we were just ranking them from best to worst.
Speaker 1: They're pretty much all worth watching one exception except for the Earthsea one.
Speaker 1: so Don't watch the Earthsea one.
Speaker 1: watch every other.
Speaker 1: one of these things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even the ones I haven't seen I can pretty confident that they're worth what?
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and my comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: and the patrons this week in order of the amount of money.
Speaker 0: They give us our.
Speaker 0: Nicholas Brando Rebecca Dunn James David white Christian coons Jess mechanical mind testing.
Speaker 0: one, two three Phil all rich Amanda to shed Renee from New Zealand Robert Lee Ryan Perrin drew open Lander rare Laval Brian Cedroni Rochelle, Monta Nona Finn Eric silver odd rim eats poop kinetic man William Eisen rose Aaron Cerise Chris midkiff Chris Knox flame dark fire Samuel Cordery Daniel Redmond Chris Haddad Doug Schneider Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: the show might have seemed a little Abbreviated and some pauses more so than usual.
Speaker 0: That's because I've been fighting off one fuck of a cold for the last week and Not gonna lie.
Speaker 0: I feel like complete and utter shit today.
Speaker 0: So That's why I'm hopped up on goofballs.
Speaker 0: well I'm hopped up on pseudo-federan guai fennison a bunch of image you a whole bunch of cough drops and some lorata Dean.
Speaker 0: So Yeah otherwise Don't think I have anything special for you cuz I kind of just want to go to bed tonight.
Speaker 0: I might do a nice subdued play of undertale cuz you guys been waiting for it.
Speaker 0: But otherwise It's bedtime.
Speaker 0: So I leave you with your moment of in this case a kind of Zen like experience.
Speaker 0: He thought he bought Oh Oh Oh Oh Can't eat Oh.