Speaker 0: It's Thursday June 11th 2015.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I am a sky and this is an episode of geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We're going to talk about luggage Literally the most exciting topic we could come up with tonight.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I was gonna talk about my blisters as like the opening bit No one wants to hear about.
Speaker 1: your medical problems is also as disgusting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the saddest part about the blisters is they like they were better.
Speaker 1: now You're talking you're gonna talk about him, but now you are actually talking about.
Speaker 1: So when I was a kid, you're not actually gonna talk about them.
Speaker 1: pass by it.
Speaker 0: So when you were a kid, I won't talk about the blisters anymore.
Speaker 0: But when you were a kid and you like cut yourself or something your mom just had like bactein or peroxide Boring.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but what about?
Speaker 0: for you don't use Neosporin for the clean and disinfect phase of an injury?
Speaker 1: I usually just pet a band-aid squirted Neosporin on it and put it right on there didn't even like wash the wound Maybe with some water not some like bactein or something.
Speaker 0: No, okay.
Speaker 0: anyway Way back when I cut the tip of my finger off and had to get a reattached I had you know that sad old story where the hospital sucked and wouldn't treat me and after four hours There's an episode of geek nights with that story.
Speaker 1: So we don't need to tell that any other.
Speaker 0: so the next day when I went into a clinic and I was like Yeah, I cut my fucking finger off in the hospital wouldn't help me.
Speaker 0: and the guy was like, okay Well, I'll attach it you like fixed it.
Speaker 0: But first he's like that shit's probably infected as fuck.
Speaker 0: So he took my hand and he told me put my finger like just totally in.
Speaker 1: this is this is gonna hurt like a mother.
Speaker 1: Fuck big bowl of iodine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and he was like just keep it in there.
Speaker 0: I'll be back in like ten minutes.
Speaker 0: So when I injured myself in the way, I won't discuss any further.
Speaker 0: I went to clean out my wounds and Because I don't have a mom who lives with me.
Speaker 0: I literally didn't own anything.
Speaker 1: Well, but he was there to kiss your boo-boo exactly.
Speaker 0: So I ordered on Amazon a giant jug of betadine for like five bucks.
Speaker 1: You just buy it at the drugstore around the corner.
Speaker 0: There's no drugstore around the corner.
Speaker 0: Oh, I live somewhere with the drugstore on the and even then actually the Duane Reade by my office does not carry Betadine or anything good.
Speaker 0: they carry just iodine which isn't really the greatest thing to use.
Speaker 0: they carry peroxide which is Indicated you shouldn't use it.
Speaker 0: That's not.
Speaker 0: the internet says you should not use peroxide on wounds.
Speaker 0: That is that is garbage advice from whoever told you to use it.
Speaker 0: We figured out like 15 or 20 years ago.
Speaker 0: the peroxide does more harm than good.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like for real Don't use peroxide.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Why did you think you could use peroxide?
Speaker 0: Who told you that?
Speaker 1: the whole internet?
Speaker 0: Well, they're wrong.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I got my betadine.
Speaker 0: Now I forgot what my other open.
Speaker 0: if it was I was gonna talk about something else too, okay That's the whole story.
Speaker 1: You bought betadine.
Speaker 0: I bought betadine.
Speaker 1: Great, congratulations, right?
Speaker 0: Right, right.
Speaker 1: so if I cover cut myself in your house when we I can splash betadine in your face.
Speaker 0: relaunched gig nights on iTunes after we Were delisted for a little while because of like our feed had some issues we had to fix once it got back up, uh I noticed that there's a bunch of reviews of geek nights from like 2005 Mm-hmm, and we had like five stars and most of the reviews.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of them.
Speaker 0: We're like, yeah, this is a great show.
Speaker 0: A lot of those people are still listeners or at least are still like hanging out in the forum even though they don't listen anymore, but the fuck.
Speaker 0: but there was a whole bunch of negative reviews that all came in around the same time and They all were from different usernames, but they all complained about the same three things in a different order.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: and Then I started googling around for like reviews of geek nights and there was an era of a few months where a ton of people Who may or may not have all been the same person?
Speaker 0: We're giving geek nights negative reviews and writing these really long rants about how shitty we are.
Speaker 0: Anywhere they could do this.
Speaker 1: We finally got a hater.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I think it's one hater I couldn't tell but it was weird because what they complained about was these guys act like they know about everything But they don't.
Speaker 1: we don't we didn't?
Speaker 1: we just really.
Speaker 1: we just read a lot of internet.
Speaker 1: therefore we can say things that we don't know anything about because you read Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: we Fucking swear.
Speaker 0: they were really mad that we swear on the show from New York continue But there they were like really in fucking New York City.
Speaker 0: multiple of these fucking reviews had paragraphs dedicated to.
Speaker 0: I wish They wouldn't use such like vile language.
Speaker 0: It's horrible.
Speaker 0: Like I can't listen because of this don't move to New York continue.
Speaker 0: and three they were mad that we interrupt each other and Argue, that's what the show's about.
Speaker 0: Okay, but they all complained in such a way.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure one motherfucker got mad at us for something back in 2006 and spent like a month Writing these reviews all over the internet trying desperately to drown out our five stars down to know six.
Speaker 1: I thought it was a recent hater.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: No, this is back in.
Speaker 0: Oh six.
Speaker 1: Come on I need a hater now someone to you know, like egg on and make their life miserable.
Speaker 0: No one hates us anymore.
Speaker 0: The only people who hate us now are that guys who stumble on our that guy panel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, come on that guy bring it bring it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll take you on.
Speaker 0: the guy who was mad that we spoiled bunny drop in our anime panel.
Speaker 1: I saved you bro.
Speaker 1: Yeah, thank me.
Speaker 0: Oh and the people who remember our biggest public failure, I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's Bring the hate I'd love.
Speaker 0: I love the fact I ground with you.
Speaker 0: fuck those guys who did that On a recent episode like a thing.
Speaker 0: I put him on YouTube.
Speaker 0: There's a comment and it referenced that obliquely and I was proud enough to our messes.
Speaker 0: the guy like dude.
Speaker 0: Good good slam good slam dude.
Speaker 0: There's a good one.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, it's Thursday it's the lounge.
Speaker 0: you can talk about whatever.
Speaker 0: it's your mom My mom would hang out in the lounge.
Speaker 1: So there's a big fiasco going down on reddit.
Speaker 1: so much a fiasco that even my co-workers was talking about it on slack today.
Speaker 0: It's amazing in the random channel because normal people who aren't internet at all will never know this happens.
Speaker 0: No or care smart people would see it as oh wow reddit did a smart thing.
Speaker 0: Good job Mm-hmm, but yet this became the biggest internet shitstorm because of that guy, right?
Speaker 1: Well, okay.
Speaker 1: So here's the explain is what's going down?
Speaker 1: so reddit is a website that is where you post links or just write text and then Upvote and downvote things.
Speaker 1: but things sort of get automatically lower scores as time goes on.
Speaker 1: so newer thing.
Speaker 1: So in order for something to be highly ranked and you know Very prominent on the site.
Speaker 1: It has to be new and hot with lots of votes.
Speaker 1: Also reddit does the interesting thing of this subreddits so you can actually go to reddit and if you make an account or go to The home page without being logged in and or fresh new account.
Speaker 1: You only see certain things.
Speaker 1: There is actually way more stuff That's completely hidden from you and you might not even know about and I didn't even know about until using reddit for a while.
Speaker 0: I mean that's the only good part of reddit like the Rangers subreddit, right?
Speaker 1: Is every single post is actually under a subreddit which is basically a forum that somebody a human being that's not a reddit employee created and Curates.
Speaker 1: so you can go.
Speaker 1: you can go to reddit and be like make new subreddit.
Speaker 1: geek nights haters.
Speaker 1: Geek nights exist because I made it but geek nights haters doesn't.
Speaker 1: so you can make that.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it doesn't.
Speaker 1: You could make.
Speaker 0: I don't know how to get nice right it.
Speaker 0: I should go post some stuff in it.
Speaker 0: You
Speaker 1: can go make a geek nights haters subreddit and then you know People could subscribe to it in which case any posts in it would show up on their home reddit home pages when they're logged in Whatnot right, so there's subreddits for every fucking thing no matter how specific your interest is, right?
Speaker 1: There's one for bicycling that I subscribe to.
Speaker 1: there's one specific to New York City bicycling.
Speaker 1: It's NYC bike.
Speaker 1: It's only things about New York City bicycling.
Speaker 1: Usually cops are giving out tickets at this intersection.
Speaker 1: today construction on this bridge Which how do I get to this place like really useful stuff?
Speaker 1: Yeah anyway.
Speaker 1: So the reddit, you know has been very very Permissive in what kinds of content it allows.
Speaker 0: I mean like they let the red pill exists Which is literally just like.
Speaker 0: how do we remove women from society, right?
Speaker 1: It used to be that, you know, the only rule was like no child porn or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: But there's subreddits out there where there's like horrible horrible stuff.
Speaker 1: Was it space something space dicks?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know off like rotten.com times a million is out there somewhere right is porn?
Speaker 1: There's everything right.
Speaker 1: anything you could imagine is there but also perfectly normal stuff like NYC bike, right?
Speaker 1: it's just about biking in New York City.
Speaker 1: if you subscribe to only subreddits such as New York City bike or your favorite sports team or Your favorite band or your favorite video game, right?
Speaker 1: Then you're only gonna see stuff about that and you're not gonna see the general reddit community.
Speaker 1: and that is the right way to Use reddit right.
Speaker 1: but in the general reddit community There's mad dramas because the new CEO of reddit and there's some new policies, which is they're going to crack down not on Content that is offensive but against any communities that are Actually harassing and attacking people.
Speaker 1: Right, so they found a few subreddits and a few users that were literally harassing You know and you know doing direct, you know threats and attacks against people and they destroyed those subreddits.
Speaker 1: And they you know hell-banned which is you know, you don't you beer bad, but you don't know it.
Speaker 0: so there's a side to some really bad users.
Speaker 0: someone made a Wikipedia article on hell band and then The reddit butthurt brigade went and edited the article to try to make it seem like there are legal Implications that doing that kind of shadow ban is actually illegal in a violation of some federal law.
Speaker 1: It's reddit's website Yeah, the website.
Speaker 1: they can do whatever the fuck they want on their own way.
Speaker 0: I went actually for the first time in years.
Speaker 0: I edited Wikipedia and I just deleted all that shit.
Speaker 0: I made a comment like these shit posters are shitting all over Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it looks like it's still good.
Speaker 1: So anyway, anyway, so this created a shitstorm amongst the shitheads.
Speaker 1: If the people who are you know upset and they're like, it's as though a million shitheads With a joke you tweet it you then can't say the joke out loud.
Speaker 0: I don't think.
Speaker 0: later subscribe to me on Twitter.
Speaker 0: You should at Shazar like cliffs.
Speaker 1: Not a joke is bad from Trigon.
Speaker 1: I mean if I go and make a tweet that's like chickens cross the road How to get the other side and then later on I go here him My chicken cross the road.
Speaker 0: It's like that'd be a good idea.
Speaker 0: I call you on Twitter.
Speaker 0: At Shazar you should totally follow me.
Speaker 1: You should follow me and unfollow him because he's just tweeting stupid jokes that he already said and also he tweeted the joke.
Speaker 1: It's a really long conversations with people that don't belong on Twitter.
Speaker 1: That's gonna fill your tweet feed up like ding ding ding ding.
Speaker 1: Well behaved Twitter's.
Speaker 0: you will only see that if you subscribe to both me and the person I'm arguing with which is usually Gerald.
Speaker 0: We don't argue though lately.
Speaker 0: It's all just like hey, I'm right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you are right.
Speaker 1: tweets too much anyway a lot.
Speaker 0: I've only tweeted 30,000 times.
Speaker 0: That's too many times.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, I got like a lot of followers.
Speaker 1: big shitstorm going on in the reddit.
Speaker 1: These people clearly have not read the XKCD comic that tells you.
Speaker 1: but freedom of speech is only mean something if the government is Gonna arrest you for saying something right reddit can do whatever the fuck they want on their website.
Speaker 1: You can't do a goddamn thing about it because it's not your website.
Speaker 0: What's hilarious, but also sad is that The the shitheads are such a quantity of people that their mass exodus from reddit actually took down like at least two Reddit clone sites.
Speaker 0: with the traffic there.
Speaker 0: are that many of these people.
Speaker 1: Yep, probably.
Speaker 0: I don't know what like.
Speaker 0: I Don't know what the projected future of shit header II is at this point because as much as I've always liked to believe that These people are a vocal minority the sheer number and quantity of them They're
Speaker 1: a minority, but they are still a high quantity and also the quantity of them on the internet Proportional is much higher than their proportional number in general society.
Speaker 0: So you say that but I have two pieces of information that might.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they counted or not one.
Speaker 0: The more local the news website is the worse that becomes.
Speaker 1: that's true.
Speaker 0: You look at like the newspaper who are shitty have small worlds and small world outlooks But it is every small world filled with enough of these people to where they're actually a big percentage of society.
Speaker 1: Well, no because in that small world.
Speaker 1: there are people with large world outlooks right their personal world is large Even though they like like.
Speaker 1: for example, I live in a particular area of Astoria, right?
Speaker 1: My apartment building could be seen as a small world But I have my my life my world the world of me is large.
Speaker 1: It is internet large.
Speaker 1: It is pecs.
Speaker 1: You know, it's it's big.
Speaker 1: But let's say there was an old lady living in my apartment building and she is living in this same small World that I am also in a part of.
Speaker 1: but her world outlook is small.
Speaker 1: The apartment building is like the thing she is focusing on in her mind, you know her.
Speaker 1: She's only seeing a very small part of the world.
Speaker 1: She doesn't have a global thought or a global mind and that is why Such a person who doesn't exist did my apartment buildings and I really have old people in it.
Speaker 1: But yeah, right It's got a person would be a shitty person right a kind of person, you know.
Speaker 1: So there's some small town.
Speaker 1: are all the people living in that small town shitty?
Speaker 1: No There's a lot of people living in the small town or just fine people.
Speaker 1: But someone who is in that small town and cares about that small town to where that's the thing that they're focusing on.
Speaker 1: That's the thing that they think about.
Speaker 1: that occupies their mind is a small minded person who is a shithead.
Speaker 1: So here's my problem and that's the person who's gonna go to the small town.
Speaker 0: If you live in a small town in a small world Then if you go to any small media you encounter this stuff all the time, but if you live a global life This stuff is everywhere and you encounter it across all those places.
Speaker 0: Regardless no matter what level you live at the percentage of those people seems to be constant.
Speaker 0: So my the.
Speaker 0: the other example of this is Another big internet thing that was happening a couple days ago.
Speaker 0: that sort of culminated.
Speaker 0: There's a. there's a town of Lancaster in Pennsylvania Resenka Canas.
Speaker 0: Nope a different Lancaster So not the Amish Lancaster side.
Speaker 0: note you can tell when a website especially a news site is a small world When it doesn't say what state something's in or assumes that you know the name of a town.
Speaker 0: So I'm looking at the website.
Speaker 0: There's no way to know.
Speaker 0: this is from New York.
Speaker 0: unless you happen to notice the tiny Buffalo calm in the upper left there could be another Buffalo.
Speaker 1: But yeah, if it's Buffalo calm Buffalo Buffalo, you know how many buffaloes are in that sentence?
Speaker 0: I think nine.
Speaker 0: not sure though.
Speaker 0: I think it's nine.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I'll look it up and you don't know where to pause and where to inflect either.
Speaker 0: You could just do it randomly.
Speaker 0: Inflection has no bearing on meaning in English except for maybe turning something into a question.
Speaker 1: There's commas in that sentence though.
Speaker 0: commas can be omitted in almost all cases except the Oxford comma which must never be omitted.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so this town Lancaster had a problem.
Speaker 0: They have like a middle school team called the Redskins.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they should change that and there's actually a lot of rise.
Speaker 1: It wasn't changed already.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, so there's a lot of.
Speaker 1: I also want to point out how come you know These Redskins teams are getting all this pressure.
Speaker 1: Shouldn't the Cleveland Indians be the number one fucking target.
Speaker 0: Yes, the Cleveland Indians I mean, they're not.
Speaker 1: they're a target, but they should be number fucking one.
Speaker 0: You know what it is redskins as a name is more offensive than their logo than in the Cleveland Indians.
Speaker 0: Indians at least at least you could argue is in the vernacular as a generic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the Cleveland Indians mascot fuck.
Speaker 0: no Well, I mean no one cares about Chicago Blackhawks, right people do but not as much and I figured out why I was looking into That a lot actually.
Speaker 0: All right, so it seems like one.
Speaker 0: it's at least it's named after a World War two regiment.
Speaker 0: Oh, so there's at least a historical reason.
Speaker 1: now that regiment was named after the tribe Blackhawk I don't think is an insult itself, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a little appropriative like you can't deny Yeah, but it's it unlike the Redskins which is just like.
Speaker 0: why don't I have the like Utah black faces?
Speaker 1: I mean, so is Yankees.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time it's okay because that's punching up not punching down.
Speaker 1: It would be a while but if it was Yankees and the team was in the south the Atlanta Yankees That would be a problem.
Speaker 0: They can punch up all they want.
Speaker 0: Okay so anyway, but With the Blackhawks - at least their logo is just like - Tom Hogg's it's not just an offensive the dude's head But he's you know, he's sort of normal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though.
Speaker 0: They did have.
Speaker 0: well, they had a mascot called Thomas Hawk But he's gone now.
Speaker 0: They have minimized his involvement.
Speaker 0: So While their name is still problematic They're at least like they've addressed it to a degree to where it's not like the Redskins who can go fuck themselves, right?
Speaker 0: so this team?
Speaker 0: There are a lot of Native Americans who live in that part of New York.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no tons and all the other schools in the area Don't want to play games with this team because of their offensive name.
Speaker 1: Good job other schools and the kids.
Speaker 0: I applaud you and a lot of the kids in the school Didn't want to have an offensive Nate team name so they wouldn't join the team.
Speaker 1: Good job middle school kids for being so educated despite living in a small town.
Speaker 0: So an awesome girl Renae like came up with a new logo and a new mascot the Lancaster legends and it's just awesome night guy with a giant ass sword.
Speaker 1: I approve of Knights with giant ass swords.
Speaker 0: So there is.
Speaker 0: Karissa Godziak made this logo.
Speaker 0: the school loved it.
Speaker 0: The kids loved it.
Speaker 1: She drew it with her art skills.
Speaker 0: I think so even better.
Speaker 1: So also Knights with big ass swords.
Speaker 1: the adults The parents in town her parents or other parents are all the parents had parents.
Speaker 0: They had the town meeting where they voted to like change this name like this.
Speaker 1: Why do they need a town meeting?
Speaker 1: just fucking do.
Speaker 0: it might have been a school board.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: kid the principal of the school just like done.
Speaker 0: Probably not.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's small-town crap.
Speaker 1: How would I?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: anything is cool, but I have to decide.
Speaker 0: we'd hope we tried to get involved in Beacon politics.
Speaker 1: Just couldn't figure out how go to town council during the day when old people are there.
Speaker 0: Yeah so, uh Basically, they had this public meeting and they voted I think it was the school board or whatever to change the name and She gave a little speech about like why it's important to change how.
Speaker 0: her logo was great Nice speech.
Speaker 0: the other parents brought out the Heil Hitler's and it descended to chaos.
Speaker 1: Yes, what the fuck.
Speaker 1: of course in a small town like that there's someone with a small mind.
Speaker 1: There's someone with a small enough mind to go to the school board meeting of Lancaster, New York.
Speaker 0: They turn their bet.
Speaker 1: they stood there And they're an adult and they took time out of their day to go to the school board meeting of Lancaster New York, that is a small person.
Speaker 0: So a bunch of the parents her stood up or just like adults who live in the town Yeah Don't live in town already involved in the school stood up.
Speaker 1: care about what the man got.
Speaker 0: little girl is giving her speech and turned Their back on her like those cops.
Speaker 1: They care about the mascot of a middle school in this tiny-ass town.
Speaker 1: That's important enough to them to take time out of their day to go to a meeting and make a statement.
Speaker 1: That is a sad individual.
Speaker 0: So read this article.
Speaker 1: I mean even let's say in New York right the middle school near me Right had an awesome night as their mascot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they wanted to change it to a clown Which is not as cool as a night and I was upset.
Speaker 1: Why first of all, wait, wait, why am I upset about what?
Speaker 1: but I don't even know.
Speaker 1: mascot of the middle school.
Speaker 0: Think like a head.
Speaker 0: you have to have to first.
Speaker 1: I have to know about this.
Speaker 1: So you're gonna put yourself I don't even know the mat the names man I don't even know where the local middle school is.
Speaker 0: So Scott imagine you lived in the same town your whole life and you went to this middle school.
Speaker 0: and now you're 40 You have fond memories of playing for this middle school team with this name.
Speaker 1: So nothing has happened in my life That's overshadowed those memories since middle school.
Speaker 1: I don't even remember my middle school mascot with your dad in Napoleon Madison middle school.
Speaker 1: Was it Panthers?
Speaker 1: Maybe my?
Speaker 1: It was a cat of some kind.
Speaker 0: mine was the middle school north And I want to say the high school was the Eagles under the number something.
Speaker 0: in elementary school It was the Falcons and elementary school.
Speaker 1: It wasn't any.
Speaker 0: in high school It was also the Falcons which I always thought was kind of a weird coincidence.
Speaker 1: in high school is Eagles.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we were the Falcons.
Speaker 0: Okay, the fighting Falcons.
Speaker 0: I think maybe just the Falcons.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Our football team sucked.
Speaker 0: The logo was really only for the marching band.
Speaker 1: Anyway, some kind of mean cat.
Speaker 0: But uh, yeah the reddit shithead level Happened in the exact same manner in this little town when they changed the logo of a middle school sports team.
Speaker 1: Well, someone cares about that subreddit that much.
Speaker 1: That Lancaster subreddits are like society that middle school mascot that much They care about this podcast.
Speaker 1: that much so.
Speaker 0: in a more positive news the review on iTunes Pizza Hut Which when I was a young kid, I enjoyed for some reason.
Speaker 1: I enjoyed Pizza Hut because number one they had one of those machines in the lobby where you could had like six Sega Genesis Games in it.
Speaker 0: Well ours had the afterburner that cost a dollar and moved, right?
Speaker 1: You could pay a quarter and pick one of the games and also an operation wolf.
Speaker 1: I usually picked Altered Beast rise from yoga.
Speaker 0: I just played Operation wolf with four quarters.
Speaker 1: Also, you sat down and get pizza.
Speaker 1: you get the garlic breads and whatnot, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know the food came quick.
Speaker 1: also like it was a good place to eat out when you're a little kid And you can't sit still in a nice restaurant.
Speaker 0: Also, we're spoiled.
Speaker 0: We live in New York now and also like pizza became better when we were young like in the 80s in Connecticut.
Speaker 1: I mean what pizza was I gonna get besides Mario the Baker?
Speaker 1: There was.
Speaker 1: there's one pizza place in that town and there still is and that's it.
Speaker 1: in the 80s.
Speaker 0: if you wanted pizza Unless you were lucky and lived next to like a for real Italian restaurant that would actually serve pizza for real Pizza Hut was probably the best you were gonna get.
Speaker 0: I mean from it was downhill from there was Domino's.
Speaker 1: Yeah, little Caesars a Pizza Hut, you know, you get a cool toy Howie's good good little menu to use your crayons on.
Speaker 0: yep, you know, so The fern for the first time in decades, there's good new Pizza Hut did something smart.
Speaker 0: They now unveiled a pizza That is a stuffed crust and the crust is stuffed with hot dogs, right?
Speaker 1: So there's a big ring of hot dog around the edge of the pizza covered in bread.
Speaker 1: Yes, so it's basically.
Speaker 1: you can just peel that off and it's just hot dog Yes, and then in between inside the ring is pizza.
Speaker 1: Yes So first of all this genius because all those people who are dumbasses don't eat the crust.
Speaker 1: now You're gonna eat that crust.
Speaker 1: but the problem is Now I can only eat like one slice.
Speaker 1: cuz I eat the slice.
Speaker 1: I eat the hot dog.
Speaker 1: That's enough.
Speaker 0: So Scott think back to an earlier.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, I'd eat like two slices, but Scott remember when you were 14 Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I could probably eat three slices and three hot dogs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I when I was 14 I don't ever told the damage on again.
Speaker 0: And this see this is why is critically for real like I am NOT joking was kicked out of a Pizza Hut For taking advantage of their all-you-can-eat buffet lunch, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah Like that that story is self descriptive.
Speaker 0: The thing is usually they asked me to leave.
Speaker 1: usually these crazy food Combination things that restaurants are coming up with are just disgusting like, you know The the double down where it's the replacement bread with fried chicken and you put this right even on the higher end like the artisanal stuff.
Speaker 0: The ramen burger pretty nasty.
Speaker 1: Yeah The ramen burger I tried it not great But this it's like.
Speaker 1: well what it's.
Speaker 1: there's nothing wrong with this because here's the problem.
Speaker 1: It's a little out there, but it's not disgusting in any way.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, what is it?
Speaker 1: It's a hot dog wrapped in bread next to a pizza.
Speaker 0: the people who make those kinds of like crazy food You put.
Speaker 1: you put sausage on pizza.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's a hot dog is not too far like the double down is you're taking some pretty shitty food and just making it worse For you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like just taking it down into the gutter like you're doing something stupid Like I'm gonna take a bacon and a rabbit and turkey.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna wrap that in more bacon.
Speaker 1: Dunkin Donuts do they had the two waffles of the breakfast?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like that shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but on the upper end you've got the artisanal thing like the ramen burger.
Speaker 0: They're like, we're gonna take a good food and try to make like a hipster artisanal experience out of it And usually it's just not well put together.
Speaker 0: But this is a lateral move.
Speaker 0: They're taking two foods that are at an equivalent level and combining them.
Speaker 1: The thing is just the fact of putting the hot dog in the crust.
Speaker 1: It's like that's what you do with the hot dog.
Speaker 1: You put it in a bun.
Speaker 0: It's just a crusty bun, which I've known kids who just eat a sliced up hot dog, and that's it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean and this is a hot dog in a bun I mean, this is just great.
Speaker 1: Chris the problem might actually go to a pizza and order one of these the pizza.
Speaker 0: They show you I'm desperate in a summer.
Speaker 1: Here's the problem desperate in a summer.
Speaker 0: the pizza they showed here is a meat lovers pizza.
Speaker 0: Go full power full power.
Speaker 1: If I'm in a non New York, and I can't get a good pizza and there's a Pizza Hut I might order that.
Speaker 0: Well after that time we fucked up and tried to go to that Godfather's.
Speaker 1: Oh god in the gas station It was a pizza place in a gas station.
Speaker 0: We should have just we wouldn't smart to have just thrown the pizza away directly upon receiving it.
Speaker 1: Drive up see that it was in the gas station and then drive away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just charge back the credit card without giving money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so they of the day.
Speaker 0: So this is just like a YouTube show.
Speaker 0: I'm linking to one episode of it.
Speaker 0: If you've ever done tech support for anyone ever ever.
Speaker 0: You might not be able to finish this video because it might be a little too real too real It's.
Speaker 0: I mean basically it's just this video about a guys at work And you see his computer and you hear his voice and he's on the phone, but it's like sped up so you get a lot of words in really quick and He's playing like Wolfenstein.
Speaker 0: and then like he gets a phone call and then it cuts to his desktop and you see this desktop
Speaker 1: Covered in icon color
Speaker 0: and he's like talking on the phone and meanwhile He's like drawing squares on the desktop and he's got like two AOL icons like kind of overlapping and he moves one of them over the other one to make it disappear and he's just talking and It gets to a point that we tries to add a row to his Excel spreadsheet and he can't.
Speaker 0: so he calls tech support Because he's out of rows.
Speaker 0: and The beautiful part about all this is that the whole time in this discussion?
Speaker 0: He is clearly in PowerPoint with a table in a like in a slide and This video is so well just trolling the tech support first.
Speaker 0: No It is.
Speaker 0: this is the story of someone who is that stupid and you hear him interacting with the rest of the world around him.
Speaker 0: It's actually really funny But it's also a little too real and I guess the reason I'm tonight is there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, these pop-ups keep coming up because it's and it just keeps escalating.
Speaker 0: He's also playing minesweeper.
Speaker 1: Does he know how to play minesweeper?
Speaker 0: He's playing a map with?
Speaker 0: 667 mines on it the absolute maximum.
Speaker 1: Is he doing a good job so far?
Speaker 0: but It's this is pretty funny because there's so many Little subtle things like he's on the tech support call in this, you know, what do you thinks is excel and The guys like hit like ctrl?
Speaker 0: I are all tired or whatever like.
Speaker 0: does that work?
Speaker 0: and he does that.
Speaker 0: But he just overwrites one of his cells like fucks up the data in what little spreadsheet he has and doesn't notice.
Speaker 0: And it's just.
Speaker 0: it's real hard to watch this.
Speaker 1: All right, so, you know a lot of people are not exactly conscious about how much energy things take right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, we can think about things in terms of one context, right?
Speaker 1: Like how much electricity does my computer use on my electric bill?
Speaker 1: Some people know that you know, but you know, how much gas does my car use per mile?
Speaker 0: Well, like people like how many complain like Oh hundred watt light bulbs I'm just mad to these complex fluorescence are coming in like well, why can't I use my hundred watt light bulbs, right?
Speaker 1: But for example, you know If you drive your car say until the gas tank is empty how much energy you know How many times how many days of computer that energy is?
Speaker 1: Right, you don't know that right?
Speaker 1: people don't calculate that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: So to illustrate this and make you be more energy saving conscious Someone made this incredible video.
Speaker 1: where they took I don't know.
Speaker 1: He's like he's an Olympic track cyclist or something, but his leg is bigger around than my head and your head Yes, even Scott Johnson's head.
Speaker 0: Scott our four legs combined would have a closely run affair fighting him in an anime.
Speaker 1: Our four legs our four bodies combined would have a closely run affair fighting one of his legs just one of the legs.
Speaker 1: so is a ginormous dude and he bikes on a stationary bike to power a toaster to toast a piece of toast and Then they tell you basically you can see how you know much energy it takes to toast a piece of toast.
Speaker 1: and then they tell You relatively speaking how many of this guy it takes to power.
Speaker 1: various other things based on how well he powered the toaster.
Speaker 1: and Now you are more energy conscious.
Speaker 1: Congratulations.
Speaker 1: I got saw this dude with giant legs.
Speaker 0: I got tired watching this.
Speaker 0: I felt short of breath.
Speaker 0: and then when they show his heart rate his heart rate is at the at like the average non athletic humans maximum, yep Maybe even above their maximum.
Speaker 1: and I guess I could have been like him if I would have spent my whole life on that And I had better genes for that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Maybe I didn't?
Speaker 1: you know being big and badass doesn't?
Speaker 0: you only really started biking for serious like recently.
Speaker 1: I biked when I was young.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but not not properly.
Speaker 1: No, I was not my fan, you know being a muscular does not run in my family.
Speaker 0: So in the moment the book club book is the wheel of time It goes around around.
Speaker 1: the first one first book is called the eye of the world.
Speaker 0: I bought it in a digital form and I'm a good way.
Speaker 1: It takes up less space.
Speaker 0: that way I'm going to start reading it on my trip to London next week.
Speaker 1: I have read quite a bit of it But I have nowhere near even 25% done.
Speaker 0: I like I don't want to lie like hopefully when I start reading it I'm trying not to be down on it, but it is a fantasy novel.
Speaker 0: I just don't want to read it now because I would rather read one of those old fuck out hidden elements books.
Speaker 1: This is probably better than those.
Speaker 0: well We'll see.
Speaker 1: we will say.
Speaker 0: that's the point of those fuck out hidden items.
Speaker 0: Books are pretty bad like especially the Shit, or the cleric quintet, which is one of the.
Speaker 1: is that way?
Speaker 1: is that five clerics who go around together?
Speaker 0: No, it is five books about one cleric named Catterley.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's not five different clerics and then it's not a quintet is it?
Speaker 0: and it's about this kind of Bullshit II minor God.
Speaker 0: and it's really.
Speaker 1: it's not even about paler or anything Paler.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's the other.
Speaker 1: that's the paler bringing your bringing your non-canon like It's in third edition D&D players hand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's like some grey house on sand.
Speaker 1: I was always a cleric of paler the most good and generic God you could pick.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, no I always play I always worship like I don't know spider whatever that they had at PAX.
Speaker 1: What is that a god?
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't worship her.
Speaker 1: Can you be a cleric of her?
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're a drow I don't know if she'd accept a non drow Worshipping here.
Speaker 0: if you're not a drow, I don't know what she'd do when I don't know any other Forgotten Realms.
Speaker 1: things that weren't statues No or books that rim read.
Speaker 1: you got a worship like Elminster and Drits the nest it like walking or something.
Speaker 1: or oh, who the hell are they?
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: I got us a magic.
Speaker 1: I've heard that name before mister.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or mr.
Speaker 0: Ill the the predator ever got head or whatever?
Speaker 1: never heard of that I hope.
Speaker 0: I guess the last character I played in D&D who worshipped a deity worshiped Elven got it.
Speaker 0: What are the elven guy?
Speaker 0: I drew Fenya the elven goddess of I think freedom.
Speaker 1: Rim knows forgotten too much.
Speaker 1: How much Forgotten Realms, you know, yeah, yeah, they're forgotten, you know, either the Forgotten Realms cuz everyone else forgot.
Speaker 0: but rim There's something more.
Speaker 1: for the fact that you remember Forgotten Realms spell jammer is a shame upon you.
Speaker 0: you you tested me.
Speaker 0: I remembered a surprising number of names from the Elaine Cunningham elfy books Like way more than I should have way more than I remembered from a book.
Speaker 1: I just read with the rabbits in it About some water ship or something.
Speaker 0: What was the name of the bird?
Speaker 0: Wow, really?
Speaker 1: Kiha, that's it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 0: Remember it now.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: What's the name of the bird?
Speaker 0: Okay I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm not enthused about this book.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna lie I'm not gonna.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to not let that color my perception of the book.
Speaker 0: However, anyway Maybe I'll just buy the heron sword and then I'll feel better about reading the baron swords.
Speaker 1: pretty awesome so far.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like swords when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: I'm welcome to canaria.
Speaker 0: I almost read the wheel of time like ten times because when I was in high school You could get from museum replicas the heron sword and it just looked amazing.
Speaker 1: So I'm not as good as the heron spear, which by the way spoilers is probably a laser cannon.
Speaker 0: It's probably yeah, probably anyway, uh Come to Connecticut.
Speaker 0: It's in a month in Hartford, Connecticut.
Speaker 0: The panel schedules basically done and I'm not gonna lie.
Speaker 0: It is the best goddamn panel schedule we've ever had.
Speaker 0: There is some good stuff in there.
Speaker 1: Kineticon is an everything geek con.
Speaker 1: if there is some geeky thing you're into it's there.
Speaker 1: Maybe you're the kind of nerd who just wants to play Magic the Gathering.
Speaker 1: You can do that at Kineticon, but you should also do something else.
Speaker 1: Don't be that guy.
Speaker 0: You've got some crazy big guests.
Speaker 0: We've got such panels as let's see Kokeshi style clothespin dolls a workshop.
Speaker 0: Ooh how to get good at Super Smash Brothers.
Speaker 1: I need that one.
Speaker 1: I'll go into that.
Speaker 0: cosplaying while black nice Introduction to comic and Adobe Photoshop art henna glitter and temporary body art.
Speaker 0: I don't have.
Speaker 0: sex death and populism the life and times of Andrew Jackson.
Speaker 1: Is that 18 plus?
Speaker 0: Yes Okay The 18 plus.
Speaker 0: I defy any convention in America that nerds go to to have an 18 plus Panel about Andrew Jackson.
Speaker 1: probably the first probably world first world history first Panel at geek convention about Andrew Jackson never happened before ever.
Speaker 0: I'm actually pretty excited about that panel.
Speaker 0: bunch of chiptune stuff Monster girl quest the lecture.
Speaker 1: I don't know what that is a bunch of Faku stuff.
Speaker 0: There is good stuff.
Speaker 0: That's just fry.
Speaker 0: That's like two panel rooms on Friday.
Speaker 0: Maybe you have like two hundred and something panels.
Speaker 1: All right, and that's just panels.
Speaker 1: Kineticon is way big as non panels.
Speaker 1: Yeah as a main events It has gaming.
Speaker 1: it has.
Speaker 0: we have screenings, but they're.
Speaker 0: it's not just anime plays.
Speaker 1: it has merch.
Speaker 1: it has arts.
Speaker 1: It has a super art fight.
Speaker 1: Hopefully again.
Speaker 0: Yep now super art fights in there.
Speaker 0: I saw him hanging out.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah So come to Kineticon if you can drive to it or take some other mass transit like a bus if you're close enough Go if you're kind of far maybe not worth it cuz it's not the biggest craziest con, but maybe it is.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: So when I was a kid I just had luggage like.
Speaker 0: that was just a thing my parents bought for me.
Speaker 0: I didn't think about it.
Speaker 1: Uh, I think I had a Suitcase the kind with a handle that you zippered open the side.
Speaker 1: It's basically a large, you know briefcase class.
Speaker 0: I didn't kind of thing travel on my own as a kid really.
Speaker 0: so My mom would like come into the room be like, here's your suitcase fill it.
Speaker 1: yeah, whenever I went places on my own it was either gonna be summer camp or Some kind of trip and I would just duffle bag just a really big at the duffle bag that was large enough for the length of the trip and Stuff it.
Speaker 0: So when I got older and I needed luggage of my own.
Speaker 0: I bought the cheapest possible garbage.
Speaker 0: I bought the cheapest bag money could buy.
Speaker 1: I kept using the duffle bag for a very very long time.
Speaker 1: I had you know, the Extra-large giganto duffle bag which I still have and the medium duffle bag which got lost somewhere and I just kept using those.
Speaker 1: They had shoulder straps, but you know it I just used those for a long-ass time.
Speaker 1: It wasn't until like maybe a few years ago that I started to be like Oh, these are actually kind of inconvenient for going to conventions all the time.
Speaker 0: So again, so that's it.
Speaker 0: So as I was a kid, I remember that adults would talk about luggage a lot And they'd complain about and compare luggage.
Speaker 1: and then I learned that luggage hold their whole stores that just sell luggage only and yeah Expensive luggage and it's like what is going.
Speaker 1: why is this happening?
Speaker 1: Why luggage is what's wrong?
Speaker 1: We're just you know, just get one double bag.
Speaker 0: You're good and luggage is really expensive like a pretty good roller bag can go for like four or five hundred bucks And you're seeing people traveling with like huge amounts of shit.
Speaker 1: It's like what the fuck is wrong with.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, the people I see at the airport.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about packing though.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about travel.
Speaker 0: It's talking about the luggage itself, right?
Speaker 0: So I didn't care and I use garbage luggage like I bought like in 2008 even like that.
Speaker 0: recently I bought literally just a roller bag Bag at one of those places that sells luggage like in the bad parts of town in New York.
Speaker 1: I mean for the longest time I was pretty much just like box.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna use a roller bag because only sissies use roller.
Speaker 0: Oh you come around on that, haven't you?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean I use it when it's.
Speaker 0: you know You Scott Scott gave me shit for like five years.
Speaker 0: but rim why do you have a roller bag?
Speaker 0: That's for babies.
Speaker 0: My duffel bags.
Speaker 0: Just fine.
Speaker 0: Only sissies use roller bags.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's true.
Speaker 0: Okay, okay.
Speaker 1: My arm is mad weak.
Speaker 1: So I was taking more stuff to conventions, you know and I have my arm was starting to struggle But where before it did not.
Speaker 0: that's what did it.
Speaker 0: because my arm is mad weak we also got away with it for a long time having crappy luggage.
Speaker 0: because if you only ever drive places and You own a car and you know, it's also a major fact it's pretty easy to have terrible luggage because you just kind of throw all the stuff that doesn't fit in your trunk.
Speaker 0: and I Remember, right?
Speaker 1: I used to take my duffel bag.
Speaker 1: That was really heavy.
Speaker 1: Just carry downstairs put in a car drive it and carry it into a hotel and that was it.
Speaker 0: So I brought board games In the trunk and then like I remember we get to a con and then we make like four trips from the car to the Hotel room.
Speaker 1: but now it's like oh I have to go to Australia and I have to get this to the airport on public transportation And I don't want to pay for a taxi.
Speaker 1: This is not gonna be good.
Speaker 1: I need something that carries more easily.
Speaker 1: But also when you just have a big duffel bag It's hard to organize your stuff in it.
Speaker 1: Everything just sort of mushes around.
Speaker 1: you can't like keep clothes folded nicely.
Speaker 1: You can't separate, you know your shoes from your clothes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't.
Speaker 0: you know if you need to bring an extra shoe with you and then whoo betide you have a multi hop journey Right where you stay in a hotel for like a week and then go somewhere else and you put any sort of specialized equipment in there.
Speaker 1: now you take a lot of electronics with you when you travel camera stuff chargers and you just.
Speaker 1: you know you don't want to just toss that stuff in all willy-nilly like having a specific like camera bag or a Compartment to put charges in or way to separate toiletries from other things in case they explode even though you do put them in a plastic bags.
Speaker 1: that right.
Speaker 0: so I decided at least to spend Whatever money it would take to have the best possible luggage.
Speaker 0: that would just make my life easier forever.
Speaker 1: also, you got to remember there's those.
Speaker 1: I don't have them but the Luggage that can take a beating.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: if the Samsonite stuff that's hard shell.
Speaker 1: So in case when it's rolling around in that airport carousel, however hard shell luggage a Lot of money.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm also not into it because the one advantage of not having the hard shell is you can cram more stuff in.
Speaker 0: I don't cram anymore though.
Speaker 0: I bring so little I'm trying to bring.
Speaker 1: I'm constantly bringing less and less everywhere I go, but but having luggage that's at least a little flexible is kind of good.
Speaker 0: So Emily and I like many many years ago.
Speaker 0: I'm two packs.
Speaker 0: We just thought we'd be clever because like I was gonna go to work or whatever Like we had this.
Speaker 0: like we're gonna meet at the airport last year.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: No, this was beautiful.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm not last year.
Speaker 1: So it was last year.
Speaker 1: you had trouble.
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't last year.
Speaker 0: We had trouble.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I've been using that silver bag for a while.
Speaker 0: Okay So we put all our stuff in one big bag to check and then I just carried like a backpack.
Speaker 0: So we combined our luggage.
Speaker 0: that was fine.
Speaker 0: on the way to packs on the way home We realized that the bag was now too heavy and we would have to pay like 80 extra dollars to check it.
Speaker 1: Cuz you bought stuff and put it in there.
Speaker 0: So what we decided was why don't we just buy a new bag?
Speaker 0: we need a new luggage.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we'll buy a new luggage here in Seattle.
Speaker 0: we go to a luggage store poking around and I look at like this pretty nice luggage and It says like.
Speaker 0: it says like Oh sale 40% off.
Speaker 0: I'm like, okay great and it's hard shell and it looks really nice.
Speaker 0: It's the perfect size and I just kind of say fuck it.
Speaker 0: I'll just get this one.
Speaker 0: I carry up to the front and then as I'm carrying it up.
Speaker 0: I actually see the price tag I expected like a couple hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: Maybe yeah hundreds was $3,000.
Speaker 1: what is it made of?
Speaker 1: gold?
Speaker 1: No Carbon fibers designer bullshit, apparently Oh like a fancy designer name on it.
Speaker 0: So then I start looking around and yeah, even the ugly bad luggage is like many hundreds of dollars.
Speaker 1: well, that's a separate issue.
Speaker 1: entirely right is that there's this industry of designer fashion bags that just Greatly inflate the price of a bag because there's a trademark on the bag because certain people in our society Highly value that trademark.
Speaker 0: regardless of the actual quality or design of the bag of this bag They're gonna check into an air load and immediately have destroyed.
Speaker 1: a normal person who buys bags and is looking for utility Cannot buy any of those even if they happen to actually be a good design in any point in time.
Speaker 1: So that's why I just buy like Timbuktu and you know That sort of brand
Speaker 0: and all my research Timbuktu like this they're not paying us or anything just as like good advice Literally never buy luggage from anyone but them unless
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's other good brands of luggage, right?
Speaker 0: I did a lot of research.
Speaker 0: I could not find good luggage that didn't cost as easily three or four times as much and That more expensive luggage was often not as well designed.
Speaker 1: but Timbuktu and other similar companies, right?
Speaker 1: They are, you know out there making things that are designed to be practical not jacking up the price based on trademarks or designs.
Speaker 1: and You know, I started off.
Speaker 1: they were only messenger bags at the beginning right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we both have the same custom messenger bag.
Speaker 1: I've made a custom messenger bag from them expecting it to last a long time.
Speaker 1: I've been using that since Probably over a decade now.
Speaker 1: It's like a long long ass time.
Speaker 1: still have the same bag still nothing wrong with it.
Speaker 1: Every day has no problem.
Speaker 1: So, you know seeing that my primary bag that I used every day and had no problems with and it was amazing I'm like, well, I trusted you for this most important bag that I have.
Speaker 1: I will trust you for these second most important bag and third most important bag and so on.
Speaker 1: now and I have not been Steered wrong.
Speaker 0: I travel a lot for highly variable amounts of time.
Speaker 0: So I kind of broke down that basically what I needed was a messenger bag Which is usually my like, you know personal item because my laptop and DS and everything's in there I mean, I use mine every single day including traveling.
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 0: then I needed either a backpack that I could check or carry on or Just a full-on luggage like a big one But not a giant one not the one that you see like those stupid people at the airport like not the one that's like Yeah, like three feet wide or whatever.
Speaker 0: I'm talking like the biggest roller bag.
Speaker 0: That is reasonable.
Speaker 0: and Between those three bags.
Speaker 0: I'm like a hundred percent set for any travel.
Speaker 0: I will ever do in my life forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I still have some older bags Like I have my.
Speaker 0: got rid of my older bags because they're worthless.
Speaker 1: I mean mine have like my initials on them.
Speaker 1: But I have like the giant duffel bag still and I have my backpack.
Speaker 1: from when I used a backpack I remember that giant blue bag.
Speaker 0: I literally just threw it away like in college.
Speaker 1: I used that backpack, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but You know I only really use the three tip muck two bags the wheelie one the not wheelie one for shorter trips and My everyday messenger bag.
Speaker 0: if I flew a lot more I would consider getting one more smaller wheelie bag Because then I could do the backpack cuz I got that really good like aviator backpack.
Speaker 1: Yeah, put that under the seat in front of you But the small wheelie bag in the overhead bin and then check the big wheelie bag.
Speaker 0: Yep, or actually Going to the airport where the backpack carry the roller bag and then if I have to check one of them It's just for the ease of transport to the airport because you can only have one wheelie one backpack if you have more.
Speaker 1: If you have two wheelies you're in deep shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I can attach my messenger bag to the backpack because the backpack is really cleverly designed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I actually also have a Tim muck 2 camera bag That is just like.
Speaker 1: it's sort of like a messenger bag, but it's only meant to hold a camera Compartments to put lenses.
Speaker 0: Well, I also have a Timbuktu Bicycling backpack that can care.
Speaker 0: It's basically I could carry enough stuff to go.
Speaker 1: Let's not make a Timbuktu ad here.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of companies that sell all this shit, too.
Speaker 1: Timbuktu probably isn't even the best at camera bags.
Speaker 1: I saw some like I forget the name of the company but like dub something.
Speaker 0: No, but this can't this.
Speaker 0: this you think like.
Speaker 0: what's so special about a biking backpack?
Speaker 0: So one.
Speaker 0: it rides way higher than a normal backpack.
Speaker 0: So when you're biking hunched over it's like perfect.
Speaker 0: It's not like sagging bag.
Speaker 0: It's not in like the bottom of your back.
Speaker 0: It's got like crazy vents on it and it's just like shaped to fit my back when I'm hunched biking.
Speaker 0: So I could.
Speaker 0: I could if I go if I do that thing right.
Speaker 0: if I consider my trip easy time From biking from Sydney to Melbourne.
Speaker 0: I will use that backpack to carry my shit with me.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: What else is there to say about luggage?
Speaker 0: Uh Don't buy giant luggage.
Speaker 0: It's literally worthless.
Speaker 0: If you think you need a giant luggage like one of those giant giant giant ones You're probably wrong and you're packing away too much.
Speaker 1: even if you have a big family Just make freaking.
Speaker 1: everyone carry their own shit and everyone has the normal size bags.
Speaker 0: Also airlines have really cracked down like the maximum weight of bags I don't know or smaller.
Speaker 1: everyone in you You mean if you have a ton of luggage that you need because you have a big family Every single person has their own wheelie bag and their own backpack even little kiddies.
Speaker 0: And if you're bringing more than that because you're moving somewhere for like six months ship it.
Speaker 1: That's also a good idea.
Speaker 0: Like don't try to bring it on the plane with you.
Speaker 1: Just actually be cheaper than putting it on the plane, right?
Speaker 0: You know that used to be the case.
Speaker 1: Depending on how heavy it is.
Speaker 0: It is basically not true anymore.
Speaker 0: I Shipped some stuff instead of bring it with me on a business trip.
Speaker 0: The shipping cost more than just another plane ticket for a human.
Speaker 1: It depends on the weight, right?
Speaker 1: So if something's really freaking heavy then bring it on the plane is better.
Speaker 1: But if you something is not that heavy Check it the airlines now.
Speaker 0: I have an upper limit of no you can't check this.
Speaker 0: Sorry, I'm not talking about that heavy, but oh that look that that level is lower than you think.
Speaker 1: hmm Figure your own shit out people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but and also a good answer for a lot of things is Don't bring it with you buy something on the other side.
Speaker 0: That is also true.
Speaker 1: travel like if you're flying to China and you know, it's like yeah a toothbrush doesn't weigh anything, right?
Speaker 1: But let's say you need boots cuz you're gonna go hiking in some mountains, right?
Speaker 1: Those boots are real freakin heavy.
Speaker 1: You might be better off just buying boots over there.
Speaker 0: I would bring my boots.
Speaker 0: My boots are worn in.
Speaker 0: they're fitted to me perfectly.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying it's $300 boots as an example of a heavy thing you might bring right?
Speaker 0: Well, I tried to do that and it didn't work out so well in Australia when I decided I'll just buy a tripod in Australia A bicycle.
Speaker 1: you can just go rent one on the other side.
Speaker 0: I would not bring my bicycle on a plane ever.
Speaker 1: Maybe you're.
Speaker 1: maybe you're a videographer and you need video cameras that are like huge.
Speaker 1: just rent those on the other side Don't bring them with.
Speaker 0: but I guess here's the advice.
Speaker 0: In my experience in Scott's experience as smart dudes If you need luggage by the best backpack the best messenger bag and the best reasonably sized really bag That that exists just by the absolutely perfect thing.
Speaker 1: And even if you don't have a lot of monies because I know most people don't I mean I bought my first Timbuktu bag And it was like a couple hundred bucks and I did not have a lot of monies then and it's worth it.
Speaker 1: it's I saved up and got it because then you'd never had to buy one again.
Speaker 1: just suffer with shitty bags until you just Use like grocery bags.
Speaker 1: just suffer until you have enough money and get the good bag and then that bag will last you forever.
Speaker 1: if you buy a shitty bag for like 50 bucks and Then it falls apart you buy another one for 50 by the time you get to your fourth bag It's like well, you could just bought the fancy one to begin with.
Speaker 0: Yep I've thrown away easily four or five wheelie bags in my life that cost way more Combined than the one like hundred and eighty dollar amazing travel backpack that I have now.
Speaker 1: Yep So it's a thing that if you you know travel a lot It's worth investing in.
Speaker 0: the other thing is if you go to if you get good bags They're measured to actually fit in like carry-on on different airlines.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the websites all the companies will tell you like this is carry-on legal at least right now until the rules change?
Speaker 0: What can mess you up though is that international flights often have different rules and Classes have different rules like business class.
Speaker 0: You can bring whatever you want pretty much.
Speaker 1: You're paying ten times as much.
Speaker 1: you bring it ten times as much stuff.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Oh the other important thing I Recently, finally, I've been sub despite this advice.
Speaker 0: I wasn't taking my own advice.
Speaker 0: for most of my life.
Speaker 0: I had a. I had the shittiest garment bag in the world.
Speaker 0: I just bought a swag garment bag.
Speaker 1: Garment bags are important.
Speaker 1: if you have to bring fancy clothes.
Speaker 0: It was like 40 bucks Which seems like a lot.
Speaker 1: you just take like a fancy suit and cram it in your luggage.
Speaker 1: Even if you fold it nicely, it's not gonna come out.
Speaker 1: Well on the other end.
Speaker 1: You'll have to go to the dry-clean.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no Scott I'll show you this garden.
Speaker 1: if you need to get off the plane and go to a business meet you need your suit to be Ready to go.
Speaker 1: You don't want to wear it on the plane and get it all stinky, especially applies long.
Speaker 1: The garment bag is anything like a necessary thing.
Speaker 0: going to a wedding Bringing the nice suit for like the nerd prom or whatever at the convention.
Speaker 0: Yeah, garment bag.
Speaker 1: Don't you got your cosplay?
Speaker 1: Maybe it goes in a garment bag because your tuxedo mask.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I just bought a for real garment bag.
Speaker 0: I'm a moron for having used my crappy garment bag for like the last decade.
Speaker 0: I really feel dumb for not having done this sooner.
Speaker 1: One most important feature of the garment bag is when the bottom of it can like, you know Connect to the top to fold it out.
Speaker 1: That is the most important feature.
Speaker 0: Wait till you see this garment bag I got.
Speaker 0: how fancy could I show it to you as soon as we stop recording?
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: cat leave for web design and brand.
Speaker 1: Ok for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.