Speaker 0: It's Thursday, March 19th, 2015.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights Tonight, our review of San Antonio, Texas.
Speaker 1: The geographical, political place.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Of course, once again, no shows next week because I'm going to London, like, Monday.
Speaker 1: Why don't you just move there?
Speaker 0: Actually, you know what?
Speaker 0: I can live in London.
Speaker 0: London is alongside New York City as the only two, like, global alpha cities in the world by that whatever, like, academic group that studies cities.
Speaker 1: Isn't there way less freedom there?
Speaker 0: Arguably, it's pretty similar to what we have here.
Speaker 0: I mean, the real difference is...
Speaker 1: I mean, there's no freedom of speech.
Speaker 1: There's not even Miranda rights.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the problem.
Speaker 0: Practically, yes.
Speaker 0: Well, practically, they're very similar, but, like, ideologically and law-wise, they're very different.
Speaker 0: The only things that practically affect, like, you and me if we were living there is the fact that truth is not defense against libel, meaning we would be fucked.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: If I'm in the UK and I say, "Rim eats poops," and I have a video of Rim eating poops, and I publish that in the newspaper...
Speaker 0: Yes, I could go after you for defamation of character by distributing that true information if I did it with intent to harm.
Speaker 0: You did it with intent to harm.
Speaker 1: My intent was to make fun of Rim because he eats poops and to let everyone know so that no one goes near him because he's dangerous with his poop eating.
Speaker 0: This is why there is a... But it's true.
Speaker 1: Here's a video that's unaltered of him literally eating poops.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so truth is not defense for that in the UK, which is why many, many, many people around the world will never go there because they have lost a case that they never went to testify in and don't want to deal with because someone else engaged in libel tourism.
Speaker 1: Let me ask a question.
Speaker 1: In the UK, do they have warning signs on dangerous things?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the pit cannot say... Here's the other problem, Scott.
Speaker 0: Because it's like British-English common law shit, the judges could just be like, "Yeah, that's stupid," in a way that we can't hear, the argument you were about to make.
Speaker 1: Good reason not to go there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time, imagine there's a lot of cases where our judges should be able to say, "That is stupid," but instead they don't because they can't because we have a constitutional system.
Speaker 0: It goes both ways.
Speaker 1: In our courtrooms with their big, tall, magistrate, scary things on the side with really hot tie-up.
Speaker 1: You always see them in the historical-type movies.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure they're not actually like that anymore, but maybe they are.
Speaker 0: Sophie!
Speaker 1: Yeah, that kind.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, my gosh.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's Thursday.
Speaker 0: You got any news for the Geek Nights Lounge?
Speaker 1: There's not really any news, and it's not a lounge.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of news.
Speaker 1: So, I had to steal Monday's news.
Speaker 0: All sorts of shit's going down.
Speaker 1: Not really, no.
Speaker 1: There's nothing going down.
Speaker 1: So, Monday's news.
Speaker 1: Windows 10, which is coming, which is looking to be the next legit Windows.
Speaker 1: I mean, even if Windows 7 is still just fine, which it is, you're probably going to need to bail on it at some point.
Speaker 1: Windows XP is just fine, but you kind of need to bail on it at some point.
Speaker 0: It's not just fine.
Speaker 0: A lot of shit doesn't work on it.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: It's still perfect.
Speaker 1: There's nothing quality wrong with it, other than the fact that they stopped maintaining it, and now it's too old.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Just like Windows 2000 is great.
Speaker 1: You can't use it anymore.
Speaker 0: It's got performance and memory.
Speaker 0: It's not... anyway.
Speaker 1: But Windows 7 is nearing that too old point.
Speaker 1: It's still usable today.
Speaker 1: I still use it today.
Speaker 1: But it's getting to be too old sometime soon.
Speaker 0: Well, I've moved to a point in my life...
Speaker 1: So, like it or not, you're going to have to go to Windows 10.
Speaker 1: You're not going to want to go to 8.
Speaker 0: You know, in the old days...
Speaker 1: Not that there's that much wrong with 8 either, just as a bad rep.
Speaker 0: The same way Vista had a bad rep.
Speaker 0: I went and bought Windows 2000.
Speaker 0: I would upgrade my operating system, and in the modern era, I only upgrade my operating system when I buy a brand new computer.
Speaker 1: So anyway, Windows 10 is coming, and they're going to make it what they should have done a zillion years ago.
Speaker 1: Well, they're not doing it exactly the way they should, but it's going to be a free upgrade to anyone who's got Windows 7 or 8 or whatever.
Speaker 0: There's a pointed, important piece of what you just said, though, that even pirated copies...
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Even if you have pirated Windows 7, you can still upgrade to Windows 10.
Speaker 1: But, if your copy of Windows is not genuine, your Windows 10, you'll upgrade to it.
Speaker 1: It still won't be genuine.
Speaker 1: So the thing is, what they're going to be doing with Windows 10 is updating it and making sure everyone's got the newest, best... Basically trying to get everyone on the same Windows.
Speaker 1: Really, that's their goal with this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is actually a really good idea, because a lot of the bad things that are happening out in the wild west of the internet is because most of the world is running pirated Windows XP.
Speaker 1: The thing is, there's a question of if people have the ungenuine Windows 10, are they going to get updates or not?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Because it's ungenuine.
Speaker 0: Also, Microsoft's fucked either way.
Speaker 0: If they say no, then half the internet is going to say, "Look at you, making the internet less secure by denying security
Speaker 0: updates.".
Speaker 1: Also, it's not free for business, but that makes sense.
Speaker 1: And, the other thing is that it's only going to be free for like a year, and then they're going to start charging for it like normal.
Speaker 1: This really doesn't make sense to me.
Speaker 1: Really, Microsoft, you want people to use your shit, you should make Windows 10 free, you should make Office 50 bucks or less for the whole thing.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't have all these different versions.
Speaker 0: Well, the target customer for Office really is businesses.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you should only charge... Continue to charge the businesses an arm and a leg.
Speaker 1: But, for regular old people, you should just make all your software way cheap and people actually buy Office.
Speaker 1: if it was affordable.
Speaker 0: Well, I would charge businesses.
Speaker 1: I have Office.
Speaker 1: I got one of those cheapo deals for 10 bucks or something.
Speaker 0: That's also how I have Office.
Speaker 1: I basically never use it.
Speaker 0: I use it all the time, but I don't ever upgrade it.
Speaker 1: I use the Excel spreadsheet sometimes.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, because the Google spreadsheet is not...
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: But, if you said that the brand new Office was like 30 bucks, I'd be like, "I never used that, but why
Speaker 1: not?"
Speaker 1: Just to have it.
Speaker 1: You never know when you're going to need that.
Speaker 1: It helps.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But, Microsoft, you know, you're screwing things.
Speaker 1: Plus, some guy out there has a Mac and they want to do boot camp, pick up a copy of Windows for nothing.
Speaker 1: That'd be real useful.
Speaker 1: But, they don't do it.
Speaker 0: I feel like we could have a long conversation about this on a Monday because there's a lot... I could talk for a good hour about just what we're talking about right now.
Speaker 1: But, yeah, interesting stuff going on with the Windows 10.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'll upgrade for free probably on my laptop or HDPC to test it out.
Speaker 0: My laptop, I'll upgrade.
Speaker 0: My PC, I'm pretty much buying a new PC after Windows 10 comes out because this thing, it's getting near the end.
Speaker 1: Mine's just fine.
Speaker 1: When did you make your computer?
Speaker 1: A few years ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mine's from 2009.
Speaker 1: Mine's not that much older.
Speaker 1: Anyway...
Speaker 0: My CPU is only 2.97 gigahertz.
Speaker 1: Mine, probably three.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I'll upgrade to one computer to see how it goes and then do the rest if it's good.
Speaker 0: So, there is a lot of news that Scott doesn't want to talk about, like, you know, global politics and all the real stuff.
Speaker 1: Something doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there is something interesting going down, not just in the Windows world, but to kind of take a page from, oh, we're slipping all our tech news into Thursday.
Speaker 0: So, there's a little, like, slap fight going on between, like, Elon Musk and Lyft CEO and the people who do Uber and Google people.
Speaker 1: He's making cars and they're driving cars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so think about this.
Speaker 1: And Google is making cars that drive themselves.
Speaker 0: So, think about this.
Speaker 0: Why are they fighting?
Speaker 0: Let's say I make the self-driving car that works and, like, the government says, "Okay, those are allowed on the
Speaker 0: road.".
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Only, like, how long will it be before no one ever fucking needs a cab with a driver again?
Speaker 0: Not long.
Speaker 0: Uber drivers are fucked.
Speaker 0: Anyone who drives cars, as far as a job, no longer has a job.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, at the same time, Uber and Lyft both basically are going after the same market of you don't have a car and you need someone to drive you somewhere and you can't afford, like, a chauffeur.
Speaker 0: Uber is going down the road of, yeah, eventually Uber will just be nothing but self-driving cars.
Speaker 0: It's going to be fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: Oh, my gosh, no one needs to own a car.
Speaker 0: Lyft, the CEO, basically, like, a couple days ago went online and basically tried to make this argument that self-driving cars are not the future and never will be.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: And it seems like he is trying to placate his drivers because they need --.
Speaker 0: basically, all the people who drive cars for a living are really -- and pay attention -- are afraid of Uber, but they're also afraid of self-driving cars.
Speaker 0: So, Lyft is trying to get all those people on their side.
Speaker 0: See, these companies -- Because the statement, like, what he said is ridiculous.
Speaker 0: The idea that self-driving cars won't be the only cars on the road within 100 years is ludicrous.
Speaker 0: 100 years?
Speaker 0: Within 100 years?
Speaker 1: He said 100 years?
Speaker 0: No, I said within 100 years.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 1: His exact -- There might be someone out there driving a car for fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe, but maybe not on public roads.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but he's basically -- a prominent CEO is taking a ridiculous position on this just to cater to people who are afraid of losing their buggy whip manufacturer jobs.
Speaker 1: That's not the thing to point out.
Speaker 1: The thing to point out is that these CEOs in particular, right, are, like, the most -- you know, they came out with these arguments, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you look at Uber and Lyft and those companies.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: You know, even Tesla, right?
Speaker 1: They're coming out with these arguments.
Speaker 1: When they make their company, they're like, "Oh, we're going to disrupt the market.
Speaker 1: We don't care about your law that says we can't sell cars direct to the public," even though New Jersey just flipped and is letting them do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wonder who got bribed there.
Speaker 1: You know, Uber and Lyft are like, "We don't care about your taxi medallion laws and shit.
Speaker 1: We're just going to taxi
Speaker 1: anyway.".
Speaker 1: You know, Airbnb, they're like, "We're just going to hotel anyway.
Speaker 1: We don't care about your regulation laws and
Speaker 1: such.".
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: "We'll let the free market decide.
Speaker 1: If the free market's going to decide self-driving cars, fuck
Speaker 1: you!".
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Tough shit, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know, they're fine with their philosophy when it suits them, but as soon as the philosophy's not working in their favor, then they want to be all like, you know, "Oh, we better ban that self-driving car.
Speaker 0: That's going to hurt our
Speaker 0: business."
Speaker 0: Except, I think, self-driving cars, you know, I used to be worried that governments were going to fight them.
Speaker 0: Like, I think New York City is going to fight self-driving taxis more than, like, some nations have waged war.
Speaker 1: Why don't we just wage war then?
Speaker 1: If all the taxi drivers go to City Hall and try to fight the self-driving car, we'll just program our self-driving car to run them over.
Speaker 1: There'll be a lot less votes for the anti-self-driving car crowd.
Speaker 0: I thought you were a pacifist and you were anti-murder.
Speaker 1: Listen, there's only one way to get things done quickly.
Speaker 1: You either wait for the old people to die or you make the old people die.
Speaker 1: I'm in a hurry.
Speaker 0: I think...
Speaker 1: When you're not in a hurry, then you can wait for the old people to die.
Speaker 0: I think the old people...
Speaker 1: When you're getting old, well...
Speaker 0: Self-driving cars, this is kind of what I'm getting at.
Speaker 0: I'll link to these three articles because it's just kind of interesting to see, like, basically the Uber CEO was like, "Self-driving cars are definitely the
Speaker 0: future.".
Speaker 0: So Lyft was like, "They are definitely not the
Speaker 0: And meanwhile, Musk is like, "Yeah, we're just making the Teslas better and better because fuck
Speaker 0: everybody.".
Speaker 1: Well, he should make a self-driving Tesla.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll give it time.
Speaker 1: They actually added a really interesting thing to the Tesla.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I saw that on Slash.
Speaker 1: If you're driving a Tesla, the number one thing you worry about is, "Am I going to run out of power and be impossible for me to reach any power station for my
Speaker 1: Tesla?".
Speaker 1: So they have a new system.
Speaker 1: they just put out in an upgrade.
Speaker 1: And the new system will basically warn you if you're driving somewhere and it's like, "Listen, if you drive any further, you will not be able to recharge fucking anywhere and you will run out of battery.
Speaker 1: Turn around and go this way.
Speaker 1: That way you will stay in range and not be
Speaker 1: screwed.".
Speaker 0: Definitely a needed thing.
Speaker 1: So as long as you have the newest upgrade and you're not a dumbass, you will never have the situation of dead, uncharged Tesla out in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: Honestly, if I have to buy a car ahead of self-driving cars, I'll probably buy a Tesla or something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually.
Speaker 0: They're not that expensive.
Speaker 1: If I had to buy a car today and I could afford any car...
Speaker 0: If I had to buy a car today, I would buy a Tesla.
Speaker 1: I would probably just buy like...
Speaker 0: Because I still live here.
Speaker 1: They have that electric BMW.
Speaker 1: that's probably way more practical.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'd get a hybrid.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'd just get like a fucking Miata Roadster.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm just going to wait for the self-driving car and then not buy a car.
Speaker 0: To turn this into Thursday news, I think this is the one and possibly only technological issue where the old people are going to be our allies.
Speaker 0: Not the rich people, the old people.
Speaker 1: Why would the old people like self-driving cars?
Speaker 0: Because right now...
Speaker 1: They're going to be afraid the self-driving cars will kill people.
Speaker 0: Old people have a lot of trouble driving and lose autonomy.
Speaker 1: But old people like driving despite the fact that they can't.
Speaker 0: But at the same time...
Speaker 1: And they're going to be mad if you have some newfang or a whippersnapper self-driving car that's going to kill everybody.
Speaker 1: More so than they're going to kill everyone driving with bad eyesight and no reflexes.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, I think it'll be a pretty easy sell to a lot of old people, especially like one more generation out.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there will be some old people who basically are having... Because it's garbage.
Speaker 1: And cabs are expensive.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: They will be happy at a self-driving car, but...
Speaker 0: Enough old people... Because there is an increasing backlash against elderly drivers and the problems they're causing.
Speaker 0: I think if that backlash pushes a little bit further, once self-driving cars are feasible, that is a huge way for really old people to maintain the autonomy they had for most of their entire lives.
Speaker 1: But people don't vote for what's good for them.
Speaker 1: And the same old people, it's like, "Man, that healthcare would really help them
Speaker 1: out."
Speaker 1: And they vote against it anyway.
Speaker 1: So that's the reason that old people are a fucking problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they vote against that kind of stuff because it's a very abstract problem.
Speaker 0: This is a very direct problem.
Speaker 1: They're old people.
Speaker 1: You basically...
Speaker 0: No!
Speaker 0: Scott, you don't pay attention to enough politics.
Speaker 0: When you put old people in front of something that directly affects them in a way that they can see...
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they'll say, "Oh my god, it's an evil self-driving
Speaker 1: car!".
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the kind of things they do.
Speaker 0: if it directly affects them and hurts them, or at least they think it hurts them.
Speaker 1: They will think that it hurts them.
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: And they will be easily swayed by people like the Lyft CEO because they're old people.
Speaker 0: No, because I think there's a lot more money on the side of...
Speaker 1: Where is this sudden hope coming from?
Speaker 0: Because this is one area where those people do have real problems.
Speaker 1: I'll believe it well after I see it.
Speaker 0: You're, you know, I'm pretty fucking cynical, but you've kind of gone off the deep end of cynicism.
Speaker 1: The fact that old people are afraid of a car that drives itself, I'm pretty sure that is the much more likely scenario than old people loving some newfangled technology.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but when the choice becomes, you don't get to go anywhere ever, or...
Speaker 1: That choice they won't have.
Speaker 1: They'll just keep fighting to keep their driver's license, which is they have successfully done for a very long time.
Speaker 0: That is true, but what might also cause this is who manipulates the old people?
Speaker 0: Who does that?
Speaker 0: It's pretty much Fox News and Republicans in Congress, right?
Speaker 1: And why would they be in favor of the self-driving car?
Speaker 1: Because they are not.
Speaker 0: A lot of them don't actually have chauffeurs and drive themselves.
Speaker 0: All you need to do is get every one of those old-ass members of Congress free self-driving cars.
Speaker 1: You mean the same ones who will make laws about banning insider trading and then insider trade?
Speaker 1: They don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: They don't care if self-driving cars are illegal.
Speaker 1: They'll make them illegal and then fucking have one.
Speaker 1: They don't give a fuck.
Speaker 0: No, but here's the problem.
Speaker 0: If you bribe them with self-driving cars and they give them to their old relatives and all that kind of stuff, they might try to manipulate the laws to make sure they can keep playing with their toys and their families can keep playing with their toys.
Speaker 0: You gotta go for old, rich self-interest to then manipulate old, scared, non-self-interest.
Speaker 1: The old, rich self-interest is to have the toy that no one else has and make it illegal and still have it.
Speaker 0: Except on public roads, it's kinda hard to get away with that.
Speaker 1: How many Congress people have been homosexual and adulterous and then while simultaneously railing against that in Congress itself?
Speaker 0: However, I think that's different because a lot of those people are also religious and self-hating.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying.
Speaker 0: I mean, they're the ones who think that up.
Speaker 0: If gay marriage were legal, then wouldn't we all just be having sex with men all the time?
Speaker 1: You were basically describing a scenario in which people who are advanced in age and/or evil are agreeing with things that young and smart people agree with.
Speaker 1: Sometimes that happens.
Speaker 1: And that is not a scenario that will ever happen.
Speaker 0: It only happens if the thing is in the direct self-interest of the older, rich people.
Speaker 1: 'Cause all the times when it is not in their self-interest, they still don't do it.
Speaker 0: Well, because the voters are manipulated.
Speaker 1: What is the time that this happened?
Speaker 0: I'm sure there are examples of this happening.
Speaker 1: One time.
Speaker 1: Any one time.
Speaker 1: Even on the tiniest issue.
Speaker 0: Alright, alright.
Speaker 1: The most insignificant thing.
Speaker 0: The most insignificant thing.
Speaker 0: Can it be on a local level or does it have to be?
Speaker 1: It could be like one of those fucking bills in Congress that doesn't even count for anything.
Speaker 1: Like, we're going to declare something national hoozits day in honor of this little Timmy who had cancer or something.
Speaker 0: Alright, you know what?
Speaker 0: Old people are generally actually really against Daylight Saving Time and yet we still have it.
Speaker 1: Since when are old people against Daylight Savings Time?
Speaker 0: Actually, they are.
Speaker 0: Old people and parents tend to be against Daylight Saving Time.
Speaker 1: I thought parents are the ones who are for Daylight Savings Time.
Speaker 0: No, they're for not switching and for never being in the current good time where we have more daylight at night.
Speaker 1: Oh, so they're for the bad thing.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: And they got what they wanted.
Speaker 1: Well, they got what they wanted, which is to keep the switching happening.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is, I guess, they got half what they wanted.
Speaker 1: Which is the opposite of the smart thing, which is to only have Daylight Savings Time.
Speaker 0: The problem is no one's for that except, like, us.
Speaker 1: Listen, your example is not an example that met the requirements.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because the national level is real hard to come up with that on the fly.
Speaker 1: But you're saying that this one is going to happen.
Speaker 1: I think this one is going to happen.
Speaker 1: You don't have one example of it in all history, but this one, you're confident.
Speaker 0: Because I feel like, unlike most other political things... Rym feels it, everybody.
Speaker 1: Rym feels the world is changing, old people are suddenly smart and rich people aren't evil.
Speaker 1: It's going to happen.
Speaker 0: Like, you forget that, like, when it comes to computer stuff, for example...
Speaker 1: You heard it here first.
Speaker 0: It's abstract.
Speaker 0: Like, they have no idea what these things are.
Speaker 0: And 99% of what our government does is abstract, so people will vote based on...
Speaker 1: Because the old people are so in favor of drones delivering them goods by sky.
Speaker 0: They're not really comfortable with the idea of delivery, so I don't think that's even a factor.
Speaker 0: Just saying.
Speaker 1: Old people are afraid of technologies.
Speaker 1: Period.
Speaker 1: End of story.
Speaker 0: But you just put them in one of the cars... My mom.
Speaker 1: My grandparents.
Speaker 0: My grandpa was using the internet.
Speaker 1: I meant... I didn't mean an individual old person.
Speaker 0: That's what you said.
Speaker 0: Those are examples.
Speaker 1: I meant old people as a whole.
Speaker 0: Old people as a whole?
Speaker 0: You know what they really like?
Speaker 0: Medical technology that makes them be older.
Speaker 1: Except all they do is complain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know what?
Speaker 0: They want hospitals, they want Social Security and Medicare to keep taking care of them, and they get that.
Speaker 0: And actually those things are probably, on the average, good things.
Speaker 1: Exactly, and they vote against those things even though they say they want them.
Speaker 0: No, they vote for those things because they have a good name.
Speaker 0: They vote against the abstract changes to those things.
Speaker 1: Let's move on to...
Speaker 0: Okay, to what?
Speaker 1: Something that makes sense.
Speaker 0: So, things of the day.
Speaker 0: I linked to an episode in a conversation on Twitter that we did back in like 2007.
Speaker 0: Because it was relevant to a discussion.
Speaker 0: Partly because a friend of ours, who we both know and hang out with often, had never seen or heard of Odoru Daiso-Sasen.
Speaker 0: Odoru Daiso-Sasen?
Speaker 0: And I realized that that is some pretty fucking vintage geek nights there.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of people we know who we did not know back when we first watched that movie.
Speaker 1: That is good shit.
Speaker 1: Movie, TV show, it's all good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The first movie's the best.
Speaker 1: The first movie's amazing.
Speaker 0: The TV show's really good.
Speaker 0: The second movie's okay.
Speaker 1: The second, I think the later seasons of the TV show, not as good as the early first season.
Speaker 0: I only watched like the first five episodes and it was great.
Speaker 1: I saw all of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I should watch that whole thing.
Speaker 0: We should do a show on that show.
Speaker 1: You know, the later seasons are not... It sort of has a similar... You know, the quality of it sort of matches up nicely with the quality of another somewhat comedic police drama,
Speaker 1: "Patlabor."
Speaker 1: Or, "You're Under
Speaker 1: Arrest.".
Speaker 1: I haven't seen... I've seen as much "You're Under Arrest" as you've seen "Odoro
Speaker 1: Daiso-Sasen.".
Speaker 0: You at least saw the episode with the hurricane and the speeder?
Speaker 1: I remember something about a hurricane.
Speaker 0: Every time a hurricane comes to the city...
Speaker 1: This was like last decade, all right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: More than 10 years ago.
Speaker 0: So anyway, in this conversation, it turns out that the person I mentioned this to comes back to me and basically says, "Man, what I really want to see is that catwash
Speaker 0: video.".
Speaker 0: And I go to the actual episode page that I linked to.
Speaker 0: Fucking every link is broken.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: And I poked around a little bit.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure two-thirds plus of anything we've ever linked to on Geek Nights is a broken link now.
Speaker 1: Probably.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day is I found that video again.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: And I'm not going to go back and fix that link because that sets a precedent that I will never follow through on.
Speaker 0: But my thing of the day today was my thing of the day from 2007 re-uploaded in 2009.
Speaker 0: The catwash.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: My thing of the day is this dude biking on a bicycle in a ridiculously dangerous place.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: Well, Scott shows me the video.
Speaker 0: I'm like, "That looks pretty
Speaker 0: fun.".
Speaker 0: And then the camera pans around.
Speaker 0: I'm like, "Whoa.
Speaker 0: Never
Speaker 0: mind.".
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 1: I don't know how this guy doesn't fall to his death, but that is why it is a video you should watch.
Speaker 0: You know what it's like?
Speaker 0: It's like the goats that walk on the sheer cliffs.
Speaker 1: I don't know how the fuck they do that.
Speaker 1: But this guy's on a bicycle.
Speaker 1: Bicycle.
Speaker 1: That's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: On a near horizontal, near vertical slope going sideways across it.
Speaker 0: So in the meta moment, we're going to be this weekend.
Speaker 0: Well, next weekend.
Speaker 0: Next weekend.
Speaker 0: Next weekend, the 26th or whatever, at Zenkai Con doing a bunch of panels on Saturday and Sunday.
Speaker 0: And then the weekend right after that, we're going to be at Anime Boston doing a bunch of panels Friday, Saturday, and Sunday.
Speaker 1: You mean just Saturday and Sunday, not Friday?
Speaker 0: We'll have some panels Friday, but not in the morning.
Speaker 1: I guess if we leave early Friday morning.
Speaker 0: We already booked.
Speaker 0: We're going there Friday early morning.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay then.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: You don't remember?
Speaker 0: We're taking like a 6 a.m.
Speaker 0: fucking train.
Speaker 1: We'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're going to not take that train?
Speaker 1: No, I have to take that train.
Speaker 0: But we don't know our schedule yet for Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Good job, Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: I assume we're going and presenting.
Speaker 0: And Zenkai Con, we know our schedule and I guess we'll link to it.
Speaker 0: I think it's up by now or whatever.
Speaker 0: And the Book Club book is still a water ship down.
Speaker 0: Scott has to read it.
Speaker 0: It's about rabbits.
Speaker 0: Pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: Rabbit.
Speaker 0: Yeah?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You obviously haven't read any of it yet.
Speaker 1: I haven't read any recently.
Speaker 0: Oh, actually one of these things today is still there.
Speaker 0: The Cthulhu Quiz Show.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what the hell that is.
Speaker 0: Lovecraft was a category on a mastermind in the UK.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: So that is still there.
Speaker 0: And I just liked it.
Speaker 0: So there we go.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: So we're going to talk about El San Antonio Tejas.
Speaker 0: It's kind of weird to review a place, but we ended up spending a lot of time in that place.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, I'd never been to Tejas, despite it having so many stereotypes and portrayals in media.
Speaker 1: I thought I knew stuff about it.
Speaker 0: I knew about it from watching Davy Crockett, particularly the Alamo.
Speaker 0: I knew about it from high school social studies class.
Speaker 1: So thanks to Pac South, we went to San Antonio and thanks to the weather in New York, we ended up staying there for an extra day or two.
Speaker 0: Now, I took a bunch of notes and I found them the other day because, you know, it's been a long time since Pac South and we didn't do a bunch of shows in that interim.
Speaker 0: So I don't have my notes on me and I'm not worried about that because there's only like two things to say about San Antonio.
Speaker 1: So, I mean, basically, you know, despite the name of the place and the fact that it's in Texas, there aren't a lot of cowboys roaming around.
Speaker 1: There were some.
Speaker 1: There are definitely not zero.
Speaker 0: There were a lot of cowboy hats around.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it wasn't like super cowboy town, yee-haw, giddy-up, saloon action.
Speaker 1: That's a, you know, the stereotype is there and only small parts.
Speaker 1: It's about the same as if you come to New York.
Speaker 1: How many New York guys you meet on the street?
Speaker 0: Like eight or nine.
Speaker 1: Not too many.
Speaker 0: You want to get to Midtown, you got to take the BRT to the MIM.
Speaker 1: The BMT.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's about the same, right?
Speaker 0: BRT, BMT.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, if you go to Boston, how many Boston, Harvard Yard guys you can see there?
Speaker 0: Everyone there.
Speaker 0: Everyone in that city is like that.
Speaker 1: It's about the same percentage, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know, that's different about it.
Speaker 1: The weather.
Speaker 1: The first day we got there, I mean, it was winter.
Speaker 1: It was a little bit cold.
Speaker 0: Way too cold.
Speaker 1: Still warmer than New York was, which had a crazy snowstorm at the time.
Speaker 1: But then it warmed up.
Speaker 1: It wasn't shorts weather, but, you know, for winter, I'll take it.
Speaker 0: So we'll tell the story.
Speaker 0: Before they announced where PAX was, other than that people, you know, people who was in Texas, all the people who don't know better assumed it was going to be in like Austin because that's where they know the nerds are and they like Austin.
Speaker 0: But turns out that most of the cities in Texas, despite being pretty big, are garbage for conventions.
Speaker 0: And Austin is like super garbage for conventions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Austin does not have the hotels necessary to support a PAX-like convention.
Speaker 0: Yep, let alone the convention center space and the infrastructure.
Speaker 1: Antonio has a convention center and a lot of hotels.
Speaker 0: A really nice convention center, actually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, very nice.
Speaker 0: Like, I would, I prefer that convention center over PAX East convention center.
Speaker 1: I guess it has a little, it's a little more complicated to get around, but it had enough space.
Speaker 0: And the spaces were better in some senses.
Speaker 0: The expo hall was not, but at the same time, I don't like the expo halls, though.
Speaker 0: You can see my bias there.
Speaker 0: But we, because we'd never been to Texas, thought, all right, we'll get there like Thursday night, we'll do PAX, and then we'll stick around for a couple days and do Texas.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That was a fucking mistake.
Speaker 1: And the weather kept us there an extra day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I thought there would be enough things to occupy a whole day of visiting San Antonio, and I actually ended up with two days to visit San Antonio.
Speaker 0: Well, first, the problem was our friends showed up like early on Thursday, spent like four hours doing everything there is to do in San Antonio, and then played board games.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Then they all left, and we were in Texas with like two of our friends, alone.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And then we both got sick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we ran out of things to do very quickly, and that was it.
Speaker 1: So San Antonio is a relatively high population city, but it doesn't seem like a lot of people live in the city part.
Speaker 1: They live, you know, outside the city.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's really wide and really flat and not very tall.
Speaker 1: There are a few tall buildings, but not that many.
Speaker 1: But like the downtown, despite the fact that- Seattle had more tall buildings, despite being less populous.
Speaker 0: Like the population is one and a half million, like it's a huge city population-wise.
Speaker 0: But like walking around, it felt like a dumpy, Lancaster-type place.
Speaker 0: Like walking around the streets at night, they were empty, pretty much everywhere.
Speaker 0: All the shit was closed.
Speaker 0: A lot of places looked like Hartford-style, like you can't even go into them.
Speaker 0: And aggressive and otherwise ne'er-do-wellish characters were hassling and being around on the street all over the place.
Speaker 1: Well, part of the reason for this is because the highlight in all of San Antonio is this thing called the Riverwalk.
Speaker 1: So the Riverwalk is basically, there's these rivers that go around San Antonio.
Speaker 1: There's like a big river, and then it sort of branches off and loops around the city a bit.
Speaker 1: And that Riverwalk is like below street level.
Speaker 1: So all around the city, you'll see stairs that go down to the Riverwalk.
Speaker 1: And you can walk around down there, and there's a river, and you can get a boat that'll take you around that river.
Speaker 1: And it's got these nice walking paths on both sides of it.
Speaker 0: And there's a bunch of restaurants.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and all that's down there is basically tons of restaurants.
Speaker 1: And of course, if you want to walk around the city, it's easier to just go down to the Riverwalk, walk along it, not have to worry about street crossings or anything, and then go up the stairs close to your location.
Speaker 0: But like most of the city that we saw, we pretty much went everywhere that was in walking distance of PAX.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is pretty much all of downtown.
Speaker 1: Every place that there was real stuff in San Antonio.
Speaker 0: If you leave the Riverwalk, a lot of really shitty places.
Speaker 0: And if you get to the places that have stuff going on, most of them are just parking garages and office towers and businesses you can't get into and no one on the streets.
Speaker 1: Right, well what the Riverwalk does, you gotta understand, so you'll be on the Riverwalk, and you'll see a restaurant on the Riverwalk directly.
Speaker 1: That restaurant is part of a building.
Speaker 1: If you look up at that building at street level, you'll see it's kind of tall.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's apartments in it or something, or offices.
Speaker 1: But if you go up to street level to that building, you can't really get in.
Speaker 1: There's no entrances or anything.
Speaker 0: There'll be a sign that's like, "Go to the Riverwalk," and a barred up door.
Speaker 1: Right, and the reason is because the restaurants are on the Riverwalk, instead of having the storage in the basement, the actual restaurant is in the basement, and the first floor is what would be the basement of any other restaurant in, say, New York City or any other city.
Speaker 1: So, on the street level where the sidewalks are and the cars are, there's a lot less storefronts and a lot less stuff in general.
Speaker 0: The other ramification of this, and this might sound very oddly specific, is that there are vents in the street around the outside of the Riverwalk, pumping out frightening quantities of foul-smelling air.
Speaker 0: Like, high pressure, like enough to, like, you will be surprised by it, and it smells like ass.
Speaker 1: I smelled it in a few places, not that many, though.
Speaker 0: I bumped into it more when I, 'cause remember, I walked off a couple times at night to try to get coffee, 'cause it turns out that all the Starbuckses are, like, in office towers and in malls and things, and you just can't get coffee anymore.
Speaker 1: It's very Hartford-like in that sense.
Speaker 1: It's not a place, I saw one grocery store, I think.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the downtown, like, clears out.
Speaker 1: It doesn't seem to be a place where people live.
Speaker 1: Most of the people seem to be working, staying in hotels, going to PAX, or waiting to get some sort of public transportation or car to get in or out to go to where people actually live.
Speaker 0: What was really interesting is walking around the Riverwalk, 'cause, like, a lot of PAX people didn't seem to go down there for dinner.
Speaker 0: Like, we did, and, like, a lot of the enforcers did, a lot of the speakers did, but, like, the average attendees seemed to come in, do PAX, eat lunch at, like, a local place, and drive home, because 90% of PAX felt like locals.
Speaker 1: It was very local PAX.
Speaker 1: Not, it didn't seem like a very large number of people at all had traveled any distance to get to this PAX.
Speaker 0: The hotels were dead at night.
Speaker 0: Like, no one was gaming.
Speaker 1: Uh, no, the lobby of Hartell was pretty crazy every night.
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't.
Speaker 0: There were, like, 15 people down there.
Speaker 1: No, it was a lot, but they were all drinking.
Speaker 1: There wasn't a lot of gaming going on.
Speaker 0: There was no gaming.
Speaker 0: There were, like, 15 or 20 people standing around drinking.
Speaker 1: There were a lot more than 15 or 20 people getting drunk in the hotel.
Speaker 0: Unless you count the restaurant.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the whole, yeah, the lobby didn't have anything.
Speaker 1: They were all in the hotel/restaurant area getting wasted.
Speaker 0: Well, there was that little bar, and then there was the restaurant.
Speaker 0: The restaurant was crowded.
Speaker 0: The bar didn't have that many people there, 'cause it had very few tables.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was no tables, but people were getting drunk instead of gaming at night.
Speaker 1: And the PAX people were still rocking the bottom of the hotel.
Speaker 0: No, they were not rocking it.
Speaker 0: The people who were down there was also a lot of non-PAX people, and no one was really gaming that much.
Speaker 1: They definitely weren't gaming, 'cause there were no tables.
Speaker 1: But there were PAX people, you know, filling the bottom of the hotel every night of PAX.
Speaker 0: I think you misremember, there were very few people down there.
Speaker 1: There were people down there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: Not that many.
Speaker 1: There weren't plenty.
Speaker 0: Noooo.
Speaker 0: I probably took some pictures with my phone.
Speaker 0: I can go look.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: I'm highly dubious of your accounts, 'cause I went down there to try to get a drink, and I went back upstairs because there wasn't much going on on Saturday.
Speaker 0: Or Sunday.
Speaker 0: Sunday.
Speaker 1: Well, Sunday, everyone already left already.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, Sunday, yeah, no one from PAX stuck around except us and the people who were stranded by the blizzard.
Speaker 1: They bailed the hell out of that PAX.
Speaker 0: But then walking around on the riverwalk, almost everyone we ran into who was not from PAX... Was old people.
Speaker 0: Was, like, 40s and up, like, families with kids who had obviously driven in for, like, the afternoon and dinner and then were driving out.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Or really, really old people, like, having dinner together.
Speaker 0: Or tourists taking pictures of everything.
Speaker 1: There were also a lot of military people, 'cause apparently there's a military base nearby, and when you go on leave, the thing to do is to, you know, find your family and hang out in San Antonio.
Speaker 1: And go get dinner on the riverwalk.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So, you know, the riverwalk itself is kinda nice.
Speaker 1: You walk along a river and there's restaurants.
Speaker 1: The restaurants aren't, you know, we ate at a whole bunch of 'em, not all of 'em, obviously.
Speaker 0: They were okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, none of them were like, "Oh my god, this is amazing.
Speaker 1: Like, I remember that restaurant.
Speaker 1: I have to go back
Speaker 1: there.".
Speaker 1: But none of them were like, "Oh my god, it's disgusting.
Speaker 1: I'll never go back there
Speaker 1: again.".
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: They were all, like, really average-y.
Speaker 0: Like, I'd say a step or two down from Providence in terms of, like, the restaurant feel in that area.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you would think that, like, you know, since it was so close to Mexico, there'd be, like, some amazing fuckin' Mexican foods or really good Texas barbecue or, you know, Texas foods would be amazing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the barbecue was okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, we had a barbecue.
Speaker 1: It was edible barbecue.
Speaker 1: I found Mexican foods.
Speaker 1: We tried, like, at least two different ones.
Speaker 0: We had so much free time.
Speaker 1: The one we had on the last night with Katsu.
Speaker 0: What was that place called?
Speaker 0: The Cafe Rosario?
Speaker 1: No, I forget what it was, but that was, like, the giant restaurant that had, like, rooms and rooms and rooms and it was super crowded.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so basically, we had so much time to kill that me and Scott and Katsu, we were just, like, Googling and doing research, like, "What is the best barbecue in San Antonio?
Speaker 0: What is the best
Speaker 0: Mexican?".
Speaker 0: 'Cause when we did that for PAX Australia...
Speaker 1: It worked really well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like, we looked for... We found the best teppanyaki restaurant in Melbourne, and you know what?
Speaker 1: It was the best teppanyaki I've had, period.
Speaker 0: It was, like, a hundred bucks each.
Speaker 1: You get what you pay for.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, it was amazing.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Did you go back there?
Speaker 0: The best... I didn't go back there.
Speaker 0: I went to other places.
Speaker 1: Mistakes.
Speaker 0: While I had very, very good food, I felt like I did not need to have hundred dollar food.
Speaker 0: I had, like, forty dollar sushi.
Speaker 1: I feel like I need that every night.
Speaker 1: Alright, anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so actually, near in Melbourne by the new convention center, the food scene is the best food scene of any PAX ever.
Speaker 0: Better than PAX Prime.
Speaker 0: The food around PAX Australia in Melbourne, there is a sushi place that is fucking legit.
Speaker 0: And it's right there, and it was, like...
Speaker 1: Nothing's on the water.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you can just walk right in, too.
Speaker 1: More close to the New York.
Speaker 0: A lot closer to the New York.
Speaker 0: So, we were like,
Speaker 0: "Alright.".
Speaker 0: Everyone said, like, everything on the internet said this place was the Mexican food place.
Speaker 0: The cantina.
Speaker 0: So, we're walking there, and it's a long walk because everyone drives everywhere.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And we pass.
Speaker 1: We weren't really in downtown San Antonio anymore at this point.
Speaker 1: It was basically, like, outside of the downtown by a few blocks.
Speaker 0: It reminded me of a quiet version of, like, Fitzroy or, like, the weird parts of Williamsburg.
Speaker 0: They're kind of off the strip.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, we're walking, we walk past a ton of, like, farm to table or wine bar.
Speaker 0: Like, the kind of places we eat at in, like, Queens.
Speaker 0: And they're all empty.
Speaker 0: Like, they're open, and there's, like, one couple eating in the restaurant.
Speaker 0: One restaurant was completely empty, and there's a waiter, like, standing outside.
Speaker 0: And he looked at us, and he didn't even try to, like, make us come in.
Speaker 1: I guess they don't do that there.
Speaker 0: So, and we're getting worried, like, "Whoa, this is all empty and scary and dark, and what's going on?
Speaker 0: Why is no one
Speaker 0: out?".
Speaker 0: And then, we see this place in the distance.
Speaker 0: It is enormous.
Speaker 0: It had extra- Hundreds of tables.
Speaker 1: It had a back room with, like, a zillion tables that wasn't even filled yet, and there was, like, one party of, like, ten in there using a big long table, and that was it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hundreds of tables.
Speaker 0: This place was enormous.
Speaker 1: While it was enormous, it was crowded.
Speaker 1: In the main area where the bar was and all the TVs were, it was, like, every table had people at it.
Speaker 0: And it was super loud, but not because of music.
Speaker 0: Just from, like, the boisterous people all talking.
Speaker 0: And it was actually, like, it was the right volume level for that environment.
Speaker 0: Like, it wasn't too loud.
Speaker 0: We could talk.
Speaker 0: That was, like, the third best Mexican food I've ever had.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it wasn't Cafe Maya.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, it was close, though.
Speaker 0: It's the first place I've eaten at in a long time that is even in the running.
Speaker 0: Like, it was really, really good food.
Speaker 1: But I thought there would be a preponderance of quality Mexican, but there wasn't really.
Speaker 0: I mean, we have weird tastes because we particularly seek out, like, Yucatan-style Mexican food, which is, like, a weird, like, that is not well represented in Mexican restaurants in the U.S Anyway, but yeah, the food, alright, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hard to get breakfast.
Speaker 1: Very hard to get breakfast.
Speaker 1: There were not, like, diners or, you know.
Speaker 0: There was one diner.
Speaker 0: We ate there, like, three times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was one place we ate at a lot.
Speaker 1: Very frequently.
Speaker 1: You know, it also had, you know, it was like a German kind of place.
Speaker 1: It had, you know.
Speaker 0: Shiloh's you're thinking of.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it had wieners.
Speaker 1: They had, you know, pancakes.
Speaker 1: They had all that kind of good stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just, like, good old, like, German/diner food, like, comfort food.
Speaker 0: That was a really good place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like a deli situation.
Speaker 1: It was right next to our hotel and the convention center.
Speaker 1: So, it was very crowded there on the PAX days, on the good hours.
Speaker 1: But it was very good.
Speaker 1: But it wasn't like any food you can't get anywhere else.
Speaker 1: It was just a really convenient, good place to eat at for that location.
Speaker 0: So, I feel like there is, at most, one and a half days of stuff to do in that city.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, there are things that you could do there that would take longer, right?
Speaker 1: So, we saw that they had, like, a big concert hall.
Speaker 1: So, it's like we could have gone to see, like, performances there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there wasn't much on the schedule.
Speaker 1: There's the Alamo Drafthouse.
Speaker 1: You can go see a movie there and it's all fancy.
Speaker 0: They were showing, like, boob animes that we didn't bother.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was actually an anime night because we were there an extra day.
Speaker 1: But it was, like, Funimation's night and it was garbage anime.
Speaker 1: So, and whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, really booby.
Speaker 1: You can see the Alamo itself.
Speaker 1: That takes about an hour if you take your time.
Speaker 0: Well, if you really, really, you could get maybe two hours out of that place.
Speaker 1: If you read every single plaque.
Speaker 0: Which we did.
Speaker 1: So, the Alamo is a famous place.
Speaker 1: Not going to talk about the history of the Alamo.
Speaker 1: You can Wikipedia that.
Speaker 1: But the thing they don't tell you because they don't allow video or photos of the inside is that inside of it is pretty much a gun museum.
Speaker 1: It's just guns.
Speaker 0: Well, there was a special gun exhibit.
Speaker 0: That's what was going on.
Speaker 0: Oh, was it?
Speaker 0: That's not permanent.
Speaker 1: Oh, what's usually in there then?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: They move stuff around, I guess.
Speaker 1: Inside the Alamo itself, the main building, I mean, I guess the whole thing is the Alamo, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It was mostly just guns in cases.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was a special exhibit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but, you know, the rest of it is just, like, is the history of the Alamo and there's a gift shop and there's a library and there's a nice garden.
Speaker 0: It was, like, really balanced and interesting.
Speaker 1: It doesn't cost anything to go in there?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it set up, like, the history before and after and during.
Speaker 0: It was a really good museum, actually.
Speaker 1: It's not a waste of your time to go see it.
Speaker 1: And the history that they presented there was not, like, a ridiculous made-up history like some museums in other countries.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Turkey.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it just doesn't take a lot of time.
Speaker 1: It's, like, a quick stop.
Speaker 0: I think we burned about three and a half hours in there, but that involved, like, an hour of just sitting in the very pleasant gardens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we just sat in the garden, like, "Ah, wow, it's nice and warm.
Speaker 1: Isn't this
Speaker 1: great?".
Speaker 1: Right now in New York, there's a horrible snowstorm.
Speaker 0: I mean, if you're in San Antonio, like, take half a day in the Alamo area and just literally, like, hang out in those gardens and just relax.
Speaker 0: It's really pleasant.
Speaker 1: There's not much else you're going to do anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We went to, like, every museum in the whole city.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we even went to -- so we're walking around.
Speaker 0: So we went to -- they have, you know, the World's Fair there a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Super long time ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so they had this tower, and it's one of those, like, "We made this tower for the World's Fair,".
Speaker 0: but they kept it going.
Speaker 0: And there's this whole, like, Tower of the Americas park around it.
Speaker 0: that's kind of like if Queens was in more repair.
Speaker 0: And it was pleasant.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That killed two hours walking around.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we went to the -- I think it was a mine or something like that.
Speaker 0: Or, like, a refinery.
Speaker 0: Like, we couldn't really tell, but it was really big to the point that we were trying to, like, figure out how far away it was to make sure it wasn't as big as we thought it was.
Speaker 1: We put some money in, like, the binocular machine to see this thing, and it was enormous.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like, enormous enough to be startling.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And because it's so flat and nothing's tall, like, you can see things that are really far away, and it's so dry.
Speaker 1: And there was a lot of stuff between us and this thing, but it was really tall, like, above the horizon.
Speaker 0: And really just blocky and huge and awesome.
Speaker 0: Like, that's where Ava's are.
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably.
Speaker 1: There's some kind of infrastructure mine thing out there.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: So then, like, we come out of that thing, and we're kind of walking around with Katsu, and we pass by this museum, and we're like, "Whoa, what's
Speaker 0: this?".
Speaker 1: It's free!
Speaker 1: Let's go in!
Speaker 1: Yeah, we go in, and -- The guy who's in there was so happy that someone was coming in.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: It was a free museum.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he was beside himself.
Speaker 0: We go in, it was, like, this awesome, like, Mexican-American art and culture museum.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we saw lots of cool Mexican-American arts in there.
Speaker 1: It was really nice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are all these exhibits and, like, different movements in, like, Mexican art specifically.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like, because the place is so close to Mexico, right, San Antonio, there's a lot of Mexican things there besides food, and especially museums and the arts.
Speaker 1: So it's, like, a lot of Maya, Inca, Aztec-type art exhibits and things.
Speaker 1: If you're going to museums, you're gonna see a lot of it.
Speaker 1: You don't see too much of it just out and about in the city, but as soon as you go in anywhere, you see a lot of that, a lot of that everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we also went to, like, the big art museum, which was, like, a city art museum.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but since we had the extra day, we just went walking on the Riverwalk as far as we could because nothing else to do, and we stumbled across, like, the main art museum.
Speaker 1: It was, like, the, you know, the big one of the city.
Speaker 0: The thing is, it was a long walk away.
Speaker 1: We didn't even see it, and this is a real-sized museum, the kind you can't see all of in one day unless that's all you do.
Speaker 1: You know, they had some Greeks and Roman statues, and they had, you know, actual old, you know, Aztec Maya arts and Native American stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the special exhibit was the Rockefellers had commissioned a bunch of Picasso tapestries.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they commissioned this French weaver to weave tapestries that were the same as Picasso paintings, and they were in this museum, and that was pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Scott got in trouble for taking pictures of him, though.
Speaker 1: I didn't actually take a picture of one.
Speaker 1: You were going to.
Speaker 1: I was gonna.
Speaker 0: To be fair, the guy got kind of surly with us.
Speaker 1: The guy got surly, and I was like, "I didn't see any sign.
Speaker 1: that said I can't,".
Speaker 1: and he's like, "Yeah, there's two signs out
Speaker 1: there.".
Speaker 0: He was like, "There's signs
Speaker 0: everywhere.".
Speaker 1: When I went out there, there were two signs out in the front, just by the door.
Speaker 0: On either side of the door, far apart.
Speaker 1: One of them didn't say anything about photos.
Speaker 1: It said something about something else.
Speaker 0: It said, "No food or drink," and the other one looked identical unless you got way close to it.
Speaker 1: It was a small sign, maybe four inches to six inches square, and in a relatively small font.
Speaker 1: It should have had a picture of a camera with a big red circle with a line through it.
Speaker 1: It just said, "Yeah, no photography in
Speaker 1: here.".
Speaker 0: See, think about this UX experience.
Speaker 0: You have two signs that look identical from a distance.
Speaker 0: One of them says, "No food," and one of them says, "No
Speaker 0: photography.".
Speaker 0: Guess what?
Speaker 1: If you go to museums in New York, they have the picture of the camera with the big red Ghostbusters thing around it.
Speaker 1: They put it on fucking every wall like, "Fuck
Speaker 1: you.".
Speaker 0: "It's right
Speaker 0: there.".
Speaker 1: "No excuses, assholes.
Speaker 1: We're an asshole museum that won't let you take pictures when we should just let
Speaker 1: you.".
Speaker 0: It was a pleasant museum.
Speaker 1: Yeah, very nice.
Speaker 0: Very, very standard museum.
Speaker 0: I saw a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cool stuff.
Speaker 0: I spent a lot of time trying to place what was going on in these Inca Aztec Mayan times next to what was going on in other parts of the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, since there aren't a lot of arts from that particular region up in this part of the country, we were able to look and see timelines of like, "Oh, at the same time, Aztecs doing this, Romans doing
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 1: Ooh, history books don't usually teach you that very well.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I get it.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: That killed four hours.
Speaker 0: That was a pleasant time, and the walk was pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Though the Riverwalk pretty much is just a jogging trail after a few blocks of restaurants.
Speaker 1: The part of it that's a circle that goes around the inside of the city and is in near the hotels and everything, that part has all the restaurants and everything, but it keeps going.
Speaker 1: The river keeps going, and there's even locks and stuff where it hits the real river.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we had so much time.
Speaker 0: We saw the locks were going to be used.
Speaker 0: We waited and watched the full locking process.
Speaker 0: What else are we going to do?
Speaker 1: But when you go there, there's no restaurants anymore.
Speaker 0: There's nothing.
Speaker 0: You go up out of the Riverwalk, and there's just the backs of condos.
Speaker 0: What's weird is that biking, they encourage like, "Oh, yeah, it's also a bike
Speaker 0: path.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, you just want to fall in the river, don't you?
Speaker 0: That thing is not a bike path.
Speaker 0: One, if we were biking, it would have taken us like four minutes to get to that museum.
Speaker 1: Also the stairs.
Speaker 0: But yet we saw tourists.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine tourists don't fall into that river every day somewhere.
Speaker 1: I didn't see anyone fall in.
Speaker 1: I was waiting for it.
Speaker 0: I was amazed.
Speaker 0: no one fell in.
Speaker 1: San Antonio otherwise just didn't have anything going on.
Speaker 1: that was memorable.
Speaker 0: It has a huge population, and it has some of the things that come with a huge population, like relatively good restaurants and concentration, art big for real museums.
Speaker 1: A convention center.
Speaker 0: But it didn't have any of the other things that big cities have.
Speaker 0: Boston is a way, way smaller city, both by size and population.
Speaker 0: Yet Boston feels like a city.
Speaker 0: Boston feels like there's stuff around you, like I can find a restaurant and a bodega.
Speaker 1: Basically, even during weekdays, there were really no cars.
Speaker 1: I mean, there were cars, but it wasn't high traffic ever.
Speaker 1: Whereas in Boston, it's like cars, cars, cars, cars, cars, cars, cars, cars.
Speaker 1: Constantly, and all the roads.
Speaker 1: Also, they have a sports team, the Spurs.
Speaker 0: I just saw the Spurs get their asses kicked by the Knicks.
Speaker 1: But that stadium is well out of the town.
Speaker 1: It's not like it's in downtown or anything.
Speaker 1: Boston, a smaller city, has a baseball stadium right in the city.
Speaker 1: And that causes a lot of happening stuff to happen.
Speaker 0: What was interesting though, I remember we went up into that tower, and there were people who have houses, like regular old houses with yards, like I lived in suburbia, that were easily like a 10-minute bike ride from the center of downtown.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: That was weird.
Speaker 1: Houses with backyards.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And I looked at like, they're not even that expensive.
Speaker 1: The Alamo Dome was there.
Speaker 1: We can see that.
Speaker 1: That's where, I forget which college football team, it belongs to a university.
Speaker 1: But it's ginormous because it's college football, right?
Speaker 1: And that's just outside the city near those houses.
Speaker 0: There was that weird building that had all the defensive-looking berms around it and things.
Speaker 0: We didn't quite figure, it was like some cultural institute.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then there's like a judge training center or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It got all kinds of, you know, there's stuff there, but it's very wide, very spread out, very not-.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you get the impression that the nightlife there is, if you live out in the suburbs, and you drive into the downtown to do stuff, and then drive back home.
Speaker 0: So you don't get like the benefits of living- Or you do stuff out in that suburb.
Speaker 1: You don't really need to come all the way to the downtown.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it'd be like living in Beacon if Beacon were closer to like a place with jobs.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are definitely places to work there.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: But like the downtown just felt really hollow and empty.
Speaker 0: And we spent a lot of time walking around like during weekdays, during weeknights, weekend days, weekend nights.
Speaker 0: They all felt pretty much the same.
Speaker 0: Like rush hour, you didn't see more people, you just saw like more traffic leaving.
Speaker 0: And like restaurant time, it got crowded, but it was only like tourists and like- PAX people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, tourists and PAX people and old people and families.
Speaker 0: It is weird that we saw a lot of people who were obviously like on vacation there.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like I can't imagine going there just to be there.
Speaker 0: Like unless I was on a road trip on my way to somewhere else, I would not go to San Antonio.
Speaker 1: Well I imagine that kind of vacation isn't like you come spend a week in San Antonio.
Speaker 1: It's like maybe you live in Dallas.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's like alright, why don't we go, you know, have a nice weekend, let's go to San Antonio.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's nicer than Dallas for a weekend.
Speaker 0: But like I like Providence, but I would only ever visit Providence primarily to see some friends, not to see the Providence things.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: But if you're old and you're retired, what else are you going to do?
Speaker 0: Play games.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: So yeah, San Antonio, I'll probably see you again next year because I guess I'll just go to PAX again, but- Yeah, but otherwise- Yeah, I'm coming in Thursday night and I'm leaving Monday morning.
Speaker 1: I might even leave Sunday night just to get the hell out.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I like having dinner and hanging out after a PAX.
Speaker 1: I can get a really late flight.
Speaker 1: I still won't go to work Monday.
Speaker 0: True.
Speaker 0: I've done that.
Speaker 0: I don't like having the flight hanging over my head.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando Kay for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.