Speaker 0: It's Monday April 27th 2015.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: It's a tech news roundup mostly about Google.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: And yeah, I know it's weird.
Speaker 0: We're doing a Monday show.
Speaker 0: This is the first time in a long long time.
Speaker 0: It's not broken.
Speaker 0: It's not supposed to be a Monday week Yes, but I was in London and Mumbai last week and I'm gonna be in Hong Kong next week, and I'm busy tomorrow.
Speaker 0: so it was now or never.
Speaker 0: I Promise we'll be back in a normal schedule.
Speaker 1: We can do a Thursday show on Thursday.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: we can but after next week I'll be back from Hong Kong and I have no significant travel until Connecticut, but anyway, so a while ago I was talking about what phone I should buy and it was all speculative and I had to make the decision because When I got to London after Mumbai I landed I had a whole day of meetings the next day like all over the city And I hang my jacket up and I sit down I turn on my laptop and I start typing and doing like sending emails And then I hear a little chh Like glass shattering.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's weird.
Speaker 0: So I kind of look around the room and I'm like, you know when you hear weird noise I'm like looking and I kind of ignore it.
Speaker 0: and then later I go to get my phone Out of my jacket and the screen had literally exploded from air pressure or something.
Speaker 0: I mean that phone was a nexus.
Speaker 0: for that I brought to Australia like the previous Australia trip and I've beaten the shit out of that phone.
Speaker 0: I've dropped it a million times and it's just been invincible.
Speaker 0: I Imagine like there was some fault or some like micro fracture that had been there from all this collected damage and then flying a whole Bunch in a row and then like being in London and the temperatures and whatever just finally caused it to give up the ghost.
Speaker 0: so Let me tell you it is that was lit.
Speaker 0: there was the first time in a long long long time that I did not have a Smartphone in a situation where I expected to have a smartphone.
Speaker 1: Oh, it really sucks, doesn't it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what anyone who says like oh you should try the disconnected life like leave your smartphone at home like, you know fuck that.
Speaker 0: smartphones are a Necessary sense for the modern era.
Speaker 0: the the life that we led before we had always connected smartphones Was a disastrous life.
Speaker 0: I Mean I had to like.
Speaker 0: the worst thing is I had all these meetings So suddenly I'd like go to Google Maps and like figure out where all the meetings were and how to get to them in Advance.
Speaker 0: that took like an hour when I could have just walked out the door the next day not giving a fuck And then I went to go to bed and I reached my phone to set an alarm.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: So now I have to like figure out how to use this like jank ass Non-smart like radio phone in the room to get an alarm in the morning.
Speaker 0: and you know what that UX was so bad.
Speaker 0: I was so Unconfident in my ability to do this that I set a test alarm For five minutes from them just to make sure the fucking thing worked.
Speaker 0: I didn't oversleep through my meeting.
Speaker 1: I would have done the same thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Not having that phone?
Speaker 0: and the thing is everyone always says like oh not having the smartphone like you'll pay attention more.
Speaker 0: You won't be distracted by your phone at no point.
Speaker 0: Did I miss the phones?
Speaker 0: like Twitter garbage.
Speaker 0: that stuff's like Pleasant but not important.
Speaker 0: I missed maps getting phone calls getting emails and texts Looking things up like the stuff I actually use in my daily life.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I had to decide and I did in fact buy a new phone.
Speaker 0: I bought a used refurbished Nexus 5 Because literally it is still the best non iPhone money can buy.
Speaker 1: I why did you just get an iPhone?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm kind of wait cuz I want to wait till September.
Speaker 1: but September it's gonna be like the iPhone 6s.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be like you're gonna be on the bad schedule.
Speaker 1: I'm on the good schedule.
Speaker 1: I get the major upgrade.
Speaker 0: I want to wait till September to see what happens because there might be a Sony like z4 z5 compact.
Speaker 0: so I I was very close to saying fuck it and trying the z3 Xperia compact because It was only they.
Speaker 0: the price has dropped so much.
Speaker 0: It was only like 80 bucks more than a used Nexus 4 or use Nexus 5 Like.
Speaker 0: it's not that expensive of a phone anymore.
Speaker 0: and hardware wise it is literally I think the best phone hardware on the market other than it doesn't have the best phone.
Speaker 0: that's reserved for the iPhone 6 plus.
Speaker 0: But despite the 5.0 Android update being available It still ships with 4/4 and I just could not trust that I would actually be able to get the upgrade.
Speaker 1: so fuck it Why don't you go get that one plus phone?
Speaker 0: You know, honestly I just bought the cheapest phone that was gonna keep doing to hold out till September and see what the lay of the land is because Nexus's are so popular.
Speaker 0: if I fix my Nexus 4 screen I can still sell it for a lot of money like people really like the old Nexus 4 and 5.
Speaker 0: So I'm confident.
Speaker 0: if some awesome phone comes out to September I can just resell this Nexus 5 for a reasonable amount of money And basically I'm paying like 50 bucks to rent a phone for half a year.
Speaker 1: It is surprising to me how it's like it used to be where the only kind of things you would repair would be purely mechanical things like cars or You know computers.
Speaker 1: desktop computers like laptops were mostly unrepairable except for some parts.
Speaker 1: right TVs You didn't really repair once they became LCDs instead of CRTs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm cheap like people stopped repairing things But with phones like I'm seeing the comeback of repairing and a lot of people are making Repairs to phone self-included that are quite successful and inexpensive.
Speaker 0: One phones break more often - they break in it like the majority of breakages are within a Fine band like
Speaker 1: it's such heavy usage that they break
Speaker 0: How many fucking million things can go wrong like you drop a laptop like just roll the dice on like You know crit to center torso crit to left torso.
Speaker 0: But with a phone like most of the time screen shattered it's replaceable Back's shattered.
Speaker 0: It's replaceable battery breaks.
Speaker 0: It's replaceable motherboard.
Speaker 0: Well, fuck it.
Speaker 0: It's done.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Enough of like.
Speaker 0: there's such a narrow band of things that break and most of those things are fixable Unlike more complex technology like a laptop that just has a lot more.
Speaker 1: Mostly just the fact that it's so small and tight and cramped that it's not like a computer is also complex.
Speaker 1: But a desktop you can open it up and really get a lot of air and space to move around in there.
Speaker 1: A human being can work on it, but I don't fix a laptop because like you open it up It's like well not getting back together.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like if I spill coffee in my keyboard I just buy a new keyboard and plug it into the USB port you spill coffee in your laptop.
Speaker 0: That's like a $400 like keyboard.
Speaker 1: really what if you spill coffee on that mixer there?
Speaker 1: It's like how you gonna fix it?
Speaker 0: I would just cry right though.
Speaker 0: Actually that mixer is eminently repairable.
Speaker 0: It comes with a full schematic.
Speaker 1: Full one sure, but it's still a huge pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: But the only digital part is in this top right corner here, so all the rest of this shit?
Speaker 1: Oh, it's just analog bit.
Speaker 0: I could probably just like wash it with solvent let it dry and then it would just work again.
Speaker 0: Maybe like I've repaired that kind of equipment many times in my life and like bits are much easier to fix Yeah, and most audio is analog.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right, so yeah, but otherwise like you know we just did our episode FPGA.
Speaker 0: so I was on a panel talking about FPGAs with like a bunch of big like a guy from solar flare was on the panel and a guy from like one of the Indian Stock Exchange is and My cursory research was apparently correct.
Speaker 0: everyone seems to agree that like Intel Phi and like Nvidia CUDA Tesla stuff is the future.
Speaker 0: and FPGAs I realized something that I didn't think about because the solar flag.
Speaker 0: I brought this up FPGAs.
Speaker 0: people like to say oh like they're they're faster They're not they're just more efficient clock speed.
Speaker 0: wise FPGAs are slow as shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah No Yeah.
Speaker 0: But a lot of people seem to gloss over that when they talk about the power of FPGAs and this guy like basically laid the Smackdown.
Speaker 1: the clock speed doesn't you know equate to real performance.
Speaker 1: We've known that forever.
Speaker 0: Well except you know like a Pentium 4 Overclocked like 5 gigahertz for a lot of the things that my industry does is Actually better than modern multi core chips if your software is written for that.
Speaker 0: Which is most because a lot of these things are just bytes in process bytes out like network card in process network card out and Those calculations are not parallel because they can't be mmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you ever see a parallel network card.
Speaker 1: It's called two network cards.
Speaker 0: Yeah They're fancy network card.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's two network cards on one piece of circuit, but I'm saying like the financial calculation, but anyway I digress.
Speaker 0: So the only other thing I got that was kind of interesting is tech wise.
Speaker 0: you know Scott and I use a lot of technology to make our video shows like all this other stuff and even geek nights, but We have to do everything ourselves.
Speaker 0: It's just us guys like we don't have anyone else.
Speaker 0: So for one of the first times in my life.
Speaker 0: I showed up at a video shoot where professionals met me Set up all the shit and literally all I had to do like it all and in time I showed up they gave me a briefing on.
Speaker 0: here's what we're going to ask You.
Speaker 0: give us at most two to three minute answers for each one of.
Speaker 1: look at this camera.
Speaker 0: Yes There will be two cameras.
Speaker 0: They stood me where I had to stand.
Speaker 0: They told me where to look.
Speaker 0: They told me how to like hold my posture.
Speaker 0: They told me when to start and stop and then when I was done talking.
Speaker 0: Then I said was that good enough?
Speaker 0: and they said yes, it's fine.
Speaker 0: We shook hands I walked away and someone else put that shit into Premiere and edited together.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the video, you know They didn't use Final Cut.
Speaker 0: I know they used Premiere because I talked to them.
Speaker 0: Okay, cuz I was like, oh you got this kind of microphone.
Speaker 0: He's like, oh, yeah Well, cuz this other kind of microphone.
Speaker 0: and I was like I see you're just using DSLRs as your studio cameras.
Speaker 0: and it was like, yeah, there's literally no reason why You're not making movies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, making some crappy video for a website.
Speaker 0: So yeah technology is great But as much as Scott and I are like like the whole point of geek nights is Renaissance.
Speaker 0: geeks like know about everything When you start to do a lot of stuff you've got to find friends who are experts at the things that you don't have time to be experts at because you literally Cannot be an expert at everything and do everything efficiently unless you don't have a job.
Speaker 1: I was trying to use After Effects the other day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can't for shit.
Speaker 1: I actually sort of I'm beginning to understand like the fundamentals of how it works But I still can't make anything that looks good.
Speaker 1: I made I even found a tutorial on YouTube and copied it exactly Like step by step like the exact numbers and everything that guy was doing and mine didn't look the same.
Speaker 0: I made a motion graphic But in After Effects that would have like a lower third like kind of come in and then fade out like and I could like use That but it took me so long.
Speaker 0: It was easier to just like do that with premieres animations.
Speaker 0: so But yeah, yep.
Speaker 0: So anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: So I got a thing of the day called the button but it's not the reddit button.
Speaker 0: It has nothing to do with the reddit button, which miraculously is still going.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Good God I convinced Emily to push the button - okay.
Speaker 0: She was like I was talking about the body.
Speaker 0: She was like should I push it?
Speaker 0: and I was like It's like when the when the dad or the mom has the kid and the kids like should I play these German board games?
Speaker 0: And you're like, yes I miss come.
Speaker 0: Emily was like should I push the button?
Speaker 0: and I was like, all right Here is how to push the button.
Speaker 0: But now this is a video, you know, the peasant box moral conundrum Like here's a button like a box with a button on it.
Speaker 0: If you push the button a peasant somewhere in the world dies and you get a million dollars.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Would you push the button?
Speaker 0: So that questions of a day.
Speaker 1: it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No feeling this has my mood.
Speaker 0: this video is The best exploration of that question I have ever seen.
Speaker 0: You should just watch it.
Speaker 0: It's two minutes long.
Speaker 0: I don't want to just watch this video.
Speaker 0: and then before you watch it Just think to yourself would you press the press the peasant box button and then watch this video and see if you jive with our protagonists?
Speaker 0: There's a moment where he exclaims solved because he solved the button and then he acts on his solution.
Speaker 1: It's beautiful use of the money to buy a thing that resurrects pendants.
Speaker 0: just watch the video anyway.
Speaker 1: so I have a highbrow thing of the day as a scientist here and He's upset about I mean, it seems like pedantry at first like he's complaining sort of.
Speaker 1: he's not complaining, right?
Speaker 1: He's a well-spoken science II kind of guy, right?
Speaker 1: Science man, yeah He's complaining about like what the word intelligence means what the word stupidity means what ignorance means, right?
Speaker 1: It's like the differences between them and about how you know our models of you know, what, you know make someone Intelligent right?
Speaker 1: He's like, you know, it brings up a lot of interesting topics like, you know Well, like IQ tests are biased toward like more affluent people.
Speaker 1: obviously that's like the obvious parts, right?
Speaker 1: But he talks about like How come a scientist is intelligent but an athlete is skilled, right?
Speaker 1: We're trying to create a monopoly on, you know intelligence for people who you know Sit and think and do maths and science, but he's like no the athlete has.
Speaker 1: intelligence is just you know intelligence of the body.
Speaker 0: Think about machine intelligence.
Speaker 0: watch some football player, you know soccer and Then watch robots trying to do that like robots can't figure that shit out.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it's just a guy Scientist guy, what's his name?
Speaker 1: It's in the link.
Speaker 0: I can't look at the link because I'm Installing my phone right now.
Speaker 1: David crack our maybe at least that's the name in the URL Androids updating to 444 and then to 50.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: The saddest thing is right before that phone broke.
Speaker 0: I had just upgraded it to 5.1. even a phone as ancient as the Nexus 4 got Android 5.1.
Speaker 1: But anyway, yeah His name is David crack our the systems theorist explains what's wrong with standard models of intelligence.
Speaker 1: He answers questions as thought-provoking as what is genius?
Speaker 1: Why do you use the word intelligence to describe gifted athletes?
Speaker 1: Do you worry as some people do the super smart machines will come to dominate the human species?
Speaker 0: No, I hope that day happens.
Speaker 1: Why do we need the science of complexity to tackle the most difficult questions all kinds of?
Speaker 0: That last one was particularly funny, yeah.
Speaker 1: So, yeah this guy You know It's typical sort of highbrow philosophy science guy and his videos were.
Speaker 1: it was interesting to hear his answers to these questions.
Speaker 0: Okay, so my thing of the day the first one of the first comments on YouTube is my brother died because of him.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's clever.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, so It's a tech news roundup.
Speaker 0: But first the meta moment.
Speaker 0: the book club book is still water ship down.
Speaker 1: I read more of it.
Speaker 0: Ooh, so are they still at the cult rabbits?
Speaker 0: No, so they got past that.
Speaker 1: They ran away from the cult rabbits.
Speaker 0: Oh, so now they run into the fascist rabbits.
Speaker 1: No, the rabbits that they used to know back in the day came and visited them.
Speaker 0: Oh and it turns out that Fiverr was right.
Speaker 0: shit went down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I don't see any fascist rabbits yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so they're basically their biggest concern.
Speaker 0: They're gonna be like wow, we fucking did it.
Speaker 0: Everything's great.
Speaker 0: There's no girl rabbits here.
Speaker 0: we're literally.
Speaker 1: I realized that like a couple chapters ago.
Speaker 0: They realize it as soon as they have time to rest.
Speaker 0: They're like, ah shit.
Speaker 0: Ah Shit, and then their next plan is how do we get some ladies to come?
Speaker 1: Tell them how awesome it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so they have two plans and it's kind of This is where the book starts to get really good.
Speaker 1: Okay Whatever you say.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a good book.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: I really liked it.
Speaker 0: I liked it about as much as I like The Hobbit you like going out to get girl rabbits.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe depends on that's the good part.
Speaker 0: depends on the girl rabbit.
Speaker 0: It's the good part.
Speaker 0: some good stuff goes down with the girl rabbit stuff.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah So, uh, we haven't picked the next book club book yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we have.
Speaker 0: well Scott has but he won't tell us what it is.
Speaker 1: Okay, finish this one first.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm reading a lot of books.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna finish it soon.
Speaker 0: We have no conventions until Connecticut.
Speaker 0: Thank Jesus I needed time off from conventions.
Speaker 0: if you want us to appear at a convention We're looking for another anime convention maybe because we only do basically one a year.
Speaker 1: So send money.
Speaker 0: we made a bunch of like.
Speaker 0: we kept making like.
Speaker 0: we have awesome anime panels But we basically do them at anime Boston and Connecticut and maybe Zenkai Khan.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, we write a panel for our packs.
Speaker 0: We do it at like seven conventions.
Speaker 0: So Feeling salty about putting all this work into these awesome panels just to do like once or twice Mm-hmm, but at the same time you've got to be a real anime con like at least 10 or 15 thousand people.
Speaker 1: So it's only a few of those.
Speaker 1: Yeah We're talking at least Thousands of people right and the closer to us it is the smaller it can be and the more money you give us the smaller You know what as long as a few hundred people will show up like in the panel rooms.
Speaker 0: That's enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if you have games that we can play when we're not doing panels, that's good, too Yeah, and if there's good food near you, that's also good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and don't be SDCC because I just really don't ever ever want to go to SDCC.
Speaker 0: Yeah or soccer account.
Speaker 0: Sorry guys Sorry guys, not going to - con either.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, it is a tech news round.
Speaker 1: last time we did this.
Speaker 1: it might seem like we're lazy doing this But in fact the last time we did it was in May of 2014 a year ago.
Speaker 0: Wow, that clock rings every year about.
Speaker 1: this clock seems to ring about once a year I'm sure.
Speaker 1: if you search for tech news roundup on our site It seems as if it's an annual thing about this time because it must be a confluence of.
Speaker 0: I wonder if like a lot of News comes around this time at least old with our dearth of ideas We have a suit.
Speaker 1: the dearth of ideas right now is worse than ever.
Speaker 0: But when we have a dearth like that, sometimes we'll come up with like basically if there's no news Then we'll come up with some bullshit idea.
Speaker 0: But if there's a ton of news we go.
Speaker 0: Oh, duh tech news roundup and there was like there was more news than we have time to talk about Whatever.
Speaker 0: So first things first Google is involved in a lot of these but Google is being sued Because the by who by I can't tell.
Speaker 0: okay But the problem that is being described is that the median age of employees at Google is 29.
Speaker 0: Thus clearly age discrimination Maybe.
Speaker 0: now what's funny is I did actually interview at Google recently Like.
Speaker 0: I went through that whole process because some recruiters just wouldn't shut up and kept bothering me.
Speaker 0: So I like I went to like the phone screening and I went in and spent like this whole day with all.
Speaker 1: they bother me A bunch too and they keep bothering me occasionally and every time they bother me.
Speaker 1: I'm like yo Like I really don't want to work a lot.
Speaker 1: How's that gonna be?
Speaker 0: and they're like, oh Okay, nevermind Wow Scott here because the people I talked to were like that's pretty much fine.
Speaker 0: We're a hundred percent results focused and The kind of job it would have been was actually like very much like these people don't seem to show up too early.
Speaker 1: How do you what exact words you use to tell them that you don't want to work?
Speaker 0: I pretty much said I'm not even actually looking for work right now.
Speaker 1: I came
Speaker 0: in because your recruiters kept bothering me and I might be able to do a show about this, by the way I have all these other jobs that I have to be able to keep doing that have significant time like
Speaker 1: See what I tell them is I say basically.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Look, I don't give a shit about what your company does.
Speaker 1: I really will never care about anything that you do.
Speaker 1: I'm really only interested in leaving where I am now if it is a significant life upgrade.
Speaker 1: Those are the words that I use and people are like, well, maybe we are.
Speaker 1: some people are like, oh, okay Never mind, and some people are like, oh, well, maybe we are a significant life upgrade like Pandora called me and Pandora.
Speaker 1: Actually, that's a good backup plan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and they were like, yeah, you know, you know We just work whatever hours.
Speaker 1: the guy told me like yeah, his daughter was sick.
Speaker 1: He just left work No problem, you know for many days because they're totally cool like that and they pay enough and everyone in the office is cool And I'm like that all sounds great.
Speaker 1: That's perfectly fine.
Speaker 1: But that's exactly what I have now.
Speaker 1: That's not an upgrade an upgrade.
Speaker 1: an upgrade would be I work three days a week every week no matter what.
Speaker 1: and if I'm sick You know, and he's like, oh I see I'm like, but you know what if my company like falls apart or something I'm totally gonna call you because that sounds like a horizontal move.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's the thing is like I'm looking.
Speaker 0: I'm like up if the ship is sinking.
Speaker 0: move horizontally to another ship if the ship is Not sinking only get on a helicopter or a space rocket, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I'm looking, you know, everyone who calls me none of them.
Speaker 1: when I say significant life upgrade They don't have a significant life upgrade.
Speaker 0: I should start using that term.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway If the median age is 29 I'm already like way older than the average Google employee and more importantly in the interviews The majority of the people I talked to were way younger than me and they were interviewing me To be them
Speaker 1: because anyone who's noticed people who are old tend to leave Google, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they're really appealing to.
Speaker 1: you know, if I just came straight out of college I would have run to Google like.
Speaker 1: yes, please.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, let my college life continue.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but now that I'm old It's like Google.
Speaker 1: I don't even want to work for you unless you give me like a double life upgrade cuz seriously Seriously well, well, that's the thing is like.
Speaker 1: is it actually discrimination or is it's just that they've structured their company in such a way That old people don't want to work there except for these ones that are suing?
Speaker 0: So the interesting thing is everyone I talked to like I was real candid.
Speaker 0: I was like look here's the deal.
Speaker 0: and they were pretty candid too and it seems like their biggest focus as a company is Retention.
Speaker 0: like they will do anything to get people to stay working there, right?
Speaker 1: Since they lost their deal with Facebook not to poach no poaching policy is gone.
Speaker 0: They've got a retention abilities Yep, I don't know that's a separate that we should do a show on like tech industry poaching non-compete stuff Mm-hmm, cuz we've never talked about that.
Speaker 0: Oh dad law show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a Thursday Anyway, but anyway, they but I so not to get derailed onto that right now.
Speaker 0: But you know, it's good.
Speaker 0: I interview a lot of people too and it's really hard For me to fall on either side of this issue because I do know older developers who were smart But at the same time and all my experience an older developer who knows like modern technology will be hired in a second Way before a younger developer with similar skills.
Speaker 0: Yep Because like a lot of like there may be aspects of the industry that I don't bump into where the younger we're in, New York.
Speaker 1: This is the California attitude that goes on here, right?
Speaker 1: Silicon Valley types the people that I can't stand the ones that are calling me that I'm asking for a significant life up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I want him to fuck up.
Speaker 0: people say like Silicon Valley is the big start-up land But New York is an equally big start-up land.
Speaker 1: It's just the startups in New York are at least some of them, you know are more reasonable.
Speaker 1: They're real companies.
Speaker 0: They make real things and they pay money instead of dreams and lottery.
Speaker 1: And usually the thing is in Silicon Valley the companies that people are starting up are technology companies, right?
Speaker 1: They put technology first.
Speaker 1: It's like what is their company?
Speaker 1: Our company is to make this software, right?
Speaker 1: That is what we do in New York.
Speaker 1: Most of the companies that are in New York We have a real business doing a real thing.
Speaker 1: But we need people who are computer people because we're a company we have fucking computers.
Speaker 1: We need computer people, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I work at Broadway.com.
Speaker 1: What the fuck do we do?
Speaker 1: We sell tickets, right?
Speaker 1: It's a real business that makes real money, but we have a website.
Speaker 1: Obviously, yeah, it needs working on.
Speaker 1: you know, it's like rim.
Speaker 1: you work at a financial company you do financial stuff Which is somewhat of a real business.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could argue about that, but it's more real business than Twitter.
Speaker 0: You know what it is because we don't we sell software and we sell services.
Speaker 0: We sell a thing and we just use technology to make those things, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you could.
Speaker 1: a lot of people I know in New York.
Speaker 1: They work for like, you know a TV station or Bloomberg or You know some real company that does a real business That makes real money and then that because it's a cut they have technology.
Speaker 1: we work the New York Times They do technology at the New York Times, which is a real business.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, but yeah, but it is not a real business.
Speaker 0: So that's my point.
Speaker 0: Is that like if I'm interviewing and there's an older person a younger person and they have equivalent experience then it comes down like attitude And personality and everything while there probably are some predatory practices like trying to hire young single people Who they know will work for less Yes or more or be willing to stay
Speaker 1: late spend more hours
Speaker 0: because like
Speaker 1: care more
Speaker 0: I have noticed that Everyone I've ever interacted with in finance and just in tech in general who is married with kids Takes way more time off like a lot more time off.
Speaker 1: Yeah I can dare.
Speaker 1: in my office right to my right is a person who is an intern with us and now graduated college and that Works for us.
Speaker 1: that person is Eager beaver.
Speaker 1: no to my left is a person who's married as a kid as a kid on the way You know, not really much, you know, pretty much our age, right?
Speaker 1: Not in the office today.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It is a hundred percent true.
Speaker 0: No, do you know how many people like work from home today?
Speaker 0: because of like today the office was like a barren wasteland.
Speaker 1: Yeah, many people were not there today.
Speaker 0: But at the same time those people get about the same amount of work done.
Speaker 1: I've found Gets about the same matter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the thing.
Speaker 0: Like I tell I like.
Speaker 0: I've never been the eager beaver.
Speaker 0: I've acted like the old guy with family except I just go home play video games or like, you know Like do my laundry or whatever.
Speaker 1: I mean, I didn't really do work most of the day in like the last hour I just did a few things.
Speaker 1: It's like I do a lot of things in a very short amount of time and I'm just spending a lot of time at work Doing nothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: So it's hard to say with this because in my experience a lot of the older people that I'd like interact with that aren't Skilled like they're worthless employees like they don't know anything about modern code Like I couldn't imagine hiring them but a young person who was that ignorant of modern practices.
Speaker 0: I would also not hire.
Speaker 1: well, I think the thing is I Want to hire the old people to get them to do stuff that they know.
Speaker 1: it's like hey, yeah I need these Linux servers administered.
Speaker 1: Please do that.
Speaker 1: But a trend I notice in the tech industry is this DevOps thing that suddenly became all right.
Speaker 0: Don't get me fight.
Speaker 0: Let's do a Monday show on that fucking word suddenly became a fucking word.
Speaker 1: It basically means don't have system administrators just have the developers.
Speaker 1: do all that work.
Speaker 1: All your shits in the cloud anyway, you don't have computers lying around.
Speaker 0: there's an argument around that.
Speaker 0: But the way I would put it is your ops.
Speaker 0: people should also all know how to write code and be smart about tech.
Speaker 1: They shouldn't just be like system administration certificate certification anyway, but yeah the and that's killing the jobs that a lot of those older type people did.
Speaker 1: who you know is Administers some Unix for us, you know trying to like get you know Cuz they can write.
Speaker 1: you know The kind of code that they write when you're older developer is not modern and only some of them have kept up their skills.
Speaker 1: So here's a problem.
Speaker 0: No one young knows how to administer a Linux server for shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, absolutely true.
Speaker 1: They don't know anything Yeah, and they don't know Unix at all.
Speaker 1: the intern guy he can't even Unix.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like no one can like I when I like everyone I to interview like barely knows like.
Speaker 0: they can't script.
Speaker 0: They don't know bash.
Speaker 0: they can use like VI and edit text files.
Speaker 1: I'm like only me and the IT guys.
Speaker 1: the two IT guys are the only ones who know how to Unix.
Speaker 1: But here's the problem.
Speaker 1: other people can't Unix people my age like 30s.
Speaker 0: We do not want to be Linux system administrators anymore.
Speaker 0: Like I don't want to do that job because while I'm really good at it, I don't like doing it.
Speaker 1: It's not I don't want to do it, but I'm very upset if it's not done, right?
Speaker 1: Yep, so I can't leave it to anyone fucking else.
Speaker 0: You realize whenever someone asks me like for help like like hey the QA servers acting funny.
Speaker 0: Can you look at it?
Speaker 0: I usually say no because if I say yes, I see how it's set up and I spend a day fixing it Yep, and then once I touch it, it's mine.
Speaker 0: So yep There's a few servers in the company that are mine.
Speaker 1: now as soon as it's not yours You know what happens.
Speaker 1: the clock's gonna be off Five minutes that fucking clock.
Speaker 1: It's always actually had a wrong clock the other day and I went to your tumbler and I fixed it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I'm telling you this shit's easy.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: Why can't people just?
Speaker 0: why can't I hurt people like you?
Speaker 0: Just alright, you can hire me.
Speaker 1: Give me a significant life upgrade.
Speaker 0: I'll give you more money.
Speaker 1: That's not a significant life upgrade unless it's enough money to buy a luxury condo in the Queen's area.
Speaker 1: Is it that much money?
Speaker 1: so yeah anyway, I guess it's not that much money.
Speaker 0: So I don't have a luxury condo in the Queen's area and you're not gonna make more than me.
Speaker 1: Yeah I need to me.
Speaker 1: I need a basically a signing bonus for the down payment and then a salary that can pay the monthly and My existing salary on top of that, but I see there is a real problem here because I don't want to stay on this news forever.
Speaker 0: But like, you know the point I was getting at.
Speaker 0: we kept getting distracted.
Speaker 0: The older like older people like me and Scott.
Speaker 0: we're above the median age of Google.
Speaker 0: We're super good at the things that like people need done.
Speaker 0: But at the same time a lot of the things we're good at are not things we want to do as jobs.
Speaker 0: So even if someone like if someone like me we're looking for work I would might not even apply to like Linux system administrator jobs.
Speaker 0: So you're gonna end up hiring Younger people who learn it because no one no one who's older is willing to do the job at the salary You're willing to pay.
Speaker 0: Yep I expect a bigger salary being old as do most people in my third in the 30s like that's like that is the peak time of You expect a lot of money because like you've made that money for a long time and you've been always getting raises.
Speaker 1: Are you gonna someone gonna sue the farm for like, you know racial discrimination?
Speaker 1: They only hire immigrants.
Speaker 1: It's like well, I mean, it's not.
Speaker 0: they're paying minimum wage to do literally back-breaking labor, right?
Speaker 1: It's not that Americans and other people have you know from other countries don't want to do the work They don't want to do it.
Speaker 1: They don't want to do it at that salary.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and only those people will See also my actual increasing Worry about h1 B's.
Speaker 0: I feel like a lot of are just a big scam for American companies to not pay To get indentured servants to do IT for them locally because that's always what they've been.
Speaker 1: That is always what those have been.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz they're very rarely are they actually to get someone.
Speaker 1: cuz it's a big country Why would we?
Speaker 1: we have someone in this country somewhere who can do what you need?
Speaker 1: You don't need to hire someone from a tiny country.
Speaker 0: In fact as much as I complain like a lot of people like I just interview or like other people I know interview like just Don't know shit.
Speaker 0: It's usually because the salaries like if you double what you're willing to pay You'll find someone who can do that job the next day in New York at least.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: So yeah, all right, let's move on to more tech news about Google.
Speaker 0: So I watch.
Speaker 0: let's skip Google come back to Google.
Speaker 1: All right guy watches out.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So here's the thing about the I watch the watch itself.
Speaker 1: There's nothing really to say about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like.
Speaker 0: I think the pebble is gonna be better for like what I do.
Speaker 1: Yeah for normal person the pebbles probably but anyway the thing that's interesting about the I watch is the buying of it at least for me, right.
Speaker 1: so Apple usually does.
Speaker 1: the way they do their pre-orders is you can pre-order online Or you can go to an Apple store and wait in line.
Speaker 1: They got rid of the Apple store.
Speaker 1: wait in line You can't.
Speaker 0: you have to go online now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, obviously, that's good.
Speaker 1: The thing is they made X number of Apple watches that we don't know yet and they pre-ordered that many online.
Speaker 1: Now that they've already pre-ordered all of those that they're making in that first shipment.
Speaker 1: You can't pre-order one now.
Speaker 1: They're sort of sold out Now.
Speaker 1: there are many reasons they might want to do this, but I frankly do not understand at all.
Speaker 1: Why don't you just take money from everyone who wants one now?
Speaker 1: Regardless of how many that is maybe a billion people on earth want an Apple watch and it cost $500.
Speaker 1: All right, take the five hundred billion dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah Regardless of how many watches you've already made or can make soon because people don't think like people.
Speaker 0: when I pre-order something I got to just assume the money is gone.
Speaker 1: Anyway, just take their fucking money regardless of how many watches you have and then as you make watches Mail them out to people based on who was first in line and the person who clicked on it last.
Speaker 1: They might get their watch next year, but fuck them.
Speaker 1: Hold on to their money until then.
Speaker 1: Why are you like making them reload pages every time you make more watches and keep clicking and do this?
Speaker 0: And no, I can think of a lot of reasons.
Speaker 0: There are bad reasons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can imagine bad reasons.
Speaker 0: I can think.
Speaker 1: I can list a ton of like smart business wise but bad for humans reasons Sure, but I mean if I ever have a business that pre-orders anything I'm going to do it that way where it's like.
Speaker 1: we will take as many pre-orders as people will pre-order up to infinity and But as we make them we will send them out.
Speaker 0: what I would do is a long time on the pre-order.
Speaker 0: I would definitely set it up where it'll show you like your rough ETA like if you pre-order now And you know what if you want to cancel while you're waiting, I'll give you a fucking money back.
Speaker 1: I don't care I'm Apple.
Speaker 1: I got I got money.
Speaker 1: I don't care Right.
Speaker 1: Why don't you just do it that way to save everyone the hassle?
Speaker 1: Not that I want you.
Speaker 0: and then you take all this pre-order money and you invest it in short-term like money money thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah Now here's another.
Speaker 1: the only other thing I'd say about Apple watch is If you don't want pebble watch if you're a big Apple person, you have a Mac and an iPhone.
Speaker 1: You're probably better off with Apple watch.
Speaker 1: definitely get Apple watch 2.0.
Speaker 1: Look at every Apple product that has ever been made Right.
Speaker 1: Look at say the iPhone one.
Speaker 1: Not good.
Speaker 1: Not a good deal, but the iPhone 3g Not bad.
Speaker 1: even today, I mean it's like all right.
Speaker 0: All right iPhone 3g is still better than a lot of feature phones.
Speaker 1: It's a huge the judge.
Speaker 1: and if you compare every iPhone to the generations of iPhone that are next to it adjacent The iPhone 3 iPhone 1 to iPhone 3g was the biggest jump.
Speaker 1: All right think about iMac.
Speaker 1: the first iMac the colored fruity thing Oh, yeah, and the second iMac Big ass jump right.
Speaker 1: since then I guess there were a couple other big-ass jumps.
Speaker 0: So the iMac's pretty old Yeah, but like we've still got one of those second gen iMacs Yeah, and like it still works and it's still like a pretty good computer, right?
Speaker 1: iPod right.
Speaker 1: first iPod with a physically spinning wheel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then they made the jump to the not physically spinning wheel Right.
Speaker 0: I'm here put in start comparison.
Speaker 0: The first iPod was what like four hundred something dollars, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could buy a Basically a CD player that would read mp3s off of a CD For like a hundred bucks, yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, if you look at Apple history product hip history of Apple products The second gen is usually the biggest jump in awesomeness.
Speaker 1: Look at the first iPad is huge.
Speaker 1: Second iPad perfectly fine today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's the same as all right, so I Would recommend the Apple iWatch 2 that's gonna come out next year or the year after is gonna be So insanely better than the iWatch 1. it's gonna be way thin and way awesome.
Speaker 1: right just get that.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be great.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends.
Speaker 0: There's one different one.
Speaker 1: Not a good deal.
Speaker 0: There's one factor here the collectability factor.
Speaker 1: I have to check out.
Speaker 1: cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, how much money can you get for an iPod one?
Speaker 0: Good point.
Speaker 0: Yeah Android the first and for Samsung phone Nexus 4.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so even to Google Glass.
Speaker 0: But I guess the factor is the thing that the fundamental thing limiting these devices is wireless communication protocols for like local high bandwidth that is like power of vision and battery technology.
Speaker 0: until battery technology has a Fundamental and significant game-changing shift the watches cannot get much better than they are now.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: So You might just have to wait until there's battery news.
Speaker 1: maybe I mean the Apple iWatch last all day Apparently and you can plug it in just easily as the pebble the current pebble lasts more than all day.
Speaker 1: The pebble time is supposedly gonna last for fucking ever.
Speaker 0: So oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the new pebble and I got the metal one, which is one millimeter thicker.
Speaker 0: Well, because it looks nicer.
Speaker 0: Okay, but they claim 10 to 14 days of light use.
Speaker 1: I believe it.
Speaker 0: Yeah I wish it wasn't a millimeter thicker, but that's the iWatch news.
Speaker 0: yeah, so we'll see.
Speaker 0: I do the.
Speaker 0: I will say one thing if you are really invested in like because you're invested in this idea like This kind of technology because I have to say Google Glass or like a smart watch of any kind is a Significant life improvement even if it is not a game changer.
Speaker 1: I mean just not having to take your phone out of your pocket.
Speaker 1: your phone goes If you don't have a watch or a Google Glass or anything.
Speaker 1: You're taking that phone out to see what that was because that could have been a call from mom.
Speaker 1: It could have been a really important email.
Speaker 1: Yeah, tell me about a base that you're gonna wait or it could have just been like, you know The sports news like Mets game starting right?
Speaker 1: So you got to manage your notifications heavily.
Speaker 1: But even though the watch you can turn on more notifications You don't turn on too many.
Speaker 1: is that your wrist is shaking all the time?
Speaker 1: You can turn on more and then you see on the notification on the watch and you go Oh, I better take my phone out.
Speaker 1: This is important or don't have to take my phone out.
Speaker 1: that's just the Mets starting and It's the greatest totally worth it Especially since an old pebble watch is actually the current one way cheap and the next one not really expensive either.
Speaker 1: Apple watch for the people with money Alright, so Comcast.
Speaker 0: it's kind of brief news, but the Comcast Time Warner merger failed in disaster.
Speaker 0: We won again.
Speaker 1: we won on the net neutrality.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we won on this FTC FCC getting it done.
Speaker 1: mad props rest of government.
Speaker 0: You're still fucking up then I'm not we're not gonna talk about.
Speaker 0: I mean you can read the stories on why it failed and what it came down to was Basically, the regulators were looking at it.
Speaker 0: So they were like, oh, well now we're fucked.
Speaker 1: Yeah and to Everyone realized cost us more money to fight and fail because probably gonna fail is not even bother.
Speaker 0: They only probably even considered the merger thinking that lobbying pull a fast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was gonna make sure that no one looked into this too closely.
Speaker 0: I don't think they expected the angry public to turn into the government actually looking at it and actually starting to evaluate it.
Speaker 0: and Like um guests started to look That NBC Comcast no problem.
Speaker 1: They're like, oh well that we slipped that one by.
Speaker 0: let's do it again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we should probably undo that previous one.
Speaker 1: In fact, we should undo a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah should probably break apart Verizon and Verizon wireless should.
Speaker 1: probably a lot of things need breaking.
Speaker 0: Yep So this is just great.
Speaker 0: Like this is a tech victory.
Speaker 0: It's kind of unprecedented a streak of the US government doing the smart thing in technology mostly due to public outrage Pay it when when there is public outrage to be had in the tech sector Do it like?
Speaker 0: send those letters send those emails like it sounds dumb.
Speaker 0: But when the FCC got those like millions and millions millions of emails, they really didn't have much of a choice.
Speaker 1: Yeah like Congress can't easily Like fuck with these things when there's well The reason that the reason that it was able to work in that case is because those emails are public.
Speaker 1: when you email your Congress Person, you don't know like let's say our Congress person is gonna do something bad.
Speaker 1: So we all everyone in Queens in our area here and I guess also Includes the east side of Manhattan we email that Congress person and we're like don't do this evil thing.
Speaker 1: Let's say every single person in the whole district said this letter.
Speaker 1: They're probably gonna listen to us because they're gonna vote against them if they don't do it, but They could say they could just go straight on TV or whatever and say my constituents are really supporting me in this And I'm gonna do it.
Speaker 1: and you have no idea.
Speaker 1: We're all sitting there believing that we're the only one in the district that sent them a letter saying no that everyone else told them Yes, or who knows what.
Speaker 0: but if you go to the executive side and go after the FCC, right?
Speaker 1: Like hey guys, hey guys, hey guys All those comments are public and anyone can see.
Speaker 1: hey the FCC just isn't gonna do this net neutrality thing Even though so many millions of people just told them do that's fucked up.
Speaker 0: Yeah More importantly the FCC can take action based on that without Congress's approval.
Speaker 1: Usually so far because that's what the law says.
Speaker 1: Congress can undo the law.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then what happened?
Speaker 1: It's actually they're.
Speaker 1: they're doing it with Congress's approval sort of.
Speaker 1: is this an old kind?
Speaker 1: the Republicans are trying to like The approval of an old Congress that wrote a lawyer cut me off.
Speaker 0: Here's what I'm getting at.
Speaker 0: if you lobby the FCC with public outrage the FCC will often now apparently do it and then basically they dare.
Speaker 0: they have to dare Congress to undo it.
Speaker 0: an Individual congressman even if their party line is against the thing that got done.
Speaker 0: if they come out publicly Against what the FCC did Then they come out publicly against Widespread public consensus and that it looks real bad for reelection Even if their constituents are nominally against the thing.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so we just said we want to break all these people up.
Speaker 0: So the EU is once again trying to break Google up.
Speaker 0: Massive massive massive antitrust case against Google.
Speaker 1: Well while I don't think that breaking up Google is necessarily The worst idea I don't think it's a good idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, you know, maybe maybe not but this particular case is really bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this one is not the right way to be going.
Speaker 1: euro.
Speaker 0: Yeah Europe has done this many times in the past.
Speaker 0: Europe is like you're.
Speaker 1: I'm glad that nothing I do is under the purview of European law Right, so specifically what they're upset about is sort of androids monopoly, which is strange because they got iPhone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the iPhone is ridiculously popular.
Speaker 1: I don't understand why they think Android has a monopoly.
Speaker 0: first of all also Android is open like you can just use it.
Speaker 0: That's like saying Linux has a monopoly.
Speaker 1: But apparently what some of this case is based on is actually the previous case that Google thankfully won Against Oracle, right?
Speaker 1: so remember when Oracle was going after Google because Android was all Java II and And Oracle bought Sun and then went after Google on the Java front.
Speaker 1: They were like, oh you're using Java without paying us money in your androids and they lost which is good.
Speaker 1: We won that one, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but during that case.
Speaker 1: there were some documents supposedly uncovered to where Google said things to various phone manufacturers such as if you want to use Android you got to be using Google stuff like you know Chrome and Gmail's and all that kind of Google wallets and what you know, all the kind of Google stuff.
Speaker 1: and That's a no-no You can't be doing that.
Speaker 1: that that was the same thing that Microsoft did where they were.
Speaker 1: like you want to use Windows get a glitter Internet Explorer on there.
Speaker 1: So, you know, that's sort of like evidence like, you know Europe wants to be like.
Speaker 1: hey You can't tell these phone man makers if they want to use Android They got to be googly and Google's like.
Speaker 1: well, it's you're obviously right.
Speaker 1: You can use Android and not be googly.
Speaker 1: Nothing's stopping you Yeah, and but they're still pushing with this case and I guess there are a few European companies Complaining about Google as they always do like they're trying to make Google do all these Changes.
Speaker 1: Yep, but like most of the time I don't know why Google puts up with it.
Speaker 1: if I was Google I would just be like Immediately as soon as they said anything to you.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't even send an ultimatum.
Speaker 1: I just just cut off all the Google in Europe.
Speaker 1: So alright Everyone in Europe was Gmail suddenly lost all their for email.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, that's too bad.
Speaker 1: YouTube just gone in Europe Just like it's just off.
Speaker 1: No one in Europe can see YouTube, you know, but it's like we're just so fucked, right?
Speaker 1: It's just like stop suing us.
Speaker 1: We do exactly what we say and we'll put it back on and I guess you could just immediately basically come.
Speaker 0: We'd be super mad if some other companies did this.
Speaker 0: what it comes down to is that breaking a monopolies?
Speaker 1: The whole thing would be mad.
Speaker 1: No the whole intent.
Speaker 1: Give me a scenario.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be mad.
Speaker 0: well So what if it was?
Speaker 0: Microsoft?
Speaker 0: okay trying to Prevent trying to think of a really good example here.
Speaker 0: Because here you're trying to say what if Microsoft use their power to say yeah Linux should be illegal like you're not allowed to install Linux and they just said we'll just fucking pull out of the u.s Unless you make Linux illegal.
Speaker 1: All right, pull out.
Speaker 0: Okay, so they do good.
Speaker 0: and So yeah, so now they're in Europe and that's fine.
Speaker 0: You think Google can do the same thing in the other direction?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I probably know they can.
Speaker 1: why not?
Speaker 0: the world is too global.
Speaker 0: It's too interconnected.
Speaker 0: You're hyperbole is silly.
Speaker 0: It's fucking but Both like a lot like especially in the search stuff.
Speaker 0: everyone I've ever seen who complains about Google search being a monopoly.
Speaker 0: is Some SEO bullshit?
Speaker 0: or someone who's mad because they're bullshit doesn't float to the top of Google.
Speaker 0: you search for Anything on any search engine in the world and you get all these spam garbage like e-commerce sites.
Speaker 0: on Google You actually get what you want and that does it if you're.
Speaker 0: if the monopoly is not causing harm Don't break it up.
Speaker 0: if it's uh Causing harm like some of the old JP Morgan stuff break it up.
Speaker 0: Don't break up monopolies just because they're monopoly.
Speaker 0: break them up because they suck or they're doing evil.
Speaker 0: But in this case, I don't really think anything Google's doing here is particularly wrong.
Speaker 1: No, it doesn't.
Speaker 1: I don't understand what they're complaining about.
Speaker 0: They're Europe.
Speaker 0: That's just a new Google.
Speaker 1: I mean it made more sense in the Microsoft case in the 90s because Windows was way more monopoly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then Android is Um Plus.
Speaker 0: what Santagen mod?
Speaker 0: They just made a deal with Microsoft.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be the Microsoft store in the Microsoft.
Speaker 0: shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Santagen mod You can run that on a phone.
Speaker 0: a company could sell a handset with Santagen mod windows as a legit phone?
Speaker 0: Sure, that would be totally okay.
Speaker 0: So how is this a monopoly again?
Speaker 1: I don't understand.
Speaker 1: it seems like they just really hate Google because it's like an American company that has a lot of power over them and Nothing to compete with it will ever come out of Europe.
Speaker 1: But Google is you know Perhaps really big and sort of monopolistic and it would be sort of interesting if I was gonna break up Google what I would do If I was like the Justice Department or whatever as I would say look, here's what you got to do.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't be like those typical breakups where it's like.
Speaker 1: All right, Google Apps is one company.
Speaker 1: Google searches one company.
Speaker 1: good, right?
Speaker 1: I would say here's what you're gonna do.
Speaker 1: You are going to set up a whole nother infrastructure with the Google search on it and have two companies that start in the exact Same position with the same search engine and we're gonna split the search employees between the two companies and now they're gonna go And now they're gonna compete.
Speaker 1: So now there's two amazing search engines and we actually have a choice But neither of them suck and they're competing and now we're gonna see what happens.
Speaker 0: that's gonna be awesome Right, if you just say well searches if I were Google and you did that I'd say fuck you and shut down Gmail in the entire country until you give up.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So you think you know you'd be okay with that.
Speaker 0: sure YouTube just disappears.
Speaker 1: all those employees You're gonna be looking for work at Bing real quick.
Speaker 0: Yeah Now you think you've been could possibly be good enough to replace YouTube.
Speaker 1: if and Google search if the Google search and YouTube employees went Over there, they would fix that shit.
Speaker 0: So maybe so ESPN has sued Verizon to stop them from having non-sports TV bundles.
Speaker 0: Yeah I Don't care who wins.
Speaker 0: Because in because there's a ton of other like lawsuits and slap fights in the table.
Speaker 0: industry.
Speaker 0: now Fuck them all.
Speaker 0: I hope they die.
Speaker 0: This is when like three warring states two of like the two bad.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's like we're sitting here in our Kingdom in our castle looking down and we see the evil show gun from the West is coming.
Speaker 1: and then Yeah, it's like they're fighting and we're like, yeah All right, I mean I do this in Civ 5 a lot.
Speaker 0: I get two enemies who are both at war with me busting out the sake like what's up.
Speaker 0: go to war with each other.
Speaker 0: Fuck the cable companies.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh, is that is that Genghis Khan over there?
Speaker 1: Who is that?
Speaker 1: Is that?
Speaker 1: is it Montezuma?
Speaker 0: Hey Genghis going at it go Oh shit means like just don't throw anything over my walls and you are welcome to go right past.
Speaker 0: Well, in fact, we'll throw food for you.
Speaker 0: Just go nuts.
Speaker 0: Have fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I found a new religion of popcorn Popcorn over here.
Speaker 0: cuz seriously fuck these guys.
Speaker 0: I just want to watch stuff on TV.
Speaker 0: The nails are in the coffins.
Speaker 0: HBO all that Cartoon Network stuff that's hard to watch is just on Hulu now like Everything's going internet.
Speaker 0: Fuck these guys.
Speaker 1: So I've talked about this before but I'm gonna say it again people who don't know right the math of how this works.
Speaker 1: So you might be thinking well, why don't cable companies just let you choose exactly the channels that you want, right?
Speaker 1: I want ESPN and I want current Cartoon Network Comedy Central.
Speaker 1: I want three channels.
Speaker 1: Give those to me.
Speaker 1: I'll pay for those, right?
Speaker 1: Well, here's the reason why that would cost you Not really much more than the 50 60 bucks a month that they're charging anyway.
Speaker 1: And the reason for that is you're basically subsidizing the same way that insurance works, right?
Speaker 1: They give ESPN is the example here X dollars for every customer that they have because everyone has ESPN.
Speaker 1: So they give them two dollars a customer or something and that adds up to a shit ton of money.
Speaker 1: A very small percentage of those customers actually are watching the ESPN, right only?
Speaker 1: maybe you know million customers.
Speaker 1: Well, you know how many people are sports fans, right?
Speaker 1: How many people do you know have pay for cable but don't watch ESPN at all?
Speaker 1: They might even be sports fans and not watch ESPN because they like hockey and ESPN doesn't have hockey.
Speaker 1: So they just watch NBC Sports.
Speaker 1: so you have this channel that they're paying two bucks a month for that they're not watching and That adds up to a shit ton if you have only had the people who actually watch the channel pay for it.
Speaker 1: If they all paid two bucks a month, obviously ESPN's make it a way less money.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna be able to have ESPN.
Speaker 1: ESPN costs a lot of money to run.
Speaker 1: you gotta have cameras.
Speaker 1: You got to go to all these sports events trucks broadcast equipment talent on the net, you know It's a really expensive business endeavor to have ESPN.
Speaker 1: They need that large amount of money even to just happen.
Speaker 1: They're not really raking it in.
Speaker 1: You know, it's part of Disney, but it's still.
Speaker 1: they're not, you know immensely profitable, right?
Speaker 1: So They'd have to charge if they only people who watched it paid for it.
Speaker 1: they have to charge those people 20 30 bucks a month something ridiculous.
Speaker 1: and no one's paying 30 bucks a month just for ESPN Even if they want it, even if they were an ESPN fan, they're not paying $30 a month just for that.
Speaker 1: You know what $30 a month gets you.
Speaker 1: are you insane?
Speaker 1: Right, and I'm gonna pay that for one time never mind like.
Speaker 0: forget about all the other channels with all their ads and all their bullshit.
Speaker 0: That literally only exists because they're subsidized by the rest and they have like this closed-loop Revenue stream of fake advertising and people who have the channel but may not be watching it.
Speaker 1: There are also a lot of channels on there that like wouldn't be profitable just on their own.
Speaker 1: They don't they just they get like pennies per Subscriber or sometimes they're even paying the cable network to be on there or just on there for free So that the cable that we can say we have X billion channels.
Speaker 0: There's an entire ecosystem.
Speaker 0: I think the majority of television stations, you know in quotes in the US the vast majority will Disappear.
Speaker 0: those companies and everyone involved will be bad.
Speaker 1: less and less people have cable.
Speaker 1: Most of these channels are just going to completely vanish Right more and more and it's gonna even if some cable company is like yeah If you get us you can have all 30 channels because all these other ones are gone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and It's pretty much gonna be direct people to content makers and channels are gonna die, which is great.
Speaker 1: YouTube is basically the channel now, which oh another monopoly for Google.
Speaker 0: Yeah The thing is not like.
Speaker 0: even like we try streaming stuff to twitch.
Speaker 1: streaming to Google just works like a billion times better Twitch is you know, I mean twitch is the thing that twitch does better than Google.
Speaker 0: the Comments like every.
Speaker 1: no is the fact that you can have this sort of one URL that people can check anytime and it goes On and off.
Speaker 1: true with YouTube You're actually creating like a new YouTube video and it's not like people can just watch your chat.
Speaker 1: your one URL to see if you're on or off.
Speaker 1: it's just.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: when you make a new one you have to sort of announce it and people have to go to it and it's not That same kind of thing.
Speaker 1: where it's like, oh it's got streaming now.
Speaker 1: Let me go check.
Speaker 1: Yep, and that's what YouTube needs to add.
Speaker 1: is they need to give you a URL like youtube.com.
Speaker 1: slash blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: slash your name Slash live or if you go there if you happen to be streaming something live at that time There it is and then just set it up to run.
Speaker 0: basically quote unquote reruns.
Speaker 1: It's not like you can have two live events at a time And if you can you just pick which one goes in the channel or they're all there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever, you know something so that people can just sort of subscribe to you and you know Beyond there.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so that's the only thing.
Speaker 0: that's which last but not least probably the most important and interesting tech news But not a lot of people are talking about it.
Speaker 0: just recently There's been a move toward Automation and farms with robots that was previously infeasible.
Speaker 0: not technologically.
Speaker 0: arms mostly robots and big machines No, but there's a lot of things that are manual processes like picking strawberries.
Speaker 1: Yeah machine can't really do that.
Speaker 0: very well Well, they can.
Speaker 0: it's just they're expensive.
Speaker 1: Oh, I didn't even realize they had a machine that could do that.
Speaker 0: Like there's a machine here.
Speaker 0: It's called the agro bot.
Speaker 0: It costs like a hundred grand and it does it great Really.
Speaker 0: and there's other miss.
Speaker 1: I'd like to see that machine in a YouTube video.
Speaker 1: make it a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I'm linking to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, look at this thing.
Speaker 1: Does it really pick strawberries?
Speaker 0: Yeah, a person drives it and it picks strawberries gingerly one by one from every one of these plants under the leaves.
Speaker 0: This is the kind of work that Previously was done primarily by undocumented illegal immigrants.
Speaker 1: Well, I thought they were.
Speaker 1: there's a special program to bring in agriculture.
Speaker 0: Then we moved up to doing it legally but paying these people, you know, basically garbage.
Speaker 0: They're.
Speaker 1: basically I paid at least minimum wage.
Speaker 1: I didn't say it wasn't garbage.
Speaker 1: I thought it but it's not illegal wages.
Speaker 0: But if the the comment like the reason like robots don't just run McDonald's the reason we still need all these unskilled laborers Is that this kind of work?
Speaker 0: Until very recently it was always cheaper to hire a whole bunch of migrant workers than to buy one robot.
Speaker 0: Now because the cost of that labor has gone up due to a combination of stricter immigration More wage pressure minimum wage is going up in places and robot technology getting a little bit cheaper It's now cheaper.
Speaker 0: So all these jobs are literally Rapidly disappearing.
Speaker 0: nice all the micro all the jobs nice and not nice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all these jobs that were below the line of like, you know, the companies would say well Americans don't want to do these jobs.
Speaker 0: Well, that's not true.
Speaker 0: The answer was Americans don't want to do these jobs at the ridiculously pathetic wages.
Speaker 0: You're willing to pay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you took the money you spent on that robot $100,000 a year and gave that to a person they would do it.
Speaker 0: But you need like a hundred of those people because it really sucks to pick strawberries.
Speaker 1: How many machines do you need?
Speaker 0: Have you ever picked strawberries?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I only picked like a little bucket.
Speaker 0: Yeah, try to pick like a hundred buckets.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I had to spend all day doing it.
Speaker 1: No, you go to the farm for like an hour and you pick one nice bucket and you go buy some cider.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you get a little.
Speaker 0: you're going around thinking like the best the best individual strawberry.
Speaker 1: You don't pick all of them right.
Speaker 0: you ate a half a buckets worth just while you're walking and then you pooped like crazy.
Speaker 0: And so it goes Barf blueberries, uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Keep an eye on this.
Speaker 0: We're hitting a huge turning point.
Speaker 0: You know robot cars are gonna be another turning point because as people don't like to talk about.
Speaker 0: the majority employer of Adults in the middle class in the entire United States far and away is driving vehicles driving cars trucks Also, yeah, don't cut trucks.
Speaker 0: driving cars Driving, you know driving things driving like vehicles on roads to places.
Speaker 0: Robot cars destroy the single largest employer of adults in America.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile ahead of that these robots are destroying one of the other biggest employers of adults but it's low income earning adults, so We're hitting a like really big turning point like now in our lifetime, and I don't know what's going to happen.
Speaker 0: We're going to destroy.
Speaker 1: we've taught we've known about this for a long time, but people in power Don't yeah, but now it's like us.
Speaker 1: we keeps up But now we're not at the point where we're gonna diamond age or anything, you know.
Speaker 0: But we knew it was gonna happen.
Speaker 0: this news is that this year it for real actually Started happening and started happening.
Speaker 1: No Vastly accelerate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but like this like we knew like we saw a little crack in the dam and we paid up.
Speaker 0: We paid a boy to stick his finger
Speaker 1: in the dam was before we were born like yeah
Speaker 0: And they paid a boy to stick his finger in it and we saw another tiny crack and they stuck their finger in it Just now like a whole chunk of the dam just fucking broke out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean we knew that was gonna happen, but there it goes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it actually went.
Speaker 0: there goes Any more.
Speaker 0: uh yeah the Rangers are playing tonight.
Speaker 0: They're gonna win.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they are.
Speaker 0: oh We're not doing this Monday show.
Speaker 0: the Rangers are playing tonight in about five minutes, so they're not.
Speaker 1: yeah They are no Monday night.
Speaker 1: No yeah Monday night the Rangers are not playing tonight.
Speaker 0: red wings.
Speaker 1: you said Rangers.
Speaker 0: I might have said red wings too.
Speaker 1: You definitely did not.
Speaker 1: you said Rangers.
Speaker 0: Let's go back and see what I said.
Speaker 0: Yep, Scott was right.
Speaker 0: I said Rangers because I'm living in New York now.
Speaker 1: It is better than the red wings Play.
Speaker 1: Rangers are taking a nap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, however the red wings Are going to be taking a nap meanwhile.
Speaker 0: very short nap yeah, but a nap meanwhile.
Speaker 0: There is a game seven still happening.
Speaker 1: Yeah Whoever that it wins that one very tired to get beat up by the well-rested Rangers.
Speaker 0: yeah, pretty much the only of the problem is the people who played.
Speaker 0: the Penguins and Winnipeg got the longest nap.
Speaker 1: yeah the big sleep.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our Website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.