Speaker 0: It's Monday, September 19th, 2015.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nods tonight.
Speaker 0: Never share your password with anyone.
Speaker 0: Ever.
Speaker 0: Ever, ever, ever, ever, ever.
Speaker 1: And anyone, anyone, anyone, anyone, anyone.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So this weekend we went upstate, me and Scott and Emily and a whole bunch of our friends, and we went to a haunted house.
Speaker 1: Well, it wasn't a haunted house.
Speaker 1: It was like a haunted playland.
Speaker 0: It was a haunted $40 land.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's a lot of money because you can go to a Six Flags for $40 with one of those sale ticket things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well for $25 more a person, we could add a Scream Pass and skip the lines.
Speaker 1: The only one line was long enough to warrant skipping and not $25 worth.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: I mean, I wouldn't pay $25 to skip lines at Cedar Point.
Speaker 1: How much is a Cedar Point ticket?
Speaker 0: When I was a kid, it was like $70 to get in for a whole day.
Speaker 1: How much is a Disney World ticket?
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: I don't usually buy a three-day, three-park pass, but how much is like a one-day, one-park pass?
Speaker 0: I have no idea, but I'm going to Disney World on Halloween, so I actually got to figure out, I got to buy tickets.
Speaker 1: I'm sure you can afford it, but it's expensive.
Speaker 1: It's hundreds of dollars.
Speaker 1: when I was there in the '90s.
Speaker 0: I will know, but luckily the hotel is cheap because it's part of a wedding block, so it kind of evens out.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, anything in Florida is cheap except tickets to Disney World.
Speaker 0: But the reason I bring this up, and this isn't what the show is about, but we went to this crazy haunted experience with a hayride and a bunch of stuff, with a headless horseman, and as far as I can tell, everyone who lives in the entire upstate region was there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was way crowded, more crowded than I expected.
Speaker 1: I expected it to be mad lame, but they were like hyping it up, so I'm like, "All right, fine.
Speaker 1: I'll pay $40.
Speaker 1: It seems like a lot of money, and I'll go check this thing
Speaker 1: out.".
Speaker 0: Scott messaged me before.
Speaker 0: He's like, "Someone's getting I Told You So, and it's either going to be them or
Speaker 0: me.".
Speaker 1: Right, so the problem was is that on the one hand, it wasn't awesome, so I really wanted to give them an I Told You So, but on the other hand, the production value was so high, I couldn't make an argument that it was super lame to deliver the I Told You So.
Speaker 0: I got about $40 worth of entertainment out of the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Maybe
Speaker 0: $20. $25.30,
Speaker 0: it was good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not
Speaker 1: $40. $40
Speaker 1: was like, "If you, Ted, hey, do you want to do this again next year?
Speaker 1: We changed everything, but it's the same production
Speaker 1: level.".
Speaker 1: I'd be like, "How
Speaker 1: much?".
Speaker 1: He'd be like,
Speaker 1: "$40?".
Speaker 1: I'd be like, "No.
Speaker 1: $20?
Speaker 1: Maybe if it's not cold
Speaker 1: out.".
Speaker 0: But if they were like, "We've upgraded that giant vagina you had to go
Speaker 0: through.".
Speaker 1: Ooh, that was one of the best parts.
Speaker 0: They could have used that to scare people way more than they did.
Speaker 1: They can't touch people.
Speaker 0: Remember the bee room where they had the little strings that felt like bugs touching your face?
Speaker 1: Well, it felt a lot like they were pretty much going for the throw paint against the wall method.
Speaker 1: Like, "Alright, you're not scared of zombies?
Speaker 1: Alright, we got a place with bees.
Speaker 1: We got a place with spiders.
Speaker 1: We got ghosts.
Speaker 1: We got
Speaker 1: clowns.".
Speaker 0: One of them was just a motel, and as you went, it was basically like the same motel room over and over again, but worse and worse and scarier.
Speaker 0: The toilet just got worse, mostly.
Speaker 0: Like, every time you came around a corner, it's like, "That toilet is worse than the last toilet I
Speaker 0: saw.".
Speaker 1: Well, it's a motel.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of toilets, right?
Speaker 1: But it's pretty much like, "There's something you're scared of, and we're gonna have it
Speaker 1: here.".
Speaker 0: I mean, even if you're just like me and Scott, they're like, "Okay, for those people, we're just gonna have someone hiding in a place they would never see, and just literally jump scare them at the best possible
Speaker 0: moment.".
Speaker 1: The giant clown was hiding behind the sign, and I'm just walking slowly, just checking stuff out.
Speaker 1: I'm mostly looking at the elaborate sets they've made.
Speaker 1: Like, "Whoa, these are really elaborate and
Speaker 1: awesome.".
Speaker 1: Just inspecting them to see how cool they are.
Speaker 1: Trying to go slowly, but they sort of push you along, right?
Speaker 1: They put so much detail into things, you don't want to go slow.
Speaker 1: You want to hang out and see what's going on.
Speaker 0: Like, there were skeletons deeply and elaborately inserted inside of a lot of things.
Speaker 1: Like, in the motel, there's a person in a room, and there's all these pictures on the wall, and all these props all stuck together.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it's like some scary library.
Speaker 1: I want to look at all the books.
Speaker 1: But, you know, I'm just looking behind the sign, and this clown is hiding behind there, and I think he saw that I was coming to look into his hiding spot.
Speaker 0: But, the one thing I want to say, this specific place, like, they have a hayride park, where I guess every year they have, like, this narrative.
Speaker 0: Like, there's a story about the headless horseman.
Speaker 1: It made no fucking sense.
Speaker 1: Why even have it?
Speaker 0: That was, like, you might think this is a weird thing to say about a haunted house.
Speaker 1: It didn't help that the person on our hayride really wasn't putting in a big effort.
Speaker 0: She was giving the desultory, "I am the witch, Hex, and I am smallpox something.
Speaker 0: Oh no, the headless horseman.
Speaker 0: You will never defeat
Speaker 0: me.".
Speaker 1: The thing is, all the other actors who were actually along the way, they seem to be trying harder.
Speaker 0: But, the overwroughtness of the plot, like, the plot of this haunted hayride was more than, like, 52 episodes of a For Real anime in terms of the amount of stuff.
Speaker 1: And how are there, like, every single possible scary thing?
Speaker 1: There was a pirate land, and a creepy western place, and a creepy colonial place, and a Dracula, and a Frankenstein.
Speaker 0: Like, there's all these villagers covered in pox marks, and they're all being hung, and there's this wizard guy, and the guy's like, "The headless horseman doesn't want these villagers.
Speaker 0: They're infected with
Speaker 0: smallpox.".
Speaker 0: And I was like, "Okay, that's oddly
Speaker 0: specific.".
Speaker 0: But then, smallpox kept coming up.
Speaker 0: Like, smallpox and some other virus are a big part of that story that I don't understand at all.
Speaker 1: But the sets are really nice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were.
Speaker 0: Like, at one point...
Speaker 1: Whoever makes those things probably does make sets for movies, but they should probably just quit that and make sets for movies.
Speaker 1: But wait, that place was making 40 bucks a head at least, times a big long line of people, times every night in October.
Speaker 1: I don't think you need another job if you own that shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, it probably costs a lot.
Speaker 1: You gotta pay the land.
Speaker 0: How much could that land cost?
Speaker 0: It's upstate New York.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of cost involved.
Speaker 1: Making all those sets was not cheap.
Speaker 0: And you can only run this thing for a month a year, basically.
Speaker 1: Right, you're paying for the cops to be there.
Speaker 1: If it rains, no one's showing up that day.
Speaker 0: Also, there were actually a lot of cops there, and a lot of security.
Speaker 0: Like, New York MSG level of security.
Speaker 1: I don't know what problems they had in the past.
Speaker 0: And it wasn't just that.
Speaker 0: We went apple picking in the morning.
Speaker 0: Same deal.
Speaker 0: They're like, "We're gonna search your car,
Speaker 0: maybe.".
Speaker 1: Well, that apple place is super paranoid that people are gonna steal apples.
Speaker 1: And it's like, "Dude, your apples are more expensive than the apples I get next to my house, which are also upstate New York apples.
Speaker 1: And they taste just the
Speaker 1: same.".
Speaker 0: But is there that much autumnal crime in upstate New York that this is a thing?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe when it gets cold, people run out of money.
Speaker 1: They gotta steal.
Speaker 1: They buy holiday presents.
Speaker 0: But really, I can't express this enough.
Speaker 0: Like, you might think, "Rim is exaggerating about the overwroughtness and complexity of the plot of this haunted
Speaker 0: hayride.".
Speaker 0: I'd love to read the script, but I think it might end... Like, you would need a... R. Scott Bakker would have trouble summarizing this in the body of works he's written to date.
Speaker 0: Smallpox came up, like, 40 times.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: So, it's Monday.
Speaker 0: It's not the lounge.
Speaker 0: Tech News Day.
Speaker 0: And there's a lot of news that we didn't talk about.
Speaker 0: And one thing I want to talk about is kinda... It's not new news, but it's a topic many of you haven't thought about.
Speaker 0: So, when I was a young lad, if you wanted to run an email server in the old days, like in the '90s, you could just start an email server and connect it to the internet.
Speaker 1: I mean, it was hard.
Speaker 1: Did you send mail?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like, you had to know computers.
Speaker 1: But, I mean, I can't even set up send mail now.
Speaker 0: I could back then.
Speaker 0: I can't now.
Speaker 1: I could... I mean, you took the class that taught you that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I did.
Speaker 1: I never did.
Speaker 1: So, I mean, like, I could read documentation on how to do it, and even with that, I wasn't able to do it.
Speaker 1: With documentation, I was able to set up pretty much every other kind of application out there.
Speaker 1: A little Apache, a little FTP, all that.
Speaker 1: Now, part of that was that email... But I couldn't set up email because it was so fucking complicated.
Speaker 0: Email used to be, like, in the old days... You know, email is one of these old internet protocols.
Speaker 1: Right, but if I knew what I was doing, I could have theoretically set up an email server, and it had a domain, and started sending and receiving emails to and from that domain.
Speaker 1: And I partially succeeded a couple times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we even Scott and I...
Speaker 1: And then I said, "Fuck it, let's Google do
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 0: We had a squirrel mail server for webmail for a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That was cool.
Speaker 0: It never quite worked 100%, but it worked better than the RIT email.
Speaker 0: I used to telnet...
Speaker 1: My RIT emails worked great.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, if you knew how to telnet into the VAX cluster...
Speaker 1: Oh, that's right.
Speaker 1: I always use my cs.rit.edu email.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the IT team used, like, IT, we also had addresses, but they used a different system.
Speaker 0: So I used the regular RIT email, which you could either telnet into Gracie, which was this old Unix cluster, or you could telnet into the VAX, which was literally open VMS, like, dear God.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure they retired those and replaced them with a bunch of Sun machines or something.
Speaker 0: But think about this.
Speaker 0: Like, everyone who got to RIT, like, email was not... Like, I know a lot of people who didn't have email addresses when we got to RIT.
Speaker 0: Like, I don't think, like, there was a different time in the year 2000.
Speaker 0: Most kids who got to RIT left behind their email address because it was, like, something.comcast.net that they couldn't take with them.
Speaker 1: Mine was, like, snet.net, when SMET was still a phone company.
Speaker 0: I had a Prodigy internet address still at that time.
Speaker 1: And before that, there was an AOL one.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah.
Speaker 0: But if you knew what you were doing, you could set up an email server, and if you just connected it to the internet, it worked.
Speaker 0: A problem with email as a service and a protocol is that it's an old protocol.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The way it was originally designed was, like, if you couldn't reach the place you were trying to send the email to, you would just send the email to someone else, and then they would try to pass it on.
Speaker 0: Like, send it to anyone.
Speaker 1: Like, who cares?
Speaker 1: Like, I'm trying to send an email to google.com, and I can't find google.com, so I'm going to send the email to whoever I find.
Speaker 1: I'll send it to, I don't know, rim.com.
Speaker 0: And then rim.com will be like...
Speaker 1: rim.com will actually do a best effort to try to get that email over to google.com.
Speaker 0: Because remember, old internet protocols, like all the old shit, that was designed to survive a nuclear strike against the United States.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: So it was designed to just kind of work no matter what.
Speaker 0: And also, in those days, there really wasn't spam or trolling or shitposting.
Speaker 0: Like, everyone on the internet was cool.
Speaker 0: In fact, the year 2000 was sort of like the tipping point where that stopped being true bit by bit.
Speaker 0: So, email had a problem once normal people got access to it, and spam appeared, and all these other problems.
Speaker 0: You know, skip, skip, skip, skip, current day.
Speaker 0: You can still, if you're an IT person, go read the documentation to like, send mail or something, and make a mail server.
Speaker 0: Totally fine, connected to the internet, and pretty much no one will ever get any email from you.
Speaker 0: People hated spam so much that they decided that they would rather miss real email and give up on an open internet than even let one spam through.
Speaker 0: So the average email service will just block emails from anyone it doesn't trust, and it pretty much only trusts big companies that are already running big email servers.
Speaker 0: So, my Gmail will go out fine, and anyone who already has big email infrastructure that has not had a spam problem happen is fine.
Speaker 0: No new email system will pretty much ever exist ever for the future of forever.
Speaker 1: I mean, you can start a new email system, you just need to like, you know, go have meetings and talk to people who run bigger email systems to tell them to trust you.
Speaker 0: This article is about, that actually isn't even true anymore.
Speaker 0: Like, you pretty much cannot get your mail server to work with any corporate network.
Speaker 0: Like, even if you get a lot of people, even big companies, to trust you, odds are an average person you send an email to won't get your emails.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, if you get Google to trust you, you're pretty much set, right?
Speaker 0: You might not be able to get Google to trust you.
Speaker 1: It's not easy, but it can be done.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, you can always send your emails through someone else, right?
Speaker 1: So, at work, we send a ton of emails.
Speaker 1: I mean, not a super ton, but we send a bunch, and they all get through.
Speaker 1: And the reason that is, is because you use Amazon SES, where basically, I use SMTP to tell Amazon SES to send the email for me.
Speaker 1: But I also point some DNS records at Amazon SES, and I give it permissions, so I can send an email from or to anyone at our domains.
Speaker 0: But, now you're dependent upon Amazon, which is fine.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's other services that do the same thing, like SendGrid, and MailChimp has some competing things, I forget what it's called, Mandrake or something.
Speaker 1: There's all kinds of different mail services you can use, either for mailing lists or just mail servers.
Speaker 1: You just point some DNS records, and you can start using them.
Speaker 0: But you pretty much have to use a service that gets identifying information from you, because anything that's more anonymized probably will get blocked for spam reasons.
Speaker 1: If you want to be anonymous, why use a fucking email?
Speaker 0: But that's interesting, because the original protocol was designed so that anyone can send a message to anyone, anywhere in the world, no matter what.
Speaker 0: And it turns out that humans would pretty much don't actually ever want a service like that ever.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: Why would you?
Speaker 0: Well, I did.
Speaker 0: I mean, remember Orkut, the first social network that we used?
Speaker 0: The first social network?
Speaker 0: It was great, because it had no controls for spam whatsoever.
Speaker 0: And it was awesome until the first shitbird got in, and then the entire service was ruined within 24 hours.
Speaker 0: So yeah, email's dead.
Speaker 0: Pretty much you have Gmail.
Speaker 0: You have some other service that lets you send electronic messages.
Speaker 0: But email, the original protocol, is for all intents and purposes dead.
Speaker 0: You don't need to know anything about it.
Speaker 1: Well, you still use it.
Speaker 0: Well yeah, but you use it the same way.
Speaker 0: you use old roads.
Speaker 0: The infrastructure, the political system that created the interstates is dead.
Speaker 0: Yet, the interstates remain.
Speaker 0: Got any news?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Lenovo, you should never buy a computer from ever again.
Speaker 0: Ever, ever, ever again.
Speaker 1: Because you can't trust them.
Speaker 1: But they're making something that I always question, like, "Why hasn't anyone made
Speaker 1: this?".
Speaker 1: They're making basically a giant table computer.
Speaker 1: It's like a 20-something-inch, 27-inch, so really not that big.
Speaker 0: Oh, it looks like it's about the same size as the new Nexus 5X.
Speaker 1: Hey-oh!
Speaker 1: It's 1,600 bucks, and it's a computer.
Speaker 1: It's just big.
Speaker 1: It's also a coffee table, basically.
Speaker 1: That's the thing that I kind of wanted at some point in my life.
Speaker 0: I've always wanted that.
Speaker 1: Not now, but it's taken this long for someone to make something so obvious.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've always...
Speaker 1: I guess you could have always just taken a television and just laid it flat and put a computer under it, but it wouldn't have a touchscreen.
Speaker 0: Well, also, most televisions don't have a great viewing angle unless you pay a lot of money.
Speaker 1: Right, and Microsoft tried to make the original Microsoft Surface, not the current one, but the original one, which was like a projector onto the bottom of a table, and the people were playing D&D with it, and then they stopped using it.
Speaker 1: Except for I think one hotel has one in their lobby somewhere.
Speaker 0: The PAX East main hotel had it down there.
Speaker 0: It might not still be there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as like a demo kiosk thing.
Speaker 1: But it's like, "Hey, that's actually a thing you could have in your
Speaker 1: house.".
Speaker 1: And it's like, "Why the hell
Speaker 1: not?".
Speaker 1: I guess it's really not that much better than, say, you have an iPad in your lap and you watch TV versus having your coffee table be an iPad and watch...
Speaker 0: But I wouldn't want to watch TV on it because I've got to look down.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: You use it to, say, choose channels or...
Speaker 0: Yeah, iPad still...
Speaker 1: But it's like holding an iPad for that is just better.
Speaker 1: Holding the Wii U tablet for that is just better.
Speaker 0: To me still, the only use case for this kind of thing...
Speaker 1: Board games.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It's not useful for generic computing.
Speaker 0: The apps that use it need to be designed for a shared screen where people are sitting around it.
Speaker 1: But it's like they're talking about using it for photo editing.
Speaker 1: That's stupid.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: That is the dumbest thing I've ever heard.
Speaker 0: A long time ago when 3D mice started appearing and all these haptic interfaces and touch screens started appearing, it became apparent immediately that for most things you use a computer for, a mouse or trackball and a keyboard is still the best interface with a screen in front of your face.
Speaker 1: One thing it seems they did get right with this is that it is battery powered and it can work with battery for a few hours and it has a little stand so you can kick it up.
Speaker 1: So you could take this with you, say camping, and play a little digital board game in the woods with it.
Speaker 0: The problem is most digital board games aren't designed for this kind of display.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no kidding.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying you just buy one of these, erase it.
Speaker 1: so Lenovo doesn't mess with you and don't do anything with it except make board games for it and play them.
Speaker 0: But that's it.
Speaker 0: It's a Catch-22.
Speaker 1: But you can just use an iPad for that and you don't want to give Lenovo money so fuck them.
Speaker 1: But please someone else make this.
Speaker 1: Or someone make a little stand for you to put an iPad on.
Speaker 1: This is useless unless it basically got the Nintendo treatment and someone was- Maybe I'll make a little stand for the iPad Pro and then you can play board games.
Speaker 0: But it needs first party apps.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm saying it would be a console.
Speaker 1: There's a ton of first party apps.
Speaker 1: You know how many board games there are for iPads?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and most of them really are still not designed for a bunch of people sitting around a big table playing.
Speaker 1: Actually a lot of them are.
Speaker 0: But the interface is not great.
Speaker 1: As long as you look away at someone's hand for a TV show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, with a giant table that's a problem.
Speaker 0: That's a big problem.
Speaker 1: It's not your turn.
Speaker 1: Just look away.
Speaker 0: That's not happening.
Speaker 0: I'm not looking away.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this is just a Catch-22.
Speaker 0: You would need first party software to make this good and it can't be productivity software because that's stupid on this form factor.
Speaker 0: No one's going to make those games because not everyone owns one of these.
Speaker 1: I don't know why they're making this.
Speaker 1: I don't understand.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Everyone else made it and it's like yeah, there's like five people who want this and you went ahead and made it.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 0: So yeah, but it doesn't matter because it's Lenovo.
Speaker 0: Anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So I follow this blog.
Speaker 0: It's called War is Borrowing and it's a pretty good blog about war stuff.
Speaker 0: Like historical war stuff, current war stuff.
Speaker 0: It's pretty well informed.
Speaker 0: But this particular article is very interesting.
Speaker 0: It talks about a very specific case during World War II where the allies were trying to assist our own POW stuck in Germany in escaping from BOW camps and rejoining the fight.
Speaker 0: And they did this primarily by hiding information.
Speaker 1: I thought it was shovels.
Speaker 0: No, hiding information.
Speaker 0: Shovels and all that nonsense were not that useful.
Speaker 0: Like that you can get on your own.
Speaker 0: People needed maps, compasses, that kind of shit.
Speaker 1: Oh, because once you escape, you don't know where the fuck to go.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: I mean, so say I took you...
Speaker 1: You didn't have your GPS?
Speaker 0: So Scott, let's say I took you.
Speaker 0: You and me get blindfolded and dropped off somewhere in upstate New York.
Speaker 0: How do we find our way home without asking someone?
Speaker 0: That's the problem they were facing.
Speaker 1: As soon as I hit like a road, I can see the signs on it.
Speaker 0: Maybe, but okay, so you see a town, Bumble Fuck, New York.
Speaker 0: Where is that?
Speaker 0: It's not a town you recognize.
Speaker 1: No matter where I am, I know New York because I studied it before I got here.
Speaker 1: So I'll just pick one direction and walk in that direction.
Speaker 1: And I'll know that let's say I head north.
Speaker 1: I'm either going to hit Canada, a river that I know.
Speaker 1: I find north by the space and the sun and shit.
Speaker 1: I-90.
Speaker 1: Or I'm going to find one of these things just by continuing north.
Speaker 1: And then once I find one of those things, I'm set.
Speaker 0: Alright, you're in a town called Bernard's and you don't know where that is.
Speaker 1: I'll just walk east and I know I'm either going to find Elmira, Coxsackie, the Hudson River, Connecticut, or Vermont.
Speaker 0: You immediately hit a river that is itself called the Passaic River, but that river name exists in a lot of places around America.
Speaker 1: But I know that I'm in New York.
Speaker 0: Alright, so you're all New Jersey.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so...
Speaker 1: I'm getting closer.
Speaker 0: They hid maps and things in places.
Speaker 1: Listen, being lost and alive is better than hanging out with Nazis and being alive.
Speaker 0: Nah, because if you escape from POW camp and they catch you and they know you as the guy who escaped once already, I suspect it's not as pleasant as it was the first time around.
Speaker 1: I mean, by the time I escaped, aren't I just like some American who's lost in the woods?
Speaker 0: I don't think any American lost in the woods in Germany in World War II was just sent on his way.
Speaker 1: Maybe I just got separated from all my dudes.
Speaker 1: They all died.
Speaker 0: But totally, they modified Monopoly boards and hid all the shit in board games.
Speaker 1: Why did the Nazis let board games through?
Speaker 1: Why didn't they check them for stuff?
Speaker 0: That's what this story is.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: It's really fascinating.
Speaker 0: It's my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: It's an article that I recommend you all read.
Speaker 1: And I hope, you know, were we checking the board games?
Speaker 1: I mean, if they were sending over some settlers or whatever?
Speaker 0: Ah, this only talks about our plan to let our POWs out.
Speaker 1: Yes, hide chiseled sheep.
Speaker 0: So one thing they did is, under the Monopoly money, it was just real fucking money.
Speaker 0: That's one of the things they did, and it totally worked.
Speaker 1: Such a great hiding place.
Speaker 0: It totally worked.
Speaker 0: They didn't check that thoroughly.
Speaker 1: Why are they not checking so thoroughly?
Speaker 0: Read the article and you'll see.
Speaker 1: Such lame checking.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: The TSA is better than that.
Speaker 0: Ah.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: I mean, the TSA will even find you three ounces of lotions.
Speaker 1: Alright, so, thing of the day.
Speaker 1: So you ever want to, like, you know, make a video of some computer usage, right?
Speaker 1: For, like, tutorial purposes?
Speaker 1: Like, you want to show someone something you did on your computer.
Speaker 1: But, uh, the thing you're showing them, you know, is just in a terminal.
Speaker 1: So it's almost like, why would I deliver to you this video of my terminal in, like, MPEG form?
Speaker 1: That's kind of, like, inefficient.
Speaker 1: And it kind of sucks, because, like, even if you see the video, you're, like, constantly pausing it.
Speaker 1: And you can't, like, you know, stop and reread things.
Speaker 1: And you definitely can't copy and paste out of the MPEG.
Speaker 1: My text, which would be super helpful.
Speaker 1: So this is a website called Ask Cinema, or ASCII.
Speaker 1: It's a combination of the word ASCII and cinema.
Speaker 1: It's ASCII Cinema, but the cinema and the ASCII are touching.
Speaker 0: Oh, they give you a pronunciation, God.
Speaker 0: It's ASCII-nima.
Speaker 1: Don't fuck yourself.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: That's the, that's the canonical machinima, GIF.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got any GIFs over there?
Speaker 1: And this website has tools which make it very, very easy to record and upload and display and share videos of things you did in your terminal that are very easy to watch and copy and paste from, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 1: So if you want to make some tutorials, teach people how to do things in terminals, or maybe just show coworkers or, you know, demo products that have command line interfaces or anything like that, this is an awesome thing to use, so do that.
Speaker 1: And also make MPEG-4 for backup in case something happens to this website.
Speaker 0: In the meantime, the Book Club book was The Wheel of Time.
Speaker 0: We're done with The Wheel of Time, book one, and we did an episode on it.
Speaker 0: We're burning through book five.
Speaker 1: I'm in the early pages of book five, like 10%.
Speaker 1: It's like chapter three or four.
Speaker 0: So if you were wondering if you should read the first book of The Wheel of Time to then listen to our Book Club episode on the first book of The Wheel of Time, all I'll say is we somehow kept reading.
Speaker 0: We're kind of burning through these books.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's exactly what we always said every time we mentioned it.
Speaker 1: It's generic fantasy, but it's generic fantasy and you're a nerd, so you like that, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you do.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: You care about world building?
Speaker 0: There's a lot of that in there.
Speaker 1: It's nothing but nerd fantasy, so just read it because you're a nerd and that's it.
Speaker 0: And then you'll know why I keep saying that Matt needs to shut the fuck up.
Speaker 1: Or read something else that has some sort of literary merit.
Speaker 0: Otherwise we have no big conventions until Magfest, which you should go to.
Speaker 0: Oh, but I think it's sold out of hotel rooms.
Speaker 0: So many people we know were unable to get hotel rooms because they did not listen to us.
Speaker 0: We told you so.
Speaker 0: With every convention.
Speaker 1: So you had been told by us and you did not listen.
Speaker 1: We were right again.
Speaker 0: And I'll tell you this.
Speaker 0: I'll make a new prediction.
Speaker 0: Next year, it's going to be as hard as PAX fucking East to get a hotel for Magfest.
Speaker 0: Mark my words.
Speaker 0: Even if you listen to us, you might not get one next year.
Speaker 0: That's my prediction.
Speaker 1: You're going to have to get on top of those internets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, do some Airbnb nonsense.
Speaker 0: You got to get an angle.
Speaker 1: There is one secret technique to getting a hotel room for Magfest.
Speaker 1: That technique is BOAT.
Speaker 1: It's National Harbor.
Speaker 1: It literally is on the water.
Speaker 1: You could pay some money to dock a boat there.
Speaker 0: Magfest website has directions.
Speaker 0: Like how are you getting here?
Speaker 0: And one of the options is boat.
Speaker 0: If you click on it, like, yeah, they totally tell you how to do that.
Speaker 1: If you get a boat somewhere, you don't have to worry about hotel as long as there's a bed on that boat.
Speaker 1: And the boat is not too big.
Speaker 1: Like cruise ship probably too big.
Speaker 0: So, yeah.
Speaker 0: Otherwise our Patreon will be starting up at some point in the near future.
Speaker 0: I got some other work.
Speaker 0: I got to finish first, but you ever wanted to hear those pre-release episodes of Geek Nights from the early days of 2005?
Speaker 1: Because we have nothing else of value or interest to give away to people who give us money.
Speaker 0: As we said before, we sang our own theme song in those days.
Speaker 0: Like we sang a song for you at the opening of every episode.
Speaker 0: I think maybe 20 people in the world have ever heard those episodes.
Speaker 0: So if the thousand, like 14, however many crazy episodes we've done of Geek Nights over the years are not enough, if you donate to our Patreon, I'm going to trickle out a bunch of episodes that have never been on the internet before.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So, Rym wanted to do an episode on this.
Speaker 1: I think we've talked about this before many, many times.
Speaker 0: I think we talked about it a lot in general in our lives, mostly Scott.
Speaker 1: But it keeps coming up, especially in the tech news all the time.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, man, we remind people of backups.
Speaker 1: By the way, backup everything all the time, always.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And if you're lazy, like I tweeted a little bit about this.
Speaker 1: Back your shit up.
Speaker 0: If you have a NAS, just a NAS, that's not a backup.
Speaker 0: That's redundancy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We've definitely talked about backing stuff up before enough.
Speaker 0: But I do now.
Speaker 1: We're just reminding you because it's never bad to remind you.
Speaker 1: But something we've talked about a lot, but I think it also always bear repeating.
Speaker 1: And I don't think a hundred percent we've done an episode on, but even if we had, that's okay.
Speaker 0: And I know a lot of you are doing this.
Speaker 1: I know so many people doing this and they always tell me whenever I tell them not to is never share your password to anything with anyone ever, under any circumstances, to any person.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: But, Rim and Scott, I hear you thinking already.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, but Rim and Scott, number one, I trust this person.
Speaker 1: They're like my wife or my husband or my mom or this person who's so incredibly close to me.
Speaker 0: Bosco.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That I trust them with like everything else in my life.
Speaker 1: Even like my credit card, my ATM card and my PIN number.
Speaker 1: Why did you tell them your PIN number?
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Why did you tell them your PIN number?
Speaker 1: Emily, do you know any Rims passwords?
Speaker 1: No, she said no.
Speaker 0: Emily knows one of my passwords temporarily because it's a bullshit password that was used for a specific purpose and is going away actually.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 0: It was, it was a, there was a, so yeah, one of the butt Rim and Scott's is there might be a system that you interact with that does not have multiple account capabilities.
Speaker 0: Old shit.
Speaker 0: One.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Like if you have a Windows computer, you can just make user accounts for all the different people that are going to use it.
Speaker 0: In the old days.
Speaker 1: And now no one needs to tell anyone the other person's passwords because you log in as you.
Speaker 0: But in the old days you couldn't do that.
Speaker 1: Like yeah, you had a Windows 3.1 computer didn't even have a password, but maybe you had a Windows 95 computer.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So now you have a password to log in or unlock a Windows 95 computer, but there's only one.
Speaker 1: It's not like, you know.
Speaker 0: That's why, uh, in the nineties, every kid who knew how to use the internet knew every website their parents ever visited, but not the other way around.
Speaker 1: So when you have a situation like that, you basically sort of have to follow the same rule.
Speaker 1: Don't tell anyone your password, but you know, the, your is multiple people and you literally just don't tell anyone else who's not one of the use.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's gotta be a need to know.
Speaker 1: If a friend comes over to and needs to use that Windows 3.1 computer, you unlock it for him.
Speaker 1: You don't tell him what it is.
Speaker 0: And of course the right answer is that system, whatever it is, is deprecated.
Speaker 0: You should assume that you're going to replace it when feasible.
Speaker 0: Now you might not be able to quickly because it's a thing that doesn't really exist anymore.
Speaker 0: Like, but, uh, you should at least bear in the back of your mind, like keep an eye out for a way to replace that thing with something that has user accounts.
Speaker 0: Also, number two, but rim and Scott, this thing doesn't have shared accounts or doesn't have account systems.
Speaker 0: You're probably wrong.
Speaker 0: A lot of things have ways to have multiple users that you don't realize.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Like Twitter.
Speaker 0: If you have a corporate Twitter account, you should set up tweet deck and then use other Twitter accounts for everyone to individually manage the group or the company Twitter.
Speaker 0: You're everyone in your company shouldn't all know the password to the Twitter account and log into it directly.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: But the reason I brought this up as a thing is that the most recent instance where this has come up is a problem you might not have thought about.
Speaker 0: I'm going to read the summary from the slash shot article that will tell you where we're going with.
Speaker 1: Well, I do want to talk about one more thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Is that you'll see on the news a lot or people a lot will say, you know, my account was hacked.
Speaker 1: My account was compromised account stolen, you know, like I lost my Warcraft account or someone stole my right.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: Ninety nine point.
Speaker 1: ninety nine percent of the time they're using the word hacked, compromised, whatever.
Speaker 1: The truth is there's no way to like figure out someone's Facebook password and steal their account.
Speaker 1: Facebook is so friggin secure.
Speaker 0: They told that password to someone.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Somebody guessed the password because it was really shitty or they told it to someone.
Speaker 1: Ninety nine point.
Speaker 1: nine nine nine percent of the time it was ninety nine percent.
Speaker 0: The other one percent is you installed malware.
Speaker 1: That's also possible.
Speaker 1: But that's base.
Speaker 1: You know, it's still.
Speaker 1: you told the password to someone.
Speaker 1: They guessed your password or they had a malware that key logs you and got your password.
Speaker 0: Or you didn't hack into Facebook.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And, you know, it's not like I can go on to Facebook and pick an arbitrary person and log in as them somehow by hacking.
Speaker 1: That's not a thing you can do with any, you know, easy method that anyone like maybe the NSA can do it.
Speaker 1: It would be difficult for them.
Speaker 1: Someone who worked at Facebook can do it as an inside job.
Speaker 0: So there's a court case.
Speaker 0: This is a.
Speaker 1: So if you think it doesn't happen.
Speaker 0: This is a summary on Slashdot by Schwitt one of an article on the Washington Post.
Speaker 1: Such a trustworthy story.
Speaker 1: Schwitt one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: On Slashdot.
Speaker 1: Whoa.
Speaker 1: This is like, whoa.
Speaker 0: But as I read this out loud, you'll start to realize where I'm going with this quote.
Speaker 0: And I'm giving proper attribution here.
Speaker 0: on Monday, the Ninth Circuit Court in the United States.
Speaker 1: The best court.
Speaker 0: We'll hear arguments in United States versus Nosal on an interesting note.
Speaker 1: Who the hell is Nosal?
Speaker 0: We'll have to find out if a person shares access to a computer account with someone else.
Speaker 0: Under what circumstances can the second person engage in unauthorized access under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act?
Speaker 1: I don't know what that act says, except that it's a bullshit act.
Speaker 0: The case.
Speaker 1: But I can tell you what it should say.
Speaker 0: The case centers around the difference between having access to something and having permission to use it.
Speaker 0: In other words, if you give somebody a desktop password to your computer so they can watch Netflix, which is already logged in, but they take advantage of that to read all your email, how does the law look at that?
Speaker 0: What happens is they come back later, log in again without your immediate explicit permission, but only watch Netflix, which you gave them permission for before.
Speaker 0: What happens if you give them your Netflix password so they can watch it at your house, but not the desktop password?
Speaker 0: They go home and use that on their desktop to watch Netflix at their house.
Speaker 0: Eugene Volko has a paper coming articulating "the legal interpretations of computer trespass".
Speaker 0: and the gist of all this is...
Speaker 1: The current law is probably not addressing any of these issues and they're probably all fucked up.
Speaker 0: You open yourself up.
Speaker 0: I'm not a lawyer, this is not legal advice.
Speaker 0: You open yourself up, in my non-lawyer opinion, to insane liability that no one can really explain to you because it's not well understood.
Speaker 0: yet if you ever give anyone your password.
Speaker 0: I mean, if I loan Scott my car and he's drunk and he kills someone with it...
Speaker 1: The law covers that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like the law will deal with that.
Speaker 0: But don't loan your car to someone that you see is visibly intoxicated or you're fucked.
Speaker 1: But in the early days of drunk driving law, the law really didn't cover that very well.
Speaker 0: So if I loan my password to Joy Jojo Shabadoo and then Joy Jojo Shabadoo gives material support to Daesh terrorists using my account...
Speaker 1: You also gave material support, didn't you?
Speaker 0: Could I get in trouble?
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: You don't know.
Speaker 1: So don't even risk that shit.
Speaker 0: And even if you think... Say someone else does something legal but against the terms of service of a website by accident... Even if you gave them that permission, who's responsible?
Speaker 0: How much trouble could you get?
Speaker 0: No one knows.
Speaker 0: And in fact, it's even worse because the courts are fucking this up and hurting people already.
Speaker 0: So if you give a password to anything, to anyone, no one knows how much trouble you or that anyone could get into.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not just things like that.
Speaker 1: Let's say you live with your friend and you don't have a lot of money and you like to play out of Hearthstone.
Speaker 1: So you don't really want to play against each other.
Speaker 1: so you don't have two accounts.
Speaker 0: My brother and I did that.
Speaker 0: There's an MMO, The Realm.
Speaker 0: We actually just used the same account and we each made two of the characters.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And that way, you save a lot of money.
Speaker 1: You buy a card, well now you both have the card because you're sharing the same account.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like,
Speaker 1: "Whoa."
Speaker 1: Rather than like, "Oh, I have Dr.
Speaker 1: Boom and you don't.
Speaker 1: Ha ha
Speaker 1: ha.".
Speaker 1: You're all just using the same account.
Speaker 1: You can't play against each other but that's fine.
Speaker 1: And you're all good.
Speaker 1: And you're just sharing the Battle.net login.
Speaker 1: Okay, so you're sharing this Battle.net login.
Speaker 1: And then your friend maybe gets drunk or maybe he's a jerk or who knows, goes and just starts harassing some people on the Hearthstone.
Speaker 1: Like he sends a friend request and then he tells the person like, "Fuck you.
Speaker 1: Fuck, fuck,
Speaker 1: fuck.".
Speaker 1: And then that person reports him and now your account gets banned.
Speaker 1: And oops, why did you share an account with somebody?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And also, you think of that, you're sort of like trying to, you know, all these situations, it's like you're really just trying to steal Hearthstone cards effectively.
Speaker 1: The same way as sharing Netflix passwords.
Speaker 1: It's like, "Yo, you're trying to avoid paying for Netflix twice.
Speaker 1: You're trying to avoid paying for Hearthstone cards twice.
Speaker 1: You're trying to avoid paying for things you're supposed to be paying for.
Speaker 1: So you kind of deserve, right?
Speaker 1: You shouldn't be doing
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 0: Of course, part of the reason this has come up lately is that a lot of services like Netflix and everything, they knew you were sharing passwords forever.
Speaker 0: They always knew that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And as time has gone on, they're using that information to monetize their platforms better.
Speaker 0: So stay tuned for how they use that information in the future.
Speaker 0: Because guess what?
Speaker 0: You gave it to them.
Speaker 0: They know, "Oh, these are the five IP addresses that Joey JoJo logs in from all the time.
Speaker 0: Based on those infinite magic cookies that we know about from privacy tracking stuff, we now know who all of Joey JoJo's friends
Speaker 0: are.".
Speaker 0: Interesting.
Speaker 0: And we got that information basically legally because he logged in, like he already signed up for the service.
Speaker 1: Your computer told us this information with software that you put on the computer and said, "Yes, software, do
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 1: And it did it.
Speaker 0: Now, there's also a technological reason.
Speaker 0: I mean, if you're a corporate user, obviously you know the reasons for this.
Speaker 0: You want everyone to have their own accounts.
Speaker 0: so when someone fucks up or something, then there's an audit trail and you can go to the police or the regulator or the auditor and be like, "Rim logged into the system at 4.51.21 at 8 milliseconds and made this change and this other thing happen
Speaker 0: later.".
Speaker 0: Or like shell history.
Speaker 0: If you all share the same shell, a bunch of stuff is in the history now.
Speaker 0: Usually, I like to have a consistent shell.
Speaker 0: As in, if I hit up when I log into my system, whatever's there is whatever I did last.
Speaker 1: Imagine if someone else did a bunch of stuff and you press up and you're like, "What's
Speaker 1: this?".
Speaker 0: Yeah, what's all this business?
Speaker 0: Now, what if my history's gone?
Speaker 0: What if I ran a command and I forgot and I needed to find it but he ran my history out?
Speaker 1: I got these files in my documents folder.
Speaker 1: Someone moved them on me.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And those things can happen by accident.
Speaker 0: Even if you trust someone 100%, it's still good for you each to have separate accounts.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter that someone can still get material access.
Speaker 0: For example, Emily and I have separate accounts on our NAS.
Speaker 0: I'm the administrator.
Speaker 0: I could just go get those files.
Speaker 1: Also, you have physical access to the NAS.
Speaker 1: There's a way to probably stick a pin in it to reset it.
Speaker 1: You can just pull it out of the wall, plug it into your own computer and do anything to it.
Speaker 1: Even though Emily's not the administrator, or maybe she is, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I could come and I could grab the NAS, take it home with me and get all the files.
Speaker 1: Nothing you could do about it.
Speaker 0: Scott and I both use our frontrowcrew.com email addresses, like a Gmail thing.
Speaker 0: A bunch of our friends use it too.
Speaker 0: Scott is the administrator of that.
Speaker 0: Scott could go get my emails.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could just reset RIM's email password, log in as RIM and read all his email.
Speaker 0: I trust him, but the difference is if we use one Gmail account with the same password, that is a way different situation from legal, ethical, auditing, and technological concerns than it is if I have my account, Scott has his account.
Speaker 0: Separately, there's the role of the administrator.
Speaker 0: that happens to be fulfilled by Scott.
Speaker 0: that has other meta capabilities.
Speaker 0: It's not necessarily that he can get access.
Speaker 1: A lot of these legal questions are totally different, right?
Speaker 1: If we are sharing a password and I send an email, then the legal question is a lot different than, "Oh, you're the administrator and you logged into RIM's account and sent an email by resetting his password without asking
Speaker 1: him.".
Speaker 0: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 1: It's totally different.
Speaker 0: It protects you and it protects the people around you to have well-defined roles of interaction in electronic systems independent of the material security underlying those systems.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: That's the entire point of this episode.
Speaker 1: Also, when a password, it has to be remembered by more people.
Speaker 0: It's going to be a shittier password.
Speaker 1: It generally has to be shittier or easier to guess because it's something that more people can memorize.
Speaker 1: If there's something that's unique to you, it's usually easier for you to memorize it or you can use something like a password card or whatever or some sort of other password-y system.
Speaker 0: I'll be honest.
Speaker 0: There are a tiny number of shared passwords Scott and I have for various reasons.
Speaker 1: There is one.
Speaker 0: A tiny number.
Speaker 0: There is one.
Speaker 0: It's not the best password, but we'll both remember it.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone else in the world will ever know that password.
Speaker 1: If someone gets the password, big deal.
Speaker 0: If someone gets, at this point, that password doesn't actually have access to much anymore.
Speaker 0: You know what you could have done with that password?
Speaker 0: You could have hacked our wireless router.
Speaker 1: It's not even something we both need access to.
Speaker 1: I could just change it on you and it wouldn't matter.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Think of it that way.
Speaker 0: A lot of regulation in the finance world and in business around who has access to what, it's not about material access.
Speaker 0: When I worked at a broker-dealer, I could give myself root credentials on the production trading systems.
Speaker 0: I could know anything.
Speaker 0: I could do select queries against the database.
Speaker 0: I could just get raw access to the database's underlying files.
Speaker 0: But I had to log in through an audited system so people knew when and how I was accessing the system.
Speaker 0: So if I log in through the front end, I only get access to the data that my role as whatever it is I'm doing is supposed to get access to.
Speaker 0: Independently, I have a role as administrator where I have more access, but those two levels of access are controlled separately and the regulation is around that.
Speaker 0: A lot of regulations are around.
Speaker 0: certain kinds of roles cannot be shared by the same person.
Speaker 0: So if I were a trader, I could not also be an administrator.
Speaker 0: If I was a trader, I probably shouldn't have access to anything.
Speaker 0: So think about that the next time your Facebook friend from out of town crashing on your couch wants to log into your HTPC and then your Amazon account to watch Netflix.
Speaker 1: Another big issue is that even if you're just not sharing your passwords with anyone, it's still having just a password is a problem these days.
Speaker 1: You really need two factor authentication to be safe.
Speaker 0: A lot of things support.
Speaker 0: Google just supports it.
Speaker 0: Gmail just supports it.
Speaker 1: Almost everything you use probably supports two factor authentication, right?
Speaker 1: Even, you know, Yahoo's doing something and every almost everything I use like Tumblr even was like send you a text with a number that you can use every time you log in.
Speaker 0: It is trivial to set up.
Speaker 0: At least use it for your email.
Speaker 0: Because as we've talked about, if someone compromises your email, they can reset everything you've got.
Speaker 1: Actually, if you have two factor authentication, they might not be able to if true because they might need to like generate a code or have the piece of paper with codes on it.
Speaker 1: The backup codes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: To reset the password on something.
Speaker 0: And I think we've done shows on two factor.
Speaker 0: I mean, I could tell you that the current two factor number of my email account, you would have six seconds to crack my actual password.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But yeah, two factor authentication is like essential for anything you care about being secure.
Speaker 1: So anything you have, even though it's a pain in the ass, it's totally worth it to enable two factor authentication.
Speaker 1: So it's not just something, you know, a password, it's something you have and something, you know, like a phone or a little USB stick or something on anything you can just because why not?
Speaker 1: It's free.
Speaker 1: It's not like they charge you for this.
Speaker 1: And it just.
Speaker 1: you're never going to get screwed over if you do it.
Speaker 1: But if you want to have multiple people sharing, you can't be doing two factor because only one person can have the thing you have.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's an intrinsic token.
Speaker 0: You can't copy that token.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's a physical thing.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, you can copy a key to a house and they both have keys.
Speaker 0: You can't copy an RSA dongle.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: So maybe barring again like that show we did on security.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: NSA spy nonsense might be able to get around this.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: But yeah, you can.
Speaker 1: There's one anywhere.
Speaker 1: Period.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: So you either have it or you don't.
Speaker 1: So if you want two factor authentication, you can't share a password with someone.
Speaker 1: So if you're sharing passwords and doing the thing we tell you not to do, then you're going to not enable two factor because you don't want to ruin your password sharing system.
Speaker 1: So don't share the password in the first place and enable the two factor and you're all set.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.