Speaker 1: It's Monday June 1st 2015. my name is rim my name is Scott, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We're talking about how to figure out how to trust the software that you download.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So far I'm on a streak of one for having no biking anecdotes being in the show.
Speaker 0: We keep this up except is that meta count as an infringement, but meta never counts.
Speaker 1: That's what I specifically said, I think was.
Speaker 1: I won't talk about fixie guys.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the only reason for the help now can't can't can't can't talk can't say anything.
Speaker 1: no bikes.
Speaker 0: I went to work today for the first time in a while.
Speaker 0: I didn't do any work and There was so much netrunner action today news wise that that took up most of my time.
Speaker 0: also Went shopping during lunch and whatnot now.
Speaker 1: I've actually I. I spent most of today at work Sitting in a meeting that was useless and then We have a trip to London coming up and like no one booked it because every time I said hey guys Let's book this trip.
Speaker 1: No no no let's wait.
Speaker 1: Let's wait.
Speaker 1: so finally like today book it.
Speaker 1: so I spent the day trying to book a flight to and from London like the week after next and Of course now.
Speaker 1: It's too late, so I'm dropping like three grand for this trip.
Speaker 0: It's not your three grand No, it's not.
Speaker 0: so it gives a.
Speaker 1: well I've been.
Speaker 1: I have an interest in the company such that a percentage of that three grand is actually my three grand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean okay, so even if you did it well and in months in advance It would have been what two grand.
Speaker 1: no like eight or nine hundred.
Speaker 1: like flights to London are not expensive if you book him in Advance.
Speaker 0: I've been to spend three grand.
Speaker 0: may as well.
Speaker 0: just spend six grand.
Speaker 0: go first class.
Speaker 1: first class is like 11,000 business class.
Speaker 1: I could get for about four or five.
Speaker 0: just go for it full full 11,000.
Speaker 0: You don't have to pay and some of you get to sit.
Speaker 1: no they would know.
Speaker 1: so a co-worker at one point did Book just business class without asking anyone And it was like eight grand and there was some drama because of that because no one's ever done that before.
Speaker 1: I Mean I booked business class when I get it like cheaper than economy because of that cool way to her thing.
Speaker 1: But anyway the problem I ran into is I use kayak usually because they're actually like.
Speaker 1: they're not like.
Speaker 1: all those sites are not great.
Speaker 1: But of all those sites that one's actually been pretty oak like it's worked out for me.
Speaker 0: I mean all the sites work the price lines the kayaks yeah, but they all suck also.
Speaker 1: Yeah for various reasons, but something to happen this time They must have changed something because I searched and I was like oh It's like a grand like these aren't so bad.
Speaker 1: so I pick a flight I'm like all right cool And I go to book it and then you know it always takes you to like the actual place You're gonna book from there.
Speaker 1: hidden fees no no it took me to this place called edreams that I'd never heard of.
Speaker 1: So all right like fine.
Speaker 1: I mean I've booked on shady ass like things like that before and it's my.
Speaker 0: is there?
Speaker 0: Why does there even exist?
Speaker 0: I mean I understand the purpose of kayak is to like search.
Speaker 0: all the different airlines together route to to you know Aggregate, but when you click buy shouldn't it always take you to the official website of the air?
Speaker 1: Because that price is usually through someone else who either bought or has a way to buy or an insurance or something.
Speaker 0: those places should Legally be permitted to exist.
Speaker 1: you know how we could fix that.
Speaker 0: imagine if you went down to the grocery store And there's the grocery store And they have apples and there's a guy in front of the grocery store And you can't go in the grocery store and get an apple.
Speaker 1: he comes out was like.
Speaker 1: Oh you want to buy an apple I'll be right back, and he comes out goes in the grocery store.
Speaker 0: He waits in line He buys the apple and then he sells the Apple to you.
Speaker 0: So like fuck you.
Speaker 1: There's an easy way to make that happen.
Speaker 1: We would just have to have laws and then also trade agreements.
Speaker 1: that said any airline Must publish in a standardized format all of their prices at all times for all of their offerings.
Speaker 1: Full-stop fuck you mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: that would make that middle layer disappear.
Speaker 0: How about all businesses that sell products to the public directly as opposed to b2b?
Speaker 0: Must publish?
Speaker 1: nope then I'd be an airline, and I wouldn't sell to the public.
Speaker 1: I'd only sell b2b to one of those shady people in the middle.
Speaker 0: Why would what?
Speaker 0: how does it benefit you?
Speaker 1: I can obfuscate everything internally and still do price discrimination.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's a lot of new prices.
Speaker 0: Why don't you just do price discrimination to make it fucking public?
Speaker 0: just be like yes I'm discriminating prices what you can do about it.
Speaker 1: So I watched a co-worker booking flights somewhere else and they opened this.
Speaker 1: they searched for the same flight on the same service in Chrome Firefox and ie all in the equivalent of incognito and got radically different prices.
Speaker 1: And we could.
Speaker 1: we tested it.
Speaker 1: it was based on browser.
Speaker 0: Is user agents to try different OS's?
Speaker 1: yeah, so you know what I figured out.
Speaker 1: if you're on if you're using Internet Explorer And you try to buy plane tickets.
Speaker 1: They just give you worse prices.
Speaker 1: I guess they think you're dumb enough to take them.
Speaker 1: okay anyway, so Then I get to this payment portal that asks for PayPal or a credit card warning.
Speaker 1: sign number one Morning, so number two.
Speaker 1: That's weird for a for booking a flight.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't use PayPal to book a flight.
Speaker 0: I mean most places online.
Speaker 0: let you choose your payment method.
Speaker 1: yeah, but it's still so.
Speaker 1: I pick credit card and then Amex is not an option.
Speaker 0: Amex is usually not an option not for flights.
Speaker 1: every airline takes Amex because that's what every corporate credit card for travel is.
Speaker 0: that's true.
Speaker 0: It is weird for a travel related business.
Speaker 1: So I look at it, and I think well I could book anyway on my own credit card And then just get the reimbursement.
Speaker 1: no that'd be fine because I'm not giving my credit card to shady Back and I'd use a Google wallet for it, so I'd be safe okay, so that would have been fine.
Speaker 1: But then I think a second and I type a dreams into Google And all the results are this place fucking fucked me.
Speaker 0: How did they fuck?
Speaker 0: you bought a ticket and you didn't actually get a ticket.
Speaker 0: bought a ticket?
Speaker 1: They charged me twice, and then they disappeared and never gave me the ticket.
Speaker 1: like crazy egregious bullshit.
Speaker 0: How come the government isn't arrested whoever?
Speaker 1: that's what a lot of people are wondering.
Speaker 1: this is a recent thing.
Speaker 0: so then I go I set up something shady like that and see how long it goes before we get busted.
Speaker 1: yeah, so then I go back in a kayak and basically Every result for like the first three pages.
Speaker 1: if you sort by cheapest is this edreams fake site Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: How did?
Speaker 0: why don't you contact kayak and say hey you should remove?
Speaker 1: I tweeted at them no response.
Speaker 1: I emailed them no response.
Speaker 0: What kind of money is kayak just getting?
Speaker 0: like the Commission Payment?
Speaker 1: there must be something going on like that.
Speaker 1: But I mean like they have all their similarly shady things there before like all sites do but like edream seems to be literally this Listen, I would just basically suck it up and pay the extra money to just go directly to the airlines.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what I did.
Speaker 0: even if I'm getting ripped off because maybe there's some reseller I can go to and get a lower price.
Speaker 0: I just go directly to the airlines website and buy the ticket because at least then I can trust yeah I just went directly to Delta.
Speaker 1: actually the one nice thing that worked out is because the ticket is so Expensive because it's last-minute or whatever.
Speaker 1: You get extra air miles based on how much you paid for the ticket, but they're my air miles not the companies.
Speaker 1: I never understood why Individual people always get the air miles when companies buy the ticket because otherwise if I didn't get the air miles I would be a lot less willing to travel for work.
Speaker 0: If I was a company I would keep all those fucking.
Speaker 1: there's been lawsuits about that.
Speaker 1: actually there have been like companies really can't do.
Speaker 0: Really yeah, that's interesting cuz they're the ones paying.
Speaker 1: yeah, so those are a separate thing.
Speaker 1: no there are Corporate air miles accounts that do things.
Speaker 1: There's the problem is every airline thing.
Speaker 1: That's let's do a Thursday show on air miles.
Speaker 1: I got a lot to say.
Speaker 1: I get a lot to say because I have air miles with like eight different fucking air miles things I have the most with Turkish air.
Speaker 1: I have like seven or eight thousand that are far away.
Speaker 1: Yeah anyway.
Speaker 1: So I guess it's Monday's.
Speaker 1: we got some tech news.
Speaker 0: It's so much tech news right now.
Speaker 1: Yep, so what we're trying here is we're gonna.
Speaker 0: We're basically We're out of Monday topics.
Speaker 1: We've run out of Monday topics that either don't require that either like we can do without doing some research like topics that we don't know enough about to talk for 45 minutes on without research or Rehashing something we've already done just with like.
Speaker 1: oh What's changed in the last 10 years since we did that show?
Speaker 0: and the thing is change in tech recently hasn't been as Dramatic.
Speaker 1: processors aren't that much faster, right?
Speaker 0: There haven't been crazy new developments.
Speaker 0: the things that are crazy new developments like aren't available to the public yet and or there's not much to say about or whatever.
Speaker 0: and You know there was so much to talk about because he started geek nights.
Speaker 0: We hadn't talked about anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we were like let's do a show on NTP.
Speaker 1: Let's do a show on how hard drives work.
Speaker 1: There was a lot of shows.
Speaker 0: so we got 10 years where the shows out of that It's like well hard drives still they changed to SSDs I guess.
Speaker 1: I guess we haven't done a show on how SSDs work have we?
Speaker 1: or like hybrids.
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: We did a show on raid, but even raid is kind of obsolete like prop algorithms usually better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, desktop Daz versus NAS Daz is coming back.
Speaker 0: It's like even all that would be one show.
Speaker 1: okay Yep, but anyway, and we've done tech news roundups where we just do like 15 tech news's and you know It's basically this week in tech but without What that show in garbage?
Speaker 1: Yeah that show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway people who know more about actual technology instead of you know enough about technology to work with technology and not just be journalists.
Speaker 1: yep, but We're trying something a little different.
Speaker 1: now what we're gonna do unless one of you has a better idea is Find a tech news that actually has like an underlying topic That's worthy of discussion and do like what two of those or one of those as the main part of the show.
Speaker 0: Because sometimes it's a tech news that we can just go on and on about because there's something going on in it.
Speaker 1: yep So we're so we're trying that.
Speaker 1: it's like halfway between a tech news roundup and a regular geek nights.
Speaker 1: Monday We're gonna try this format.
Speaker 0: There is so much tech news right now.
Speaker 0: Why don't we discuss that yeah?
Speaker 1: So uh I got a tech news too because Scott used to always complain when we were doing the show.
Speaker 1: It's like a room that tech news you have isn't a tech news.
Speaker 0: well, it's so much tech news out.
Speaker 0: there is actually just either business news or Political news that is somehow related to technology.
Speaker 0: for example Oh this tech companies got bought as IPO in is VCs invested in this and it's like that's business business news about a tech company right?
Speaker 0: or you know?
Speaker 0: oh Right now for example there was just a Supreme Court decision today about a guy making threats on Facebook And you know what that's legal news.
Speaker 0: It just happened to be that it somehow involved Facebook.
Speaker 0: that doesn't make it tech news.
Speaker 0: It's not about technology.
Speaker 0: technology touches every part of our lives in this society that we live in in the West.
Speaker 0: Therefore you could if you were so loosey-goosey in your definition consider everything is tech news Even just you know yep, but you can't.
Speaker 1: so I have a Legit real tech news here.
Speaker 1: a very specific thing and let's see how much you guys care about it.
Speaker 1: Not at all.
Speaker 1: so I knew about half of what's going on in this and Scott knew the rest cuz he actually writes code.
Speaker 1: really so so MSV CRT is that thing that you download in Windows to make some programs just work.
Speaker 0: You'll see Time, but you know basically on time RT.
Speaker 0: I think yeah, I don't know what it stands for exactly.
Speaker 0: Application.
Speaker 1: they get an MSV CRT error in their computer.
Speaker 1: blue screens.
Speaker 0: They don't know why doesn't blue screen?
Speaker 0: But basically someone else out there has Visual Studio And they write a program in C, and they want that program to run on your computer, but you need some libraries.
Speaker 1: That is the majority cause of blue screens in old days that DLL blue screens.
Speaker 0: Okay, you need some libraries and for some reason.
Speaker 0: They don't just fucking include these things in Windows.
Speaker 0: So you need to get this MSV CRT C library thing installed so that The person's program that they wrote in C in Visual Studio will run on your Windows computer.
Speaker 0: Why don't they just include these libraries in Windows?
Speaker 1: I don't know anyway, so there's a bug if you use that and you use Min GW.
Speaker 0: so Min GW is sort of a similar kind of thing But you're in a scenario where you have a Windows computer, and you've got a program written in C for Linux type machines right?
Speaker 0: or GNU machines You know could be BSDs.
Speaker 0: you know Unix is whatever.
Speaker 0: so for example you got W get you get the source code you want to Compile it and run it on Windows.
Speaker 0: Min GW is sort of the thing that gets that done.
Speaker 1: So it turns out if you're using Min GW and depending on a bunch of other factors Here, I'll read the article because they give a pretty good Explanation.
Speaker 1: so let's say that you need accurate floating-point numbers more accurate than usual.
Speaker 1: And you have decided to use the long double data type for extra precision already.
Speaker 1: We've lost all the Python programmers and me.
Speaker 1: So you're using this long double and then after you do a bunch of calculations you print your number to look at it for Troubleshooting like whatever to your shock.
Speaker 1: I love this article.
Speaker 1: instead of the number being one two three dot four five six seven eight nine.
Speaker 1: It is printed out as negative six point five one eight four two seven times ten to the 264th or Two point seven four five five six three depending on your specific computer, right?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean it could be Big Endian or Little Endian.
Speaker 0: right this is due to a bug.
Speaker 1: It could be two's complement in some versions of Min GW G plus plus.
Speaker 1: four point eight point one Where That library still uses MSV CRT for some of its functions like print, right?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean usually when you are running something cross-platform you and you have a light, you know And something's written for a library a but the platform you're on has library B. what you'll do is you'll just make a new version of library a. That is supposed to look like the original library as far as the application is concerned But really you replace the contents of some of its functions with wrappers around the local system library.
Speaker 1: Now that's actually something I'm very familiar with because one of my first big IT Projects when I worked at IBM and was like just working at places for real was using wine and tools like it To make crufty old Windows applications run in Linux to make thin terminal, right?
Speaker 0: So for example, I write a program on Linux and I you know Import this library the printing the standard input/output library and then I go standard input/output library dot print Okay, great.
Speaker 0: And then on the Linux machine obviously there that library exists and it contains the code to execute when someone wants to print something.
Speaker 0: So now I want to take that code that I wrote and run it on Windows, but Windows doesn't have that library.
Speaker 0: So we need to install a library that looks like that standard input/output library that was on the Linux machine.
Speaker 0: But obviously we just take the code from the original library and bring it over to Windows.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna work because printing works differently.
Speaker 0: So we'll take that original library and we'll change it around to the inside of the print function actually says oh Yeah, go find the windows print function and use that.
Speaker 0: Yep So so now my original code is untouched.
Speaker 0: You can compile it against this phony library and then the phony library when my program Calls the code in that library will then call the code in the windows library, which will then actually print things.
Speaker 1: So MS V CR T's runtime reserves 80 bits for double and long double 80 bits.
Speaker 0: Wouldn't it just be 128 bits?
Speaker 1: It's 80 bits min GW When it uses when it uses MSV CRT 64-bit thing right print this out Interprets it using the first 64 bits Isn't?
Speaker 0: I mean?
Speaker 1: I know this discrepancy causes quote garbage results to be output.
Speaker 0: isn't a 64-bit machine and and regular old integers supposed to be 64 bits.
Speaker 1: Microsoft C++ runtime library reserves 80 bits for double and long double.
Speaker 0: Shouldn't a long double be even more than a double fuck?
Speaker 1: if I know I've write Java and Python I don't write.
Speaker 0: or I mean on the 64-bit machines.
Speaker 0: are the C Compilers still considering a regular int to be 32-bit just to be nice and then doubles become 64?
Speaker 0: But then wouldn't a long double be 128?
Speaker 1: maybe a long double is 80 for some are like.
Speaker 1: I honestly don't know.
Speaker 1: Okay, so That is some tech news now one That is also the difference between someone with a classical computer science degree versus like software engineering or IT Like CS people learn that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: also a more than nobody in the world gives a fuck about this.
Speaker 0: Cuz who the hell is compiling?
Speaker 0: Who's doing this?
Speaker 1: only the weirdest people the same people who use like Cygwin legitimately On top of min GW, yes.
Speaker 1: So the people who run Cygwin and then run applications in Cygwin as their primary desktop Yeah, they're having trouble.
Speaker 0: They're having trouble right now with some of their fancier programs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I need high precision floating-point numbers.
Speaker 1: So this actually fuck Fuck fuck.
Speaker 1: one of my developers actually might have You know what?
Speaker 1: This is gonna sound crazy.
Speaker 1: This might explain an issue.
Speaker 0: all your shit is Java.
Speaker 1: No, there's some CC plus plus stuff that has JNI connections are using Minji W One of the development environments probably is I'll bet there's a unit test that I see only matters if it compiling against those libraries I'm gonna go look at.
Speaker 0: I mean someone just you know, you know already.
Speaker 1: is I mean abandon?
Speaker 1: all hope you use You're using long doubles up to got abandon.
Speaker 1: I'll hope you use JNI.
Speaker 1: Okay, JNI That's how you basically have a C++ program interfacing directly with Java.
Speaker 0: Wouldn't you just use some?
Speaker 0: I mean if I had I don't like you wouldn't what?
Speaker 0: wouldn't you just use some sort of data interchange like a database or a file?
Speaker 1: or JNI is the web service as a way for managed code written in Java to interact with native code written in C plus plus or C or A named pipe?
Speaker 0: or you know, just why do you need the programs like directly call each other?
Speaker 1: Necessary are the two answers I have for you one old people or two vague discussion.
Speaker 0: Is this so that a Java program can call a function in a C library basically?
Speaker 0: or a C program can call a function?
Speaker 0: It is written job.
Speaker 1: So Java code running inside of a JVM can call and be called by native applications written like both ways.
Speaker 0: Yes You should just use something to go between like a database or a message queue or anything.
Speaker 1: So actually there's a. there's a decent performance case for doing it this way Involving the libraries that already exist to do network capture are pretty much all written in C C++.
Speaker 0: Alright, well then you shouldn't be writing in Java.
Speaker 0: You should be writing the parts that don't need to be C for performance reasons and ease of writing reasons in Python Which can natively directly call C. Yeah, well and don't need to have this weird JVM and J and I getting in the way I'm tired of and don't like Java.
Speaker 1: I'll put it that way.
Speaker 1: You
Speaker 0: don't say yeah
Speaker 1: increasingly tired of Java, but the main point of me making this my news is one that is an example of actual tech news and - if you want to go into computer science, like you're in high school like a lot of our listeners computer science You'll learn what that is,
Speaker 0: even though technically that isn't even really.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's programming.
Speaker 0: but computer science is actually like language parsing And all kinds of other.
Speaker 1: like if you have a computer science degree You'll understand the story much more readily than a lot of people I know who would have software engineering or IT or other computer.
Speaker 1: yet degrees, okay.
Speaker 1: So anyway, you got any news?
Speaker 1: I Forgot don't you?
Speaker 1: you forgot what your news was?
Speaker 1: You didn't link it to me yet either.
Speaker 1: No, there's the last thing you sent me.
Speaker 1: is that hipster dice thing.
Speaker 0: There's so much tech news going down right now that it's hard to even keep it all under control.
Speaker 0: You didn't know G+?
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah, that's that's your tech news.
Speaker 0: There's that's right the Google thing.
Speaker 1: There was so much Google and any rabbit from the book club book Any rabbit any is the main one?
Speaker 0: All right one more big wig is the second.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway might as well just take the easy path.
Speaker 0: why should I go for the hard ones?
Speaker 0: yeah Silver there you go.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: There's a hard one.
Speaker 0: All right, so Google had mad announcements their Google iOS and whatnot.
Speaker 0: They announced some Android M, which I don't I didn't even read about it yet I just saw headlines.
Speaker 0: I don't even know what it is.
Speaker 1: There's good stuff in there But I can't talk about it cuz I don't even know I'm gonna do a dedicated news about it But I didn't want to do it today because that is newer than the stuff that I wanted to bring up today.
Speaker 0: What I did find what I do know about is Google Photos, right.
Speaker 0: so Google Photos Solves a few photo related problems, right?
Speaker 0: The problem a lot of people have is taking a lot of freaking photos these days with your phone cameras.
Speaker 0: Yep, and You know, we've had for a while say, you know Even the Google+ app would automatically look in your phone's photo library.
Speaker 0: Take all those photos and put them up on Google+.
Speaker 1: You know where they would be safe, but then it was like hard to make a library to share them.
Speaker 1: There were limits.
Speaker 0: There's all kinds of weird stuff right every phone were like auto upload stuff.
Speaker 0: So now the new Google Photos Smartly organizes for these photos based on things.
Speaker 0: so it's like oh I see that you went on a trip To you know based on the IP the geolocation and all these photos are taken in this other place where you don't live.
Speaker 0: But during this week, let's group those all together in trip to place.
Speaker 1: I've been doing that for a while.
Speaker 0: I love that Yep, so it's doing that for you, but mostly the thing is they're giving everyone free Unlimited photo storage with photos up to a certain size, you know in megapixels or megabits or whatever.
Speaker 0: So as long as the photos your phone takes are lower resolution and lower file size and JPEG Then this limit it will automatically.
Speaker 0: now, you know in the new Google Photos app Which is separate from G+ G+ is slowly being phased out.
Speaker 0: Store those for you forever used that to pay.
Speaker 0: if you hit a certain storage limit You still can pay in which case they'll let you have images of any size You know full resolution whatever and store as many as your pay to store.
Speaker 0: the thing is is People are acting like oh Google you have saved us, you know on our photo storage woes liquor has been.
Speaker 0: Well, okay.
Speaker 0: So first of all flicker for as long as I've been using it Which is since college is like 25 bucks a year and it still is for unlimited ever for unlimited everything full resolution everything.
Speaker 0: so Flicker is already the king.
Speaker 1: but flicker was way behind for a while on like an app on your phone that works.
Speaker 1: Integration with other systems.
Speaker 0: Yeah now they've got that under control pretty do.
Speaker 0: now It's pretty much that and Google Photos pretty much the same.
Speaker 0: in this regard.
Speaker 0: Amazon also is Amazon Photos.
Speaker 0: Guess what that does.
Speaker 0: also the same goddamn thing for a small annual fee.
Speaker 0: Yeah, unlimited storage full resolution and whatever.
Speaker 0: I think what's interesting is also Apple has iCloud which I think is a little bit more expensive But also does the same exact.
Speaker 1: so I pulled a bunch of people who aren't like as tuned into this as we are Just kind of at working around and the general sentiment is Everyone likes like.
Speaker 1: they know what flicker is, but they're quote.
Speaker 1: I'm not a photographers.
Speaker 1: I don't use it.
Speaker 1: They love g+ because suddenly it just works because they take pictures and it's all already set up.
Speaker 1: and the people who use iPhones hate iPhoto Absolutely hate iPhoto.
Speaker 0: iPhoto is no good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you if you're just using the built-in camera app, right the iCloud photo store thing, you know I don't use iPhoto.
Speaker 0: but for example, you know, you couldn't.
Speaker 0: Apple the you know, the annoying Apple software updater That's always on your Windows computer trying to get upgrade iTunes all the time.
Speaker 0: It always wants you to install this iCloud garbage and I just say do it to make it shut up and it doesn't bother Me, but I actually use one function of it Which is take a photo on your iPhone and it's automatically an iCloud just automatically no matter what?
Speaker 0: Then you can go to the Windows computer and there's a folder that is iCloud photos.
Speaker 0: You click on it and there's all the photos that are on your phone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't need to like do a transfer or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Just there they are.
Speaker 0: I was gonna use, you know flicker Google+ or Amazon.
Speaker 0: I would have to go to flickers website or go to the Google+ which isn't that much harder But then I have to download the photo onto the computer Which I guess is still happening when you go to the iCloud photo, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, it's just it's right there in the Windows Explorer.
Speaker 0: I can drag it right from there into this Photoshop as it saves me a whole step.
Speaker 1: I mean if I just say anything about this g+ thing, it's a victory.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not g+ anymore That's the news of it.
Speaker 0: All right, right.
Speaker 0: In fact, you know how when you search on Google if you search for a person often You'll see like their Google+ profiles like above the results.
Speaker 0: They were starting to remove that.
Speaker 0: It's getting phased out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Google+ is disappearing even though I've started using it more and more lately.
Speaker 0: Oh, there are you know, it's weird because it's sort of in the RPG communities.
Speaker 0: Oh, there are a lot of communities that are on there and using Google+.
Speaker 0: So if they really just hose it.
Speaker 0: it's not like when they host Google Wave and not a tier with shed.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, but we'll see this.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about this separately because Photography workflows if you have multiple devices that take photos like there it's a complicated mess of what's backed up where and when and all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: and like what's your record?
Speaker 1: like How do you share the photos?
Speaker 1: And I feel like for all the casual photos that I take basically everything I take on my phone G+ like.
Speaker 1: well, I keep saying G+ the new Google Photos thing has a Pretty compelling UX compared to all the other ways.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just use a whole bunch of them all at once.
Speaker 1: Yep, guys, there's something with that was when it wasn't unlimited.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know your Google Drive space.
Speaker 0: any one of them dies or has a problem or whatever.
Speaker 0: It's like I don't care I mostly.
Speaker 0: just you know, I don't use flicker and I use Lightroom.
Speaker 0: I don't use any of the other things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just you know, like the Amazon is just like.
Speaker 0: I just let it be Yep, and if I ever need it is there.
Speaker 1: but here's the difference.
Speaker 1: letting Google just be before was filling up your Google Drive That's true.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 1: It's not literally just let it be.
Speaker 1: So the great thing is now independent of the workflow.
Speaker 1: Have you got an Android phone?
Speaker 0: I mean, this is way bigger news for you.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, if I have an Android phone now, it's great because every photo I take over like is immediately uploaded as fast as possible to both flicker and Google.
Speaker 0: this is mostly big news for the people.
Speaker 0: the Android phone Smash my phone.
Speaker 1: There are two copies of that photo on two different services.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's that's what's important.
Speaker 1: It's very important things of the day.
Speaker 1: I was a big fan of Seinfeld as was Scott when we were younger.
Speaker 1: Doesn't hold up that?
Speaker 0: well The laugh track really is the thing that makes it not hold up.
Speaker 1: laugh track is like a punch.
Speaker 0: I think if they got rid of the laugh track It would probably have some sort of weird emptiness to it.
Speaker 0: That would also be problematic, you know in like the all the pauses for the laugh track, but Other than that it would.
Speaker 0: it's actually good if it not for the laughter.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So what happened like when I show people like Emily who have never really seen Seinfeld what instead of like saying?
Speaker 1: Oh, let's watch a random episode.
Speaker 1: I've kind of decided to curate it cuz they're like 10 or 15 memorable episodes.
Speaker 0: Yeah There are episodes like the high concept episodes like the parking garage Chinese restaurant rager.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like though the holes the holes Yeah, the You know, yeah, there's about right there.
Speaker 1: It's basically like that whole.
Speaker 0: Yeah So but there's a lot of episodes that are just like.
Speaker 0: alright, it's another Seinfeld episode.
Speaker 1: So I saw this.
Speaker 1: or also it's just like.
Speaker 1: it's interesting because the show is really funny to me as a kid Having never lived in or even been to New York.
Speaker 1: now that I live in New York The show has a whole nother level of wow.
Speaker 1: That's actually way too real.
Speaker 0: It was actually very surprising when the show was new.
Speaker 0: how like Globally universally popular it was when it was so New York It is like.
Speaker 0: so that would be like if people who didn't play video games are laughing at penny arcades.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course nowadays penny arcade actually probably is funny to a lot of people that don't play a lot of it.
Speaker 0: I mean some of it but you still get it's crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: so this is a little mini article Someone put together about the fourth wall in the set meaning that in the whole run of the show Jerry had an apartment and then They changed it once a little bit like they got rid of that bike and stuff hanging in the background.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like they moved that background bedroom area because they used to show a bathroom.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm or and then What?
Speaker 1: basically someone showed that there's a wall that you never saw in the yeah to the right of the kitchen.
Speaker 0: Yep, because no they never looked to the right of the kitchen.
Speaker 0: the camera only goes to the people in the kitchen.
Speaker 0: It never goes to the area In front of the kitchen.
Speaker 0: or I mean you sort of always feel in the show Like there's not a lot of room there and it goes pretty much to the windows of the facing out or the wall or whatever is over there.
Speaker 1: someone found a picture of The wall and what's on the wall that you never got to see.
Speaker 1: and then they also put together a series of clips following a Kramer that Actually show literally the full extent of the apartment that you ever see.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and it's just a neat little article.
Speaker 1: It's one of those think about this kind of information that is lost to the ages because there's literally who would think to Like save like what was the full design of the set?
Speaker 1: we live in an era where this sort of thing will stop happening.
Speaker 1: Because like I suspect that within 20 or 30 years Every set to every TV show ever that has a set is gonna be 3d scan for posterity and put in a museum, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like we don't know.
Speaker 0: say on the set of Ed Sullivan show, right?
Speaker 1: It's like what was behind the desk.
Speaker 0: Is there a spot that we couldn't see?
Speaker 0: this is does anyone remember what was there?
Speaker 0: Is that right?
Speaker 1: Is there any photo of Dick Van Dyke show?
Speaker 0: Does everyone know like everyone who worked on mean the credits?
Speaker 0: It's like what was lost.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot of these old things episodes have been lost.
Speaker 1: Imagine if like.
Speaker 1: imagine if you had a shot from every talking show ever like.
Speaker 1: So like every show where a guy sat by a desk and talked at you What it looked like to him like from his perspective.
Speaker 0: just like a lot of old live television things are just lost forever, right?
Speaker 0: You know, I think the first Super Bowl there's no film or there's only one shit Cameras they use went direct to a broadcast machine.
Speaker 0: They weren't recording they weren't gonna put actual film in there and you know just to record this thing unless it was a major important thing because it cost a lot of money and it was pain in the ass to develop and Recording technology from like digital.
Speaker 1: digital like modern cameras came after broadcasting technology, right about that.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot.
Speaker 0: TV shows just live stand in front of the TV, you know front of the camera do the show and That's it.
Speaker 1: And as a bonus, I just noticed at the end Also has an interview with the Seinfeld production designer Specifically on the parking garage episode.
Speaker 1: Okay, so there's just a lot of good stuff going on here.
Speaker 0: so One of the bestest game developers out there Zach Tronics.
Speaker 0: He is the maker of many.
Speaker 0: well they I guess is more than one person now, but it's mostly Zach.
Speaker 0: At least he's the name behind it, right?
Speaker 0: it's his deal, you know makers of such games as space cam and infinifactory and You know the programming games.
Speaker 0: You got a new game.
Speaker 0: It's early access on Steam.
Speaker 0: You can get it right now.
Speaker 0: I'm probably gonna get it when I get home.
Speaker 1: I'm not.
Speaker 0: it is Ti s 100 teslaated intelligent system.
Speaker 0: What do you do in this game?
Speaker 0: you program in assembly language this fictional computer and At the same time that you are learning to program assembly language or using your existing assembly language programming skills.
Speaker 0: You are discovering the secrets of this computer much like uplink So sort of like space cam plus uplink plus.
Speaker 0: just you're just straight-up programming assembly.
Speaker 1: Not like a metaphor for programming like space cam with chemical, you know, right you get the impression There's kind of there's gonna be like a cool Probably sinister plot as you figure out what this computer was doing or what was supposed to be doing.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there is.
Speaker 1: would you even be fixing it?
Speaker 0: I haven't programmed assembly things in any assembly language since college and when I did Somehow I got an a even though I didn't consciously fully understand everything.
Speaker 0: I Sort of had this natural like inborn talent.
Speaker 0: like there's an evil spirit inside of me That is really good at programming in assembly language, but it is not in my brain.
Speaker 0: It is somewhere else perhaps in my hands.
Speaker 0: print and explore like I made a deal with the devil to play banjo Even though I couldn't tell you how to play banjo.
Speaker 1: Ooh, the game comes with a manual.
Speaker 1: That's one of those old-style reference manuals to a computer.
Speaker 0: You need that for programming any assembly language because it's different from chip to chip.
Speaker 1: the first computer I bought my 486 SX - mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It came with like five multi-hundred page books Describing everything down to the voltages on pins and things that came out of the back.
Speaker 0: mine had that as well.
Speaker 0: I also bought a copy of Borland turbo c++ Something for Windows because it was 90 bucks instead of like.
Speaker 0: the full one was hundreds of dollars.
Speaker 0: It came out like 11 floppies that I think I still have and that came with giant books.
Speaker 0: I think I still have them like like a full definition of all the like the.
Speaker 0: I don't think it was a C language Definition.
Speaker 0: you had to buy the C book for that.
Speaker 0: But it had all the like the documentation because it was been a lot of data to download this kind of documentation And you only had so many megabytes in your hard drive and only so many floppy disks, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the internet didn't necessarily exist in those days.
Speaker 0: I don't think there was a network library in there.
Speaker 0: All it was mostly documentation on the windows the owl the object windows library Which is how you made windows pop up and control their X buttons and all those sorts of menus and that sort of stuff.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment the next convention we're gonna be at is kinetic on we will be doing a bunch of panels edit along With you know running the whole panels department.
Speaker 1: as we always say it is a great convention.
Speaker 1: if you live within a day's drive Hartford Connecticut, it is well worth your time and money to go to kinetic on.
Speaker 1: If you have to fly to it, I would not necessarily recommend it unless you have money and time to burn in other news.
Speaker 0: Saturday, June 6 of five days from now is the netrunner regional championship in Cambridge, Massachusetts.
Speaker 0: Are you yelling?
Speaker 0: I'm going to the beach.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: However, I have obligated somehow to go to the Philadelphia netrunner regionals somehow somehow on the 20th and we're gonna live stream from there and maybe I can convince rim to come and help me live stream from there 20th.
Speaker 0: that might actually work out cuz I could use some help with the technologies.
Speaker 1: Well, then I can bring my camera to still have to super high.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna bring the live wedge.
Speaker 0: We're gonna put in a whole thing there.
Speaker 0: So because this is also the regional championship in Philadelphia where the world champion happens to be from.
Speaker 0: so it's a big deal.
Speaker 0: People are gonna be interested.
Speaker 1: We we could make some magic happen.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 1: Yeah together.
Speaker 1: Anyway, well the cool things coming in watch our videos on YouTube and share them.
Speaker 1: the more they get watched The more likely it is we do shit.
Speaker 1: We are seriously considering going to PAX Australia for a third year in a row due to popular and money.
Speaker 1: if you want us to go either watch out for an upcoming patreon or Email us and ask us how to send you those money.
Speaker 0: Just give me money or ask packs like and you might be like way.
Speaker 0: I have a lot less money than you.
Speaker 0: Why would I send you money?
Speaker 0: and that is possibly true.
Speaker 0: That is true Especially if you're just like some pump kid.
Speaker 0: You definitely do not have as much money as someone who lives in New York City and has money.
Speaker 0: So it might seem like a jerk to ask you for money.
Speaker 1: But if a thousand punk kids give us five bucks we can come to PAX Australia.
Speaker 0: I really have money.
Speaker 0: I don't have enough money.
Speaker 0: You know, I'm not 1%.
Speaker 0: I cannot afford to go to Australia year after year Especially since I've already been there once.
Speaker 0: I sort of feel like if I have enough money to go on a vacation I should go somewhere else that I haven't already been.
Speaker 0: So if I'm gonna go to Australia again, I will need monies from another source.
Speaker 0: So it's really about you wanting me to go to Australia and not about me wanting to go there.
Speaker 1: Yeah me going to Australia the two times that I've gone cost more than a year's rent in places I've lived right.
Speaker 0: so don't think of it as I want to go to Australia On a trip and I'm getting you to pay for it because that is not true.
Speaker 0: I don't actually want to go there again that badly.
Speaker 0: I mean, I wouldn't mind going.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna lie But it's you want me to go there badly enough that you will pay money for it.
Speaker 1: The rewards we're looking at for like the tiers and stuff for like people who actually make this happen are Like one will obviously do meetups like in the places we go in Australia.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean Someone else is paying for me to go somewhere.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be at their whim and not my own whim except fuck you.
Speaker 0: I'm going to the coral reef, but I'll do that on my own dime.
Speaker 1: we'll probably do a video interview show where Churba was one of our Favorite and most famous and friendly and just generally debonair listener.
Speaker 1: friend fans will interview us and There will be no bounds to what he asks us about.
Speaker 1: so that could be interesting.
Speaker 1: great video that in Australia.
Speaker 1: Sure, we'll do two panels at that point.
Speaker 0: I agree to this.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that could be that would be cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they told us that if we can get to the packs in Australia that they'll give us two panels.
Speaker 0: So we don't have to worry about not being approved or anything, but we need.
Speaker 0: What do you want us to talk about for those panels?
Speaker 0: We don't do the same panels you always do over again.
Speaker 1: Well, we're gonna do the same two panels that we submitted to pecs prime.
Speaker 0: Are those new?
Speaker 1: Yes Oh good, the one about the rules thing and the one about the moving your body thing.
Speaker 1: All right those two those two.
Speaker 0: we'll see if those happen.
Speaker 1: yeah, so uh other thing.
Speaker 1: one last announcement.
Speaker 1: We are back on iTunes.
Speaker 0: So yeah with shitty album art.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll say it's better than the old album art.
Speaker 1: Sure, if you have an iTunes account Goes even though you don't use iTunes anymore.
Speaker 1: cuz iTunes is terrible.
Speaker 1: Just go subscribe or at least review us because there are.
Speaker 1: the top reviews are from like 2006 it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: I mean only do it if you want to shamelessly promote us.
Speaker 0: But I'm doing it way worse.
Speaker 1: media than us shamelessly self promotes through its fans way more than us.
Speaker 0: And it's all because I have Pride, I'm not gonna do low-class shit like that.
Speaker 0: But if other people do low-class shit like that on our behalf We don't feel bad, but it's low-class to even ask them to do low-class shit, which is why I'm not asking rim is asking Class.
Speaker 1: there's a nice layer of segregation there.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: No, it's uh, it's quite lowbrow.
Speaker 0: It is very oh Yeah, and the book club book is Scott's pick Robert Jordan's first book of Wheel of Time.
Speaker 1: Listener already messaged us saying please don't make it the book.
Speaker 0: But a lot of other people said actually I love these books.
Speaker 1: I have to go see if anyone who said Wheel of Time is good also said ready player one is good Cuz ready player one.
Speaker 0: Well, I can tell you our bitch.
Speaker 0: I have read in garbage.
Speaker 0: I ever.
Speaker 0: I agree I have read a few chapters now of This Wheel of Time and so far it is Fantasy novel.
Speaker 1: but is it on the level of an RA?
Speaker 0: Salvatore or no, it's way better than that.
Speaker 1: It's no prince of nothing now.
Speaker 0: I'm assuming Not yet.
Speaker 0: All right, nothing nothing in I mean prince of nothing in the first chapter is already prince of nothing, right?
Speaker 0: The first chapter so far, I'll tell you what.
Speaker 0: so basically it this is sort of a similar typical structure.
Speaker 0: Right first thing in the book maps good sign, right?
Speaker 0: Actually.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's kind of a good site.
Speaker 0: Then there's a prologue about like oh the of the great characters right like the great king and the big shield door Right, and then it goes to the village with the normal characters.
Speaker 0: and then whoo some powerful characters Superfantasy show up and of course, it's the dark times are coming.
Speaker 0: Whoo, and that's so far all I've read.
Speaker 0: So generic fantasy story.
Speaker 0: this you know village normal village folk are getting it involved in the big plot Because there's dark times all over the world not just in their village and they've only found out now because only now Have people from the other parts of the world come to visit them.
Speaker 0: They thought it was just dark times in their area.
Speaker 0: It turns out dark times everywhere.
Speaker 0: evil who got to fight it.
Speaker 1: I guess what worries me is that there are three distinct classes and equal parts of people who have told who have said things about this book after we picked it the first third of People saying I love the book.
Speaker 1: the second third of people saying that book is garbage.
Speaker 0: and the third third are people Putting a lot of effort into defending the book that people put a lot ever to defending anything when we assaulted which we did Without knowing even reading one page.
Speaker 1: I mean I randomly I was chat I was like pruning my shit in YouTube and there are some butthurt comments on that really brief video We put up about the Kingkiller Chronicle of people saying guys, it's way better than you're making it out to me.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: Yeah Sorry, I mean, sorry Rothfuss.
Speaker 1: So I guess we should do the actual show, right?
Speaker 0: So it's an issue going down with SourceForge people don't know.
Speaker 0: before there was github There was days of Isildur.
Speaker 0: Well, what was the other site that died?
Speaker 0: and we did a news when it died.
Speaker 1: Oh God fresh meat.
Speaker 1: yes Wow that I just had a flashback to an earlier era, right?
Speaker 0: Well, and there was download comm in the way olden days I mean, I guess I technically still exist.
Speaker 1: download comm exists today in the same way cows two cows in the same way That the that Russia is a successor to the Soviet Union in the successor to the czar.
Speaker 0: in the days before steam There were all these gaming file sites to go a game spot.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but there's SourceForge and SourceForge is basically.
Speaker 0: I have an open source project.
Speaker 0: We are going to use CVS because that was what was there back then.
Speaker 1: we're too old to use github.
Speaker 0: eventually SVN came around but there was CVS and then SVN and I want to work at his open source project with people somewhere else on earth and we need to have a publicly hosted Code repository so that anyone who wants to you can check out the code and submit commits and also so that when we build binaries or zips or Redistributable files for this project.
Speaker 0: They are also hosted and downloadable.
Speaker 0: So there's a site called SourceForge That offered that service.
Speaker 0: It was one of the cores of the like the open source developer can write I mean Linux for hosted their stuff and they still do it.
Speaker 0: kernel that org whatever.
Speaker 0: but you know Slashdot eventually bought the SourceForge company.
Speaker 0: They're part of the same company both owned
Speaker 1: by like dice or someone whatever
Speaker 0: company it is these days I don't know but it was the place you would go for if there was like an open source project usually found a Windows computer because if you're On Linux computer just apt-get or yum, or whatever it was.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or you know, whatever I don't know.
Speaker 0: emerge.
Speaker 1: The gimp is the example using now if you
Speaker 0: had a man on arch, right if
Speaker 1: you needed a program like the gimp Yeah
Speaker 0: on Ubuntu you go apt-get install gimp but on Windows you have to download gimp set up that exe and What you would get that from would probably be SourceForge.
Speaker 1: because in the old days if someone asked me like, you know Ten years ago if someone said hey rim, where do I download name of open source thing?
Speaker 1: I'd say just go to SourceForge don't trust it from anywhere else, right?
Speaker 0: Because that's like.
Speaker 0: that's the source, right?
Speaker 0: That's the.
Speaker 0: you know The hosting there is associated with the source code that it was made from.
Speaker 0: So, you know, that's a good place to download the file because that's directly from the people who made it.
Speaker 0: It's not like some third party took that perhaps Modified it and then delivered it to you on some other shady file website like download.
Speaker 0: calm We're just like oh good download calm search or something you find it.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's not the original program which may have already been able to begin with.
Speaker 0: It's a modified setup exe that really just has some evil thing and then unbundles the original setup that exe afterwards.
Speaker 0: Screw that now.
Speaker 1: This was not as big of a problem back then as it is now like There weren't as many just like this is malware exe is masquerading as legit software like it happened But not as often as you would think compared to today, right?
Speaker 1: So fast forward to the future and if you go to one of those like C neti download e.com type websites You're already fine.
Speaker 1: It's all just malware and garbage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but most people still think of SourceForge is oh, yeah Go to SourceForge turns out that is not the case and that is the scandal that is coming out.
Speaker 0: Cuz github has destroyed SourceForge.
Speaker 0: Basically, the thing is github doesn't do as good a job at offering the be already compiled distributable files, but they sort of do.
Speaker 0: But you know in terms of host your source code in a place so that everyone can work on it together GitHub destroys everyone else is blow them out of the water.
Speaker 0: So SourceForge is really seen a lot of people leaving and they're not making money anymore.
Speaker 0: So they've resorted to Evilness to sort of keep their shit going.
Speaker 1: so what they did is they basically took the gimp the windows binary.
Speaker 1: windows binary made a mirror and Compromised it with adware bullshit.
Speaker 0: So if you download the windows gimp right from SourceForge the place that it was used to be officially hosted It was sort of you're gonna get a modified setup that has evil malwares on.
Speaker 1: here's their SourceForge is statement on this quote.
Speaker 1: in cases where a project is no longer actively being maintained, but it's being maintained It's the gimp.
Speaker 1: SourceForge has in some cases Established a mirror of releases that are hosted elsewhere.
Speaker 1: This was done for gimp win In quote.
Speaker 1: now I point out Yeah, it was a mirror an ad enabled installer.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So don't go to SourceForge anymore and you can read this story to learn about all the details.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the gimp team was like.
Speaker 1: no that's bullshit.
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: You know, it all sucks.
Speaker 0: just yesterday I had to go and get a program that I wanted and SourceForge wasn't just.
Speaker 0: It was the only place to get it and it's a very good program and luckily I checked and that installer was not modified.
Speaker 0: Now I have the installer.
Speaker 0: I never need to go to search for it again.
Speaker 1: Yep, so That the problem is the succinct topic for the remainder of this show.
Speaker 1: Now in 2015 How do you determine like where the actual version of software is?
Speaker 1: and you'd think oh just go to the maintainers website like the actual?
Speaker 1: Website.
Speaker 1: a lot of projects don't have a maintainer's website.
Speaker 0: So this is a long time Existing problem that you know, mostly Linux and open source people have had to deal with right.
Speaker 0: because when it comes to something like You know a big company like Adobe or Microsoft or whatever, you know There's like this official place to get the programs from you know, you need to download software install it on your computer.
Speaker 0: How do you know that?
Speaker 0: what you think you're downloading is what you're downloading creative cloud exe from?
Speaker 1: Adobe creative cloud TV, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you install steam from valve comm.
Speaker 0: you're gonna be 99% sure.
Speaker 0: That's just steam right.
Speaker 0: and then you inside of steam click say install that game.
Speaker 0: You're pretty sure that's totally legit.
Speaker 0: because still on your iPhone you go to the App Store You click install on an app.
Speaker 0: It's coming from the official Apple App Store.
Speaker 0: They're sort of taking care of you, right?
Speaker 0: you know that it's not the same time.
Speaker 1: that is problematic as we've talked about many times because the App Store model of Controlled vetted walled garden is a controlled vetted walled garden.
Speaker 0: obviously it has problems but it doesn't have.
Speaker 0: the problem of What you think you're downloading is not actually what you're downloading.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: This gets extra complicated and the best example of what I'm about to describe you in the world is putty right.
Speaker 1: putty is the SSH SCP clients for windows Period if you want to SSH into something putty is it?
Speaker 0: I mean there are many forks of putty like kitty and others and there's also similar putty clone.
Speaker 0: ish programs like Mobex term is out there, but that cost money sort of and you know.
Speaker 1: So if you want to download putty and you go to most places that have the putty exe you're fucked.
Speaker 1: That is malware.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: In fact, there's a specific malware that's targeting the financial sector right now putty.
Speaker 1: I've been warning people about.
Speaker 1: yeah but the only way to know if you go to the legitimate site the Actual maintainer and creators website and you're not an ultra nerd who just knows you would not trust this site for shit It's just all text.
Speaker 1: the URL to download putty is www.chi arc dot green and are you sure that's right?
Speaker 1: dot UK?
Speaker 0: How can that possibly be right tilde SG test?
Speaker 0: I thought it was like putty dot org or something that no putty dot org also redirects here as it.
Speaker 1: Yes, if you go to putty dot org I'm doing it right now in front of Scott.
Speaker 1: because so download putty.
Speaker 1: you can download putty here Chi arc green and dark or okay.
Speaker 0: All right now does this slash tilde username putty download?
Speaker 0: So, how do you know?
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: so maybe someone else bought the domain putty org or bought this domain and pointed it at some Other server and it's serving up shady.
Speaker 1: putty dot exe and did some like Google juice to make it show.
Speaker 0: Maybe someone hacked into the putty server and changed some of the stuff files around right so that you go download putty exe.
Speaker 0: You're getting the wrong one.
Speaker 0: How do you know?
Speaker 0: well first of all SSL is supposed to protect you in some fashion because that way this site is not Ssl-secured.
Speaker 0: that's a problem, isn't it?
Speaker 0: because you should need the SSL because that way you know that when you look at your location bar and it says putty org and You see the SSL that means aha This actually is putty org.
Speaker 0: It didn't get redirected some other computer.
Speaker 0: This is the legit putty or not?
Speaker 1: T.org?
Speaker 0: you don't need the encryption part of it You need the signing part of it as in you know There was a digital signature.
Speaker 0: the person who owns that certificate Which was verified and whatever that human being signed it.
Speaker 0: But it is confirmed that this site is the site that you want to go to.
Speaker 0: it's their site.
Speaker 0: even I'm shady.
Speaker 1: you have to trust the certificate authority and any delegations in the entire chain leading down to that certificate.
Speaker 1: and there have been Numerous cases of dodgy Chinese certificates being made with dodgy chains of trust that don't immediately get caught.
Speaker 0: that is true.
Speaker 0: So, how do you know that when you download putty.exe that that is a legit putty.exe?
Speaker 1: Well, there's a checksum on the website MD5.
Speaker 1: So if I download it from this website This website will let me confirm that what I download it is from this website, right?
Speaker 0: So you MD5 some the exe that you downloaded.
Speaker 0: any number comes out.
Speaker 0: you look at the number on the website and they match.
Speaker 1: It's like aha but it's the same.
Speaker 0: that tells you that the person who made the website and wrote that number there is In fact the same person who is Telling you that this exe file is trustworthy.
Speaker 1: So here's a signed letter from myself and you can trust the website is legitimate.
Speaker 0: Then you can also trust that the file is legitimate.
Speaker 1: So we could use the MD 5 in another way.
Speaker 1: So say I already have putty running and Scott needs to download it.
Speaker 1: So we download.
Speaker 0: we assume that rims putty is good.
Speaker 0: It's not evil.
Speaker 0: You can MD 5 some his putty and I can MD 5 some mine and if we get the same number.
Speaker 0: We know we have identical files and we can.
Speaker 0: if I can trust his I can trust mine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course if there are new versions the hash changes I've there are different builds.
Speaker 1: the hash changes even different platforms.
Speaker 1: The hash will likely change.
Speaker 1: The other factor is that a lot of these kinds of projects have a series of tools but if you want say the gooey thing or The windows build or install or whatever they link to you to let a third website Mm-hmm with the windows builds of a lot of old open source things are on even dodgier looking websites.
Speaker 0: well, the fundamental problem here is that these software packages are being distributed as binaries on Linux machines and other open source platforms.
Speaker 0: you can distribute things as source if you want and if you're distributing programs as source You can trust them because you can read the source code and compile it yourself And then you don't want to do that.
Speaker 1: if you have to get install or whatever, you know You're using like RPM yum, whatever pirate then you at least are trusting that the repository Maintainer has gotten legitimate bill, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know, for example, you have Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: You're using Ubuntu so you have to get install something.
Speaker 0: what actually happens there, right?
Speaker 0: This is what actually happens.
Speaker 0: by default in the apt configuration file are URLs of Repositories that you are trusting and by default the only ones in there are the official ones Run by canonical the Ubuntu company and you have secure SSL certificates.
Speaker 0: Right so that when you are connecting to those machines to get your package list and your package updates and your software You're verifying Cryptographically that that computer is the computer that you trusted before.
Speaker 0: it hasn't changed as it moved.
Speaker 0: It's not some other masquerade It's legit the same original.
Speaker 0: The only the people who are modifying what's on that computer are the people you trusted in the first place.
Speaker 1: Yep, so the moral you got to trust someone.
Speaker 0: Yep, and You can if you want to.
Speaker 0: you can do add apt repository add right to add More repositories to get software from somewhere else.
Speaker 0: But you're manually saying add this certificate as a trusted certificate.
Speaker 0: any software that they provide I will trust and then it will do the same verification and in addition to that it gets the MD 5 sums from Those trusted places and even after it downloads files from the trusted places It compares those checksums to the files to make sure that those are the ones that have been trusted.
Speaker 1: So here's a. here's a deeper problem From first principles.
Speaker 1: How do you decide who to trust first?
Speaker 0: So I guess if you're trusting someone with the OS, right?
Speaker 0: It's like well, alright.
Speaker 1: So which Linux?
Speaker 1: who maintains that particular flavor of Linux, right?
Speaker 1: You got to trust Linus and you got to trust the people who make that Linux or you can read the source code.
Speaker 1: Are you gonna do that?
Speaker 1: No, I mean, I guess first principles wise the only the only by a car.
Speaker 0: How do you trust that that cars is not gonna explode?
Speaker 0: but there
Speaker 1: is not a modern history of people selling malware cars Here in town selling a whole bunch of fake cars like Donald Duck that suddenly collapse on
Speaker 0: Exploding cars though, you know
Speaker 1: Actually, I read interestingly that the car you're thinking of was no more likely to explode in that kind of accident or kill its occupants.
Speaker 1: Then other similar cars.
Speaker 0: I was thinking about when the Mafia rigs your car to explode on purpose.
Speaker 1: That's a separate thing.
Speaker 1: That didn't happen as office.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I think the real answer right now because we can come up with some clever idea of like a hat like a repository of Hashes with its own SSL people just that people to agree to trust like techies all know That is like if you want to check if your build is legit, they maintain an archive of legit.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's like, you know, you can go and get your OS X DVD or USB stick from the Apple store Which you can trust.
Speaker 0: yeah, then put it in and only install things from the App Store.
Speaker 0: Right, and then you have this chain of trust like why trusted the Apple Store?
Speaker 0: physically?
Speaker 0: they gave me this stick.
Speaker 0: physically I trust that and I only get apps through the Apple App Store.
Speaker 0: That's official.
Speaker 0: I can trust that - yep Stay in a walled garden.
Speaker 0: You won't accidentally install some app from some website.
Speaker 0: That was my.
Speaker 0: that isn't what you think it is.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm installing VLC.
Speaker 0: ha ha no evil person who modified VLC and tricked you into downloading my modified VLC with evil spyware in it.
Speaker 1: now bear in Mind we're not talking about downloading apps that are bad on purpose.
Speaker 1: We're talking about apps that you think are one app but are actually another app, right?
Speaker 0: And usually this only happens if you go to places that are obviously not official download.com CNET You go to like Pirate Bay because you don't want to pay for Photoshop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're pretty much gave you do that kind of shit.
Speaker 0: You're almost guaranteed to get hosed.
Speaker 1: almost in the modern era You are guaranteed.
Speaker 1: years ago.
Speaker 1: I think as an experiment.
Speaker 1: I set up a Windows VM.
Speaker 1: I went and download a bunch of Adobe software and one by one I tried installing them and then I watched and catalogued the Ridiculous amount of data that started flying out of my computer to IP addresses all over the world.
Speaker 1: It was amazing.
Speaker 0: Yep, so it's like technically speaking on a pure mathematical cryptographic trust basis You can't even really trust putty.org to be it's legit for it's not.
Speaker 1: nor Can you trust reading the source code.
Speaker 1: remember that story we did years ago about people who showed that you could compromise?
Speaker 1: compilers to then compromise software compilation Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So you also have to know the compiler.
Speaker 1: and so basically here's the real answer.
Speaker 1: I came up with it during the show.
Speaker 1: be realistic.
Speaker 0: Just make sure you're at the official websites of things Downloading the most official versions of things.
Speaker 0: don't install shit.
Speaker 0: You don't need only install and it you know, it's not just you know, make sure you get your programs You know from the right place.
Speaker 0: It's don't use shitty program.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like VLC is a pretty trustworthy video player.
Speaker 0: Don't go and get like X Something something player that no one ever fucking heard of that.
Speaker 0: shady as hell.
Speaker 1: That's why your laptop crashes at your panels, right?
Speaker 0: You know use something that's popular.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, you can use Chrome You can use Firefox.
Speaker 0: don't go using like, you know chameleon?
Speaker 0: weirdo, bro I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think chameleon is a browser just like Weirdo browser made by someone else.
Speaker 0: That's no name.
Speaker 1: Also in terms of like Windows builds of open software I think I can list every piece of software you should ever bought.
Speaker 1: download Unless you have a clean really the only things you need most.
Speaker 1: what like gimp?
Speaker 1: if you're doing photos You can you putty paint.net if you want.
Speaker 1: instead putty win SCP brow like a browser.
Speaker 1: OBS.
Speaker 1: Already, I can't take VLC a bit torrent client, but even then most of those are bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't sound look do not download the actual bit torrent client and also do not download micro torrent.
Speaker 1: They're both bad now steam.
Speaker 0: Yep, Spotify.
Speaker 1: It's not open.
Speaker 1: It's just binary.
Speaker 0: a fish, you know Adobe apps But those are paid right anyway, you don't need on a modern computer.
Speaker 0: There's so few things you actually need to install.
Speaker 0: 99% of everything you do is in your web browser.
Speaker 0: Anyway, and then you know you just need to go by SSL for trustworthiness there from a first principles standpoint.
Speaker 1: if you Can't figure out if it's legit or not.
Speaker 1: There's only one way to know Ask someone like us like really ask someone who's an actual tech person who is old enough to know.
Speaker 1: The people who are a lot younger tend to be over trusting and people are a lot older.
Speaker 1: They're running Cygwin on their windows desktop for day-to-day operations.
Speaker 1: So Virtual box you can install find someone between the ages of like 19 and 40 ish and ask them Where to get the name of the software because they'll either tell you she arc dot green and dot org dot UK.
Speaker 0: Don't use that software at all.
Speaker 1: use this other software and you're gonna get a chromogeny tirade like you just got.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're downloading something dumb, but you won't download malware.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.