Speaker 1: It's Tuesday November 24th 2015.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 1: Matchmaking in video games not in other places.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So dangerous things have been happening.
Speaker 0: Dangerous as I've said a couple times and the most dangerous.
Speaker 1: I joined that GMR the giant multiplayer robot long-form game of Civ 5 and then basically I first formed another one of those games For all of us, so it's like our crew like eight FRC people playing Civ 5 And I play Civ 5 a lot when I travel which against the AI like it's not the same as against humans.
Speaker 1: But also most of our friends have not played Civ 5 a lot Recently or have never played with all the expansions that made the game good.
Speaker 1: So the problem is as a result all of us Started playing Civ 5 single-player a little bit to like.
Speaker 1: remember how to play so we don't fuck up in the game.
Speaker 1: It's like I'll play a bunch of turns.
Speaker 0: Yeah I can play like ten turns of a single-player game over and over and over again and get really good at those first ten turns.
Speaker 0: And I only played like what.
Speaker 0: six turns so far seven not too many turns so far in the other game exactly But like every it's weird playing against humans like.
Speaker 1: I care a lot more about how well it goes down Like I really like if Scott gets to a hut before me fuck that I got like.
Speaker 1: I can't lie.
Speaker 0: I've got a lot of huts.
Speaker 1: I only got two.
Speaker 0: computer doesn't fuck me.
Speaker 0: I'm about to get one more hut.
Speaker 1: watch out though that computers get well.
Speaker 1: like I said AI gets bonuses, but AI is stupid mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: the danger is Multiple times in the last few weeks, and I'm sure I'm not the only one this happened to I thought well It's ten o'clock.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go to bed soon.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna start a game of sieve and play like the first 20 turns And then I'll quit.
Speaker 0: you mean the first 20,000 turns you mean well I won.
Speaker 0: It's turn 200 cliche of one more turn is because of civilization.
Speaker 0: That's the game.
Speaker 0: there wasn't some other game with the one more turn.
Speaker 0: it was civilization.
Speaker 0: That's the one I think.
Speaker 1: what got me those the last?
Speaker 1: so two nights ago I'm literally just like but but but.
Speaker 1: and then I said to myself out loud all right just one more turn.
Speaker 1: And then I realized what I was saying, and I just quit the game without saving.
Speaker 0: that's immediately.
Speaker 1: I was like quit no more.
Speaker 0: That's right good move.
Speaker 1: the problem is if I runs on my laptop So it's actually it's nice iPad here.
Speaker 1: what I might do is I can bring.
Speaker 1: the thing is unless other people also take their turns quicker I could take the laptop to work and if my turn comes up I could just play the one.
Speaker 0: all I want is for me to take a turn when I wake up in the morning with some Orangey and some breakfast a little bagel, and I want when I get home from work Or it's before I go to bed one more turn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's all I'm asking because that would be you know it's nice No convenient little time you know.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm gonna try to take my turn right after the show.
Speaker 1: I'm not taking it while you're watching.
Speaker 0: cuz why not?
Speaker 0: yeah Really gonna learn that much in turn five six seven I'd rather you.
Speaker 1: if you want to find out what's going on my business You've either got a somehow convinced me to give you open borders or like risk sending a missionary into my biz.
Speaker 0: Why don't we make an embassy?
Speaker 0: uh?
Speaker 1: If I meet you I will maybe grant you an embassy from mutual nominal fee mutual embassy Mutual embassy you know.
Speaker 1: it's interesting because against the AI's There's all these things of that affect your relationship based on mechanics in the game, but against a human it's just humans humaning.
Speaker 1: so Like me spreading my religion to you is not going to make you look favorably upon me.
Speaker 1: nope I'm not gonna go for religion.
Speaker 0: I think though so Religions got too much complicatedness.
Speaker 0: I don't understand well enough.
Speaker 1: This is eight players so only five religions can be founded.
Speaker 1: I didn't know that so you could just let other people's religions come in.
Speaker 0: and what do they do?
Speaker 0: for if they come in on?
Speaker 1: Me they don't hurt you.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So what's the problem?
Speaker 1: But the person who's spreading them get like you get a boon and the person spreading it gets like a double boom.
Speaker 0: That's all right.
Speaker 0: I'll send my great musician to play non religious music all over their country.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you come for the culture victory who knows, but if I get a great musician And I don't have a spot for great music in my Cathedral or some shit guess where he going.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it puts a lot of tourism if you get.
Speaker 1: because the thing is if you get tourism Early game and you've there's some other players that don't have a lot of culture output.
Speaker 0: What's the earliest terrorism you can get?
Speaker 0: There's someone not easy to get it.
Speaker 1: There are some wonders.
Speaker 1: they give it to you like right the fuck away, which one I don't remember off.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen any.
Speaker 1: I never go for that.
Speaker 1: Also, the musicians will give a one-time cult like tourism bonus like against one player like right away.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I've been playing a lot of sit five and I gotta play a lot less at five while I'm playing sit five.
Speaker 0: So you got any news?
Speaker 0: I do have some news.
Speaker 0: So I'm having a lack of you know.
Speaker 0: It's a little bit of video game season right now staying inside in the cold.
Speaker 0: But I'm having trouble finding a multiplayer video game that you know, we'll talk about this in the main bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but a multiplayer video game I can play online that is fit in the bills Of the things that I need.
Speaker 0: so what's your bill?
Speaker 0: Cuz counter-strike like there's so we'll talk about that later.
Speaker 0: But a game that I used to play a lot multiplayer online and s2.
Speaker 1: Ooh, I stopped playing that a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I'm playing a long time ago also, but NS to natural selection - if you didn't know They basically stopped updating it and let the community update it and they the unknown worlds the company that makes it left Said all right you community volunteers can work on NS - we're gonna work on this alien ocean game called subnautica.
Speaker 0: That's still being developed and I'm excited for subnautica, but it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not out yet, and I'm not really interested in the early beta play.
Speaker 0: I'm just waiting for it to be done.
Speaker 0: done.
Speaker 0: They decided hey, you know what we're gonna.
Speaker 0: Do is we're going to take some of those community and as two people and We're gonna hire them for as real employees now.
Speaker 1: That is how counter-strike went from good to great.
Speaker 0: That's right, and we're gonna say you know what?
Speaker 0: We are going to give you three months and see if you can You know revive this game.
Speaker 0: Can you build the player base?
Speaker 0: Can you improve the game now?
Speaker 1: That's real interesting because I have this like I loved natural selection like I played the fuck out of that game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you know.
Speaker 0: It's like this game is still some mildly active You know.
Speaker 0: but can you community people if we hire you and that's all you work on can you revitalize this game?
Speaker 0: And if you do you know?
Speaker 0: maybe sales of you know new people coming in or right?
Speaker 0: yeah, so the new The original team was like 24 people.
Speaker 0: the current team is eight people gaga and if they can revive and like at the first patch that they release I'm gonna go reinstall the NS2 and I'm gonna see what's different.
Speaker 0: since I played probably do that probably a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna see if anyone's playing it, and I'm gonna go ruin their game because I'm gonna suck.
Speaker 1: you know The reasons I stopped playing NS2.
Speaker 1: one of them is something we'll talk about in this in the real part of the show But the other part is I liked NS1 a lot partly because it was kind of weird.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: I think I liked it for a lot of the reasons that people like the original dota Like it's kind of jank and broken and as one was jank NS2 was there.
Speaker 1: I'm saying it's like the original NS.
Speaker 0: That was both NS's.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: I just maybe on slot when I go home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the original natural selection was really fun, but a lot of things I liked were the kind of weird broken bullshit things that would happen.
Speaker 1: I like the core gameplay Yeah, but I like the core gameplay in the earlier days when the matches lasted a lot longer Even though it wasn't as good of a game in a lot of ways.
Speaker 0: well.
Speaker 0: That's a fundamental problem of gaming.
Speaker 1: yeah But the game like when they polished it with NS2.
Speaker 1: it Felt a lot like when Civ 5 first came out before the expansions because Civ 5 was like the most polished Civilization game you could possibly make and as a result like there was no emergent gameplay And it was really boring Civ 5 was not worth playing until brave new world came out.
Speaker 1: so NS2 like such people in it Polished the game a lot and I remember wanting to like it But in any I ended up over time enjoying it less.
Speaker 1: But I think that's because of it also failed in the part.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about next mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is really interesting though.
Speaker 1: I wish them the best of luck because the concept of NS is so solid.
Speaker 1: I love that game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: well You know they released tribes too recently or all the tribes games for free legally recently.
Speaker 1: all right We're gonna get in on that, but you still can't really play it online.
Speaker 0: Convenient it's like.
Speaker 0: you can install it, but it's crashed for me, and you can't play it online conveniently It's not.
Speaker 0: you know they didn't really put in the full effort of reviving it setting up servers and all that kind.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, you know I gotta look into if there's a way to make that stable.
Speaker 0: Here's the.
Speaker 0: you know here's the setup dot exe and here's a CD key and which you didn't even need to type in.
Speaker 1: and yeah But at least it's a setup exe.
Speaker 1: I can trust.
Speaker 1: instead of yeah set up exe from bit.
Speaker 0: Oh, I mean I have the CD-ROM probably somewhere you could use.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know where the CD-ROM is But anyway, so yeah, but NS2.
Speaker 0: You know is a legit game.
Speaker 0: You can play without those kinds of technical problems, and I'm sure there's someone playing it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel I mean some of eight people are dad dedicated to the community.
Speaker 0: They would get hired.
Speaker 0: there's definitely enough people playing it.
Speaker 1: Well you know things that are hurting the community more so now.
Speaker 1: So as you might have noticed I've streamed twice.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna finish the stream this week possibly after Thanksgiving because I got food to eat, but I've been playing undertale which is sort of a shmup slash bullet hell slash earthbound RPG game all right released by Toby Fox.
Speaker 0: I don't know who that is.
Speaker 0: what else did that person make Mostly known for music.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the game hurt.
Speaker 0: really good music.
Speaker 1: the game has an Amazing soundtrack all right there you go like so amazing.
Speaker 1: you should probably just go listen to the soundtrack even if you never play The game.
Speaker 0: it's on Spotify.
Speaker 1: Uh it's on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's good enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah, YouTube red.
Speaker 0: It's good though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you do red tube.
Speaker 1: Yep listen to it on the red tube.
Speaker 0: It's just YouTube red.
Speaker 1: but the game is Really really fun and a lot of people I know are avoiding playing undertale because they saw the fandom going.
Speaker 0: ape shit Isn't it just like a 4chan homestuck kind of things?
Speaker 0: Stylistically.
Speaker 0: uh you know people say that but no I get I get that feels from looking at it.
Speaker 1: the homestuck has this like Incomprehensible nonsense story and all these like deep inside jokes.
Speaker 0: isn't it a fucked up internet shit kind of thing like you like Not even close, so it's more like Madoka actually.
Speaker 1: Or imagine if earthbound Got.
Speaker 0: earthbound has some of that too.
Speaker 1: Yeah so imagine if earthbound itself got the Madoka treatment and when?
Speaker 1: Kind of what?
Speaker 1: if this was really the kind of game you think it is like let's go Okay, but it's short too.
Speaker 1: It's basically the game is sort of you you're a human and you fall into the underworld and there's all this drama And you kind of go around and it's RPG combat except you can fight Or you can just talk to people like in a visual novel and Spoilers.
Speaker 1: the game pretty much says like in the beginning you meet a great character and she's like.
Speaker 1: maybe you should just talk to people like.
Speaker 1: maybe you shouldn't kill people and You can kill people or not people?
Speaker 1: you can kill her if you want to.
Speaker 1: you can kill your mom like right away And just go nuts and you can kill fucking everybody if you want to can even kill that snowman you meet or not kill them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, does that mean I don't have to do stupid RPG combat?
Speaker 1: Yes, you.
Speaker 1: instead the RPG combat could boil down to in a puzzle combined with a bullet hell.
Speaker 0: But that I still have to do it to talk to people, but even I don't kill anyone.
Speaker 1: You're gonna fight people.
Speaker 0: It's just I don't want to fight people.
Speaker 1: be like attack And you'll be like mercy or you'll be like try to flirt with them or ask them about their head.
Speaker 1: Oh, but then I have to do a puzzle or well No The puzzle is what do you talk to them about or ask them about?
Speaker 1: Like you can figure out if you're smart the ways to get people to back off and then in the fighting part It's pretty much as bullet hell.
Speaker 1: move your little heart around.
Speaker 0: I don't want to do that part.
Speaker 1: Why not do you ever play Gradius?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if I'm gonna play Gradius, I'll just play fucking Gradius or G Darius with the giant fish robots.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's up your alley.
Speaker 1: play the game up until cool, dude Happens with papyrus, and if you don't laugh out loud at that cool, dude and papyrus.
Speaker 0: this sounds internet weird shit like you.
Speaker 1: It's not because when you know internet weird shit, like the Homestuck fandom kind of nonsense is Kind of immersed in the obtuseness of itself.
Speaker 1: Undertale is not obtuse.
Speaker 1: It is direct.
Speaker 1: It is telling you what is going on.
Speaker 1: There's no like deep Mystery, but aesthetically it's all.
Speaker 1: Why would you say it's weird?
Speaker 1: you're basing that solely on the fandom nonsense and not the game itself.
Speaker 1: The game itself is just characters talking to you.
Speaker 0: I saw pictures of the game and it looked like that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: Well, what defines that kind of stuff?
Speaker 0: It's hard to define.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would not say it's that I'll think about it.
Speaker 1: I think I'll just say this a lot of people are avoiding this game because of the fandom.
Speaker 1: Imagine all of you who are doing that right now if you avoided Steven Universe because of the fandom.
Speaker 0: I know I don't judge anything by the fandom.
Speaker 0: I judge the thing by the thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, most people who are avoiding undertale are avoiding it because of the fandom and because they see porn on tumblr.
Speaker 0: I don't care fortune.
Speaker 0: people like a thing.
Speaker 0: They like Monica - it's like yeah, you know, they like Yotsuba.
Speaker 0: That's their mascot, but I love Yotsuba, right?
Speaker 0: I guess I do with the fandom.
Speaker 0: it has to do with you know It looks like a particular aesthetic.
Speaker 0: that is not my tea, but I guess of course no tea is my tea.
Speaker 1: I don't like tea will give you a bunch of nonsense that you basically need to read.
Speaker 1: lore and like.
Speaker 1: do about you like it's not.
Speaker 1: You can't really just figure it out at face value.
Speaker 1: Undertale is not subtle.
Speaker 1: It has subtle elements, but it is not subtle.
Speaker 1: It is telling you everything just like Monica is Telling you everything.
Speaker 1: you watch Monica and it's like Toward the end.
Speaker 1: you can step back and be like, okay that all makes a hundred percent sense.
Speaker 1: Now that I figured out what the deal is you didn't figure out.
Speaker 0: they told you what to do with.
Speaker 1: yeah, but you Figure things out and they tell you things at the end and it all makes sense and you could have figured out pieces along.
Speaker 1: the Undertale is like that stuff happens.
Speaker 1: And if you read the words you can figure out what's going on.
Speaker 1: It's not like homestuck.
Speaker 1: The music also really makes this game great, but I'm gonna continue live-streaming it.
Speaker 1: So if you can if you're not convinced I guess you can just watch my live stream until you figure out if the game is something you want to play or not.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll compete with your live stream and just stream earthbound.
Speaker 0: Ah Yeah, you can't beat that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but earthbound has random encounter fights for me to watch.
Speaker 0: well actually earthbound is the one great game.
Speaker 0: And yeah when you eventually get high enough level, they'll definitely get high enough level right away.
Speaker 0: I know snakes just like oh a snake.
Speaker 0: Oh shit is nest get the fuck out of here.
Speaker 0: Oh, no Look at that baseball bat.
Speaker 0: That's a snake-beaten bat Isn't it no seal club?
Speaker 1: But say neat thing is is that everything you do matters in a little way like at the end of the game like Chrono trigger.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well way more than chrono trigger.
Speaker 1: I'll see.
Speaker 1: Yeah No Jigga, I would not watch a chrono trigger stream.
Speaker 1: I watched the chrono trigger speedrun and that was enough for me.
Speaker 0: Ooh, I should watch that.
Speaker 1: It was good.
Speaker 1: It was real good.
Speaker 0: Three real good.
Speaker 0: How do you deal with the speedy bike part?
Speaker 1: Uh Yeah, they talk a lot about the speedy bike part rail.
Speaker 1: That is not a happy time.
Speaker 1: No The craziest thing about it is how much randomness manipulation they do to make fights end quickly because the character will be standing in the Right spot at the right time.
Speaker 1: because some bullshit they did like walking around before.
Speaker 1: Like it was kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: I wish the game was that fast when I just played it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm playing undertale and my official geek bite having played a significant percentage of the game Is that it is definitely worth playing and it's not even that expensive.
Speaker 0: How much is it?
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: I just bought on Steam like ten bucks.
Speaker 0: Mmm, that's so much.
Speaker 0: I'm paying for fallout for next year.
Speaker 1: Yeah next year I can play this right now.
Speaker 1: I might I might play 15 bucks for fallout if I get all the DLC in the package.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: So now I got weird internet shit for you.
Speaker 1: This is a mashup of The fights and the events of undertale with the old spice guy.
Speaker 1: Alright, it's kind of great.
Speaker 0: Okay, is that it?
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Okay, watch it some dude.
Speaker 0: I think his name is Nick Luciano because that's the name of his YouTube channel But it might not be his name.
Speaker 0: his dad Is an awesome dad in?
Speaker 0: This video his dad performs The victory poses of all of the combatants in Street Fighter 2.
Speaker 0: That's the video.
Speaker 0: Dad must like Street Fighter 2 or be really willing to make a funny video with his son Nick.
Speaker 0: That is so great way to go dad.
Speaker 0: great video.
Speaker 0: Nice doll seam.
Speaker 1: Yeah In the meta moment wheel of time was the book club.
Speaker 1: We're still reading it.
Speaker 1: I'm like mostly done with.
Speaker 1: the fifth books got finished.
Speaker 1: the fourth book Fifth book is when shit starts.
Speaker 0: I'm reading comics lately.
Speaker 0: So I'm just gonna.
Speaker 0: it's not Wednesday.
Speaker 0: There isn't gonna be a Wednesday episode for a while.
Speaker 0: So I just want to let everyone know Master Keaton is being published in English.
Speaker 0: I got volume.
Speaker 0: I got volume 4.
Speaker 0: There's way more master Keaton than there is in the anime, even though a lot of it overlaps and it's the same story.
Speaker 1: Yeah, is it worth reading compared to just watching all the anime?
Speaker 0: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 0: because I like the anime a lot and Gun in the origin manga is almost done.
Speaker 1: No, I gotta read that.
Speaker 1: I really gotta read that.
Speaker 1: But otherwise, we're gonna be a magfest.
Speaker 1: Panels are like getting sorted out.
Speaker 0: Am I gonna be at breakfast?
Speaker 1: Well, you're on a bunch of panels.
Speaker 0: Am I?
Speaker 0: Yeah, my name's on there.
Speaker 1: I put you on them.
Speaker 1: Okay, if I can see well, I guess I can't announce what you're on right now.
Speaker 0: But are they panels?
Speaker 0: I can do I think so without preparing you.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah Scott I mean am I getting a badge but not gonna have like a trouble when I go to get the badge?
Speaker 1: Well, I'm gonna send you another email.
Speaker 1: cuz you got to sort that shit out.
Speaker 0: cuz I have a badge.
Speaker 0: I filled out the thing and I never heard anything.
Speaker 1: cuz yeah, you waited like months before filling out the thing.
Speaker 1: I sent you that link like 11 times.
Speaker 1: This is why I'm the producer and you're the host.
Speaker 0: filled it out.
Speaker 1: I'll sort it out.
Speaker 1: But yeah, you're at a bunch of panels.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't really want to be on the panel They just want to go.
Speaker 0: well, you can find place in space war.
Speaker 1: Well, then you can buy a badge and just go and I'll do all the panels.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like being on the panel.
Speaker 0: Hey, but I put you I'm gonna pay.
Speaker 0: I'm a little bit quarters in the space war.
Speaker 1: I put you where did?
Speaker 1: there's an eSports panel that we're both on.
Speaker 1: Okay, just talking about like the current state basically eSports stuff that you weren't allowed to say.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, I'm not allowed to say anything scheduled or anything and Probably redoing the far future of gaming.
Speaker 1: I did not put you on that one because What I plan to do is like it has you going.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, he's gonna be on much of the panels But I'm gonna record.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna also video that panel if they let us do it at magfest, you know Why.
Speaker 0: he actually called me randomly Recently recently.
Speaker 1: I you I was talking to.
Speaker 0: he was like in the city and he's like hey And I was like, oh wow, I was playing netrunner.
Speaker 0: that's right.
Speaker 1: that was not recently it was that was a while ago.
Speaker 1: I remember cuz we Emily and I were not home Like we were actually out of town and not like yeah enough to hang out.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: That's when that was.
Speaker 1: that was a long time ago Scott.
Speaker 1: Anyway, when you said recently I was like what this week now see in town.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: No go hang out.
Speaker 0: Not that we do some stuff.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: So what I plan to do, this is like secret spoilers for people.
Speaker 1: So you actually listen to the show is I'm take the video of the far future of gaming panel We had at PAX and the far future of gaming panel that I hope will be doing at magfest.
Speaker 1: combine them together like the highlights and like the important answers instead of just here's a video of the panel and Then I'm gonna interview some people as well.
Speaker 1: and instead of just putting up a video of a panel It's gonna be a documentary except it's only gonna be like two hours long two hours.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe an hour and a half We'll see what I cut it down into but this is an experiment Because it's a two-hour documentary is something that you should kick-start.
Speaker 1: I'm big.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, maybe I will kick-start it once I have like enough together Like I got to make sure that I'll have enough content from two goings of this panel at two different conventions To be worth continuing and doing something weird with it.
Speaker 1: reason I'm doing this?
Speaker 1: because I've noticed that people watch the videos of our lectures But Almost no one watches the videos of panels on game design.
Speaker 1: They only watch videos of panels if it's someone who's famous just completely on their own.
Speaker 1: They don't give a shit about like a panel on game design for the most part.
Speaker 1: So I want to see if there's a way to make that popular or make that watched by people.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 1: That's my plan.
Speaker 1: Also, I'm just sick of putting up a video like we do the same panel 15 times Right?
Speaker 0: other meta things in the meta moment this Thursday in the United States in case you don't live here or know about here Is the Thanksgiving which you talked about in a previous episode?
Speaker 1: Yep Uh, will there be a Thursday episode only if we record one right after we record this?
Speaker 1: Otherwise, no unlikely.
Speaker 0: So yeah, look for geek nights in the early weeks of December But probably not the late weeks of December or the early weeks of January.
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably in the mid January because I think the magfest is in the late January.
Speaker 1: Yep, and actually babe end of January February is rough because then we got packed south.
Speaker 0: I'm flying from an animo move Boston animal and impacts East are coming right after that.
Speaker 0: Yeah I should tell work about those things.
Speaker 1: Oh, I can think I got a deal.
Speaker 1: I got finished sorting out the anime Boston stuff, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah Otherwise, yeah geek nights join our patreon and buy our t-shirt.
Speaker 0: No don't save your money.
Speaker 1: So I don't play rocket league that much anymore.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, I love rocket league is a great game.
Speaker 0: But after playing it like I started playing it a lot say the past week I was playing it like hours a day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and because you were playing I started playing again in over the weekend.
Speaker 0: I played it a whole bunch two nights ago.
Speaker 1: I just started up rocket League.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh Scott's playing I'll play and I hit find me a game.
Speaker 1: matchmaker.
Speaker 1: matchmaker find me a game and I sat there For like ten minutes with it not finding me a game.
Speaker 0: Whoa, that barely happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, usually puts me and it kept saying messages like expanding the skill group.
Speaker 1: We'll look at expanding the regions and then it put me in a game in Europe.
Speaker 1: So my ping was like a hundred and sixty.
Speaker 0: well I've never had that happen and I always get a game in the East and I was like and it doesn't take long to put Me in a game.
Speaker 1: I think it's cuz I haven't played much to the matchmaking decided.
Speaker 1: I was terrible.
Speaker 1: So it matched me with people who I'm bad at rocket League.
Speaker 1: Like don't get me wrong.
Speaker 1: I was neo compared to these people.
Speaker 0: So yeah Yeah So thing is we're used to use rocket League is the example because that's what brought this topic Fucked by this real hard.
Speaker 0: There are basically almost no games ever To have gotten this right counter-strike.
Speaker 0: counter-strike has it mostly right?
Speaker 0: Starcraft has it mostly right.
Speaker 0: ish Chess.
Speaker 0: chess has it right.
Speaker 0: chess has a system I guess.
Speaker 0: Yeah But anyway, so the problem is matchmaking specifically with online video games with random opponents.
Speaker 1: Yep, wait the situation is even more so with random teams.
Speaker 1: Yeah with just random opponents, which means rocket League NS - right out of strike.
Speaker 0: So you would probably agree most people would agree rocket League is a fun game or say basketball.
Speaker 0: basketball is a fun game, right?
Speaker 0: But there is a problem which we have talked about many times in the past, which is the air hockey problem.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go play some basketball.
Speaker 0: Let's say me and rim play basketball.
Speaker 0: That'll probably be okay, right?
Speaker 1: Yep Both suck.
Speaker 0: rim is probably more athletically inclined but like Scott have more basketball skills.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my my free thrower percentage is like 12% like.
Speaker 0: I think I think I could make it like, you know ridiculous percent.
Speaker 0: I don't understand how.
Speaker 0: NBA players.
Speaker 0: There's a low percentage.
Speaker 0: Yeah back in when I was like in middle school.
Speaker 0: I was like, I basically didn't miss free throws.
Speaker 0: I didn't stand there as long as you want Right, but anyway, it'll probably be reasonably fun.
Speaker 0: now Basketball.
Speaker 0: the game is fun to play but if I had to play against LeBron, right?
Speaker 0: Suddenly, even though it's the same goddamn game because my opponent's skill level is so high.
Speaker 0: That is not fun.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna get to do any of the fun things that there are in basketball like touching the ball Shooting the ball dribbling the ball Blocking shot.
Speaker 0: I'll be able to do none of those things.
Speaker 0: LeBron will stand there.
Speaker 0: He'll be really tall.
Speaker 0: He'll shoot it right into the net immediately.
Speaker 0: I can't do anything about it because I can't jump that high to reach where he his hands are now.
Speaker 1: Imagine this is even worse than a team game.
Speaker 0: then if I if he gives me the ball and I start with it, he'll immediately steal it from me and there's nothing I Can do about it and then he'll put it in the net again.
Speaker 1: Let's do it on a team instead.
Speaker 1: So it's three LeBron's versus two Jordans and Scott.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: So they you know, the two Jordan team is gonna have a little trouble because who's covering that third LeBron?
Speaker 0: Third LeBron is pretty much it's gonna you know, there's no fright, you know even or how about this a LeBron and two Scots right, yeah versus Three like college basketball players like average, you know, they're good at basketball.
Speaker 1: that might actually be a good matchup.
Speaker 0: It's possible.
Speaker 0: It could be a good man here.
Speaker 1: Even if it is a good matchup Scott's not having fun?
Speaker 0: Yeah, Scott's not having fun.
Speaker 0: First of all, also I'm betting on the LeBron and two Scots.
Speaker 0: I think it's the game as such is an aspect of the game that you know You look at.
Speaker 0: even in the NBA a LeBron and four schmoes can beat five okay players.
Speaker 1: Women's hockey is like that.
Speaker 1: specifically too Like if there's one player who's really good because the you know, because the league is not does not support the players.
Speaker 1: Well, there isn't like a deep well to draw from.
Speaker 1: so if you've got like two really good stick handlers They just walk around scoring like boop boop boop.
Speaker 0: Exactly so, you know in Rocket League, especially if you've got I guess the Michael Jordan of Rocket League is this guy named chrono V. So if chrono V's on your team is chrono V and two Scots, right?
Speaker 0: Well, I know chrono V and two rims versus three Scots.
Speaker 0: The two rims just sit in the two rims and the three Scots will do nothing.
Speaker 0: Well, the chrono V just puts the ball in the net repeatedly.
Speaker 0: Boom.
Speaker 0: Boom go go and there's nothing we can do about it.
Speaker 0: in my heart we try.
Speaker 1: now what's interesting is that I was blind to this problem when I was in high school because I play, you know, I got really into FPS's and I played them all the time.
Speaker 1: Yep, so I was in that upper like top tier in like capture the flag kinds of games.
Speaker 1: So to me like when Team Fortress 2 came out way later I didn't like it because all I could think of was wow I'm really good at this game and this.
Speaker 1: and now Team Fortress 2 just hobbles me like it doesn't let me use my skill
Speaker 0: Right, so
Speaker 1: I'd be the dude with the grappling hook like flying around like if I get the flag I capture it and no one No one can stop me unless I'm playing on a private server with a bunch of pros.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so in a skill any skill based game Regardless of what the game is if it is a game that is truly testing skills.
Speaker 0: The game will only be enjoyable even if the game itself is a really good game.
Speaker 0: a Skill game is almost universally Regardless of your taste.
Speaker 0: I mean you might really like getting your ass destroyed Someone way better than you or you might be a real asshole and really like beating up on players.
Speaker 0: You can't put up a fight.
Speaker 0: Uh, but most people the majority of people do not enjoy that.
Speaker 0: They enjoy a good matchup right.
Speaker 0: a skill based game becomes interesting and fun when you know It's slightly challenging for both players.
Speaker 0: Both players have a chance to win right and there's some meaningful competition.
Speaker 0: me running a race against Usain Bolt is not interesting to spectate or Participate in but Usain Bolt versus whoever is the second fastest but not as fast as Usain Bolt becomes interesting because it's like maybe that guy improved since the last time we saw them race.
Speaker 1: now take Ice hockey or American football an example of a game.
Speaker 1: because the games are so widely played.
Speaker 1: There are so many levels of play from the NHL all the way down to like the local Ajo no, like local like kids playing ice hockey on a pond in the middle of Canada.
Speaker 1: Yep, so no matter how good or bad you are at that game There is a wide community of people who have the exact same skill level of or
Speaker 0: relatively, you know You might have a young Wayne Gretzky on your you know elementary school But then
Speaker 1: he could compete with people in a higher tier.
Speaker 1: like that here exists, right?
Speaker 1: But with a video game that hasn't reached, you know Like in the old days where quake - like that was it like that was the game.
Speaker 1: So everyone playing FPS is we're playing quake - right?
Speaker 0: So if you have a skill based game and you have random players on the internet playing Teams or not You need to somehow figure out how good people are and put them in games against other people of similar skill levels.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, no one's going to have fun playing the game.
Speaker 0: Even if the game itself is Like basically rocket League really doesn't have enough many flaws.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's so simple and pure.
Speaker 1: There's really nothing wrong with the game But it's not so widely played right that there is a wide body of players at every possible skill Let alone a good way to rank players skill, right?
Speaker 0: Well, there is a good way to rank players skill.
Speaker 0: It's called Microsoft team score, which is the best way that's been invented so far and it's pretty good, but they don't use that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so but yes, so the problem is how you know in it with the teams and the random players.
Speaker 0: how do you figure out how good someone is what team to put them on?
Speaker 0: and When there's not enough players like in your area of a similar skill level, you know rocket League.
Speaker 0: It says, you know in a few minutes as time goes by we're going to expand the skills.
Speaker 0: We will consider so great.
Speaker 1: So now it's LeBron's and people who literally don't have a control, right?
Speaker 0: They will air rather than make you wait for a half hour for like five other people of your skill level to show up And play with you.
Speaker 0: They will say alright fine We'll just play a game with who we've got even though their skill levels are have a disparity.
Speaker 1: now as I noticed There aren't people that it determines to be at my skill level because it always does that to me immediately when I join a game Right.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean I have a higher skill level than you.
Speaker 0: I say a moderate skill level.
Speaker 0: I'm like, I know how to play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can control the card reasonably.
Speaker 0: Well, I can't do too many fancy aerials and hit.
Speaker 0: I make mistakes occasionally because I'm not perfect and I'm an old man with slow reaction times.
Speaker 0: But I you know strategically like I stay on the right side of the ball.
Speaker 0: I make a lot of saves, you know, I generally ignore the general patterns, right?
Speaker 0: I'm slightly below average, you know mediocre type player, but I got you know, I got the shit down and Every single game I play I was actually writing them down for like like 10 20 games in a row.
Speaker 0: No Every single game either a Someone on the other team had a skill level.
Speaker 0: There wasn't anyone like credo V level doing you know, ridiculous aerials.
Speaker 0: they were just slightly better than everyone else or having a really good game somehow and That allowed them to score like four or five goals and now every we.
Speaker 0: basically it was meaningless.
Speaker 0: I we should our team should forfeit.
Speaker 0: sometimes we did.
Speaker 0: sometimes some idiot refused to.
Speaker 0: you had to waste the rest two minutes of Our lives waiting to lose.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: sometimes someone on our team was the best player and totally crushed the opponents And I just sat in the goal to making you know blocking some shots Maybe but the ball didn't even come to our end of the field because this good player on our team Was able to keep the ball on their end of the field and just keep scoring and I just watched myself win Which is also boring as hell.
Speaker 1: now part of like.
Speaker 1: I can already see the problem, right?
Speaker 0: And once I was the best player and I just went and scored like three goals and I didn't let the other team score I was able to get all the way back down the field and defend before they could get the ball back there Clear it to their end and score like I was just like wow.
Speaker 0: I'm really in control of this game.
Speaker 0: did I get a lot better?
Speaker 0: and I tried that in the next game doing the same thing I did in the previous game and I wasn't able to because this really good player on the other team just came and fucked me over all the time.
Speaker 0: So so it really was a situation where I got matched up with people way under me right now on steam.
Speaker 1: There are like three hundred thousand people playing Dota 2 and like two hundred and fifty thousand people playing counter-strike.
Speaker 0: That is a critical mass right there.
Speaker 1: and there are.
Speaker 1: Rocket League is not even in the top ten.
Speaker 1: Rocket League's got about 17,000 right.
Speaker 1: Rocket League is under Grand Theft Auto.
Speaker 0: that's the binding of Isaac.
Speaker 0: 17,000 is all Rocket League players online.
Speaker 0: right now It doesn't.
Speaker 0: so when I play Rocket League, I'm only choosing the solo queue.
Speaker 1: Yeah Right the solo queue has less than 2000 got five has twice as many people playing on a daily basis as Rocket League.
Speaker 0: Right and this that's not counting the PlayStation 4 players.
Speaker 1: I don't think good who also are playing against Yeah, but I don't think it's much better over there.
Speaker 0: No, it's not really any different.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this is like.
Speaker 0: so even though Rocket League is a great game I want to play if you don't have enough people of the same skill level Then you can't play.
Speaker 0: it's not worth my time.
Speaker 0: And also even if there are enough people at the right skill level you have to figure out who they are.
Speaker 0: Alright, this is the real problem.
Speaker 0: is you know, how do you figure out who these people are in a reasonable way?
Speaker 0: Well, if you only playing one-on-one matches we have a system for that.
Speaker 0: it's called elo.
Speaker 1: It's not perfect but elo because it's not an acronym.
Speaker 1: It's just a dude's name.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: But I like to talk about the electric light Orchestra.
Speaker 0: They're really good at how you know, they know a lot about this sort of thing.
Speaker 1: But yeah one-on-one there are many different algorithms that can pretty objectively say Here's the ranking of players in order.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But even then it works really well.
Speaker 0: in tennis.
Speaker 0: It's super accurate.
Speaker 1: that only helps you if there is a deep well of players to draw from Mm-hmm as the well gets shallower and shallower.
Speaker 0: I mean the Rocket League well is deep enough for the one-on-one ranking system.
Speaker 1: maybe the problem is if a game has a very high skill cap a game like a counter-strike or a Rocket League or a Weapons factory or a dota then what you'll see is there isn't.
Speaker 1: it's not like like saying like I am the hundred and eighth Strongest person on me pros island the hundred and seventh strongest person might be a hundred times better than me.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: You'll see that there'll be clusters of players in a few bands and huge gulfs between them.
Speaker 0: Usually that has to do with the mechanics of the game.
Speaker 0: For example in counter-strike, you know It's like.
Speaker 0: they'll be like sort of like the you're.
Speaker 0: it's like you're good at counter-strike You got the fundamentals down and then like you master like actually aiming Yep, and so it's like.
Speaker 0: this is particular skill that if you learn it like puts you way ahead of people who have not learned That particular skill.
Speaker 0: so they'll be like this huge gap between people who don't have it and people do like a tennis.
Speaker 0: It's like if you learn the backhand and you can actually control and hit a decent backhand suddenly that puts you Way way up.
Speaker 1: or like the serve like when you learn how to do a real serve instead of the tennis serve that most people Do and they write.
Speaker 1: it's like it's just like ace ace ace rice.
Speaker 0: There's like individual skills in these games that when you master them or at least develop them to a reasonable level Launches you into like a huge Huge gap between people have that skill and don't.
Speaker 0: and this difference is multiple skills.
Speaker 0: There's multiple gaps right in between the groups of people who have or do not have you know, these skills developed within themselves.
Speaker 0: So in rocket League, it's aerials if you can, you know perform aerial maneuvers hit the ball when it's way up in the air Precisely, you know, you're way ahead of all these people who can't.
Speaker 0: and like it launches you way You know, it's like way up there and then people who can not only do that But also when they hit the aerial can hit the ball into towards the enemy net.
Speaker 1: that will never happen.
Speaker 0: Accuracy on a consistent basis that puts you in the pro level, right?
Speaker 1: Yep so so if you see a game that has Like banding very distinctly where there's a bunch of players in these top tiers and a ton of players way at the bottom and big between them.
Speaker 1: it's a self-fulfilling cycle that will only get worse because Anyone who gets good enough to get past those first bands will have no one to play with so they'll never get better.
Speaker 0: It's like if you can do a serve in tennis You can only play against opponents who can also serve well and return the serve Otherwise, it's like anyone who doesn't have that particular skill.
Speaker 0: It's just like not even gonna play with.
Speaker 1: and if there's only seventeen thousand people playing on steam Like the odds of finding a team of people we haven't even gotten into how to rank teams Of a similar skill level for you to practice and get better are negligible and counter-strike 250,000 people.
Speaker 1: I think the peak was like 600,000 people playing the game.
Speaker 1: I'll just hit rando game and I'm pretty much guaranteed to find some people Right.
Speaker 0: So Rocket League has teams and here's the problem when you have teams.
Speaker 0: It's hard to just use some ELO system that's only based on winning and losing.
Speaker 0: because Did I win because I happen to have Lebron on my team?
Speaker 0: Am I gonna get credit for that?
Speaker 0: Did I lose because Lebron just happened to be on the other team and that reflects nothing about how good I am.
Speaker 0: Right, you know you're trying to figure out like, you know, this my particular skill level.
Speaker 0: But the only data you're using is whether my team won or lost.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'm really good.
Speaker 0: I just had two really shitty teammates who really screwed it up for me and I'm not Lebron good So I couldn't win it on my own.
Speaker 0: But if I had two other people as good as me we could have beaten that opponent team, you know It's like so.
Speaker 0: but you're judging only on the wins and losses Whether my rank should go up or down and that's a problem with teams.
Speaker 0: You need something more advanced need more advanced data to figure out somebody's individual skill level when they're on a team.
Speaker 1: Now counter-strike has a very clever like modified elo system that it uses to rank teams Based on your contribution to the team and all these other fights.
Speaker 0: So it's theoretically possible that even if your team loses your secure rank could go up.
Speaker 0: If your individual skills are improving you just happen to get put on like shitty losing teams all day.
Speaker 0: Your rank could still be up at the end of the day Because you have you made major contributions to that team and it can tell oh you were just unlucky.
Speaker 0: your teammates ruined it for you.
Speaker 0: Right because it's judging you individually despite the fact that you're on a team.
Speaker 1: Yeah because you can sort of do this diff like even you can imagine algorithms that will look at the way a team a Person is performing.
Speaker 1: like alright this guy played on ten different teams.
Speaker 1: All the teams did worse when he was on them compared to similar teams without.
Speaker 0: professional sports had been very very good at this For a very long time even before we had advanced analytics.
Speaker 0: We just regular player statistics, right?
Speaker 0: They knew Wayne Gretzky was the greatest even though he was on the LA Kings and didn't win anything Except for when he was on the Oilers.
Speaker 0: right because they're like, oh shit He scored like a million goals.
Speaker 0: his team just fucking sucks.
Speaker 0: So he lost.
Speaker 0: they could tell.
Speaker 0: you can watch the games and tell with and you don't even need to watch them To see.
Speaker 0: you can just look at the statistics and be like, wow, this guy scored more goals than like anyone ever.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter that his team lost a million games.
Speaker 0: clearly He is an amazing player Alright, and now we have an advanced analytics that eat tell you even more data than that where we can be like, aha Yeah, this picture is like the greatest picture like, you know in terms of that They're like there they have like all these crazy statistics now like wars and all kinds of not.
Speaker 1: well Look at fantasy sports like that.
Speaker 0: Mathematically and relatively empirically, you know calculate real numbers that tell you the value of that player.
Speaker 0: Like you will be expected to win this many more games if this player is on your team, right?
Speaker 0: regardless of and that like you'll see nowadays like in baseball like people win the MVP award or like You know like all kinds of you know Trophies and awards at the end of the year like golden gloves and all these things even though their team sucked ass Because they can tell how good the player is based on all these statistics and analytics they have which aren't bullshit.
Speaker 1: So I guess the moral of all this is games that want to have a competitive scene.
Speaker 1: and it's interesting is this Primarily only applies to like eSports and video games skill and skill games.
Speaker 0: if it's not as so because bork hardstone You don't need this because in hardstone It's mostly
Speaker 1: luck table like German style like table top board games that we like to play don't need this system because
Speaker 0: no teams
Speaker 1: well even even single-player you still need it like single-player games with board games as much because Those games tend to have a very short cycle like anyone who plays them enough and pays attention Will go from I don't know how to play to.
Speaker 1: I'm a near master of this game in a relatively short span of time Like and the skill cap isn't super ridiculously high.
Speaker 1: It's like you can't keep getting better at you know, like if you play fresh fish, which is a pretty good game right 20 times There is not much you can do to get better.
Speaker 0: and if you're smart enough if you're smart enough to play fresh fish Enjoy it play it 20 times and get better at it.
Speaker 0: Right then you're smart enough to master it.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine someone who could play fresh fish 20 times want to play it understand the rules play it Well, and wouldn't master it in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like by the end of like the Civ 5 we're all playing like we're all gonna be pretty good at Civ 5.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but a game that has dexterity components execution components There's like there's no limit to how good you could be.
Speaker 1: There's a theoretical limit, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like there's no hockey player in the league now who's weighing Gretzky?
Speaker 0: good and it's still possible.
Speaker 0: Someone could be even better than that is no reason you couldn't be there.
Speaker 1: Like the laws of physics there could be a person who just reacts to pucks faster and is an unstoppable goalie, right?
Speaker 1: That could happen.
Speaker 1: It's that what there's no what.
Speaker 1: I want that data, huh?
Speaker 1: I want that day to come.
Speaker 1: I'd love to see the god goalie.
Speaker 0: Yeah We have the king goalie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you want to know something sad?
Speaker 0: How old is?
Speaker 1: Heinrich oh my god, they're all.
Speaker 1: he's got to be more like 31.
Speaker 0: Heinrich Lundqvist is one Two actually two months Younger than me.
Speaker 0: I mean older than me and younger than you.
Speaker 0: He was born in March first 82.
Speaker 1: Yeah thing is you want to be a real baby.
Speaker 1: March 30 look at the ages of f1 racers.
Speaker 0: early March 82.
Speaker 0: He's pretty much just our age and meanwhile He's like the king of this town and we're just two nerds across the river doing a podcast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and he's basically the same age as us.
Speaker 0: We had just as much time.
Speaker 0: We could have done that and we beat it in his shoes right now, but we didn't.
Speaker 0: well I don't really like getting pucks flung it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can kind of ice skate though.
Speaker 1: So you got that going.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could wobble around.
Speaker 1: you guys keep walking.
Speaker 0: I can't even skate backwards.
Speaker 1: I've seen you wobble around though.
Speaker 1: That's a start.
Speaker 1: That's better than a lot of people have to relearn it every time.
Speaker 1: So think of this you need if you have a video game that you want competitive multiplayer to exist and it's a skill based game for a for a with a high skill cap for a period of time beyond the Very beginning.
Speaker 1: when you first release your game you need to somehow one Maintain a deep and wide body of players And to have an accurate matchmaking system to ensure that those players continue to play.
Speaker 0: and you need to air.
Speaker 0: If someone who wants to play the game, they say find me a game You cannot ever put them in a game where they are mismatched.
Speaker 0: You should just make them wait even though they are waiting.
Speaker 0: But if you make them wait Like I do that's why you need the large body of players They'll give up and then you don't have the wide body of the wide body of players to decrease the wait time because there's a limit To how long someone's gonna wait.
Speaker 0: But you should still err on the side of waiting rather than playing a bad game because if someone has a bad experience they're gonna hate your game and blame it on your game, even though your game is perfect or really good like rocket league and The matchmaking is just awful,
Speaker 1: but no matchmaking system will protect you from.
Speaker 1: if the player base is already stratified Yeah, and is small like NS You can always reset it.
Speaker 1: the reason I couldn't play NS too much is that I didn't get in on the ground floor of playing the betas a lot because It didn't work that well.
Speaker 1: by the time the game was stable there was a set of people who were like unto gods compared to me and No one else.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So if I join any game, I was that shithead ruining it for the team.
Speaker 1: Yep, the mat even if the matchmaking was perfect.
Speaker 1: It would have said rim.
Speaker 1: You're the cheese.
Speaker 1: You're gonna stand alone.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: So the one major prop that the.
Speaker 0: I want to just comment.
Speaker 0: one last thing which is how these games are doing it now Specifically rocket League and hearthstone.
Speaker 0: even the hearthstone is not skill base.
Speaker 0: I'll talk about Team Fortress 2 as well right is they're making this the ranking system.
Speaker 0: They are using The here.
Speaker 0: the problem with it's a rocket League.
Speaker 0: What is a grinding ranking system?
Speaker 0: It's not some right theoretically.
Speaker 0: Let's say I'm a natural at rocket League.
Speaker 0: I'm as good as kernove and I just I play rocket League a few times.
Speaker 0: I learn it and then I'm just God, right?
Speaker 0: It's gonna take a long time for my rank to go all the way up to where it belongs.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz our grinding ranks because every time my team wins I get a few points based on you know They adjust it a little bit based on how good my opponents are how good I you know and things like that.
Speaker 0: But if my team loses even though I may have displayed my godly skills and scored five goals Maybe my teammates own gold six times I'm gonna lose points, even though I displayed my godly skills in that game.
Speaker 0: So it's gonna.
Speaker 0: I just had to keep playing tons and tons of fucking games before the game has recognized me at the true You know skill level and pair me up against players.
Speaker 0: I should be playing against who are also godlike.
Speaker 0: Sailing hearthstone.
Speaker 0: It's like my brother is really good at hearthstone.
Speaker 0: He plays it way too much, but he didn't get to legendary until like last month.
Speaker 0: He was so proud, but it's like I could get to legendary too.
Speaker 0: You know what, you know what changes my rank from season to season.
Speaker 0: hearthstone whether or not you play how much I play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I play a lot of fucking hearthstone.
Speaker 0: I can get up to like single-digit ranks.
Speaker 0: I played it.
Speaker 0: I'm not like rank eight or nine now, but if I don't play a lot then it's like no I should be able to play like five games of hearthstone and after trouncing five noobs It should shoot me the fuck up to like rank five where I usually.
Speaker 0: you know where I kind of belong, right?
Speaker 0: You know, but because the system is based on grinding.
Speaker 0: It's like it's.
Speaker 0: you know, sometimes I randomly lose.
Speaker 1: Grinding is because a lot of people They need to feel a sense of progress even if they are not actually progressing like in counter-strike.
Speaker 1: I only progress through the ranks if I do well.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, I do not progress through the ranks.
Speaker 1: Yeah But a lot of games will grind up whatever indicator it gives you of how good you are.
Speaker 1: So you get a little bit of reward every time you play on rocket league.
Speaker 0: They actually have two separate measures.
Speaker 1: Yeah Trying to give the people who don't understand these things like you can mostly don't.
Speaker 0: most people don't even play the ranked mode Which is why it's hard to find matches.
Speaker 0: But in the ranked mode your rank goes up and down as you win and lose, right?
Speaker 0: Which is bullshit, but it should be based on your individuals.
Speaker 0: We talked about that already.
Speaker 0: But there's another thing that goes up no matter what but it goes up more if you score more and goes up more if you Do better but only goes up.
Speaker 0: and that's sort of like your experience and you unlock like skins and all that kind of bullshit And your label changes from like pro to veteran to expert to you know And it's like that only goes up and like you're basically grinding that no matter what it's like.
Speaker 0: get rid of the fucking grinding bullshit.
Speaker 1: Just figure out my true skill level.
Speaker 1: But people want that grinding because someone who is not getting better at a game And someone who is not a person who is who you know.
Speaker 0: It's possible to like a skill based game like rocket league because it's way fun But not be the kind of person who cares about ranks and skills and improving.
Speaker 1: Here's my counterpoint, but it assumes that people are making poor decisions.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of people should.
Speaker 1: they shouldn't be playing that game But you really need them to be playing or you'll have even fewer players and more gas.
Speaker 0: But if you just make their skill if you make their thing constantly go down because they suck at all quit.
Speaker 1: They'll quit because those people want to see their rank going up.
Speaker 1: They want.
Speaker 1: it's like the people who play an RPG.
Speaker 1: They want to see the number go up because they've played longer.
Speaker 1: That's why MMORPG players get so fucking mad when someone buys Levels or buys gold because they feel like they got cheated because they ground that shit out, right?
Speaker 1: grinding's got to go but you at the same time the psychologically people there are people who will not play your game unless you give them a reward for grinding because people you know They just want they should just play a different game.
Speaker 0: You know there needs to be games for serious people and games for not serious people.
Speaker 0: So here's my.
Speaker 0: I have a crazy idea.
Speaker 0: All right I'm not.
Speaker 0: did I say this on the show before?
Speaker 1: maybe you might have said it in a panel.
Speaker 0: Maybe I don't think I said it in a panel because it's too crazy.
Speaker 0: So you should have a game with serious mode and in serious mode You have to make some sort of deposit.
Speaker 1: because oh that idea.
Speaker 0: did I tell this idea on the show?
Speaker 1: I don't think so and you've said in the forum a bunch of times, right?
Speaker 0: And I definitely said it online a bunch because people are really mad about it.
Speaker 0: They're so mad.
Speaker 0: I don't know why they're so mad.
Speaker 0: so you to make some sort of deposit because you agreed to serious mode, right?
Speaker 0: You're serious enough that you're gonna put money down.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna keep.
Speaker 0: we're not gonna keep your money.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna spend the money's in escrow.
Speaker 0: It's a deposited money.
Speaker 0: does guarantee that you're in serious mode.
Speaker 1: like the game cost a hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: 50 bucks was like you bought the game and 50 bucks is sitting in s right.
Speaker 0: You don't have to play serious mode if you don't want to.
Speaker 0: it's entirely optional, right?
Speaker 0: We only want serious people in serious mode serious people who are serious enough to put a deposit down.
Speaker 0: once you're in serious mode Right.
Speaker 0: We're only gonna let you play with people who are also in serious mode because you're all super serious.
Speaker 1: You're only playing against super pros who care a lot meaning the people who care enough to put money down in serious mode.
Speaker 0: So now matchmaking should be.
Speaker 0: you know already we've separated people who are serious enough, right?
Speaker 0: And you can always withdraw from serious mode.
Speaker 0: if you want, you know, we can take.
Speaker 0: give your money back Once you're in serious mode.
Speaker 0: shit is serious, right?
Speaker 0: if you like, you know a bad sportsmanship We're just gonna penalize you in money.
Speaker 0: We're gonna take your fucking money, right?
Speaker 0: It's like oh you cursed it that dude Five Scott five hundred dollar fine.
Speaker 0: Fuck yourself.
Speaker 1: counter-strike does already have that with the cooldowns and that if you were on sportsmen like in Ranked games and people rat you out then basically you get a cooldown where you can't play for 30 minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, if you're not good enough if you do it again, it's like two weeks.
Speaker 1: if you do it again It's like a month like you Know.
Speaker 0: I want to take your fucking money.
Speaker 1: why though that's not the people?
Speaker 1: being shitty to each other is not the problem.
Speaker 0: It is a problem.
Speaker 0: and now it is not the problem, but there are.
Speaker 0: there are other things I'm gonna take your money for for example.
Speaker 0: What if you just quit a game?
Speaker 0: you rage quit?
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm gonna take your fucking money because you rage quit.
Speaker 0: but you know ruining serious mode.
Speaker 1: None of these things fix the matchmaking brah.
Speaker 0: They can fix the matchmaking problem because by punishing people with fines for all these transgressions You're basically guaranteeing that people are gonna come play the game seriously.
Speaker 0: So we can assume all these things that we Basically can make a good ranking system even better because we have all these assumptions that are now truths Right.
Speaker 0: people aren't gonna be scoring own goals on purpose to fuck up our ranking system.
Speaker 0: People aren't gonna be rage quitting to fuck up our ranking system.
Speaker 0: Everyone's actually trying to.
Speaker 0: things are fucking up the rankings every but I mean they're not fucking up the ranking systems.
Speaker 0: The ranking system is garbage.
Speaker 0: to begin.
Speaker 0: It will make our good ranking system even better.
Speaker 1: I'm not having to account for even those things among the like 15 people who are in the series.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: If your game is really good.
Speaker 0: Hopefully you'd have a lot of God.
Speaker 1: I would not.
Speaker 1: I would not put money down in rocket league serious mode.
Speaker 0: if that you're not serious I mean that you're not seriously enough for that.
Speaker 1: No I want to be serious at the game But I would not trust that there'd be enough people who put money now if it'd be worth it.
Speaker 1: and the non serious mode already Has a terrible matchmaking system.
Speaker 0: I guess the thing is you don't really have a game That's like.
Speaker 0: I guess that's your game for all time.
Speaker 0: But like if there was a serious mode online netrunner with a good user interface, I'd be serious mode.
Speaker 1: Well counter-strike is kind of that.
Speaker 0: would you pay for counter-strike serious mode?
Speaker 1: No, cuz kids serious mode already exists and works great and doesn't cost money.
Speaker 0: It's okay.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with it?
Speaker 0: It's not perfect What's?
Speaker 1: no?
Speaker 1: what is not perfect about it?
Speaker 1: that your system fixes?
Speaker 0: That people just be shitty come back and be shitty again, no one does that though you'll be rage-quitting.
Speaker 1: no, people don't rage.
Speaker 1: quit serious games.
Speaker 1: when they do they get punished and actually it's a pretty bad punishment.
Speaker 1: and if and the only Way to get around those punishments is to pay for counter-strike again.
Speaker 1: They get penalized monetarily.
Speaker 0: I thought you said that they don't get penalized monetarily up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if they keep fucking up, they got to buy a new steam account.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay by counter-strike.
Speaker 0: That's the same as what I was saying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's already there, but that is not the problem.
Speaker 0: I think you said you just had to get cool off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the cool offs keep escalating.
Speaker 1: It's not it escalates and escalates.
Speaker 1: But the problem with the matchmaking there is just that There's a top tier of super pro people and a bottom tier of terrible people and a big gulf between them.
Speaker 1: Your system doesn't fix the fundamental problems that are affecting most actual games in the real world.
Speaker 1: You're solving the last 1% problem obviously in serious mode.
Speaker 0: You're only gonna be playing against people, you know Really close to your skill level and you're willing to wait now because only to all of them limited number of people bother to put Money down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the people who are so serious that you want to play with I'm a noob, but I want to be serious.
Speaker 0: Well, there's something else to consider right?
Speaker 0: Is that depending on the game like take for example, you know, like especially a board game like Puerto Rico, right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I guess there's someone out there who's even better at Puerto Rico than us.
Speaker 0: We probably can't beat them.
Speaker 1: We haven't played in a long time Like.
Speaker 1: I don't remember the full sequence of my like there.
Speaker 0: maybe there.
Speaker 0: maybe let's say you got five board gamers, right?
Speaker 0: And there's you know, we're you know that and they're all at five different skill levels with definite gulfs between them.
Speaker 1: But if the five of us play Puerto Rico five times by the end everyone's near the top tier.
Speaker 0: well, maybe but Even in that first game there's a huge gap between let's say who's like someone we know who's like can play board games But isn't godlike?
Speaker 1: Alright, and then I can imagine that person, right?
Speaker 0: Okay, and then I'm like the third and then the fifth is some like genius person who's like, you know, amazing You're just gonna win no matter what right?
Speaker 0: and we all play Puerto Rico together.
Speaker 0: Well, even though our skill disparities are so big and it's a skill game And that person in rank one is gonna win that will still be an enjoyable time Right because we're all serious.
Speaker 0: See you go to a netrunner tournament and you're gonna meet up with someone.
Speaker 1: It's just got way better than you when I hear series and they're serious.
Speaker 1: But when I play rocket League, I'm in a lot of games where everyone's serious.
Speaker 1: It's just the skill gaps are so wide that the game is terrible.
Speaker 0: The skill disparity is way bigger than it is in a board game.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I'm saying if the skill disparity were wider in a board game like that There are board games like glory to Rome.
Speaker 0: age of steam is the one you want to talk Rome.
Speaker 1: if I played glory to Rome so much that if I play it with someone who like it's their first time playing It is not fun.
Speaker 0: They don't get to do anything.
Speaker 0: They don't get to the I mean age of steam.
Speaker 0: It's just like I eliminated it in turn two or three.
Speaker 1: I got eliminated not too long after you.
Speaker 1: I remember that game.
Speaker 0: I think it was the same turn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I made it one more turn because I had like a dollar left, okay Yeah, this is one of those things where if you have a game You this meta thing that's like out.
Speaker 0: It's like you made the perfect game But then you ruined it because you messed up this meta.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that there's a much higher level of discussion needs to be had here.
Speaker 1: Look at the game like Team Fortress 2 which despite only having like 40,000 people playing it Like doesn't have this problem because the skill disparity is lower.
Speaker 1: because because it's a skill based game Does the game itself does not reward individual skill much beyond a pretty low bar?
Speaker 1: So the things that rewards are teamwork.
Speaker 1: Imagine the Team Fortress 2 version of rocket League would be a game Where no matter how good you are at aerials if the other team has someone everyone has auto aim on their car.
Speaker 0: So if you go towards the ball, you're gonna hit it.
Speaker 0: You're going to hit it towards the net no matter what.
Speaker 1: so it's like in hockey if Choosing what line and who to pass to mattered but everyone had the same skill at passing.
Speaker 1: The Wayne Gretzky can't pass better than the can't shoot harder or more accurately Yeah Or he can't shoot much harder like he's 2% more likely to score with a percent the percentage of goals that go in when you shoot or equal.
Speaker 0: Yeah goalies are all you know Like a relatively equal percentage of shots.
Speaker 1: So for a team game that is a way to address the problem by pulling down the individual skill But ensuring that that is not replaced by grinding or nothing.
Speaker 1: It has to be replaced by team coordination matters.
Speaker 1: like in Team Fortress 2 If a bunch of rims and a bunch of Scots play against each other It would be a dead 50/50 match.
Speaker 1: the skill would be do the rims Coordinate like when they attack better than the Scots.
Speaker 1: That kind of thing.
Speaker 1: do the rims like switch classes at the right time and there's this balance going on.
Speaker 1: so That is a way to get around this problem.
Speaker 1: But it becomes a very different game.
Speaker 1: team for just it was a very different game from counter-strike as a result of mega skill Gaze game.
Speaker 0: get the matchmaking right, you know, the Microsoft team score talked about before right is a pretty good system.
Speaker 0: It's not perfect.
Speaker 0: Right, but there are many systems out there for doing better, you know.
Speaker 0: analysis of Individual players skill team-based or not, right Sports.
Speaker 0: I already talked about advanced analytics.
Speaker 0: We can determine how good someone is even if they're on the losing team.
Speaker 0: Yep And then try to pair people up as much as you can with people of equal skill level.
Speaker 1: The second problem of the depth of players is almost an afterthought.
Speaker 1: You have to get the matchmaking as good as it can possibly be right right one like Rocket League You know.
Speaker 0: It's like they can do a lot better than they're doing even without getting more players.
Speaker 0: if they don't do better Then it's making me not want to play the game even though I really like the game because I can't get a good game on because I don't get matched up with.
Speaker 1: but it's easy to Not see the problem because if you already got past that Gulf like if you're good enough at counter-strike or good enough at Rocket League then you find a great game every time you play or No, you don't cuz it's really.
Speaker 0: I get even games where I beat up everyone.
Speaker 0: It's kind of boring.
Speaker 0: I want to play against an evil match tight game.
Speaker 1: He's got.
Speaker 1: the other thing is those people form a team Mmm, if you're in that tier like I'm not good enough for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're not past the level.
Speaker 1: I'm saying if you get past that bar, if you're over the waterfall, you're not falling back down the waterfall.
Speaker 1: There's like a paradise of you.
Speaker 1: get your three friends and you play the perfect game all the time with other teams that are similarly Serious, no one wants to organize Yeah.
Speaker 1: but the only way to avoid that problem is either to make your blue to flatten the playing field somehow Team Fortress 2 style or To have the best possible matchmaking from day one
Speaker 0: and then
Speaker 1: hope
Speaker 0: you can always reset your Matchmaking and start a new with a perfect system.
Speaker 1: if you messed it up to begin to a degree unless you lost players It won't come back sure.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah, you may have lost players who won't come back those critical first few weeks.
Speaker 0: You've got to make it so that but you can still as long as you have people playing.
Speaker 1: you can always just reset all Your ranking system and install a new one and do things the right way as long as a pro can join and in a reasonable Amount of time be matched pretty much only with pros.
Speaker 1: Yeah And a complete noob can join and always have games with noobs and someone who's old like us Can join and at least have a reasonable game 80% of the time.
Speaker 1: Right, that's your best shot at keeping the depth of play enough to keep your game going.
Speaker 0: Also, even if you don't have enough players if your ranking systems be good enough You'll get more players playing more and that will fill it up right.
Speaker 0: if your ranking system is bad You're only gonna make it worse.
Speaker 0: It's a self-fulfilling or self, you know Helping kind of thing.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Speaker 1: music can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and my comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patrons this week are And it's kind of hard to read all these as I've said before.
Speaker 1: so once again if I'm pronouncing your name wrong week after week Email me.
Speaker 1: rim at front row crew.
Speaker 1: calm if you never guessed my email address that goes directly to me and I will not only fix it, but I will apologize.
Speaker 1: but this week we have Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando James David White Christian Koontz Jess mechanical mind Renee from New Zealand Robert Lee Ryan Perrin drew up and Lander rare Laval Brian Cedroni Rochelle, Mantanona Finn Eric Silverald rim eats poop Edgar Mendez William Eisen rose Chris midkiff Chris Knox flame dark fire Samuel Cordery Daniel Redmond Chris Haddad Doug Snyder Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: So yes, you know the front row crew a bunch of us are playing a sort of private civ5 game on the giant multiplayer robot.
Speaker 1: I highly recommend it.
Speaker 1: Like I don't want to promote it or anything as an official like hey do this thing, but it's pretty legit.
Speaker 1: and Scott keeps trying to see what I'm doing on my turn.
Speaker 1: So I can't take my turn until he leaves after geek nights.
Speaker 1: So I'm trying to think of a way to use the fact that he's trying to see this to trick him into doing something bad.
Speaker 1: But that might require me to craft a save file Where it looks like it's my turn in that game, but it's really a fake game I made.
Speaker 1: so I can put myself somewhere different.
Speaker 1: and If you have any ideas of how I should trick Scott With this because I'm gonna like up got to go to the bathroom before we do the main bit and he'll notice that civ5 Has got open in the background and I'm hoping you'll click on it and see what's going on in my civilization.
Speaker 1: I really want to roll him in a critical moment.
Speaker 1: like 80 turns into this game In other patreon news.
Speaker 1: I did start pre-production on geek nights presents utenna 14.
Speaker 1: I Have been fighting off so many DMCA takedowns on those videos.
Speaker 1: you have no idea but so far they're all still up and we are continuing with episode 14.
Speaker 1: I'm doing pre-production now and it's all because of you you guys Donating money on our patreon.
Speaker 1: So really seriously.
Speaker 1: Thank you.
Speaker 1: We can't keep doing the cool stuff like geek nights presents utenna without something other than just doing the show and The patreon is a big step if geek night's lieutenant goes well and that like documentary I was talking about doing also goes well.
Speaker 1: thinking about making maybe even drastic life changes that really push geek nights to a big level and If the patreon was not here, I would not have the confidence to go forward with that.
Speaker 1: so now as always Your moment of literally the opposite of Zen.
Speaker 2: Hey, I read somewhere that mathematicians can turn a sphere inside out.
Speaker 2: Yes, that's true.
Speaker 1: What's the big deal?
Speaker 2: Just poke a hole in it and pull it through?
Speaker 2: Sure, but the point is to do it without making a hole, but then it seems impossible.
Speaker 2: You're right.
Speaker 2: You cannot do it with an ordinary sphere like a basketball.
Speaker 2: You have to understand the rules of the game.
Speaker 2: This sphere is made of an abstract elastic material that can stretch and bend and pass through itself.
Speaker 2: but you cannot rip or puncture this material without destroying it and You cannot crease it or bend it sharply if the surface can pass through itself.
Speaker 1: What's the problem?
Speaker 2: Do you think allowing self intersections makes it easy?
Speaker 2: Try it.
Speaker 1: I'll push the two halves right through each other.
Speaker 2: Be careful.
Speaker 2: What about that ring around the equator?
Speaker 2: Remember you mustn't tear or crease it.
Speaker 1: Ah Let me try again.
Speaker 2: That's no good either.
Speaker 1: You're pinching it infinitely tight But then there's no way.
Speaker 1: it's impossible.
Speaker 1: You'd have to crease or pinch it to turn it inside out.
Speaker 2: It is surprising but watch this.
Speaker 2: Is this it?
Speaker 2: Is this a sphere turning inside out?