Speaker 0: So this is actually a very special episode of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: So we talked about it on Thursday, but suffice it to say, the episode got messed up due to a crazy timing issue between the sound card and the wazapi drivers and whatever.
Speaker 0: So super corrupted audio.
Speaker 0: This was very close to being a lost episode of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: In the 10 years and 1100 or so episodes we've done, we've lost maybe four or five episodes total, but if any of you do entertainment, let me tell you, it is really, really fucking hard to redo an hour of banter that you've just done on the same topic.
Speaker 0: However, thanks to Tracy for doing a wonderful job of helping me write a script that would remove the null samples from the messed up corrupted audio, and then following up an audition with a bunch of filters, I was able to un-lose this episode.
Speaker 0: The quality is not the typical Geek Nights quality, so if you listen to the following episode, and it does not sound as silky smooth as I do right now, this is the only episode of Geek Nights that will ever sound like this.
Speaker 0: We have since put in place measures to make sure that this sort of thing can never happen again.
Speaker 0: So this episode, which was lost forever, has been recovered and you can now listen to it.
Speaker 0: This is something that, but for technology and perseverance, would never have been heard by any human in the entire world, except myself and Scott.
Speaker 0: So stay tuned for future episodes that will sound good again, and if you think this episode sounds bad, this is as good as it could have been made given the technology we have today.
Speaker 0: And without further ado, it's Tuesday, June 23rd, 2015.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: - I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: - And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we're talking about one of the newer Wolfenstein games, 'cause Scott played it, but he didn't seem to remember which one he played, so we'll see what the show's about.
Speaker 1: - Let's do this.
Speaker 0: - 'Cause I tried to play the game that he told me to play, which you say.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, you've tried to play it this morning before work.
Speaker 0: - No, no, no, yesterday, so yesterday, it was Wolfenstein New Orders, the one you said you played.
Speaker 0: - Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I was like, oh whatever, I'll just, like I bought it 'cause I own every game on Steam, I just don't play them.
Speaker 0: So I right clicked on it, like yesterday, and I was like, install, and then it was like can't, and I'm like, oh, and I back up, and then I look, and I'm like, oh right, it's a modern AAA game, it's like 40 gigabytes of shit.
Speaker 0: So I put it on my fast SSD that I use for like, the few games I play that matter to me, and just, you know, I figure that game would like, the performance of that drive.
Speaker 0: And then I just forgot about it, and then that night, I thought, all right, I'll play this game now for a few hours, and then I'll be good to go, and then I look, and it's 80% installed, and I said, well, I went to bed.
Speaker 1: - Wait, wait, wait 'til the last second.
Speaker 0: - Yep, well, we only decided to do the show like two days ago, so, to be fair.
Speaker 1: - We could've done it on something else, we can still change it right now, and stop recording.
Speaker 0: - We could still change it right now.
Speaker 0: - I don't know, Muzdah?
Speaker 1: - No, I didn't hear you played Muzdah 1.
Speaker 0: - Oh no, I've never played Muzdah 1.
Speaker 0: I can talk a lot about Advance Wars.
Speaker 1: - Great.
Speaker 0: - But yeah, so what I've been working on instead is actually, if you might've noticed, my YouTube channel and Scott's YouTube channel have both been rocking, 'cause Scott's been doing the streaming, and I've been vastly, rapidly working through our massive archive of old footage.
Speaker 0: Which we didn't do anything with.
Speaker 0: So, panels from PAX South, Expo Hall from PAX South, that video about race walking from the panel from PAX South, where we should all have a race walking, where there's some super butter race walker in my YouTube comments, getting increasingly angry at my dismissal of her entire world, apparently.
Speaker 0: So, you can follow that in my YouTube comments, because that's the only place this little adventure will exist.
Speaker 0: So, I guess in terms of gaming news.
Speaker 1: There's only one news that we care about, that is big enough that we should, well, I guess there's all this Nintendo E3 news, but I really don't care.
Speaker 1: Until that shit comes out, it's like, whatever.
Speaker 0: - There's a lot of E3 news that I'm interested in, in the sense of that's a game I'll play, but there's nothing I'll say that you're not gonna read on whatever blog aggregator is gonna tell you.
Speaker 0: Like, oh, this game came out.
Speaker 0: I don't know any more than you do.
Speaker 0: I know everything that people who are at E3 know, and you also know all of that.
Speaker 0: I don't have anything new to add.
Speaker 1: - But in the world of board gaming, there is a huge to-do.
Speaker 0: - So, you know, Wil Wheaton's show, TableTop, which, to be honest, is kind of shitty.
Speaker 1: - Well, it's also kind of a big deal, despite being kind of shitty.
Speaker 1: The production value is high, and it has semi, you know, the famous nerds, famous among nerds people are on there, promoting TableTop games.
Speaker 0: - And it's a show where they play TableTop games together.
Speaker 0: Like, that's a perfect storm of awesome, right?
Speaker 1: - The target audience is people who aren't super into, who are nerdy, but maybe aren't into super TableTop games as much, right?
Speaker 1: It's not for competitive board gaming.
Speaker 1: It's not for us, right?
Speaker 1: It's for people who don't know about TableTop games, or maybe you're only into them a little bit, 'cause they're kind of nerdy.
Speaker 0: - Like, oh, I heard there's a game where you can have, like, skeletons running around.
Speaker 1: - Right, you're in the nerd community, you know who these people are, you maybe played Settlers once or twice, and now these people are gonna introduce you to all kinds of good, you know, other games, and, you know, that's not a bad, you know, it's a good thing for that to exist, and for those people to want to promote TableTop games with, like, no relatively little compensation for doing so, simply because they want to promote TableTop gaming as a thing, that's good.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, however, the problem is, which isn't the biggest problem in the world in and of itself, but they pretty much always get the rules wrong.
Speaker 1: - Well, specifically, they got the rules wrong, like, a little bit the first season.
Speaker 1: I think in the first season, they were playing games that, like, they knew and loved, so they knew the rules better, - But even then, like, they were still making some mistakes.
Speaker 1: - Yes, they were still making mistakes, and season two, which is the one that they kickstarted, which means that people paid for it, they got the rules wrong a lot, and in the Kingdom Builders episode, they got it way wrong, like, big time wrong.
Speaker 0: - Now, that could've been the news in and of itself, like, that could've been us doing our typical, like, the grognard, like, ugh, this movie is about hacking, and then it's cool kids skateboarding.
Speaker 1: - I wouldn't have even known about this if it weren't for the Streisand effect of Wil Wheaton coming out and saying something about this.
Speaker 0: - Now, I'm gonna quote Wil Wheaton, I'm gonna paraphrase what he said right now.
Speaker 0: I'm actually a dick, and I'm throwing my friend under a bus.
Speaker 1: - Right, so, A, he admitted that they fucked up the rules, which is good, he at least said that he's taking responsibility, which is, I guess, correct, you should say that, to, well, whatever, I'm not gonna number this.
Speaker 1: He said that, yes, it's a problem that they got the rules wrong, and it's an even bigger problem, because he messed up these episodes that people paid for that were Kickstarted, right?
Speaker 1: So, he recognized that that was bad, and that he's gonna fix it if they ever make any more, which is good, but most of the post he made, he was pretty much blaming it on this one producer, and he basically says, yeah, I gave this one producer the job of learning the rules to all the games, and that producer fucked it up, you know, I trusted them, they messed it up.
Speaker 1: It's like, whoa, you just said you're taking responsibility, you can't say you take responsibility in the same paragraph that you blame someone else, that's not how that works.
Speaker 1: I can't say, yes, I take full responsibility for Rym totally fucking up and breaking this whole podcast.
Speaker 1: (laughing) I mean, you said the word's taking responsibility, but you didn't actually do it.
Speaker 0: - Now, there's definitely a, like, Wheaton's Law is extra--
Speaker 1: - It's funny that it's called Wheaton's Law, don't be a dick, because here he is being a dick, and there are many people now who are coming out with their stories of him being a dick, perhaps it should be called Wheaton's Law because he's a dick, and not because you shouldn't be like him, as opposed to you should be like him.
Speaker 0: - I am often a dick, I can tell, like, too often.
Speaker 1: - I'm not claiming to obey Wheaton's Law, but Wheaton's Law isn't Scott's Law, is it?
Speaker 0: - Exactly.
Speaker 1: (laughing) - It isn't Scott's Law.
Speaker 0: - Rym's Law is be a dick a lot of the time.
Speaker 1: - Be a dick to the race-walking person who deserves it.
Speaker 0: - Oh my God, that race-walker is so funny.
Speaker 1: - So anyway, but there's a broader issue here, - There's a lot of issues that you can get out of this post.
Speaker 0: - So let's back up first to the broader issue, because one of the, we don't know if we're doing this lecture at PAX Prime, but we have a new lecture we've been working on called Learning Games, because this problem, pretend this wasn't tabletop, pretend this was a guy and a bunch of his friends played a game, and then they realized they got the rules wrong.
Speaker 1: - Happens all the goddamn time.
Speaker 0: - Oh, it happens to us, and we're pro, like, we're pros at this.
Speaker 1: - We're as pro as you can be.
Speaker 0: - And we've, like, we fucked.
Speaker 1: up--.
Speaker 1: - As anyone can expect.
Speaker 0: - We fucked up the rules to Amun-Re for over a year, and then we corrected them, we found out, like, a couple months later, we were still fucking 'em up.
Speaker 0: So this happens to everyone, but it's endemic in tabletop gaming, because it's always the same story.
Speaker 0: Nobody wants to learn the rules to a new game.
Speaker 1: - Nobody wants to read the rules, 'cause it sucks.
Speaker 1: B, the people who write the rules fuck up at writing them.
Speaker 1: C, people, even if they do read the rules, fuck up at reading them.
Speaker 0: - And then four, nobody questions the rules effectively in the course of learning or playing the game.
Speaker 1: - If you learn the rules from someone else, 'cause you're the vast majority of people who doesn't wanna read the rules, you just send someone to teach you the game, right?
Speaker 1: He just wants this producer to read the rules and teach it to him.
Speaker 1: You can 100% trust that that person is telling you everything correctly, and any mistake they make is now passed on to a whole bunch more people, and then mistakes, specifically in tabletop games, rules mistakes spread like wildfire.
Speaker 0: - So our entire friend group-- -
Speaker 1: And one person reads a rule book, and 100 people learn it by word of mouth, because apparently they wanna go back to the Stone Age, where you can only pass stories down verbally through oral tradition, and not through the magic of written
Speaker 0: text.
Speaker 0: - If you didn't go for writing, and you went for horses instead, then maybe I could understand that.
Speaker 1: - Well, I mean, yeah.
Speaker 1: - Oral tradition-- - If there's horses in your starting area next to your settler, why would you build writing first?
Speaker 1: Are you fucking stupid?
Speaker 1: You can just steal the stone tablets from Gandhi next to you.
Speaker 1: He's got 'em.
Speaker 1: If you got a horse, his elephant ain't gonna catch up to you.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, but, so, here's an example of that.
Speaker 0: Glory to Rome, kind of a complex game to learn, because it doesn't follow a lot of typical patterns of games.
Speaker 0: - Our entire friend group, except us, found the game, and a few of our friends found it first, taught everyone but us.
Speaker 0: Then we played it.
Speaker 0: We're like, "Oh, this is a pretty good
Speaker 0: game.".
Speaker 0: And then after we played it once, I bought it, and I immediately took the rules and wrote 'em cover to cover.
Speaker 1: I went back to our friend-- - Something that most people do not do.
Speaker 1: They'll buy a board game and throw the rules out.
Speaker 0: - And then I could probably find the forum post where I told all our friends, "Guys, you've been playing this game 100% wrong.
Speaker 0: "What the
Speaker 0: fuck?".
Speaker 1: - Yep.
Speaker 0: - So, the problem, and this is, we see it in D&D, too, in a different sense, of once someone's the dungeon master, they're the dungeon master forever, but every gaming group in tabletop has the rules, bitch.
Speaker 0: The person who actually knows the rules to all the games and ends up having this annoying duty of every game you play ends up being a teaching game where you are 100% responsible, because if I teach a bunch of people at a table at a con a game, and I mess up a rule, I ruin the experience for them, and they're gonna blame me for their bad experience.
Speaker 1: - Right, well, if someone teaches me a game, I always ask for the rule book and start checking what they're saying, right?
Speaker 1: Always, me or Rym, you'll see, whenever anyone teaches our group a game, either me or Rym will have the instruction book.
Speaker 0: - One of us is listening.
Speaker 1: - 'Cause no one else can be trusted.
Speaker 1: - One of us is listening, one of us is reading, and even-- - And even if Rym is doing the reading, I'm basically constantly like, "Hey, Rym, check that.
Speaker 1: "Hey, Rym, is this
Speaker 1: right?".
Speaker 1: I'm asking him the questions, 'cause he's got the rule book.
Speaker 1: I'm not asking the questions of the person teaching the game.
Speaker 0: - Yep.
Speaker 1: - I'm asking Rym, holding the rule book, "Hey, check on this.
Speaker 1: "Hey, what if this
Speaker 1: happens?".
Speaker 0: - There is an easy solution, but it involves any way.
Speaker 0: If you care about tabletop games, it's--.
Speaker 1: - Right, so that's the obvious question that comes up.
Speaker 1: It's like, Wil Wheaton and other people on tabletop and all board gamers in general.
Speaker 1: If you like board games so much, why don't you like reading the rules?
Speaker 0: - Now, maybe we answered that question before.
Speaker 0: Board games today, especially American board games, and especially, especially Kickstarted board games, have the worst written rules.
Speaker 1: - Even Netrunner, the game that I play more than any other game, has so many rules-writing problems on the cards, it is like the number one problem with that game.
Speaker 1: It is heinous.
Speaker 1: A guy came, here's a story, right?
Speaker 1: This guy comes to the Netrunner meetup.
Speaker 1: He had been playing Netrunner alone.
Speaker 1: You know, we're with his friend, I guess, right?
Speaker 1: He hadn't really played with people in the public anymore.
Speaker 1: - He hadn't been to tournaments or anything like that.
Speaker 1: You know, he works in New York Public Library.
Speaker 1: He was a totally cool dude.
Speaker 1: He comes to our Netrunner meetup.
Speaker 1: He's like, "Hey, I found your meetup.
Speaker 1: "Wanna play some
Speaker 1: Netrunner?".
Speaker 1: I'm like, "That is the best thing ever.
Speaker 1: "Come and play Netrunner with
Speaker 1: me.".
Speaker 1: So I played Netrunner with him.
Speaker 1: And then he puts a card on another card, and immediately I see he's trying to do something very clever, very clever indeed.
Speaker 1: And if it had worked and was not against the rules, it would have been quite strong.
Speaker 1: However, I also immediately recognized, oh crap, that if you read the text on those two cards, the way they interact, any reasonable human being with a grasp of the English language would assume that the thing that he was doing would be a perfectly acceptable and legal play.
Speaker 1: But me, because I am engaged in the online community and the competitive community, and I read the FAQ and I read Twitter and I read all these things, knew that the thing that he was about to do was against the rules.
Speaker 1: And I was like, I was basically apologizing to him.
Speaker 1: Like, it was like I was the bad guy for in giving him the bad news.
Speaker 1: That like, sorry, that doesn't work.
Speaker 1: And your entire deck concept doesn't work because you got the rule wrong.
Speaker 1: It's the people who make the games fall.
Speaker 1: But imagine if-- - They suck that badly.
Speaker 0: - But think about the people who don't read the rule books and talk to other people in these situations where the rule books are not great.
Speaker 0: Then, and we run into this often, especially when we play Kickstarted games, where two intelligent humans will read a rule book cover to cover who understand games and disagree about how the game works.
Speaker 0: And unless there's a canonical answer, like the game designer says this is the way, the game is fucked.
Speaker 1: - Go back and listen to our ancient review of Hellas.
Speaker 0: - Oh my God.
Speaker 1: - The game with the rules that were not answered on BoardGameGeek in a proper fashion.
Speaker 1: So even though we shouldn't, you should never have to go online 'cause apparently like most people don't.
Speaker 1: Like the guy at the Netrunner meetup, he didn't go online to find the rules.
Speaker 1: He only checked the fact after I said something to him and then discovered that I was right.
Speaker 0: - Now it's not like this is impossible, especially like German games that were released, like Puerto Rico, Tigris, New Freighties.
Speaker 0: Like there was a bunch of games that came out within a span of time that they basically are written as best you can write rules.
Speaker 0: They should be like an RFC.
Speaker 0: Rules should be very explicit and very clear in their language.
Speaker 1: - There should be no ambiguity whatsoever.
Speaker 0: - May not do this, must do this, after doing this.
Speaker 1: - And there should be no scenario or combination, there should be no game state which is unexplained or undefined, right?
Speaker 1: Unlike say the C programming language, there are certain undefined states.
Speaker 0: - What does that lead to?
Speaker 1: - For a board game there should be none.
Speaker 0: - That leads to an exception and then a crash?
Speaker 0: Like board games can crash.
Speaker 0: Hellas crashed and we had to stop playing.
Speaker 0: Well we did a stack, I used to try to figure out.
Speaker 1: - So there's a lot, there's so much going on in this news, we can make it the only news, right?
Speaker 1: Why do people not want to read rule books?
Speaker 1: Why are people bad at reading rule books?
Speaker 1: Why are they bad at writing them?
Speaker 0: - So if we do that panel of facts.
Speaker 1: - Why is Will Wheaton a dick?
Speaker 1: It's like there's so much going on here.
Speaker 0: - So another aspect of it is that in terms of people teaching games or wanting to play games, we found this phenomenon a lot, even with a lot of our friends.
Speaker 0: We know people who love board games and will play the fuck out of them.
Speaker 1: - The storm is here.
Speaker 0: - But there's a huge thunderstorm going on.
Speaker 1: - It went from nothing to shh in about a fraction of a minute.
Speaker 0: - So on Sunday, right, me and Emily are out biking.
Speaker 0: We're gonna go to Radagast and have salsa's dinner.
Speaker 0: And it's sunny and clear, and then in the distance we see this thin thunderstorm.
Speaker 0: So we're like okay, so we're biking, biking, biking.
Speaker 0: And then suddenly Emily says, "Is that a wall of rain fast approaching
Speaker 0: us?".
Speaker 0: And sure enough, there is a wall of rain, thick to the point that buildings were disappearing in front of us.
Speaker 0: It was like a magic spell coming to our doom.
Speaker 0: It hit us like a brick, it was amazing.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so clearly forgot my tan, whatever.
Speaker 0: All right, so people don't like the process of learning games, but some-- - People don't like to learn.
Speaker 1: People try to avoid learning.
Speaker 1: That's why they don't use VIM.
Speaker 1: They don't want to learn something, even though it's better once you learn it.
Speaker 0: - And part of that, I think, is that most people who teach games-- - They're anti-intellectual if you don't like learning.
Speaker 0: - Even if, let's say it's like us.
Speaker 1: We learn the games, so we take the time-- - I don't want to bike with gears, then have to learn how to use them.
Speaker 0: - But we learn the games,
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 0: we teach the games, even though I don't necessarily want to be, because I know that if I teach someone, and they learn the game from me, they're gonna play it right, unless it's Amun-Re, and then it'll be good, and I just kind of spread the right, you know, there's a lot of reasons why I do this.
Speaker 0: The same reason your friend who hates DMing is always your dungeon master.
Speaker 1: - 'Cause it'll be a shitty game if you do it.
Speaker 0: - But most people teaching board games do a terrible job of it, even if they do know the rules.
Speaker 0: So there's a whole separate discussion, even beyond everything, of how do you teach rules?
Speaker 1: - You're bad at teaching, bad at reading, bad at writing, bad at everything having to do with the rules.
Speaker 0: - Actually, I was on a panel at PAX last year with, I think, Donna Prior and Luke Crane, everyone were talking about that, and some people, you know, like learning, people learn different ways.
Speaker 0: Some people learn better, where you play the game one, say, look, this is a teaching game, we'll just play, I'll explain each rule as it comes up, but then everyone has to understand that, yeah, because you didn't learn the game fully before you played it, your strategy might literally ruin you, and you have to expect the fact that you're gonna lose horribly.
Speaker 0: A lot of people--.
Speaker 1: - Luke Crane should not be talking about writing rules properly, 'cause he'll put the same rule in his book three different places.
Speaker 0: - He's slightly so in every play.
Speaker 1: - Crook's slightly slow each time, worded a slightly different way.
Speaker 1: - The biggest ambiguity
Speaker 0: in his rules that bothers me a lot is, there's a situation in Dwarven Greed that says one thing that leaves an ambiguity, most people interpret that ambiguity one way, then gives an example that gives a categorical number for the thing that was ambiguous, that is the opposite of what most people interpret the rule to be, 'cause they forget about that sentence.
Speaker 0: that was an example.
Speaker 0: But I digress, I love you, Luke.
Speaker 0: - If you wanna hire me, I'll rewrite Burning Reel, I'll edit Burning Reel's rules.
Speaker 1: - We'll hate it, 'cause we'll put Oxford Commas in.
Speaker 0: - I would be willing to leave the Oxford Comma out, however it would double my fee, because there's some suffering that would go on.
Speaker 0: That would be, that's hard, that's a very difficult thing you ask of me.
Speaker 0: So outside of all that, tabletop is a great idea for a show, but no one's making it except these guys.
Speaker 1: - Well, production value's very high, and they have famous people.
Speaker 1: - They do.
Speaker 1: - I feel like without the famous people, it doesn't work, because then how do you attract in the nerds who aren't into tabletops a whole bunch already?
Speaker 0: - Yep, well the problem is, if you make the show that is more for the tabletop people, who are good at and care about tabletop, those people are already in, so you're not really getting them into more.
Speaker 1: - Right, it's a different audience, that would be, you know.
Speaker 0: - That audience is more like, I'm gonna watch a bunch of people be funny, and I'm gonna learn this game.
Speaker 1: - Right, the only way to do it without famous people would be to have people who are just really likable characters, either acting or actually likable people, so that people could identify with them and, you know.
Speaker 0: - So why don't we write the show, and we'll get Dave and Joel to play us in the show.
Speaker 1: - Let's not do this.
Speaker 0: - But I was thinking about this a lot, and I kinda wanna like, you know, I don't wanna do the whole production value thing, but I feel like we could just do two player games, so Scott and I have enough equipment to fully deck that out with pretty high production values, if it's only two players, and I feel like we should just try to make this show with a slightly different format, 'cause I realized the format that they need to avoid.
Speaker 0: this rules problem is one, everyone in the show is gonna have to read all the rules, or have a rules coach or something.
Speaker 1: - Right, so that's the other thing I wanted to talk about, the last thing I wanted to talk about that I didn't, right, where the solutions to this problem, it's like, whoa, okay, so you didn't wanna read the rules.
Speaker 1: First of all, you should read the rules.
Speaker 1: Second of all, you had this one producer read the rules for you, the person you threw under the bus.
Speaker 0: - Nobody else at any point.
Speaker 1: - It's like, if I'm doing a show, and I'm a big, they're a big fucking deal, right, you know, famous, famous people.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, Wil Wheaton could've asked--.
Speaker 1: - You could get the designer of the game to come when you record, you can get a representative from the publisher of the game to come when you record the show, you can go on BoardGameGeek and find a nerd who lives locally, and even if that nerd is not suitable for television, you could have that nerd consult from off-screen, and who's an expert at the game, you have me playing, and I guarantee that rules layer nerd, they will make sure that you get every rule correct, Mr.
Speaker 1: Wheaton, no, no, no, you can't roll that dice over there, that's not the time yet.
Speaker 0: - In fact, you make it a shtick, like Pee-wee's Playhouse, where someone's about to make a wrong move, and aah!
Speaker 1: - Well, you don't even need, you can just edit that part out, you don't even need to see the nerd.
Speaker 1: Finally, you could have just somebody watch your episode before you upload it and make it public on YouTube, 'cause it's a, it's not a live show, not live at all, and they could say, hey, you got these rules wrong here, and then you could put notes in the episode, or edit the episode to conceal the parts where you got the rules wrong.
Speaker 0: - Even the notes would be fine, in fact-- - You could tug over it and get the rules right.
Speaker 0: - The format I would use is actually a little more subtle.
Speaker 0: I'd have the teaching section that I could upload separately, that's also part of the episode, where it's like, the gaming group that's in the show, learning the game, like being taught it, however that is.
Speaker 0: And then the part of the show, or the show, like part two, where they're playing it, maybe someone starts to mess up a rule, and that's part of the interaction, like oh, Scott, you're fucking that up, right there.
Speaker 0: - Maybe.
Speaker 0: - Or, oh guys, we messed this up, because shows like this also, by plowing through and ignoring rules ambiguities, because when normal gamers play a game, there's always that moment where someone-- - Everyone stops, you gotta check the rules, and we're all sitting around going, eh.
Speaker 0: - Or, you're all playing, and Scott's doing his turn, and then I just say, hey, Pete, can I see the rule book?
Speaker 0: And Scott's like, why do you wanna see the rule book?
Speaker 0: I'm like, I just wanna see the rule book.
Speaker 0: I just wanna look at something.
Speaker 0: Keep taking your turn, I'm just looking.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, no, no, you can't attack me in Umbria.
Speaker 1: - Ha ha, actually I can't.
Speaker 1: You can't stop me.
Speaker 0: - But make that part of the show, either script it, like if there's a commonly messed up rule, you script it where Felicia or someone messes up that part of the rule, and then you guys fix it in game.
Speaker 0: There are some games, like Puerto Rico has a rule, where if you fuck up the ship, there's a rule for what to do.
Speaker 0: In Fury of Dracula, if you fuck up Dracula, there's a rule you follow to fix it.
Speaker 0: Like, make that part of the show, 'cause the reality is, rules fuck up.
Speaker 1: - That's what actual tabletop gaming is like when you're playing a game for the first time.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, or even, you know, four years after you start playing a game, even when you're a pro, Amun-Re.
Speaker 0: If any of you are playing Amun-Re, let me know, and I'll make sure, 'cause I'll bet you're messing these rules up, too.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, make sure you give the gods the correct sacrifice.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, ha ha ha, you don't get goodies from the gods if you also steal from the temple, and the extra farmers can go fucking anywhere.
Speaker 0: Anywhere.
Speaker 1: - Even where there isn't a farm, they can go in, what's the place with no farms, Dokla?
Speaker 0: - Dokla.
Speaker 1: - They can go to Dokla.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, suddenly Dokla's pretty awesome, if you got three of those things in your hand, bam, bam, bam, yeah, anyway.
Speaker 0: Well, one per turn.
Speaker 1: - That's fine.
Speaker 0: - There's a couple other rules that we also, but anyway.
Speaker 0: So yeah, people should try to make the show better, maybe, or we'll just, I don't know, this is really easy for you to fix for your show, and--.
Speaker 1: - If you ever make any more.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, but you kinda--.
Speaker 1: - Also, I'm surprised to find out their show wasn't publisher game developer sponsored, like they were just picking games they wanted and being funded by Kickstarter money.
Speaker 1: Hey, game publishers, send us a copy of your game, and also some money, and I will produce a show playing your game, but my review will be 100% honest, if your game is garbage, I'm gonna say so, so deal with it.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, we'll even do a whole tabletop-y kind of episode thing.
Speaker 1: - If you want me to say your game is amazing, no matter even how garbage it is, - Give us enough to retire.
Speaker 1: - Give me enough money to go to the beach, and not come back.
Speaker 0: - So we're here in Monaco on our eighth week of vacation playing Munchkin now.
Speaker 1: - Why would I be playing Munchkin, watching the Grand Prix from our yacht?
Speaker 0: - Is the Grand Prix of games, I highly recommend it, just like I recommend this caviar as a champagne.
Speaker 1: - Yes, if you see, whoa, Kimi's coming out the tunnel.
Speaker 1: What level are you in the Munchkin, I don't know, three, whatever.
Speaker 0: - So yeah, there's a lot more to be said, but most of it will involve, hopefully will be us in a panel at either PAX or somewhere else, if we decide to do this one instead of the other one, on sports.
Speaker 0: Things of the Day.
Speaker 0: This is a YouTube video that, it asks a question where the answer is not obvious.
Speaker 1: - I don't know the answer yet.
Speaker 0: - And you might even think, oh duh, but then when you think about it, it doesn't make sense, and then it goes beyond that, so the question is, and it's a Vsauce episode, these guys are good, why do we have two nostrils as opposed to one big one?
Speaker 1: - Right, wouldn't there at some point in the history of genetics, there would have been some genetic variation to where some creature had one nostril, and why did that one nostril creature somehow have a disadvantage at life and surviving, compared to the two nostril creatures?
Speaker 1: that resulted in every creature that has a nose having two nostrils?
Speaker 0: - Now the guess I had was it's like a screen door to keep bigger things from getting into it, like a big bug.
Speaker 1: - No, that's what the hairs are for.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, but also I get this one line down the middle.
Speaker 0: Two, I wondered if it was something around the nose, like if something covers your face and blocks it up, because you got the little ridge that kind of sticks out past the players.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, maybe if it's stuck in one nostril, you can survive with the other one.
Speaker 0: - Yep, but the answer is not what you think.
Speaker 0: And then it answers another question that you probably didn't realize you had until just now.
Speaker 0: You ever notice how sometimes one of your nostrils seems like it's way more open and flowing than the other one?
Speaker 0: - Yes.
Speaker 0: - That's all the time.
Speaker 0: You always have one primary or fast, and one secondary or slow nostril, and your body shifts stuff to change which one it is at different times during the day.
Speaker 1: - Fucking body, why don't you just keep both of them fast all the time?
Speaker 0: - Yeah, you know what, the answer to that is kind of amazing.
Speaker 1: - I should just get a surgery to make that happen.
Speaker 0: - No, you'd be fucked if that happened.
Speaker 0: - Why?
Speaker 0: - Because you wouldn't be able to smell some things anymore.
Speaker 0: The slow nostril smells different things from the fast nostril.
Speaker 0: - What the fuck?
Speaker 0: - This video blew my mind in nine minutes and 22 seconds, so I now know why we have two nostrils.
Speaker 0: - Are you sure this is true?
Speaker 0: - Yes, actually.
Speaker 1: - This YouTube video can be trusted.
Speaker 0: - So right now, my left one's slow and my right one's fast.
Speaker 1: - Same.
Speaker 0: - Yep.
Speaker 0: This video was amazing.
Speaker 0: Also, Vsauce is amazing, so you should just follow them.
Speaker 1: - All right, so I was gonna use another thing of the day, but there was this better thing of the day, so the other one's gonna wait.
Speaker 1: So I'm sure maybe some people have seen this, but I've seen a lot of the old, original Japanese TV commercials for Famicom games that were made back in the day, like the live-action Zelda one and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Apparently, there was a TV commercial for Mother, also known as the original Earthbound, right?
Speaker 1: 'Cause Earthbound was Mother 2 for the SNES.
Speaker 1: This is Earthbound for the NES, or Mother for the NES.
Speaker 1: The original TV commercial in Japan.
Speaker 1: Oh my God, this commercial.
Speaker 1: It's short, but holy shit, that's a fucking commercial right there.
Speaker 0: - I know that it is perfectly accurate to the game despite displaying no gameplay footage whatsoever.
Speaker 1: - It's like, any game that had that commercial, how could you not buy?
Speaker 1: How could you not buy?
Speaker 0: - It would be interesting.
Speaker 0: 3D model the actors in that, and then make a remake of the game where it just looks like that the whole time.
Speaker 1: - You don't need that.
Speaker 0: - That would be, anyway.
Speaker 0: This commercial is pretty amazing.
Speaker 0: - Yeah.
Speaker 0: - In the meantime, the book is the first of all those Wheel of Time books, which I actually, I'm like 12 chapters in now.
Speaker 1: - All right, you're about as far as me.
Speaker 0: - They made it over the river.
Speaker 1: - Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: - The big river.
Speaker 0: In the ferry, did you get the ferry boat?
Speaker 0: Am I already past you?
Speaker 1: - Maybe.
Speaker 0: - Did a dragon thing attack them?
Speaker 1: - A dragon thing.
Speaker 1: No, troll dudes.
Speaker 0: - Did they, yeah, which time?
Speaker 1: - They burned the village down.
Speaker 0: - Okay, I'm quite a bit past that.
Speaker 1: - I haven't read it in a while 'cause I've been busy.
Speaker 0: - The village is a distant memory, and they just fucked some--.
Speaker 1: - I'm at the part where they're about to leave the village.
Speaker 0: - Okay, they are long past the village.
Speaker 1: - I figured that's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: - Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: - It's a fantasy novel?
Speaker 0: - It's a fantasy novel.
Speaker 1: - Isn't that what I said?
Speaker 0: - It's exactly what you said, and now when I was trying to prod you for more, but I don't know what else I could say.
Speaker 0: It's a fantasy novel.
Speaker 1: - It's a fantasy novel.
Speaker 0: - What I find interesting is that it has the same pace as Dumas in The Count of Monte Cristo.
Speaker 0: In that, the action, the writing, the words, things that happen per page is constant, and it never zooms out, it never zooms in, it never speeds up, it never slows down, it never fucking skips anything.
Speaker 1: - That's true.
Speaker 0: - And I'm not saying that's bad.
Speaker 1: - Mr.
Speaker 1: Dumas lover over there.
Speaker 0: - Nor am I saying that's good, but this is a fantasy novel.
Speaker 1: - This is a fantasy novel.
Speaker 0: - And it is better than most fantasy novels.
Speaker 0: I will already give it that.
Speaker 1: - Well, you don't get to be ultra famous with being complete garbage.
Speaker 1: -
Speaker 0: I'm starting to see why some of our friends who were really into these books when they were younger are the way they are today, if this was their formative fantasy book, and why I'm the way I am today, 'cause my formative fantasy after Lord of the Rings Hobbit
Speaker 1: was
Speaker 0: pretty much all the like Elphie, Elphie, forgotten
Speaker 1: of Adams.
Speaker 1: - Of all the nerd media someone consumes, the fantasy novels they consume, define them the most?
Speaker 0: - In terms of their fantasy and role-playing tastes, I think.
Speaker 0: I'll bet you could predict what classes people play in D&D when they're in their 20s, based on the first 10 fantasy books they read.
Speaker 0: That would be a study I would like to see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, otherwise, we uploaded a ton of videos of stuff that I'll link to, our bad games panel is up on YouTube, and very, very soon, I will have uploaded, remember we did that walkthrough, like PAX Prime Expo Hall Live as an experiment, and it was pretty good.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, people seem to like it from whatever it is.
Speaker 0: - Like we fucked up a bunch of stuff, 'cause we just kinda made it and it was fine, so this is our second attempt from PAX South, because that's how far behind I am in video, but it's not twice as good as that old one, so continuous improvement.
Speaker 0: Scott's got video of the Netrunner Championships he was just at.
Speaker 1: - Yep.
Speaker 0: - And otherwise, we're gonna be at Kineticon in a few weeks, in Hartford, Connecticut.
Speaker 1: - Very soon.
Speaker 1: - And like we've said-- - If you are a nerdy person of any kind, which you are, 'cause you're listening to this, if you are within driving distance of Hartford, Connecticut, you should be at Kineticon.
Speaker 1: If you're farther away, maybe not worth it unless you're really rich and got nothing better to do.
Speaker 0: - Like I would say, we'll fly to PAX Australia and PAX South from here, you don't necessarily need to do all those same things.
Speaker 1: if I can go to the coral reef this time.
Speaker 0: - Nah, maybe we'll take turns, maybe I'll skip it, you go to this one, and then Geek Nights has been to every PAX since 2008.
Speaker 1: - Go to the coral reef without you.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, 'cause the worst thing is, - You wanna buy me an underwater camera thingy or just bring GoPro?
Speaker 1: - If I went to the coral reef, I'd probably buy the newer, I'm waiting, the new GoPro should be out later this year, I guess it'll be GoPro 5?
Speaker 0: - Yeah, I'm glad I held out, 'cause I haven't used mine that much except skiing, really.
Speaker 1: - I used mine for biking, but yeah, I mean, the one I have now only does 1080p 30, the current one I think does 4K 30.
Speaker 0: - It does some crazy shit, the thing is, forget the 4K, you wanna--.
Speaker 1: - The newer ones gotta do 4K 60, right?
Speaker 0: - No, you stay down at like the 720 and 180p, but then you have the ridiculous frame rate.
Speaker 1: - You don't need the ridiculous frame rate.
Speaker 0: - For skiing, ridiculous frame rate.
Speaker 1: - That means you can do the slow-mos, but I don't need the ridiculous frame rate for the fishies.
Speaker 0: - No, not for the fishies.
Speaker 1: - I wanna see the fishies in 4K.
Speaker 0: - Huh?
Speaker 0: Yeah, for the fishies, I'd use the 4K.
Speaker 0: - 4K fishies, anyway.
Speaker 0: - Plus high frame rate, low light, anyway.
Speaker 1: - Okay, so, during the Steam sale which just happened, there were many games available, and one of them was Wolfenstein, The New Order, also Wolfenstein The Old Blood, which I guess is some sort of extra game.
Speaker 1: They're basically newer, I guess, remakes of, not remakes at all, actually, just new Wolfenstein games, 'cause it is the original Wolfenstein, the 2D, then there's Wolfenstein-- - Which was made before we were born.
Speaker 1: - Then there's Wolfenstein 3D, the real first Wolfenstein, you know.
Speaker 1: Brian Lavin, that one, right?
Speaker 1: Then there was those ones sorta in the Quake III era, that I think they were actually using the Quake III engine, and no, I didn't really care about those at all.
Speaker 1: And now there's these new ones, and I was just sorta in the mood for a single-player FPS.
Speaker 1: I just wanna walk around, shoot guys, whatevs.
Speaker 1: Hey, Wolfenstein, I like Wolfenstein 3D.
Speaker 1: I wonder how much Wolfenstein is in this Wolfenstein.
Speaker 1: And I can tell you there's a lot more Wolfenstein in it than there was in those Quake III era ones.
Speaker 1: But basically, it's a single-player FPS, and it's super, triple-A, generic in terms of its structure, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, do some stuff, watch an FMV, do some stuff, watch an FMV, plot, plot, plot, shoot, shoot, shoot.
Speaker 1: The shooting isn't that particularly exciting, right?
Speaker 1: It's not like there's anything special about the shooting part.
Speaker 0: - So what game is it most like?
Speaker 0: 'Cause honestly, the last triple-A-- - Every FPS that's genero.
Speaker 0: - So iron sights?
Speaker 1: - Uh, sort of, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, some of the weapons have different sights, but yeah, I mean, usually you'll, it's not, it's like, when you right-click to, 'cause I love default controls, you right-click to aim.
Speaker 1: If the gun has iron sights, the gun will come up, but it's right in the middle of the screen.
Speaker 1: So it's not like, it's not like, you know, it's not like, you know, the iron sight part matters, really, plus when you're not, when you don't have, when you're not holding the gun up to aim, there's on-screen sights.
Speaker 1: It's not only iron sights.
Speaker 1: There's, you know, it's like Counter-Strike.
Speaker 0: - So I'm not gonna lie, the last single-player, triple-A, first-person game that I played all the way through was Deus Ex Human Revolution.
Speaker 1: - So Deus Ex, I wasn't into that game.
Speaker 0: - I'm super into that game.
Speaker 1: - But I can tell you the shooting part of that game is a million times superior to the shooting part of the Wolfenstein game, 'cause it wasn't genero.
Speaker 1: You could actually do stuff in that.
Speaker 1: You know, you had different aspects of shooting it.
Speaker 1: This is just literally, walk around, shoot some guys.
Speaker 1: I beat every area using my basic strategy, which is find cover, hide behind that cover, picking guys off until there are no more guys, move only when there are no more guys, go and find the remaining guys if there are any and eliminate them, and I did that every single part of the game, and it worked.
Speaker 0: - Huh, it's kind of a shame.
Speaker 0: Was there any, like, tactics to the shooting, or was it just--?
Speaker 1: - No, the shooting was the most boring.
Speaker 1: I mean, it was like, I got what I wanted, which was go around shooting guys, but there was nothing particularly exciting about the shooting part, other than you could, if a grenade was thrown at you, if you could aim at the grenade and push E, you could throw the grenade back, which is kind of cool.
Speaker 1: That was like their clever mechanic, or just throw a grenade back.
Speaker 1: You could do some stealthiness if you wanted.
Speaker 1: It was kind of easy to do.
Speaker 1: You know, you can get up behind a guy and middle click to sort of kill him with a knife quietly, or use the silenced pistol to kill a guy quietly, and there were certain areas where, clearly they wanted you to do that, and you could do it, you know, to get away with progressing a little more quickly instead of, you know, attracting the attention of every Nazi in the area.
Speaker 0: - Nah.
Speaker 0: So in terms of, 'cause like, Wolfenstein 3D, like, when I think of Wolfenstein, I always think about, it's Explorer Maze, and the shooting and everything is kind of ancillary.
Speaker 1: - So, the shooting wasn't ancillary in this one, but there were a lot, you know, they really did try to make it a lot like Wolfenstein 3D in ways such as there are a lot of secrets to find, right?
Speaker 1: You can really go through every area looking for secrets, and secret areas, and all that kind of stuff, just like the original Wolfenstein 3D, and that part, I like that part, because some of the secrets are pretty well hidden, you know, vents, and things you could destroy, and, you know, a little bit of platforming, a little bit of pushing here and there.
Speaker 0: - I don't know, it's hard to sell me on vent-based gameplay.
Speaker 0: if I played Deus Ex, 'cause Deus Ex is the vent game.
Speaker 1: - This, I mean, this has the same amount of vents that, you know, an FPS is expected to have.
Speaker 0: - Okay, it's not like the Deus Ex of like, there is guaranteed to be a vent everywhere.
Speaker 1: - No, no, no, no.
Speaker 1: Not at all.
Speaker 1: You know, but it wasn't very maze-like.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much go, you know, figure out how to get to the next area, right?
Speaker 1: Kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: It wasn't, you didn't have to like, you know, search.
Speaker 1: But I guess Wolfenstein 3D, even though it was a maze, we sort of were just sort of also going ahead, right?
Speaker 1: Get the key, open the door, go to the next area, whatnot.
Speaker 1: So, whatever.
Speaker 1: The things that stood about this game were, the plot is, the plot had some positive aspects, but was mostly a ridiculous stereotypical triple-A game plot that was so groan-inducing.
Speaker 0: - Oh, no.
Speaker 1: - Right?
Speaker 1: So, you have the good parts of the plot where that.
Speaker 1: basically, it tries to explain the ridiculousness that was present in Wolfenstein 3D.
Speaker 1: Like, why are people holding, why is there a ridiculous Nazi in like, a robot suit?
Speaker 1: And why are there ridiculous Nazi Frankenstein?
Speaker 0: - No, no, in a way, that sort of retcon, like, Adventure Time does that.
Speaker 0: Like, hey, what was the deal with that thing way back in season one?
Speaker 1: - Right, so basically, the story here is basically the story of Captain America.
Speaker 1: B.J.
Speaker 1: Blazkowicz.
Speaker 0: (laughing) - I faked my dude.
Speaker 0: - He basically-- - Oh, he has his own Wikipedia article.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, he takes some damage, basically, and is holed up in an asylum for a long-ass time, from the '40s all the way to the '60s.
Speaker 1: And then in the '60s, the Nazis come and shut down the asylum, and he wakes up from his vegetative state, and is B.J.
Speaker 1: Blazkowicz again.
Speaker 1: But the Nazis have won, and they have all sorts of ridiculous technologies, including, I'm gonna spoil the fuck out of this, 'cause who gives a shit, right?
Speaker 0: - Yep, so that's fine.
Speaker 1: - Including Nazi moon base that you go to in one of the last levels.
Speaker 0: - That's kind of expected.
Speaker 1: - And after he escapes, at the beginning of the game, the plot is actually sort of reasonable, and based in, you know-- -
Speaker 0: They should've made it on Mars, and then they could've made it be a UAC facility, and then it turns out that UAC was just a Nazi science program, and linked it to Doom.
Speaker 1: - They could've.
Speaker 0: - If you're gonna go crazy, that's the only advice I have, I'll let you continue.
Speaker 0: If you're gonna go crazy, just go all the way crazy.
Speaker 1: - They did go all the way-- - Go Metal Gear.
Speaker 1: - They went all the way crazy.
Speaker 1: Basically, you hook up with the Resistance again, right?
Speaker 1: As soon as you hook up with the Resistance, shit is insane, because the Resistance is the most ridiculous band of characters that only someone who likes AAA game plots could love.
Speaker 1: You've got the ex-Nazi who's taking care of the giant dude with brain damage who's still a child at heart, and has toys in his room, and the tough old lady who's in a wheelchair 'cause her legs are smashed up, who's in charge of things, and your girlfriend who's the smart girl who you escaped from the asylum with, and she was the nurse who took care of you when you were a vegetable, and the crazy math girl who's totally insane, and you choose one of two people to rescue at the beginning of the game, and the Nazis kill the other one, so you can either go with the English Scottish friend guy who's a veteran, or the young, promising Private Wyatt.
Speaker 1: I chose the old dude, and then there's a scene where he's like, "You should've picked Private Wyatt," and it's like, "Oh, come on, bro,
Speaker 1: whatever.".
Speaker 1: If I choose you, I looked it up online, right?
Speaker 1: If I choose you, I get health upgrades throughout the game.
Speaker 1: Private Wyatt doesn't do Jack.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: - Really?
Speaker 1: - The game is only slightly different based on that choice.
Speaker 1: The ending is basically the same goddamn thing.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, well, the endings, I mean, even "Day of Sex,".
Speaker 0: the end was literally, "Here are four
Speaker 0: buttons.".
Speaker 1: - Right, and then they tried to explain where all the Nazi technology comes from.
Speaker 1: Basically, there was a group of Jews called Dat Yechud who developed all the secret technology simply for the sake of it, because inventing things is their religion, and they keep all the secret technology hidden away, and you rescue, basically, one of the Jews who's like the old Jewish guy from Independence Day, basically, from a concentration camp, and he hooks you up with the crazy technology of awesomeness.
Speaker 0: - Oh, see, also "Doom
Speaker 0: Guy.".
Speaker 0: "Doom Guy" also has his own Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: - Right, and it's just, the plot is so crazy.
Speaker 1: It's just like, "Oh, my God,
Speaker 1: really?".
Speaker 1: It's like, every time, the more crazier the plot got, I was just like, and then, so there's all these gratuitous sex scenes between you and the girl you escaped from the asylum with that were unnecessary, and this gratuitous violent scenes for no reason, and it's just like, and then it's like they get to a point where it's like everything is chapter-based, so you'll go on a mission, it's like, go to the prison, you bust everyone out, then you'll be back at the, you know, the base of normal people doing some fetch quests inside your base, fetch quests in an FPS, then you go out on another mission, and then some more fetch quests back at the base, and then another mission, and then fetch quests back at the base, and then after the second to last mission, the base is destroyed, mission in the base, it's like, oh, the Nazis are in your base, shoot them, right, it's like, the base is on fire.
Speaker 0: - I feel like fetch quests were played out in about 1992.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, it's like, find the secret places in the base where you can find the items and learn about the people in the base, it's like, I don't give a shit, just I wanna shoot Nazis.
Speaker 1: - Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, I guess if you like, you know, stereotypical FPS plots that are really bad, and you don't find that groan-inducing, I guess it's a Patrick Rothfuss level of plot here, right?
Speaker 0: - Wait, so there's a bunch of girls that I could date, but I won't?
Speaker 1: - No, there's the one girl that you basically have sex with immediately, and then have sex with again, and whatever.
Speaker 0: - Can I choose not to have sex?
Speaker 0: - No, you can't.
Speaker 0: - That's great, that's a shame.
Speaker 0: - Yeah.
Speaker 0: - I'm really, really feeling great about that 48 gigabyte download that I could just delete now.
Speaker 1: - I mean, and then you shoot a bunch of Nazis with the same weapon.
Speaker 0: - These are the shootings that I've seen, I could just play Day of Sex Human Revolution and pretend the enemies are Nazis, and I'll feel just as good.
Speaker 1: - So I started that, then I just started playing the other one, 'cause I paid for it, right?
Speaker 1: Why not shoot some more Nazis?
Speaker 1: Wolfenstein, The Old Blood, so Wolfenstein, The Old Blood actually takes place in the past, not in the future, you know, before, it's against a prequel, and so far, it's much better, because this less ridiculous plot, way less ridiculous plot, it's pretty much like, well, the Nazis are winning this war, go to Castle Wolfenstein and find this secret code or something, it's like, all right, it's just level one, you know, chapter one picks off or chapter two left off, there isn't this disjointedness of going back to base and having a completely different chapter.
Speaker 1: that's, you know, so separated, it's pretty much just one big long mission in a big Nazi castle, I just save the game after I open the front gate, and I'm going in.
Speaker 0: - That's, we'll play that one first instead.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, I mean, you really don't need to play the second one to understand, the actual first one to understand the prequel, right?
Speaker 0: - Maybe what I should actually do is just play Doom 2 again, but in a second monitor, watch Inglorious Basterds.
Speaker 1: - I guess you could do that.
Speaker 1: - I guess it sounds like-- - You can just play Wolfenstein 3D.
Speaker 0: - It sounds like I need two punctuated pornography scenes on a third monitor to fully replicate the experience.
Speaker 1: - Uh, oh, there's one more thing I say about this game is that there's one thing that it uses over and over and over again, and it's not quite a jump scare, it's maybe a subset of jump scare, right?
Speaker 1: - All right.
Speaker 1: - Even the old blood keeps reusing.
Speaker 0: the same thing, the same sort of trope happens like 100 times in these games, which could be fun, like in Doom, the trope is, oh shit, the lights go out and you're surrounded by monsters.
Speaker 1: - Right, the trope worked the first time, and after that, the second time they did it, it's like, oh, I guess it's a trope, and then they kept doing it over and over and over again.
Speaker 1: And it's basically, for example, you'll see a vent, and you'll be like, well, that's the place to go, you'll climb up into the vent, and there's like one of the Nazi characters in there and grabs you, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like, oh, I guess it's cutscene time, right?
Speaker 1: You've been captured by Nazis, you know?
Speaker 1: And it's like, you'll be walking down a hallway, and it's like, you'll have to open a door, so it's like, you'll open the door, and then the big Nazi comes out and grabs you.
Speaker 0: - See, that happened once in Metal Gear, and it was fine.
Speaker 1: - There was a part where it's like, well, I guess I have to do the speedy run jump to get over this broken catwalk, and you get to the other side, and around the corner comes a giant Nazi robot that grabs you.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you just keep getting captured by things that come around corners, out of vents, or whatever, to sort of end the section that you're in, and take you into the next cutscene plot part, where you're captured by Nazis or something.
Speaker 1: And this happens like a zillion fucking times.
Speaker 0: - I guess this reminds us why-- - So many times.
Speaker 0: - The number of, like, FPSs in particular, there are a lot of them, like AAA FPSs.
Speaker 0: Very few of them do anything interesting, or have any serious craft put into them, at least from a game design perspective.
Speaker 1: - It's like Half-Life 2 came out more than 10 years ago.
Speaker 1: We were in college.
Speaker 0: - Might be the best ever, still.
Speaker 1: - Right, it's like, why aren't you, like, you haven't learned any of the lessons, from Half-Life 2, have you?
Speaker 1: Half-Life 2 had no cutscenes.
Speaker 1: Everything was in the game engine at all times.
Speaker 1: There's no reason your game should not be doing that.
Speaker 1: They didn't stop and have a chapter, right?
Speaker 1: Gordon Freeman is going from place to place to place.
Speaker 1: There's never any question of like, well, how did he get from there to there, or anything like that.
Speaker 1: It's like, literally, he's 100% from beginning to end.
Speaker 1: Every step Gordon Freeman takes is a step you take, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, if I'm making an FPS, I'm starting at Half-Life 2 and progressing from there, not progressing backwards, right, to an older time before Half-Life 2 existed.
Speaker 1: Why would I do that?
Speaker 0: - Unless you're going to that older time to then take an element that was dropped and focus on it, like Serious Sam did for that Doom-style gameplay.
Speaker 1: - Right, of course, but that's not what this is.
Speaker 0: - That's not what this is, it sounds like.
Speaker 1: - This is a single-player plot FPS.
Speaker 1: You should at least do everything Half-Life 2 does, and more.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't be doing the cutscene nonsense and whatnot.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I mean, it's surprising, though, how much Wolfenstein feel.
Speaker 1: They were able to get into this game.
Speaker 1: It's like a lot of homage to the old Wolfenstein.
Speaker 0: - I can take that.
Speaker 1: - And there's even a part where you go to bed, and then you go to a nightmare, which is the first level of Wolfenstein 3D, but you're controlling it like it's the new game with the new weapons, but the map is old Wolfenstein, the bad guys are old Wolfenstein, but you have the new weapons and the character control, right?
Speaker 1: All the secrets are easy to find because when you walk up next to a wall that has a secret, the little thing highlights up, it says, "Press
Speaker 1: E.".
Speaker 0: That's nice.
Speaker 1: - Mega Man, Mega Man, Mega Man.
Speaker 1: - Well, I didn't want to bother finding the stupid secrets.
Speaker 1: I mean, I knew where they were in that level, right?
Speaker 1: In the second one, I got to the part where you play the next level of Wolfenstein 3D, which is great.
Speaker 0: - You remember the Wolfenstein levels in Doom 2?
Speaker 1: - Yeah, at the end with Commander Keen.
Speaker 1: - Yep, yep.
Speaker 1: - And the Cyberdemon or whatever.
Speaker 1: - Yep.
Speaker 1: - Anyway, the one other thing about this game is, you know how?
Speaker 1: in Half-Life 2, there's a gravity gun, which is sort of like, there's always that one weapon that's not just a shooting weapon?
Speaker 1: - In this one, it's the laser craft work.
Speaker 1: So at one point, you find a laser cutter and you can use the laser cutter to sort of cut open fences and cut chains and things like that to progress and get into secret areas.
Speaker 1: You have to recharge it by finding things on the wall that are basically power recharging stations and you press E and it recharges the laser cutter.
Speaker 1: Eventually, you find the laser craft work, which is like a super laser cutter that can cut even open better things, right?
Speaker 1: Thicker things, including certain--.
Speaker 0: - It can pick up the darker rocks.
Speaker 1: - Right, exactly.
Speaker 1: It can cut open crates you couldn't just smash open and whatnot.
Speaker 1: It can open secrets.
Speaker 1: you couldn't just, it's also actually useful as a weapon.
Speaker 1: It has two modes, you can switch between weapon mode and cutting mode.
Speaker 1: And then you find all these upgrades for it, like a scope and like an auto shot and all these upgrades for it, so it gets crazy powerful.
Speaker 1: But when you use the scope method, it can like target multiple enemies at once.
Speaker 1: You fire once and it shoots all of them at one shot with like perfect aim, but then it uses all its energy in like one go.
Speaker 1: But it's useful because if you run out of ammo for all the other guns, you can always use the laser craft work.
Speaker 0: - Well, just like the bug gun in Half-Life.
Speaker 1: - Right, and when you fight like the giant, giant robot near the end of the game, you have to use the laser craft work to mess with it, right, and whatnot.
Speaker 1: So, you know, 'cause you're gonna run out of ammo if you try to shoot it with your other weapon.
Speaker 1: So there's some interesting things going on with that mechanic.
Speaker 1: It's not as good as the gravity gun, but I imagine it was a lot easier for them to program.
Speaker 1: And I guess it's more Nazi themed, you know, laser craft.
Speaker 1: So if you wanna shoot some Nazis, maybe find some secrets, you're in the mood to shoot some AI controlled dudes.
Speaker 1: You know, this game was way cheap during the Steam sale.
Speaker 1: But if you--.
Speaker 0: - It's not cheap anymore, so I wouldn't buy it necessarily.
Speaker 1: - No, I got it for a ridiculous cheap Steam sale price.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, wait for it to be on sale again.
Speaker 1: - It will be.
Speaker 1: And if you don't like a single player FPS, if you're bothered by a really bad plot with really wacky characters and nonsense, then you probably shouldn't, maybe you only want the plot with nonsense, you can probably watch it on YouTube, right?
Speaker 1: I guess it's all these collectibles, like find all the enigma codes and find all the golden bits.
Speaker 0: - Well, I care about that to a negative degree in all games.
Speaker 1: - The only other mechanic I haven't talked about is the perk mechanic, which is like the way to level up.
Speaker 0: - Is it like Dave's X?
Speaker 1: - I don't know what Dave's X is like, but it's basically--.
Speaker 0: - So you basically, you get like an upgrade point and then you have like a bunch of different areas you can spend it that have like trees.
Speaker 1: - It's not like that.
Speaker 1: So for example, it'll be like, oh, you want the knife upgrade, huh, to where you can hold more throwing knives?
Speaker 1: Well, get this achievement of, kill X guys with throwing knives, and then it'll unlock.
Speaker 1: the hold more throwing knives, and then it'll unlock more achievements you can accomplish, which will unlock more upgrades.
Speaker 1: I basically completely ignored them and had no problems beating the game whatsoever.
Speaker 0: - That's fine, maybe I'll just try it on a harder difficulty.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, I mean, I played on Bring 'Em On, the only things above that are Hurt Me Plenty, or I guess Hurt Me Plenty's after that, right?
Speaker 1: And then Uber?
Speaker 1: - Uber?
Speaker 1: - Oh no, it was.
Speaker 1: I Am Death incarnate, and then they added Uber after that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I played Bring 'Em On.
Speaker 0: - This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: - Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: - Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: - Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: - Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.