Speaker 1: It's Tuesday October 27th 2015.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We're talking about subterfuge.
Speaker 1: It's about submarines.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Get it.
Speaker 1: So this is kind of news.
Speaker 1: It would be metanormal.
Speaker 1: You'd say this is the end of the show, but I'll bring it over the meta moment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe we'll bring it up in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: We will but I'll bring it up at least here.
Speaker 1: for those of you who just listened to the show is all rims idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is uh, you know I've noticed that there's people who are in the forum don't listen to the show and people who listen to the show don't use the forum, so we launched a patreon Mostly to run.
Speaker 0: launch to patreon all the projects.
Speaker 1: we want to do that.
Speaker 1: We can't do for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 0: I won't do anyway, you'll probably won't do anything different than did before.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll do more stuff.
Speaker 1: Things gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well if you don't come over and do it I'm just gonna do them all myself cuz actually I can do a lot faster that way.
Speaker 1: but anyway, if you want to give us money, we have a patreon and now there's a way for you to do that.
Speaker 1: and If we hit $300 a month our first little goal.
Speaker 1: I put goals in there.
Speaker 1: Then we're gonna release the all the beta episodes of geek nights Which a listener just now messaged me and found them online.
Speaker 0: They're not hard to find.
Speaker 0: it's just a yeah You just common sense URL pattern little bit a little bit of thinking got to know some stuff all you know.
Speaker 0: I've given all hints that I'm never gonna give in that forum thread and some people figured it out.
Speaker 1: But I looked at what's in there.
Speaker 1: I think there I have more episodes that we never put anywhere.
Speaker 0: I don't know about that.
Speaker 1: Well, I have a lot of.
Speaker 1: I have all the flack files from the original days.
Speaker 1: But anyway, that's interesting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna do it.
Speaker 0: Those are all that there was.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna figure that out for sure.
Speaker 1: And if we hit that goal I'm gonna publish them for backers like one by one with commentary and I'm gonna remaster them as much as I can.
Speaker 1: Because the other MP3 podcast commentary this no, I'm gonna introduce them like, okay.
Speaker 1: Here's the deal.
Speaker 1: Okay, I don't want someone to listen to one of those and be like.
Speaker 1: this is fucking geek nights.
Speaker 1: This is what you guys listen to because they're not good.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I don't understand why even people give us money for this like why what why?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well honestly, well, we'll get into it more.
Speaker 1: talk about in the meta bit.
Speaker 0: he should probably cancel your patreon.
Speaker 1: We also I we are reselling the original geek nights t-shirt.
Speaker 0: Why not see?
Speaker 0: that's even crazier than paying for geek nights.
Speaker 0: I mean you guys will at least entertain someone better than some other podcasts.
Speaker 0: I mean, there are definitely better podcast than geek nights, but they're also many many that are worse.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not gonna lie I can't but it's still better than most podcasts.
Speaker 1: So the funniest thing we might.
Speaker 0: Why would you wear a picture of us on your self?
Speaker 0: So true fact, how would you pay money for that?
Speaker 1: I wore that t-shirt to work today.
Speaker 1: Why to see if anyone noticed that I was literally wearing a shirt that had a picture of me on it Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: No one noticed.
Speaker 1: Okay, or at least no one said anything.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I think they would have said something.
Speaker 1: I was kind of hoping they would.
Speaker 1: But Yeah, the t-shirts back and like four of you have bought them.
Speaker 1: so before I got that.
Speaker 0: okay, that's our.
Speaker 0: that's a Reasonable expectation for how many stupid people?
Speaker 0: Listening to the show.
Speaker 0: people isn't the show usually?
Speaker 0: aren't that dumb?
Speaker 1: So for dumb people, okay Well, yeah Scott's the self-deprecating one.
Speaker 1: I remember way back.
Speaker 1: We were at zinc icon and This kid like a young kid like obviously it like early high school comes up.
Speaker 1: It's like oh my god room.
Speaker 1: and Scott big fan of your show.
Speaker 1: Ah, da da da.
Speaker 1: Can I have your autograph?
Speaker 1: And our two responses were me doing my usual.
Speaker 1: Well sure glad you listen.
Speaker 1: Thanks to whatever.
Speaker 1: shake his hand It's cops.
Speaker 1: Like why do you want my autograph?
Speaker 1: That's stupid.
Speaker 0: What is wrong?
Speaker 1: Don't listen to our show.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 1: why do you want this book, but I needed a video to put on the patreon.
Speaker 1: So all I did was string together us introducing ourselves at a whole bunch of different panels over the years.
Speaker 0: That's a good video.
Speaker 1: We uh, We always do the exact same shtick in the beginning of every panel and ever really realized it until I watched it go by.
Speaker 1: What I put in that video is a small fraction of the dozens of almost identical things we've said over the years.
Speaker 0: It's a good idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah the only problem is the quality of the video gets worse and worse and worse as I go further back, but Anyway in the actual news, it's Tuesday.
Speaker 1: This isn't the meta part.
Speaker 1: We're not supposed to talk about geek nights other than during the one specific part of geek nights.
Speaker 1: Uh Gator gates back in the news a little bit.
Speaker 0: Are you talking about them?
Speaker 1: because this is actually worth knowing about.
Speaker 1: so South by Southwest is a convention.
Speaker 0: It's not really a convention.
Speaker 0: Well this thing that sort of takes over Austin and messes up the town for a few days I remember and it's really weird.
Speaker 0: It's like it's not like any other.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've never been to.
Speaker 0: well I don't make this.
Speaker 1: magfest isn't a convention either.
Speaker 1: It's a festival.
Speaker 0: Whatever magfest is like conventions despite its name, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it just happens to have concerts that don't stop a schedules a little different.
Speaker 0: But South by Southwest is like it's spread out all over town with these separate events, you know You know packs there's sometimes like corporate events outside of packs, right?
Speaker 0: It's all by Southwest for what I can tell is a lot of things like that and it's well You know why they're the strangest combination.
Speaker 1: You want to know why they're that way.
Speaker 1: We know that because penny arcade when they open, you know, they were gonna do a pack south.
Speaker 1: They looked at putting it in Austin and Austin literally cannot host a large event, right?
Speaker 0: It doesn't have hotels or facilities but there's music festival.
Speaker 0: this technology this and it seems like it's the most corporate thing and from what I can tell it's just a really big excuse for Trendy companies both startups and you know the midsize somewhat successful ones right that are all trendy and cool to all party get wasted and Have a blast in Austin for a week a year or whatever.
Speaker 1: not gonna lie.
Speaker 1: And I really not go to this.
Speaker 0: I have no, you know for everything that I've heard about it.
Speaker 0: I have no intention of ever going and I wouldn't suggest that anyone else go.
Speaker 0: But it's I don't know that I've never been.
Speaker 0: so I could be wrong.
Speaker 1: on the Wikipedia page Gross to the festival has brought concerns of violence and safety but I would have maybe considered going cuz they do panels like do a panel.
Speaker 0: I'm sure nobody goes to.
Speaker 1: yeah, but They don't compensate their panelists at all, aren't you paying to be a panel?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're paying for the privilege of being a panelist Right.
Speaker 0: It's it's a corporate event.
Speaker 0: It's not something for a convention like we're used to.
Speaker 0: it's not a fan-run thing It's a man.
Speaker 0: also
Speaker 1: Anecdotally, I've met a lot of people who are really into South by Southwest just in my like professional circles Most of the people I know or have met I hope they're not listening to this who have been to South by Southwest and like it are the kinds of people I would never want to be alone in a room with Not not the highest caliber people by and large.
Speaker 1: But anyway, they do have panels.
Speaker 1: and apparently the way you submit panels to South by Southwest is so stupid.
Speaker 1: It's on the tier of that reddit convention that fan not reddit to young blur the tumbler convention that failed.
Speaker 1: that shall not be named.
Speaker 1: so basically, what happened is Some people submitted a bunch of panels and Some of the panels were talking about like harassment and games and things and I think like Brianna Wu independently had a panels you Wanted to do.
Speaker 1: like people are just submitting panels I'm gonna quote from an article.
Speaker 1: That is a great insider view of what actually happened the full details.
Speaker 1: But I'm gonna quote because this just explains it all.
Speaker 1: I hadn't previously been aware not having submitted to SXSW before that SXSW makes proposed panels Available for a public vote which includes both up votes and Down votes.
Speaker 1: the ability to download or just like something has proven in the past to be a pretty terrible idea.
Speaker 0: blah blah blah blah If you have let.
Speaker 0: if you let the public choose your panel schedule every convention is gonna be 4chan the convention.
Speaker 1: Can you imagine PAX if they didn't have the super smart people?
Speaker 1: they have just picking the panels and they actually were like hey internet Vote on what panels you want from this list 4chan the panel, 4chan the panel, 4chan the panel.
Speaker 1: So basically the Gomergate morons flooded this thing with death threats and nonsense and voted down all the actual good panels.
Speaker 0: None of those people are actually gonna go to SXSW.
Speaker 0: Shouldn't you at least have to have a SXSW ticket to be able to vote?
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that would make sense, right?
Speaker 0: I mean if you only let people with tickets vote then you might like actually succeed with this plan.
Speaker 0: It actually could work.
Speaker 1: basically SXSW did nothing to deal with the ridiculous like violence threatening screeds that were being posted in the threads about all these panels and Then they cancelled all the panels that were getting this controversy Basically giving the Gomergators a win by cancelling all the harassment type panels that were gonna be at this convention.
Speaker 0: Wouldn't a thing to do to be cancel all the Gomergate panels and then it make those good panels win by default To make the Gomergate people lose.
Speaker 1: SXSW appears to be run very poorly.
Speaker 0: I mean Like if someone says hey Scott, we're gonna threaten you don't play Counter-Strike anymore, and I say Okay, I won't play Counter-Strike anymore, and I just play TF2.
Speaker 1: Well, then I'd threaten you to stop playing TF2.
Speaker 0: I just gave them what they wanted shouldn't I?
Speaker 0: shouldn't?
Speaker 0: the response be fuck you I'm gonna play extra Counter-Strike.
Speaker 1: The thing is this would happen at any convention if you let the internet vote that the answer is.
Speaker 0: I think I don't say any.
Speaker 0: I think if can.
Speaker 1: any large convention that was it was in.
Speaker 0: for example if we had Kineticon if we let them vote Only people had tickets vote.
Speaker 1: Okay, only people who have already pre-registered only people who have pre-registered members of Kineticon.
Speaker 0: if we let them vote Wouldn't be perfect.
Speaker 0: There would be problems.
Speaker 0: For example, they would probably vote in some homestuck panels that we don't want and they probably not because they're homestuck But because they're just ask a homestuck nonsense.
Speaker 0: Also, they would probably There'd be a lot of fan crab.
Speaker 0: the largest community right amongst all the nerd communities We get them get would probably dominate the schedule panels right.
Speaker 0: So like if cos if the cosplay community was bigger than the Doctor Who community then they could fill like the whole Schedule with cosplay panels
Speaker 1: which would be a problem because wall cosplay is a huge part of like Kineticon and lots of cosplayers Attend and like it's a big part of the kind of people are really.
Speaker 0: but the proportions would be off.
Speaker 0: You'd have like if people don't go to the cosplay panel 50% of the pet schedule would be cosplay panels, but cosplay just outnumbered the other geekery.
Speaker 0: So maybe 20% and all the other ones.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying it would be an adverse selection where that community would get their content in but yet their panel content is actually not Well-attended or pop and also a few panels.
Speaker 0: that should happen despite no one going to them like, you know Dog mushing probably wouldn't happen at all.
Speaker 1: I mean also like.
Speaker 1: honestly, I see all the submissions.
Speaker 1: I would not be comfortable as a person response, but it wouldn't be.
Speaker 0: but it wouldn't be as bad as The South by Southwest.
Speaker 0: let the enough vote.
Speaker 0: No, no, that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: You wouldn't really shouldn't do it, but it wouldn't be that bad.
Speaker 0: Just be bad one.
Speaker 1: if you're a prospective panelist never perform at a convention that won't at least comp your badge ever like fuck that Yeah, and oh.
Speaker 0: and also if they make you pay for pretty much and it's like you're working for them.
Speaker 0: They're putting on a convention and they need entertainment to get people to come to it.
Speaker 0: So usually when you're a convention you pay special guests money to fly Stay in a hotel and be at your convention and you advertise.
Speaker 0: this person is gonna be here that you paid.
Speaker 0: You know you paid their appearance fee and now people are gonna buy tickets to cover that fee to come to your convention because they want to see this famous Person.
Speaker 0: if you're not as famous a convention isn't going to want to pay you a lot of money because you're not really Increasing their ticket sales, but you are still working for them.
Speaker 0: You are providing entertainment to their paying guys.
Speaker 1: You're providing ticket sales for the next year, right?
Speaker 0: You're doing work and giving them your time and effort for them to profit by selling tickets.
Speaker 0: You should not be paying them for the privilege of working for them.
Speaker 0: That's like if I went to a diner and I said hey let me buy some pancakes and then I went in the back and made the pancakes with ingredients that I brought and sat in the Diner and ate them.
Speaker 0: that is not a thing that you do Nor would anyone who common sense would not do that.
Speaker 1: So why I made this news on a Tuesday is one.
Speaker 1: it just happened and it's still evolving like apparently Buzzfeed and now Vox media and the verge all said the box is the verge.
Speaker 1: Yeah polygon Yeah, but they're like each of them had separate like sets like they're all running panels.
Speaker 1: Apparently they all said they're gonna pull out of the convention and just not perform that.
Speaker 0: they don't need to be there.
Speaker 0: They're not increasing the ticket sales But who's going?
Speaker 0: because they're there.
Speaker 1: the moral of this is one Pax.
Speaker 1: the gaming conventions are the best run fan conventions in the world.
Speaker 1: Like there's lip There's.
Speaker 1: so every.
Speaker 1: well every problem that a convention like this has is solved by just looking at packs and doing things the way they Do them and that might not.
Speaker 1: that might sound like we've drank some kool-aid But if you've been to a PAX and then been to like some anime con I've been to him.
Speaker 0: We've probably been to more conventions than almost everyone listening.
Speaker 1: if not everyone listening, you know better All right, but but number two the Gomer gate nonsense is far from done and is still a huge problem.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: it's a very small number of people relatively But they're causing these huge problems because there are morons out there if you're basically taking it.
Speaker 0: It's like when you play a board game and there's one player who's a noob and they don't know what's up.
Speaker 0: And if you're the troll player, you can totally just roll them over.
Speaker 0: But that's that's.
Speaker 0: what's happening is that South by Southwest is the noob in the board game and Gomer gate is the troll who?
Speaker 0: Just bowled them over.
Speaker 1: It's like South by Southwest is the example of because they're unprofessional They have been all of us right all of us.
Speaker 0: We're all the other players in the game going?
Speaker 0: No, you you're one shitty player.
Speaker 1: ruin the whole game, you know, it's like guys lock your door Just lock it and they can't get in right.
Speaker 0: we have to get everyone's skills up to.
Speaker 0: you know, keep the fortress safe.
Speaker 0: So yeah, but there's one of the guards at the one of the draw bridges doesn't have the draw bridge works.
Speaker 0: It's like fuck who put you on guard, dude?
Speaker 1: There's a big hole in the wall and the draw bridges can't be drawn up at South by Southwest apparently now, so don't go there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's an unsafe for it.
Speaker 1: But that roiling mess of like basement dwelling gamer gate morons is there and if you let the shields down They do still come in and cause problems.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you got any news Tuesday.
Speaker 0: I don't have any news because I mean there's a whole bunch of little gaming.
Speaker 0: news is like for example Fallout 4 is like imminent and they finish all the cute little videos.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and I really want to play it but I'm waiting for the game of the year edition for 10 bucks or whatever.
Speaker 0: That's gonna be in steam sale 2016 Money.
Speaker 0: why would I pay 50 bucks now for the same exact thing next year for 10 bucks?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I learned that lesson with Fallout 3 and then like the way three was literally the game where I learned the lesson.
Speaker 0: So there's no way I'm making the mistake on follow.
Speaker 0: If anyone though wants to give me a copy early, I would play it now.
Speaker 0: I'm down with that, but I'm not paying.
Speaker 1: wait Wait, you don't want people to donate money to our patreon, but you want them to just give you games.
Speaker 0: Giving me a game is not a waste of money because I would get your.
Speaker 0: you know, fallout review real early.
Speaker 0: Oh You know some other games like doom is coming real close and some other stuff.
Speaker 0: Oh the The Blizzard tf2 clone overwatch is like bleeding.
Speaker 0: now Alright, it's because it's holiday season all the games are coming out of the woodwork.
Speaker 0: Mario maker got a big update that adds the important checkpoint feature.
Speaker 0: Yeah a little flag in the middle of the level.
Speaker 0: So if you get through my really hard part, I don't make you do it again because I'm not that evil.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but I don't have any significant gaming news.
Speaker 0: I can do some geek bite on a game I played that rim did not play and I'm gonna play soon if I do a full video.
Speaker 0: So we saw this game at PAX Prime in the mega booth on The last day of facts and we did some video of it though.
Speaker 0: I think some of that video may have been lost.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I haven't gone through all that Briefly.
Speaker 0: we briefly discussed it in an episode of geek nights But I want to talk about it a lot because I played it a lot in that game.
Speaker 0: It's called sub level zero and this game was pitched to me as dissent plus roguelike.
Speaker 0: If you don't know what dissent is, it's an old DOS game.
Speaker 0: There's also descent to descent three descent free space and I think free space too, but it was a game.
Speaker 0: It was the first game and only game that I played.
Speaker 0: that wasn't VR.
Speaker 0: They gave me some kind of motion sickness though It also cured my motion sickness because I just forced myself to play it for five ten minutes And then I was fine with it.
Speaker 0: and I haven't been motion sick playing a game since.
Speaker 0: and the thing with descent is Basically an FPS except the zero gravity.
Speaker 0: so you can rotate in any direction pitch yaw Etc left right.
Speaker 0: you can translate in every direction up down left, right?
Speaker 0: You can barrel roll in both directions to a barrel roll and you can thrust forward Reverse go straight backwards and also after burning a super fast forward.
Speaker 0: So you basically have complete 360 control and most people can't handle this.
Speaker 0: But it was an awesome game.
Speaker 0: It was a lot like doom and that it was the kind of FPS where you go around a maze fight bad guys get keys Open doors find secrets that sort of thing And had the best music descent to especially I just freaking rock music.
Speaker 0: it was fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: It was just.
Speaker 0: you could just take the CD and put it in a CD player and listen to it because it's you know DOS game.
Speaker 0: But this game sub level zero is does descent, you know that same full free space movement inside a maze.
Speaker 0: But it's a roguelike.
Speaker 0: So that maze is procedure lie Generated and bad guys are inserted into it and you get loots and if you die The whole game over again, just like there's definitely been a like roguelike plus X-trend.
Speaker 0: and let me tell you half or two now.
Speaker 0: so let me tell you about this game.
Speaker 0: first of all, right the controls in this game the most important thing are Better than any descent game I ever played.
Speaker 0: they really they polished those fucking controls.
Speaker 0: How you playing it mouse keyboard Okay, right.
Speaker 0: They polished the fuck out of it so hard.
Speaker 0: It is so smooth is Like there's.
Speaker 0: no I have no control complaints whatsoever in any way, right?
Speaker 0: Number two the difficulty ramps up quite a bit The way that you know, it's like once.
Speaker 0: basically I can't get past.
Speaker 0: you start on sub level zero then one two Three four five and that's the end.
Speaker 0: I the boss of sub level two just like kicks my ass and there's some bad guys that are just really fucking nasty.
Speaker 0: I wonder if they're gonna adjust them or it's a roguelike.
Speaker 0: It's supposed to be nasty.
Speaker 0: Just fucking deal with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, either way or but yeah, there's some guys that are really hard to deal with.
Speaker 0: you can get into tight situations And especially like you'll have a guy come at you and it's like for example You'll you'll be in a narrow hallway because it's procedurally generated.
Speaker 0: you get into bad, you know luck times, right?
Speaker 0: You open the door at the end.
Speaker 0: There's a kind of guy who charges at you.
Speaker 0: It's like oh fuck.
Speaker 0: So what do you do?
Speaker 0: You're not gonna go forward?
Speaker 0: Yeah You mean you can't ram them right back, but you're gonna take serious damage and there's not a lot of health.
Speaker 1: So you're feeling this already cuz I'm thinking about like playing doom and like the kind like when I was good at.
Speaker 1: FPS is single-player.
Speaker 1: FPS is in the old days and even to send part of it came down to.
Speaker 1: I'd memorize and learn patterns And I'd know my way around maps.
Speaker 0: No, no It's like you go reverse.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay.
Speaker 0: He's coming down the hallway at your reverse is real slow.
Speaker 0: It's like, alright You can shoot but then cause explosions right near you because he's charging in.
Speaker 0: You can end up with like a lot of bad choices.
Speaker 0: sometimes your only choice like this guy's run into that room as fast as you can and then just try to take them all out with a lot of movement to avoid getting hit and There's just too many gives more guys in that room than you thought and they're all coming at you now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and some of them are really dangerous tiny and hard to hit and it's like god damn it Man this sounds really good.
Speaker 1: I feel like I really do need to play.
Speaker 0: There's four different kinds of ammo and it's like you have to combine weapons together to craft them into better weapons.
Speaker 0: And it's some kind sometimes like you'll have a whole bunch of one kind of ammo But you'll have a really shitty weapon that uses that ammo.
Speaker 0: it's like you can't get the ammo for the weapon you want to use and You just try to find a bad guy to kill or a treasure chest to open or just something so you can get some.
Speaker 0: You know energy or some ammo or some health, you know a lot of resource managing going on there.
Speaker 0: You know and there's like a lot of tricky things that you know.
Speaker 0: You upgrade your engine or do you use that thing to craft, you know at the end of a level you collected enough nanites Do you want to spend them to.
Speaker 0: you know, which upgrade do you want to choose?
Speaker 0: And it's like there are a lot of things to choose like you can make all your bullet based weapons better But it'll make all of the not bullets based weapons weaker.
Speaker 0: Do you want to do that?
Speaker 0: And it's like I have a really strong bullet based weapon.
Speaker 0: Yes, and the next level They're just like, you know what fuck you on bullets.
Speaker 0: No bullets for you No, no bullets this time.
Speaker 0: You just run into ammo for that gun.
Speaker 0: You're like fuck me.
Speaker 1: some people will complain about that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: But thought for me like a roguelike like I play.
Speaker 1: I still play crypt of the necro dancer like I like that game a lot Okay, and sometimes you just get completely fucked.
Speaker 1: That's kind of the point of a roguelike like.
Speaker 0: it might be bad news behind that door But this roguelike because it's descent is not just bad decision bad luck bad procedural business.
Speaker 0: This it's if you have skills.
Speaker 0: It really doesn't matter if you have super descent skills even better than me because I'm not the greatest.
Speaker 0: You could probably just dominate the whole game because by dodging and moving and shooting and you know Cuz like if you don't get hit well You don't have to worry about not getting health.
Speaker 0: and if you kill guys quickly then you know We can get with really accurate shots.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna run out of ammo.
Speaker 1: So yeah, well, I mean crypto the necro dancer if you just remember are good at patterns.
Speaker 1: Don't mess up like everything's easy and you'll just win.
Speaker 1: just move right?
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm pretty sure the descent games themselves are on GOG.
Speaker 0: So I highly recommend you play those.
Speaker 0: if you haven't and you don't and you can overcome the motion sickness I could play those again.
Speaker 1: Maybe we could do a show on dissent.
Speaker 0: I mean, okay dissent is exactly what I just said Not procedural not procedural.
Speaker 0: The the plot of dissent is actually really awesome.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like this terrible secret of space situation where you're like this dude material defender and all the robots that work in all the space mines and asteroids and things have all gone crazy and You basically are sort of a bounty hunter who's been hired to like go and fix all the broken mines To restore the galactic economy.
Speaker 0: I don't know but it's like there's plenty of terrible secret of space going on.
Speaker 0: It's really weird.
Speaker 0: Yeah But because the descent levels are handcrafted there's secrets and things and the levels is really amazing Especially in descent - and the music anyway sub level zero.
Speaker 0: play that game on steam.
Speaker 1: Anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: This is just a fascinating little video that I saw.
Speaker 1: It's a rundown from a gun expert on five overly complicated guns and It's how did a gun be overly complicated?
Speaker 0: you put in bullet this revolver bolt action automatic Open bolt or closed bolt.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying none of the.
Speaker 0: none of these kinds are overly complicated.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what?
Speaker 1: what do you mean?
Speaker 1: one of these kinds?
Speaker 0: what constitutes an example of an overly complicated gun?
Speaker 1: These five guns in this video and if you watch tell me about one of them, they're over engineered like what.
Speaker 1: like some of them have see, I'm not an expert on guns to this degree, but like one of them has this complicated mechanism of loading the cartridges up into the gun.
Speaker 1: is this pistol, but as a result you actually load them backwards into the Clip Not the clip.
Speaker 1: you load them backwards into the magazine.
Speaker 0: Does it reverse them when you get to the top?
Speaker 1: I've I don't know.
Speaker 1: I didn't watch that.
Speaker 0: It's like a little ferris wheel or the bullet turns around.
Speaker 1: one of them just takes a base forward.
Speaker 1: This one just takes weird.
Speaker 1: or do you?
Speaker 0: or does it just shoot yourself when you shoot?
Speaker 1: Some of them just have like really complicated Stuff.
Speaker 1: that makes them cool and awesome guns like the guy.
Speaker 1: basically all these guns are awesome according to the guy Like really well designed really awesome.
Speaker 1: They're just way over complicated and a less complicated design that did a similar thing would be a lot more Reliable in the long run and there's a reason why I would actually be able to fix it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like there's a reason why these guns were not widely used as Technology got better.
Speaker 0: if you can't take apart a gun if you can't practice taking apart a gun and putting it back together really fast It's not a practical gun.
Speaker 1: Well the or like they have a lot of interesting features that just aren't in other guns.
Speaker 1: He talks a little bit about like why they don't do that even though it's super nice to have it.
Speaker 1: Why do guns just don't have it?
Speaker 1: Those are really well shot like the lightest.
Speaker 1: It's a good video.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So this guy he made some kind of program.
Speaker 0: I can't fully understand how he did this technologically speaking But what he did is he took real music specifically that the number one example uses staying alive by the Bee Gees Right that song and he converted into a MIDI file.
Speaker 0: It's like well this MIDI files.
Speaker 0: of that you can make a MIDI file.
Speaker 1: I have some applications that did shit like that in the past, right?
Speaker 1: They were really bad at it.
Speaker 0: Sure, but he didn't make a MIDI file that just sort of like Results with like the score, you know The same.
Speaker 0: if you took the score of the song you bought a copy of it or printed a copy of it out and typed It into.
Speaker 0: you know, one of those songs you can just score music and then it plays it back with me.
Speaker 1: He'll cakewalk studio, right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: that's not what this does.
Speaker 0: yeah, what it does is it uses various piano instruments, I think as many as a MIDI file can handle and by playing notes on the piano Actually plays the freaking song and you can even hear the vocals.
Speaker 0: But it's like it's this weird psychological trick We're like if you listen to it just sounds like a mess, but if someone tells you Oh, by the way, this is staying alive by the Bee Gees and you know the song and you start listening to it It's like you.
Speaker 0: suddenly you hear the vocals and I go my god.
Speaker 0: Suddenly you hear the song and it's really just a ton of freaking piano.
Speaker 0: No, it's like if you had freaking Mario Paint but they let you use as many friggin swans as And you can stack up the swans and squeeze them as close together and it unless I'm just doing one MU for swans it's like sub pixel rendering.
Speaker 1: It's using your brain tricks.
Speaker 1: It's like rendering part of the song in your brain based on your memory, right?
Speaker 0: So he does a bunch of songs in this video, but you only need to hear the first one and it is freaking.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: And he really pushes MIDI to the limit and it's like why is MIDI even still a thing?
Speaker 1: Cuz MIDI is useful because it's basically a command-and-control architecture for controlling remote instruments.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it was useful when we didn't have PCM enough memory to miss.
Speaker 0: do everything with PCM.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it's not because of the PCM as much It's it's not.
Speaker 1: it's basically what you're saying is it's a mechanism.
Speaker 1: You can chain a bunch of real instruments together and send digital abstract signals that say play this kind of note But the instrument does it.
Speaker 1: while however, it knows.
Speaker 0: but whatever that instrument is is gonna be a synthesizer And you could have just plus.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of existing technology Like our mixer like firewires already way obsolete.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't need our mixers firewire because that's you know, this mixer is perfectly good.
Speaker 0: It'll be good for 20 years to come tell you let's just make a company that makes audio equipment.
Speaker 0: It's only modern.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of stuff supports MIDI though, right?
Speaker 0: We could start by.
Speaker 0: I mean we just start by selling it to like all you know Like those guys at concerts in the middle.
Speaker 1: I could do a show on MIDI.
Speaker 1: I could tell you guys how that works.
Speaker 0: Nobody cares about this dead technology.
Speaker 1: I used to have a lot of expenses used only for making quirky YouTube videos.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I used it to back before mp3s.
Speaker 1: I had a piano that had MIDI like a really nice digital piano and I would actually download MIDI files Mess with them to make piano like mixes of songs And then play them through the piano because that sounded better than the synthesizer in my sound blaster for playing a piano.
Speaker 0: So your keyboard had a better sound card than your.
Speaker 1: my keyboard had a really expensive sound card.
Speaker 0: effective Yeah, oh, but this is not the thing of the day.
Speaker 0: But we did a thing of the day a while back where there's a guy who told you how like the graphics and old computers Worked.
Speaker 0: he did a video more recently that tells you how the sound and old computers work.
Speaker 0: You should watch that because it's related to this discussion.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so in the moment the booklet book was and still is the wheel of time.
Speaker 1: We did book one.
Speaker 1: We did a whole show on it.
Speaker 1: You know, listen to it.
Speaker 0: I started book five a little bit, but then I'm reading comics now.
Speaker 1: So yeah I just also.
Speaker 1: I basically just finished book four for real so I could start book five any day.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I haven't really yet.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: Maybe we'll just pause there.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should do a mid mid show on it.
Speaker 1: As I said, we launched our patreon.
Speaker 1: So if you give us Any amount of money you'll get a bunch of content in there.
Speaker 1: if you give us five bucks Like I said, and it's super dumb.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna say your name at the end of every show after the credits.
Speaker 1: Dave and Joel do that actually with the t-shirts.
Speaker 1: anytime you buy a t-shirt from them.
Speaker 1: They say your name on the show.
Speaker 0: I Highly recommend you do not pay for such a stupid thing.
Speaker 0: This is nothing.
Speaker 0: I didn't plan this.
Speaker 1: I also promised that I'm gonna do.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do ultra dumb stuff.
Speaker 0: Why didn't you clear this with me first during that part?
Speaker 1: So dumb stuff and names of people will happen after the credit.
Speaker 1: So if you already gave us money, you can listen for that.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna say your name.
Speaker 0: if you give me ten bucks I will make fun of you.
Speaker 0: So guys we're being so dumb as to give me ten dollars a month when you probably need it more than I.
Speaker 1: there are several People backing us at ten dollars a month right now.
Speaker 0: What is wrong with you?
Speaker 0: But also unless you're really if you're really rich.
Speaker 0: first of all If you're rich enough, you can spend ten dollars a month on geek nights.
Speaker 0: I mean that is half.
Speaker 0: that is almost the cost of Hulu.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is 12 bucks a month Are you crazy?
Speaker 0: But we think about what Hulu gets you the greatest movies and some of the greatest TV shows to ever exist.
Speaker 0: So guys with no commercials, I'll skip me.
Speaker 0: just geek nights only ten bucks.
Speaker 0: You must either be fabulously wealthy or dumb and if you're fabulously wealthy Give me a lot more than ten bucks you cheap ass.
Speaker 1: So one Scott's really making the hard sale here.
Speaker 1: But more importantly we do have a one of our milestones at the top here.
Speaker 1: If you guys scrape together 20 grand a month, we'll do geek nights full-time and quit our jobs.
Speaker 1: So yeah, probably but I'll give it to it.
Speaker 1: that'll happen.
Speaker 0: If you're so rich.
Speaker 0: they have 20 grand a month.
Speaker 0: Just hire me.
Speaker 1: if we had 20,000 fans who gave us a dollar a month We could quit if we had 20,000 fans.
Speaker 0: We wouldn't need even them to have patreon.
Speaker 0: We could just sell things.
Speaker 1: Valuable things won't like our geek night's t-shirts that we're also selling now.
Speaker 0: It's not a valuable thing.
Speaker 0: I guess it's better than patreon.
Speaker 1: Let's look I did the thing on the back that we couldn't do before because we were cheap.
Speaker 0: But like we could just make you know a product and sell it to them.
Speaker 1: or maybe we'll make that forum.
Speaker 1: Anyway Yeah, that is enough talking about things that aren't subterfuge because this is a game that we kind of all decided to play in the.
Speaker 0: So there was a game and it's still around actually has a sequel.
Speaker 0: we've never played.
Speaker 1: Oh Neptune's pride Neptune's pride.
Speaker 0: We might have done an episode on this game.
Speaker 1: I did not play it.
Speaker 1: I just didn't play it.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't get into it I was busy.
Speaker 1: Oh, so Neptune's pride know about it I just didn't play.
Speaker 0: it was a game We played online and it had an interesting business model or you'd like almost pay for play like one person would pay and everyone Would get to play.
Speaker 0: it's like if I put a quarter in the arcade machine and everyone gets to play gauntlet.
Speaker 0: all right, but the idea of Neptune's pride was that you're in space and You spawn yet some planets and you could order ships to fly from planet to planet in groups of however many number and it wasn't Complicated like Master of Orion.
Speaker 0: customizing ships is just how many ships.
Speaker 0: so you would say like oh I'll send a hundred ships from here to there and Obviously if there was uninhabited you would take it over and it would start producing ships.
Speaker 0: and if there was inhabited by you It just like okay you docked at your base and it was inhabited by someone else.
Speaker 0: you fought And never had more ships won and then the remaining ships would still be there.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so think of these is like RTS is but distilled to their fundamental elements.
Speaker 0: right now The thing is with Neptune's pride is that the ships moved not in real time But also in real time.
Speaker 0: not in real time as in.
Speaker 0: this is how fast ships move in space.
Speaker 0: But as in it would say on the screen It will take three hours and 40 minutes for those ships to get there.
Speaker 1: No one thought you were saying they move in real real time in space like real spaceships.
Speaker 0: But in three hours and 40 minutes, that's when those ships will get there.
Speaker 0: so you're basically checking this game 24/7 or every once in a while to make sure Nobody like.
Speaker 0: because if somebody springs an attack on you and it takes five hours for those ships to get there and you didn't check The game in those five hours, you just got blowed up without realizing it.
Speaker 0: So you have to check at least so, you know You have to say okay if anyone attacks me the soonest they can hit any of my planets is an hour.
Speaker 0: So I have to check hourly to make sure there's no sneak attack.
Speaker 1: But anyways, so this subterfuge game that we got into very similar even more distilled But it fixes all the problems of Neptune's pride.
Speaker 1: as far as I can tell it is described as a week-long Game of strategy and diplomacy because the time frames are like if I want to move guys From one of my bases to another outpost the time might be like 40 hours.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a lot longer.
Speaker 0: So so here's what subterfuge differs from Neptune's pride and how it fixes it.
Speaker 0: number one and Neptune's pride It was in space so you might be positioned at the start of the game like on the edge.
Speaker 0: So you're only facing like one person.
Speaker 0: it's like the left of you if you're on the right side Maybe someone below you and or above you But someone's in the middle and it's someone else's off.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: it's like the positions are very bad subterfuge.
Speaker 0: It's a planet made of water and you all live in submarines.
Speaker 0: it instead of outer space, but it's the same goddamn thing.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter but everyone is surrounded.
Speaker 0: the planet is dark.
Speaker 0: The planet is round.
Speaker 0: You can wrap around like pac-man in every direction.
Speaker 0: So everyone is equally surrounded on all sides by everybody.
Speaker 0: There's no bad positions really, right?
Speaker 0: The other thing they fix is that it's not just a numbers game, right?
Speaker 0: A lot of times Neptune's pride was like, well, I have more guys than you.
Speaker 0: deal with it.
Speaker 0: You're gonna lose.
Speaker 0: You know here that every once in a while everyone no matter what gets a specialist and if you get us yeah, you can choose from among three and you know, which three are coming up next to choose from.
Speaker 0: and Specialists are really powerful.
Speaker 0: like there's some specialists They're just like worth 20 ships in a battle, but they keep fight.
Speaker 0: as long as they don't die They keep giving up.
Speaker 1: They're all.
Speaker 1: you're powerful.
Speaker 1: They're really power.
Speaker 1: This ship just moves twice as fast three times as fast.
Speaker 0: What one that extends my sonar range?
Speaker 0: It's like I can really don't have any fog of war really anymore that anywhere.
Speaker 0: that matters for me because I can see so much Further than everyone else who doesn't have that specialist already.
Speaker 1: But the biggest change in that regard to make it not a numbers game is that it's if I just say what this game is Most like.
Speaker 1: it's most like the board game.
Speaker 0: diplomacy Yes is most like diploma fixes diplomacy too because really this is a vote.
Speaker 0: who wins game in the end, right?
Speaker 0: Neptune's pride had some flaws in the vote.
Speaker 0: who wins?
Speaker 0: because your votes were limited by your you know Numbers or your position.
Speaker 0: now you can pretty much vote for almost.
Speaker 0: I can't vote for the one person.
Speaker 0: I can't get near the person.
Speaker 0: I want to vote against so you need to vote against that person.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I want to vote against them so badly, but I can't do.
Speaker 0: they're so far away.
Speaker 0: I can't do anything about it.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll give you a base near that person and you can send your fleet there and then Reconnoise and leave my bases open for you to take back that I took from you.
Speaker 1: I need that.
Speaker 1: I need that factory back real bad.
Speaker 1: No So the game has a very clever chat thing where you can start a chat with between you and any combination of other players.
Speaker 1: so I started.
Speaker 1: at one point someone started a chat with Everyone except one player and that was the war room of.
Speaker 1: how do we get this player out of the fucking game?
Speaker 1: I have a chat with just one person.
Speaker 0: I have a lot of chats.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everyone's chatting me up But like I have a chat of one Alliance I have a chat with another Alliance and they're not the same people.
Speaker 1: I have two chats one with four people and one with three people because that fourth person's danger is luckily They're about to be eliminated.
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 1: I have to worry about them as much anymore.
Speaker 0: I have a lot of chats.
Speaker 1: so the game comes down to not checking every few hours and doing stuff so much but Making deals and just doing the diplomacy game.
Speaker 0: right you want to attack someone you're basically gonna have to leave something Undefended to someone else because you're surrounded.
Speaker 0: everyone's surrounded.
Speaker 0: So if I attack rim on the right I'm leaving myself open from the north because it's my northeast place.
Speaker 0: I'm evacuating to say because if you have a guy in a in a in an outpost They're defending that place.
Speaker 0: if they leave to attack that place is now less Defended and it can be if you move your Queen which provides many shields and super defends one outpost.
Speaker 0: What if it gets hit mid movement?
Speaker 0: It's not providing shields when it's in between outposts if you just get blowed up.
Speaker 0: So yeah, you can only move it when you're sure nobody's gonna take advantage of that.
Speaker 0: But the final times you have to trust people and though yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 1: Otherwise, I have a list now of the people I can trust because I've been trustworthy for real and the people that I will never Trust in this game again ever Never trust me again because I blew your shit up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you didn't specifically say you wouldn't so I guess that but anyway.
Speaker 0: But the other reason I mean, I basically just saw that you left this place completely because I was helping row out.
Speaker 0: I mean, I saw a completely undefended place.
Speaker 0: I had a super strong position in that area and I needed a factory.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, it's rim.
Speaker 0: I don't want rim to win.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I'm not winning actually because so I mean that's good But I mean it's like the game we played.
Speaker 1: with the exception of like one or two people Everyone in the game messaged me.
Speaker 0: It's a vote who wins game.
Speaker 0: I have the ability to cast a vote against someone.
Speaker 0: I have to cast at least one vote against rim.
Speaker 1: Yes So how could I?
Speaker 0: why would he vote for rim?
Speaker 1: I get all these messages from all the other players one by one over the first few hours or setting up the game saying Yeah, Scott formed a chat of everyone but you it is trying to get everyone to gang up on you.
Speaker 0: Lol No, I basically all I said in that chat was look guys.
Speaker 0: Remember?
Speaker 0: This is the vote who wins game And I just I don't care if I lose just don't vote for it.
Speaker 1: It was interesting.
Speaker 0: That's what I said.
Speaker 0: It was interesting.
Speaker 1: who told me about that chat?
Speaker 0: when they told me about it I should have just included you in the chat because I told you about the job.
Speaker 1: But other people told me about the chat on their own.
Speaker 1: one two people sent me screenshots of it in case I didn't believe them.
Speaker 1: And I just want to point out there was one person who specifically did not tell me about the chat attacked me immediately And yeah, someone fell for the vote against rim.
Speaker 1: Yeah So great, that's interesting.
Speaker 1: But the other game design thing it does to make the diplomacy stuff happen and make it fun is the way you win.
Speaker 1: is there's A resource you can mine?
Speaker 1: you have to.
Speaker 0: oh, that's the other thing it does.
Speaker 0: That's much fixes Neptune's pride.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, so basically you can mine the stuff neptunium and if you hit 200 you just win game over.
Speaker 0: I like to call this the Gandhi strategy.
Speaker 1: the first person to get 200 just wins.
Speaker 0: So you don't have to go conquering everyone.
Speaker 0: you can just hold up and defend yourself and spend all of your extra subs making mines.
Speaker 0: and if you can defend those mines and No one can take them from you.
Speaker 0: You can get enough points to just win the game just by defending.
Speaker 0: now If you might think it's in order to build a mine you just sacrifice Lots and lots of submarines every time you build a mine.
Speaker 0: that place you just built a mine is now super undefended because you know There's way more - there's way more to it than that on a sub from a design standpoint.
Speaker 1: So if you attack someone else's mine and take it from them you get that mine.
Speaker 1: you get the mine You don't get any neptunium.
Speaker 0: You just get the mine Hundred stuff from a mine and rim takes that mine.
Speaker 0: He starts mining stuff, but I still have my hundred.
Speaker 1: No, so if you lose a mine you lose 20 neptunium only 20.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's basically it'll.
Speaker 0: So if you mine less than 20 you lose it all.
Speaker 0: but if you mine 50 you keep 30.
Speaker 1: But the point of all this is that you if you take out someone's mine Literally remove victory points from them without gaining them directly yourself.
Speaker 0: So it's not a zero-sum game.
Speaker 0: it
Speaker 1: facilitates deals and diplomacy and planning to take down the leader and that also fosters opportunities for backstabbing and shady dealings because Anyone who is beating another player in terms of actual or all neptunian mind By 20 or more can choose to check a box and start funding that player.
Speaker 0: now, you'd be like, oh who's gonna do that?
Speaker 1: So thus Everyone gangs up on say Scott because Scott's got the most neptunium and he's winning and we got.
Speaker 0: have you know?
Speaker 0: I have no neptunium by the way, so they don't.
Speaker 1: you might don't do fund to other players.
Speaker 0: I actually sort of want to lose the game.
Speaker 0: That's like a tiny part that wants me to just lose the game so I can stop checking my stupid goddamn phone.
Speaker 1: Well, I can't check it that much now knowing I got to go into full defense mode because you've motherfuckers all fucked me.
Speaker 0: But it's like it's so annoying to check the game.
Speaker 0: It's like I almost just want to lose and quit.
Speaker 1: We're just the way the game is designed the the not to get into all the details.
Speaker 1: You can just watch the tutorial videos and see how the game fully works with shields and everything.
Speaker 1: But it is cleverly designed to make all the things that you expect to happen if you play diplomacy happen Without all the not funness of diplomacy.
Speaker 0: You don't have to have the stupid rules order resolution in diplomacy And you don't have to have the stupid now.
Speaker 0: We're gonna deploy diplomacy now We're gonna take actually play the game diplomacy not that alternating.
Speaker 0: It's like because it's slow and real time.
Speaker 0: things take hours to happen.
Speaker 0: You can just constantly diplomacy and move and shake without stopping.
Speaker 1: So the other thing to note is the specialists like the people in the game It is.
Speaker 1: I'm pleased that it is a widely varied in terms of gender age and skin color cast.
Speaker 0: I haven't paid attention to that at all.
Speaker 1: It stood out because it's so rare.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's that's the point I mean I guess when you live under the sea then a submarine Everyone's got to get along and to.
Speaker 1: the game is technically free to play but oh, that's the one bullshit.
Speaker 1: No, it's not though.
Speaker 1: Cuz really the game cost 10 bucks.
Speaker 1: Sure, and I enjoy it enough to where like I'm glad I paid.
Speaker 0: But so what do you get for 10 bucks?
Speaker 1: So you can just.
Speaker 1: you can join any public game and you can join any private game.
Speaker 1: But if you pay 10 bucks once then forever you can start Private games that you invite only your friends to.
Speaker 1: okay.
Speaker 1: and two you can issue unlimited numbers of orders in the future because the game has this really Beautiful UX
Speaker 0: where Neptune's pride did not have this as effectively but basically the UX and all of the the System of giving orders giving orders in the future rolling time forward and back to see what's going to happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I can roll.
Speaker 0: according to your current information I can issue orders.
Speaker 1: if I'm gonna issue a contradictory order It warns me like up that's and you can always cancel things before the last second.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So y'all like send all my ships over the horizon and then I find out once I get closer and get more Intel That the shields on Scott's battle station are fully operate.
Speaker 0: That's the other way I'm making this game more fun.
Speaker 0: is I'm basically doing Emperor Palpatine role-playing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and so far I've had both situations.
Speaker 0: I've had my fleet on the far side of the Centauri moon.
Speaker 0: that happened.
Speaker 1: that rim didn't know about.
Speaker 1: no I didn't know about that.
Speaker 1: I know about that.
Speaker 0: And then I had he.
Speaker 0: you know, he attacked He counter-attacked after I took his factory and I'm like, oh by the way, the shields will be fully operational when you arrive.
Speaker 0: You can't recall Sure enough 20 minutes before he lands the Emperor lands just where he was going and the shields go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was bad news.
Speaker 0: I could have even chosen a specialist to get the shields even bigger But I realized I would win even without it.
Speaker 0: So I chose the long-term specialist instead.
Speaker 1: Yep But that UX is so well done.
Speaker 1: So like little stuff like I can pick another Outpost like an enemy outpost and just drag forward from it and in real time as I drag my finger It's showing me what the game state will be at every point.
Speaker 0: You can even measure with a ruler how how long like I can go to rims factory and drag a line over to my factory And it'll say aha it will take rim.
Speaker 0: if he gives the order now this instant It will take him 14 hours to reach me State.
Speaker 1: I can attack.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then I can measure with my own thing and be like well if I attack that now Leaving this spot open.
Speaker 0: I can then move these guys into position to defend my open spot before 14 hours.
Speaker 0: So rim can't.
Speaker 0: if he tries to attack when I leave it open.
Speaker 0: He will run into a fully operational shield.
Speaker 0: He didn't know it's gonna be there.
Speaker 1: So it's a free-to-play game.
Speaker 1: it's just on smartphones, that's the other thing.
Speaker 1: you can just play it all the time.
Speaker 0: And rim has an Android phone.
Speaker 0: I have an iPhone.
Speaker 0: We're all playing together.
Speaker 0: It totally works.
Speaker 0: We don't even know what other people are using.
Speaker 0: It's great.
Speaker 1: So oh and the other thing is only Neptune's pride.
Speaker 0: We had to check like on our PCs all the time here.
Speaker 0: Everyone's checking all the time.
Speaker 1: if you pay you can join multiple games at the same time, which I would never do.
Speaker 0: I don't want to do that.
Speaker 0: No unless you have literally no life.
Speaker 1: I Fun like.
Speaker 1: I'm actually kind of into this.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna play.
Speaker 0: everyone else's seems like they're way more into it than I am.
Speaker 0: I'm just sort of like playing my game.
Speaker 0: So I will commit to running to be the Emperor.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna pretty much continuously.
Speaker 1: each time a game ends I'll start a forum game and I'll invite you guys and we'll just keep playing this.
Speaker 1: I'll play table future.
Speaker 0: I'll play it during times of the year when I have time for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, once once summer comes again We're not gonna play this much but the game is fun and you can play it for free.
Speaker 0: So I do recommend you check it out and it sends you notifications which it's happening.
Speaker 1: so you could actually if you just ominous I'm laying there I was about to go to bed.
Speaker 0: if you basically only look at it when you get a notification you will do very well.
Speaker 1: But suddenly my phone buzzes a whole bunch of like what the fuck.
Speaker 1: so I go look and it's all these notifications of 40 Drillers appeared on your horizon aimed at I'm like, oh no Yeah, but sometimes the notification like I got one today.
Speaker 0: that's like you can see.
Speaker 0: someone has 30 drillers and a specialist that you just never saw before.
Speaker 0: you can see now and I open it up and it's like it's so far away going To their own planet.
Speaker 0: It's like, alright, but I didn't need a notification for that.
Speaker 1: I take that information and give it to certain people who then act on it and things like in someone's internal territory.
Speaker 0: Were you?
Speaker 1: yeah, yeah, cuz I saw a martyr hanging out somewhere.
Speaker 1: That's some scary shit.
Speaker 1: cuz martyrs can destroy entire outposts permanently.
Speaker 0: Yeah How does that work?
Speaker 1: if they're in a combat everything within a radius is destroyed No matter what it is.
Speaker 0: see the martyr coming and just abandon the outpost.
Speaker 1: So what?
Speaker 1: if so, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: say I had sent a ping.
Speaker 1: I got one shit one sub going toward a place and that place had sent a martyr at me earlier unbeknownst Wherever they collide whatever is nearby which might be an unrelated outpost.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah.
Speaker 0: So wherever the martyr gets killed explodes.
Speaker 1: as soon as I found out there was a martyr and someone warned me.
Speaker 1: it was there.
Speaker 1: I sent a single submarine with one driller From every one of my places that had guys to every one of that players places just to make sure there's no way it could Come after me and if it blows up somewhere because of that that's gonna be so fucking hilarious.
Speaker 1: The game is super fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I should have sent those one sub pings at the game start.
Speaker 1: Yeah Now I know a lot more.
Speaker 1: I really look forward to the second game of this and I'm gonna continue my never lies strategy.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: So as promised the the text of our patreon does say and I quote this is super dumb.
Speaker 1: But if you support us this much we will say your name at the end of each episode after the credits Along with something ultra dumb.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna read these every time in order of the amount of money that you're giving us.
Speaker 1: So if you want to be at the top of the list, I guess you could add another dollar.
Speaker 1: James David White Kristin Koontz, Jessica L Barlow mechanical mind.
Speaker 1: William ice and rose Chris midkiff Chris Knox flame dark fire.
Speaker 1: Samuel corduroy Daniel Redmond Chris her dad Doug Snyder Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas han.
Speaker 1: There is one more person who would have qualified but they are listed as not wanting the reward.
Speaker 1: So if that person feels sad that they were not listed here Just email me and I will take care of that on Thursday's show.
Speaker 1: and now Your dumb thing.
Speaker 0: as long as I wear this I'm able to cast the three spells simultaneously.
Speaker 0: Remember, this is dangerous kid.
Speaker 1: So don't try it at home.
Speaker 0: I Don't Remember.
Speaker 1: this is dangerous kid, so don't try it at home.
Speaker 0: Remember this is dangerous kid, so don't try it at home.