Speaker 1: It's Monday, October 5th, 2015.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I am Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights, back after a surprisingly long hiatus, here to talk about For The People.
Speaker 1: Rating people on the internet, like y'all.
Speaker 0: Not Ra-ding, like Oakland.
Speaker 1: Ra-ting, with a T. Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, I'm not gonna tell like every story from, you know, me traveling all around the world, but the small stories I will tell now is one, I flew to Asia business class because fuck all y'all.
Speaker 0: Someone else paid for it.
Speaker 1: No, someone else did not pay for it.
Speaker 0: You used your own monies to pay for that ticket?
Speaker 1: So, normally I fly coach, but I can get premium economy if there's a reason.
Speaker 1: Like, if I'm flying overnight or something, or like I'm gonna land somewhere and I have a meeting, like the next day or like something real quick, then yeah, I'll go like premium economy, which like on Turkish air, that's better than most business class in the US.
Speaker 1: Like, that is pretty nice by itself.
Speaker 1: But I will usually try to sweet talk people who work for the airlines into, "Can I just slip into that business class?
Speaker 1: I know there's no one sitting up there right
Speaker 1: now.".
Speaker 1: Like, I'll try to pull shit.
Speaker 1: It very rarely works out.
Speaker 1: But I booked premium economy all the way to Asia and one thing led to another and one of my legs, because I booked it through one of those dodgy sites that like gets your stuff for you, I don't know what happened on their end, but they ended up giving me premium economy on a very, like a little leg in one section of the, because I had a layover, because there aren't a lot of direct flights that far, even from New York.
Speaker 1: So, because my big leg was business class, it made the whole trip count as business class.
Speaker 1: So, I got to fly in one of those little cubicles that has a full flat lay down bed and like a little shield I can put up, just like a tiny room.
Speaker 1: And I got to stop at my layover and go into a tiny apartment and take a shower and take a nap in an actual bed and eat a bunch of free food and drink a whole bunch of wine and then get on my premium economy flight the rest of the way.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you, I would never in my life pay that much money, even if I was rich, to fly like that, because it is so much money, it is stupid.
Speaker 0: But what if I'm so much rich?
Speaker 1: But the sheer classist hierarchy of it, it's so weird to fly like that, because you do not-.
Speaker 0: But the thing is, I don't understand who is rich enough to afford that, yet not rich enough to afford the private jet.
Speaker 1: So, actually, the private jet's kind of a pain in a lot of ways, because they can't get, like private jets can't go to Australia from New York easily.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: They don't have that much range.
Speaker 1: You're not going to get a 737 as your private jet.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: You just don't.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: Google has one.
Speaker 1: That's too much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Google.
Speaker 1: Not Sergei, but Google.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: Sergei doesn't have his own.
Speaker 0: If he wants to go, he's going to go.
Speaker 1: But, so, basically, the weirdest thing is that all that crazy luxury I experienced on this trip is a pale comparison to first class.
Speaker 0: The people- Business class is not first class?
Speaker 0: No, first class- If business class is a little cabin with a lay down bed, is first class like there's a mansion in the front of the plane?
Speaker 1: I linked to an article a long time ago of a guy who flew 25 hours first class, like across the Pacific, and he had a room about half the size of the studio we're sitting in right now.
Speaker 0: So it's not that big.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but with a full bed in it, a butler to take care of him, custom menu, you're driven to- the airport picks you up, if you don't have your own driver, and you don't even interact- You go to a separate area of the airport and are checked in manually by people who take care of everything for you.
Speaker 1: Private security screening, right there.
Speaker 1: You never interact with any of the plebes in the airport.
Speaker 1: Like you're taken out of the plane separately.
Speaker 1: Sometimes by a different ramp, sometimes they drive a little car and let you walk up the ramp on the other side of the plane that no one else even knows they put there.
Speaker 1: A chef deals with your meal arrangements for the entire trip, including at the airport.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's messed up.
Speaker 1: But I got that, and it was great.
Speaker 1: The other story I'll tell is how I almost died out in the bush.
Speaker 0: Doing things I told you not to do.
Speaker 1: So I went up to Lura in the Blue Mountains, and I did a whole bunch of mountain biking- How many lives you got left there, Mr.
Speaker 0: Kent?
Speaker 1: I've burned through maybe three or four.
Speaker 0: It's not looking too good.
Speaker 1: So this one's- this is a great- I'm very proud of this thing that happened.
Speaker 0: You're so proud, you're all gonna die.
Speaker 1: I'm hiking.
Speaker 1: The first day, all these warnings, everyone's like, "The Australian bush will fucking kill
Speaker 1: you."
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And even when I get there, I hike on this little trail, and I go down- so the Blue Mountains, there's this valley, and there's like a kilometer-ish tall sheer cliff surrounding it.
Speaker 1: So you go down into the valley, which is already a pretty substantial hike, and then down there- How do you get back out?
Speaker 1: Fucking climb.
Speaker 1: It's real hard.
Speaker 1: There's three or four points, at least where I was, where there's a stairway- I'm making finger quotes- bolted into the side of the mountain so you can get up.
Speaker 1: But the stairway is half stairway, half ladder, half rough cliff edges.
Speaker 1: There's a little train you can take in one point.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: That sounds good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there is a train, and basically, everywhere near that train is where all the people who- Who aren't gonna die.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who can't hike.
Speaker 1: There were people wearing flippy floppies, little kids, families.
Speaker 0: They did not have a brush with death in the brush.
Speaker 1: So the one thing I learned real quick was that all the signs and all the stuff everywhere, because there's all these signs that are like, "If you were behind this sign, well, you might just
Speaker 1: die.".
Speaker 0: They're not lying.
Speaker 1: So what's behind those signs is not that deadly, assuming a couple things.
Speaker 0: Not that deadly.
Speaker 0: So it's- Assuming you are Superman.
Speaker 1: It is no more deadly than the trails I hike in upstate New York, because basically, all those signs, they're trying to scare away tourists, because a lot of tourists go there.
Speaker 1: People who go to the Appalachian, the mountain areas, and climb in the US, very few people go to those places, except White Mountain, that you can drive up to the top of, unless they know how to deal.
Speaker 1: They know orienteering.
Speaker 1: They know hiking.
Speaker 1: They know this stuff.
Speaker 1: But the Blue Mountains in Australia, a lot of tourists go up there- Sure, there wasn't a poisonous animal there that was too small to see.
Speaker 1: Nah, not really.
Speaker 0: Some spiders.
Speaker 1: So the only special warning I got- When I went mountain biking is a guy's like, "Oh, wait, you're from the States.
Speaker 1: Do you know about Australian
Speaker 1: snakes?".
Speaker 1: And I was like, "Don't fuck with
Speaker 1: them.".
Speaker 1: And he's like, "Yeah, don't fuck with
Speaker 1: And that was literally the extent.
Speaker 1: He wanted to make sure I knew not to fuck with snakes in Australia.
Speaker 0: Who was gonna- I'm sure he's had tourists fuck with snakes.
Speaker 0: I guess.
Speaker 0: Like, "Ooh, a snake.
Speaker 0: Let's fuck with
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: "Ooh, an alligator.
Speaker 0: I'll poke it with a
Speaker 0: stick.".
Speaker 1: Well, you know, people who live in the US, there's a lot of places where the average snake you run into is pretty harmless.
Speaker 1: Like a lot of kids will catch garter snakes, but anyway.
Speaker 1: So all those warnings basically say if you don't fucking know what you're doing, it's dangerous back here.
Speaker 1: So if you know what you're doing, it's actually not dangerous.
Speaker 0: So- Except for the one time it is.
Speaker 1: So what I did is I hiked on Federal Pass.
Speaker 1: I did a bunch of other hiking.
Speaker 1: I was in the Valley all goddamn day.
Speaker 1: So I took this little trail out through Federal Pass, through all these, like this old coal mine, through an area- Oh, that's not dangerous at all.
Speaker 1: Not in the coal mine, like through the area where the coal mine was.
Speaker 1: Over an old land slip, so this giant landslide, you kind of skirt the edge of the ruins.
Speaker 0: That's not dangerous whatsoever.
Speaker 0: And way out there- I just walked across the pit of lava, and up the mountain of doom, and over the jagged rocks of death.
Speaker 1: So I'd been hiking all day, and I was real tired.
Speaker 1: I'd gone a long way.
Speaker 1: And I still had plenty of provisions, like I was pretty good on water, and I had a little bit of emergency food left, and all my, it's like my Mylar blanket, and my life straw, and my compass, and all the stuff I would need.
Speaker 0: Going through Tombstone Gulch.
Speaker 1: So I'm going to leave, and then I say, "Oh, I'd read this trail map that said, 'Ruined Castle Rock is a really cool thing to see,' and Mount Solitary, which is further out from that, is amazing.
Speaker 1: But all the things I read said it's real hard and dangerous to get to these places.
Speaker 1: But then I get to- Does Ruined Castle Rock have an actual ruined castle?
Speaker 1: It has a giant rock formation that, from a distance, really looks like a medieval castle.
Speaker 1: It looks like a medieval castle that fell into disrepair.
Speaker 1: But then you get up to it, it's like, "No, it's just
Speaker 1: rocks.".
Speaker 0: But- Quite a disappointment.
Speaker 1: But yeah.
Speaker 1: But still, from a distance, it really looks like a castle.
Speaker 0: I'll look on Google Image Search and all that.
Speaker 1: From what I read, early people who got to that area, white people who were colonizing and disrupting, they saw it in the distance, they were like, "Uh-oh.
Speaker 1: Is there civilization?
Speaker 1: Uh-oh.".
Speaker 1: But then they got out, they're like, "Oh, it's just a rock
Speaker 1: formation.".
Speaker 0: Arty har har.
Speaker 1: So I see a sign, and the sign's like, "Ruined Castle, 3.6
Speaker 1: kilometers."
Speaker 1: That's not far.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Even over rough terrain-".
Speaker 0: Of course, you have to cross over Tombstone Valley.
Speaker 1: Even over rough terrain, that is not a hard hike.
Speaker 1: So I look at my maps, and the trail gets dodgy in a few places, but not that bad, so I figure I'll go for it.
Speaker 1: And I actually ran there, because I run five k's, they're like, "It's no big
Speaker 1: deal.".
Speaker 1: So I get there, and it's basically these three pillars of rock, hundreds of feet tall.
Speaker 1: And it's amazing.
Speaker 0: You knocked one down, and it fell on you.
Speaker 1: So I climbed up on top of the tallest one.
Speaker 0: That's a bad idea.
Speaker 1: Because I know how to climb, it's not that dangerous.
Speaker 1: Like Emily and I, either one of us- You knocked down the historic castle rock.
Speaker 1: It is trivial to climb this thing if you have even basic bouldering skills.
Speaker 1: Luke Burrage apparently also climbed the exact same rock, he's been on that same spot.
Speaker 1: You destroyed the historic castle rock.
Speaker 1: No, no, the story's about how I almost died, not how I knocked down Stonehenge.
Speaker 0: And you fell off of it with the rocks that ripped off.
Speaker 1: So, I'm standing on the top, there is zero wind, there is nothing higher than me in any direction, except way off.
Speaker 1: in the distance is the cliff wall of the valley surrounding me on all sides.
Speaker 1: And then in one direction, the one side other than that, is Mount Solitary, which is another four kilometers.
Speaker 1: But apparently there's no tracked trail, you've got a straight up orient to it.
Speaker 1: And I actually didn't have enough water to make it to Mount Solitary, and back to Castle Rock, and back to Civilization.
Speaker 1: So I decided not to go to Mount Solitary.
Speaker 1: In retrospect, I kind of wish I did.
Speaker 0: Is Mount Solitary?
Speaker 1: I would have had to hike back in the dark, which I was prepared for.
Speaker 0: It's not because Superman lives there.
Speaker 1: I was not, I could have hiked back in the dark, but I did not want to.
Speaker 1: I did enough night hiking the night before.
Speaker 0: Almost dying once is good.
Speaker 0: Actually dying.
Speaker 1: Night hiking was pretty easy because of the super moon, actually, believe it or not.
Speaker 1: Because I had to go up the cliff face at the end, but the moon was at my back so I could see everything great.
Speaker 1: I didn't even need the flashlight until I got over the top of the valley and had to hike the rest of the way to the car.
Speaker 1: So I'm on top of this thing.
Speaker 1: It's amazing.
Speaker 1: It's breathtaking.
Speaker 1: I see Mount Solitary in the distance.
Speaker 1: I'm standing there on a pillar of rock that's about a meter in diameter.
Speaker 1: And suddenly a giant bug hits me in the face.
Speaker 1: And I instinctually go, ah, to swat it out of my face.
Speaker 1: And I was wearing my fancy sunglasses that stick out further than my normal glasses.
Speaker 1: And I literally hit my glasses, knocked them off my face, and they were gone.
Speaker 1: And you know me.
Speaker 1: I can't see for shit.
Speaker 1: I probably could have climbed down the thing, but I don't think I could have made it back to civilization without my glasses.
Speaker 1: I would have had to call the Rangers for help.
Speaker 1: I would have been in a lot of fucking trouble.
Speaker 1: And in fact, climbing down the thing would have been doable, but not optimal.
Speaker 1: I would have had to make a lot of very serious decisions in a hurry without my glasses.
Speaker 0: There happened to be someone there?
Speaker 1: No, I did not see a human being anywhere in that valley.
Speaker 1: It was easily a 5K hike to any humans.
Speaker 0: Called someone on your phone?
Speaker 1: So I did have cell service, which was good.
Speaker 0: Where was the cell tower?
Speaker 1: The whole, because it's in a valley.
Speaker 1: So the whole valley actually has cell service, which is great.
Speaker 0: So the valley with no people in it, but cell service.
Speaker 1: Because a lot of hikers are back there.
Speaker 1: So actually for safety, like that's the cost to run that cell tower is probably way cheaper than the cost of Rangers looking for people who are dying on a regular basis.
Speaker 1: So it was a Samurai Jack moment.
Speaker 1: My glasses are flying off and I just freeze and close my eyes immediately.
Speaker 1: And I listen and I hear a little, and it was too soon to have been the glasses falling all the way down.
Speaker 1: Also too loud.
Speaker 1: And it didn't sound like they hit rock and bounced.
Speaker 1: So based on where the sound was, I creep over to the edge of this pillar and I look over and there's a bush sticking out of the side and there's a couple other bushes a little bit further down.
Speaker 1: And I think I see, it looks like my glasses might be hanging from that first Bush.
Speaker 1: So I very carefully climbed down the side and they're not in the first Bush there's, but they are in the second Bush, the second Bush.
Speaker 1: So I put them back on and I climbed back up to the top because it was too dangerous to climb down there and I wait for my adrenaline to stop pumping.
Speaker 1: and then I enjoyed the rest of my day and it was great.
Speaker 0: Why don't you get the thing that A. attaches less to your face, B. contact lenses, C. new eyeballs.
Speaker 1: So I have the thing.
Speaker 1: D.
Speaker 0: don't do anything where you could die.
Speaker 1: To hold the glasses to my face.
Speaker 1: I have a croaky.
Speaker 1: It's in my ski stuff.
Speaker 1: I didn't think I would need it hiking.
Speaker 1: I did not think I would punch myself in the face.
Speaker 0: You did not think you would die, but it's going to happen if you keep doing crazy stupid shit.
Speaker 1: So I highly recommend if any of you are ever in the blue mountains, uh, if you know how to hike and camp and all that shit, seriously, ignore the warnings, hike to at least ruin castle.
Speaker 1: It is breathtaking.
Speaker 0: I recommend bringing more, more than zero people with you.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Make that solitary mountain not so solitary.
Speaker 1: So Mount solitary, they do recommend having at least three people and one skilled orientarian.
Speaker 0: Bring some equipments with you.
Speaker 1: Maybe I had a lot of equipment with me.
Speaker 1: So I had multiple layers of sports gear, so I was actually equipped for very cold weather if need be.
Speaker 0: I had melting when it's hot out.
Speaker 1: Uh, no, I wasn't because it's fancy sports gear.
Speaker 1: I could shift layers and open.
Speaker 0: So rich people only.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Actually I had a life straw so I could actually drink water if I needed to.
Speaker 1: I could forge for water safely.
Speaker 1: I had a mylar to mylar Cape safety blanket.
Speaker 1: So if I like broke my leg and was stuck there dangerously, I could wrap myself up in a mylar cocoon to stave off, uh, exposure death long enough for someone to find me.
Speaker 1: I had a real compass, like a sighting compass.
Speaker 1: I had a topographic map.
Speaker 1: I was at my cell phone and I had maps and everything in there.
Speaker 1: I was tracking my GPS positions the whole way and I had registered my hike and my estimated return with the ranger's office.
Speaker 1: So if I didn't come back, someone would have eventually gone and looked for me and I had enough equipment to survive.
Speaker 0: Or would they?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they would have.
Speaker 1: They take that shit seriously.
Speaker 1: In fact, I could have taken out tracking beacon with me.
Speaker 1: if I wanted that I could hit a button on it as a, Oh shit, Rangers, come find me.
Speaker 1: But I decided I was not doing anything dangerous enough to warrant that.
Speaker 0: That was wrong.
Speaker 1: Uh, I wasn't, I didn't need that beacon for where I was, whatever your glasses were not in the bush.
Speaker 1: Uh, then I would have climbed down and decided what to do.
Speaker 1: Either I would have called triple zero or, uh, to, you know, and just basically nine one one and waited for Rangers to find me.
Speaker 1: Or I would have slowly made my way down the trail that I had taken towards civilization and gone as far as I could safely get without seeing and hope to run into someone.
Speaker 0: And then you don't see the snake.
Speaker 1: Uh, that would have been a danger except it was evening and actually, cause I couldn't see any way snakes.
Speaker 1: So snakes really would only be on the trail during like bright, bright sunlight resting cause snakes avoid people.
Speaker 1: So I would have made noise people living snakes.
Speaker 1: So get this, if it was dark, I wouldn't have been any worse off and the snakes wouldn't be out.
Speaker 1: So actually walking back in the dark without my glasses would have been a way easier time for the poison bats and spiders, poisonous bats, owls.
Speaker 1: Uh, the biggest danger might've been a cockatoo fucking with me because they like to fuck with people.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Eat your eyeballs.
Speaker 0: Not protected now.
Speaker 1: But anyway, we're back.
Speaker 1: Geek Knights is back.
Speaker 1: We're hopefully going to be mostly uninterrupted like normal.
Speaker 0: Be prepared.
Speaker 0: The last episode of unique nights is coming soon.
Speaker 0: Next time rim goes on a deadly trip.
Speaker 1: You wouldn't continue the show without me.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I'll get.
Speaker 1: Emily knows how to use a Mackie.
Speaker 1: She could keep the show going.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: We'll make the last geeky.
Speaker 0: Nice with rim.
Speaker 0: Enjoy it while you can.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 1: October 31st is going to be our 10th anniversary of geek nights.
Speaker 1: Exciting for real arbitrary numbers, but anyway, that's all.
Speaker 1: At a moment stuff.
Speaker 1: I got an announcement for them at a moment, but uh, yeah, it's Monday.
Speaker 1: It's tech news day and there's so much tech news.
Speaker 0: We've got to focus on a show and so long there's news and bits for everything.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of things I want to talk about that we're going to skip because there's bigger things that happened more recently.
Speaker 1: So I guess your news is probably the most interesting.
Speaker 1: I guess mine is.
Speaker 1: So yeah, Volkswagen is probably the biggest news in terms of like actual impact of the world.
Speaker 1: Volkswagen is a horrible fucking company and Jews never buy Volkswagens.
Speaker 1: I like how John Oliver basically was like, remember the member, the Nazis trusted Volkswagen and he had all these spots.
Speaker 1: He was, he was very fairly unfair to Volkswagen.
Speaker 0: Jews don't buy Volkswagen.
Speaker 1: So Volkswagen independent of their interactions with the Nazis in world war II because you know, IBM, a lot of companies interacted with the Nazis in world war II IBM at least.
Speaker 1: it's interesting how Germany is basically the model for a modern democratic socialist state.
Speaker 1: Like for real actual social, like Germany's a pretty great place governmentally.
Speaker 1: Germany's taken in more problems, but so does everybody, but they're taking in more refugees than everyone, which is kind of interesting in light of their, but Volkswagen was always seen as a like fair, well run company globally.
Speaker 1: Like Volkswagen would be given the benefit of the doubt by a lot of countries and a lot of people.
Speaker 1: And they had a reputation for making diesel cars that were super fuel efficient, super non-polluting, super green, like the best cars.
Speaker 1: Like if you care about the environment and you want to save money on gas, like these are the best cars.
Speaker 0: I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: We went to the Volkswagen dealer, that lady was giving us the hard sell and I listen to that.
Speaker 1: She closed the door repeatedly.
Speaker 0: and make us listen to how great the thing that really made me realize we shouldn't buy any cars there, you know, because at first, you know, at first, obviously Jews don't buy Volkswagens.
Speaker 0: It's like, all right, you know, I buy an IBM computer, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, whatever.
Speaker 0: It's not like.
Speaker 0: I went there.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I saw the big lineup at the service center.
Speaker 0: The other car dealers did not have.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: That's actually true.
Speaker 0: Volkswagens are super unreliable.
Speaker 0: So the long story short, because I realized it wasn't just an anecdote like that Volkswagen had a big lineup that day.
Speaker 0: It's like, no, they're actually statistically not reliable cars relative to other cars.
Speaker 1: So if you haven't been following the story, I'm going to summarize it really succinctly.
Speaker 1: Volkswagen has been cheating on their emissions tests for a long time.
Speaker 0: So the software in the car was written such to detect when the car was being given an emissions test.
Speaker 0: And when a car was being given an emissions test, the engine changed function to have lower output so that it would pass the emissions test.
Speaker 1: And other things too, like basically it turned on all the emission controls that the cars said they have.
Speaker 1: Like it did what the car is expected to do all the time.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, it turned the air conditioning off, right?
Speaker 0: It turned all these things off, you know, to make sure that you were getting, you know.
Speaker 1: But it's a little worse than that.
Speaker 1: The controls, like the actual, like not just air conditioning, like basic stuff like that, but like the actual pollution control systems themselves were all on.
Speaker 1: If the car was reasonably sure that it was being driven on the road by a normal person, it turned everything off.
Speaker 1: It spewed ridiculous amounts of pollution.
Speaker 1: We're not talking like one percent more pollution.
Speaker 1: We're talking like 40 times the amount of pollution.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: This is interesting.
Speaker 0: People think they're like, oh, industrial pollution is really the big problem.
Speaker 0: And yeah, it is, you know, but all the cars added up is a tremendous problem equal to, you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, people don't realize if you take just five percent of all the cars, the five percent of cars that are really, really bad, that have awful emissions, put out like ninety five percent of all the air pollution.
Speaker 0: If all the cars on the road were like super nice and even though they're gas powered.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You're not even hybrid cars, just efficient, well maintained, not broken, truly passing emissions.
Speaker 0: test cars like.
Speaker 0: total air pollution from cars goes down by ninety five percent.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's one reason why like hybrids and electric cars are such a big deal for pollution, because yeah, they're using the same energy, arguably more because of transmission losses.
Speaker 1: But instead of having five, you know, millions of poorly maintained, I mean, I did not maintain that purple car I had at RIT very well.
Speaker 0: But I mean, even just a normal, non hybrid, non electric car that actually has, you know, regular good, you know, good efficiency and is, you know, proper pollution controls is perfectly fine.
Speaker 0: You know, at least is ninety five percent better than a Volkswagen.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying on that other argument, the electric manufacturing can have an economy of scale.
Speaker 1: If you can put pollution controls on a giant smokestack that you can't put on millions and millions of tiny little smokestacks.
Speaker 1: But the the the moral of this is that this isn't just like they cheated a little bit or they cheated a ton.
Speaker 1: They cheated, biggest cheating openly, blatantly, hugely to the point that like the article I'm going to link to here talks about how this would have had to have been a gigantic institutional conspiracy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Because you have to you have the software.
Speaker 0: So obviously the engineers who wrote the software have to know.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, hey, Scott, Broadway dot com.
Speaker 0: We need someone told you an engineer is just not going to think to do that.
Speaker 0: Someone told them to do it.
Speaker 1: Scott, we need you to put a backdoor in the site personally.
Speaker 1: Now, don't tell any of your other teammates about this, but put a backdoor here.
Speaker 0: So it could have been just a small number of people, but it had to be like the QA.
Speaker 0: people are checking this code.
Speaker 0: People are testing this.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, there's a lot of people who would have had to been in on this who didn't blow the whistle.
Speaker 0: It might not have been.
Speaker 0: everyone like the CEO might not have known about it.
Speaker 0: You know, it's possible.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But a lot of people at the company had to know about it and not say anything.
Speaker 1: And even worse, low level people wouldn't do this on their own.
Speaker 1: Like, that's crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Why would they think to do that?
Speaker 0: And even if they thought to do it, it has someone had to order someone to do this.
Speaker 0: I mean, no, no one who's just like a software engineer is going to write this into the softwares of their own unless like they'd have to be like a genius who wanted to really get the company bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So beyond that, the reason it wasn't caught for so long is partly because Volkswagen had such a good reputation that the EPA and all the testing that just happens both in the US and other countries, they didn't give Volkswagen a pass, but they had bigger fish to fry.
Speaker 1: So they didn't give them deep scrutiny because they had a good reputation and they were mostly going after big diesel trucks lately because those are the real problems.
Speaker 0: They're real bad.
Speaker 1: And two, they're underfunded because of Republicans and politics in the US.
Speaker 0: Everything's underfunded.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like this would have been caught immediately if the EPA had been funded.
Speaker 1: So and also, you know, there are a lot of states that don't have emissions testing like in Michigan.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: My I drove a car that would not have been street legal in New York or California when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: That's just how it went.
Speaker 1: But the testing now, basically, from what I can see, there's a big move to where the people are responsible for this testing.
Speaker 1: One, this is such a big deal that there's talk of criminal charges like.
Speaker 1: I hope that people go to jail.
Speaker 1: I hope that the US extradites executives from Volkswagen and Germany better not say no.
Speaker 0: Why don't they just put them in German jail?
Speaker 0: Why do we got to be always doing that?
Speaker 0: We're always cleaning up their messes.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, you know, and then when they try to come after our companies, Google alone, you fuckers, it's like you could go after Google if they did something this bad and I would be like, OK, go for it.
Speaker 0: But they didn't do anything.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, it was on.
Speaker 1: if anyone Amazon's doing bad stuff right now by deciding to not sell streaming devices except theirs.
Speaker 0: If you're a store, you're allowed to sell whatever you want to.
Speaker 0: a grocery store is only selling Chiquita bananas now to a point and not Bonita banana to a point.
Speaker 1: Amazon is such market share that they.
Speaker 1: it's arguable that in a class, we're in a class where another division of Amazon competes streaming devices.
Speaker 1: They probably shouldn't be allowed to ban competitors products from their store using yours.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Also, I mean, antitrust is so weak lately.
Speaker 0: I know I know.
Speaker 0: Antitrust is what it should be, but all of these companies would be in like one hundred pieces.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying Europe's going after Google for the things they're going after Google for and get this Amazon shit.
Speaker 1: OK, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: Because, you know, there's an Amazon dot code at whatever country and they're happy with that.
Speaker 1: But based on the existing law, Volkswagen basically would be fined a certain amount per vehicle, which, because this is such a huge conspiracy, could be twenty, thirty billion dollars, never mind.
Speaker 1: And that's just the statutory fee.
Speaker 1: That's not punitive and criminal charges on top.
Speaker 0: We should basically just own their company like Volkswagen is not property of the US government.
Speaker 1: It would be like.
Speaker 1: these are the things that couldn't easily happen.
Speaker 1: But if this were a manga like Eagle, you could see the president being in Congress being like.
Speaker 1: Volkswagen is banned from selling in the United States.
Speaker 0: I know it'd be like Volkswagen.
Speaker 0: The company is now a subsidiary of the United States of America.
Speaker 0: We are selling all of it and taking all the money or eminent domain.
Speaker 1: Every unsold Volkswagen car in the US.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Every Volkswagen car in the US is also owned by the US government.
Speaker 1: Well, no, although if a consumer owns one, the government should at least pay you the unsold ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think dealers.
Speaker 1: I think every everyone who owns one of these Volkswagens should basically be given a new car by Volkswagen.
Speaker 1: because because here's the thing.
Speaker 1: They bought a car that had emissions ratings and performance ratings.
Speaker 1: The recall will fix the emissions problems by ruining the performance.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: You didn't get what you paid for.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Fuck Volkswagen.
Speaker 1: That's what I got to say about this.
Speaker 1: And every other car company, there's hints from the EPA and a lot of other regulators that basically, guys, if you're cheating, might be good to tell us now because you think we're not going to test every goddamn car ever from now.
Speaker 0: And also, even if you like you stop cheating now, your old cars are on the road now.
Speaker 0: You can't go and get your Toyota Camry from 2010 and like bring it back and fix it before the EPA finds.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that code is there.
Speaker 0: They're going to.
Speaker 0: this is also, you know, you should be forced to have open source software in your car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you shouldn't be allowed to have that.
Speaker 0: Should be closed source.
Speaker 1: So this gets into a wider problem of the fact that corporations can have such control over these things like car firmware and car emissions.
Speaker 1: And yet, you know, people who are against tighter regulation of technology, which I'm for in a lot of cases like Internet, like I want more regulation.
Speaker 1: I want a neutrality as a lot of technologists do.
Speaker 1: the fact, you know, people say we don't need regulation, but a trustworthy or at least until now trustworthy, respected global company that generally people had a very high opinion of engaged in massive global, cripplingly damaging to the environment, fraud and conspiracy to commit fraud pretty much says you need regulation.
Speaker 0: Well, someone said something very clever, which is that regulation is built on the idea right that you can't trust people to not lie, but you can trust things to not lie.
Speaker 0: But this is a case where things lied.
Speaker 0: And the only way to make things not lie is if it's not any proprietary, closed source software, then, you know, things aren't lying.
Speaker 1: because if you have code, you can hook up unit tests all around that code and ask the code.
Speaker 1: Hey, what do you do?
Speaker 1: You can ask the car.
Speaker 0: Everyone should be able to read the code.
Speaker 0: If I own the car, I should be, you know, by law, I should be able to have, you know, the full diagram plans for everything in the car, including all the software.
Speaker 0: For any device you buy, all that stuff should be given to you, even the OS that runs on the device.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I take a radical stance, but I don't.
Speaker 1: I don't want to go that far.
Speaker 1: I would be happy with a little bit of that.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: I'm paying you any amount of money for this thing.
Speaker 0: And especially a car where your life is on the line.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 1: I agree with you.
Speaker 1: I disagree in the sense that politically we can't get anything done.
Speaker 0: No, but that's, you know, let's not talk about anything else except the fact that governments are corrupt because there's.
Speaker 0: no we can't get anything done.
Speaker 0: Paging Lauren's lesson is not talk about anything else because there's no point.
Speaker 1: You got any other news?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's a tiny news.
Speaker 0: Adobe had a big thing today.
Speaker 0: They made a bunch of announcements and updates to their stuff.
Speaker 0: The one that probably matters to people listening here, if you care, is they update a lot of the mobile apps for the Android and the iPhone.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, the iPhone and the Android even.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Correct order there.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So the big update is Lightroom Mobile's way improved.
Speaker 0: And I think it's even.
Speaker 0: it says in the update, I think it's some somewhat free.
Speaker 0: Like if you'd even if you're on Creative Cloud, I think Lightroom Mobile is somewhat free.
Speaker 0: And some of these other apps might be partially free.
Speaker 1: I noticed that because some of the apps I installed, like they did stuff before I authenticated my creative.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And I mean, there's apps that do the same thing that are also free.
Speaker 0: So it's kind of stupid.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Like you can get VCO cam for free.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the big one they did is there are four apps, brush, hue, color and shape, and they combine them into one, which is Adobe capture.
Speaker 0: And it's like, yes, I don't have four stupid icons on my screen.
Speaker 0: Now I only have one icon.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's the best news.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, Google split wallet into wallet and Android pays.
Speaker 1: And I got two icons instead of one.
Speaker 1: And also, and I'll talk about this on another show in the future, but last tiny news, the much awaited successor to the Nexus five, the Nexus five X. Like it's out.
Speaker 1: The specs are out.
Speaker 1: It's garbage.
Speaker 1: It's not materially better than the existing Nexus five, except it has a working camera as opposed to a garbage camera.
Speaker 0: How about some iPhone action?
Speaker 1: We'll see what I do now.
Speaker 1: My last hope would have been the Xperia Z five.
Speaker 1: if one, these overheating problems aren't true.
Speaker 1: And two, I hold in my hand someone else's Z five compact that they have gotten Sanogen mod working on and they tell me how they did it.
Speaker 1: Those are the only two ways I'll ever buy a Sony phone.
Speaker 1: And the Nexus five X is garbage.
Speaker 1: It's bigger than the Nexus five.
Speaker 1: It's not that much faster or more powerful.
Speaker 1: And it has a bigger bezel.
Speaker 1: The screen's higher resolution, but the screen's not actually bigger.
Speaker 1: Just the bezels bigger.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know why they made this phone because they're not good enough.
Speaker 0: They're trying to do good, but they suck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but like the Nexus five X is just like it's a shittier version of all the other big phones.
Speaker 0: They're not good at it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So we'll see.
Speaker 1: I'll continue to use my Nexus five, which is still the best Android phone on the market, even though it has a bad camera.
Speaker 1: I know, Conrad, you keep telling me it has a bad camera.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: How many pictures you take him with it?
Speaker 0: I take a lot.
Speaker 1: I take a lot of crappy pictures with it because it's phone.
Speaker 1: I have a real camera to buy a camera.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Things of the day.
Speaker 1: NASA has released a little flicker gallery.
Speaker 1: All the pictures they took on the moon, not just the good ones like they'd released before.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like if you go to my place like because think about it, even a crappy picture of the moon in 1969 from the moon is a picture of the moon.
Speaker 0: Well, the 1969 reason these pictures look good is because if you look up the kind of cameras they brought when they went into space, they brought like these Hasselblad cameras that are like incredible.
Speaker 0: So that's why all the pictures of space from those days look incredible.
Speaker 0: But it's really interesting to see this because you can even you can even get the manual on how to use that camera that they gave to the astronauts because not like they were photographers or anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I mean, just think about that.
Speaker 1: We can see the full.
Speaker 1: it's like looking at my flicker photo stream like, yeah, that's all the pictures I took, not just the good ones.
Speaker 1: Like there's six pictures of Scott doing something weird and they're all like from different angles and like they tell a little story by themselves.
Speaker 1: That's not interesting enough to feature, but kind of neat to see.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So there's this group of kids called the Louisville, obviously from Louisville, Kentucky, leopards, percussionists.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it's like this is after school program where.
Speaker 0: You don't have it doesn't cost a lot of money or no money.
Speaker 0: And the kids can go and they practice percussion, drums, cymbals, marimbas, remember, xylophones, xylophones.
Speaker 0: And when they get these kids together, they make them play the highest quality tunes for your enjoyment.
Speaker 1: So if you search for them on YouTube, this already looks like a high quality group of kids here.
Speaker 0: If you search for them on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: There are many, many songs that they are playing.
Speaker 0: If you look in the sidebar there, I saw one where they're playing like I see a lot of Zeppelin hanging out in some war, some low rider.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, you know, here's that we're linking to a little Zeppelin here, but you can make a little YouTube playlist and enjoy.
Speaker 0: Also, you should be like very sad that these little kids are way better than you playing music in the moment.
Speaker 1: The book, the book was the Wheel of Time book one.
Speaker 1: You can get reviews up like it's done that episode.
Speaker 1: And Scott and I just kept reading them.
Speaker 1: So Scott's on book five.
Speaker 0: I'm almost on book five.
Speaker 0: I'm getting close.
Speaker 0: I'm almost done with book four.
Speaker 1: I'm about halfway through book four.
Speaker 0: So I'm on like 90 percent book four.
Speaker 1: So I'm not going to announce the new booklet book because we might just keep talking about the Wheel of Time a little bit because we're burning through them and they continue to plot at the same level of quality and pace.
Speaker 0: It's just plodding along.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The only thing I can travel to tell her on Riyadh in the early book, in the early high.
Speaker 1: I know a lot about that place now.
Speaker 1: I know about wolves now.
Speaker 1: So in book one, I wanted all three kids to shut up because Maureen and Land are the only people who know.
Speaker 1: And Tom were smart and the kids were stupid.
Speaker 0: Tom is still the best.
Speaker 1: In book two, the Perrin was the only one I liked other than the adults.
Speaker 1: Book three, all three of those kids are OK now.
Speaker 1: and the girls who want to be teenagers, they need to shut up.
Speaker 0: They need to just ram so sexist on the ladies to show up.
Speaker 1: Seriously, half the problems in that book stem from one of them said something they shouldn't have because they are kids and they don't know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: Well, the one who's not a kid is like so angry all the time.
Speaker 1: She is the worst of them.
Speaker 1: Just cool it seriously.
Speaker 1: Ninna vinna ninna wee.
Speaker 0: Oh, by the way, the pronunciations, if you look in the glass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like them.
Speaker 1: I was right on about 30 percent of them way wrong on the rest.
Speaker 1: Like I got more rain.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I got land.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, that's hard.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It could have been a long land party, long land party.
Speaker 1: It's a grain, I guess, not a grain.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, I thought it was a boy's name because I don't know how that stuff works.
Speaker 0: This is going.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Go away.
Speaker 1: Go in those two.
Speaker 1: Those two guys.
Speaker 1: I still can't tell them apart.
Speaker 1: I forget which one's which on text.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, every time they're mentioned, the context tells you which one it is because no one knows their names.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're just one of.
Speaker 0: the one is who's too good that he's bad.
Speaker 0: And the other one is the prince.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Anyway, generic prince guy.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, we're going to keep reading the Wheel of Time and goes round and round.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: No counts for a while till Magfest.
Speaker 1: We'll be talking.
Speaker 1: We're going to be at Magfest.
Speaker 0: We're doing a bunch of panels and I go to the New York Comic Con, but we're not going to the New York real soon.
Speaker 0: You can go if you want.
Speaker 1: We're doing things around the New York Comic Con.
Speaker 1: But we're not actually going to the New York Comic Con, which seriously, guys, unless you already live here, the New York Comic Con sucks.
Speaker 1: Like, I'm not even going to front like it.
Speaker 0: Every nerdy person I meet is going.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, why?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they like that.
Speaker 1: I have a free badge and the subway goes to the Javits.
Speaker 0: Now and now the subway goes directly there.
Speaker 1: I can get in a subway that I can see from my window and get out at the New York Comic Con with a free badge.
Speaker 1: I'm still not going.
Speaker 1: That's how much.
Speaker 1: I really don't like the New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: You just want to buy comic books and wait in line, wait in line to see things that have someone to have someone announce something or see a famous person that I don't give a shit about, who's in like some TV show.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: They're all famous people that you can usually see at smaller cons.
Speaker 0: Well, you can see the big famous people are on TV, but I don't watch garbage TV like you people.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And all the people I would want to see, they're not coming.
Speaker 1: Or if they're coming, they're at a bunch of other cons, too.
Speaker 1: So I'm not going to your comic.
Speaker 1: I'll see him in some smaller kind of what I actually care about.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like some of those people will be like mocha.
Speaker 0: So sure.
Speaker 1: So, yeah.
Speaker 1: And we're going to start off the Patreon we're talking about soon.
Speaker 1: But I realized there's something real I can offer through that Patreon to interest you kids.
Speaker 1: You know, we did beta geek nights for a long time before we did real geek nights.
Speaker 0: Anyone who signs of the Patreon gets the beta geek nights.
Speaker 1: I will prop.
Speaker 1: the one of the rewards I will give is I will periodically in Patreon only put up one of the pre geek nights beta episodes.
Speaker 0: Do you even know where they are?
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course I know where they are.
Speaker 1: I check every few months to see if they're still downloadable.
Speaker 0: But you're not going to give them the URL.
Speaker 0: You're going to upload them in a different place to put them up.
Speaker 0: But of course, once one person gets them, they can share them with everybody.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they could.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: I stand by my idea that DRM free.
Speaker 1: So if you say if you pay us a dollar on Patreon, steal these and make a torrent and post a link in the forum.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to stop you.
Speaker 1: You're a dick.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, I'm going to practice what I preach about DRM.
Speaker 0: Why don't we just make geek nights episodes that are only in there?
Speaker 1: There's going to be Patreon exclusive content, but it's going to take me a long time to spin that up because you can't even make regular content.
Speaker 1: Do you realize the majority of the messages I get through YouTube are yo dawg, why, you know, geek nights presents utenna 14.
Speaker 1: That is the majority of the of the messages I get.
Speaker 1: So Patreon is coming soon.
Speaker 1: And if enough people sign up for it, we will commit to going to PAX Australia 2016.
Speaker 1: So for the people dot com is down and that saga came to an end.
Speaker 0: So if you don't know what the saga might not be over yet.
Speaker 1: But saga is wonderful.
Speaker 0: But we had to talk about this.
Speaker 0: So there's something we've wanted for a long time.
Speaker 0: And suddenly this thing came out called People PEPLE.
Speaker 0: that was going to do exact all sort of exactly the thing that we thought about and knew was coming, which is Yelp for human beings.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: There would be a page for people and you would rate people.
Speaker 1: I've wanted that along with like Google Glass.
Speaker 1: My dream of augmented reality is to go to a room party at a convention and the that guys are rated and flagged as that guys by people I trust.
Speaker 0: As you look around and you see people and then you get information about those people just by looking at them like, oh, this guy's internet runner is a chill dude.
Speaker 1: This is a that guy.
Speaker 1: This gentleman actually was flagged by three of your friends as being a straight up creeper pickup artist.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So right now we have the Facebooks and stuff, which is you make a profile about yourself and you put your own stuff up on your own page.
Speaker 0: This would be the opposite.
Speaker 0: You put a there's a profile about you and other people put the content there about you.
Speaker 1: Now, there are two sides of that coin and a conceptual level.
Speaker 1: It's so obvious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Captain Obvious.
Speaker 1: Before we even talk about people.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, my use cases are great.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, you saw what happened with gamer gate and Twitter and all that nonsense.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know, I need to say that Sarkeesian's page is going to be so great.
Speaker 0: She's going to have such great reviews that are all true.
Speaker 0: And that's going to be a totally helpful profile to visit when you want to learn about her.
Speaker 1: So there were actually what's cool is like my sarcasm.
Speaker 1: The tech is totally working now when Scott and I came up with this idea and we still want to make this happen.
Speaker 1: Our idea was to use augmented reality and face recognition, all that.
Speaker 1: But it's not a public database of reviews.
Speaker 1: You subscribe to friend networks of individual people.
Speaker 1: So like my personal friends all share data about people we've reviewed.
Speaker 1: No one else gets that data.
Speaker 1: So I flag a dude is bad to my friends.
Speaker 1: So it's the same as me pulling you aside and saying, yo, see that guy over there in the fedora?
Speaker 1: Don't talk to him.
Speaker 1: So I think that gets around like 90 percent of those problems.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but people had another interesting way.
Speaker 1: And none of the reporting about people actually talked about this.
Speaker 1: The way people worked was everyone has a profile.
Speaker 1: Only positive reviews go up ever.
Speaker 1: Negative reviews never appear unless that person themselves has an active people account.
Speaker 1: So you can't negatively review someone who's checking all of these.
Speaker 1: Well, you have to give star ratings and stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but who's checking to make sure there's negative, what's negative and what's positive that I'm curious about?
Speaker 0: Actually, it's a manually check all this.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 1: I mean, maybe I didn't read all the details because people's gone.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There was.
Speaker 0: so it was such a controversial idea that they just shied away and disappeared.
Speaker 1: Supposedly, any negative review, even if you had an account, would go into a holding area and you get a notification.
Speaker 0: How would they know reviews negative?
Speaker 1: And I'm skipping that part, supposedly.
Speaker 1: That's why I keep saying supposedly.
Speaker 1: And you'd have 48 hours to contest it or flag it or whatever.
Speaker 0: And checking every 48 hours, you got to keep it in there for a long time.
Speaker 1: I guess the kind of people who would use the system like this, because honestly, I would not have signed up for people.
Speaker 0: No, I would not.
Speaker 0: What do I need it for?
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I want I'm going to rate people around me like like Yelp.
Speaker 1: I would rate the dude who sat next to me on the flight home from Australia.
Speaker 0: Jesus, God.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that guy.
Speaker 1: Oh, blessed be.
Speaker 0: That's what it's lasted.
Speaker 0: Be that's what it's for.
Speaker 1: He wheezed through his fedora.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that guy was.
Speaker 1: this was I can imagine I could write the review of that guy right now and just posted anonymously on Craigslist.
Speaker 1: That would be funny.
Speaker 0: But that's what it's for.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So I think we should just make people.
Speaker 0: They were too chicken to make it or at least it appears that you're going to make it.
Speaker 0: Well, let's just fuck while the iron's hot, let's just fucking strike.
Speaker 0: We'll make it.
Speaker 0: And here's how my version of people is going to work.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's going to be just like Yelp for people.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All profiles will be public.
Speaker 0: There's nothing private on the site whatsoever.
Speaker 0: However, we're not just going to make a profile for everyone.
Speaker 0: We're going to start only by making profiles for famous people because it's very clever.
Speaker 0: It's legally open season on famous people.
Speaker 1: In fact, if they're dead, you can basically do anything.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Van Gogh's going up first.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: We can learn.
Speaker 0: We can rat on Van Gogh all we want.
Speaker 1: We start with old dead celebrities and work our way down.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Then if you want one, a profile on there for a not famous person, we got to figure out where the line is on famous.
Speaker 0: But we'll probably just start with the epically famous only like, you know, president level.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And probably avoid known litigious actors like leave Tom Cruise off for a little while.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 0: Anyway, and then working our way down.
Speaker 0: But the way it's going to work is let's say I want to have a profile for me, but I'm not famous.
Speaker 0: The profile of me can only exist if I make it.
Speaker 0: Well, how do we know that someone else will just make a Scott Rubin profile?
Speaker 0: Well, because anyone who wants to make one, they have to call us themselves and we'll check and super check to make sure they're actually the person they say they are.
Speaker 0: And we'll make the profile for them after being super sure that they're them and they wanted the profile up.
Speaker 0: But once they do, there's no change in your mind.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Which is why we made super sure.
Speaker 0: And then once you have a profile, not only do you have a profile, but you can now review other people.
Speaker 0: You can't review other people unless you're putting yourself up to be reviewed.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So if you want to go up and, you know, get an account, you know, to go on to Scott Rubin's page and say how much of a jerk I am.
Speaker 0: Well, you better be ready for me to go on your page and say, well, this guy's just a random person who hates me.
Speaker 0: And that's the reason he hates me is because of this and this and this.
Speaker 0: And here's the horrible things I'm going to reveal about him.
Speaker 1: And that way, slander, libel, all that stuff pass through just like Google with the copyright stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's through led law.
Speaker 0: I guarantee that the person who posts this is actually this real person, because not the person who was commented on and the person commenting both verified with us that those accounts belong to the people they say.
Speaker 0: Oh, and those accounts cost money.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And that's how it should work.
Speaker 1: Now, the meta level, because people is pretty obviously one of those like startup people, startup, startup people had some money and an idea and they were getting other people to work for equity or whatever.
Speaker 0: Probably like this is going to exist whether you like it or not.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: We don't, you know, just like this is, you know, we talked about this on a privacy show many, many times.
Speaker 0: I think we had a whole show about it.
Speaker 1: A lot of people were so mad about people like guys, the people will exist.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I just want to reiterate this.
Speaker 0: It's like because so many privacy advocates out there and the thing that's the funniest to me are the people who are like they're anti copyright and pro privacy.
Speaker 0: It's like they're the same issue.
Speaker 0: The issue is whether you agree that it should be this way or not, it is impossible to stop the transfer of information that can be digitized as long as the Internet exists.
Speaker 0: There is nothing you can do about it.
Speaker 0: There is no legislation you can make that will stop it.
Speaker 0: There is no technological measure you can make that will stop it.
Speaker 0: It is a law of the universe, just like you can't, no matter how much you don't like gravity or the law of conservation of energy, you cannot stop them.
Speaker 0: Therefore, you just even though it sucks and I agree, it might be better in many or some ways if it wasn't this way, just like the world would be a lot better without the law of conservation of energy.
Speaker 0: But you just have to deal with it rather than try to fight it.
Speaker 1: Preventing something like people from existing in any form is impossible.
Speaker 1: It's like preventing me from telling Scott that some guy I met on an airplane flying back from Australia was a really horrifying person and personally annoyed me.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Therefore, we have to instead of trying to stop people from making a thing like people and should figure out a way for you to live in a world where people is an inevitability.
Speaker 1: Because it is an inevitability like I am shocked.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm not shocked, but it is interesting to see the ridiculous, immediate and such widespread, voluminous hate toward and anger about this platform.
Speaker 1: Like I get the impression that they expected a moderate amount of pushback and what they got was the Hoover Dam exploding like.
Speaker 1: And I suspect that's mostly because of all the nonsense that happened recently.
Speaker 1: Like this is a real problematic issue right now because U.N.
Speaker 0: play God.
Speaker 1: Well, it means that the people who made people have no idea what's going on on the Internet.
Speaker 0: Well, they're definitely they're out of touch for sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like this had to launch a specific incident, though, if this had launched two years ago, it would have made billions and been sold.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: But now it's hard to sell it as it is this kind of idea, because people are really mad about people and things like people.
Speaker 0: That means is a strike while the iron's hot, like I said.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean, most of the complaints were that people are afraid that they will get raided poorly and slanderous.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So let's imagine a world.
Speaker 0: let's say I could put up a site tomorrow and on the site, anyone can make a profile for anyone, upload any picture they want and write any comment they want.
Speaker 0: And all the URLs are like, you know, Scott's people dot com slash name.
Speaker 1: Now, the things like what would happen is the Internet actually did kind of exist.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: What would happen if I did that?
Speaker 1: There'd be a bunch of dicks and defamation and slander and libel and nonsense on there all over the place.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: And the people are on that side of you super mad at you and try to make you take it down for making a database with a Web interface that had upload picture, write name.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I mean, remember, Web blogs or when people would sign the guest book on a Web site, those basically had that same kind of content.
Speaker 1: Pretty much the day normal people get access to the Internet as opposed to just researchers, every one of those things was filled with spam and slander.
Speaker 0: You should just make a Web site and be like, just like that, be like, let it be spam, just like.
Speaker 0: just let it go, see what happens.
Speaker 1: I mean, I feel like harassment is something that has to be dealt with specifically and it cannot be dealt with with the blanket idea that you can't have other people.
Speaker 1: Third parties cannot talk about you on the Internet.
Speaker 1: You cannot prevent third parties from talking about you on the Internet, but you can deal with harassment in some fashion.
Speaker 1: And that is way beyond the scope of this episode.
Speaker 0: How to deal with it also comes into Europe's little right to be forgotten.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, let's say you did something really shitty a long time ago, like the prime minister with his pig dick thing.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And then someone post that so that now the whole world knows it's true in the U.S.
Speaker 0: Truth is safety from libel and slander because you did this thing a long time ago.
Speaker 0: It's true.
Speaker 0: And now you're it's like, well, that was a different time.
Speaker 0: You understand?
Speaker 0: I don't want to have to carry that my whole life.
Speaker 0: Well, you shouldn't have fucked up now.
Speaker 1: To be fair, it's easy for us to say that because we haven't fucked up.
Speaker 0: Well, not only that, I haven't done anything that I'm ashamed of.
Speaker 1: But what about things that you are not ashamed of?
Speaker 1: But widespread knowledge of them would harm you in the society in which you live.
Speaker 0: Anyone who tries to harm me, I'll fuck them over.
Speaker 1: What if you are a disempowered minority who does not have the ability to fuck them over?
Speaker 0: Then I'm not on the Internet, so it's not really a problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are disempowered minorities on the Internet.
Speaker 1: Are you being?
Speaker 1: are you racist?
Speaker 1: You're saying that minorities don't use the Internet?
Speaker 0: The Syrian refugees are not on the Internet.
Speaker 0: I'm not talking about them.
Speaker 0: The Internet is the least of their problems.
Speaker 1: I'm not.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about way higher in the tier than them.
Speaker 0: OK, so not super disempowered.
Speaker 1: Only still still pretty super disempowered, not mega or extremely disempowered.
Speaker 0: OK, you got a different disempowerment scale over there.
Speaker 1: Gargantuan, like D&D.
Speaker 0: What's the?
Speaker 0: what's the highest possible level of disempowerment?
Speaker 0: You're left alone on the moon?
Speaker 1: Yeah, on fire in a ditch, that whole thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: OK, you derailed my train of thought.
Speaker 1: I was going somewhere with this.
Speaker 1: OK, I was going somewhere pretty good with this.
Speaker 0: Why is anyone making a profile out of you if you're so disempowered?
Speaker 0: Why does anyone care?
Speaker 1: Well, because some bully in your high school decided to target just you and got everyone on board and then 4chan piled out on top of that for lulz.
Speaker 0: OK, so there's a page on the Internet that says bad things about you.
Speaker 0: This page exists.
Speaker 1: And it's truth.
Speaker 1: And it's and it says that you're homosexual and you live in Russia.
Speaker 0: OK, why are you still living in Russia?
Speaker 1: Because not everyone can just leave Russia.
Speaker 0: OK, so go to someone else's page and write down that they're homosexual on it.
Speaker 0: What are they going to do about it?
Speaker 1: Except that you don't have the clout with all the anti homosexual bullies.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: You just went to someone else.
Speaker 0: You went to every single page of everyone in your whole class and you wrote the same thing there.
Speaker 1: But your page has a dog pile of all the other people that the bullies knew amplifying it in a way that you cannot.
Speaker 0: How is it amplified?
Speaker 0: It's on one page.
Speaker 1: No, because they like it.
Speaker 1: So it's got like ten thousand like, yes, this is true.
Speaker 0: It has likes.
Speaker 1: So they post.
Speaker 1: so your profile has that from a thousand different accounts.
Speaker 1: OK, and their profile has it from one account that they just say, well, obviously it's Scott because he's so mad.
Speaker 0: How do they know?
Speaker 1: how did him?
Speaker 1: It's obviously not.
Speaker 0: how do you how do they know that what's on my page is actually true?
Speaker 1: Because they don't.
Speaker 1: they were doing it just to bully you.
Speaker 0: OK, so my page is a thing on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so so now so they amplify that with other people that they know because they target you semi randomly at that point.
Speaker 1: OK, so now there's an amplified signal against you and that signal is a signal that in that society could get you beaten up.
Speaker 0: How do they amplify the signal?
Speaker 1: Like I just specifically.
Speaker 1: OK, so usually what happens is one bully decides to pick on one kid for whatever reason.
Speaker 0: This has been.
Speaker 0: this has been true before the Internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: How is this any different?
Speaker 1: Because he does it on the Internet so he can amplify that signal way more, way beyond.
Speaker 1: In the old days, you could leave a high school, go to another high school, no one knew who you were.
Speaker 1: Nowadays, that bully train literally follows you to that high school.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 1: That it really does.
Speaker 1: That's how it works now.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: But I mean, so there's.
Speaker 0: but all you're not saying that have a web page is a web page that exists that has your picture and it says you're homosexual on it.
Speaker 0: How is that affecting you really that badly?
Speaker 1: If you live in Russia and you could be killed for being a homosexual.
Speaker 0: But how do they know that it's true?
Speaker 0: Everyone's page says it on there.
Speaker 1: Yours says it and more.
Speaker 1: yours says it more often.
Speaker 1: OK, like that's true.
Speaker 0: So if I make a spam bot and post it on someone else's page a thousand times, that makes suddenly makes them gay.
Speaker 1: And my 50 friends and their 500 friends all say it about you.
Speaker 1: And then one of those people just goes and beats you up because they knew you were targeted by me.
Speaker 1: What do you do about that?
Speaker 1: You can't fight back.
Speaker 1: You don't have an amplification back against that.
Speaker 0: That's how they.
Speaker 0: how can they tell the difference between a thousand people and a spam bot?
Speaker 1: They don't need to.
Speaker 1: They just know.
Speaker 0: They just know.
Speaker 1: Scott, you know how 4chan mobs form, right?
Speaker 1: Someone post saying, go after this kid.
Speaker 1: Here's his phone number.
Speaker 1: And a few thousand people decide to go after that specific person just because they don't need a reason.
Speaker 0: So 4chan already does this.
Speaker 0: So what does it matter if there's one more website that does the same thing?
Speaker 1: No, I'm saying that concept is the problem, not one more website doing it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: The problem still has to be dealt with in some fashion.
Speaker 1: Right now, it's not being dealt with.
Speaker 0: That problem has nothing to do with people.
Speaker 1: People, as it was modeled, could probably make that problem worse because it's not.
Speaker 1: it has so much media attention.
Speaker 0: I still don't see how there is.
Speaker 0: I could make a Web page tomorrow with a picture of.
Speaker 1: no one would care about your page, but if people had gone live, people would have cared about it a lot more because it was in the news and grandma and everyone's talking about it.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 1: And also, they're probably not going to have the the negative detection that we were talking about, because, like you said, how do they do that?
Speaker 1: And they didn't say how they think they could do that.
Speaker 0: I think the sort of humans reviewing, which is humans reviewing every single one, which is not going to work.
Speaker 1: I mean, guys, we used to review every single person who applied to the forum, and that was actually a lot of pain in the ass work.
Speaker 0: Well, it was only pain in the ass work because vanilla had really shitty spam filter, these spam applications.
Speaker 0: Now they fix that at least.
Speaker 0: So we still review everyone who tries to join the forum.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but now there's no there's very few spam applicants, so it's much easier.
Speaker 1: I've gone on for about an hour, but yeah, it looks like people came and went in a flash.
Speaker 0: There will be another people.
Speaker 1: There will be 10 things like people within five years that are all big enough to have the same impact.
Speaker 1: And it'll be interesting to see how that all evolves, because I don't want to miss out on this.
Speaker 1: I don't want to miss out on my Google Glass where I can find out if any of my friends have flagged someone as a creeper or racist.
Speaker 0: That is the right.
Speaker 0: That's the thing is people keep concentrating on like this worst case scenario, which isn't really any different than the Internet we have already.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And they're not focusing on the positive, not even thinking of any positive of this.
Speaker 0: And the positive of this is you can find out about people who really are bad well in advance and avoid them instead of like finding out later.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Horrible secrets about things.
Speaker 1: That's why maybe you make a really focused one.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: I just want to make some like fedora someone
Speaker 0: who, you know, and people don't have the sense of like justice, I guess, that I have and that some other people may have is that if someone did a bad thing, truly, maybe they deserve social consequences for the bad thing that they truly did.
Speaker 0: And they shouldn't be able to get away from that somehow.
Speaker 1: But the counterpoint to that is that there's a lot of societies where things that the society as a whole declares bad are not bad.
Speaker 0: That's that the real problem is that society.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: What do you do about Russia?
Speaker 1: What do you do about home up?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they look like they want to go to war.
Speaker 0: Let's give them war.
Speaker 1: I do seem to want to go to war and they want to go to war.
Speaker 0: Fine.
Speaker 0: I just like I just call up.
Speaker 0: if I was president, I would just call Putin.
Speaker 0: He'd be low on my list.
Speaker 0: I'd be calling up much worse places than that.
Speaker 0: But like I would call it I'd be calling up Saudi Arabia and I'd like Saudi Arabia.
Speaker 0: Let women drive tomorrow.
Speaker 0: No, I'm blowing up your country in one hour unless you let women drive.
Speaker 0: Are you the women driving it?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Here come the F-16.
Speaker 1: So I remember.
Speaker 1: Oh, was that Mecca got blowed up?
Speaker 0: Why don't you fix this?
Speaker 0: Oh, how many aircraft carriers do you have that you can do about this?
Speaker 0: No, let the women drive.
Speaker 1: Wasn't that Ex Machina, the now Saudi United States, the New York marriage.
Speaker 1: Welcome to America.
Speaker 1: Why don't you make that?
Speaker 1: Why does someone make that same comic?
Speaker 1: But it's the president.
Speaker 1: But he acts like Batman.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't understand why we don't do this.
Speaker 0: Why do we spend all this money in his military if we're not going to use it?
Speaker 1: Well, Russia's working on it.
Speaker 0: Russia is working on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They're going to, I mean, you saw these, they authorized sending ground troops to Syria, which is amazing because...
Speaker 0: What do they want there?
Speaker 1: That so...
Speaker 0: What do they care?
Speaker 1: what happens there?
Speaker 1: ...to derail.
Speaker 1: But if it was a video game or a movie, I'd assume that that is to put, to oil the war machine to make sure it works, to get it going again.
Speaker 0: Practicing.
Speaker 1: But that's crazy in the modern era.
Speaker 1: Also, because Russia's military sucks.
Speaker 0: And why do they care what happens in Syria?
Speaker 1: Well, because Syria is their ally for a bunch of reasons and they sell a lot of arms to Syria.
Speaker 0: But now you're not selling them arms.
Speaker 0: You're using arms that you bought.
Speaker 0: That you're losing money doing this.
Speaker 1: It might hardly be because they want to keep this puppet regime there to counterbalance what they perceive stupidly as American influence in the region.
Speaker 1: Because, yeah, our Afghanistan and Iraq puppet states are so valuable and secure to us.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes.
Speaker 0: What if it's a big con game?
Speaker 1: This is a long scam by the U.S.
Speaker 1: to trick Russia into getting embroiled in a land war in the Middle East.
Speaker 1: so we can back away and be like, "Well, not our
Speaker 1: problem.".
Speaker 0: Good strategy.
Speaker 1: That would also be a good plot for a movie.
Speaker 0: A+ strategy.
Speaker 0: Haha, we tricked you into going to war and ruining your own country.
Speaker 0: Yeah, here's the movie.
Speaker 1: It's Dave, but he is trying to trick Russia into invading North Korea.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it works.
Speaker 0: Russia, the country is ruined.
Speaker 0: And it's like, "Oh, he did all our work for us.
Speaker 0: We don't need the military.
Speaker 0: We can just do everything by
Speaker 0: talking.".
Speaker 1: Alright, it's been an hour.
Speaker 1: Uh, Geek Nights will be continuing normally from this point on.
Speaker 1: Stay tuned for, you know, videos to come up.
Speaker 1: I got a huge backlog of videos.
Speaker 0: We had to make the craziest show to make people remember what Geek Nights is about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's about this.
Speaker 0: We couldn't make anything that was serious or sensible.
Speaker 1: I was serious, mostly.
Speaker 0: How could you be serious about something on a website that misspelled the word "people"?
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I am not as serious as Land the Water.
Speaker 1: Who I think is the most serious person in that entire...
Speaker 0: Land's middle name is serious.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.