Speaker 1: It's Thursday, April 14th, 2016.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I am Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nides.
Speaker 1: Tonight, we're recording this in the future because Rym's off somewhere doing something.
Speaker 0: You mean the past.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Boat times.
Speaker 1: Times on boats.
Speaker 0: I'm on a boat.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: I actually watched that video again randomly recently because I had YouTube playing music.
Speaker 1: All these remixes.
Speaker 1: I can just let it go.
Speaker 1: YouTube was just playing its videos.
Speaker 1: Just video, video, video.
Speaker 1: But I wasn't watching them.
Speaker 1: I was just listening to them while I was working on something.
Speaker 1: And suddenly, I'm on a boat came in and I was like,
Speaker 1: "Alright."
Speaker 1: And then I just basically listened to their entire discography after that.
Speaker 1: I think my favorite song they've ever done is actually that Michael Bolton one.
Speaker 0: How did I know you'd pick that one?
Speaker 1: How could I not?
Speaker 1: When it gets to the Scarface stuff at the end, I can't help it.
Speaker 1: It's just too good.
Speaker 0: I think my favorite one is, "Throws you on the
Speaker 0: ground.".
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the most useful one in my day-to-day life.
Speaker 1: That one gets quoted the most.
Speaker 0: You can't trust the system.
Speaker 1: So, yeah.
Speaker 0: Then it's not a phone.
Speaker 1: I guess I'm at a financial conference today, so I'm not actually here right now.
Speaker 1: So that's my opening vid, and we're recording extra shows in the past for the future.
Speaker 1: So you got any news?
Speaker 0: No, because it's two days in the past.
Speaker 0: I don't know what's happening on Thursday.
Speaker 0: I can't do news about you.
Speaker 1: Not at all, but our news isn't supposed to be breaking news.
Speaker 1: You're not supposed to get your news from geek nights.
Speaker 0: Nothing has happened.
Speaker 0: It's been so boring.
Speaker 0: It's cold still.
Speaker 0: There's your news.
Speaker 1: It's warm now in the past, like warmer than it was.
Speaker 1: I wore sandals to work today.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: It's not warm enough.
Speaker 1: I wore sandals and white jeans.
Speaker 0: It's too cold.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll bike to work tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Just getting up there.
Speaker 0: It's too cold.
Speaker 1: It's not that cold.
Speaker 1: It's too cold.
Speaker 1: Not like last weekend.
Speaker 1: Fuck that.
Speaker 0: Fuck all this cold.
Speaker 0: It needs to be 80 at least.
Speaker 1: So for those of you who don't know, it got cold enough to snow last weekend in New York City, and this whole swatch.
Speaker 1: So I was at work on Thursday, and I saw someone tweet at me, and they tweeted at me this weather forecast that showed snow in New York days in the future, and I assumed they were joking.
Speaker 1: I did not believe them until later when I got a New York City advisory saying, "Yo, dawg.
Speaker 1: It's gonna freeze, so take your plants
Speaker 1: in.".
Speaker 0: It's too cold.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I got news.
Speaker 1: This is something Scott and I talked about a bunch in our lives, but we didn't talk about it on geek nights.
Speaker 0: It's not news.
Speaker 0: It's the oldest story in the book.
Speaker 1: March 20th, 2016 is not that long ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's a specific instance of a thing.
Speaker 1: Name another instance where this happened in this manner.
Speaker 0: Uh...
Speaker 1: I can name an instance where the opposite happened.
Speaker 0: That would give away a prank that I have been pulling on you for a very long amount of time, and I would rather not give that away.
Speaker 1: Ah.
Speaker 0: So just keep it going.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: So Kraft reveals revamped mac and cheese 50 million boxes later.
Speaker 1: The story is that Kraft, for various reasons, changed the ingredients in their mac and cheese.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The new formula removed artificial preservatives, swapped out artificial dyes for a combination of paprika, annatto, and turmeric under development for three years, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: So basically, they changed the ingredients, and this probably didn't change the flavor.
Speaker 1: They just made the ingredients better.
Speaker 1: So it's telling that they used paprika and all this, not necessarily because of their flavor profile, but to make it look like cheese, as opposed to what I guess it would look like without those things.
Speaker 1: I imagine Kraft mac and cheese looks hellish and inedible without food coloring in it.
Speaker 0: It looks, I mean, the way it looks when you make it is golden, right?
Speaker 1: If you make real mac and cheese, it doesn't look golden.
Speaker 1: It looks kind of whitish, but then it has the baking sort of like browning around the edges.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But they did this, and they had a big problem in the company, and apparently they debated this for a while, about whether or not to tell anyone that they were going to do it.
Speaker 0: All right, so let me tell you.
Speaker 0: So I used, for many moons, right, from like when I was very young until college, or no, until Beacon days, I drank this pineapple orange juice.
Speaker 0: It was Dole brand, right?
Speaker 0: The one with the sun for the... Dole brand, pineapple orange juice specifically.
Speaker 0: And if you looked at the ingredients of pineapple orange juice back in the day when I drank it, the ingredients were like pineapple juice, orange juice, lemon squirt, and then a bunch of other crap like, you know, water and maybe sodium benzoate.
Speaker 1: You drank this stuff like it was of religious libation.
Speaker 0: This show was so good because it basically had all the power of orangey, but the pineapple cut off the sort of, you know, super orange flavor and sweetened it up.
Speaker 0: But then this lemon squirt brought back the, you know, the citrus sting that you need.
Speaker 0: And it's like, it would clear your throat out of any gunk.
Speaker 0: and, you know, refreshing morning feelings came in like, ah, way better than Tropicana orangey.
Speaker 1: That drove people to drink and prescribe vinegar if they were out of lime juice to prevent scurvy.
Speaker 1: And guess what?
Speaker 1: That doesn't work.
Speaker 0: That doesn't work, but it tastes great.
Speaker 0: And one cup, eight ounces of it gave you 200 percent of your daily intake, which is unnecessary.
Speaker 1: But it still tasted good.
Speaker 1: In old geek nights, we used to talk about orange juice a lot.
Speaker 1: Like, I don't think you guys understand how important orange juice was to our day to day lives.
Speaker 0: So anyway, at some point when we were in Beacon, they changed the formula and it said on the carton like new, improved formula, whatever.
Speaker 0: And the difference here is that not only was it new, improved formula, but they drastically changed the flavor.
Speaker 0: The ingredient, number one ingredient, if you buy the stuff today, is apple juice.
Speaker 0: And it tastes mostly like apple juice.
Speaker 0: That squirt of lemon isn't even in there anymore.
Speaker 0: I don't know how much pineapple and orange there is, but not much.
Speaker 0: So at that point, I pretty much abandoned it and drank other juices.
Speaker 0: And I've tried to replicate that juice, you know, like just by taking oranges, pineapples, and lemon and combining them and it doesn't quite taste the same.
Speaker 0: Now, it tastes better sometimes because it's mad fresh, but it doesn't taste the same.
Speaker 0: So, but the thing is they, A, actually changed the flavor and B, told you.
Speaker 0: Here, they didn't change the flavor.
Speaker 0: They just changed the ingredients and they didn't tell you.
Speaker 0: because if they told you, but they didn't, you know, actually change the flavor, you'd still believe that it tasted different when it didn't.
Speaker 1: See, there's a third element to this, a third direction.
Speaker 0: And sales might go down and people start buying bunny brand instead.
Speaker 1: When this, I mean, it's interesting how this is something that's largely forgotten among young people, but we, you know, Coke, Coca-Cola changed and became New Coke.
Speaker 1: And they changed the flavor and they told everyone about it.
Speaker 1: Now, in that case, all the research they had done showed that people overwhelmingly preferred the new flavor.
Speaker 0: In a blind test, people preferred the new flavor.
Speaker 1: They would always say the new flavor was abjectly superior.
Speaker 1: And yet, when they told the public, "Hey, you all, we proved scientifically that you all love this new flavor, so this is the new flavor of
Speaker 1: Coke.".
Speaker 1: And people went crazy, boycotted it, disaster.
Speaker 1: This was, like, one of the biggest corporate disasters in, like, consumer product history.
Speaker 1: To the point that they actually went back to classic Coke.
Speaker 1: That's why Coca-Cola today will be like classic Coca-Cola.
Speaker 0: Every time you ask a question, like, "Why does company do something so stupidly?
Speaker 0: They could do it so much better.
Speaker 0: Why don't they do it so much
Speaker 0: better?".
Speaker 0: It's because most people on Earth are morons.
Speaker 1: Living in the dark, blindly feeling their way through things.
Speaker 0: And they just, they hate change.
Speaker 0: No matter what the change is, change is the enemy, right?
Speaker 0: The status quo is the friend.
Speaker 0: So, you can't change anything.
Speaker 0: So, Kraft did the smart thing, which is, "Yes, change it for the better, and don't tell anyone, because then the morons will stop buying
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: If they would have just started putting that better Coke in the Coke cans without saying anything, even then- People would have been like, "Whoa, this Coke feels really good, ah,
Speaker 0: ugh.".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't know why they don't do that now, especially, you know, but whatever.
Speaker 1: So, basically, if you read this article, because I'm not, you know, you can read the article, I'm not just going to summarize it all for you, but what Kraft did is they changed it, they changed it, and they kept it a desperate secret for a long time.
Speaker 1: Until they were confident that people had been eating the new one for a long time.
Speaker 1: No one noticed at all, and then they announced, "Hey, we've got a new Kraft whatever, and guess what?
Speaker 1: We already sold over 50 million boxes, and you've been eating it-".
Speaker 0: But they didn't make, like, a huge announcement.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they're TV commercials.
Speaker 0: I think the announcement was just like- They did a new ad campaign.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: After it was out there for a long time, saying, "It changed, but it hasn't, because none of you noticed.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing you've always had, but we did change it, so eat a
Speaker 1: dick.".
Speaker 0: They didn't have to say anything ever, they could have just kept doing what they were doing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the story is just an interesting sort of, even if you know there is a smart, right thing to do, or you know an answer to a question, if you interact with the mass market, you sometimes have to do very counterintuitive things, or hide information from people that is not relevant to them, because otherwise they will make very poor, ill-informed decisions based on things that they literally made up.
Speaker 0: You don't need to know that.
Speaker 0: What you need to know is that if you're the kind of moron who opposes something simply because it's changed, you're the problem in this world, fuck you.
Speaker 0: If you're the kind of person who, when you hear that something is now changed and improved, and that makes you excited, and you want to go seek it out, you are the good person who is the savior of this world.
Speaker 1: Now I wonder if the fact that you had such difficulty in those early days, because you guys don't understand, Scott was like experimenting with different mixes of the three juices for weeks when he lost his recipe, like trying to recreate it.
Speaker 0: If they hadn't said anything- I sent them a letter and they didn't help me out.
Speaker 1: If they hadn't said anything, would you have noticed?
Speaker 0: Would I have noticed, right?
Speaker 0: Well it is- Because maybe the reason- It is a very significantly different flavor, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I actually, if I recall correctly, I bought it and drank it and then said, "This tastes different," and then noticed the thing on the carton afterwards.
Speaker 1: But is it possible that the reason, because there's only three ingredients, like there's not that many options for your dosage here.
Speaker 1: Is it possible that the reason you can't recreate that flavor is that that flavor existed solely in the nostalgia post-change?
Speaker 1: Your brain created an ideal that cannot be attained.
Speaker 0: The only thing I have to reference the flavor now is my memory.
Speaker 0: I don't even have a sample, so I can't know.
Speaker 1: So you might have mythologized the memory of that flavor.
Speaker 0: But the original change happened at a period where I had a container of the old stuff and a container of the new stuff in the fridge at the same time.
Speaker 0: I polished off the old one and the next day I went for the new one, and I said, "Whoa, what's going on
Speaker 0: here?".
Speaker 0: There are times where, for example, one time I went to Grand Central to the Hot N' Crusty, which is closed by the way.
Speaker 1: I'm real sad about that.
Speaker 1: I haven't fully grokked it yet.
Speaker 0: I bought the one serving orange juice and I started to drink it and I went, "Ah!
Speaker 0: What is wrong with this one serving orange juice?
Speaker 0: Is it
Speaker 0: bad?".
Speaker 0: And I looked at it and I had accidentally purchased grapefruit orangy, and I can't take grapefruit.
Speaker 0: It's too acid-y and it's no good.
Speaker 0: And so even though my brain was thinking the whole time, "This is orangey," and didn't suspect any, you know, I just thought it was orangey.
Speaker 0: I didn't, you know, but my tongue did not lie.
Speaker 0: So there is an extent to which you can change something to where the senses will still detect change regardless of psychology.
Speaker 1: True, true.
Speaker 0: You can't put battery acid in the milk container to have someone drink it and go,
Speaker 0: "Ah!"
Speaker 0: Milk!
Speaker 1: Not with Benjamin R!
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day!
Speaker 1: What do you got?
Speaker 0: It was another link that I sent you.
Speaker 1: You don't remember this too?
Speaker 0: I have to click on it to remember it.
Speaker 1: Alright, so I can do mine first.
Speaker 1: So, as you know, one of the things that I hate and am displeased by more than anything else in the world is bike thieves.
Speaker 1: I've had my bike stolen multiple times.
Speaker 1: I know a lot of people have their bikes stolen.
Speaker 1: New York City is the bike stealingest place in America.
Speaker 1: It's a problem for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: And this is a video, purportedly, now I do not, I mean, it looks pretty legit, and I was going through this guy's channel, and I am not making a claim that everything in this channel is 100% legit.
Speaker 1: But, "Stun gun in bike seat, prank in the hood, electric bait bike prank, karma, social experiment" is the video.
Speaker 1: And the video is basically, he has a stun gun rigged with a cell phone hidden in a bike, and the stun gun is right where your balls are in a bike seat.
Speaker 1: So, he can call a number, and the stun gun just starts going.
Speaker 0: What the fuck is going on?
Speaker 1: And then the video is just leaving the bike unlocked in bad neighborhoods, waiting for someone to eventually steal it, and then calling the number and watching them get their balls shot.
Speaker 1: It is extremely cathartic to watch this video, and while I'm not necessarily a fan of vigilante justice, I'm not that opposed to this level of entrapment.
Speaker 1: The level of, here is an easy crime that would harm a person if it was a real crime, but it's actually a trap that will not kill them, it's not like there's a shotgun in the bike seat, but will cause them significant discomfort.
Speaker 1: So, while I enjoyed this, there's another video in the channel that I saw right after that, that I have to call attention to.
Speaker 1: Car Bomb Bait Car Prank in the Hood, Public Bomb Scare Prank, Instant Karma, Best Pranks.
Speaker 1: This guy has this fucking rigged up, fake looking, like a bomb, like three sticks of dynamite, and a really long set of, you know those fuses you buy if you make your own fireworks?
Speaker 1: Like the ones that go real slow and real big like pssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssss ssss.
Speaker 1: car and driving it around at people which is funny in its own.
Speaker 1: I mean obviously a little mean but just the idea of that is kind of funny to me.
Speaker 0: use it in a crowd.
Speaker 0: let me get on the roller coaster next.
Speaker 0: swerve gentlemen.
Speaker 1: but basically the what the gist of this video is purportedly and the video is pretty funny is he Lee.
Speaker 1: he parks a beater car in a bad neighborhood with the window down in the door and locked and there's some valuables laying around in the car and in the backseat is just this fake fucking bomb to sit in there and he waits for someone to sit down in the car because a car thief will just steal the car but it's a thief of opportunity will not like stand around outside the car like people who regularly steal from unlocked cars.
Speaker 1: they know what they're doing.
Speaker 1: if you see an unlocked car you open the door and you sit down in it and close the door.
Speaker 1: that way you're in the car.
Speaker 1: unless someone walks up to the car is the owner of the car.
Speaker 1: they're not going to think anything wrong with someone sitting in a car.
Speaker 0: so now I think this person knows a lot about bike stealing and cars.
Speaker 0: yeah it's not a high quality prison.
Speaker 1: well they're all they're they're they're.
Speaker 1: they're regular modern-day Batman.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: so the way this works is that after they sit in the car and there's cameras like rigged up in the car everywhere wait a few minutes or a few seconds and then trigger this.
Speaker 1: so the person turns around and usually some variation of what the fuck holy fuck followed by like running out of the car screaming dropping stuff.
Speaker 1: it's pretty great.
Speaker 1: but he went one step further.
Speaker 1: the car is rigged so that the handle on the inside of the car will not work.
Speaker 1: hmm so they have to jump out the window.
Speaker 1: so I invite you to enjoy these videos.
Speaker 0: so this guy someone I guess who follows this YouTube channel this is big Clive dot-com.
Speaker 0: what's up big Clive?
Speaker 0: somebody found a USB charger similar to the ones we get from anchor that let you charge five USB devices.
Speaker 1: I'm holding one of my hands right now.
Speaker 1: this one charges six.
Speaker 0: whoa daddy.
Speaker 0: yeah anyway I want to work.
Speaker 0: that is 10. so but this is like some off-brand crappy one.
Speaker 0: and someone bought this somewhere and when they went to use it they noticed like huh this shocked me when I tried to use it.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: well that can happen.
Speaker 0: no it shocked me like my muscles were like contracting whoa.
Speaker 0: this shocked me like when I put the wire near something.
Speaker 0: there were sparks like when rim was in that cage.
Speaker 1: oh yeah when I tell when I touch when I grabbed the door to the server cage to open it and then I stopped because I thought an earthquake was happening and it took me a while to realize that I was being shocked.
Speaker 1: with one phase of a 220 line.
Speaker 0: so big Clive knows about electronics.
Speaker 0: so they sent this to big Clive and he made this video examining this USB charger.
Speaker 0: and apparently you know when you make an electronic device that say plugs into the wall you know you have AC power coming from the wall right yep and mains love power deadly power deadly power.
Speaker 0: but on the other side you've got USB which is like a handful of volts.
Speaker 1: but if you make a shitty device I mean it's just wires right the wire.
Speaker 1: from all searches the wire that's on the USB
Speaker 0: on the circuit board they'll always be sort of this divide between the part that uses the PI powered electricity and the part that uses like the low power DC with the transformer in between in a big gap so that there isn't any short circuits of electricity jumping across and apparently in this USB charger that gap was not sufficient you know and big Clive goes to investigate exactly what's wrong here.
Speaker 1: the moral is don't buy dodgy imported like Chinese nonsense USB chargers.
Speaker 1: they might actually kill you.
Speaker 0: yeah this video though the problem with it is is like 28 minutes and 20 seconds long my kind of video fast forward.
Speaker 0: most of this because it's mostly him trying to like break the case open for like five minutes.
Speaker 1: so there's a channel I follow that isn't like I didn't live editing.
Speaker 1: there's a channel I follow that's edited better than that but it's basically just this guy tearing apart shitty imported Chinese electronics and showing how dangerous it is and they're really long videos.
Speaker 1: but he really goes into that detail.
Speaker 1: that's the guy who showed me about those shower heads.
Speaker 1: that will shock you if you get close to them.
Speaker 1: but yeah there was a story actually a few months ago of a woman I think was in the UK who was killed by an iPhone charger because she had headphones plugged in and this thing just mains line and killed her straight up.
Speaker 1: hmm so uh yeah don't buy cheap USB chargers guys by it when it comes to electricity.
Speaker 1: at least anchor anchors the minimum for a USB charger.
Speaker 0: get the name-brand biz.
Speaker 1: yeah Sorni magnet box mmm asinonic if you can't tell I've been watching a lot of Simpsons lately.
Speaker 1: yeah in the minute moment.
Speaker 1: next weekend we're gonna be at PAX East 2016. we're doing a panel on Sunday at 3 30 Atari game design.
Speaker 1: we're gonna be there Thursday playing games in the awesome tabletop area.
Speaker 1: their megathon is off the hook.
Speaker 1: the book of the book is Oryx and Craig by Margaret Atwood pretty much done with Wheel of Time temporarily.
Speaker 1: so I'll actually read that book.
Speaker 1: probably start it like right around packs times mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: otherwise the patreon hit its first goal the gig.
Speaker 1: nice patreon.
Speaker 0: so I am you can all stop giving.
Speaker 0: now you hit your stupid goal.
Speaker 0: I know there's another girl.
Speaker 0: you don't need that goal.
Speaker 1: if you hit the next goal I'm gonna make videos detailing the full gig nights process like all the filters I use.
Speaker 1: go back to zero all the all the everything no one.
Speaker 1: you get the next goal.
Speaker 1: after that we're gonna live stream every episode of gig night.
Speaker 1: you don't need to just go back to zero.
Speaker 1: let me fun stuff.
Speaker 0: you can go back to zero now.
Speaker 0: you got your beta episode.
Speaker 1: we're also stepping up the rimily review.
Speaker 1: so Emily and I are gonna be reviewing a few things in the coming weeks.
Speaker 1: you don't need that either and I'm re-releasing all eight or possibly nine pre publication beta episodes of geek guides with commentary remastered in the patreon over the next few weeks.
Speaker 0: you got what you wanted so you can cancel that.
Speaker 1: nope now there's gonna be so much more.
Speaker 1: the more the higher it goes the more I'm ramping up the shit and you don't need any that guy gonna be amazing.
Speaker 0: no your life will be much better off without that stuff in fact.
Speaker 1: so I've never been on like a Princess cruise or a Carnival cruise or anything like that.
Speaker 1: and while several people in our lives have tried to convince me that they're worthwhile I am highly dubious of that kind of boat time.
Speaker 1: hmm I mean it.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell those cruises are pretty much just hotels turned sideways that you can't leave easily.
Speaker 1: yeah with that move with buffets and norovirus and you can't.
Speaker 0: but they provide you with much food and you know you go to a hotel.
Speaker 0: usually you don't like go in the pool but when you go to that hotel you can't.
Speaker 0: you can't leave and go to attractions near the hotel.
Speaker 0: you do all the in hotel stuff like spas and pools and shit.
Speaker 1: now my suspicions were concerts and parties and whatever by other people I know who work on cruises who were like yeah it's mostly just old and or fat people but it was double can.
Speaker 1: he's in there the last time I was in Sydney and I think I talked about the same geek guys I was the basic folk I was running.
Speaker 1: I was doing a long run like all around like the opera house area and a big cruise ship was getting ready to depart so the people who were going on the cruise were all showing up.
Speaker 0: let me guess you're gonna talk about how old and fat they were.
Speaker 1: they were so old.
Speaker 0: how how were they?
Speaker 1: it was like I would say the people who were cuz it was weird.
Speaker 1: the staging area one.
Speaker 1: there was a giant line of people who were I guess standing in line to use the elevator to go up because they didn't want to walk up the stairs and up there.
Speaker 1: there was like a restaurant.
Speaker 1: there was a little like you could check your bags.
Speaker 1: there was a lounge and a bunch of bars.
Speaker 1: I think there was a hotel even like people were staying there for a few days before they even got on the cruise ship
Speaker 0: regaven
Speaker 1: and 95% of the people appeared to be either or both these are not mutually exclusive over the age of 70 maybe 65 maybe 65 and over 300 pounds.
Speaker 1: it was amazing to behold.
Speaker 1: and while the argument that has been made to me by many people is that the beauty of a cruise is that if you go with like a lot of your friends like 20 or 30 for like really close friends then it's like those college days where you're basically in this hotel floating with pools and all the nonsense.
Speaker 1: other people are taking care of everything for you and you basically just hang out with your friends on a pleasure cruise and ignore all the other people.
Speaker 0: but couldn't you do that in a place that doesn't have all those other people to begin with?
Speaker 1: or couldn't you just do that in say Vegas?
Speaker 1: I decided that if because I went to Vegas with Emily not that long ago for a wedding if you're gonna do that just go to fucking Disney World or Vegas and you get all those.
Speaker 1: say all the things that people say you can get from a cruise like that.
Speaker 0: Vegas is warm.
Speaker 1: yeah Vegas is warm.
Speaker 1: if shit sucks you can just go to a different hotel.
Speaker 1: it's not like you're stuck on one hotel in Vegas the whole time.
Speaker 0: You can get a flight to anywhere on earth yep and it's otherwise.
Speaker 1: it's like it's all the accoutrement of a cruise without having to be stuck on a boat full of norovirus mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so have you ever had a boat time you ever been on a boat?
Speaker 0: I've never been on a biggest boat like that.
Speaker 1: I've never been on a cruise ship like that.
Speaker 0: I've been on all right.
Speaker 1: what's the biggest boat you've ever been on?
Speaker 0: I went on like this tiny cruise.
Speaker 0: it was like we were in high school.
Speaker 0: we went on a trip to DC and then part of the trip to DC was at one night we had dinner on this boat.
Speaker 0: so we got on the boat and we ate dinner and so it had.
Speaker 0: it basically was like a boat that you would get like you know to have like a wedding on or something only you know right and in like the main area is like a ballroom.
Speaker 0: yep yep and then it goes out and then you and then you go up on deck and it basically went up and down.
Speaker 0: you know this the river that's outside the National Harbor right?
Speaker 0: yeah yeah basically went up and down that river and then we got.
Speaker 1: well didn't we do the same that you came with when we saw was joco.
Speaker 0: this was bigger than that boat but same kind of.
Speaker 1: but yeah we did that.
Speaker 1: the mini joco crews were basically we just got on a boat with a bunch of cool people and there was a concert and drinks and hanging out on a boat going up and down the yeah
Speaker 0: imagine like that same exact deal only all high school kids and boat was two or three times as big.
Speaker 1: I actually did stuff like that a lot when I was younger but I grew up in Michigan where there actually is a significant boat culture.
Speaker 1: like there's a lot of canals and places where people to zone boats like.
Speaker 1: they'll have a boat in their backyard and the canal just like goes behind all the houses in the subdivision and everyone has a boat parked in their boat parking lot behind their house and they can take the canals and get out to the lakes and stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean it's summer camp.
Speaker 0: I did a lot of rowboat canoe kayak.
Speaker 0: I never did anything with a sail on it cuz I no one taught me how.
Speaker 1: but I guess it's interesting that like here and I've been on really big boats that were just docked like you know oh like in South Street seaport like the pirate ship kind of things.
Speaker 0: well I mean like like in Groton Connecticut like I went on.
Speaker 0: you know giant submarine.
Speaker 0: it was just there right.
Speaker 1: but living here like the only boats I'll go on in New York City are like that joco thing where they're like there's a lot.
Speaker 1: there's a common event.
Speaker 0: people will do wherever you go in the circle line.
Speaker 0: yeah it's also.
Speaker 0: there's also some restaurants that are just docked boats that don't move.
Speaker 1: but like people will rent a boat and do an event and you pay money to do that event.
Speaker 1: or you're a rich person and you own a boat.
Speaker 0: I think I've been on like a slow riverboat that might have been Disney World or was it somewhere else.
Speaker 0: you know the kind with the thing in the back that goes chicka chicka chicka like a paddle boat.
Speaker 1: no a paddle boat.
Speaker 0: no like the Mississippi River style.
Speaker 1: yeah a paddle boat.
Speaker 0: you're not paddling like you know.
Speaker 1: Oh Scott that's called a paddle boat paddle wheel.
Speaker 0: they called a riverboat.
Speaker 0: it's just like a giant mill in the back.
Speaker 1: pedal boats have the pedal wheels on the back.
Speaker 0: oh not like that.
Speaker 1: yeah not like that.
Speaker 1: you're thinking the one with the one giant wheel like a maverick.
Speaker 0: yes yeah like that one.
Speaker 1: so but what I was getting at is that here probably like boats are a rich person thing or a bunch of people get together and basically rent a boat and charge admission to cover the rental of the boat.
Speaker 1: but where I grew up boats were like a lower middle class middle class thing.
Speaker 1: like a lot of people I knew own boats well I use them regularly.
Speaker 0: well see it's all Japan right.
Speaker 0: so if you live in a place where there's a lot of bodies of water it's cheaper to live near the body of water.
Speaker 0: you can get all kinds of you know getting an actual boat is kind of cheap.
Speaker 1: maintaining a boat is what's really expensive yeah but if your house only cost a hundred grand and it has five bedrooms and it happens to be on the water like you can afford to buy a boat and spend all that like your boat money and mate.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: but if you less than guys in a suburb that's not near any kind of lake or anything or any large body of water having a boat is only you know something a rich person you do.
Speaker 1: yep but if you live in New York you can't afford to live here and have a boat.
Speaker 0: unless you're so rich you can afford to live here and have a boat.
Speaker 1: so it's interesting that perspective because where I grew up like so many of my friends had boats that a common thing I would do in high school is one of my friends be like hey we're gonna have a party on the boat and a bunch of us teenagers would just get on a pretty big boat.
Speaker 1: and the one slightly wealthier friend who either had permission from his parents or scammed like 30 bucks out of all of us so he could afford to like refill the tanks.
Speaker 1: they wouldn't notice that we took the boat out.
Speaker 1: then we just take the boat out to like the mid like we go way out into one of the Great Lakes and just hang out on a boat in the middle of the night on a boat.
Speaker 1: yeah and those are some of my best high school times.
Speaker 1: there's something about like.
Speaker 1: I've always enjoyed that sitting in a boat in the middle of the water way out at night where there's all black around you you see like cargo ships way off in the distance and you see the shore.
Speaker 1: they come and smash in you but don't go into the shipping lane.
Speaker 1: the fuck's wrong with you.
Speaker 1: at least everyone who took the boats out knew what they were doing with the boats.
Speaker 1: I never went out with the people who.
Speaker 0: that's the thing with a car?
Speaker 0: you know even though you look around this country right and people are driving everywhere in the world people are driving everywhere and they can't drive for shit but they do it anyway.
Speaker 0: yeah it's they manage to get by even though they suck.
Speaker 0: with a boat you can't get by if you suck.
Speaker 0: also there's a lot more to know than there is to know like if the boats already out out of the docks you can get by knowing nothing pretty easily unless there's any unless there's even some even the slightest thing out of the ordinary.
Speaker 0: if you just have to make the boat go and change its direction and it has a steering wheel you can get by.
Speaker 1: yeah because you'll turn the steering wheel and fuck it up and you'll go way off course but there's nothing to hit.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: but as soon as you get into a situation of any kind like there's something not exactly 100% right with the boat dead you're just dead right.
Speaker 0: yeah everyone's dead.
Speaker 0: you know the boat is having a trouble or you know the boat is leaning one way.
Speaker 0: you know there's someone coming near you.
Speaker 1: it's like well I'll put it this way like we talked about how everyone's a shitty drive there's a fish.
Speaker 1: most people who drive cars cannot parallel park at all like they can't do it.
Speaker 0: well most places you don't have to do it so they don't learn how.
Speaker 0: they don't make anyone.
Speaker 1: so actually taking a moderate sized boat and getting it back into the dock without fucking everything up is about like parallel parking.
Speaker 1: you got to know what you're doing and if you like use boats at all.
Speaker 1: it's real easy.
Speaker 0: you don't want to crash into the dock.
Speaker 0: yeah you don't want to miss the dock and be too far away to tie up to it.
Speaker 1: mostly there's not a lot of space in there and there's a lot of other boats around to navigate and also the steering of a boat out in the middle of the water.
Speaker 1: it's real easy because if you're way off it doesn't really matter that much.
Speaker 0: but when you have to maneuver it the precision needs to be so tight it's so you've got.
Speaker 0: the water is also affecting your boat.
Speaker 0: it's not like a car where nothing affects its movement.
Speaker 0: it's just sitting still.
Speaker 0: the boat will move on its own if you just don't do anything yeah and also things like you're going forward in a pretty good clip.
Speaker 1: right there's no break on the boat it's not like.
Speaker 1: well I'm gonna stop now folks gonna keep going forward.
Speaker 1: you start to turn to the left you're gonna start spinning while you're still moving forward.
Speaker 1: yep and I've watched a lot of people fuck their small boats up because they don't actually know how to maneuver it in close quarters or they vastly underestimate their speed and just don't know about boats.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so but it was.
Speaker 1: but again I grew up in a place where everyone knew about boats.
Speaker 0: so we're boat people and you hang out on boats and some lakes there.
Speaker 1: I actually do wish that boating was more accessible financially in the New York area because there's a lot of water here.
Speaker 0: I would really I don't touch the water but I wouldn't mind being in a boat.
Speaker 1: I don't really enjoy taking a boat out with like.
Speaker 0: say like you me Emily I see some boats going down the river and man those are some fancy fucking boats.
Speaker 0: I saw a boat that was basically like evil Bondville in the boat and I'm like damn I should just hijack that motherfucker.
Speaker 1: like imagine on a nice night with the fireworks right we go out and we just like do a long leisurely circle out like seeing New York in the distance the fireworks in the distance.
Speaker 0: I don't think they'll let you boat when the fireworks are there.
Speaker 1: well not right where the barges are but you go off a ways and you can but imagine like that like hanging out like I'm driving the boat.
Speaker 0: you guys are all rent a boat then big money man.
Speaker 1: no that much money.
Speaker 1: a one-night rental one-night rental of a big boat is actually not that cheap.
Speaker 1: and I am NOT going to say that my boating skills are adequate to this area because I mean first of all we know people's boating skills.
Speaker 0: and two you can always rent someone to go with the boat.
Speaker 1: yeah the right way to go is to rent the kind of boat that did.
Speaker 1: like that Hall & Oates thing we went to on Judith's bachelor party.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm you it was a real funny boat time.
Speaker 1: so it was the same kind of boat as the joke of thing and it was a Hall & Oates tribute band okay which I'm into.
Speaker 1: okay there was another boat that was bigger that was filling up next to us and there was something else going on that looked way better on that boat.
Speaker 1: but there was a weird sort of aside.
Speaker 1: there was a stark dichotomy between the people getting on the boat.
Speaker 1: the Hall & Oates tribute band boat was basically all yuppie hipster looking white people.
Speaker 1: the other boat was all cool people.
Speaker 1: hmm that other boat like whatever party was happening on that boat looked amazing and that boat went off into the sunset.
Speaker 1: I heard the music coming from that boat.
Speaker 1: that's the boat I should have been on.
Speaker 0: why didn't you get on the cool boat?
Speaker 1: I would had to jump and swim for it and I don't know if they would let me up.
Speaker 0: you couldn't do good weren't close enough.
Speaker 0: you couldn't jump and grab.
Speaker 0: it was too late.
Speaker 1: the boat was action but the Hall & Oates boat went up and down the East River and no one went to see the Hall & Oates.
Speaker 1: we all just hung out on the deck.
Speaker 1: because that feeling of being on a boat with the shore in the distance looking up at the sky the fresh breeze drinking something hanging out with friends good times smells like water.
Speaker 0: yep I really enjoy smells like East River.
Speaker 1: it smelled okay actually for some reason.
Speaker 1: wind blowing the right direction yeah something blowing the wrong direction you know in that Jersey air coming back across yeah what all little boats yeah ever go like kayaking.
Speaker 0: I talked about summer camp.
Speaker 0: you know every summer camp has a tiny lake and that always has you know like a kayak.
Speaker 1: yeah a rowboat you know what I always enjoy.
Speaker 1: a lot of kids we talk about skill.
Speaker 1: kids fucking don't know how to use canoes.
Speaker 0: windsurfing I know how to use a canoe.
Speaker 1: yeah most kids don't seem to know how to use canoes and rafts are way harder than canoes for people who don't know how to use them.
Speaker 0: well I mean a raft sucks.
Speaker 0: it's a big rectangle just like it sucks right and you can get your raft you just spin around in a circle way worse than a canoe does at least you know.
Speaker 0: at least a canoe has a point.
Speaker 0: so you know which direction is forward or backward.
Speaker 1: actually I think the hardest thing that the kids have the most trouble with an actual like traditional rowboat like the slightly wide we have two people.
Speaker 0: a rowboat I think is just less efficient.
Speaker 0: so you need more muscles to move it.
Speaker 0: yeah and it's heavier and right.
Speaker 0: it's less.
Speaker 0: you know dynamic they're also really unstable.
Speaker 0: it takes.
Speaker 0: yeah it takes a lot more like you know power to move the rowboat like we had a race you know you could lose.
Speaker 0: it's a strong person in the rowboat could lose to a somewhat weaker person in the canoe just because the canoe is better.
Speaker 0: it's like yeah you know someone's got a Ferrari and you got a not Ferrari.
Speaker 1: yeah I do really enjoy kayaking but I don't like tandem kayaking that much.
Speaker 1: I like my own kayak.
Speaker 0: yeah I don't I don't understand.
Speaker 0: the two-person kayak is the whole point of the kayak is like ah finally the one-person boat not a stupid two-person canoe action.
Speaker 1: the two-person canoe is good well canoe but the two-person kayak is good.
Speaker 1: if you're doing distance kayaking like what if you're kayaking like all the way up the river to Yonkers or like beacon or something?
Speaker 0: well that's.
Speaker 0: the other thing with the kayak is that it's so tiny.
Speaker 0: you can just like throw a rope and just like you know binge off someone else's kayak.
Speaker 0: yeah right it's like I'll just tie myself to your kayak and take a nap.
Speaker 1: but I really enjoy kayaking.
Speaker 1: actually it's a sport I kind of miss that.
Speaker 1: I feel like I should get into again.
Speaker 0: I like kayaking.
Speaker 0: I just have no arm strength so I can't really do anything except let the water push me.
Speaker 1: yeah you know you need to do.
Speaker 1: you know you're biking so much.
Speaker 1: you got strong legs.
Speaker 1: you got to do that to your arms then you can kayak because if you're strong or I could just not do that but if you're strong kayaks can go real fucking fast.
Speaker 0: yeah what kind of hurry am I in?
Speaker 1: it's just really fun to go really fast in the water like that.
Speaker 0: yeah I like some.
Speaker 0: I like some lazy river action.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking about fast.
Speaker 1: I think I want to go out to Jamaica Bay and rent a kayak and go poking around and all those like marshes and everything.
Speaker 0: are you allowed to go in?
Speaker 0: there isn't.
Speaker 0: there isn't a reserve.
Speaker 0: you're not allowed to go in there.
Speaker 1: some areas you know some you can't but there's a lot of kayaking out that way like you can just go out and buy a kayak and tie it to the roof of your car like a yuppie whatever.
Speaker 1: no you'd you'd fucking like go out there and rent a kayak and use it there and then leave the kayak when you go home.
Speaker 0: I've never seen her kayak rental over there.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of kayak rentals.
Speaker 1: New York.
Speaker 1: actually there's places here.
Speaker 1: you can get kayaks and go up and down the river.
Speaker 1: hmm I mean you're not gonna get that.
Speaker 0: I've seen.
Speaker 0: I've seen kayak in the Hudson River like you can next to the intrepid.
Speaker 0: there's like free there's like kayaking you can just do.
Speaker 1: as far as I can tell there's an old thing that they set up where there are campgrounds that are accessible to kayaks and canoes and things all the way along the river from New York City like way up almost all the way to Albany mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so you're then there space such that if you have are a reasonably proficient goer you will get to one every day and be able to camp.
Speaker 0: so you're gonna bike up the Hudson River.
Speaker 1: well the Hudson River changes direction so just time it with the tides mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: good luck with that.
Speaker 1: yeah people do it all the time.
Speaker 1: actually it's a really common hobby.
Speaker 0: they're mad strong.
Speaker 0: yeah biking that also no matter which direction the water is moving you're gonna touch Hudson River water.
Speaker 1: yeah so I was really learned about that unrelatedly recently.
Speaker 0: there are different standards for how dangerous water is based on whether or not yeah it's not the fucking Ganges alright it's not gonna kill you but you don't want to touch it anyway.
Speaker 1: Hudson River water is in a category where you do not want to immerse your body in it but occasional contact like in kayaks and canoes totally fine like negligible danger of anything yeah but you'd still be better off not touching it.
Speaker 1: I think you're.
Speaker 1: there's more danger eating bacon on a regular basis than there is in that.
Speaker 1: so I might take I might do the kayaking trip but don't you eat bacon on a regular basis?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna mortise those dangers because I do.
Speaker 1: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night
Speaker 1: and the patrons for this episode in order of the amount of money they give us in continuing basis are Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brandau Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette James David White.
Speaker 1: Christian you can guess what bullies called me in high school cunts.
Speaker 1: just my state.
Speaker 1: e.com.
Speaker 1: Sean Hayworth mechanical mind.
Speaker 1: William Eisen rose Jeremy minor Spartacus.
Speaker 1: Spartacus.
Speaker 1: Spartacus Kimberly bachelor kachar Tava Shan.
Speaker 1: Jonathan shout out to dick Kunstman Romer Joshiro Joe star Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Robert Lee Ryan pair and drew open lender.
Speaker 1: Ray Lavelle Brian should said Roni Rochelle Montanota Finn Eric silver on can't melt steel beams.
Speaker 1: kinetic man Aaron series Chris mid give Chris Knox.
Speaker 1: I expected the Spanish Inquisition.
Speaker 1: Sam Cordery Daniel Redmond Chris had Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: as you know we hit the goal.
Speaker 1: I am literally remastering all those beta episodes of geek nights.
Speaker 1: it was actually somewhat difficult because they were recorded on incredibly bad hardware with incredibly bad processes a long long time ago but I remastered the first one.
Speaker 1: I am listening to it probably on my way to work tomorrow as a podcast and then I will be able to record some commentary on what it was like listening to us do literally the first geek nights thing we ever tried to do.
Speaker 1: some of its funny some of it is haltingly horrific to listen to but it is very interesting to hear what we sounded like because it wasn't most of the time it doesn't sound like I was having a natural conversation like we did in that era.
Speaker 1: we actually sound more natural now even though that natural sounding conversation and banter we have is actually sort of an act and kind of synthetic.
Speaker 1: so it's weird that when we were more natural on the show it ended up being halting and over time we sort of rediscovered the way to do what we would do in our normal lives but in a performance setting.
Speaker 1: and you'll when you listen to the episode you'll see what I mean once.
Speaker 1: I actually read some commentary and say it in front of a microphone.
Speaker 1: but that's neither here nor there will be a PAX.
Speaker 1: East next week might not do a full set of shows next week because of that but I will release at least that first beta episode of geek nights to all of you who are backing us on patreon very soon hopefully over the course of the weekend.
Speaker 1: and now I leave you with something odd about.
Speaker 1: so we got two new DS games just because then you're saying we it's like but it's like there's a third person here.
Speaker 1: they're part of the conversation that I'm not addressing them directly but yeah but even all right.
Speaker 0: even then if your selection of words whatever but there's no other way to bring that up.
Speaker 0: it's not the tone of the way you're saying it.
Speaker 1: I say that way anyway it doesn't sound right.
Speaker 0: that's how I talk.
Speaker 0: no it's a bleeding radio guy talking.
Speaker 1: oh it's not.
Speaker 1: I think you're hung up too much on this radio guy thing.
Speaker 0: it just feels awkward.
Speaker 1: that's the way I talk.
Speaker 0: it feels awkward when to say something like that and it kind of throws it.
Speaker 1: we're sitting here right now.
Speaker 1: I'd be like so we got two new video games this week.
Speaker 1: no you'd be like.
Speaker 0: so I got the the Castlevania.
Speaker 1: no I'd probably say like so we got trauma center in Castlevania.
Speaker 1: there you go.
Speaker 1: he got one I got the other one.
Speaker 1: that way we don't have to buy a boat.
Speaker 0: that's better.
Speaker 0: the way you said that the only difference I didn't say we and the tone of the saying.
Speaker 1: it was a little different because you're actually talking to me because I actively talk.
Speaker 1: weird that's not the way I talk.
Speaker 1: I think you're too hung up on this.
Speaker 0: it's just.
Speaker 0: it's just that like.
Speaker 0: it's not really a hang up like.
Speaker 0: I think it hurts the podcast.
Speaker 0: it just makes it the the talking awkward.
Speaker 0: they're like doesn't mean it does to me.
Speaker 1: well you're not used to this.
Speaker 1: I guess I'm really used to speaking in public because you'd like when you speak on a panel or something.
Speaker 1: that's the kind of language you always have to use.
Speaker 1: and yeah while you're speaking to each other.
Speaker 1: not only this is like it's it's like a recording.
Speaker 1: how it's a no because a recorded conversation in and of itself is kind of yeah but that's what all the big.
Speaker 0: that's what the podcasting is about because you know people don't like the radio.
Speaker 1: that's why they're listening to fun.
Speaker 1: no they don't like the radio because there's nothing they want to hear on the radio and that's what the ads on the radio right but the.
Speaker 0: that's one reason.
Speaker 0: but the other thing is that if you notice the podcast that are stuck in the Brady like this still the normal radio format or don't listen to.
Speaker 1: so I don't think we need to worry about that.