Speaker 0: It's Wednesday February 10th 2016.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 0: And this is geek nights tonight shows We watched a reasonable amount of and then just never finished them.
Speaker 0: quite a topic there for you guys.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So, uh, if any of you listen to the Monday episode this week my knob came today and Polish his knob all night.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna use that knob to crank out a whole bunch of editing on the utensil thing.
Speaker 1: That is part of you know patreon and all that gonna spend all night Calibrating the knob and I guess you get anything done.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be knobbing a lot tonight after I get the show up.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: maybe the knob sucks.
Speaker 0: Maybe the knobs a bad deal.
Speaker 1: Hey, you're gonna get a whole bunch of knobbing it.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna get any work done.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll send the knob back if it isn't Optimal.
Speaker 0: but a bunch of people I trust told me that the knobs a good deal and then I had.
Speaker 0: it's good thing I bought the knob.
Speaker 0: So you got any news?
Speaker 0: anime manga comics episode of geek nights, I do have a news.
Speaker 1: so The New York Children's Film Festival is coming up and even though we're not children That is always a great opportunity To see some animated films which tend to be thought of as children's films, even when they're not.
Speaker 1: It is in fact one of the best ways yeah, and in the past we have used this opportunity to see such movies as I think we saw when Marnie was there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we saw we pretty much summer wars like Every single movie like this that comes out.
Speaker 1: We just immediately go watch, you know It's basically we tend to go see those anime movies that aren't that like the number one top tier anime movies Like the the big-time jubilee movies.
Speaker 1: they get put out everywhere and you know, right but also Aren't the lowball ones like, you know one piece 15 or whatever course.
Speaker 0: A lot of these are the ones that get a wider release later, but we get to see him pretty early.
Speaker 1: So for example, we saw you know We saw some rewards that didn't really get a wider release in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Which is a shame because that's one of those movies that like you can get mom to watch and be really into sure.
Speaker 1: and then we saw When Marnie was there and that got a little release.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even though that was a very like artistic big-boy movie in a lot of ways Yeah, but so now you know Mamoru Hosoda who seems to make anime movies right in that zone and who has also been getting increasingly furry as time goes on.
Speaker 1: Sure, his new movie is I think we've mentioned on the show before is Boy and the Beast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess they replaced the beauty with a boy.
Speaker 0: I think we haven't talked about it a lot on the show partly because we haven't stopped.
Speaker 0: we're gonna go see it right But it's getting can?
Speaker 1: it's getting a wider release.
Speaker 1: So on March 4th, if you live anywhere near like a major, you know place and not you know The middle of nowhere where there's nothing but a multiplex.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you should probably be able to see this movie.
Speaker 0: It's an anime movie that I will predict is going to be good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even in like secondary cities, you know Like say I don't know some place like Omaha, Nebraska, you should be able to see this movie.
Speaker 1: I didn't actually look at the list.
Speaker 1: You might not be able to.
Speaker 1: I didn't actually look at the list of theaters is playing it I don't know.
Speaker 0: I give it a 50/50 shot if it's in Omaha.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's better than this, you know, it's way better than like the.
Speaker 1: you know zero right?
Speaker 1: See a March 4th, you can see this movie and you know.
Speaker 1: also there's like, you know Oscar nominee.
Speaker 1: It's all.
Speaker 1: it's award season for movies, right?
Speaker 1: So in the nominations for all the animation categories boy and the world the Brazilian movie seems to be winning Beating out boy in the beast.
Speaker 1: It's a battle of the boys Yeah, so and also all the movies that are nominated like four of them are distributed by G kids.
Speaker 0: Yes G kids is always just hitting it out of the park.
Speaker 1: well they're pretty much just like.
Speaker 1: huh, no one else wants these amazing animations from other countries that aren't America and We will just license all of them and put them in America.
Speaker 0: We win Yeah, but Emily and I were looking at like a lot of the other movies in the festival.
Speaker 0: I think I'm gonna go see like three or four movies like.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of movies to go Yeah, but there's good stuff.
Speaker 0: Good shit.
Speaker 0: Good shit bunch of good shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can go see it You know, it won't be hard to see.
Speaker 0: So I realized how you know We.
Speaker 0: we used to attend a lot of anime conventions and a lot and we did a lot of panels and shows and staff and whatever.
Speaker 0: But you can tell how far out of that loop we are that I this is our friends.
Speaker 0: They were like, oh let's hang out because this weekend we're gonna be at a con and I assume they're gonna be at some like dumpy con upstate somewhere.
Speaker 0: cuz you know There's a con every weekend somewhere in the eastern seaboard and I was like, oh what kind of you guys go to and they're like Katsu khan.
Speaker 0: and I was like, whoa Moderately big.
Speaker 1: yeah
Speaker 0: It was a con that we not only used to go to But once hosted a late show with live music and Steve Bennett as a guest and we learned a lot about the Civil War Reenacting God the hobby and about why he has that hat on a
Speaker 1: comedy went to with our friend katsu and didn't make one joke the whole time about how his name was the same name as the convention.
Speaker 0: cuz yeah a con.
Speaker 0: where we were on the staff and Technically is yes We were brought into the staff and all we did was there's a video game room that had like an arcade Like an arcade that's better than what Pax has today, but not like what magfest is now.
Speaker 0: But it's like the size of the pack is about the size of the Pax one but better game selection yep, and We just DJ that room like.
Speaker 0: that was our job to play music and DJ the room and just kind of be there Weird times back in those old days, but yeah, it's coming up and I learned something interesting about Katsu con.
Speaker 0: They moved to the Gaylord where magfest is.
Speaker 0: apparently the Gaylord has a ridiculous and draconian like Anti-photography rule across the entire facility.
Speaker 1: There's crazy rules about the mag.
Speaker 1: magfest is like photo central.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so from what I can gather there was running discussions between Multiple conventions fan convention.
Speaker 1: the magfest photo policy is pretty much the same as every other conventions photo policy.
Speaker 1: But I think it says something like you know Like you have to license your photo and assert like Creative Commons or whatever like you can't be.
Speaker 0: you know I don't know if magfest did anything with the Convention Center, but the Convention Center's technical rules were apparently pretty bad.
Speaker 0: and from what I found out from Katsu khan that they have this official statement pointing out that the Katsu khan is a special photo policy from the Gaylord for Katsu khan that is Considerably more relaxed than their standard policy.
Speaker 0: So you're allowed so you are allowed to at Katsu khan Take photos in public areas Which apparently you weren't allowed to do.
Speaker 0: I mean I'm sure the whatever policy the hotel yes on its own can so long as you use handheld equipment only You may not set up lighting of any kind.
Speaker 0: Photographers near subjects must respect the hotel environment by not being disruptive, which I guess The problem was.
Speaker 0: people were like getting in fountains and things okay, and everyone's got to have a badge Which I guess makes sense.
Speaker 1: you can't be in the convention without a badge regardless of photography except Which is interesting because they're a lot.
Speaker 0: that space is weird because a lot of it is not part of a convention.
Speaker 0: that's in there.
Speaker 1: I mean if you're outside on the street, it's a public street.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but well like of the Shrek area I guess you can take your cosplay photos in there, but that's not part of the con as far as I can Yeah, but it's still in a hotel lobby.
Speaker 1: So it's still a privately owned area.
Speaker 1: Yeah kick you out, right?
Speaker 1: So like you don't have a right to be in a hotel lobby like a homeless bum Can't just go in the hotel lobby and fall asleep.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I was digging around to try to figure out like all the deal and we'll just there's an interesting story back there That I stumbled upon because I was reminded that katsu khan existed However, the only anime con we perform at is still anime Boston because katsu khan as far as I can tell does not comp its panelists.
Speaker 1: so Yeah, we'd have to buy a badge.
Speaker 1: Yeah Not buying a badge to provide not buying a badge to any.
Speaker 1: I don't buy a badge to pack cuz I'm not buying one to God.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway all that aside a little geek bite But I watched with Emily all of over the garden wall like all the way through And I seen not in or I haven't seen like it wasn't like I saw the first half.
Speaker 1: It's like I saw episode one and I like episode four and like the last episode.
Speaker 0: so I we watched all of it and I've almost watched all of it again because it is Crazy good.
Speaker 0: So once Scott watches it all then we'll probably do a show on it.
Speaker 0: But just go sit just go watch it.
Speaker 0: It's on Netflix.
Speaker 0: It's like ten episodes long.
Speaker 1: I don't have Netflix.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or no, I think it was on Hulu.
Speaker 0: I'd never know what anything's on anymore cuz I just have them both.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I think it's Hulu.
Speaker 1: I only pay for what I want at a time.
Speaker 1: Why should I waste a bunch of money?
Speaker 0: It's ten short episodes The best way.
Speaker 0: I can really describe it as cross adventure time with waiting for Godot.
Speaker 0: hmm and Just just watch your show.
Speaker 0: Like you're gonna wonder what the.
Speaker 0: just watch your show.
Speaker 0: It's really well put together.
Speaker 1: That's some song of the sea in there also.
Speaker 1: Yeah The other way around you could say song of the sea has some garden wall.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what?
Speaker 0: It's waiting for Godot, but then Godot shows up that that's what's going on in this thing.
Speaker 0: Also the bird Beatrice might be my favorite character.
Speaker 1: Yeah I saw one bird episode where they're like a bird could take you back to your nest.
Speaker 1: the bird was like Oh and the bird went somewhere else.
Speaker 0: Yeah The bird bird is.
Speaker 0: bird is Scott and like if you're gonna cosplay a character because you're gonna act like them you're Beatrice.
Speaker 0: Beatrice is just like yeah, you guys are dumb.
Speaker 0: Let's go this way.
Speaker 0: Anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: so I remembered this one when I was a kid like little kid and I never was really a hundred percent sure what its deal was until I stumbled upon it randomly on YouTube.
Speaker 0: This is a made-for-tv movie Written by dr.
Speaker 0: Seuss released in 1980 before I was born And it's called Pontiful Pock, where are you?
Speaker 0: the story of this movie is that there's a sad kid who's kind of dumb whose parents died and left him a rundown house that he's too Dumb to maintain.
Speaker 0: so a local business owner gives him a job at a pickle factory.
Speaker 0: out of charity He proceeds to fuck up the job by pushing on the pull him and pulling on the push him.
Speaker 0: So they arrest him and then fairies give him a magic piano That'll take him to a faraway land where he can get a new start.
Speaker 0: He does this and then angers the locals so badly that their military attacks him.
Speaker 0: He goes to a series of other places and continues to fuck up.
Speaker 0: and the moral of the whole movie Go back home work in the pickle factory.
Speaker 0: That's the best you'll ever do in your life at the end.
Speaker 1: Well, if you're a ponniful puck, that's true.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but he he never makes it out of that pickle factory.
Speaker 0: I'm surprised they even hired him back at the pickle factory.
Speaker 0: I don't know what this movie's trying to say because as far as I can tell it says Be grateful for your miserable lot in life and don't try to better yourself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why my number one.
Speaker 1: Dr Seuss is the Lorax the real one not states for the trees.
Speaker 1: Not that CG bullshit, right?
Speaker 1: You know?
Speaker 1: and then if you really want to get fancy, right if you really want to fuck your brain up a little You know, you want to double your ponniful pock power?
Speaker 1: Go and watch the five thousand fingers of dr.
Speaker 1: T.
Speaker 0: You're talking about that the other day, right?
Speaker 1: See if you can see if you can find it and then watch it and tell me what you think about some real dr.
Speaker 1: Seuss.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 1: Oh thing of the day, alright.
Speaker 1: so there's a guy that you know, but you don't know if you're a nerd and that man is named Bo Shek.
Speaker 1: and Before today, I didn't know who I mean, I knew who Bo Shek was that is didn't know his name was Bo Shek.
Speaker 0: it is telling that I read an article about Scott's thing and then Scott asked me if I knew who Bo Shek was and I was Didn't actually read the article.
Speaker 0: That's why I read an article by.
Speaker 1: so this is guy named Bo Shek.
Speaker 1: He is in Star Wars episode 4 for like less than a second when obi-wan goes into the cantina And he's got these like bounty hunters like well not bounty hunters like smugglers lined up and he's talking to them and he's like Hey, who should I you know?
Speaker 1: you want to take us for a ride is a and there's a guy standing in front of Chewbacca and The guy's like nah, but you can you know, he points and he's like, hey you should talk to the Wookie, right?
Speaker 1: That guy is Bo Shek.
Speaker 1: Well, at least that's the character's name.
Speaker 1: How do we know that's the character's name?
Speaker 1: Because if you buy the toy, there's an action figure for Bo Shek and it says Bo Shek on it.
Speaker 1: How you know?
Speaker 0: wait wait, so let me get this straight because this is this is why this is an amazing thing.
Speaker 0: There was a character in one of the most well-known movies in human history Who had a speaking line.
Speaker 1: you didn't say anything.
Speaker 0: Oh, he didn't know that.
Speaker 0: I asked him but he didn't just points, right?
Speaker 0: But he got.
Speaker 0: so he talks.
Speaker 1: if you don't hear him time, you know what he had.
Speaker 1: He had some direction other than face was on these faces on the screen.
Speaker 0: He was addressed by a major character in a pivotal scene and he had an action figure.
Speaker 0: Yep, and yet no one knew who he was.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean Star Wars nerds knew that that character is named Bo Shek and they probably know more like alternate universe stuff about him.
Speaker 1: That's no longer canon, but nobody knew at least nobody knew who the actor was.
Speaker 1: They didn't know who that person was like.
Speaker 1: there's his face on the screen clear as day.
Speaker 1: But like you search and no one knew who it was.
Speaker 1: They wasn't in the credits.
Speaker 1: so and it's like they even called up like Lucasfilm and you know, whatever No one knew who this guy was.
Speaker 0: now Imagine that you work at a job and someone calls you and they're like, hey Who the hell is that person in this photo of your company the person's in a movie in the 70s, right?
Speaker 1: You know, they could look up other movies around that time find a similar-looking actor and they there were some you know possibilities people saw You know play that got clips of like this one TV show in the UK where there was like a Russian thug who looked pretty similar To the guy and like I was that him?
Speaker 1: maybe I don't know.
Speaker 1: So this guy was investigating is like it's my mission.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna find Bo Shek.
Speaker 1: That's how I'm gonna do Right, so he goes out and he's looking.
Speaker 1: he's looking.
Speaker 1: he can't really find starting to give up.
Speaker 1: There's a whole article written by the guy Billy Jensen.
Speaker 1: Well, it's Billy Jensen calm and eventually one day he gets a. he gets contacted by someone Barry Gregory and Barry Gregory Was the grandson of Bo Shek Oh snap.
Speaker 1: and then he immediately emails Barry back and he got ever.
Speaker 1: he got the email address of Barry's mom who I guess was Bo Shek's daughter Sylvia Holt.
Speaker 1: and Sylvia Holt said my dad mr.
Speaker 1: Francis Alfred Basil Tomlin played the part of Bo Shek.
Speaker 1: everyone knew my dad is Tom.
Speaker 1: Fortunately, my dad passed away over 11 years ago.
Speaker 1: It'd be nice if we could get his name Recognized as his claim to fame was as part as Bo Shek and a stormtrooper in the first Star Wars film.
Speaker 0: now My question to the archive the archivist now is which stormtrooper?
Speaker 1: You have no way to know that but as proof she sent him a photo and there is no question.
Speaker 1: unless Bo Shek Mr.
Speaker 1: Tomlin had an identical twin.
Speaker 0: Wait, it might be taller Bo Shek Unless you know, you know the taller Luke thing, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay, unless he had an identical twin There is no doubt that this is the right person.
Speaker 1: and how could you pot the odds of being able to get a photograph of?
Speaker 1: this person Without being related to them are so small.
Speaker 0: So now we know who Bo Shek was so, you know every year There's like the news events that spawn Halloween costumes and cosplay like someone's gonna dress up in a tarp and that Crap like next year.
Speaker 0: Like what are the hot costumes?
Speaker 0: The pro move is to dress up as Bo Shek.
Speaker 0: You're gonna see a lot of big checks.
Speaker 1: That's already been the pro move.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna see any Bo Shek see unless you go to Star Wars celebration Which I don't know they still have.
Speaker 0: I'll bet you five dollars.
Speaker 0: We see a Bo Shek at Kinetic on.
Speaker 0: no You want to shake on it?
Speaker 1: We won't see one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, boo you bet five bucks Are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: well, you might convince someone to do one, right?
Speaker 1: You can't.
Speaker 1: how can I know you didn't?
Speaker 1: That's the problem.
Speaker 0: I might convince someone simply The bet.
Speaker 1: let's bet.
Speaker 1: uh, you know, I told you so yeah, that's all right.
Speaker 0: I will bet.
Speaker 0: I told you so Okay, that way there's no incentive for me to pay someone to dress up as Bo Shek.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: You know what actually the pro move would be to dress up as the guy in the photo that proved he was Bo Shek.
Speaker 1: Can't just find a guy who looks kind of like Bo Shek either and be like, oh he's dressing his.
Speaker 0: yeah Cuz the problem is I can imagine a lot of people who kind of look like that Just wear some like vaguely 70s clothes.
Speaker 1: And yeah, he's got to look like the action figure with the same You know flight suit and shit.
Speaker 0: and you if you if you ask him he has to be like I'm dressed up as Bo Shek.
Speaker 0: That's right You know.
Speaker 0: if they're dressed up as the guy That counts too as long as they know.
Speaker 1: if you ask them who are you?
Speaker 1: What is your costume?
Speaker 1: and they say I'm Francis Alfred Basil Tomlin, then that will count as well.
Speaker 0: Yeah that if that happens then you can.
Speaker 0: then you can say I told you so that happens and it's not one of you listening Right now whoever it is.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna interview for the show.
Speaker 0: Just be like, all right, dude Right.
Speaker 0: So in the meta moment, we're gonna be at magfest next weekend.
Speaker 0: Whoo.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be on.
Speaker 1: Hopefully they clean up the katsucon by the time we get there.
Speaker 0: Yeah Apparently our friends are actually going to katsucon and just staying for the week for magfest like we did between PAX East and What do you do in National Harbor for a week?
Speaker 1: and doesn't that cost a lot of money?
Speaker 0: What did we do in Boston between PAX and anime Boston?
Speaker 0: The answer was we drove to New Hampshire.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: We did something.
Speaker 0: They're gonna do a similar thing.
Speaker 0: They're gonna like go around in the area like I have a base.
Speaker 0: Can I go out and like visit people and stay with friends and all that stuff?
Speaker 1: All right, you know make the most of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And of course, don't forget one of our three PAX South panels is on YouTube.
Speaker 0: The other two will come as soon as I finish the utenna episode.
Speaker 0: geek nice presents to ten episode 14, which?
Speaker 0: I'm about a little over a third done with it, but with the knob Watch out.
Speaker 0: I think I'm gonna get it done real quick now.
Speaker 0: Otherwise Show.
Speaker 0: So recently like I'd say the last six or seven years.
Speaker 0: It's very rare that I'll watch more than like one episode of an anime and not finish it Like I'll.
Speaker 0: just I'll watch a show and like having the first episode.
Speaker 0: I'm like nope and I never watch it again or I watch the whole show all the way through because it's that good.
Speaker 0: but there was a time in the distant past where Scott and I would both watch like Tens of episodes of shows and then just stop for some reason and One.
Speaker 0: we realized that we've done a show on Anime, we've never seen that are really important or big.
Speaker 0: I guess we did a show on shows that we've seen but never reviewed.
Speaker 0: for some reason.
Speaker 0: We did a episode on shows only Scott seen.
Speaker 0: on shows only rim seen.
Speaker 0: we never did an episode.
Speaker 0: Oh, and we've done episodes and shows that were bad based on one.
Speaker 0: Never done a show on shows that we watched a significant amount of and then for whatever reason didn't finish them.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's kind of like, you know, very few like.
Speaker 0: for a long time in my life I had a sort of personal rule.
Speaker 0: I would if I started reading a book That what there was a fiction book no matter what if I got past the first chapter I would always read it to the end no matter what.
Speaker 0: and There was a book that ended that for me and that book was dragons gold serpent silver.
Speaker 0: Come here as copper by Pierce Anthony and some other chucklefuck.
Speaker 0: That might have been the worst book I ever read and I got about halfway through that monster before I quit.
Speaker 0: Okay, like it was just like I was.
Speaker 0: it was bad and I just hated it and I hated it more and more and more.
Speaker 0: And then this voice appeared in my head.
Speaker 0: It said rim.
Speaker 0: Just put it down.
Speaker 0: Just throw it away Never open it again that you don't have to finish it.
Speaker 0: And Yeah, so that was the best we could come up with because I watched a bunch of shows.
Speaker 0: Scott hasn't watched and Scott read a bunch of comics.
Speaker 0: I haven't read.
Speaker 0: so we're in that situation here again.
Speaker 1: Maybe you should you know watch the same thing.
Speaker 1: I watch or read the same thing.
Speaker 0: I read what name and we have.
Speaker 0: you're not watching any cartoons though.
Speaker 1: I just watched all of evangelical We've.
Speaker 0: we've.
Speaker 0: not only we already done multiple shows about evangelical But we did a show about anime that we've watched that we watched again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we so you want to do.
Speaker 1: but after watching Evangelion again, I understand all of it now I'm like a hundred percent clarity.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it isn't interesting.
Speaker 1: I only had like 90% clarity before.
Speaker 0: I know there's only a few shows I'm like that with like utenna Evangelion eska flown in like.
Speaker 0: those are the shows like I've just seen.
Speaker 0: so there's an episode.
Speaker 0: Scott shows We've rewatched more than once Like the shows that get the annual watch the biennial.
Speaker 1: I haven't watched this in like since I was living in Beacon When I think about it those kinds of shows like.
Speaker 0: it's like a four year ish cycle.
Speaker 1: This was like seven eight years for me.
Speaker 0: It's all four because I watched Ava again About five years ago because I had that platinum whatever edition and I just watched it like on my laptop.
Speaker 0: Well, I was traveling just like all right Ava.
Speaker 0: hmm.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I think the show that really typifies this and it's gonna start it all off is attack on Titan because I have technically Seen all of it so far But we know there's more coming and I mean you've seen all.
Speaker 1: I mean if you've seen it there's like a season.
Speaker 1: I mean, it wasn't even a season right that it wasn't a tag on Titan season one.
Speaker 1: It was a tag on Titan and you saw every episode.
Speaker 1: So you've seen it all.
Speaker 1: but well so anime wise if you don't count the manga or anything true.
Speaker 1: But we do know there is an OAV that comes with one of the manga volumes that I have.
Speaker 1: That's about the diary or whatever of so-and-so, but it is one of those shows.
Speaker 0: It's not like I don't know a shonen fighting whatever show that's gonna have like 700 episodes that goes on forever.
Speaker 0: At least I hope not.
Speaker 0: Nope, but it's a show that has a story and at the end of what's come out so far That story was not done.
Speaker 0: No Like not even close.
Speaker 1: like the manga goes on and I'm sure the anime will pick up again at some point.
Speaker 0: So I just kind of assumed I was gonna watch it when it came out.
Speaker 0: like whenever there's new attack on Titan I just watch it, but then I didn't even read the manga.
Speaker 0: I just read every spoiler I could find.
Speaker 1: I'm reading all.
Speaker 1: I got mangas and I've read a bunch of them and I think I'm gonna stop reading them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't want a whole bunch of attack on Titan.
Speaker 0: volumes hit me up and once I read the spoilers I realized that the only thing the action scenes I liked and I like the characters.
Speaker 0: But then that kind of got played out there wasn't much new.
Speaker 0: All I actually cared about for the second half of the show was what's going on.
Speaker 0: I wanted to know the mystery.
Speaker 1: Well in the manga it gets to a point where it's not real.
Speaker 1: you don't get that sort of you know characters stuff anymore you don't get like a potato girl and whatever anymore and They start telling you more about the terrible secret of space, which is the best part.
Speaker 1: The problem is it's not a terrible secret of space and is neither terrible.
Speaker 1: No, it's it's a disappointment.
Speaker 0: It's not it's not terrible It's just terrible right exactly.
Speaker 1: Usually the terrible secret of space is something amazing Like yeah, or it's something that just fucks with your brain.
Speaker 0: But this is just like well, that's so lame like there's Titans in the walls, right?
Speaker 0: And now I know like what they are and why it's just super dumb and the coordinate.
Speaker 1: It's like you could have come up with a cool reason for why things are the way they are.
Speaker 1: But even even the expected reason that like, you know everyone like the most common theory that people would have at that point.
Speaker 1: But no, it was something dumb.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think the things that really made me not give a shit was like the secret of his dad is dumb The the king.
Speaker 0: that stuff goes.
Speaker 1: no king is the number one thing, right?
Speaker 1: So the king it's like this.
Speaker 1: they talk about royalty and like the royal family and you know that in the middle of the town And in the most secret place where the terrible secret of space is kept always in the middle You know the center the big tower or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: I mean this doesn't actually have a big tower in attack on Titan.
Speaker 1: But yeah, you know the the metaphorical big tower that all animes have where all the secrets are, right?
Speaker 1: you know an evangelical is actually a big hole in the ground or the bottom of the secrets are and It's like the king.
Speaker 1: we've never seen the king.
Speaker 1: we don't know anything about the king.
Speaker 1: It must be this mysterious awesome, dude Who's got like super evil and he's knows everything.
Speaker 1: and he's you know, he's got his machinations right and a full metal Alchemist this King Bradley.
Speaker 1: and while he's not, you know, he's not like the perfect ultimate badass king It's like it's still like whoa, that's his deal.
Speaker 0: He's got.
Speaker 0: wait like when you run it gets revealed you're like, oh, it's like oh shit son King Bradley.
Speaker 1: Oh snap, right?
Speaker 1: The king in full metal the king in attack on Titan is like the biggest disappointment.
Speaker 1: It's like really really That's what the king is really pointing in two ways.
Speaker 0: Cuz one you all the theories you might have are so wrong and it's so dumb.
Speaker 1: It's dumb.
Speaker 0: it being revealed sends the show in yet another direction.
Speaker 0: That is also dumb.
Speaker 1: Yep So disappointing.
Speaker 1: it's like oh, that's what the fuck.
Speaker 1: I don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: Yep, if they do they could have just done the cliche thing and made the king a badass of evil and I would have been like oh How did he become a badass of evil?
Speaker 1: Well, it's like.
Speaker 1: where's how you know, what's he knows?
Speaker 1: Nope, they didn't do any of that.
Speaker 0: So is it?
Speaker 0: because remember way back cuz there was noir and hack side and we watched all of noir.
Speaker 1: Well, those shows weren't really that related except for the music.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but a time in which they came out exactly.
Speaker 0: but that's how anime like.
Speaker 0: that's how they're stuck together in my head because One of them tricked me and then I realized what was going on with the other one cuz noir.
Speaker 0: not good Like real bad after the first four episodes and super bad, but it's not good.
Speaker 0: Like it's just the anime rim of 2016 would have watched the first five minutes of the fifth episode of noir and said nope and just turn it off.
Speaker 0: probably on yeah, but Hexine was the I think the first anime where I consciously wanted to watch it.
Speaker 0: Everyone else I knew was into it.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh this is the big show and I was really into it and I was trying to be into it and then Episode 13 came around.
Speaker 0: I was like, you know what?
Speaker 0: I just don't care.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was what you know.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of.
Speaker 1: most of the anime is actually that I started and did not finish even like, you know They're full run of was for this reason which is it just dragged and nothing happened, right?
Speaker 1: So hack sign is the biggest drag of them all where it's like key of the Twilight Key of the Twilight.
Speaker 1: Where is the key of the toilet?
Speaker 1: What's the key of the Twilight?
Speaker 1: Where is it?
Speaker 1: What is it?
Speaker 1: Who's good?
Speaker 1: What's going on?
Speaker 1: And then just are like.
Speaker 1: I realized at a point like after 13 episodes They made like one step of progress towards the key of the Twilight.
Speaker 1: I was like For like seven episodes nothing happened.
Speaker 1: Did it?
Speaker 1: No nothing happened for like the last seven episodes.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm done watching Yep, the same thing happened in Naruto, right?
Speaker 1: So Naruto is a situation where it's like they fought they fire fighting this big guy with a big sword who had like a partner who stood off to the side and After 13 episodes they beat the guy with the big sword and then like my brain woke up and was like They've been fighting the big guy with the big sword for like seven episodes.
Speaker 0: now I had quit before they even beat that guy because there was a moment where like Naruto did a move And I was in the fight with that.
Speaker 0: Yes, so Luke and Everyone in the anime club who was watching it faster than I was and they were like, oh my god When you find out how Naruto does the thing like it's crazy.
Speaker 0: and then I saw it and I was like They just made up a bunch of proper nouns.
Speaker 0: That's all they did.
Speaker 0: Nothing.
Speaker 0: They didn't even animate it And I stopped watching but you kept going.
Speaker 1: I went for 13 episodes ish, right?
Speaker 1: There was another show.
Speaker 1: what the hell was the name of that at least with the Shonen?
Speaker 1: There was a Shonen one with the little pet that had a pointy nose.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah the rave master That's the one you watch that show.
Speaker 0: I didn't watch any of it.
Speaker 1: I watched.
Speaker 1: I watched rave master because It had this cute animal friend with a pointy nose and after some number of episodes I forget how many I realized.
Speaker 1: wait a minute.
Speaker 1: This show has been in this one throne room ish room Fighting for like at least five episodes now.
Speaker 0: I'm done Yep, but I never even started that one because it was another show.
Speaker 0: only watch it because there's a cute monster Yeah, but also like people's also kids show mostly we're all talking about it Like I saw the spiral nose guy everywhere at conventions.
Speaker 0: I was like, well you still see him occasionally Yeah, who who?
Speaker 0: yeah, but who is the person who is still into that show?
Speaker 0: Nobody?
Speaker 1: No one who remembers it.
Speaker 0: All right other shows ever do you hockey show?
Speaker 0: We were really into that.
Speaker 1: I was about to bring up you.
Speaker 1: How do you show?
Speaker 0: I could remember the name of until a second ago?
Speaker 1: Oh, so you hockey shows.
Speaker 1: a similar situation where actually I think you hockey shows better than all the shows You just mentioned by a lot.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah But it's like it actually is the best example of the show that starts drugs Naruto.
Speaker 1: the first few episodes are funny ninja school and then it drags right rave master.
Speaker 1: The first few episodes are like genero fantasy and then it drags, right?
Speaker 1: You know hack sign the beginning doesn't really do much and then it you know what episode one and then it drags.
Speaker 1: But you hug a show.
Speaker 1: the first two episodes Start so strong setting up the world and then it's like tournament time and it's like man.
Speaker 0: Come on I think you you have a show was the show where I went from Watching a bunch of episodes of a shonen show and then being disappointed to starting to see it coming ahead of time I was like, wait a minute It's like it.
Speaker 1: those if you just made instead of having a stupid fighting part if you just made all the episodes just like those First beginning episodes that set everything up, you know If you just progressed plot without fighting all the time, however,
Speaker 0: there is the problem having
Speaker 1: an explicit tournament of fighting.
Speaker 0: So it's not that analogous.
Speaker 0: but Full Metal Panic had plot that was serious and interspersed with that plot was Ridiculous nonsense and comedy.
Speaker 1: Oh, that was what.
Speaker 1: that's a more typical pattern where yeah comedy starts in the early parts and then it fades.
Speaker 1: Slayers does the same thing that Full Metal Panic does where the comedy is strong in the early episodes and then it fades as the Plot takes over in the later episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but so I watched about half the thing is with Full Metal Panic The comedy is okay And the plot is really weak.
Speaker 1: and then I actually watched the whole first season because I don't know.
Speaker 1: And then I watched like one Fu Mafu and I'm like, nope Inuyasha got me pretty bad because it was a.
Speaker 0: you know, we're gonna go Takahashi.
Speaker 0: But it was actually really good.
Speaker 0: and there and I was like wow This is actually like the plot is moving as Keflon a style like shit keeps happening and there was literally a moment Where they have the MacGuffin.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh wow Cuz you know though, you know when there's a show where like you expect the MacGuffin to be the whole show.
Speaker 0: And then the MacGuffins like done in the fourth episode.
Speaker 1: Yep
Speaker 0: So that happened and then they dropped it and it exploded to a million shards and the one character is like now we have to go Collect all the shards and I literally hit pause and was like welp
Speaker 1: shouldn't they just be on the floor right in front of you?
Speaker 0: No, they flew off around the planet or something.
Speaker 0: use a vacuum [Laughter].
Speaker 0: So then there are the shows that we actually Liked and just stopped watching for some reason like Ergo Proxy Scott and I were watching in Beacon.
Speaker 0: Well, you're watching on Netflix physical DVDs Yeah, and I remember like we weren't super into it after the first couple episodes.
Speaker 0: But then like it got better and better as it started to deconstruct itself It was like oh, maybe this show isn't about what we thought it was.
Speaker 0: this looks interesting.
Speaker 0: and then as far as I can remember a DVD came that was scratched and wouldn't play and then eventually we got another DVD That was a different one.
Speaker 0: That was also scratched and wouldn't play and then we just kind of forgot about the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it really it's all about friction right and like effort to watch another episode, right?
Speaker 1: So like if I have the whole show right there and I've got nothing to do I'll just be like next episode next episode next episode next until I've seen the whole thing right unless something stops me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like Windows Ergo Proxy DVDs came.
Speaker 0: we watched all four episodes.
Speaker 1: So something stops me, right?
Speaker 1: So let's say I watch you know, six episodes of evangelical and then I got to go to bed.
Speaker 1: that stops me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: now sometimes it doesn't though with the shows good enough.
Speaker 0: like that six episode ends It's two in the morning and you're like I gotta watch one more right and then you know.
Speaker 1: So the next day I get home from work is the show strong enough to make me after or while eating dinner Pick it up again, right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: does it have the strength to keep to occupy my brain space from the previous day?
Speaker 1: and in a case like Evangelion it sure does but not every show has that strength.
Speaker 1: There were a lot of shows where I could watch them a bunch and then I completely forgot about them.
Speaker 1: There are other shows say for example Like I was watching space run away e day.
Speaker 1: Oh Right, so I was watching it while biking inside, right?
Speaker 1: So I'd bike inside and watch a day on at the same time and then the Sun came out one day And I was biking outside and no longer biking inside.
Speaker 1: So the habit of watching e day.
Speaker 0: Oh every day Disappeared, you know what happened.
Speaker 1: the same thing old Sailor Moon when I didn't yeah I didn't have this sort of it wasn't able to pull me.
Speaker 1: like man.
Speaker 1: I really need to know what happens in the next episode.
Speaker 1: I really care about this show.
Speaker 1: It was just.
Speaker 1: it was just this habit and if the habit was broken there wasn't anything pulling me.
Speaker 1: Yeah show didn't have any strength.
Speaker 1: now some watch another episode, you know.
Speaker 1: There are also times where that's happened with shows were like a weekend or a convention or you know.
Speaker 1: It's like I'll be watching it all week and I'll go away and come back and I'll forgot that I was watching.
Speaker 0: That was when we were rewatching old Sailor Moon cuz.
Speaker 0: they were releasing like two episodes a week and I was just keeping up I think.
Speaker 0: we went to a Scott Johnson party Yeah, and then came back and then forgot Yeah, because then it was a little bit behind and then I just let it get.
Speaker 0: leave town come home.
Speaker 1: You know you missed the habit and they were releasing four episodes a week or two or something.
Speaker 1: It was more than one Right, and then it's like.
Speaker 1: well I didn't watch him last week edited and watching lists week and now there's like eight of them and I'm like, well, I'm way behind now
Speaker 0: Yep But as opposed like ergo proxy had a lot a strong drive to the point that I we tried Two times to get the DVD to watch it before we gave up.
Speaker 1: So actually I feel I mean there were other shows.
Speaker 1: we got a Netflix DVD that we didn't finish.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, you know what those best example of that is fucking cause they know you Jim.
Speaker 1: That's the one I was about to say.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the show We did an episode on a long time ago.
Speaker 1: You can go listen to that episode cuz.
Speaker 1: I don't remember it enough now But I definitely have a podcast of a time when I did remember it.
Speaker 0: But the show basically had a problem where it was pretty good.
Speaker 0: But like after an episode ended there was a moment where I realized I didn't really give a shit.
Speaker 0: if I never saw more of it.
Speaker 1: I do not give any shits.
Speaker 0: It's not like cowboy bebop.
Speaker 1: or you show someone episode one you show and then half an episode and pause it and then they're like What I kill you Reaching to push the unpause.
Speaker 0: it was it Pete.
Speaker 0: I think it would never seen Cowboy bebop Alex.
Speaker 1: maybe it was one of our friends.
Speaker 0: All right, Pete, maybe like we were at school We moved into our apartment early like school didn't start for like days and we're all hanging out.
Speaker 0: We're like, oh you've never seen cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: So we showed him one episode.
Speaker 0: We're like, this is what it's like.
Speaker 0: We'll show you an episode will lend you the DVDs and then the three of us just watch the entire show that day.
Speaker 0: Yeah all the way to the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think we broke for dinner and we ate dinner watching episodes like it was.
Speaker 0: So there are shows that are bad But they're not really.
Speaker 0: they don't fit on this list because usually the show is bad.
Speaker 0: We're just like well that's bad We don't watch it.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm just plenty of things I've seen one episode of and then that's it Right, and it's like that doesn't really count as stopped watching.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I wasn't watching it really to begin with I just was a glancing or inspecting or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: But like I remember love Hina was.
Speaker 1: I watched the whole thing.
Speaker 0: I don't know how because it was real big.
Speaker 1: I will tell you how I watched the whole thing.
Speaker 1: love Hina came out our Turtle.
Speaker 0: you want to get to the turtle?
Speaker 1: Well, yeah turtle there was a turtle episode, by the way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a point with the turtle like the horse in utana.
Speaker 0: Did I assume the turtle stole someone's bra though?
Speaker 0: No, really?
Speaker 1: Maybe dip.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: So love Hina freshman year of college We saw like one or two episodes at anime club and it was just cute and it had a turtle.
Speaker 1: So I downloaded the whole thing and this is towards the end of that freshman year.
Speaker 1: So I didn't watch the whole thing in college.
Speaker 1: But then it was summer and I did some camp counselor action in summer and then I was And then I was in Connecticut in my house in Connecticut with nothing to fucking do in the summer Except I guess sit outside in the summer and I had my computer and I had a 56k modem.
Speaker 0: So, you know what that?
Speaker 1: I had CD roms and on those CD roms was every episode of love Hina That's got is a different episode.
Speaker 0: that is an episode of geek knives shows we watched all of because we were trapped in the wilderness Because I did the same thing with read or die TV.
Speaker 0: that show is garbage Garbage, but I had it.
Speaker 0: I had a bunch of DVDs with with it burn like pirated and I was living in a place with no internet.
Speaker 0: I was bored.
Speaker 0: I watched the entire show and it is Terrible.
Speaker 0: at no point does it redeem itself ever?
Speaker 1: Well, you know love Hina wasn't the worst thing to watch cuz.
Speaker 1: I had not at that point Watched a harem show and I guess you everybody gets one.
Speaker 1: you could find a lot worse harem shows and not saying love Hina's good Don't don't watch love Hina.
Speaker 0: No, no, you're gonna watch a harem show like full disclosure.
Speaker 0: watch tenshi.
Speaker 1: I don't want anyone to misinterpret and think I'm Cuz it was not good for you know for the one harem show that I've seen all the way through It's like that's you know, I could have done a lot worse.
Speaker 1: I could have done better but it's like it's fine.
Speaker 0: Tenchi Muyo is the best harem show.
Speaker 0: Mmm I'm gonna say it like that in that genre the best Harem of girls guy character show.
Speaker 1: it is the best one has to be one guy and a whole bunch of girls.
Speaker 0: Yeah I feel like there's other shows that me cuz tenchi had enough sci-fi and humor going on - it's not the worst show in the World.
Speaker 0: like I give it a solid B rating overall.
Speaker 1: There had to be other shows that are technically harem shows that but they're all There's.
Speaker 0: well, there's other tenchi.
Speaker 0: that's real bad.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I guess they're.
Speaker 0: you know There's a factor where love Hina was a show where I quit watching it because I want I was creeped out by it Mostly when the young character came in and then they kind of kept like she was part of the harem That.
Speaker 0: that was when I started to notice that shit going on more and more in anime.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean that's it by watching the whole thing, right?
Speaker 1: That's I was learning about the evils of those ways and now and then after that I was well informed.
Speaker 1: back then We didn't know there was able to avoid danger in the future.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like we didn't know.
Speaker 1: I have not hit any danger since then.
Speaker 1: I'm protected.
Speaker 0: shows like love Hina the resistance the anime Around us.
Speaker 0: we're super into it.
Speaker 0: So, you know you get a new situation at the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah for like about a week But it's a situation where there's a show that all the people around you are watching and you watch a few episodes And you don't like it, but everyone else keeps watching it.
Speaker 0: So you feel like well am I missing something?
Speaker 0: Am I dumb or no, they're dumb.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're the but they're the wrong ones.
Speaker 0: Not you I know.
Speaker 1: are there any shows that were actually Because all the shows you mentioned so far were like, oh it was a show that we started watching for some reason But the show wasn't actually any good.
Speaker 1: So he stopped.
Speaker 1: is there actually a good show?
Speaker 0: ergo proxy.
Speaker 0: We stopped because of technical difficulties.
Speaker 0: So Rosaphone I hear is a really good show, but I got the whole thing.
Speaker 0: It's Okay.
Speaker 0: So I've heard reviews of it.
Speaker 1: beginning is way better than the later part ranging from it's pretty good to it.
Speaker 0: Does Ava better than Ava?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: whoever said that is fucked up and I am.
Speaker 0: I'm not super Believing that that's a fucked up stupid person, but I just kind of stopped watching it because after four episodes I didn't feel like it was going where I cared about and I just stopped.
Speaker 0: but it wasn't.
Speaker 0: I don't think it was necessarily that bad.
Speaker 1: I think I just watched it all because of inertia.
Speaker 1: It's one of those shows where if I had been interrupted by say a trip out of town I might I probably wouldn't have continued watching Yeah.
Speaker 1: But because I was in a situation where no blockers came in I just kept rolling like lazily on and saw the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Oh, here's one.
Speaker 0: So Fuji go mean a when it first came out.
Speaker 0: We watched a couple episodes.
Speaker 0: It was crazy good Yeah, and I watched every episode as it came out.
Speaker 0: But then I basically got distracted and kind of forgot it existed.
Speaker 1: like I was also distracted Yeah, and I didn't forget it existed.
Speaker 0: I was just doing other stuff, but I like forgot about it for a long time.
Speaker 0: It was only recently when all the new Lupin stuff started coming out that I was like, oh right Lupin I didn't finish that other Lupin and I haven't seen Lupin in a while.
Speaker 1: I need to refresh my Lupin.
Speaker 0: Oh, I think we're entering a golden age of Lupin.
Speaker 0: It's Lupin.
Speaker 1: It's definitely Lupin o'clock right about now That Bell is ringing so hard.
Speaker 0: Those clock hands are crushing so many counts.
Speaker 1: It is currently Lupin o'clock.
Speaker 1: Actually, maybe I'll watch it when I get home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what do you would?
Speaker 0: so when you get to the point where Lupin sees the owls - I that's like that's.
Speaker 0: that's when it Starts to get into the plot like the plot plot.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: I never seen a Lupin with the plot.
Speaker 1: That wasn't just a movie that ended.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean the show is just yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like the spongebob of heist anime Shows that are really good that we never finished.
Speaker 1: Well, one of them for me is one that people like love the fuck out of which is Jojo's Bizarre Adventure, right?
Speaker 1: So I was watching the newer one the one that has the roundabout closer, which is like the one of the best Yeah, I ever seen right.
Speaker 0: I watched a bunch of episodes.
Speaker 1: I was into it.
Speaker 1: I was enjoying it.
Speaker 1: I wanted to find out what happened.
Speaker 1: You know, I cared about do is so evil and badass.
Speaker 1: I wanted to see him get some fighting action, right?
Speaker 1: And I was also curious because I'd known a lot of stuff about Joe Joe's and I know that like they go to Egypt at Some point like I read a ton of the manga.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wanted I wanted to know about that shit, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know, I was I was into it and then it got to this point.
Speaker 1: We're like, okay He's learning some you know, some like, you know fighting powers and then they meet this huge dude They have to fight and then
Speaker 0: I know you're describing every episode of Joe Joe's right
Speaker 1: and it was like, oh, I'm like, okay I'm you know I'm with this.
Speaker 1: There's some fight in a castle or something and then I just didn't watch the next Episode when it came out and then I fell behind and then I forgot about it and then that was that.
Speaker 0: the problem I have With Joe Joe's is that I love everything about it except actually watching it.
Speaker 1: I think that's what it is Like.
Speaker 0: I love the aesthetic.
Speaker 0: I love the characters.
Speaker 1: The story is so just fucking crazy that I love it But I actually watch it and then I just kind of when I actually watch it It's like I might enjoy myself while watching it, but there there's no pull for the next episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right It's like it doesn't make me want anymore.
Speaker 0: I'm not like really worried about what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: because what's gonna happen is gonna be Joe Joe being like, haha I did X because of Y and Z right.
Speaker 1: for some reason fist of the North Star is Quite similar, but when you watch fist of the North Star is like I just want to watch another one.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm.
Speaker 1: you know, when I watch it Joe Joe's like I'm seated like I'm like, oh, all right.
Speaker 1: That was amazing.
Speaker 1: I'm good I think delicious star and then you're full.
Speaker 1: but if you eat fist of the North Star is delicious steak or you eat it And you're just hungrier.
Speaker 0: fist of the North Star does a better job.
Speaker 0: They're both like trains going somewhere.
Speaker 0: but Joe Joe's you can't tell where the trains going at all unless you know a lot about the Joe Joe verse.
Speaker 0: But this is the North Star does a good job of pointing out like trains kind of going in this direction Like you can see where this trains going.
Speaker 0: you want to go where this trains going.
Speaker 1: I will go I will ride that kentro train wherever it goes.
Speaker 0: But like you get on the Joe Joe train and then just like cars start falling off into pits and they're like They're like station.
Speaker 1: stop New York and I'm like, oh, it's my stop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then you're like, what's the next stop?
Speaker 0: Poughkeepsie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, fuck that.
Speaker 0: So there's a bunch of shows that I watched a bunch of just because I was stupid and I was.
Speaker 1: I haven't had that problem.
Speaker 0: Well, like when anime was not super easy to come by or when I first got to RIT anime There's probably the worst.
Speaker 0: there's two times in my life where I watch a lot of three times There's a lot of bad anime.
Speaker 0: the one times when I watch reader died TV because I was a little into the woods the time before that was when I got to RIT and got access to the RIT anime library because All the great classics of anime as far as the previous generation to us of anime fans was concerned Was there.
Speaker 0: so I had all these senpais coming to me and being like oh Marmalade boy is a super important anime and you should watch it.
Speaker 1: I actually didn't watch any of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Marmalade boy, not a good show.
Speaker 1: Oh I hope they're listening.
Speaker 1: Yeah How about that Kimogori orange road that they love so much?
Speaker 0: oh my god.
Speaker 0: So I liked Kimogori orange road a lot, but I also stopped watching it because it's not good.
Speaker 1: How about that?
Speaker 1: Please save my earth.
Speaker 1: They love so much I was.
Speaker 0: so I was really into.
Speaker 0: please save my earth because it was the first show I've seen that had like the really really deep secretive space with a lot of like.
Speaker 0: it looked real deep and like.
Speaker 0: there was a lot to chew on and analyze.
Speaker 0: and Then I got to the end of the show and I was like, oh Not only did they not get to explaining all of it But what little they explained is really dumb kind of like attack on Titan.
Speaker 1: So you bring up the anime club library.
Speaker 1: that makes me remember there were shows that I was getting tapes of weekly and then stopped And the number one of those was card capture Sakura.
Speaker 1: I was.
Speaker 1: it was just such a famous show at the time and I just started watching and I didn't disenjoy it.
Speaker 1: I just you know I only could get two tapes a week and I stopped choosing that one because there were other choices and one of the choices I Picked it was on the best shows ever, which is pat laboire, right?
Speaker 1: that time I Didn't finish the show.
Speaker 1: I actually went back and finished it later in life.
Speaker 1: And the reason I didn't finish it was because those VHS tapes they had.
Speaker 1: I don't
Speaker 0: know why
Speaker 1: I think I heard from somewhere that They were just direct rips of the laserdisc and that they were structured in such a way that you would get one OAV episode and then like two or three TV episodes and then the second OAV Episode and then two or three.
Speaker 1: so like the order was all fucked up.
Speaker 1: But I couldn't really a hundred percent follow everything that was happening.
Speaker 1: and when I was able to rewatch it years later And see that is the best thing ever I was watched the first OAV first TV the second, you know I watched it in the correct viewing order and was able to get everything out of it.
Speaker 1: So that's actually a show that I stopped watching and did go back and finish later.
Speaker 1: but I think that might be one of the only ones where the shows that you stopped watching and Then actually did go back to and watch the whole thing at another point
Speaker 0: You know, there's a whole separate class of shows of the shows that are really good or funny and really long But are so episodic that they're.
Speaker 0: they're like a Seinfeld where you're not gonna marathon a season of Seinfeld or Lupin.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're gonna watch an episode like Nichijou like I probably have seen every episode of Nichijou I haven't but in a completely random order because I'll just be like.
Speaker 1: I just saw goat gifts and I watched a couple episodes and I didn't see any goats and I'm like, alright, I'm done.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think.
Speaker 0: well, I Like the show a lot.
Speaker 0: There's some good stuff in there.
Speaker 0: But like Ranma, Urisei and Sura.
Speaker 0: I love both their shows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've only seen like a handful of Ranma's.
Speaker 1: I've seen like two Urisei and Sura's.
Speaker 0: I've seen a ton of Urisei and Sura and I've read most of the manga that was released in English at least in the old Days or like Gintama is like that too.
Speaker 1: Like I really thought Meizani Koku was the manga.
Speaker 0: Meizani Koku has a serial plot.
Speaker 0: Urisei and Sura is just nonsense.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's so much better.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: actually it is because you can pick a random episode and watch it and I guess they count because I have not seen every episode of these shows
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: I really like them and I feel like actually I should just start picking up random episodes and watching them again.
Speaker 1: I feel like I should watch Urisei and Sura in order.
Speaker 0: Uh We could just start cranking them out in a week.
Speaker 0: Sure, I did when it went.
Speaker 0: yeah, I watched the first five or so in a row a few years ago.
Speaker 0: Then I just stopped for some reason.
Speaker 0: I think I got busy.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Uh Then there was Sailor Moon Crystal.
Speaker 0: That was just bad.
Speaker 1: It's a different story.
Speaker 0: Uh I've never actually seen The you know, the Landsman movie like the anime.
Speaker 1: I thought you owned it on VHS.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've never seen the entire thing in one go.
Speaker 0: I've seen every part of it, but I've shown it to people so many times.
Speaker 0: But then I'd like leave the room or fall asleep.
Speaker 0: that I've never watched it awake from beginning to end in my entire life.
Speaker 1: That's really strange Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I've seen every minute of footage in the movie or at least in the dub that I taped off of the sci-fi channel.
Speaker 1: That's really weird.
Speaker 0: yeah Yeah, it is really weird, but I did stands out in my mind.
Speaker 0: I almost feel like I should never watch it because I'd always fall asleep.
Speaker 0: Especially there's that part at the end where he's on that like he's with the green guys flying Kind of like near the last battle.
Speaker 0: I always wake up with the green guy flying really fast through that scene near the end.
Speaker 0: So whatever I'd miss in that middle, I'm just gonna wake up at the green guy flying.
Speaker 0: I'd be like, well that happened again.
Speaker 1: Okay I've started reading the lens of in novels and I read a bunch of them, but I didn't finish all of them.
Speaker 1: No Does that count?
Speaker 0: Actually, I'm just because I wrote down a bunch of shows.
Speaker 0: so great teacher Onizuka I was oh, yeah That's a classic show that I was like.
Speaker 1: I started reading watching the show and reading the manga and didn't finish either one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was super into it cuz it was really funny and then Nothing new happened.
Speaker 1: It didn't have staying power.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like they ran out of jokes and they just got more and more perverted and I didn't care anymore.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Well, there was another show that I was really into her.
Speaker 0: Uh, the one Boy the boys over flowers.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah originally anime anime.
Speaker 1: I think if I'm gonna watch that I'm gonna watch the live-action drama version from country of choice.
Speaker 1: I want the Korean one of the Japanese one is better.
Speaker 0: I watched the anime pretty much all the way up until people started dating and Then the show kind of ran out of steam because I didn't care anymore about any of the people.
Speaker 1: anime was way strong in the beginning.
Speaker 1: And yeah with the f4 that's what it's about no matter which version you watch.
Speaker 0: Actually, you know what that show and Nana both had that same problem like Nana.
Speaker 0: I didn't finish either Yeah, because Nana was great and then it got to a point like wow Every character is an amazing person except Nana who's actually really boring.
Speaker 0: and now this is just becoming like baby mama drama This like basic girl ruining her life and making poor decisions.
Speaker 0: This is like some made-for-tv nonsense.
Speaker 1: now All right, you have any more.
Speaker 1: I think I'm running out I'm running low here And I'm sure there's more I can't think of.
Speaker 0: I used to go to anime club marathons.
Speaker 0: You know we drive her like every at least once a month on over a weekend And I went to them
Speaker 1: a lot less often is than you, but when I did go I usually saw the whole thing
Speaker 0: Yep, but the first one where I left as opposed to watching the whole show was actually a magic Knights rare.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't go to that at all.
Speaker 0: so I went.
Speaker 1: I have the manga.
Speaker 1: I only read the first volume.
Speaker 0: it was another one of those famous shows that a lot of people are super into.
Speaker 0: hard to follow Yeah, so I watched.
Speaker 0: like the first nine.
Speaker 0: I was the manga is hard to follow and then I went outside to like at a snack And it was real warm and nice outside because it was during the summer just didn't go back.
Speaker 0: So I just I was like.
Speaker 0: you know what.
Speaker 0: there are things more important than anime Mm-hmm?
Speaker 0: well no there's things more important than Magic Knight rare.
Speaker 0: If that had been Evangelion I would've been right back in that room.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: the patrons for this episode in order of the amount of money.
Speaker 0: They give us our Nicholas brand our Rebecca Dunn John our knobs.
Speaker 0: the second Amanda douchette James David white Christian coon's Jess Sam cordery Mechanical mind William Eisen rose.
Speaker 0: you expected the next name to be yours, but it was me.
Speaker 0: do.
Speaker 0: Clinton Walton my stady calm Phil all rich Renee from New Zealand Robert Lee Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Rare Laval Brian Sidroni Rochelle, Montanona Finn Eric Silveraude, and then he placed a single finger upon his moustache.
Speaker 0: kinetic man Aaron Cerise Chris midkiff Chris Knox.
Speaker 0: He was a dark and stormy knigget.
Speaker 0: Daniel Redman Chris a dad Doug Schneider Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: We're actually getting pretty much back into the swing of things.
Speaker 0: We've got magfest four days, which might prevent us from doing a Thursday show next week.
Speaker 0: But after that we pretty much got nothing until like PAX East and Connecticut and anime Boston and all that nonsense.
Speaker 0: So pretty much a hundred percent back on geek night schedule.
Speaker 0: for the foreseeable future I'll have the two packs videos up as soon as I get at least one utenna up.
Speaker 0: Then I'll get the second utenna up since we actually recorded episodes 14 and 15 the other weekend when we had our film shoot This coming weekend.
Speaker 0: We might record episodes 15 16. if we can't even 17 because the more video I get recorded Then it's just a matter of me having the time to actually edit it all together.
Speaker 0: And as I've said repeatedly I have the new knob so I might be able to do it pretty quickly.
Speaker 0: and now I leave for you something that's kind of amazing and It's particularly amazing if you watch the movie, but only watch this one part entirely out of context.
Speaker 1: I'm a lucky young man.
Speaker 1: Oh, I have a piano That'll take us away from it all.