Speaker 1: It's Thursday September 15th 2016.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: I can't believe we never did a show about pizza and all these years of complaining about not having Thursday show ideas pizza really Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I had the ancient ancient Laser printer that Scott and I shared at the geek house and over time it sort of stopped working like it still printed.
Speaker 0: I think it worked.
Speaker 1: Okay, it didn't.
Speaker 1: it wouldn't load paper unless you sort of like shook it and like push the paper in and half the time It would load multiple sheets and then fuck itself up.
Speaker 1: paper got jammed in it all the time.
Speaker 1: The toner was still mostly present like it would print like it was running low on toner But the problems were all the rest of the mechanical bits.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So we family needed a printer for something Something else.
Speaker 0: rim breaks to make an excuse to buy something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would rather have not bought a printer.
Speaker 1: I use printers.
Speaker 1: Like the only thing I print anymore is The thing I have to mail with my rent every month because they made an online system But they charge 50 or so bucks to use it.
Speaker 1: So I have to print my thing every month Which I do at work, but what if I didn't go to work or something or you know change?
Speaker 0: Like what if I just didn't have a friend print character sheets for RPGs, but I could use my iPad maybe and I print?
Speaker 1: There were a couple times where I needed to print Sheets not for me to use an RPG But for everyone else to use because it was an RPG that I had some sort of higher level interest in.
Speaker 1: But in those cases that printer was too unreliable.
Speaker 1: So I just go and print it at work.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, but I mean that's kind of like the only thing that it's like.
Speaker 1: oh and if I use mega bus I got a print the ticket because they won't let you use your phone Why not?
Speaker 1: they just won't they specifically on the website like fuck you You cannot show us your phone like they were.
Speaker 1: the last time I checked they were very explicit about that Which was always weird, but I hate about not taking their bus.
Speaker 1: So yeah, the thing is mega bus is the only non Amtrak way to get to Hartford.
Speaker 0: Just cars cars go there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you want to rent a car.
Speaker 1: I'm not renting a car.
Speaker 1: I'm done renting cars.
Speaker 0: I got other methods.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you have parental methods.
Speaker 0: You can come and get in the same car that I get in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you left way later than us.
Speaker 0: So, what's your hurry?
Speaker 1: I'd like to get there earlier.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I do a lot more work on the staff.
Speaker 1: We'll see if I keep staffing but at least for now, I do a lot of work on the staff.
Speaker 0: Nothing had.
Speaker 0: Thursday doesn't really exist.
Speaker 1: Yeah, most lives like I like to get like I'm older now and it's weird.
Speaker 1: I've gone back and forth.
Speaker 1: There was a time when I go to a convention.
Speaker 1: I would want to maximize my time at that convention like in those early Otacon days Like we'd get up at the crack of dawn on Thursday and our goal was to be in Baltimore by noon Because that just means more time hanging out like yeah.
Speaker 1: But then I got older and I actually had stuff to do outside the conventions.
Speaker 1: So I started like I remember a couple anime bosses.
Speaker 1: we'd roll in Friday morning and leave like Sunday early afternoon Which became problematic because may a bolt bus would often get stuck in traffic on Friday morning.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I feel like I either want like I either want to get in early enough to have dinner and go to bed as opposed to Show up late and be kind of hungry, but it's Hartford or Baltimore or whatever and there's nowhere to eat.
Speaker 1: I'd rather actually eat a real dinner.
Speaker 1: So I tend to show up at cons at like 5 p.m The day before the con.
Speaker 1: that's like.
Speaker 1: that's my go-in.
Speaker 1: That's my modus operandi now mmm.
Speaker 1: So you got any news on this Thursday geek night's the lounge?
Speaker 1: I do have always gonna say is I bought a new printer and it's just like professional color laser printer and We didn't know what any printer papers that would sitting up there and I haven't actually set it up yet.
Speaker 0: So well a while ago many months ago I finished watching like every Zatoichi movie and I finished watching a bunch of animes.
Speaker 1: now I gotta I gotta watch those the tochis.
Speaker 1: I've only seen a handful.
Speaker 0: Is that tochi your mom, right?
Speaker 1: I heard that he had a war with a Nobunga.
Speaker 0: Yeah And then of all the animes that were on Hulu but weren't on crunchyroll I finished watching those.
Speaker 0: so and I have crunchyroll still.
Speaker 0: So there was ice.
Speaker 0: basically you I didn't cancel the Hulu.
Speaker 0: I basically said stop paying for the no commercial Hulu.
Speaker 1: and then they stopped offering the free Hulu.
Speaker 0: No Yeah, it's not offering the free one But it's like I was paying for the no commercial super one because that I don't want to see commercial.
Speaker 1: I was too and I remember I stopped paying for it.
Speaker 1: one day when I logged in I was like, alright There's no shows in here that I can't watch elsewhere.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like I already watched all this that you have, you know, and I'm good.
Speaker 1: So then now if they had more archives I'm outta kept paying like if you could watch old Simpsons, but you can't.
Speaker 1: so I just downloaded torrents of every Simpsons but first 20 seasons.
Speaker 0: today May be the day when I pay Hulu monies again because I remembered why I paid Hulu monies in the first place.
Speaker 0: It's when do you watch TV?
Speaker 0: Primarily for one show the park of South.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: I guess I gotta pay for Hulu again.
Speaker 0: It has return ed.
Speaker 0: there was a new episode Yesterday, so I could mind having cable television.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sure we could.
Speaker 1: I guess the problem is what I've run into recently is that you pirate Bay.
Speaker 1: unless you're pirating something like Right after the episode which I guess I would with South Park It's hard to get good quality rips of things later.
Speaker 0: Like I haven't had that experience.
Speaker 1: Try try getting like all the episodes of Adventure Time you've missed.
Speaker 0: I haven't had a problem ever getting an episode.
Speaker 1: What was the last episode you watched?
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: but thing that happened in Adventure Time Don't remember.
Speaker 1: but how many arms does fan have?
Speaker 0: That changes all the time, but there's a current number.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: But anyway, how many did he have when you last watched?
Speaker 0: I don't remember name another character other than Jake Uh Lovey's face princess.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Okay the when I downloaded that episode that I watched most recently I had I was actually like 10 or 20 episodes behind at that point Yep, and I downloaded all of them individually.
Speaker 0: No problem from bit Torrance.
Speaker 1: See I tried to do that a few weeks ago.
Speaker 0: I think you're just really bad at bit Torrance Like you're really bad at googling.
Speaker 1: No, so you can get him easily.
Speaker 1: Just don't go to pirate Bay You gotta go to.
Speaker 0: I always actually got them from pirate Bay.
Speaker 0: No problem.
Speaker 0: That's where I got them from.
Speaker 1: Just try doing that recently because there are four specific adventure time episode.
Speaker 0: when I get home I will go and stock up on the missed adventure times.
Speaker 0: I'll remind here's the rules.
Speaker 1: It's gotta actually be HD.
Speaker 0: Of course It's a adventure time isn't actually 1080p at 720p first.
Speaker 1: That's fine But yeah I always get HD every time cuz I thought a few of them the only one that had anyone actually seating were like these 480 whatever like bad rips the people.
Speaker 0: I've never seen a non 720p Adventure Time.
Speaker 1: They're out there.
Speaker 1: They're out there Steven Universe, I just pay for but whatever We're at site lets you pay for that.
Speaker 1: It's just on Amazon.
Speaker 0: Oh You buy it direct buy a buy it as a show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it's worth it.
Speaker 1: I mean that show is probably the best cartoon other than Bojack out right now and I like it a lot.
Speaker 1: so I might as well pay money to the people who made it isn't it?
Speaker 0: It's not on Hulu or Netflix.
Speaker 1: Oh Hey, well, all those things are on those services, but they're always like so far behind.
Speaker 1: that is literally pointless.
Speaker 0: But far behind is good cuz I'm not that far behind.
Speaker 1: you think like I'm behind on Adventure Time.
Speaker 1: All right Well watching one of those services.
Speaker 1: No, those services are so far behind.
Speaker 1: It's a joke.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean if you're starting at the beginning you can get caught way up.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I'm not mmm, that's my problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you can just go on Hulu and watch all the South Park, yeah But you can't do that to the Simpsons from episode one.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway So, uh, yeah South Park, I guess I mean that shows always been pretty solid.
Speaker 1: I guess it will continue to be solid.
Speaker 0: it will continue to be solid.
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: in other news our our friend Luke crane and while this is a game It's also improv and it like it's not just like it's kind of beyond a game I could see people who have never played you
Speaker 0: don't need an excuse to talk about this just cuz it's not Tuesday.
Speaker 1: I don't know what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: people who don't play role-playing games and maybe don't even know really what a role-playing game is.
Speaker 0: It's better if you know.
Speaker 0: if you've heard the word larp before it's and you have an idea of what that is and haven't done.
Speaker 0: I don't know because it's probably better that no one tells you that this is a larp even though it is cuz.
Speaker 0: maybe you'll play It if no one calls it a larp.
Speaker 1: I feel like there's a. there's an uncanny valley of larp.
Speaker 0: Like if you don't tell a kid that a food is a vegetable he might get him to eat it.
Speaker 1: But like someone who knows what larks are is gonna assume that it's just all weird vampire sex or 90% of it is or people hitting each other with foam swords.
Speaker 1: 80% of it is this is this is an experience.
Speaker 1: This is the 10% that is neither our good friend Luke crane who you may know from burning wheel and project donut and other such things.
Speaker 1: Quite like seven years ago long goddamn time ago had this little like mod scenario of burning wheel that he called inheritance and get a bunch of people together and The prodigal son returns having been exiled for a decade for murdering his brother to claim his grandfather's inheritance.
Speaker 1: And it's just this role-playing scenario.
Speaker 1: We played it at an uber con like sitting around a table and he kept working on that thing year after year after year and Many years refining it and refining and refining it to the point to where it's its own standalone game.
Speaker 1: now It's on Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: It was released on Kickstarter this morning.
Speaker 0: Why does it only have 17 days to go aren't?
Speaker 0: kickstart is usually more than 18 days long.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I guess you could pick a number of days like.
Speaker 1: I'm actually not sure.
Speaker 1: maybe it was on.
Speaker 1: I mean, I can't imagine it was there before.
Speaker 0: it just seems like arbitrary number of days 18 days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well a plus 17 more days.
Speaker 1: well, I mean I don't need to tell you to back it cuz he only wanted 10 grand and he's already got 25 grand as a 25 grand from a mere 236 people.
Speaker 0: so that's an average of hundred dollars a person.
Speaker 1: Well, it's a hundred dollars to get the good edition that has the cloth stuff.
Speaker 0: Oh, so did everyone kick all.
Speaker 0: two hundred thirty people got the cloth?
Speaker 1: Well, pretty much everyone who could got the six hundred dollar wood edition and they're gone.
Speaker 0: How many of those were there?
Speaker 0: Uh 20 it looks like 20 people paid six hundred dollars for the wood edition.
Speaker 1: Whoa So the cloth edition is a hundred bucks or a ninety?
Speaker 1: Yeah hundred bucks ish and there's only 21 of them left.
Speaker 1: No, and everything else is not.
Speaker 1: you want the cloth edition.
Speaker 1: I think for like 70 you can get the paper edition, which is still the game.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's fine But the game is a. it's kind of a one-shot like you can play it again.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've played it a bunch of times through the year.
Speaker 1: So I actually know all the at least many of the crazy spoilers I've seen this game change over the years.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I you know I can't imagine too much of the story and characters that the core have changed.
Speaker 1: the core story is still there.
Speaker 1: I can pick out from this image.
Speaker 1: He's got who most of these people are.
Speaker 0: That priest is so lame.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was imagined him being way cooler Christian.
Speaker 1: why would he be cool?
Speaker 1: And the one time the last time I played this when it was closest to his current form I fucking tracked that priest down and murdered him in the epilogue.
Speaker 0: Where's where's runecasting?
Speaker 0: dwarf, man?
Speaker 0: That's my guy.
Speaker 0: I Always hiding in the back inside in the back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was your guy.
Speaker 0: But I think that if I play it again, I think that would still be my guy.
Speaker 1: but seriously Inheritance.
Speaker 1: if you've never played one of those like Scandinavian or Nordic style LARPs It is not like what you expect from America.
Speaker 1: Imagine a bunch of people just in a room arguing violently and Crying and getting weirdly emotional and playing this sort of very human drama.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, it's a. it's a you know a typical thing you see in a soap opera right, you know The old man dies.
Speaker 0: There's a big inheritance - and all the family gets together and the lawyers there and you're all fighting, right?
Speaker 1: Usually in the so I guess in the soap opera the sonu murdered his brother ten years ago comes back to claiming Exactly.
Speaker 0: It's just a typical plot.
Speaker 0: There's nothing special about it Except for the fact we just change the setting to be all ye Norse Vikings and suddenly it's awesome.
Speaker 0: And it's not some corny soap opera because everyone's got horns on their helmets and swords.
Speaker 1: Also, it has very simple elegant mccain or hammers or magic And as a result, it's very freeform and open.
Speaker 1: So what you find is that that even though they get like the snare is pretty much the same every time same characters.
Speaker 1: It plays a specific not nine people and a facilitator like you can't play with less.
Speaker 1: you got rid of all those options.
Speaker 1: It's just an experience.
Speaker 1: if you've played it enough, you'll know literally all the spoilers and yet it'll go a different way every time.
Speaker 0: Maybe a different people.
Speaker 0: It'll go a different way every time but in the same people at the same people.
Speaker 0: You're gonna do something different cuz you learn something from the last time.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: The last time I played it I ended Like if you play a text adventure five times It'll be different five times because you're not just gonna sit there and make the same exact choice.
Speaker 1: Like that pretty real scenario the sword.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: I've seen the sword end with all of them dying.
Speaker 1: I've seen it end with like the human guy becoming king and everyone else dead.
Speaker 0: I've seen the rat scurry away with the sword.
Speaker 1: Yep, Pete ran that one.
Speaker 1: What con were we at?
Speaker 1: Was that Zenkon Con or Magfest?
Speaker 1: Where he ran the sword for these kids?
Speaker 1: They got really into it and he just kept rolling with it and it ended up being like the rat.
Speaker 1: people like fighting for their Kingdom like way off distant from where it began.
Speaker 0: You gotta stop the sword before it gets to that point.
Speaker 1: He just kept going and it just kept rolling.
Speaker 1: Just roll that wheel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, inheritance is crazy amazing.
Speaker 1: I would say that the last time I played it was literally the peak role-playing experience of my life to date.
Speaker 0: The problem with this is that you know, like rim got the cloth edition, so I don't need it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, usually like burning will codex comes out like everybody kicking that right.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm gonna say everyone needs a book.
Speaker 0: Not everyone needs one of these which is fine.
Speaker 0: You just need one per group.
Speaker 0: Make sure you know someone who who backed this on Kickstarter and if the only person you know is you that guess who's buying.
Speaker 1: Yeah But seriously I'm getting this and I plan to run it for people at conventions because it takes a few hours Like it's not like it takes longer to play Eclipse than to play this for serious heavy-duty RPG.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz you gotta learn a cliff.
Speaker 0: Yeah Lips is coming out for PC tomorrow.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna play.
Speaker 0: so if you want to play eclipse with us You know go buy it on Scott's in charge of that.
Speaker 1: cuz I facilitated the subterfuge which I kind of want to play again But buy it on Steam tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Yep, and got the Civ 5 also.
Speaker 1: patreon backers There's two of you haven't joined.
Speaker 1: the patreon backers said five game.
Speaker 0: That's how people do?
Speaker 1: they pay for shit and they don't join it like real soon or I'm replacing you with alternates.
Speaker 0: You know how many people buy like humble bundles and don't play the games like me?
Speaker 1: Oh, I can see exactly how many people look at the content in the patreon Like.
Speaker 1: I get a lot of data and all I want to say is that data is fascinating.
Speaker 0: Are people spending money and they're not even checking it out?
Speaker 0: Uh, they're just.
Speaker 0: they just forgot about it and they're giving us money every month without even looking actually listening to any podcast or anything.
Speaker 1: A lot of people started subscribing to gig nights in patreon like regular gig nights because it has this whole RSS feature now Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So they're using that instead of our feed and They I actually talked to some people about it.
Speaker 1: the main reason seems to be that They actually subscribe to a lot of things on patreon and they basically patreon is now the feed of all the things they like.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, so they don't just use an RSS reader like feedly or something.
Speaker 1: Well if they do they RSS the patreon Mm-hmm because it's like an aggregator of their stuff Interesting and it's not like they can just go like it.
Speaker 1: They have to have the account because a lot of it is stuff that they paid for and patreon is getting real interesting.
Speaker 0: It's interesting that without google reader, you could suddenly charge people money for each individual feed in google reader.
Speaker 0: No, you want us to add this to your google reader.
Speaker 0: one dollar a month.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: It's like what you're just getting this for free.
Speaker 0: Well the people i've talked to There's a really interesting article by the guy who was in charge of google reader when it died and he's basically so sorry.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's like it's all my fault.
Speaker 0: I sucked so I should have been concentrating more on getting more users, but I didn't care.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well i've done some informal sampling and it seems like most people who back to patreon They don't care about any extra rewards.
Speaker 1: They just want to give us money because they appreciate what we've done.
Speaker 1: stop But there's a small number of people who back it only to get the rewards.
Speaker 0: smart, but the rewards are worthless.
Speaker 0: Why are you backing?
Speaker 1: and one person and only one person stopped backing us and they filled out the exit survey and the exit survey was basically Didn't get enough extra content.
Speaker 0: smartest person.
Speaker 1: Yeah He was giving more money.
Speaker 1: Well, he or she I don't know but that person was giving more money than I would have expected.
Speaker 1: Also, some of you are giving a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Good god Good god, just give me the money.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, if you tell me something good you're gonna do with it.
Speaker 0: I just built a computer.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, and what's that gonna facilitate in terms of content?
Speaker 0: All the things I have to watch then review on this show.
Speaker 1: But it doesn't cost you money to watch those things.
Speaker 0: It cost me a whole computer to watch those things.
Speaker 1: You can watch those things on your old htpc.
Speaker 1: you just can't play pac-man on your old htpc.
Speaker 1: not a full frames anyway But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: This was in my feed and it was way more terrifying than I thought it was going to be when I read it.
Speaker 1: So I got two things today that are related.
Speaker 1: They both involve ants.
Speaker 1: So this is a uh, the headline is bizarre ant colony discovered in an abandoned polish nuclear weapons bunker.
Speaker 0: So wait, I didn't know that the poland ever had nuclear weapons.
Speaker 1: that's news to me, uh Why don't you know about the cold war?
Speaker 0: Oh, are you saying those are russian nuclear weapons that were in poland?
Speaker 1: Uh, poland did not control nuclear weapons directly.
Speaker 1: No, as far as I know, okay, but uh, I was I was.
Speaker 0: I guess I was not aware that russia Put it that way.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, so basically they develop video games these days.
Speaker 1: I'll summarize this but you got to read this article.
Speaker 1: This is Fascinating, but basically there's this one kind of wood ant that is pretty like a termite.
Speaker 0: It eats it eats wood.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I think so or it lives in the world.
Speaker 1: I don't know a lot about ants But you don't say but these oh soviets built the bunker during the cold war to store nuclear weapons, blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: Okay, basically this giant and code to store them.
Speaker 0: It wasn't a launching place, but it was hidden.
Speaker 1: It was a storing like it was camouflaged and hidden.
Speaker 1: Okay, so it's abandoned.
Speaker 0: Poland is a good place to hide nuclear weapons.
Speaker 0: No one's gonna look for them there.
Speaker 1: It's abandoned.
Speaker 1: and ants?
Speaker 1: these ants just formed a colony on top of it.
Speaker 1: But then one day apparently the center of their colony was right over this metal pipe ventilation pipe that had a metal cap on it.
Speaker 1: And the cap eventually corroded and this hole opened.
Speaker 1: a bunch of the ants fell into the bunker And there is this horrific minds of moria ant death colony down there.
Speaker 0: now wait, wouldn't the ants that fell down there just be Dead because it's dark and there's no food.
Speaker 1: So that's what's fascinating.
Speaker 1: basically ants that fall in can't get out.
Speaker 1: No shit, but lots of ants fall in.
Speaker 1: So the ants that fall in keep falling in because there's a giant hole.
Speaker 1: ants aren't that bright individually.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: you gotta read the article to explain to answering most of your questions.
Speaker 1: I would just read the whole article to you and it's long.
Speaker 1: But basically these ants fall down there and they can't get out.
Speaker 1: But they're still alive and there seems to be something they can eat.
Speaker 1: it's not just cannibalism.
Speaker 1: So they continue to live their lives And try to make their colony work.
Speaker 1: But instead of the colony being refreshed by new ants being born down there It's refreshed by otherwise happy ants falling into this hell pit and being trapped there.
Speaker 1: Uh, what do they call it?
Speaker 1: Uh trapped for years in a hostile environment of cold and total darkness.
Speaker 0: Then how I mean?
Speaker 0: the ants can't even make anything down there because this is just concrete.
Speaker 1: Uh, there's dirt and grime and there's bats in there too.
Speaker 1: Oh, so there's some bat guano.
Speaker 1: uh scientists pulled one cubic decimeter of material out of the bottom and found eight thousand corpses.
Speaker 1: they estimate there are Millions of dead ants in the ant cemeteries.
Speaker 1: the ants down there when the when the ant catacomb Yeah, the anticum.
Speaker 1: so when the other ants die, you know ants have cemeteries Like.
Speaker 1: they carry the ants away and they put them all in a place.
Speaker 1: There are millions of ants in the cemeteries down there.
Speaker 1: So basically when you fall into this hell pit you live your life maintaining the colony and then when you die One of the fresh ants puts you in the cemetery and then does what you used to do.
Speaker 1: And this is just terrifying and fascinating.
Speaker 1: but much more directly terrifying is apparently there are people who keep fire ants in their houses as pets.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: How do you even do that?
Speaker 0: As soon as you go near a fire ant is it gonna bite you and you're gonna be in excruciating pain for a long time?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this dude keeps these fire ants in an ant colony.
Speaker 0: How did he get them?
Speaker 0: Uh, just ordered them online or something You can buy them or did you just take them from the street?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: All I know is this guy.
Speaker 1: apparently there's a lot of people who do this.
Speaker 1: This is Ants Canada.
Speaker 1: So he has fire ants.
Speaker 1: but this video is him explaining how he figured out that the fire ants Were trying to escape because they run out of space to live And if they escaped they would have escaped into his house.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why did you put them in your house?
Speaker 0: So this video is just like every time i've gone to florida.
Speaker 0: no one goes on the grass ever because fire ants And pretty much everyone's like oh shit watch out fire ants and they're constantly exterminating the fire ants.
Speaker 1: This video is great because you like see those.
Speaker 0: why would you bring them into your house on purpose?
Speaker 1: See those three ants right there?
Speaker 1: Yeah, all the other ants are moving around doing shit.
Speaker 1: But those three ants are just sitting there at the edge of the territory.
Speaker 1: Ants and ant colonies do that when they're planning an escape when they're planning a way to go across a dangerous obstacle.
Speaker 1: So when you see that happening watch the fuck out because your fire ants are about to get loose.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah ants that's that's what I found.
Speaker 0: Here's a good idea.
Speaker 0: if you got some fire ants as pets Kill them all and don't get any more.
Speaker 1: No, he keeps expanding the colony.
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: He's got a lot of fire ants.
Speaker 0: I hope that they break out and infest his whole house and bite him.
Speaker 1: when I was a little kid I read a horror story about that.
Speaker 1: a kid had an ant colony and he tortured the ants also.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 1: and then the ants got out and they bit him to death.
Speaker 0: You know, there's a law that's like you can't have ferrets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, would you get rid of that law and make a law?
Speaker 0: You can't have fire ants.
Speaker 1: Oh if someone has fire ants in new york in their apartment and I find out Burn the building down Don't shed it too.
Speaker 1: I'm not afraid of him.
Speaker 1: I just don't want to get bit Like spiders whatever but colony of fire ants biting me.
Speaker 1: that is that is objectively unpleasant.
Speaker 0: So you gotta think at least.
Speaker 0: if like a snake poisons you like you'll die.
Speaker 0: I don't know how painful it is.
Speaker 0: But fire is biting you all over.
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway, so Tomorrow I have tickets to go see the world's Greatest lower mid-tier prog metal band.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I forgot about that.
Speaker 0: the devin towns and projects not sold out because metal doesn't sell out.
Speaker 0: um And they have been doing on the devin towns in youtube channel.
Speaker 0: Uh, you know some tour videos like.
Speaker 0: there's like there's a guy traveling with them making videos every day every single day they're making videos and these remind me of Like a lot of the video legendary like behind the scenes Band touring videos used to see back in the day like pantera videos and stuff like that Only, you know, almost perhaps more funny, but obviously less hardcore and less insane.
Speaker 0: uh So you should go The devin town sends youtube channel and watch all the videos that he's posted since the start of this tour because there's a documentary Of you know the making of the new album You know sort of mixed in with the daily videos of what's going on in the tour.
Speaker 0: and it's like all this shit happens Like you see them going to like places you might recognize Or like, you know, the bus breaks down and they're at some hotel that the outside of denny's for a whole day.
Speaker 0: Hey Like he hurt his foot and like, you know, one of the fans of wives is a podiatrist and he brought her over.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: it's just all this, you know, really awesome kind of stuff that you know, if uh, We went somewhere for longer than one weekend.
Speaker 0: We could do something a video series like this.
Speaker 0: Also, it would help if someone followed us around and did all the video work while we slept and just did our thing.
Speaker 1: See if I get enough money I'll hire cameraman.
Speaker 0: We'll hire this guy.
Speaker 0: He's do really fucking good job.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you were doing on a tour or want someone to follow you around to the camera producing videos of your shit The guy who makes these is like way good.
Speaker 0: and i'm sure as soon as this tour is over He probably I mean, I don't know him, but I guess I might see him tomorrow and say hi Yeah, I imagine he would very much like to do that more often for money.
Speaker 1: Uh, so there you go, so in the meta moment, uh, the book club book is rebecca.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna read it before I watch the movie which i've never seen or I might have seen as a kid But I can't remember and I might have conflated it with a much worse movie.
Speaker 1: So we'll see when I when I actually watch it or read it if suddenly my brain's like
Speaker 0: i've seen the movie twice and not Recently,
Speaker 1: yeah All i'm gonna say is if you ever if there was a movie that traumatized you as a kid and all you remember Is this creepy girl singing the worms crawling the worms crawl out that is a movie called Uh, imagine or picture mommy dead and it is not rebecca Uh, otherwise
Speaker 0: the movie from my childhood that I remembered scenes from but could not actually remember the name of at least attaching it Was uh time lords.
Speaker 0: Ah, I knew what time was was and I remember had memories of this movie.
Speaker 0: I just didn't realize that that movie was time right.
Speaker 1: as a kid I think I also actually conflated a lot of sean connery movies together because I saw a lot of them when I was too young to really process Because my like my dad would watch him.
Speaker 0: So like It was james bond that said I am the last one.
Speaker 1: Yep Um, we got no conventions till magfest.
Speaker 0: guys it was the dragon that said.
Speaker 0: yeah, they said when he goes to the hospital You send two of those to the moon.
Speaker 1: When you're the last one It's the chicago way.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, I should just make a.
Speaker 0: it's the dragon way I should.
Speaker 1: may I should just take Line sean connery set and string them together into one long rant and make the dragon say them.
Speaker 0: Make the dragon say all of them except for the ones the dragon says at the very end of the video.
Speaker 1: make james bond say So, uh, yeah, we got no conventions coming up.
Speaker 1: I got nothing really big to plug except the usual stuff.
Speaker 1: So now that we're back Like I said follow scott's youtube channel follow my youtube channel because we're making shit as fast as we can.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna make a whole bunch of videos about making an htbc Even though the number one thing if you search on the internet if you want content related to computer building There is a never-ending supply, but i'm gonna add to that never-ending supply because I can.
Speaker 0: that's fine.
Speaker 0: Actually, I gotta start doing my also because all the people giving you creating all those that content about computer building Are crazy overclock nerds and i'm gonna tell you how stupid they are.
Speaker 1: I can't believe we never did a show on this.
Speaker 0: Maybe we did.
Speaker 0: we've talked about it very often.
Speaker 1: I searched about it in the last episode we did So i'm not gonna elaborate too much.
Speaker 1: I guess I will a little bit on the saddle thing.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about why that pizza was bad.
Speaker 0: I think this is a thing we've talked about but I searched and there was no episode named pizza.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the word pizza did not appear.
Speaker 0: People love food episodes and pizza is such a big deal that we can talk about it beyond just food.
Speaker 1: Like it's such a pop culture Phenomenon mama me a pizza pie, right, but I want to make it very clear.
Speaker 1: Unlike scott.
Speaker 1: I do not have this ridiculous obsession with new york pizza being special because I didn't grow up in new york.
Speaker 0: It's not special.
Speaker 0: It's just that it's different.
Speaker 1: It's a style of pizza, but I don't even care about the style.
Speaker 1: It's not even my favorite style of pizza.
Speaker 0: It's my favorite style of pizza.
Speaker 0: All i'm saying is also the most delicious style of pizza and um most other style.
Speaker 1: the thing is my favorite style of pizza is actually the thin crust from A fancy italian restaurant.
Speaker 0: That's a fine style of pizza.
Speaker 0: Yeah, i'm not saying that it's the only good stuff I'm saying that's my favorite.
Speaker 0: I'm saying that most other styles of pizza of all the styles Uh are garbage shot.
Speaker 1: It's the chicago way.
Speaker 0: No, the chicago way is a bad way.
Speaker 1: I like chicago pizza a lot.
Speaker 0: No, it's also not pizza, but that's that's a semantic argument.
Speaker 1: It's pizza.
Speaker 1: if I go to wikipedia I'm, pretty sure i'm gonna be able to say that that's pizza.
Speaker 0: It's deep dish pizza.
Speaker 0: It has an adjective attached.
Speaker 1: All i'm saying the only preference I got to make is that I don't think new york pizza Is that high on a pedestal, but I do think having eaten pizza all over the goddamn world uh The the average shitty pizza in new york Is better than the average delivery pizza in the entire rest of the united states.
Speaker 1: Like a shit slice of pizza from a shit bodega here Tastes better independent of style than pretty much anything you can get delivered in most places.
Speaker 0: It's because of the style.
Speaker 0: you could make pizza like that in a shit.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's the style.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's the water.
Speaker 1: I think it's the cheap ass mozzarella.
Speaker 0: You don't think they have cheap ass mozzarella in other places.
Speaker 0: I think they use an expensive mozzarella.
Speaker 1: I think they're either using more expensive mozzarella or they're cutting it with ricotta or something?
Speaker 0: No, I don't think that's what it is at all because in my experience if you go to other places and get the delivery pizza This big puffy thing.
Speaker 0: It's not you know, it's a different style of pizza.
Speaker 0: The dough you can see right away is different.
Speaker 0: the amount of sauce the variety of sauce.
Speaker 1: So take the pizza.
Speaker 0: the whole thing is different.
Speaker 1: take the pizza We had.
Speaker 0: the cheese is like not a thing.
Speaker 0: that's like resting on top.
Speaker 0: It's like sort of like integrated into the bread almost like it's a garlic bread the pizza we got in seattle.
Speaker 1: My problem with it was not its style.
Speaker 1: The problem was that the mozzarella it wasn't new york style.
Speaker 1: No, it wasn't new york style.
Speaker 1: Okay, but had it been made in its style Well, it would have been a fine pizza.
Speaker 1: the problem was the mozzarella was overcooked to a significant degree.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 1: If your pizza is mostly brown on top you fucked up.
Speaker 1: That is true and that's across the board.
Speaker 0: burnt cheese suddenly gets a bad flavor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that mozzarella was that like ultra greasy runny ass shit, but not you know, new york style pizza is greasy.
Speaker 0: I actually thought that it was actually like so dry that that mozzarella because it was so burnt and All the grease all the grease had run off the pizza was not dry but the mozzarella they used to make the pizza I expect was greasy and also shitty way.
Speaker 1: but that grease was gone in the actual pizza because they did congealed by the time it got.
Speaker 0: the other problem is that the Like the crust underneath the cheese and almost non-existent sauce was all this puffy kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Well, because it was full of the congealed grease, uh, and it was very chewy and it was not you know A nice crispy crust.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and while I do also enjoy a chewy pizza This was not the good chewy.
Speaker 1: This was the congealed grease chewy.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but so remember, uh, I was infamous at rit because I worked at the bar downstairs for a while.
Speaker 1: I was in charge of the pizza station and uh, I made pretty much the worst pizza you can imagine And I want.
Speaker 1: I remember I tried to make it better and the only way to make it better Was to steal The more expensive mozzarella and use that.
Speaker 0: where'd you steal it?
Speaker 0: Where was it to be stolen from?
Speaker 1: I just went to the other restaurant on campus and because we could like in emergencies like oh we need supplies.
Speaker 0: Like the different restaurants had different qualities of cheese.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: So if I got better mozzarella, the pizzas were okay, even if I fucked up but the default cheapest mozzarella.
Speaker 1: Well when the pizza cooked it'd get like super nasty greasy And then that grease would immediately like run out or congeal and the pizza was the worst Right.
Speaker 0: the thing about you know, when you make a pizza, right?
Speaker 0: You're taking a big piece of bread or dough, right?
Speaker 0: Not bread It's dough.
Speaker 0: it becomes bread.
Speaker 0: Uh, it's really flat bread.
Speaker 0: You roll it out get it flat You put the sauce on there.
Speaker 0: You don't want to put too much sauce because then suddenly if you put too much sauce the cheese will slide right the fuck off.
Speaker 1: Yep, unless you're making a different style of pizza, but you want to put sauce in there because that is you know I like a soupy sauce.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, it's not pizza.
Speaker 0: It's cheesy bread.
Speaker 1: Like my main complaint about new york pizza if I have one is that often it doesn't have enough sauce, right?
Speaker 0: Well, you know, you gotta have enough sauce that you can taste the sauce.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't actually want the sauce to create like a layer.
Speaker 0: You need that cheese to like stick on there, right?
Speaker 0: Uh, and then you put on the cheese and the cheese melts the sauce heats up and the dough bakes all at the same time In the oven all together and creates a perfect thing.
Speaker 0: now As that cheese heats up Grease comes out.
Speaker 0: That's how cheese works.
Speaker 0: It's a dairy thing, right?
Speaker 0: I don't think there's very few cheeses.
Speaker 0: I can imagine making them hot where no grease would emerge from them.
Speaker 1: And the thing is probably some horrible cheeses where that happens.
Speaker 0: super hard dry cheese But not a not a cheese you're gonna put on a pizza.
Speaker 0: And the thing is you want that grease to come out because that grease is delicious, right?
Speaker 0: And creates the nice texture on the pizza, right?
Speaker 0: You know makes nice and shiny, right?
Speaker 0: It gives us something for maybe some oregano or some pepper flakes to like dissolve into right if you shake it on there, right?
Speaker 0: But if too much grease comes out you might get into trouble with the cheese sliding right off when you pick up the slice Which is solved by waiting for it to cool But then it congeals.
Speaker 0: Yes You could also get into a situation where you pick up the slice and the cheese is still on there But it's still too greasy and the grease drips all over the fuck.
Speaker 0: And when you fold and make that little crack in the crust you get a grease drip coming out the back of the slice All over you.
Speaker 0: so that's also too much grease.
Speaker 1: take the new york slice and take it to its extreme like make it bad.
Speaker 1: And you know when I grew up as a kid like I was in michigan Unless you went to a sit-down place the only pizza style you could you could get uh dominoes You could get not pizza pizza hut not pizza.
Speaker 1: It's it's pizza.
Speaker 1: It's just bad pizza.
Speaker 1: Pizza hut was pretty much the best delivery you could get later.
Speaker 1: You get papa john's And you could get little caesars, oh god, I actually like a little.
Speaker 0: when's the last time you had a little caesar?
Speaker 1: uh When I was in arizona Two times ago.
Speaker 1: Wow, because they opened little caesars opened up some chains in arizona because there's so many midwest transplants.
Speaker 1: imagine a new york pizza, but 50 times greasier.
Speaker 1: That is little caesars pizza.
Speaker 0: So the thing is even though I grew up mostly in connecticut obviously visiting new york and having a pizza from new york many times New york pizza was available in connecticut, right?
Speaker 0: It's not like it's.
Speaker 0: you can only get it in new york You can get it in many many places.
Speaker 0: like i've ever had good pizza in florida in a place where new yorkers lived Or even like all the places i've lived or gone.
Speaker 1: like you can often get a pretty good pizza Even if it's not even a new york style.
Speaker 1: like you can get at least a good pizza.
Speaker 0: But anyway, uh, so I just want to you know not talk about the food pizza right but people I don't think realize Pizza as we know it in america is somewhat new.
Speaker 0: If you watch like old tv old movies read old books pizza wasn't a thing in like The 60s.
Speaker 0: like you you don't see like things from the 60s people ordering pizzas getting them delivered eating them, you know, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, you're doing a lot of uh in some pop culture.
Speaker 0: It's not like it didn't exist at all.
Speaker 1: I think you know what it is.
Speaker 1: delivery pizza Is pizza.
Speaker 1: as far as most americans are concerned.
Speaker 1: delivery pizza is pizza, right?
Speaker 0: It's not like pizza didn't exist.
Speaker 0: It just wasn't enormous, right?
Speaker 0: It wasn't super huge and popular everywhere, right?
Speaker 1: Actually in canada pizza was really popular in the 50s and 60s.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it was but in the united states It wasn't this tremendous deal until you know, at least as far as I remember like 70s and then really 80s 90s and we were young.
Speaker 0: that's when you had like, you know, suddenly pizza was everywhere, right?
Speaker 0: It was this big, you know, ninja turtles were eating pizza.
Speaker 0: Right, like pizza was a big deal as well.
Speaker 1: It was when pizza became like a popular reference in pop culture, right?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like suddenly pizza was everywhere.
Speaker 0: There were you know, Restaurants like pizza hut dominoes got way bigger.
Speaker 0: Only pizzeria.
Speaker 1: Uno is a big part of america's pizza history.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no pizzeria.
Speaker 0: Uno.
Speaker 0: I remember the first one like 1943.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it was the first one ever obviously it wasn't.
Speaker 1: but yeah 1943.
Speaker 1: You did not go to the first one ever.
Speaker 0: No But one opened in connecticut and it was like this.
Speaker 0: it seemed to us like this brand new thing We had never heard of before.
Speaker 0: and actually, you know what?
Speaker 0: I hate pizzeria.
Speaker 0: Uno every time i've eaten at one.
Speaker 0: It's like this style of pizza that's different from every other place.
Speaker 0: Well, and I don't like that.
Speaker 1: I don't like that style.
Speaker 1: Now pizzeria.
Speaker 1: Uno is tgi friday's effectively quality wise but I do really like deep days in chicago style pizza a lot.
Speaker 1: It's one of my favorite kinds of pizza.
Speaker 0: It's like top five.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying it's a disgusting food.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying it's not pizza It's pizza.
Speaker 0: Also.
Speaker 0: I don't really want it.
Speaker 1: In fact, uh, wikipedia specifically calls it pizza.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Whatever Uh, there are actually there are academic citations on this.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh Whatever.
Speaker 0: So you disagree?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you do.
Speaker 1: What's it?
Speaker 1: I could make a reference to you disagreeing but you haven't watched frickin morty.
Speaker 0: All right So we don't need to tell How much.
Speaker 0: how often are we going to go back to the topic of whether or not this thing that is so unlike?
Speaker 0: Uh pizza How far away can you get from pizza while still being pizza, right?
Speaker 0: Is it calzona pizza?
Speaker 0: It's just a piece of folded over.
Speaker 0: It's got sauce and cheese on the inside.
Speaker 1: No, it's not just this fold over It's also cooked folded Yeah, so so that's like still bread sauce and cheese.
Speaker 1: So is a hoagie different from a sandwich different from a sub different from a grinder is a pizza bagel not a pizza.
Speaker 0: What if?
Speaker 0: what if I put sauce and cheese on an english muffin and put it in my toaster?
Speaker 0: Is that a pizza?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Let's see what the definition word pizza blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: What if I take a a cheese stick a mozzarella cheese stick dip it in sauce and then put it on a bread?
Speaker 0: Roll the bread up like a hot.
Speaker 1: I put it on a hot.
Speaker 1: I see you're going with this.
Speaker 0: All i'm saying is when I put a mozzarella stick on a hot dog button pour sauce onto it and then eat it Is that a pizza?
Speaker 1: your position that chicago style is not pizza is outside of weird new york and connecticut bullshit circles Not recognized by anyone.
Speaker 0: i'm saying there's a point at which you diverge so much from the formula of a very flat piece of bread.
Speaker 1: I would agree with that.
Speaker 0: and you know what the and you are no longer the same thing Even though whatever word you want to use right you want to use the word pizza for all these things fine.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: It's semantics.
Speaker 0: I'm saying It is different enough that it is in a different category.
Speaker 1: Chicago style pizza is so similar to all other forms of pizza.
Speaker 1: They could make babies with it.
Speaker 1: It's the same species.
Speaker 0: No, I don't think you could.
Speaker 1: All right, what?
Speaker 1: what makes a chicago style pizza fundamentally different?
Speaker 0: It's so deep right?
Speaker 1: It's almost Sicilian Sicilians.
Speaker 0: deep Sicilian is just square.
Speaker 1: Uh, it's also thick real deep like an inch thick.
Speaker 0: not in new york.
Speaker 0: I just had a new york Yesterday.
Speaker 0: it was not deep.
Speaker 1: I had Sicilian from little italy's downtown.
Speaker 1: You know what it's an inch thick.
Speaker 0: Uh, the one I had wasn't an inch thick.
Speaker 1: Well, you went to a shitty place That actually knows a really good place.
Speaker 0: Most Sicilian pizza in new york is real thick.
Speaker 1: Its squareness is not its identifying characteristic.
Speaker 0: Anyway, let's talk about some other.
Speaker 1: anyway Let's ignore the fact that i'm wrong and just continue.
Speaker 1: All right more important uh Why do people eat such shitty pizza?
Speaker 0: Because they don't have good pizza.
Speaker 1: and then it has to be it because I tweeted like, you know We were in seattle like this pizza's garbage down here and a lot of people were trying to tell me that it was not garbage.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing, right?
Speaker 0: So first of all There are situations in life where if you live in a certain area Or you grew up in a certain way you got used to something, right?
Speaker 0: So for example someone who grew up say getting used to I don't know chef boyardee, right?
Speaker 0: Uh, which is a pizza related food that has sauce and pasta which is bread like And then suddenly are encountered with like real italian food or the real italian restaurant may not like it Even though it is objectively superior because they are used to crap and they have grown To enjoy that crap because it has this familiarity and this psychological thing in their brain, right?
Speaker 0: So if you grew up with eating dominoes you have this thing for dominoes even though it's crap And you like it.
Speaker 0: and if you encounter good pizza You may not like it even though it is better because you're used to and have this, you know Nostalgia affection for this bad thing and that's why you like it.
Speaker 0: I think I see this the most actually not with pizza But with taco bell.
Speaker 0: there are people who just fucking love taco bell and they know it's crap, but they always want to go there Even though they know it's not like even really mexican food.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but i'll put it this way if if I was really hungry and I was in a bad place And the restaurants lined up in front of me were mcdonald's burger king arby's and taco bell.
Speaker 1: I go to taco bell in a heartbeat.
Speaker 0: What were the choices?
Speaker 1: mcdonald's burger king arby's taco bell arby's.
Speaker 1: what are you gonna get at?
Speaker 1: arby's?
Speaker 1: chicken fingers chicken fingers and curly fries?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would not touch anything else in that restaurant.
Speaker 1: When was the last time you ate those curly fries?
Speaker 0: They're really good.
Speaker 1: When was the last time you ate them?
Speaker 0: Probably in college.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because you know what your mouth is gonna say These are all right, and then the rest of your body is gonna say oh hell no Uh, that's all right.
Speaker 0: That's better than anything.
Speaker 0: The taco bell is gonna do to me plus I.
Speaker 1: I think it's partly that they're A lot of times.
Speaker 1: if you don't it's not that people like a lot of people I talk to it's not like they will say Uh that new york pizza is disgusting.
Speaker 1: They actually much prefer the new york pizza But their line of what is acceptable is much lower because they can't get good pizza nearby.
Speaker 0: You got to lower your bar based on what you can get right?
Speaker 0: You don't want to just like.
Speaker 0: imagine you just you know, if we were stuck in some place Where literally the only pizza was mediocre pizza.
Speaker 1: I just won't eat pizza.
Speaker 0: And then but you go so long and eventually when you get a cave I would just i'd give up on pizza when you're gonna cave.
Speaker 1: if I lived in downtown Seattle and that delivery pizza was all I could get I would never eat pizza again.
Speaker 0: But what if you didn't know better?
Speaker 1: Well, that's the decision once you.
Speaker 1: once you find out you can't go back.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 1: I mean remember that time we accidentally ordered the godfather's pizza in albany.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So I got.
Speaker 0: I got some pizza related anecdotes here.
Speaker 0: I got pizza related.
Speaker 0: Anecdote number one red baron red baron.
Speaker 1: Yep, red baron.
Speaker 1: I was reminded of that recently because our friend jared sorensen tweeted at length about he cooked.
Speaker 1: he cooked a cheese brat in the microwave and forgot what microwaves do with cheese.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: And I think he's dead now.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so in college we would get we would need food.
Speaker 0: It'd be late at night.
Speaker 0: The only food we could get was frozen food and they had these frozen pizzas called red from red baron.
Speaker 1: They weren't even frozen They were refrigerated.
Speaker 1: They were in a bag.
Speaker 0: They came in this little piece of cardboard that was like had shiny foil on it.
Speaker 1: They were like a dollar forty nine, but it wasn't tin foil.
Speaker 0: so you could microwave it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they were like a dollar forty nine.
Speaker 1: We basically run to the corner the corner store.
Speaker 0: Yeah at like 11 at night.
Speaker 0: It was the only food we could get.
Speaker 0: we were hungry college kids.
Speaker 0: You put it in the microwave.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: This is an old microwave.
Speaker 0: We would just make everything crazy hot.
Speaker 0: Uh, so but we were so hungry.
Speaker 0: We would eat it before it was cool like hipsters I would burn.
Speaker 0: we would burn the roof of our mouth on this not good pizza.
Speaker 1: that pizza was awful But I was so hungry.
Speaker 0: It would fill our college stomachs at 11 at night.
Speaker 0: the red baron.
Speaker 1: so I still have fond memories there.
Speaker 1: In fact, I imagine eating one right now and imagining it still being really satisfying.
Speaker 0: Well, I think part of it was you burned your mouth so you couldn't taste it.
Speaker 1: Yeah So my my anecdote will just trade anecdotes, uh, you know The apocryphal tale of people getting kicked out of all-you-can-eat restaurants.
Speaker 1: I did get kicked out of an all-you-can-eat pizza hut.
Speaker 0: It was an all-you-can-eat pizza.
Speaker 1: So pizza hut used to do a thing when I was in high school of all-you-can-eat at lunch.
Speaker 1: So I was on a band trip and we stopped at a rest stop the area.
Speaker 0: They figured that no one who could eat that much would come there for lunch.
Speaker 1: We had an hour and a half to eat lunch and do whatever we wanted But we had to be back on the bus.
Speaker 1: Everyone stupid went over to mcdonald's and taco bell Me and a couple other of my friends.
Speaker 1: We were like guys.
Speaker 1: There's a pizza hut across the freeway.
Speaker 0: That reminds me when I was in israel And we got off a bus to eat lunch and me and this other guy whose first name was actually ruben.
Speaker 0: We went to like this crazy awesome Thai place and got these ridiculous sandwiches that were like crazy long and a delicious meats on them And everyone else went to mcdonald's.
Speaker 1: So me and the four of us were like let's go across the freeway.
Speaker 1: like it was kind of dodgy to get over there But we did it to the pizza hut did the lunch buffet.
Speaker 0: That's why no one went over there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because They fucked up.
Speaker 0: They didn't want to get killed by a car.
Speaker 0: It wasn't worth it.
Speaker 1: We all got the all-you-can-eat.
Speaker 1: We went up to the pizza bar and there were only three pizzas up there.
Speaker 1: We took every slice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we ate them all.
Speaker 1: We went back up took all the breadsticks and ate them all and then we waited Like 20 minutes later.
Speaker 1: They brought out a bunch more pizzas.
Speaker 1: We went out the mall took them all ate everything And then we just stood by.
Speaker 1: we went back up and we stood by the buffet table like waiting for our pizza to come out And then other customers kind of walked up too because apparently we'd taken all the pizzas so they didn't get any.
Speaker 0: They didn't make enough pizzas.
Speaker 1: So we're standing there and then we got more pizza.
Speaker 1: We start to take it and then literally the manager comes out and he's like you guys have had enough you've got to leave.
Speaker 0: It's like it's all you can eat.
Speaker 0: screw you give us.
Speaker 1: so we made a big stink And we kind of argued with the guy for a while and we ended up paying but we gave a zero tip.
Speaker 0: Yeah And why don't you do tip if you got up and got your own?
Speaker 1: Yeah one I got my own pizza.
Speaker 1: two It wasn't enough pizza.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: No tip for you, and it was very telling that that promotion ended Just generally.
Speaker 0: all you can eat generally and did is I haven't seen it.
Speaker 0: in a lot of places golden corral still exists.
Speaker 0: Uh golden corral is not the worst It's not the worst.
Speaker 1: well when was the last?
Speaker 0: it's second the worst maybe.
Speaker 1: Have you ever seen the inside of golden corral?
Speaker 0: I've seen the outside.
Speaker 1: have you seen the inside of one?
Speaker 1: No Uh farx had stories relatively recently about what goes on inside golden corral.
Speaker 1: Do not go into those places.
Speaker 1: I would rather eat at an old country buffet than a golden girl.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Yeah No, it is.
Speaker 1: the food is equal quality.
Speaker 1: the clientele.
Speaker 1: Golden corral is a feeding trough of sin and misery.
Speaker 0: Oh that kind of sounds more interesting than a country Maybe is a spectator.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I feel like it would.
Speaker 1: it's scarring.
Speaker 1: Uh, I would rather eat at a chucky cheeses than eat at a golden corral.
Speaker 0: So one time me you and james went to An ice hockey game a college ice hockey game.
Speaker 0: It was in oswego.
Speaker 1: Oh the oswego one, right?
Speaker 0: I was in the middle of fuck nowhere in new york.
Speaker 0: uh we drove there and then we finished the hockey game and we wanted food and there was nothing to eat in the middle of nowhere and We had like a more than an hour drive home.
Speaker 0: There was nothing.
Speaker 0: there was nothing that was open for eating except for this pizza hut.
Speaker 0: We went into the pizza hut.
Speaker 0: we ordered one pizza for three people.
Speaker 1: We were the only people in there.
Speaker 0: There's someone else in there the one waiter.
Speaker 0: Anyway, he brought us a pizza And he you know, we're just getting ready to eat it.
Speaker 0: I didn't even notice but before we start eating he says hey It doesn't look like there's a lot of cheese on that pizza.
Speaker 0: So we look at it and sure enough this is basically bread with sauce on it.
Speaker 0: And he's like, I think he like, you know Realized you were the kind of people who weren't going to fight with him and were so hungry and it was crazy late at night.
Speaker 0: He'd get rid of this obviously, uh malfunctioned pizza.
Speaker 0: Yep Uh, even like compared to other pizza pizzas, right?
Speaker 0: This one was messed up.
Speaker 0: They had no cheese.
Speaker 0: Yep He's like, how about you don't pay for this pizza?
Speaker 0: And we're like, we're okay with that.
Speaker 0: And he's like, but instead of me giving you another pizza, that is good You just shake parmesan on there and eat that.
Speaker 0: and i'm like, I don't give a fuck.
Speaker 0: But I was like, it's too late for this shit.
Speaker 1: I was like, I only have like 28 total in assets right now.
Speaker 0: Oh, right the repo the repo man was coming for you.
Speaker 1: that was at like the deepest poverty of my college days.
Speaker 0: So yeah, by the way a pizza with parmesan is not a good pizza.
Speaker 1: I was so hungry.
Speaker 0: Hunger is the best spice.
Speaker 1: Not only did I not care and I remember that pizza tasting really good But I was still super fucking hungry after we ate it.
Speaker 1: Yeah And when we got home, I remember I remember specifically like we finally got home and I went and I opened the fridge and there was Nothing to eat like not eat like nothing unless I wanted to cook and we only had like two eggs.
Speaker 1: And I remember I cooked both those eggs, then I went to bed and I was miserable.
Speaker 1: Good hockey game though.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: I don't remember if we won or lost.
Speaker 1: I think we lost.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, oh Anecdote.
Speaker 1: do I have a good anecdote?
Speaker 1: so one time I was doing science olympiad with the people who were in charge of that in my middle school and they were like Let's get a. and they named like this weird pizza place like a weird style of pizza I'd never heard of and my dad knew what it was.
Speaker 1: He was like, yeah And everyone was into it except me and a few and a few of the other kids No idea what the fuck they were talking about.
Speaker 1: And then they started grilling us like oh you never had one of these.
Speaker 1: Uh, like making a big deal about it.
Speaker 1: What eventually got delivered?
Speaker 1: Was more than two inches thick.
Speaker 0: Well more than two inches.
Speaker 1: it was shaped like a pizza, but the crust went all the way around.
Speaker 1: it was basically like a dough Crust container in the shape of the dough was on top and bottom and sides.
Speaker 0: I've seen i've seen tv commercials with pictures of those it was filled to the brim.
Speaker 0: It's basically a sauce cheese pie Yes, but sometimes there's other stuff in there.
Speaker 1: a pizza pie one might say.
Speaker 0: well, usually a pizza pie That does not have a crust over the top like an apple pie does.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow Usually making distinctions.
Speaker 1: now there too Why do we call it a pizza pie?
Speaker 1: It's not a pie So, but we call it a pie.
Speaker 0: the thing that you had though with the crust over the top that was a pie.
Speaker 0: That was a pie.
Speaker 1: it was full of like chopped ham and artichokes and all this nonsense.
Speaker 1: And it was crazy good and I ate a whole bunch of it and then I got kind of sick.
Speaker 1: and that's the end of that Story.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those aren't bad.
Speaker 0: They're just uh, not pizza.
Speaker 1: So that one I might I might accept saying that that is not pizza, but you know what I would call it.
Speaker 1: I would call it a casserole maybe.
Speaker 0: so regardless of any pizza not pizza semantics What is the best varieties?
Speaker 1: Of pizza, I really mostly in terms of toppings and such, you know Ask me at different stages of my life My answer is very different.
Speaker 1: when I was in like middle school high school As much meat and garbage as you can like.
Speaker 1: just cover the pizza in garbage.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna eat it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And in rit, it was whatever pizza we can get because everyone was stupid one.
Speaker 1: I was hungry and two Between everyone we knew no one would fucking eat anything on their pizza.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the greatest thing about pizza actually is that it's so unifying.
Speaker 0: even if someone unless someone's a vegan and doesn't want cheese Yep, everyone can eat pizza.
Speaker 0: It's a vegetarian thing.
Speaker 0: Yep It's almost.
Speaker 0: there's almost nobody who doesn't like even like even someone who prefers.
Speaker 0: most people prefer not just cheese pizza but Almost everyone like.
Speaker 0: i've never seen someone who like just doesn't like any pizza.
Speaker 0: At least someone will at least if they're like a super pickiest eater They will still like cheese pizza as one of the things they like to eat.
Speaker 1: Well, cheese pizza is one of the things next to uh chicken wings or chicken nuggets that those kinds of people will eat.
Speaker 0: it's like you're only sort of pushing out the lactose intolerant and the vegans and Dude, a lot of lactose intolerant people I know will fucking eat pizza anyway.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, and the people who can't eat bread, but pretty much everyone else.
Speaker 0: It's like it's.
Speaker 0: there's no food that more people can eat Right together that you can order and get for a party or anything than pizza.
Speaker 0: It is so unified.
Speaker 1: in my in like the broad adulthood of my life my actual favorite kind of pizza was hawaiian pizza.
Speaker 1: Yeah No Because I like the sweet and savory mix together like the pineapple sharpness and sweetness with the ham like.
Speaker 1: I just love hawaiian pizza.
Speaker 1: the problem is Now that i'm older and I eat basically much more expensive food all the time I find that unless you get hawaiian pizza from a really fancy place They make it like garbage and really fancy places usually aren't going to have hawaiian pizza.
Speaker 0: That's the thing.
Speaker 1: cheap places like all the super fancy delivery places around here They all have hawaiian.
Speaker 0: those aren't super fancy.
Speaker 1: if they're delivering, uh here even the fancy places deliver.
Speaker 1: Anyway, like even the italian restaurants will deliver their fancy restaurant pizza here.
Speaker 0: Whoa, like like I guess I guess vesta will deliver me a pizza if I ask them to yeah Like masa all the places down by vernon jackson.
Speaker 1: They'll deliver the pizza.
Speaker 0: This is not that fancy.
Speaker 1: Anyway, their pizza is the fancy style.
Speaker 1: It's not the delivery style.
Speaker 0: See I like a wide variety of pizzas.
Speaker 0: There's almost no topping that I do not want on a pizza lately.
Speaker 0: I will even eat in it the empty, uh, You know the much maligned anchovy pizza.
Speaker 1: Oh, dude anchovy pizza is the best, right?
Speaker 0: It's not the best but like if it's there I will eat it.
Speaker 0: I'm not like ew anchovies like tv is right.
Speaker 1: Yep anchovies are delicious.
Speaker 1: get them in your caesar salad, too, but My favorite pizza is actually.
Speaker 0: I like the simpler pizzas right like a pepperoni mushroom Right, but I prefer pepperoni onion.
Speaker 0: But yes pepperoni onions also great, you know.
Speaker 0: But the thing is I you know, it's that's that is only the greatest when it's made the greatest, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you can make a crappy.
Speaker 0: just you can go somewhere that's crappy and get a pepperoni mushroom and it sucks.
Speaker 0: But when it's really good, it's really good.
Speaker 1: That's my favorite pizzas lately are things like margarita pizzas grandma pizza.
Speaker 0: It's so top tier.
Speaker 0: the grandma pizza and I tend to as much as like the grandma pizza is like so deceptive Like it looks like a regular pizza like.
Speaker 0: how is that is?
Speaker 0: what's the difference?
Speaker 1: then you get that little garlic the marinade Some basil going on, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like it tastes more like a pizza that italian grandma made than just sauce and cheese on a bread.
Speaker 0: It's it's got.
Speaker 1: there's a place near my office that makes a really good grandma pizza.
Speaker 1: I get it like twice a week.
Speaker 0: No, I don't get pizza that often but I eat a lot of food.
Speaker 1: What do you want?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the pizza.
Speaker 0: there's so many pizza places near us, uh, living, you know in such a touristy zone.
Speaker 0: But there's one place it's just called gotham pizza and it looks like a regular old pizza place and the pizza isn't the best pizza But it's like so solid new york pizza right with the.
Speaker 0: you know It's just made.
Speaker 0: everything is made properly.
Speaker 0: All the different varieties are good.
Speaker 0: Their oven is hot.
Speaker 1: the place I go downtown is one of the like 30 places named little italy pizza.
Speaker 0: I think we also got to talk about.
Speaker 0: you know There's certain varieties of pizza that are like kind of rare.
Speaker 0: you can only get them in certain places For example the two boots.
Speaker 0: There's only a few.
Speaker 0: there's only a few two boots.
Speaker 0: They're not like everywhere in the world.
Speaker 1: I've only ever seen them in new york two boots than I used to be Because it used to be that they were the cool weird pizzas.
Speaker 1: But the last time I had two boots was about two years ago.
Speaker 1: It was just kind of shitty.
Speaker 0: I haven't had it in Maybe over a year, but I used to have it pretty frequently when I was working like a few blocks away from a two boots And it was the best pizza in the area.
Speaker 0: and the thing I like about two boots is that it's you know It's got the same crust as regular new york pizza and the same cheese, but the weird stuff, right?
Speaker 0: They got really good topping combinations.
Speaker 0: But usually if you get a topping combination in normal pizza place, you'll get like big old chunks of broccoli and stuff on there.
Speaker 0: It's like that tastes good but it's like they don't put the toppings on right and you'll end up getting like.
Speaker 0: You know, you won't be eating those toppings together in sort of a good food way.
Speaker 0: It'll just be like this bite had broccoli in it.
Speaker 0: This bite had a pepperoni in it Whereas two boots, you know the way they prepare the toppings and put them on there so evenly and so well mixed And like under the cheese or in the cheese as necessary.
Speaker 0: Well, that is how I decide it comes into like, you know a well constructed You know thing that you can fold and shove in your mouth.
Speaker 1: that's how I decide in a vacuum where to order pizza from.
Speaker 1: because if a place just says Get a pizza and pick your toppings.
Speaker 1: That place is almost always garbage.
Speaker 1: If the place has here are the 10 kinds of pizza we make it's probably a much better place.
Speaker 0: Someone went.
Speaker 0: put some thought into that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and what i'll do now is i'll order only from those kinds of places.
Speaker 1: So i'll get like the grandma pizza or something.
Speaker 1: But then i'll always do an augment like i'll add one topping.
Speaker 1: and lately the things I want to add are either onions cremini mushrooms or capers Capers.
Speaker 1: capers are real effing good on a pizza.
Speaker 0: capers are pretty powerful flavor, though I feel like they overpower.
Speaker 1: you gotta use it on the very specific kind of pizza.
Speaker 1: Like you.
Speaker 1: don't mix capers with something else.
Speaker 0: that's also strong and almost anything with capers is overpowered by caper power.
Speaker 1: So a grandma pizza with capers as long as the capers are subtle as long as they're sparse Yeah, they gotta be sparse like two per slice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah Just like this layer of capers.
Speaker 0: Where could you even get that many capers?
Speaker 0: It could have been afforded.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just take them take the little.
Speaker 0: they're not that cheap.
Speaker 1: Take that little bottle just dump it all out on the pizza.
Speaker 1: Yeah What the fuck is this new haven style pizza is a thing that has its own wikipedia page.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so apparently people it's called a pizza.
Speaker 1: white clam is the kind of pizza they make here.
Speaker 0: Yes, there's a place in new haven that's like, you know near yale that pepe invented it.
Speaker 0: That's like their famous pizza place.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: it's like such a big deal.
Speaker 1: It's like the biggest white pizza with olive oil oregano cheese chopped garlic and clams other than And they can they cook it way too hot.
Speaker 0: Yes Other than you know yale itself.
Speaker 0: this pizza place in new haven is like the biggest deal in the town.
Speaker 0: It's like the only thing they've got.
Speaker 0: and if you go there and ask people what to eat That's like the only thing that people bring up is this one pizza place.
Speaker 0: I've never actually been to it because even though i've been to and through new haven very often I've never like downtown.
Speaker 0: new haven is not near like the highways or anything.
Speaker 0: I don't go there that frequently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it looks okay.
Speaker 0: You know, I just never went to that place because I just never did so.
Speaker 1: So I used to like much meatier pizzas, but just i've actually tried to cut a lot of meat out of my diet.
Speaker 1: Just you know, I eat too much meat.
Speaker 1: At least I used to eat too much meat.
Speaker 1: So If I get meat on a pizza now, I used to always go for like sausage But pretty much I actually prefer pepperoni.
Speaker 1: pepperoni is delicious Like that's my favorite meat on a pizza now.
Speaker 0: pepperoni is a really delicious meat And it's really only appropriate in like a few scenarios, right?
Speaker 0: You don't usually get like sandwiches with pepperoni too.
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, but it's like a pizza is where it belongs and that is you know If you want to enjoy its flavor, that is the best place.
Speaker 1: because yep The worst though is when you get a pizza that has pepperoni, but they cook the pizza wrong.
Speaker 1: So the pepperoni is on top of the pizza Curled up into little bowls of pepperoni filled with its own grease and burned on the edges.
Speaker 0: mistakes are made.
Speaker 1: That is like.
Speaker 0: that's also a sign of low quality pepperonis.
Speaker 0: Yep, and that is also how it's sliced too thick.
Speaker 1: That's how the pepperoni has looked on every pepperoni pizza I have ever gotten anywhere in the city of seattle except in a sit-down restaurant since 2008.
Speaker 1: So i'm sorry, stop telling it's usually.
Speaker 0: it's usually a consequence of too thick cutting the pepperonis.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you want thin ones Yeah, but they're tiny they're shitty and also they put them in the wrong places or they don't pre-cook.
Speaker 0: Yeah, some people put too much and some people don't put enough.
Speaker 1: Yep Just I don't that cup of grease.
Speaker 1: It's just like like why do you think that's okay?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Now the final thing we must discuss but I hope everyone knows already is the proper way to eat a pizza, right?
Speaker 0: If it's not a square pizza, which it rarely is it's a triangle pizza.
Speaker 0: Well, it's a circle that's cut into triangles.
Speaker 0: You fold that shit from the back and you put the pointy end in your mouth.
Speaker 0: All right If you do if you get a fork and knife you can shove it the fork in your left eye And you can shove the knife in your right eye.
Speaker 1: so you don't deserve the pizza.
Speaker 0: use a fork and knife Then you can shove them in your eye.
Speaker 1: So I do it.
Speaker 1: if i'm hungry And the pizza is way too hot like the point that it burns my hands when I touch it then just wait.
Speaker 1: No, i'm too hungry.
Speaker 1: So I cut the tip then you burn your mouth.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you should cut the tip off.
Speaker 1: That's what you should do and then it'll cool really cool.
Speaker 1: You got yours cut off, right?
Speaker 0: And you're saying that's what you deserve.
Speaker 0: after you uh, ate the pizza with a fork and knife.
Speaker 1: Uh, if it's chicago style you're gonna cut it up with a fork and knife.
Speaker 0: that's not pizza though.
Speaker 1: So that's fine and it's good.
Speaker 0: That is the right way to eat that food.
Speaker 1: but also Sometimes even in new york even a new york style pizza You can't fuck crack the bottom and hold it up because the front end will go blorp Like that.
Speaker 1: that happens a lot even in good places that it.
Speaker 0: no that does not happen if the pizza is made.
Speaker 1: Well, no that happens even in good places.
Speaker 0: Also, it is dependent on your skills of folding.
Speaker 0: maybe since you grew up in michigan You don't have the skills.
Speaker 1: So what I will often do is i'll cut just like i'll go again.
Speaker 1: I'll cut the tip off the pizza I'll eat that and then i'll crack the rest of it.
Speaker 0: It's actually I think a number file video about You know the shape of the pizza and whether it'll blorp and how to get it to unblorp.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: That's like the video that taught me the correct way to eat a hamburger.
Speaker 1: Well, you put your pinky and your thumb on the bottom and the three fingers on the top and I felt really stupid for having Not figured that out in 20 years.
Speaker 0: Okay I don't know how you're eating hamburgers.
Speaker 1: So the video talked about it at length.
Speaker 1: americans do not do that.
Speaker 1: Americans put their thumb on the bottom and their entire hand on the top.
Speaker 1: Okay, like no one puts their pinky down there.
Speaker 1: pretty much if they do it's kind of weird.
Speaker 0: And doesn't everything fall out the back if you don't do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a very common thing that happens with hamburgers.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't eat the way anyone else eats, right?
Speaker 1: I just keep the fork on my left hand a hundred percent and you hold it backwards and you kind of like Just kind of just stab at your food.
Speaker 1: You're weird.
Speaker 0: It works.
Speaker 0: It's way more efficient.
Speaker 1: It's just fascinating to watch you eat like.
Speaker 1: I will never get over it.
Speaker 0: Don't you know how to?
Speaker 0: why don't you just eat the same way if it's so fascinating?
Speaker 1: It's fascinating to watch it's not?
Speaker 1: I wouldn't do it.
Speaker 1: It's like watching someone.
Speaker 1: it's like watching someone biking with a really weird technique like wow, they're going Good for them.
Speaker 1: That's fascinating.
Speaker 1: Not gonna emulate it.
Speaker 0: My technique is way more powerful.
Speaker 1: Should we have an eating contest?
Speaker 0: who can eat something faster, but you have to use a fork and knife you can't, you know?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, we'll make a challenge.
Speaker 1: You gotta eat a pizza with a fork and knife.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: I'll stab you and not the two eyes with the fork and a knife and then eat the pizza comfortably with my hands.
Speaker 1: The one problem I've had with pizza lately is that even though like it's easy to order pizza Uh, if I consult the people who are going to be eating the pizza At all even among close friends Everyone's a super picky eater and doesn't want something.
Speaker 0: That's not a pizza problem.
Speaker 0: That's a people problem Yeah, but that problem happens even if you order something that's not pizza.
Speaker 1: So what i've decided what i've done i've tried this now is instead of asking anyone.
Speaker 1: The problem is usually I can only get away with this if i'm just.
Speaker 1: i'm gonna order pizza for everyone because you know Otherwise people might be like eh And often they'll give me the five bucks anyway, even if I say that.
Speaker 1: but I just say I ordered pizza It'll be here in an hour.
Speaker 1: I don't even say i'm gonna order pizza.
Speaker 1: I say I ordered it even if I didn't.
Speaker 1: I say I ordered pizza.
Speaker 1: It'll be here in an hour.
Speaker 1: And if everyone's like, yes Then I order weird pizza because fuck them.
Speaker 1: and if they're not that into it I order bland ass pizza because I know they're hungry anyway, and at least I know they'll eat it.
Speaker 1: And that strategy's worked really well and I hope none of the people i've done that to are listening right now because they'll figure me out.
Speaker 0: Oh and if you are listening and you got you figured rim out, uh, you know, you're mad at rim right now.
Speaker 0: Be mad at me too because you're all picky eaters.
Speaker 0: get babies Eat anything.
Speaker 0: if someone orders a pizza and it's like if I don't want the hawaiian pizza, right?
Speaker 0: I just i'm not a fan of it.
Speaker 0: I would not order it on purpose.
Speaker 1: Pizza is you can almost any topping you can pick it out Like I could see if you had a religious thing like a food allergy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you have a real allergy a religious thing, whatever you got an excuse.
Speaker 0: but like I just don't like kawaiian pizza I would not order on purpose, but you know what.
Speaker 1: pick the ham out of there.
Speaker 0: if rim ordered it on rim ordered it And it was there and I was hungry.
Speaker 0: I would eat it because i'm an adult and this applies to all kinds not just pizza.
Speaker 1: Would you eat the mcdonald's pizza?
Speaker 1: It's a pizza, but it's got mcdonald's hamburger meat ground up on top of it.
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying would you eat that?
Speaker 1: or would you say no ew?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean is this saying it's just a matter of perspective.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's.
Speaker 1: I mean, so Would you eat it?
Speaker 1: Because i'm gonna say right now.
Speaker 1: No, fuck that.
Speaker 0: It depends.
Speaker 1: Is this a situation where if I was starving to death, it's about I would consider it.
Speaker 0: It's about the scenario, right?
Speaker 0: Is this a scenario like if i'm at a party?
Speaker 0: Right, and I really you know This party is a scenario in which food is being delivered for everyone to eat And the person hosting the party orders a fuck ton of mcdonald's for everyone to eat.
Speaker 0: I would actually probably go for that pizza ahead of like a big bank, right?
Speaker 0: In display of available mcdonald's foods.
Speaker 0: and that's a situation where i'm going to be an adult and eat the food that's at the party.
Speaker 0: But if it's just like, you know, I want some pizza.
Speaker 0: would I go to mcdonald's?
Speaker 0: No I think in that scenario unless if someone on the street said here Do you want a slice of pizza?
Speaker 0: It's a mcdonald's pizza.
Speaker 0: I would say no.
Speaker 1: if it was a hospitality situation Like if a family invited me into their home and they bust out that mcdonald's pizza.
Speaker 0: if i'm with a group of people And we're all hanging out together because they're like visiting town and every single person Wants to go to mcdonald's and i'm in this group i'll go but I won't eat.
Speaker 0: Uh, I would probably eat Chicken nuggets and french fries.
Speaker 1: I think I would just not eat Unless it was before breakfast time that I would.
Speaker 0: maybe i'd get an apple and ice cream.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't get their salad.
Speaker 1: Anyway, uh, so what we have not talked about at all because i've cut it out of my life entirely once I left college But it was a staple It would like.
Speaker 1: it was one of my food groups throughout basically my entire life until I graduated and until like halfway through our time in beacon frozen pizza Like actual frozen DiGiorno or whatever pizza.
Speaker 0: Listen, those pizzas depending on the situation Are not the worst.
Speaker 1: they do that thing to your body Like if i'm hungry.
Speaker 0: they can often be better than delivery pizza based on where you live.
Speaker 1: Oh compared to the pizza I got in seattle.
Speaker 1: I would rather eat one of those frozen pizzas.
Speaker 0: However, there is no reason to get them because there is a better technique.
Speaker 0: You can buy at the grocery store for less than the cost of the frozen pizza refrigerator pizza.
Speaker 0: You can buy a bag of dough And a can of sauce.
Speaker 0: No, not even that's got a bag of cheese.
Speaker 1: That's already too much.
Speaker 1: the point of the frozen pizza is that you do literally nothing to it.
Speaker 0: You can buy the dough.
Speaker 0: that's already bread.
Speaker 0: Basically instead of buying a bag of dough Buy a can of sauce.
Speaker 0: No, too much work.
Speaker 0: scott You're forgetting to lower the sauce on there put the cheese in there put in the oven.
Speaker 1: remember at rit instead of getting we kept a few frozen pizzas for emergencies because You know stuff wasn't open late at night.
Speaker 1: like food emergencies happen on a regular basis and if you had a frozen pizza you were saved.
Speaker 1: But instead in wegmans, I would get the refrigerated pizza.
Speaker 1: It's already made just throw in the oven.
Speaker 1: Not as good as the real pizza.
Speaker 1: Oh that kind way better than the frozen pizza.
Speaker 1: just as convenient but it only lasts like a week in the fridge.
Speaker 0: the point is if you do the methods I just said where you buy the Bag of dough the can of sauce the sack of cheese has way more work.
Speaker 0: any toppings that you want.
Speaker 1: That's way more work than literally just hitting a button on your oven.
Speaker 0: It's not a lot of work though, and you will get a fucking delicious pizza if you do that shit.
Speaker 1: Uh, actually so lately we've been making a lot of pizza because blue apron had a bunch of pizzas.
Speaker 0: We remember I usually cancel my blue apron as a pizza because I can't eat all that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess there's two of us.
Speaker 1: So we would.
Speaker 1: one of those pizzas is exactly dinner for two and it is way too much food for one person the pizza in particular.
Speaker 1: but We started making pizzas again because we got the bread maker that'll like make the doughs.
Speaker 0: I got a pizza.
Speaker 0: I got a pizza stone.
Speaker 0: So I just buy a dough at the bakery and then you know roll it out.
Speaker 1: Yep Uh, I think i'm gonna keep making pizzas because i'm feeling that it's like a ridge.
Speaker 1: It's way less work than some of the like regular blue apron things we get lately.
Speaker 0: It's also cheaper than even delivering one.
Speaker 0: It's way cheap.
Speaker 0: a bag of dough It cost almost nothing a can of sauce cost almost nothing and a sack of cheese is like a dollar or two.
Speaker 1: But I don't really feel like thinking back on what frozen pizza tastes like.
Speaker 1: It's not good.
Speaker 0: The thing is it's not good It's not the worst.
Speaker 1: and then mcdonald's way and that in retrospect I feel like it's so full of salt and sugar That it's tricking my body into like enjoying it.
Speaker 0: on this If you buy one of those like yeah, depending on the brand most likely that is exactly correct.
Speaker 1: Yep It's kind of like how if i'm hungry Even though the thought of eating mcdonald's hamburger is like physically revolting to me if I smell it a little bit Part of my body says hell no and this other animal part of my body says yeah, you could eat that.
Speaker 1: You should go eat that.
Speaker 1: go eat it.
Speaker 0: I mean pizza is basically bread.
Speaker 0: You know milk Salt and sugar anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah I should start putting msg on pizza.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it would taste great.
Speaker 1: It tastes really great.
Speaker 1: I'm real hungry.
Speaker 0: You've covered all the pizza related topics But i'm sure everyone in the world doesn't say about pizza because everyone eats.
Speaker 1: almost every other anecdote I have.
Speaker 1: is It relates to someone being picky when i'm trying to order pizza?
Speaker 1: Uh is that?
Speaker 1: is there any other anecdote other than that cow bunga?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I made it fun.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music cat lee for web design and brand.
Speaker 0: ok for the logos Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech mondays gaming tuesdays anime comic wednesdays.
Speaker 1: and indiscriminate thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the patreons for this episode of geek nights the owner of the amount
Speaker 0: of money they give us on a continuing basis are
Speaker 1: Ellen joist rebecca dunn nicholas brando logan stanford heidi mcnichola manda duchette james david white christian coombs construction noises mystady.com Sean hayworth william isen rose jeremy miner chris rimer and thomas on rachel montanona super boy the rainbow in the dark aaron serice brian fisher sailor vista Jail fried pork geeky kid matthew smith don schlick jar tovishon joshiro joestar tyler eller sean jager sam cordrey clinton walton Ren from new zealand ryan parenter openlander rare lavelle brian sedroni finn eric solverod the rural juror chris midkiff chris knox daniel redman sean klein chris rimer and thomas han.
Speaker 1: We're super hungry.
Speaker 1: So we cut this one off real quick.
Speaker 1: talking about pizza for an hour and not eating Was real hard, so i'm gonna cut this one short.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna talk a lot at the end here I'm, just gonna play my weird thing.
Speaker 1: But uh, like I said stay tuned to all our stuff.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be doing a lot more in the near future.
Speaker 1: In fact, I started pre-production for utana episode 16 as well as a bunch more sieve videos and we'll see you soon.
Speaker 1: Why are we getting back on the bus?
Speaker 0: it's time to go son we can't leave.
Speaker 0: we never met that chick.
Speaker 1: Damn it.
Speaker 1: We were supposed to get some Settle down babies.
Speaker 0: No, I won't settle down not this time.
Speaker 0: Damn it.
Speaker 1: This always happens.
Speaker 0: I think i'm gonna score and then I never score.
Speaker 0: It's not fair.
Speaker 1: We've traveled a um, um a hundred miles because we thought we were gonna score But now it's not gonna happen.
Speaker 1: damn it.
Speaker 1: hey buddy sit down shut up ass wipe.
Speaker 1: i'm sick and tired of this.
Speaker 1: We're never gonna score.
Speaker 1: It's just not gonna happen.
Speaker 1: We're just gonna get old like these people but they've probably scored.
Speaker 1: Hey i'm warning you sit down.
Speaker 1: It's like this chick's a slut And look at this guy.
Speaker 1: he's old, but he's probably scored a million times.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but not us.
Speaker 1: We're never gonna score.
Speaker 1: We're never gonna.
Speaker 1: All right, that's it nutnuts Oh.