Speaker 1: It's Monday November 28th 2016.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: It's that time.
Speaker 1: It's computer buying time.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So at work my computer is this Lenovo x220?
Speaker 0: For working that's just fine.
Speaker 0: That's just fine for working because I'm not doing any 3ds or any games or any anything.
Speaker 0: I'm just typing text.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I you looking at websites.
Speaker 1: I use the x230 And I like edit video on it, and it's not great, but it's not that much faster than the head I.
Speaker 0: it has i7 you know.
Speaker 0: the only problem with it is that it only has 8 gigs of RAM Which is the mat which is the supposed maximum.
Speaker 0: someone said you could put 16 in there, but I'm not trying that.
Speaker 0: It's not my computer, but anyway.
Speaker 0: So yeah because it only is 8 if I like.
Speaker 0: have a virtual machine and Spotify and two browsers.
Speaker 0: it starts going slow.
Speaker 0: It's got like two SSDs in it.
Speaker 0: There's nothing wrong with it except today.
Speaker 0: I get to work, and it was off.
Speaker 0: I don't remember turning it off, but it was off.
Speaker 1: That's always a bad sign.
Speaker 0: I go to turn it on and You know I start putting my stuff away, and you know whatever and then I go look at it and still off.
Speaker 0: So I push the button again, and this time I watch it right to see why.
Speaker 0: you know make sure it's turning on.
Speaker 1: It's funny in the oldest days when I would boot up a computer like I'm talking 486 like like I would sit there whenever I booted a computer because you didn't leave your computer on like you turned it off Whenever you weren't using it.
Speaker 1: so I would turn it on.
Speaker 1: I would literally always sit there and watch like the entire post process.
Speaker 0: I didn't do that, but anyway.
Speaker 0: So I watch it, and it goes think bad push blue button for BIOS And I'm like nope and then it says beep beep beep fan error.
Speaker 0: And then it just turns off fan error.
Speaker 1: that is like in the old cuz.
Speaker 1: they know I used to work at IBM.
Speaker 1: That is the like.
Speaker 1: yeah This computer is hosed error because it usually means that Something went so wrong in the beginning that like the motherboard can't even really bring everything online.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it means fan error because I turn it on again And I listen with my ear, and I don't hear no fan.
Speaker 0: I don't hear no fan.
Speaker 0: So I go so I email IT using my phone, and I'm like I think my computer broke did and they come over with a can of air.
Speaker 0: we blow out the fan and I push the button and Nope, don't turn on.
Speaker 1: well in my experience with servers like you get fan error when the motherboard was hosed Like that's just the error that would bubble up in the end.
Speaker 0: the motherboard is hosed.
Speaker 0: How would it even go to like you know BIOS screen?
Speaker 0: You'd be surprised like I mean I suppose if the motherboard was hosed in such a way that the first thing that was broken was that it couldn't provide power to the fan and It detected that fault before proceeding to other fault detection mechanisms and refute it.
Speaker 0: because computer even if I push the blue button to go To BIOS is like no I will not do anything if the fan is not working because because right
Speaker 1: I'm in a situations where I overrode Checks to force like a server like that to boot and it would like that the things that were wrong with it would be way Worse I guess
Speaker 0: if I somehow disabled the fan fault detection, which I don't even know how I would do maybe
Speaker 1: server I could trick
Speaker 0: it into thinking the fan is on by providing some power on the fan port or something and Hope that even works, and it's like It could just be the fan is dead too right, but anyway.
Speaker 0: So yeah, they couldn't fix it.
Speaker 0: So they gave me this really ugly looking Dell laptop temporarily because I guess that they ordered the surface book But it's not gonna come for a while performance base, or just regular.
Speaker 0: I asked for the one that had 16 gigs and a 512 gig SSD because that's what I need to do my work.
Speaker 1: It looks like the most tricked-out one is like 3800 bucks, but I think that's a terabyte SSD.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well I mean that would be nice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's crazy.
Speaker 0: I also asked for this has a little dock thing You know.
Speaker 0: so It's a really ugly looking Dell laptop, but you know what the IT guy?
Speaker 0: he done a good job.
Speaker 0: he took my SSD out of my ThinkPad, and he shoved it in this Dell.
Speaker 0: and Except for the fact that it's really ugly looking It was like I had my own computer except I had a second SSD in my ThinkPad with like my virtual machines on it Daddy to SS that was.
Speaker 0: it was in the docking station, so I gave it to him and He couldn't really get me in my virtual machine, so I couldn't do a lot of work, so now I gotta bring my SS SATA to USB adapter to work.
Speaker 1: I have one of those somewhere.
Speaker 0: I have like two of them, but yeah I got to bring that to work tomorrow, so that I can load my virtual machine, so Semi-related.
Speaker 1: just you know how we like.
Speaker 1: I'm remastering all those old beta episodes of geek nights.
Speaker 1: I'm putting them up on the patreon and listen to one of them.
Speaker 1: last night as I was remastering it And I think it's the last one like.
Speaker 1: we actually ordered the mixer.
Speaker 1: But I don't like.
Speaker 1: we're just sort of talking before we do the main thing and all like.
Speaker 1: I can't figure out exactly what happened.
Speaker 1: But this was that era in beacon where we had a lot of computers like all over the house And we just found that hole in the stairway and had run a network cable down to the bottom.
Speaker 1: Here are the two crazy things that happened.
Speaker 1: one.
Speaker 1: We're talking about some network troubles.
Speaker 1: We had we were still using that hub That hub hub we were using.
Speaker 0: this even make hubs anymore Think.
Speaker 1: so we were using a homemade.
Speaker 0: the only reason hubs existed back in the day is because they were cheaper.
Speaker 0: Do you remember what switch required like chips that were expensive?
Speaker 1: Yeah, at RIT we bought a switch was slower, and the hub was in some cases And I remember we like dreamed of being able to afford a switch.
Speaker 0: It's like a switch.
Speaker 1: Whoa you can remember what was special about that hub.
Speaker 0: it was it wasn't Full duplex.
Speaker 1: that was it and we.
Speaker 1: so there was a 10 and a 100 Hub and the 100 hub was like four or five dollars more, and we were like oh shit hundred hundreds better than ten fuck Buy it.
Speaker 1: we bought it, and we didn't realize though years later.
Speaker 1: It was half duplex piece of shit Got the job done.
Speaker 1: so apparently we had bought a switch upstairs that was expensive and we put the hub Downstairs.
Speaker 1: at the other end of that cable we ran through yeah, and you know who's plugged into that downstairs a computer the duron 900 and You said I forgot that they were even durons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the sentence you said in this of course at the beginning of this episode is downstairs We have a working Gentoo.
Speaker 1: You know on the duron Mm-hmm we were running Gentoo on it and apparently we hadn't updated the Gentoo in Months because it took too long to update because it was so slow.
Speaker 0: yeah those duron times.
Speaker 0: Basically it was like those are the days where AMD was better than Intel and cheaper And we didn't have bad moneys.
Speaker 1: like a Pentium 4 was a lot of money.
Speaker 1: It wasn't that fast and Athlon like Thunderbird was a gigahertz, but they were mad unreliable.
Speaker 0: so I got for myself.
Speaker 0: I bought like AMD k7 whatever and Or Athlons and I got a Real computer for like my parents whatever it was like they don't need performance.
Speaker 0: I'll get this duron.
Speaker 0: It's like the same thing only cheaper because that you know.
Speaker 0: they had Celeron's in those days And now they've simplified it with i3 i5 i7.
Speaker 0: so like a Celeron in those days It was like the low end.
Speaker 0: and then you know Pentium was the real deal.
Speaker 0: the same thing like duron and Athlon.
Speaker 0: duron was the low end.
Speaker 1: and the only other thing is interesting in That is basically they were so unreliable.
Speaker 0: they break all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah We had all remember we had that like.
Speaker 0: That's why I had so much equipment because I kept having to replace broken shit.
Speaker 0: And I you know if I had just bought an Intel one from the beginning.
Speaker 1: Yep, we had a lot of frankencomputers that era and we kept making all these servers like I was still running.
Speaker 1: that counters.
Speaker 0: well because every time you it's like oh this one's sort of broken now, I'll buy a new one and Then you take all the old pieces lying around and put together a working computer and be like up server.
Speaker 1: So we had another server And I don't know what happened because that is cut off of the audio.
Speaker 0: the other things that would happen is like you know This is my second or third computer at this point.
Speaker 0: I guess five years right, so I built my first computer 99.
Speaker 0: I built my first one in 2000 I built another one at RIT in 2005 and then 2010 and then do right.
Speaker 0: So I had like these old computers But like my original computer for 1999 the most reliable computer to ever exist.
Speaker 0: the only thing that broke about it We X board the BX board the a bit vx6 r2 motherboard for a Pentium 3 slot CPUs with a Pentium 3. that was the most reliable.
Speaker 0: I bet I still have it.
Speaker 0: I bet it still works if I can get enough equipment to make it work.
Speaker 1: in fact I was thinking Scott if we could get it to work.
Speaker 0: We could use it to generate all new GPG keys Sure, but anyway, I could just use my Apple to GS to do that.
Speaker 0: just be slow But like I probably still works.
Speaker 0: So it even though it was slow to do things like serving up static websites and such or even PHP VB websites It did that job for many moons and didn't need to have any GPUs or anything like that.
Speaker 1: Like I remember we had an a we had an AMD I think video card or an ATI video card that worked But you could not in Linux tell it to output video on the S video port Which is what we needed to plug into
Speaker 0: and the cheapo and video card we had would output as video just on boot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz it wasn't a piece of shit.
Speaker 0: That's why you should not buy a non Nvidia video card.
Speaker 0: They're just better.
Speaker 1: that ship sailed and sank a long time ago, but the drama that was happening.
Speaker 1: That's also funny is Apparently like the audio starts.
Speaker 1: I'm basically like complaining to you that you broke the DHCP DNS server and you're like, I gotta fix it.
Speaker 1: But and we talked about it at length.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the problem was.
Speaker 1: All I know is you broke the DHCP DNS server that we were using in the house And that was a minor source of drama and then we did an episode about something.
Speaker 0: All right So here's my.
Speaker 0: so check this news.
Speaker 0: I'm checking right?
Speaker 0: So this isn't really news is more of a geek bite of OS X The Apple operating system, I'm not talking about the whole thing.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about a piece of it that I discovered at work today.
Speaker 0: So at work, right everyone has everyone on our whole team has an Apple computer except me.
Speaker 0: And everyone has this problem that when they run the website the cert, you know, our dev environment locally.
Speaker 0: It's way slow Except me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I've always been like yo, it's cuz you got them Apple sort of half sarcastically But also half it probably is something up with the Apple.
Speaker 0: But I know one else knows enough to fix it or figure out what it was Except me and I wasn't doing that because I'd have an Apple computer.
Speaker 1: Did you finally look at it and figure it out?
Speaker 0: So I did.
Speaker 0: So what happened today is someone comes over right and they're like, they're like, hey, how do they ask me?
Speaker 0: You know, they keep giving me the XY question, right where they're like, how do I do this not addressing the real problem?
Speaker 0: And he's like, hey, you know When we download the database all the domains don't have.
Speaker 0: they have www.
Speaker 0: how do we get rid of the www?
Speaker 0: And I'm like, why does it matter?
Speaker 0: I'm like.
Speaker 0: just type www is not a problem What he's like, but if I don't do www it's faster and I'm like what?
Speaker 0: What that makes no sense?
Speaker 0: You could use asdf.
Speaker 0: It's just a domain name.
Speaker 0: Whatever in your host file is gonna be just fine.
Speaker 0: You could type And it would be just as fast.
Speaker 0: Like that makes no sense whatsoever.
Speaker 0: that changing the name would change the speed right, right?
Speaker 1: Well, yeah I'm just racking my brain for situations.
Speaker 0: So I can imagine I go over there and I try a bunch of stuff and you know to make sure it's not browser caching.
Speaker 0: I'm using private browsing windows and I'm messing with the host file.
Speaker 0: and you know Cuz like you're working on this local dev server, right?
Speaker 0: So you don't just want to type localhost You got to type in.
Speaker 0: you know You know Whatever and you want to have that resolve to your load that you know Your local computer so you can load up the website start like in my world.
Speaker 1: It's even more because a lot of things Really won't work if you point them a localhost because they're intended to be like big server.
Speaker 0: I see you go in your host file and you type in a whole bunch of stuff like you add a whole ton of domains For localhost that when you spin up dev servers you can point, you know, you can visit them.
Speaker 1: I've always I don't know if this is lazy or the opposite of lazy I've always run a local DNS server and just connected to that.
Speaker 0: That's not a bad idea because it's just if you want to do that.
Speaker 0: There's a thing called DNS mask masq.
Speaker 0: It's really good for that because you can do wildcards and stuff.
Speaker 0: It's really good.
Speaker 0: That's what we used a back and vegan on that.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I look into that.
Speaker 1: cuz I'm really I don't really need to run like a full bind of it.
Speaker 0: So it's a much simpler configuration file than bind and it's meant for you know, your local tiny DNS problems.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I mess around with it a whole bunch and it's pretty much slow No matter what I do and I'm like, uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: See name doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: See name doesn't matter, right?
Speaker 0: And then eventually they're like no put it back the way it was like originally and it was fast.
Speaker 0: So they mess around with it and it's fast and I go and I look and I see what they did.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: They did what they do.
Speaker 0: They were visiting the domain of the local computer.
Speaker 0: All right without the WW in front.
Speaker 0: All right, and They had removed that entirely from the host file.
Speaker 0: So I was like, how is this even resolving to localhost?
Speaker 0: and it's because the DNS server in the office the local You know network DNS server was resolving the name of their machine to their machine.
Speaker 0: It just wasn't doing it for any subdomains or any other domains.
Speaker 0: But I'm like, wait a minute that makes no sense.
Speaker 1: Why would that be faster?
Speaker 0: that be faster than your host file?
Speaker 0: Shouldn't the host file be the fastest possible thing?
Speaker 1: Yeah, not even making a DNS request I mean on a Linux server in a production environment you pretty much hard code stuff in the host file.
Speaker 1: So you're never.
Speaker 1: you're saving on DNS.
Speaker 0: You're saving milliseconds by doing that, right?
Speaker 0: But this was an order of like with with it in the host file It was taking like over 10 to 30 seconds to load the website.
Speaker 1: at that point I would type I would type into Google Apple host file slow question mark now that I knew what to search for.
Speaker 0: See, I didn't know that.
Speaker 0: Of course, I find indeed that OSX.
Speaker 0: how wait if you're writing an operating system network stack, right and you're writing the DNS part.
Speaker 0: What would the logic be you use?
Speaker 1: All right, so already windows.
Speaker 1: People don't realize that if you'd like in Linux and Linux you type nslookup It will ignore your host file.
Speaker 1: That's correct and go to the DNS server because that assumes you're not so stupid that you need to use nslookup To look at your own host file.
Speaker 1: It assumes you want to find out what the real world knows about that.
Speaker 0: Dig does the same thing.
Speaker 0: Yes, but that's not the issue, right?
Speaker 1: If you were writing operating system, the rule is you look at the host file and if it's not there then you DNS.
Speaker 1: Maybe you look at both and use whatever comes back first or use the host file If it comes back first, like you could come up with some cleverness, but it's host file then DNS, right?
Speaker 0: So OS X of course is a piece of shit.
Speaker 0: First of all, if you format the host file differently like putting multiple domains on one line That can make it do weird stupid things that make it slow But no one knows it will.
Speaker 0: it seems to do DNS first and then fall back on the host file.
Speaker 0: Well, if you don't if you have ipv6 turned on but you don't have an ipv6 entry in the host file That can make it way slow.
Speaker 1: Linux machines will have that problem, too.
Speaker 0: that's a weird but from from what I could tell is if you have the thing in your host file and It will basically because you're visiting a website, right?
Speaker 0: So you're actually making many many requests for this domain not just one request for the domain.
Speaker 0: You're making a whole bunch right because you're serving the images and these static files.
Speaker 0: It was basically Going through the full DNS timeout on each and every request to the local server and then looking at the host file Basically for every single request to the local server that was in the HTML.
Speaker 0: It's like first it made one request waited like three seconds for this timeout Got the HTML and then for each and every image in each and every CSS file in each and every GS file.
Speaker 0: You were getting another three second timeout when it was looking for the DNS of a domain that didn't exist on any DNS server And then looked at the host file afterwards thus making the website load in like 30 seconds.
Speaker 0: And this is because OS X is a piece of shit.
Speaker 0: Is why I don't use that shit.
Speaker 0: I don't know why so many developers use it.
Speaker 0: I've complained about this crap kind of thing for a long time and every time you know It comes off as me just going OS X sucks.
Speaker 0: But then in the end it turns out that I'm right.
Speaker 0: I like when everything else in the universe where I have a feeling about something and I say it and then I turned out to Be vindicated later because I'm always right.
Speaker 0: So what one aside I don't point out times when I was wrong.
Speaker 0: They didn't happen.
Speaker 1: I don't know if some of the software that you know I as a job Manage would work on OS X cuz I don't really care.
Speaker 1: like so I officially say it doesn't work and we don't support it Rather than ever even attempting to test it for all I know it works fine - I'm googling around so Scott how it on an Apple.
Speaker 1: What's the difference between Etsy hosts and private Etsy hosts?
Speaker 0: I never even heard of such a thing.
Speaker 0: Why would there be two hosts?
Speaker 1: Apparently there's a forward slash private And then there's Etsy and a bunch of shit in there.
Speaker 1: All right I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: and I see I'm just.
Speaker 1: I'm googling around for OS X host files And I'm finding websites that just made me even more confused.
Speaker 1: I think it's worse than you're implying, right?
Speaker 0: Basically, it's it's Unix technically the kernel whatever but it is not follow any of the standards or it doesn't follow enough of the Standards for how it works as a Unix.
Speaker 0: This is why it needs like its own like you compile stuff for like one Linux.
Speaker 0: You can run it on another Linux.
Speaker 0: You can file stuff for a Unix.
Speaker 1: You can run slash private.
Speaker 1: The first thing just not Google is folder Mac.
Speaker 1: What does?
Speaker 0: yeah It's like.
Speaker 0: they just did all this stuff.
Speaker 0: That is unlike any other Unix and all these people were like, oh I use it cuz it's like standard Unix.
Speaker 0: It's like you're full of shit.
Speaker 0: It's fucked up and messed up compared to all the other.
Speaker 0: real even Linux which isn't Unix is more Unix than OS X is.
Speaker 0: At this point terms of in terms of practice and not in terms of like.
Speaker 0: don't give me that technical nonsense.
Speaker 0: Like it's approved by the Unix Authority.
Speaker 0: trademark.
Speaker 1: Look if I want to compile something like the other day I had to compile.
Speaker 0: as far as the user Experience goes it is fucked the fuck.
Speaker 1: I had to compile pcap on a server the other day because I needed some cap packet capture and I needed like particular.
Speaker 1: There's a whole long story.
Speaker 1: I had to compile pcap.
Speaker 1: So of course, I just install like lib pcap and lib pcap - devel Maybe it's called - lib on your you know distro or whatever and then I type make and all that biz.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: It just worked.
Speaker 1: I'm some random Linux distro.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm confident that would not have worked on a Mac.
Speaker 0: No, so Yeah, I think what I'm gonna have to do is figure out how to set up.
Speaker 0: I got to get a Mac figure out how to set up DNS mask on it and go around to everyone's computer And get them to use that instead of their host file.
Speaker 0: that might be your best bet and then it should be fast.
Speaker 1: Well one will that work on Mac - will it go to the regular?
Speaker 0: Refers it during the period where I had a Mac.
Speaker 0: That's what I did.
Speaker 0: Oh, which is why I never had this problem.
Speaker 1: when you install it Do you just like point your resolver at.
Speaker 0: yes, you basically got local, right?
Speaker 0: So if you have a resolve.com file you would make this.
Speaker 0: you make the first entry be localhost.
Speaker 0: Okay, so that your DNS request go to localhost first and then you put your you know isp's DNS server is the second entry in resolve.com.
Speaker 0: or If you have like a GUI for setting up your DNS like in Windows.
Speaker 0: You just put your localhost as your first DNS server, right?
Speaker 1: You probably want to just put it because you don't want it to round robin.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is in your DNS mask configuration.
Speaker 0: You could tell it to.
Speaker 0: if you don't resolve then hit the right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the right way to do it.
Speaker 1: You wouldn't want to put your isps one second.
Speaker 1: You want to put DNS mask right?
Speaker 0: You could put the isp's one in the DNS mask conf or on your right?
Speaker 0: It's it's up to you.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna set it up because I have my bind is not super well configured cuz I was in a hurry.
Speaker 0: I mean all I do the I'd for these days.
Speaker 0: I just point everything at the Google.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, no I have like three VMS on my local machine at work that are all sort of working with each other because I'm testing a bunch of weird shit and I'm just running bind on one of them.
Speaker 0: Dns mask does the same thing only simpler for situations like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's probably what I'm gonna do.
Speaker 0: You couldn't use it for like a big organization or whatever.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, but you could use it for like.
Speaker 0: I just need some DNS right now I decided I don't want to mess with bind file.
Speaker 1: I will not use any IT service provided by my company.
Speaker 1: I use all my own IT services my own environment Cuz well your own email server, uh Google use Google for that.
Speaker 0: Okay, so you have an exchange server.
Speaker 1: That's oh Bunch of people use outlook from the old days when they had that shit.
Speaker 1: But they're just pointed at Google and they have problems all the time because usually that works.
Speaker 1: It does work.
Speaker 0: It's just their problems are usually They've messed up something in their outlook and there's people I mean, you know, there's people out there who really like outlook.
Speaker 0: You know, I don't understand those people I mean But it's like hey you can at the newest.
Speaker 0: newest outlook is actually better than older outlooks and you can point it like Especially the iPhone iPad apps.
Speaker 0: you can point it at Google.
Speaker 1: In my experience the people who say they prefer outlook tend to also not like newer versions of outlook Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So in other news something amazing happened to a mass transit system in San Francisco.
Speaker 1: It's basically they're like have mass transit.
Speaker 1: I guess they have trams or I don't know what it is, but they have some sort little choo-choo.
Speaker 1: It has to be like DC's I guess because I'm pretty sure they all use the bus, right?
Speaker 0: That's why people keep talking about throwing rocks at the Google bus.
Speaker 1: Well, those yeah, those buses are private though, right?
Speaker 0: But I'm saying is like if they you know, why is everyone busing if they have a mass transit?
Speaker 1: Well, they mean buses technically are mass transit, but I guess there's other mass transit.
Speaker 1: but anyway, the notable thing is that all the systems that you use to like interact with this or Put your ticket in to get through the turnstile or buy a ticket Got infected with ransomware.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, this is San Francisco where all the tech people are.
Speaker 0: So that's where you need things to be the most secure, right?
Speaker 0: Yep So it's like, you know, if it's if it's we're in like cyberpunk future, right?
Speaker 0: The computers in podunk vale don't actually need to be that secure because no one is from cyber land gives a fuck.
Speaker 0: But the cyber land computers of neo Tokyo need to be ultra secure because the cyber hackers everywhere.
Speaker 0: So San Francisco computers need to be the most secure.
Speaker 1: It also apparently got their email systems and possibly internal servers as well And this has been going on for days and days.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure if it's actually back up or not.
Speaker 1: The only solution they had until they fix it which probably involves reinstalling on every device they've got.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which probably will take a while is they've just opened all the fair gates and everything's free.
Speaker 1: Oh sweet So, I don't know if the hackers who did this hack the metro card.
Speaker 1: We're hoping to get paid or we're hoping for the Robin Hood situation to occur.
Speaker 0: Let's let's hook the metro card.
Speaker 1: I just find this all hilarious.
Speaker 1: Like you guys are worried about like voter fraud or recounts or whatever Everything in America is so thinly secured.
Speaker 1: Like you should be worried about like nuclear power plants Here's what we're going to do.
Speaker 0: We're gonna hack all the transit in New York City.
Speaker 0: Is that all the transit that is used by rich people like cabs?
Speaker 0: the price goes up and they don't.
Speaker 0: And then all the this.
Speaker 1: if you swipe and like a poor neighborhood It's actually free like one in ten is just free and it just it says like it just like winks at you on the thing I got.
Speaker 0: and then and then we like.
Speaker 0: we figure out like who's poor people just based on where they've swiped and we figure out Who's tourists and we charge the tourists like ten bucks a swipe Right and people are like why and you know, they swipe and won't let him in or tourists wife.
Speaker 0: So you just take all their money no matter how much they got.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's like zero.
Speaker 0: I put a hundred on here.
Speaker 1: Well, fuck you, but there's also I mean, it's not just Windows systems.
Speaker 1: I've run into many people who apparently work in IT and think they know things who bristle at.
Speaker 1: you know any suggestion of security I might provide to them with a this sort of canned line of.
Speaker 1: you don't need antivirus on Linux and I'm sure I guess they think like I'm in a V or like something you don't need Antivirus anywhere period.
Speaker 0: right that particular security measure is not useful.
Speaker 0: Like intrusion protection systems You still need security systems no matter what you're using.
Speaker 0: real security like a real server.
Speaker 0: Etsy shouldn't change Network network level security.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like there's a whole file systems They should.
Speaker 1: literally nothing in them should ever change without a change ticket.
Speaker 1: So you should at least have a thing that says yo dog opt changed this.
Speaker 1: there's a new file in opt So we're shutting everything down.
Speaker 0: Just keeping you aware You know Did you just detects if anything on any drive changes and if so?
Speaker 0: Saves a copy of that for forensic purposes and then wipes it and restores it to its original.
Speaker 1: Yeah the argument I got against that was an unnamed person who said but if you have you watch like the Transaction logs of the database server then like it'll change all the time.
Speaker 1: It'll be worthless.
Speaker 0: You don't look at those.
Speaker 1: Yeah Exceptions dude, you don't?
Speaker 0: you don't look at the whole file system.
Speaker 1: much like how would I tell you how to make a peanut?
Speaker 1: Jelly sandwich?
Speaker 1: I don't specify that you have to put it on a plate nor do I specify that you should use a butter Knife as opposed to a steak knife.
Speaker 1: I sort of assume all those things to get to the higher level.
Speaker 1: instruction I mean if a peanut butter jelly bread?
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: mean if a computer is literally just running an application and the only thing that ever like I think about like a web server The only files that ever change when it's just running our logs or the actual application if we do a release and only then so really and Only the
Speaker 1: last user That
Speaker 0: isn't in var log changes during a non-release period that computer is suspect and should be you know down
Speaker 1: Nobody knows.
Speaker 0: that's an excellent security measure.
Speaker 1: Yeah things of the day.
Speaker 1: The headline on this article says it all.
Speaker 1: This is for on a V Club and it's a very in-depth article.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna I'm not gonna spoil all the juicy and pertinent bits.
Speaker 1: But if you were a fan of double dare I Watch that show quite a bit back in the day was a big fan of double dare.
Speaker 1: as a kid I wasn't like.
Speaker 0: it was one of those shows like I wasn't super excited like watching it.
Speaker 1: Like if you turn on the TV and like it was on it was on.
Speaker 0: I was watching it and I'd be in and want To watch it.
Speaker 1: I always wanted to be on it because the prizes to a kid brain We're the best goddamn prizes.
Speaker 0: You know what it was like.
Speaker 0: care kids game gear.
Speaker 1: We'll give you a game gear and send you to Disney.
Speaker 0: You know what you only like.
Speaker 0: I never cared about the prizes and game shows.
Speaker 0: I just wanted to play the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I want to go and you know, I wanted to slide down the slide into the pile of mud.
Speaker 1: So I learned now that I did not want to be in any part of double-dare.
Speaker 1: I know because the headline of this article which is very accurate and you really need to read the whole thing because it's long.
Speaker 1: It gets into a lot of detail Like why the prizes were the way they were like.
Speaker 1: everything about the story of this like this is.
Speaker 1: this is great journalism.
Speaker 1: Quote it smelled like death.
Speaker 1: what an oral history of the double dare obstacle course.
Speaker 1: Apparently that shit smelled like dead things.
Speaker 0: Isn't it?
Speaker 0: Just like whipped cream.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah rotting forever.
Speaker 1: Why'd you clean it into all the surfaces such that they couldn't be clean?
Speaker 1: because none of the people involved in this were experts At any of this.
Speaker 1: they were just winging it.
Speaker 0: Oh, so they didn't clean it properly.
Speaker 1: Apparently after the first season they cleaned it like thoroughly.
Speaker 1: at least they thought they did cuz it was just this mat.
Speaker 1: They rolled out in the studio this gigantic like rubber mat.
Speaker 0: Just get a new one.
Speaker 1: So they rolled it up after cleaning it and stored it for a year and then they like dried out first to do another season.
Speaker 1: And it didn't smell bad yet, but supposedly anyone who touched it broke out in horrifying blisters.
Speaker 1: Okay, read this thing.
Speaker 1: It is terrifying and fascinating.
Speaker 1: How double dare came to be?
Speaker 0: Okay I've used this guy's my thing of the day before.
Speaker 0: he's basically finding with all these security weaknesses and stuff and He's got this great one today the poison tap.
Speaker 0: It's actually like a week old or whatever, but you haven't seen it.
Speaker 1: I have not seen it.
Speaker 0: So it's the poison tap.
Speaker 0: He's it's basically a tiny Raspberry Pi with an Ethernet cable on it, right?
Speaker 0: so you go to a computer and this computer is on but it's locked and You cannot log in because we're gonna assume the password on that lock, you know Cuz?
Speaker 0: they pressed window L or command L and it's legit locked and you cannot unlock it.
Speaker 0: But you want to exploit this person and take advantage of them in a way.
Speaker 0: How do you do this?
Speaker 0: You take this Raspberry Pi zero and you plug it into their Ethernet hole, which is not protected in any way whatsoever.
Speaker 1: I have seen cases in high-security environments where the computers themselves were locked in cages and inaccessible Sure, but then we're talking about a laptop on a table and even there you know what I would do if I had to.
Speaker 1: I Would cut the Ethernet cable and then splice my own crossover with an a cable in.
Speaker 0: but I mean like you could go into an Office room for existence or up to a lectern and plug in your Ethernet cable and little do you know.
Speaker 0: there is one of these On the other end of the cable hidden inside the table.
Speaker 0: Ah, right.
Speaker 0: But anyway So we're going to a library this Ethernet cable sticking out of the wall and you plug in and up anyway.
Speaker 0: So here's how it works.
Speaker 0: your computer Even if it's locked when it sees that Ethernet cable is gonna stop using this Wi-Fi and try to use that Ethernet.
Speaker 0: It's gonna do some DHCPs.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So, of course, there's a little DHCP server on there that goes, uh-huh I see that right.
Speaker 0: It's a little fake DNS on there.
Speaker 0: Go.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: We're good.
Speaker 0: Yeah This is not.
Speaker 0: this is actually the Internet and not just a computer pretending to be the Internet.
Speaker 0: And meanwhile because you're a normal person you had your web browser open because that's what you do.
Speaker 0: Oh all those pages your web browser your web browser is not closed, right?
Speaker 0: It's open behind that lock screen and it's still doing stuff, right?
Speaker 0: I mean if you were to unlock your computer and there was a new email in Gmail It would already be there because your browser all the JavaScripts are running in that browser, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know you plug into this.
Speaker 0: suddenly your computer thinks that's the internet and doesn't know better.
Speaker 0: So all the things all the requests it was, you know sending or receiving Are going to this little tiny computer instead of to the real internet.
Speaker 0: and if you don't have SSL that's done properly.
Speaker 0: Your browser will believe that.
Speaker 0: yes indeed that thing pretending to be Gmail is Gmail.
Speaker 0: Of course, right won't work on Gmail because the SSL is done properly, but For some other website, it will totally believe that and it will send over the cookie for that website.
Speaker 0: and now the person who has that little Raspberry Pi computer can take that cookie and Manually put that cookie into their own browser.
Speaker 0: and now they're logged into that website as you Done.
Speaker 1: This is good stuff.
Speaker 0: Your computer was locked.
Speaker 0: You thought it was totally safe, but they plugged in a thing.
Speaker 0: They waited a few seconds They looked at the data and now they're logged into that website as you and the only protection is Make sure all your like turn your computer off all the way.
Speaker 0: Yep Don't leave your browser open even behind the lock screen.
Speaker 0: Don't have an Ethernet hole.
Speaker 0: don't let people plug shit into your computer.
Speaker 0: don't plug your computer into strange things and Only log into website sites that have real well done SSL because the SSL is done properly.
Speaker 0: What will happen is that fake internet will be like, yeah I'm google.com and the web browser goes.
Speaker 0: prove it with this encryption Little Raspberry Pi is like oh no I do not know the secret key of Google because I am NOT a Google server.
Speaker 0: for real I cannot win this encryption battle and it goes you're not real.
Speaker 0: I will not tell you any cookies.
Speaker 1: No Have any like built-in man-of-the-middle attack attempts or any of that nonsense.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you can plug in real internet to the other side of it.
Speaker 0: I think it just basically tries to get all your cookies and then whatever.
Speaker 0: but you can watch the video To see all of its advanced features and such.
Speaker 0: that's that's the main feature.
Speaker 0: But it does many other things.
Speaker 1: Oh siphons cookies exposes internal router and installs web back door.
Speaker 1: Yep Web back door is good in the moment.
Speaker 1: The book club book is Rebecca Mmm, I'm gonna read it as soon as I finish.
Speaker 1: I'm almost.
Speaker 1: I'm completely.
Speaker 1: I'm like at the end of the mad Adam trilogy I was gonna read.
Speaker 0: I was getting ready to read it again But then I started playing that single-player the new doom game As soon as I got the BFG.
Speaker 0: So as soon as I find a cyberdemon to use it on that should be the end of the game And then I've been playing a lot of overwatch and civ6.
Speaker 1: So that's been delaying me from more reading as well.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna be at magfest.
Speaker 1: We should.
Speaker 0: Well, I just bought my bus ticket today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I bought my Amtrak a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Scott will be on two panels cuz he's a little baby and I will be on five.
Speaker 0: Oh good I'll have plenty of time to play games.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna be doing quitting.
Speaker 1: And the grind that's me and Scott like.
Speaker 1: quitting is a brand new panel and this is the first time anyone can see it.
Speaker 1: It's not on YouTube And we probably won't put this one on YouTube because we're gonna practice it there and put a different version of it.
Speaker 1: when we do It at Pac South where we're very likely doing it as well Pac South will be like the main version and this is like the beta version of quitting.
Speaker 1: We're doing that grind panel again.
Speaker 1: I actually updated it because I found some more research and then I'm gonna be on.
Speaker 1: When does Sisyphus rage quit which is a panel discussion as James part.
Speaker 0: now on it are we already doing a quitting panel?
Speaker 1: Yes, our quitting panel is us telling you about quitting and this is a bunch of experts.
Speaker 0: Young Sisyphus young Scott office, uh, he rage quit after pushing that rock for a long time.
Speaker 1: I look at the rock from a distance.
Speaker 0: Yeah, 2016 Scott office sees that rock far away.
Speaker 0: He sees other people pushing the rock and goes Ramaphis didn't even read a review of the rock.
Speaker 1: remember this looks up the Wikipedia on the word rock and says yeah
Speaker 0: I think the transition between old Scott office and new Scott office is sometime around the World of Warcraft era Where I had been playing muds and then I saw people playing World of Warcraft and I said ain't pushing that one.
Speaker 1: Yeah and then I will be on.
Speaker 1: also, uh, the sounds of horror in games in cinema and The virtual mixed and augmented reality panel because I learned a bunch of stuff about AR and VR kind of recently, too Paying attention to it.
Speaker 1: I also think if you made a Five Nights at Freddy's kind of game legit and put it on an oculus and like really made It right.
Speaker 1: I don't I might mess people up like it might be over an ethical line.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure yet Kind of want to make it or have someone make it and play.
Speaker 0: sure horror games in VR will exist once VR is real.
Speaker 1: Well, I saw people having real bad reactions to the like very primitive attempt at something like that.
Speaker 1: It was the the you're being beheaded simulator.
Speaker 0: rule 34 isn't just about porn, right?
Speaker 0: If anything I think it's just porn.
Speaker 0: if anything can exist it will exist.
Speaker 0: pretty sure.
Speaker 1: rule 34 is just porn.
Speaker 0: it is.
Speaker 0: But I'm saying anything that can exist will exist.
Speaker 1: So what is the including porn?
Speaker 0: Rule 34 is a subset of an also true rule.
Speaker 0: That is not rule 34.
Speaker 1: moral is that we are going to be at both mag fest and Pac South and it is going to be glorious.
Speaker 1: also Enforcer applications are open for Pac South still but will close soon if you listen to geek nights and you've never enforced the packs And you're already gonna be going back.
Speaker 0: That was probably the easiest one to enforce because so chill and because they're slightly short like they could use more enforcers.
Speaker 1: I'll put it that way.
Speaker 0: Sorry guys.
Speaker 0: I'm playing some games meaning all the way to San Antonio.
Speaker 1: I'm playing games Yeah, I because we're panelists and gamers and every other packs and we go to like all the paxes.
Speaker 1: I didn't force a paxis, but I don't enforce it all the paxes.
Speaker 1: But if you've never done it I highly recommend you check it out because it's it's way.
Speaker 1: It's a way different view on pax.
Speaker 1: Like even if you only do it once like if you think you've staffed like an anime con or something See in the way enforcers do it will make you want to never attend an anime con again Like it is.
Speaker 1: it's off the hook.
Speaker 1: and also if you already bought a badge and you think but rim What if I already bought a badge?
Speaker 1: but I want to enforce don't enforcers get free badges.
Speaker 1: They'll probably take care of you and refund the cash you paid for that badge.
Speaker 0: Wouldn't worry about something so trivial, but they'll.
Speaker 0: they got you back.
Speaker 0: if you're worrying something about so trivial You're probably not cut out for enforcement.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but pax has got you back and forcing is great.
Speaker 1: I highly recommend if that thing is still open.
Speaker 1: when you listen to this and you're at all intrigued just go check it out.
Speaker 0: I guess the the gamers of Texas just aren't cool enough to enforce.
Speaker 1: Otherwise you Scott's YouTube channel does not have his new cooking show yet.
Speaker 0: Listen I was gonna add it some netrunner videos to edit to and You know even with working on it a whole bunch this weekend.
Speaker 0: I could not finish any of them.
Speaker 1: Why don't you pay like the listener to do it.
Speaker 1: multiple people have offered for a fee to edit your shit for you as there I haven't seen anyone.
Speaker 0: if you want it if you want me to send you piles upon piles and gigabytes upon gigabytes of raw videos of varying quality and then Arrange them into complete YouTube videos to put on my youtube channel I will pay you an amount of money to do that because it's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: and then You know I could pay you actually at minimum $40 a month because if I did not have to edit video I could reduce my Adobe subscription from the $50 a month one that has premiere to the $10 a month one that only has Lightroom and Photoshop.
Speaker 1: I Legit if someone wanted me to edit video for them would charge two hundred and thirty dollars an hour.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying $40 is enough.
Speaker 0: I'm saying that is the minimum amount of money that I have available minimum.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess it was just premiere like and not like super crazy shit.
Speaker 1: I'd probably only charge like on 150 an hour because 230 is like.
Speaker 0: but the other problem on Professional services rate the other problem is like there's only certain the stuff that I have to do like.
Speaker 0: I do a lot of dubbing Over and I can't have another person dub over because they don't know what I'm gonna say.
Speaker 1: Well you so you don't just want an editor you actually want a producer who's gonna be like Scott.
Speaker 1: I need you to say all this shit right now?
Speaker 0: Well, no because like I got to watch this thing like to make a netrunner video, right?
Speaker 0: So I got a video of a netrunner game.
Speaker 0: It's 20 minutes long.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I gotta watch it.
Speaker 0: That takes 20 minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then I got to watch it while talking.
Speaker 1: So why you gotta watch it the first time?
Speaker 0: just watch and go because I need to know What's gonna happen in the game in advance to so I don't miss out and talking about the good shit.
Speaker 1: So the way I do stuff like you can do a way better.
Speaker 0: Commentary on a sporting event if you've seen the sporting event already.
Speaker 1: so the way I do stuff like that because I do this with pretty much anything where I'm reading either reading from a script or I'm doing some sort of like ad hoc commentary on a thing that I might be watching is the first time I watch it.
Speaker 1: I do commentary anyway while I'm watching but I throw that away and then I do it again and do the commentary even still.
Speaker 0: So it's already a minimum of 40 minutes Not counting the editing time and all the other part.
Speaker 0: so it's like be a lot faster if you had a knob if the knob doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: So just like all of this is it take to make a 20-minute video takes me multiple hours and it's like on a weekend.
Speaker 0: That's really what I want to do.
Speaker 1: Oh How do you think all these YouTube videos of geek nights are?
Speaker 0: and the other problem is I shoot lots of video?
Speaker 0: And then even when I'm done like I'm not satisfied when I look at the video like the cooking one I'm like, uh, I maybe I'll change the way it's shot.
Speaker 1: You know, I thought your philosophy was fuck it just start spraying your internet all over.
Speaker 0: that is that's the philosophy that I wrote down on Paper, but I can't.
Speaker 0: actually it's hard to bring myself to do that.
Speaker 1: I have forced myself to do it Scott You saw that five minutes ago But you keep uploading a bunch of crap was really popular though And the people like crap that but you also like crap.
Speaker 1: But in terms of like the video of when you see my face just sitting there talking like yeah I can see exactly how I lit that scene the wrong way.
Speaker 1: But I said fuck it and just uploaded it instead of like waiting a month and then re-recording it.
Speaker 0: And then you upload piece of shit.
Speaker 1: I think it's better than you know.
Speaker 0: runner videos my non-existent.
Speaker 1: So anyway, it's computer buying.
Speaker 0: you had to have a hand with poop in it or an empty hand Depends.
Speaker 1: poop might be worth a non-zero amount of money depending on where what the context is.
Speaker 0: At least my hand don't stink.
Speaker 1: I think your hand stinks.
Speaker 1: no, it's just it's inside of a box.
Speaker 1: You haven't let it out into the world.
Speaker 1: No, so I almost bought a computer.
Speaker 1: like I was sitting at work today.
Speaker 1: I was like, you know what?
Speaker 1: Fuck it.
Speaker 1: I almost just did the thing where you take a new egg Wishlist and say add to cart and then you say bye in the car.
Speaker 0: Well, first of all nowadays, you can't be doing that because Amazon Especially when you're like me with the Amazon Prime and Amazon credit card Some things are cheaper and they are on Amazon.
Speaker 0: So you have to go through that cart and say and look up each item on Amazon You're gonna buy from Amazon and which ones you get for new egg.
Speaker 0: Here's the way I do that I put which is actually like I'm Upset that I have to do this because back in the day you could just trust that new egg was gonna be the best and Just do that.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm gonna have to do it now because as I keep refreshing this thing Things keep coming in and out of stock right now the CPU and motherboard.
Speaker 0: I want her out of stock.
Speaker 0: Oh not on Amazon.
Speaker 1: Maybe not the trouble with Amazon.
Speaker 1: You got to make sure who you're actually buying it from.
Speaker 0: You got to do that.
Speaker 0: a new egg - yeah new egg has the same issue.
Speaker 1: Yep, where there's third-party sellers on there Yep, I worry that Amazon's third parties are on the whole less reliable and less safe.
Speaker 0: Well, the ones that are Amazon's third-party sellers if they are fulfilled by Amazon are actually mostly safe Except you get a lot of counterfeit shit through there and that's what the problem.
Speaker 0: if I'm buying computer stuff though for a computer That's gonna last me five years.
Speaker 0: That is the most important thing that I own.
Speaker 0: I am making sure that I get everything legit brand new perfect.
Speaker 0: But what
Speaker 1: I do is I add the whole cart in the new egg like from the fluish list and then I go through each item and I look on Amazon and a couple other places and then I Slowly if I if I find it better on Amazon I delete it from the new egg cart add it to the other card.
Speaker 1: So when I'm at the bottom of the list, everything is in one of three shopping carts.
Speaker 0: So anyway, I was doing the same thing because my computer well, it's definitely got another year or more in it in terms of power In performance.
Speaker 0: It's been having some hardware blue screen crash type problems.
Speaker 1: And I read why did you break your computer?
Speaker 1: So you have to buy a new one.
Speaker 0: Why did my computer works fine?
Speaker 1: Your computer works fine.
Speaker 0: I reset way to reset windows.
Speaker 0: your computer has some issues.
Speaker 1: My computer's blue screening Some I got.
Speaker 1: my computer works fine.
Speaker 1: Which one?
Speaker 0: it blue screens occasionally, but it's like it's all good.
Speaker 1: It's still good.
Speaker 1: It's just a little bit blue.
Speaker 0: It's on this borderline where it's like the blue screen isn't so frequent that you can't use the computer But it's not so rare that it will never fuck you.
Speaker 1: your computer is blue screening at about the rate that the remember the computer The tall giant case I built like a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah that we did geek nights on with a resound forever.
Speaker 1: That thing would blue screen About once a month.
Speaker 0: This is a little more than that.
Speaker 1: So when it blue screen once a month Anytime you saw it blue screen you gave me easily 10 minutes of shit about how my computer is shit and I'm shit.
Speaker 0: I think I think the motherboard just messed up because it also If you if you bump it like you'll hear the USB like a doo doo doo doo doo doo Even though you didn't.
Speaker 1: I'm telling you USB headers are like the no cuz.
Speaker 1: so it worked today, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz I was telling you this and some other.
Speaker 1: multiple people have been talking about their computers having issues and a lot of them have fixed it or at least made it better by unplugging USB headers to their old case or Disabling all the USB ports.
Speaker 0: They're not using but anyway, so I was thinking well and it work.
Speaker 1: a dude literally.
Speaker 1: I watched him.
Speaker 1: he went over and got a new USB cable cuz like his was broken or something And he plugged it into his computer and then the computer just rebooted.
Speaker 1: He was like what and I looked over at him.
Speaker 1: I was like you should disable that USB thing on your case.
Speaker 1: It's probably dead.
Speaker 0: So anyway, I was I was gonna just replace the motherboard now Even though my CPU is great.
Speaker 0: It's an i7.
Speaker 0: It's great.
Speaker 0: My video card is a 680 which is not as good as newer video cards.
Speaker 1: Well, which I seven you have because you're that's Broadwell at best.
Speaker 0: probably I think it is as well.
Speaker 0: I think it's had something.
Speaker 0: it has something well, but it was like it was great.
Speaker 0: I think it has well It's 75% as good as the newest i7 of Lake or whatever.
Speaker 1: Cuz again, my my i7 is so much older than yours.
Speaker 0: mines three and a half gigahertz.
Speaker 0: It's fine.
Speaker 0: Anyway, mine's two point six six eighty is not a 1080 It's not a 980 but it's a 680 and it gets a job done.
Speaker 0: It's great.
Speaker 0: There's nothing wrong with it.
Speaker 0: So it's like I really just wanna play some motherboard.
Speaker 0: I cannot find a suitable replacement motherboard that is like trustworthy because it's a weird old socket from those days.
Speaker 1: so I used to have this philosophy the old days of I'd buy a computer with the eye of.
Speaker 1: I will upgrade many Components of it as it ages and that's still true.
Speaker 1: But there was a time when I expected to be able to do that with CPUs and I kind of expected that I wanted a socket Like I'd get the new socket or the new slot.
Speaker 1: remember when slobs were a thing?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right when it was new so I'd have the longest lifespan of that slot or socket.
Speaker 1: But now sockets don't last that long.
Speaker 0: every single CPU architecture has a new socket that goes with it.
Speaker 0: So you buy the fastest CPU that goes in that socket and then that's it.
Speaker 0: If when you want a new CPU get a new motherboard and you know what it didn't even work back then Cuz I got an.
Speaker 1: I got an Athlon k7 800 Least other things don't change 800 up to 933 and it worked great.
Speaker 1: But then it died and the motherboard died.
Speaker 1: like well the CPU was fine the motherboard died But then Thunderbird like the gigahertz came out and it went back to slots a socket instead of slot.
Speaker 1: So I was just fucked like you can.
Speaker 1: now you just got it.
Speaker 1: You can't worry about buying a new motherboard and replacing it with the after like six months.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about building a PC today.
Speaker 0: What's available on the market right now?
Speaker 0: It's sort of a weird time right.
Speaker 0: on the one hand things are on sale cuz it's Black Friday holiday season.
Speaker 0: This is a good time.
Speaker 0: Cyber Monday is today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but in terms of the big picture It's sort of a weird time because the kid would the.
Speaker 1: the Intel i7 6700 K quad-core Skylake has been the CPU to buy for over a year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like 16 months old and it's been the number one home desktop CPU you can get there isn't?
Speaker 1: There isn't a better one.
Speaker 0: there are faster better ones, but not for a normal person with a normal computer.
Speaker 0: There's only ridiculous nonsense extreme bullshit.
Speaker 1: If you search for desktop CPUs, there isn't one better.
Speaker 1: the best you could do That's maybe better is getting one that has more cores, but the clocks actually way slower if you do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well now there's like some Zia nonsense you could buy.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so yeah The same CPU has been the number one CPU for like 16 months and so early next year is gonna be the net.
Speaker 0: This is Skylake right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah So this is gonna be Kaby late, which is a tick.
Speaker 0: Kaby Lake is gonna come out early next year.
Speaker 0: supposedly, right?
Speaker 0: It's been delayed.
Speaker 0: From everything that people have said it is going to be effectively an insignia.
Speaker 1: Maybe Lake is beyond tick and talk there.
Speaker 1: It's not tick tock anymore.
Speaker 0: It's just weird, but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It is going to basically be insignificant.
Speaker 0: all reports are Insignificantly better.
Speaker 0: there won't be a reason to get a Kaby Lake versus.
Speaker 0: The only thing I've heard about like Kaby Lake is like oh if you have Netflix you can watch 4k if you have that.
Speaker 0: But well, that's it.
Speaker 1: The only thing I can see a Kaby Lake that actually might matter at all is that it might actually be faster in the gigahertz Because maybe kind of maxed out at four, but it's the same.
Speaker 0: that is the same nanometers and everything, right?
Speaker 1: But you know, but it has a better fab process.
Speaker 1: that Process and chip yields matters way more than you realize it uses.
Speaker 1: less power is a big part of it.
Speaker 0: It's not worth like waiting for this thing.
Speaker 0: No, no, it's not gonna be.
Speaker 0: you're not gonna get better more performance out of it.
Speaker 1: Here's where I might wait for it.
Speaker 1: If you were building a tiny HTPC.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that might matter.
Speaker 1: It's worth it to wait.
Speaker 0: Especially one without a video card.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz this shit is Real good if you don't have a video card.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But yeah, otherwise there don't say right after that is gonna be some other leak like at the end of next.
Speaker 1: coffee Lake is the next.
Speaker 0: no that one that's a weird one.
Speaker 0: That's not a normal one.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that is the oh I didn't.
Speaker 1: so I didn't look past Sky Lake cuz you know It's Kaby Lake is literally like as far as I could possibly think cuz my current computer literally cannot make it past Kaby Lake.
Speaker 1: But yeah, you're right.
Speaker 1: Coffee Lake is just yet more process optimization.
Speaker 0: No, but it's it's not enough for desktop CPUs.
Speaker 0: It's a weird.
Speaker 1: And Lake is the next one that is 10 nanometer and too far out to even think about right.
Speaker 0: So the 10 that's at the end of next year is gonna be or the early 2018 is like the next time there'll be a 10 nanometer process.
Speaker 0: So that will be a Significantly better CPU.
Speaker 1: also it will not.
Speaker 1: so there's been some updates there.
Speaker 1: Apparently there have been yield problems.
Speaker 1: Sure it.
Speaker 1: so When it comes out, they're only gonna have the low power versions as far as I can.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but the point is Your choice is to buy a CPU that's like over a year old which feels bad and isn't cheaper now than it was then or wait Over a year to get one that's significantly better.
Speaker 0: So it's like damn it.
Speaker 0: I don't want to buy this thing that feels old and obsolete but it's not gonna be old and obsolete for a whole nother year.
Speaker 0: But I usually buy computers every five years.
Speaker 0: Wait that if I can hold out and wait that year and get that 10 nanometer chip at the end of next 2017 early 2018 you know is gonna last five years for sure the but in the modern era thinking like that Like this is the longest plateau ever.
Speaker 1: I think in modern computer history le CPU wise and The what makes me full.
Speaker 1: if you just if you try to wait if you always if you go to Wikipedia and look at like Each architecture so cannon lake will come out and you're like, yeah, and I'm gonna get cannon leg But then you're gonna see Successor and you'll see what's coming out in just eight
Speaker 0: more months.
Speaker 0: No, that will be out.
Speaker 0: No, that is they're going so slow now, whatever comes after that is gonna be like years after that.
Speaker 1: I am dubious of the idea that cannon lake will be available in a high-performance high-power Consumption capability on desktops before the like third quarter.
Speaker 0: What's upsetting is that this i7 you can buy now the 6700 it's not cheaper.
Speaker 0: It's only 25% better than the i7.
Speaker 0: I've already got yes It's not even that much faster i7.
Speaker 1: My i7 is even older than it's.
Speaker 0: even older than mine is 2.6 gigahertz.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mine's three and a half.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it'll get up to three if I overclock it, right?
Speaker 0: So that's the CP.
Speaker 0: the state of CPUs is kind of sad and upsetting but the state of GPUs is the exact opposite.
Speaker 0: The 1080. the 1080 is the king.
Speaker 0: It's so much faster than every other video card that has come before.
Speaker 0: it is ridiculous.
Speaker 0: It's even lower power.
Speaker 0: It's just sick.
Speaker 0: It's insane.
Speaker 0: It just came out.
Speaker 0: It's like you cannot go wrong buying a 1080 or 1070 today.
Speaker 0: It is just like boom here.
Speaker 0: it is.
Speaker 0: It's super new relatively speaking and it's super powerful and it's expensive but with a good reason.
Speaker 0: now I am not going to 1080. that shit is gonna last you like six years.
Speaker 0: It's so strong.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna buy a 1080 right away because the only reason video cards not my bottleneck right now.
Speaker 1: I got a 770.
Speaker 1: It's doing okay.
Speaker 0: My 680 does just fine, right but it's like man.
Speaker 0: how that 1080.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's just so fucking but it's in my near-term horizon.
Speaker 0: I got a 1070.
Speaker 0: I'm a HTPC.
Speaker 0: It's just insane and I'm like damn if that's a 1070.
Speaker 0: What is the 1080 right?
Speaker 0: It must be like the video card of God.
Speaker 1: so we're at an interesting point in hard drives.
Speaker 1: so, you know if I feel bad because if I built this computer a year ago, I Basically could have paid mostly the same for the chip and like motherboard and RAM that I would get today That feels real bad.
Speaker 1: That means I could have paid the same and had a years of this computer already.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but hard drives have come a long way.
Speaker 1: They have m2 is a big deal Yeah, and way back like I found some old specs when I was speccing out PCs and I specced out this 256 gigabyte like m2 SATA drive that was just kind of bullshit, right?
Speaker 0: So so for you don't know, right?
Speaker 0: So we had regular old ID that's dead.
Speaker 0: s ATA is now every drive, right?
Speaker 0: Even is it a six?
Speaker 0: say the three dead right 60 gigabits per second.
Speaker 1: There's a to express and whatever.
Speaker 0: people are buying SSDs So we're not even worried about spinning magnets anymore.
Speaker 0: So that's what I have in my computer.
Speaker 0: I have SSDs with sata 6 gigabits per second and I didn't think about even going faster than that because like Disc speed hasn't been an issue because that's what I have right.
Speaker 0: but no M2 is basically this longish kind of rectangular.
Speaker 1: It looks like a RAM stick.
Speaker 1: basically plug it into the side, right?
Speaker 0: It's basically an SSD that's exposed and there's a one spot on the motherboard for it to go in and it some mother who if you get a fancy
Speaker 1: mother some
Speaker 0: motherboards it even goes underneath like especially if it's a micro ATX and it's like you know, it basically takes up no room doesn't have any cables doesn't need anything for the power supply and it's a Storage device.
Speaker 0: It's a SSD storage device here.
Speaker 1: Here's the two things that make this good.
Speaker 1: So now and there was some earlier confusion.
Speaker 0: It's like that's just.
Speaker 0: that's nice.
Speaker 0: But why is it so much more money than an S that?
Speaker 0: is that a standalone?
Speaker 0: Sata SSD.
Speaker 1: so if you get a crappy one, it's not better.
Speaker 1: It's just nicer.
Speaker 0: It's just nice that it's you know So much smaller and takes up less room.
Speaker 0: really good if you want to make a tiny PC and not have cables and stuff.
Speaker 1: So first let's back up a little bit.
Speaker 1: It used to be any SSD is better no matter what even if it's low-end.
Speaker 1: Nowadays low-end SSDs are pretty shit and like you look at benchmarks pay more for the better SSD.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Samsung one is like the king.
Speaker 0: Yeah the Samsung a Samsung is basically like conquered the world of storage in terms of solid-state storage because they had it conquered before Back in the day like you would if you buy like, you know an Apple iPhone.
Speaker 0: There's an SSD chip in there.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have a spinning magnet drive anymore.
Speaker 0: Right and guess who makes that fucking Samsung, right?
Speaker 0: You know, I ever since the iPod stopped having spinning magnet drives in it Samsung has been like the king of solid-state storage.
Speaker 0: So you can when I first built this which is why see gay and Western Digital and such are in trouble That now people are moving to solid-state storage.
Speaker 0: I paid spinning magnets.
Speaker 1: I paid almost four hundred dollars for a 32 gigabyte SSD to put my OS on.
Speaker 1: well now right now the Samsung 850 Evo is an SSD.
Speaker 1: you get a 500 gigabyte one for a hundred and sixty bucks.
Speaker 0: Damn, son.
Speaker 1: No, but they have a four Terabyte version.
Speaker 1: It's a thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: Let's see the two terabyte.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's still not it's you know, it's it's way.
Speaker 0: okay, the two terabyte is 620 it's still a lot.
Speaker 1: the one terabyte is 350 that's that's reasonable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like that's I could go for that if I was going high-end.
Speaker 1: However, that is a normal SSD using SATA, right?
Speaker 0: So the m2 drives have this advantage where if you put if you have one and your motherboard is right and your m2 drive is Right and you get the good ones Even though you plug it into the same hole on the motherboard you configure in the BIOS and whatnot properly It won't actually be an SATA device.
Speaker 0: It will be Considered by the computer a PCI Express device X4.
Speaker 1: I it's the max sequential read from this drive Two thousand five hundred megabits per second.
Speaker 0: I can't even imagine like how fat your computer will turn on.
Speaker 0: like boop It's on cuz it'll load so fast.
Speaker 0: you put like Photoshop on there.
Speaker 0: You know when you start Photoshop, it shows you this little splash screen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this splash screen will be there for like a fraction of a second cuz big boot loaded Like little.
Speaker 0: let you install a video game on there from steam has levels that take a long time to load.
Speaker 1: No boot loaded now.
Speaker 1: These drives are still too small.
Speaker 1: Like you don't want to put stuff on them You pretty much buy them to put your OS all your games all your applications on them.
Speaker 0: You can't there's not enough room on these to put anything else.
Speaker 0: But now if you put your OS and your applications you frequently used applications on there.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't put unfrequently used applications on there.
Speaker 0: Yes, you'll fill it up Like it.
Speaker 1: basically I'm gonna put your computer story games like another disk.
Speaker 0: things will be so fast You won't eat.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, it's crazy.
Speaker 1: And this is why this is crazy because right now the Samsung 950 Pro which not only does it do all the things Scott said But it is just like one of the higher performing SSDs out there m2 ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's 300 bucks That's pretty.
Speaker 0: that's pretty good for 512 gigs.
Speaker 0: You know, that's all you need.
Speaker 0: 512 is what I need for my OS and apps.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the 256 gig one is not significantly cheaper anymore.
Speaker 0: The only negative of it being 512 is that in steam.
Speaker 0: which steam has this feature?
Speaker 0: Luckily also battle net has it as well as you can tell it at Adobe Creative Cloud.
Speaker 0: Also, you can tell it where to put each individual app.
Speaker 0: So you have another drive and you might have to say alright install Photoshop on the m2 because I use that a lot.
Speaker 0: I don't use speedgrade a lot.
Speaker 0: You could install that on this SSD.
Speaker 0: That's a normal one and it'll load a little bit slower, but at least I won't fill up my m2 drive.
Speaker 0: So spinning this install install that game.
Speaker 0: I play every day civ6 on the m2 drive.
Speaker 0: So it loads fast.
Speaker 0: that game I'm gonna play once and then delete.
Speaker 0: you can put that on the SSD.
Speaker 1: so because I work with a lot of video all the time spinning to still have their use and I'd like to have something fast instead of a NAS and I'm you know I can't afford like a super expensive sand or anything crazy.
Speaker 1: Spinning discs for the things that they're useful for are also crazy cheap.
Speaker 0: They've been crazy cheap for a long time.
Speaker 0: But what they're getting bigger though?
Speaker 1: Yeah So here's the thing.
Speaker 0: right now my NAS is has four two terabytes ones.
Speaker 0: if I bought a NAS today It would have at least four four terabyte ones.
Speaker 1: So Western digital blacks are like the high-performance ones.
Speaker 1: They're not like 10,000 rpm like crazy bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those are just like high-end nice magnetic drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, five terabyte ones.
Speaker 1: You can get a pair of them.
Speaker 0: I don't trust five.
Speaker 0: I only trust even numbers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the six is way more expensive and the four is not cheaper enough.
Speaker 1: So the price point like the magic price point for these performance drives just happens to be five terabytes.
Speaker 0: Mmm, I don't try that.
Speaker 0: I don't trust five.
Speaker 0: It seems weird.
Speaker 0: Like is that?
Speaker 0: why does 60 big round number?
Speaker 0: I know you just gave me the big round number.
Speaker 0: I don't trust things that aren't even numbers right like for example that they gave me a loaner laptop at work today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it has 12 gigs of RAM and I'm like what?
Speaker 1: No That's an even number.
Speaker 0: It's not even power of two Sixteen thirty two.
Speaker 0: See none is twelve.
Speaker 1: this computer the geek night's rig has 12 gigs of RAM.
Speaker 0: No, that is not allowed.
Speaker 0: That's bad.
Speaker 1: In fact, you know what this RAM is.
Speaker 1: It's three-way interleave.
Speaker 1: There are six two gigabyte dims in there.
Speaker 0: That's ridiculous.
Speaker 1: Yeah this computer when I bought it was ridiculous.
Speaker 1: Do you know how fucking crazy you is have 12 gigabytes of RAM in this thing?
Speaker 0: That's stupid.
Speaker 0: I I don't trust weird numbers.
Speaker 0: It has to be the right number.
Speaker 0: something shady about a five terabyte drivers Like shouldn't it be a six or a four?
Speaker 0: So anyway, how did you get five?
Speaker 1: Let me see what the what the six actually costs.
Speaker 1: cuz I'm on the fives.
Speaker 1: cuz for 380 I can get two of these five terabytes.
Speaker 1: So the computer I'm building will have that sand that 950.
Speaker 0: crazy It's not entirely sure.
Speaker 0: I trust a one terabyte drive Even though that's an odd number.
Speaker 1: All right, the six terabyte one is 300 bucks by itself and not on sale.
Speaker 1: Okay, the five terabyte one is Hundred and ninety so it's two-thirds of the price for five.
Speaker 1: six of these Stuff the four terabyte one right now.
Speaker 0: So it's 33% off the money.
Speaker 1: the four terabyte one cost more than the five terabyte one.
Speaker 0: Something's shady with the five terabyte one.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's because of this psychological thing that I have.
Speaker 0: other people have it too and the five terabyte ones aren't selling.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's my sweet spot or there's something up with the five terabyte ones and I'm right.
Speaker 1: Well, it's got good eggs.
Speaker 1: But anyway, here's what I'm doing.
Speaker 1: This is the actual computer I'm gonna build.
Speaker 1: the the Samsung 950 Pro m2 crazy nonsense is gonna be my main drive for all maps.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna have the Samsung 850 a regular SATA drive for like all that B tier stuff and Adobe swap and Then I'm gonna have two of these five terabyte drives Mirrored for fucking everything else.
Speaker 0: What about your existing drives?
Speaker 1: I'm leaving them in the old computer.
Speaker 0: I Always bring my drives over.
Speaker 1: I'd used to and the problem is Every hard drive I've ever owned except the one that crashed is in this computer right now.
Speaker 1: There are like seven hard drives.
Speaker 0: Maybe though see right now in my computer.
Speaker 0: today, right?
Speaker 0: I got a 512 gig SSD.
Speaker 0: that's my main drive.
Speaker 0: then I got a one.
Speaker 0: Oh, I think it's actually 256. then I got a 128. that's like my you know Adobe swap and then I've got like two two terabyte drives and a four terabyte drive and even some like a 500 gigs Whole bunch of magnet drive.
Speaker 1: I got six drives two of which are SSDs in this computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's basically what I have right.
Speaker 1: so I'm done with that shit.
Speaker 1: I want one drive of store shit one drive of swap and one drive of applications.
Speaker 0: I might you know what if I can.
Speaker 0: it's gonna feel so good if I wait long enough to buy a new computer just one M.2 with everything.
Speaker 0: No, I might be able to get like a terabyte m2 and then like two terabyte.
Speaker 0: Like if I hold out long enough to those things become cheap, right?
Speaker 0: Like I can get big SSDs and then not have any magnets in my main computer.
Speaker 1: The thing is then you could probably get to like 12 terabyte magnets Mirror them and just store locally fucking everything for I probably still have some magnets.
Speaker 0: but the point is I would you know, like I can basically just get you know, even my like if it gets to the point where even a 512 gig SSD looks puny and I'll just get like yeah m2 One terabyte SSDs four terabytes each I get two of those bad boys.
Speaker 1: The thing is I said those four drives I'm buying right.
Speaker 1: that's actually kind of important because I was gonna get a bigger case The NZXT.
Speaker 1: there was this case that we looked at it packs.
Speaker 1: It was pretty good.
Speaker 0: Well, okay.
Speaker 0: So there's this case.
Speaker 0: you looked at it packs and it looked all gamery and ricey and I think it looked great.
Speaker 1: I think it looked like this cool.
Speaker 0: This is someone who likes, you know crappy internet.
Speaker 1: It looked like it was made of ceramic.
Speaker 1: Like it just looked really cool.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I went to look online at cases and this brand even though that case is ugly.
Speaker 0: They have another case.
Speaker 0: that actually is the first case.
Speaker 0: that made me look at the antique cases and usually it's antique all the way Because they are so reliable in the good cases, but they had this one.
Speaker 0: It's just a black sheet.
Speaker 0: The only thing it had was a window, which is not great.
Speaker 0: I'd rather have no window there, but if that's the only thing that's crummy about it is basically it looked like you know Monolith just perfectly black and smooth and I'm like damn son functionality was.
Speaker 1: the only difference between this and the case I was originally gonna get is that this one's actually way smaller But still ATX and it only holds four drive two SSDs and two two magnets.
Speaker 0: I actually can hold three drives inside underneath this like cover area.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I think you can spit one more like.
Speaker 0: It's a little tricky because I watch some YouTube videos and you have to like if you want to put the three drives under there It.
Speaker 0: basically this is a little hidey hole where the PS the power supply goes.
Speaker 0: You have to put those drives in first before you put the power supply it.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, it's gonna be a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you basically put your.
Speaker 0: you can either put three magnet drives or two magnet drives and an SSD under the hood And then there's two SSDs that go above the hood And then your m2 drive.
Speaker 1: So the other case had a lot of drive bays because my original plan when I first specked out the computer and five terabyte drive.
Speaker 0: This does not have a five and a quarter drive, but you cannot put an internal CD ROM in this.
Speaker 1: it does not have any External drive bays which means the front is smooth and baffled which actually solves a lot of noise problems.
Speaker 1: Yep, like that's actually Like we're deciding to have zero and it has the way it has.
Speaker 0: I put my computer, you know on the flow I don't put it up on the desk Yep.
Speaker 0: And this has its USB External headphone holes and stuff on the top facing straight up not at some angle not forward Straight up which is optimal for a computer that is on the ground Especially because it is shorter than the average ATX.
Speaker 0: But it has feet that are slightly taller to keep it up off the ground.
Speaker 0: Yes, but if you're not have a carpeted floor then the PSU is blowing straight down.
Speaker 0: That's really good.
Speaker 1: But this case just looks great and you're going along with it with the modern era of chips.
Speaker 1: The one thing about that Intel chips that it doesn't come with a fan anymore.
Speaker 0: So if you get an Intel chip these days some of them come with heatsinks with fans.
Speaker 1: only.
Speaker 0: the slower ones Those are the normal ones like the one I got in my HTPC is i5.
Speaker 0: it just came with a fan.
Speaker 0: it works great.
Speaker 0: But the ones with the letter K that means they're unlocked for overclock purposes Which and nowadays you don't even have to like.
Speaker 0: we're not talking about overclocking like tweaking and stuff and breaking your computer.
Speaker 0: This is like a supported overclock feature where you tell your motherboard Listen, just go as fast as you can go safely and it will just automatically go as fast as it can go safely as necessary Within the limits of cooling, you know You can
Speaker 1: still do the crazy tweaks and like up your ramp
Speaker 0: But you don't.
Speaker 0: you can just say auto overclock and it's a supported feature from Intel and As you just all you have to do is make your CPU cool and it will go as fast as it can go as needed.
Speaker 1: The result of this you pretty much need a radiator if you're gonna use your computer.
Speaker 0: These K unlocked CPUs do not come with a heatsink.
Speaker 0: You need to provide your own and you would like a quiet one and you would also like whether it's really good Because the better it is the more safer it's gonna be and you'll get more performance just by making it colder.
Speaker 1: So to keep these things cool in these small cases You would need this like with a traditional heatsink like what we're used to.
Speaker 0: you need some monster Monster.
Speaker 1: that's gonna be a pain in the ass inside of your case.
Speaker 1: the modern era liquid cooling is like mainstream.
Speaker 0: now It's a liquid cooling used to be this hack thing that you would do That would be really difficult and people would mess it up and get their computers wet or they?
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: It'd be hilarious and you wouldn't even go for that if you were unless you were way rich and could afford to break computer parts right.
Speaker 0: But nowadays they sell these completely contained systems where it's like there's a heatsink you put on the CPU just like normal and it has Two hoses coming out of it connected to a radiator.
Speaker 0: It's all connected in the box already.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's already filled with liquid already.
Speaker 0: Liquids not gonna come out and squirt you right and all you got to do is Put the radiator in the case and then put the heatsink on the CPU.
Speaker 1: now If you're a hobby and then you plug it in is done if you're a hobbyist or an overclock Like if you're.
Speaker 1: basically if you're like I was when I was in high school or early college You can be a little more efficient because some of the 1080 video cards because they're the same way if you cool and better They'll just work better.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So some of the 1080s come with radiators as well, but Putting one just on your CPU seems normal.
Speaker 1: Like that's what you do in modern computers.
Speaker 1: You don't want like three different things in your computer having their own radiators.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so at that point there you can buy system.
Speaker 1: basically that's where you do the hobbyist thing where you buy a pump and you basically wire one big cooling loop of All your different components and then put a giant radiator somewhere, right?
Speaker 0: So the way so the way you're supposed to do this is you get this radiator.
Speaker 0: So all the heat from the CPU is the.
Speaker 0: the liquid is being you know sent through right to this radiator.
Speaker 0: So now you need to cool the radiators that you're sending cold liquid back to the CPU.
Speaker 0: So you have the two fans at the front of your case are pulling cool air from outside the computer Over the radiator so that air heats up and then comes into the computer.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile the CPU a lot of these blow out as exhaust all the.
Speaker 0: I research this thoroughly.
Speaker 0: The way you want it to work is to blow the cold air in over the radiator.
Speaker 0: Like if you're driving a car the cold air at the front of the car comes into the radiator at the front of the car Right, and even though that brings hot air into where the engine is.
Speaker 0: that's how it's supposed to work right.
Speaker 0: you cool the radiator Right.
Speaker 0: So even though it's hot air in your case You have a fan on the top blowing up and you have a fan in the back blowing out.
Speaker 0: So that shits pretty much goes going straight out and the CPU doesn't even care about that hot air Because it's only touching this cold thing that's touching it.
Speaker 1: So in this case though, it does look like you mount that radiator in the top.
Speaker 0: Oh There's a top mounting one.
Speaker 1: That's where this one goes in this case.
Speaker 0: All the screenshots I'm looking at all everything that I looked at.
Speaker 0: the one is one that mounted in the front with two fans.
Speaker 0: I don't know which one you looked at the Kraken 61 like that mounts in the front.
Speaker 0: I watched YouTube videos that showed how to do it.
Speaker 1: I've seen multiple screenshots of this case with it mounted in the top.
Speaker 0: I've never seen such a thing.
Speaker 0: I looked at many things.
Speaker 0: it goes in the front.
Speaker 0: it probably won't even fit in the top because the top only has one fan hole and the That cooler is a two fan hole cooler.
Speaker 1: Oh wait that but that might be for the video card.
Speaker 1: There
Speaker 0: is a smaller one you can get that goes that is a single fan hole cooler and if you use that it which might be sufficient actually where the radiators only one fan hole big you could actually get a Video card cooler that is one fan hole big and put them both at the front like that.
Speaker 1: So I saw one set up that look cool.
Speaker 1: But this is again where you get into the part where maybe you should use up one full loop.
Speaker 0: I think getting a video card that has either the blower style cooler or the three fans is just fine.
Speaker 0: You don't really need the liquid cooling for that.
Speaker 1: So the review said that the 1080s that have the radiator are way quieter.
Speaker 0: I'm sure they are but I mean you're already.
Speaker 0: it's already gonna be so quiet You're not gonna even notice.
Speaker 0: so does it really need to be even quieter.
Speaker 0: There's three fans on there.
Speaker 0: They don't need to go that fast and there's three of them.
Speaker 1: Yep It's the.
Speaker 1: it's the one cooler sitting in the top in those screenshots, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just did a Google image search instead of looking on the end the website.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would get the two cooler because basically the thing is with these coolers is like they go with the case.
Speaker 0: I don't even know why they oh, yeah the moral of all this.
Speaker 1: whatever case you buy buy the coolers made by the same company.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz otherwise you can't trust that it's gonna fit or work properly.
Speaker 0: I don't know why they don't sell it as a package.
Speaker 0: Like why doesn't the case just already have this thing built into it?
Speaker 0: Why do they make you buy it separately?
Speaker 1: You know, here's here's the Corsair one that goes in the back.
Speaker 1: Look at this big chunky thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a little weird.
Speaker 0: I don't like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it looks kind of and you know the one that goes in the front It's like, you know, I think it's so much easier to work with right?
Speaker 0: Cuz it's a place where fans would already normally be.
Speaker 0: you're putting this thing Yeah out of the way.
Speaker 0: You know You just have these two cables coming across.
Speaker 0: the one that's big and chunky in the back is covering up like the back of your Motherboard.
Speaker 0: it's hard to get in there and do stuff.
Speaker 0: What if like this jumpers under there?
Speaker 1: Oh my god This is the worst.
Speaker 1: This is if you've got so you have a big radiator.
Speaker 1: This is sticking off of the CPU.
Speaker 1: It's directly on the CPU.
Speaker 1: You have this giant radio.
Speaker 0: It's creating a wind tunnel Yep, and a fan on it inside the case.
Speaker 0: That's a little weird.
Speaker 0: plus I mean 120 millimeter fans are so big that they're quiet and a lot of cases now these days are even having fans even bigger Than that, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Also, I can't tell you my htbc that I built recently I bought like these slightly more expensive fancy highly rated fans and They're just better.
Speaker 0: they are better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're slight they're not super better, but they're better.
Speaker 0: You know, they came with like these extra bits and they were super smooth, okay here I found an example of this.
Speaker 1: guy's got his g-force is 1080 and his CPU Both going to a front radiator and he has a separate pump.
Speaker 0: See, that's a cut.
Speaker 0: That's that's nonsense.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna have one of these reservoirs.
Speaker 1: Yeah my computer.
Speaker 0: It's not happening.
Speaker 0: It's not an out-of-the-box solution.
Speaker 0: The point is you want for cooling you want an out-of-the-box solution that is guaranteed to be compatible with your other bits.
Speaker 0: Are there any other computer parts?
Speaker 0: we gotta discuss the only other.
Speaker 1: so that's my whole computer except PSU.
Speaker 1: just use one of those calculators and then like Whatever like, you know, it's like five fifty six fifty seven fifty.
Speaker 1: Whatever one is above your number.
Speaker 1: I mean, let's real close that realistically.
Speaker 0: realistically people are buying psu's that are way more powerful than they need or I think some Of those psu's are like falsely advertising how powerful they are.
Speaker 0: The point is even for a computer with like the newest i7 and a 1080 and a bunch of drives and a bunch of USB devices like a 650 is already overkill.
Speaker 0: Five fifty is gonna get the job done very very nicely.
Speaker 0: 758 59 a 650 is like safety zone just because you just you just feel safer with more power.
Speaker 0: But like you don't even need that five 50 or an 850. if you have one ally with two video cards
Speaker 1: if I'm doing SLI and I have a custom cooling rig that requires More power or
Speaker 0: if you've got like really like a ton of drives Like you have a giant case and the whole front is just filled with drives Yeah, then you might need 750. but like 850 950 a thousand.
Speaker 0: I see these things on.
Speaker 0: like that people are buying.
Speaker 0: there is no reason to buy that.
Speaker 0: You're just.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you're wasting your electric bill because it might not pull more electricity than it needs from the wall.
Speaker 0: But there's no reason you're spending more money on the power supply for no reason just because you like bigger numbers Motherboard.
Speaker 1: so the aces Z170s are pretty much fine, right?
Speaker 0: So if you're getting the K CPU with the auto overclocking you need to get the z170 Chipset on the motherboard or it won't work.
Speaker 0: I think the Can't choose any other Chipsets.
Speaker 0: you have to get a motherboard with that chipset and it's hard to tell which motherboard is the best.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the reviews on this aces are 50% of them are.
Speaker 1: this is amazing and the other 50% are.
Speaker 1: it came do a guy.
Speaker 0: So it's like every motherboard no matter how highly rated on.
Speaker 0: Newegg is like.
Speaker 0: it seems like a perfect motherboard on paper But a whole bunch of reviews are like this thing just totally didn't work.
Speaker 0: I had to send it back or it worked for a while.
Speaker 0: then it broke and it's like man.
Speaker 0: the thing I'm looking for is Stability.
Speaker 0: I got a blue screen and computer and you're telling me to sell me a motherboard.
Speaker 0: We're half the people who buy it have it like messing up and not working.
Speaker 1: It seems like they don't mess up subtly anymore.
Speaker 1: It's either it's fucking broken or it's perfect, right?
Speaker 0: So you might have to buy more than one.
Speaker 0: and if you buy a Newegg right now not we're not Sponsored by Newegg or Amazon by the way, but Newegg does have like a super bonus holiday return policy.
Speaker 0: That's different from the regular holiday return policy.
Speaker 0: So it's a good time to buy because of that even if you missed a Black Friday sale or something.
Speaker 1: now There's a bunch of variance on this like even in this aces like there's a pro gaming version and a deluxe version and a saber-tooth All the same thing with all motherboards.
Speaker 0: get one that has the connectors you need in the size you need and ignore all that other Nonsense, right?
Speaker 1: Yep I mean like.
Speaker 1: so the one that's interesting is the tough one the saber-tooth because it's basically got this big heatsink over the entire Motherboard.
Speaker 0: it just looks fancy.
Speaker 0: that doesn't do shit.
Speaker 1: So look at the reviews of those things and read the text and you'll see the true story.
Speaker 0: For example, this one that looks like it makes it hard to work with.
Speaker 1: Yep, the reviews are one hard to work with - oh my god That thing's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: to get off if you have a problem and drop a screw in there.
Speaker 1: three I dropped a screw in there.
Speaker 0: What the fuck do I do?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there is if you if you're mega mega rich they do have this Republic of Gamers equipment, right?
Speaker 0: That's like.
Speaker 0: this is for the people who are just like ah fuck.
Speaker 0: I don't even give a shit about money, right?
Speaker 0: And it looked basically just like you're paying a bunch of money for nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, five hundred dollar motherboard, but it did have like twelve USB three ports on the back Which is like I need that.
Speaker 0: you know how many devices I have right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I need that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like right now all I had to buy a USB PCI Express card to add four more ports to the computer I have.
Speaker 1: now I like a son.
Speaker 1: I got USB 2 on this computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it said the other.
Speaker 0: that's it is something I want to mention though.
Speaker 0: all these new motherboards, right?
Speaker 0: They have USB twos because you might as well.
Speaker 0: Yes They have USB threes and they have enough of them that you can get your front ports and rear ports.
Speaker 0: and who has that?
Speaker 0: many USB three devices.
Speaker 1: They'll always have like one You can plug your keyboard and mouse in the USB - you know I gotta plug mine into a three because I want to have this three hub on the top.
Speaker 0: Oh, you got a hub.
Speaker 0: Okay, make sense, right?
Speaker 0: This guy's plugging into a - but all of these computers have one USB 3.1 port and one USB C port and I feel like That feel like those probably work just fine, but I work like your USB 3 work, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I feel like maybe you would since USB C is definitely gonna be a thing.
Speaker 0: It won't be.
Speaker 0: I mean Apple jumped at.
Speaker 0: jump the gun of it for sure.
Speaker 0: But if you buy a motherboard a year or year and a half from now it's gonna have like four USB C's on the back or maybe even six and you're gonna want them in the front - and These that doesn't do it today.
Speaker 0: so You know that could be an issue.
Speaker 0: where sure even if your performance and power of a computer you buy today is just fantastic And doesn't go obsolete for five six years because it that's just how things are.
Speaker 0: You might be sad in a year from now when you start buying a new phone and New other things that are all USB C and you have a bunch of USB C to USB 3 adapters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz you can't plug that many USB C things into your computer that only has one hole.
Speaker 1: You can't wait for that stuff.
Speaker 0: You can't even reach it can't wait for that stuff Forever you can't.
Speaker 0: but some you know, if you're on depending on your schedule It might be worth it to wait for that if you can.
Speaker 1: so the last thing I need to buy None of you need to buy is I need a firewire adapter.
Speaker 0: No one needs that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like even to this day all the good per audio equipment like Mackie like all these mixers.
Speaker 1: There isn't a USB option It's just firewire.
Speaker 0: Can you get like a USB to firewire?
Speaker 1: No, so the reality of the world is that Most manufacturers of this stuff won't help you and will give vague advice.
Speaker 0: What can?
Speaker 0: I just ask him what computer they have that they're plugging it into a computer that has native firewire.
Speaker 0: Which computer is that?
Speaker 1: Usually it's old shit computers.
Speaker 1: Okay, get like this computer has firewire on the motherboard.
Speaker 1: My age is T PZ over.
Speaker 1: there has firewire on the mother.
Speaker 0: my old my computer has a firewire and so it is my old Htpc.
Speaker 1: So the real problem is that low-end firewire cards are the shittiest shit that ever shed out of a poop shit Like they like those Roseville ones.
Speaker 0: Why not just get like the old MacBook for super cheap That's super good and use that for the audio bits because I use this audio for things like live-streaming, too Like this mix.
Speaker 1: the reason I have this mixer.
Speaker 0: you could live.
Speaker 0: you could live stream from an old Mac with.
Speaker 1: Oh, I can't actually to do what I want to do.
Speaker 1: I need if I need like a current like 3 gigahertz CPU minimum and you know It's not.
Speaker 0: plenty of people did live streaming with shittily.
Speaker 1: I want to plug multiple HD webcams in.
Speaker 1: I got shit I got plans for.
Speaker 1: But the thing is I'm really like I have this giant wedge for that because I use a lot of the stuff in it Like I can really gives me a lot of control for live streaming recording video and all this nonsense.
Speaker 1: So I need if I knew I want to plug this firewire device into my computer because if I can't plug this mixer into my Computer, I'm just not gonna have a mixer anymore.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna get one of those USB 3 or 3.1 or whatever like input devices and that'll be the end of that era.
Speaker 1: Mmm, I really like having this as my sound card.
Speaker 1: So TI seems to make the chipset that has the most likelihood of working.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it'll just work.
Speaker 0: I bought like that USB 3 card.
Speaker 0: I bought that goes in the tiny PCI.
Speaker 0: Just work.
Speaker 1: so firewire cards will just work.
Speaker 1: if you plug hard drives into them if you plug audio or video equipment It's just Russian roulette.
Speaker 0: I don't see any reason why it wouldn't work.
Speaker 1: I have plugged this mixer into multiple Rosewill firewire adapters for my laptop and It just doesn't work.
Speaker 1: like the Mackie drivers just won't find it like it.
Speaker 1: just you cannot use it as a sound card or all the channels won't show up or It'll drop audio because most firewire cards are reportedly implemented.
Speaker 1: You need a good firewire card.
Speaker 1: I found eventually after buying three a firewire card from my laptop that works, but it uses that saw that Express slot that is also now obsolete.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I found this $40 sig firewire card that one person on the internet In a forum thread from two years ago said they plugged the same mixer.
Speaker 1: I have into it and it works.
Speaker 1: So well, it's a $40 experiment Mmm, so yeah, it's computer buying season.
Speaker 0: That's how you buy a computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you basically you plan 2017. you kind of forget how like.
Speaker 1: the details like.
Speaker 1: I don't know the details of like which motherboard which chips like.
Speaker 0: we didn't talk About RAM, but it's like you can go listen to our old episode.
Speaker 0: It's like any DDR4 RAM.
Speaker 0: buy whatever is the most eggs the RAM that's like the higher like right now.
Speaker 0: I think 2133 is like the base speed DDR4 RAM that goes.
Speaker 0: Some people are trying to sell you on like two six six six or thirty two hundred.
Speaker 1: this two six six six I'm gonna get is cheaper than the 2133 from the same company and you might as well get it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's no the.
Speaker 0: everything I can tell is that on the newest computers that we're talking about Overclocking the RAM doesn't really get you anything.
Speaker 0: You will not notice it will not matter.
Speaker 0: You won't get extra frames, right?
Speaker 0: You might as well just even if you buy faster RAM because it's cheaper might as well run it at 2133 Yep, or just let the computer do whatever it wants because it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Yep some of these motherboards like in the BIOS you can be like you're doing overclock me a little bit if you spend even if you're Crazy, and you're spending the $500 on the crazy motherboard to get 12 USB ports, right?
Speaker 0: Spending $500 on the RAM sticks to get 64 gigs of RAM?
Speaker 0: first of all 64 gigs of RAM is stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: You can get 32 now and if you need 64 later on You're making an HDPC.
Speaker 1: get 1x32 and stick it in one of your two dim slots or any mother, you know 2x8.
Speaker 1: Now cuz you only know six small motherboards almost always have two.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: If you're getting a real motherboard get a 2x16 and then you can get 2x16 more.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz 2x16 is significantly cheaper than 1x32.
Speaker 1: That's right now Yep, and don't get 8888 cuz then you're gonna want to get more RAM like two years from now when RAM cost a dollar.
Speaker 0: Also, it's like people talk about like quad channel, but it's like I looked at and it seems like even the newest motherboards They're all just dual channel only.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they don't do quad channel or triple channel or whatever.
Speaker 1: So a caveat cuz I've seen some people get this wrong.
Speaker 1: if you have some DDR3 lying around it will not Fucking work with the modern Intel chips.
Speaker 0: You are your shit.
Speaker 0: You need DDR4 for sure.
Speaker 1: Yes, now there's confusion because there's a bunch of literature saying DDR3 will work.
Speaker 1: That is true in a very specific situation.
Speaker 1: that I guarantee does not apply to you Right,
Speaker 0: but yeah You don't try to overclock like if you spend a bunch of money to get the crazy fast RAM like 3600 speed RAM You just wasted a whole bunch of money and a whole lot of nope
Speaker 1: But if you have what you think is perfectly good RAM from your previous computer do not
Speaker 0: put it in a new computer.
Speaker 1: We switch from three to four.
Speaker 1: three won't work in four.
Speaker 1: In fact three pulls so much voltage you might break your motherboard.
Speaker 0: whenever you buy a motherboard Look and see what RAM the motherboard wants and buy that RAM.
Speaker 1: do not buy any other Rams and do a quick Google search for The exact RAM you're buying and the exact motherboard you're buying because there's a chance you'll find a forum thread where someone says the shit Didn't work.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Usually the motherboard manufacturers website has like a list of approved RAM brands.
Speaker 1: Buy one of those.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons in order the amount of money they give us on a continuing basis are Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunne, Nicholas Brando, Heidi McNichol, Amanda Duchette, Construction Noises, Ivy Faye, MyStacy.com, William Eisenrose, Jeremy Miner, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: Christian Koontz, Hahn Reimer, and Chris Thomas, Shervin Von Horl, Iggy Kid, Rare Lavelle, James David White, Rachelle Montanona, Superboy, A Playground With No Kids, Erin Cerise, Brian Fisher, SailorVista, JFriedPork, Matthew Smith, Don Schleich, Jar Tovishan, Joe Shorjostar, Tyler Eller, Sean Yeager, Sam Cordray, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openladder, Brian Cedroni, Finn Eric Silveron, Redacted, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: Back from the holidays, mostly on our regular schedule.
Speaker 1: I just recorded another Castlevania 2 Simon's Quest And I also just mastered another beta episode of Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: So anyway, now I leave you with something.
Speaker 0: It's a piece of cake to bake a pretty cake.
Speaker 0: If the way is hazy You gotta do the cooking by the book.
Speaker 1: You know you can't be lazy.
Speaker 1: Never use a messy recipe.
Speaker 0: The cake will end up crazy.
Speaker 1: If you do the cooking by the book Then you'll have a.
Speaker 0: Break it down bitch.
Speaker 0: Let me see you back in love.
Speaker 0: Drop that ass down low and pick that motherfucker up.
Speaker 0: Break it down bitch.
Speaker 0: Let me see you back in love.
Speaker 0: Drop that ass down low and pick that motherfucker up.
Speaker 0: Now pack that pussy, she's a motherfucker.
Speaker 0: Hey pack that pussy, she's a motherfucker.
Speaker 0: It's a piece of cake to bake a pretty cake.
Speaker 1: If the way is hazy You gotta do the cooking by the book.
Speaker 1: You know you can't be lazy.
Speaker 1: Never use a messy recipe.
Speaker 1: The cake will end up crazy.