Speaker 0: It's Monday July 25th 2016.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: the right to repair and the DMCA and all that nonsense in Still a problem.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: It was raining so hard that when I got off the salt like I was on the subway in the seven train after like ridiculous Delays and like people crammed in everywhere I basically only got on the car because I sort of Shoved people out of the way and elbowed my way on there wedged myself in a corner.
Speaker 0: But then when the train came out of the tunnel into the daylight into the wall of rain the rain hit the subway car so hard that people in the car kind of went like ah and everyone sort Of reacted in a surprising and shocked fashion, which I've never seen people do on the subway before.
Speaker 1: so it was nice and clean.
Speaker 0: Yeah, nice and air-conditioned car wash.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm actually impressed at how well all the air conditioning and that system is working considering We're riding relatively new train cars even though you saw they're gonna get all new new train cars soon.
Speaker 1: with the bumbleweeds I thought they were just modifying existing cars to put little thingies in between.
Speaker 0: hard to say because the Story looks like I think they're gonna take the oldest rolling stock and replace it with the ones that'll have the sort of articulated Open framework and less seats.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you always assume the newest cars replaced the oldest cars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except apparently I guess the C train will never get anything replaced.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: the C train has the word the oldest worst rolling stock in the entire system then aren't isn't that first in line to get?
Speaker 1: Replaced?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: the C trains weird - they're shorter than the other trains.
Speaker 0: Okay, you know what you don't know about the C. Have you ever ridden the C on purpose?
Speaker 1: I've ridden other blue I don't know.
Speaker 1: I've ridden blue trains, but I've never ridden a blue train where it mattered which one I took unless it was the e.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, the e is the useful one.
Speaker 0: the a is the a one.
Speaker 1: unless you're going to Brooklyn like if I'm taking a blue Train it's either.
Speaker 1: I need the e or I need any blue train.
Speaker 1: Yep I don't think and I don't know which one I'm on.
Speaker 0: I'll bet you haven't ridden any train cuz the train kind of sucks like a lot of e trains to go to the no.
Speaker 0: No, sorry the C. The C. You're probably never ridden.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've just if I have I didn't you know see is notably shitty Okay, but anyway, so I was in the beach this weekend and something strange happened.
Speaker 0: I was at Russo's, you know that place like we always do standing there with Emily we're waiting for our Russo sandwiches to get finished by the ladies behind the counter and Suddenly and what looks like an employee of Russo's Wearing a Santa hat walk.
Speaker 1: I had to head in July
Speaker 0: walks up to us holding a bunch of things that they call sand scrapers that are like this as-seen-on-tv thing to get sand off your feet and
Speaker 1: Three and stupid big
Speaker 0: blocks of Boar's Head cheese Like wrapped up packaged Boar's Head cheese, and they're like Merry Christmas and they hand it to us.
Speaker 0: They handed you free cheese like three huge blocks of cheese and these Expired.
Speaker 0: it expires next year.
Speaker 0: Like it's fine.
Speaker 1: Why didn't they give it to the units to everybody?
Speaker 0: So we're looking at her and Emily's like, oh, no, thanks, you know, cuz like you do when someone's more you Yeah, and gives you cheese.
Speaker 0: that is either a scam or they stole that cheese.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: We don't want that.
Speaker 1: What is going on?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they're like, it's Christmas in July.
Speaker 0: It's free.
Speaker 0: You can take it.
Speaker 0: and then I noticed that there's other Russo's people walking around giving everyone in the store like three or four Giant blocks of cheese all like so big you need your own deli slicer to cut it.
Speaker 0: No, like half a pound or a pound each.
Speaker 1: So like the kind of block you would buy in the grocery.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like a grocery store block, but that's a lot of free cheese.
Speaker 0: when I get free cheese It's always like a tiny free cheese and Boar's Head is like middle-of-the-road cheese.
Speaker 0: So We were so skeptical that we engaged in like a minutes worth of conversation like, okay This is free.
Speaker 0: You're just giving me this cheese.
Speaker 1: Alright, where did this cheese come from?
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: And then later on we finally get her food.
Speaker 0: as we're leaving I see them walk up to this lady and they're like free cheese and they gave her way better cheese than they gave us.
Speaker 0: and She was like, no, no, no, no, no, and they're like, it's free and she's like and she was just as scap as we were.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got a better way to give away your free cheese.
Speaker 1: then just walk up to people with a Santa hat But I noticed behind them they had giant boxes of cheese and you should also give people a reason you're giving them free cheese.
Speaker 0: Oh, the reason was Christmas in July.
Speaker 1: That's not a good reason.
Speaker 1: Where do they get a money to buy all that cheese?
Speaker 1: for no reason?
Speaker 0: so in the background I see one of the employees is standing there looking at another one and they have one of these giant boxes Of cheese open and I see tons more boxes that are obviously cheese.
Speaker 1: Where did that?
Speaker 1: where did the boxes come from?
Speaker 0: and one of them is like them?
Speaker 0: So you're just giving away all this cheese and the other employee just laughs and is like Christmas in July.
Speaker 1: So Was it a mistake in delivery?
Speaker 1: Was it stolen cheese?
Speaker 1: Was it mafia cheese?
Speaker 1: So on the person who owns Russo's just so wealthy.
Speaker 1: They bought you that much though on the B. Why cheese?
Speaker 1: you could have bought something better than she.
Speaker 0: when I go for my run There's one group of people that are set up on the beach, you know, but they're like beach towels and everything but the beach towels all have snowmen on them and they put up Christmas lights and shit.
Speaker 0: and Then while we're laying on the beach Parade drove by in cars on the beach of a bunch of bro-looking people playing Christmas songs and singing Christmas carols while wearing swimsuits and Santa hats.
Speaker 0: and Apparently it was just.
Speaker 0: it was Christmas in July in Wildwood and I can only assume that the cities of Wildwood's just gave all the businesses incentives to do Christmas in July or something and We just came home and gave all the cheese.
Speaker 0: Let's go to.
Speaker 0: his parents were like, hey, we bought you some cheese for the house Thanks for letting us stay here.
Speaker 0: and they were like, oh, thanks.
Speaker 0: They were really excited.
Speaker 0: Hey, it was free, you know his parents.
Speaker 1: Yes, you chose.
Speaker 1: you went shopping to buy me a present and you bought three blocks of cheese.
Speaker 0: I think if I gave them anything they would be excited.
Speaker 0: if nothing else they try to sell it at that garage sale.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying to be like if someone came up to me.
Speaker 1: It was like got your present three blocks of cheese.
Speaker 1: They'd be like, where did you get this free cheese for?
Speaker 0: We were like Russo's and they were like we got it from Russo's for you and they were like awesome Thanks.
Speaker 0: and then she immediately caught one of them up to like feed Kaylee make a snack for herself and kept the other two because That was that was how that went down.
Speaker 0: And Okay, yeah, I believe me I am.
Speaker 0: it's interesting watching New Yorkers interact with any human being.
Speaker 0: whoever talks to them especially offering something like my shields are so strong at this point that a literal like magical godlike Savior of humanity could come down do magic in front of me and offer me gold and I would be like.
Speaker 0: I don't really want to talk to you.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: Avoiding.
Speaker 0: I can't act like trying to get around them in the street.
Speaker 0: Yeah, got any news.
Speaker 1: So I guess the news of the day is that Verizon bought Yahoo's core business.
Speaker 1: So what does that even fucking mean?
Speaker 0: once valued at a hundred and twenty five billion like Yahoo's web assets were sold to Verizon for?
Speaker 0: 4.8 billion, right?
Speaker 1: So Yahoo the US company Consisted of a a bunch of internet shit like Yahoo Sports Yahoo weather Yahoo websites Yahoo Finance flicker etc.
Speaker 1: Etc.
Speaker 1: right it consisted of an investment in Alibaba Like 15% of Alibaba.
Speaker 0: Yeah no, you guys gonna realize how incestuous all these companies actually are.
Speaker 1: like a lot of companies own big chumps like when you buy if you buy a Percent of Yahoo, you're actually buying one over 15% of Alibaba.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so it also Yahoo US owns 35 and a half percent of Yahoo Japan Which is actually a separate company.
Speaker 1: that's actually successful.
Speaker 1: Yep So basically all the parts of Yahoo America us that weren't Investments and other things that were just web stuff God sold to Verizon for like five billion dollars.
Speaker 0: Apparently they tried to include the Alibaba stuff And the only reason they couldn't according to these articles is that they were afraid they'd pay more taxes if they did So anyway, so Yahoo is basically split into two parts.
Speaker 1: one is just a company That's nothing but investments like all right like a holding company and the other part is the operating company Which like he does things like software and websites Which is the part that Verizon bought.
Speaker 1: and Verizon already bought AOL for a similar amount You know a while ago.
Speaker 1: So and you think just the web part of AOL and just the part of Yahoo that actually do internet stuff, right?
Speaker 1: Like Yahoo mail AOL mail pretty equivalent in value pretty close, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if there is one company I trusted the least to do anything with those assets is Verizon.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean not the least but it's way down there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not a highly trusted operation.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, that's probably bad.
Speaker 1: if you use any Yahoo things and I actually use a few Yahoo things I'm
Speaker 0: probably the one that the only one that I actually worry about is flicker because flicker is like the core of my photograph sharing and archiving technology Mmm, like I use flicker like as my 100% core workflow.
Speaker 0: I process stuff through Lightroom, but in the end the actual photos I put them all on flicker because that's how I share them.
Speaker 0: That's what I use it for.
Speaker 1: I highly doubt they'll kill it, but it could be like Verizon flicker and it could you know could just get bad.
Speaker 1: It'd be covered in ads and turn shitty.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's other options.
Speaker 0: The only the only thing is all the stuff that's happened over the years.
Speaker 0: flickers just remained Mostly running.
Speaker 0: it has some problems like occasionally old photos just won't load for a while And then they float again like a couple days later.
Speaker 1: I never seen that.
Speaker 0: a lot of people complain about that.
Speaker 0: That's a really common problem that's been going on for a couple years now.
Speaker 1: You can always use smug mug.
Speaker 1: It's not free.
Speaker 0: But you know this Lakers not free.
Speaker 1: this I mean, but it's a way, you know, there's a lot of choices Yeah, but flicker is the best of them still so far.
Speaker 0: Sure Let's see how this all goes down.
Speaker 0: This is a situation where I would be much more worried about the antitrust and neutrality aspects of this?
Speaker 1: No, I'm not.
Speaker 0: well see the thing is yeah, I am worried would be if Yahoo wasn't already like this sinking ship Well tethered to another.
Speaker 1: I'm.
Speaker 1: obviously if I was in charge of antitrust I wouldn't allow this but they already allowed NBC Comcast.
Speaker 1: So it's like well, this is way less bad than that.
Speaker 1: So Really?
Speaker 1: They should not allow a company period any corporation in the United States or anywhere to do more than one thing Period.
Speaker 1: that's how it would be One thing.
Speaker 1: well, for example, if you're McDonald's you sell you you make food and sell food, right?
Speaker 0: What if I make video games and social media software?
Speaker 1: No, you shouldn't be allowed to do that.
Speaker 0: What's the difference?
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: what's the difference?
Speaker 1: what's the difference between making two different kinds of things?
Speaker 0: what defines what a kind of thing is?
Speaker 0: It's just software Me.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah businesses You can't make clothing and food.
Speaker 0: It's so different.
Speaker 0: self-driving cars because that requires lots of software that is also used for very very different things.
Speaker 1: You're basically saying because this is semantic issue of defining.
Speaker 1: What's a different thing?
Speaker 1: You're gonna get it you're gonna let it stop you from.
Speaker 1: You know the common-sense definition of what.
Speaker 0: I would go much more simply and say that mergers of companies that are above a certain size are met with extreme Skepticism and the more disparate their assets are the higher the bar.
Speaker 1: I can actually even go so far as to say we should not allow a company to exist with assets greater than X Period and it's a company becomes greater than X Even if it does only one thing
Speaker 0: how to pull split
Speaker 1: it into two companies that both do the counter
Speaker 0: point.
Speaker 0: a lot of the Things we use probably would never been created if there weren't companies that had that much asset under control.
Speaker 0: Maybe maybe not like a lot of the good lot a lot of stuff Google did we really just never been done ever?
Speaker 1: Maybe maybe not?
Speaker 0: probably not not unless you had governments doing it and you know, that's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: I'm okay, you know You never know just saying you're uh, you're overly simplistic.
Speaker 0: views on this are in contrast with my much more nuanced views And more nuanced view isn't necessarily better.
Speaker 0: You you fall to the folly of the shortest path.
Speaker 1: Shortest path is a quick path.
Speaker 0: Yeah quick path to the opposite of salvation either literal damnation or suicide.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll see welcome we're reading the Prince of Nothing books again, so watch out for they just made a new one.
Speaker 1: I Took a short path right to the end of that book.
Speaker 1: I'm I got there faster than rim with my short path.
Speaker 0: I took a shorter path because I didn't even read orgs and Craig because I was reading this first But instead of finishing the book at the beach.
Speaker 0: I just laid there at the beach.
Speaker 0: So I embraced the zero guy For a little while.
Speaker 0: So you're damned as well, this is a totally side news, but remembers it.
Speaker 0: remembers of car?
Speaker 1: They're still around I guess but they have a lot of competition now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I've decided like I haven't used that car in a while.
Speaker 1: He's still paying the fee.
Speaker 0: Well, the fee is $70 a year.
Speaker 0: So it's basically nothing but nothing.
Speaker 0: that's a whole video game a brand To video games, but I was paying for it because I used it.
Speaker 0: But I haven't used it at all this year and I'm gonna cancel it like tonight.
Speaker 0: like I decided a zip car is fucking dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the reason is zip car is literally worthless.
Speaker 0: It is worse than every other option now.
Speaker 0: So the reasons I used to use zip car were one I don't want to talk to human beings and deal with them trying to sell me bullshit.
Speaker 0: I just want to rent a car Yeah, - I just want to know a set price of what the car takes and just go pick it up with technology.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm three.
Speaker 0: I pretty much want to pick up a car near my house Like I'll go to my house pick up the car.
Speaker 0: That way I can rent it for the exact period of time I need.
Speaker 0: it's like I pick it up Friday after work drive to the beach I drop it off Sunday at like 10 o'clock at night and I only pay for that time.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and that was great.
Speaker 0: But and back then it was cheaper than rental cars or at least the same cost as a rental car.
Speaker 0: free gas Yeah or it caused more than rental car but the free gas and all the other things evened it out or the Convenience was worth the slight difference in price.
Speaker 0: Over the last couple years the prices of zip car have gotten up to where you know what?
Speaker 0: It would have cost for me to rent the cheapest possible zip car for the weekend last weekend to go to Wildwood hundreds four hundred and seventy eight dollars Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So now outside of New York, I could rent a car for the weekend for like Sixty bucks, but it's New York.
Speaker 0: So the cheapest I could get was 200 bucks.
Speaker 0: The problem is if I rent from a non zip car place You have to rent it from somewhere that won't let you drop it off on Sunday.
Speaker 0: No, no rental car place will let you get a rental that ends on Sunday.
Speaker 0: So you pretty much have to keep it till Monday and then drop it off Mm-hmm, but getting the car like Friday afternoon to Monday morning from like White Plains was Basically half the price of a zip car.
Speaker 0: So I took the train up to White Plains picked up the car picked up Emily because her office is up there.
Speaker 0: Drove to Wildwood family's office when Emily get the car Because I drive a lot more than her and I don't think she really wanted to drive the car.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I mean most of our friends in New York like Judith doesn't even know how to drive.
Speaker 1: Why don't you just take the train to Jersey and get a car?
Speaker 0: I thought about that and it ended up being much more a pain in the ass for a bunch of traffic reasons.
Speaker 1: You just take the path train then get a car.
Speaker 0: Yeah We did that once and actually it took.
Speaker 0: it ended up taking way longer than what we did now Mm-hmm because I could skirt New York City to a surprising degree from coming from the.
Speaker 0: but anyway in the month in the Monday morning I drove Emily to work and then I just dropped the car off like at North White Plains And then I took the train to work and I worked out fine.
Speaker 0: But I think what killed zip car is that one remember zip car got bought I didn't forget watch Which rental car company owns them.
Speaker 0: and once that happens zip car just kind of sucks.
Speaker 0: and it got worse and worse and worse - Zip car wanted to be sold to people who live in cities who don't own a car But occasionally need to use a car to like do something.
Speaker 0: 90% of those use cases are now covered by uber.
Speaker 1: Uber is not gonna take you to the beach though
Speaker 0: No but zip car wanted to sell zip car to the kinds of people like their business model was basically a Shit version of what uber does now like
Speaker 1: anyone
Speaker 0: who would use a zip car for the business model zip car had.
Speaker 0: now We'll just use uber.
Speaker 0: Everyone who had zip car actually used it the way we used it of.
Speaker 0: we actually just want to rent cars like a normal car Rental and they can't make money with that.
Speaker 0: So I think zip car is just completely fucked.
Speaker 1: The thing is we need uber long, right?
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: yeah, I would never take a car to go somewhere short.
Speaker 1: I don't only take a car to go somewhere in another town, but an uber is not gonna take me to like Pennsylvania.
Speaker 0: it's like cars on demand.
Speaker 0: I want an uber where someone drives a car to my apartment at a certain time Leaves it with me and then comes to pick the car back up on another date at another time.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: That's what I want That's not bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that would actually be great.
Speaker 0: So uber killed zip car and while zip car still exists Beware you who use it.
Speaker 0: It is basically worthless at this point and it's interesting how that like the use case like a use case that a huge number of pretty affluent people in a major city have is Literally not served.
Speaker 0: like there is no solution for people like us It is literally go to a shitto place like Hertz and go through the normal garbage Terrible process talking to human beings and dealing with the crap or buy a car and pay to park it somewhere every month.
Speaker 0: Yep, so if we used a rental car if we used a zip car.
Speaker 0: with the current prices four times a year.
Speaker 0: It's cheaper to own a car even with paying for the hundred fifty bucks a month for parking and the insurance And everything and the maintenance.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I did the van.
Speaker 1: It's a really nice car.
Speaker 0: I know it'd be it could be a crappy car Who cares like some used piece of crap.
Speaker 0: actually if I did that I'd probably get like a minivan Because then we can bring all our friends to places and it actually would be really worthwhile.
Speaker 0: Why not get like, you know, one of those I can't can't have more than like 12 seats Or then it doesn't count as a consumer van.
Speaker 1: I'm saying like that, you know the church van where it's like three benches and can fit a ton of people.
Speaker 0: Oh, I see what you're thinking.
Speaker 0: Just why don't we just get a school bus?
Speaker 0: They get like one mile per gallon, I guess that's the problem.
Speaker 1: You need a special license to drive.
Speaker 0: that I could get that license.
Speaker 0: I think is C license or whatever.
Speaker 0: But if we get regular rental cars We would have to use a rental car like 14 times a year and then it's cheaper to own the car.
Speaker 0: I don't think we use them 14 times a year more like four.
Speaker 0: Yeah, thus Zip cars dead in other news.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: What other tech news did we have?
Speaker 0: So something interesting is happening with the EU.
Speaker 0: The European Union is going to basically pay to have its own engineers Like the government that the the people who do like security auditing are going to do an audit of Apache and key pass specifically, okay The rationale is that those two open source or open projects are used very widely Both by government agencies and the private sector and also just the public and they decided that it would be a public good to use taxpayer money to have an independent body of Professionals audit and check on the security of those things and generate a report and work with both of those projects to make them better From a security standpoint.
Speaker 0: All right, this is kind of amazing.
Speaker 0: It's kind of it's actually gonna be a really good thing.
Speaker 1: They're open source things.
Speaker 1: do whatever you want.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's I don't know if this has ever happened before.
Speaker 0: I think the only times that I can find evidence of a government entity doing auditing of open source software is If they're auditing a specific use of that software within another company Se Linux.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, but who?
Speaker 0: who audited that specifically?
Speaker 0: and where's the report?
Speaker 1: It's the NSA's version of the Linux kernel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm saying where's when's the last like independent audit of its security?
Speaker 0: It's continuous.
Speaker 1: It doesn't end.
Speaker 1: they do it all the time.
Speaker 0: It's is there a report.
Speaker 0: It's a living me to it.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they have a report.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, this is the NSA has a fork of Linux that they continuously maintain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and probably put holes in for us to get.
Speaker 0: did you trust the NSA hundred percent?
Speaker 1: Se Linux is like the real deal.
Speaker 0: Well se Linux is the thing that most bullshit most Linux people who are system administrators.
Speaker 0: in my experience open source It's not.
Speaker 1: there's no.
Speaker 0: most people I know and like every company I've ever like looked at their servers Se Linux is disabled because someone runs into a problem.
Speaker 0: It doesn't know how to fix it and the solution on like some garbage stack exchange.
Speaker 0: answer is just turn se Linux off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the real answer is the software that you're trying to run on that secure kernel is not secure.
Speaker 1: Edit that software to make it secure.
Speaker 0: Actually, I found 90% of the time.
Speaker 0: the real reason was your clock is off and I see Linux freaks out.
Speaker 0: if timestamps are messed Up, it's also her problem.
Speaker 0: That's like the movie that nine times out of ten if se Linux doesn't work It's because you didn't set up NTP.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but this is cool and it kind of lets, you know, a lot of people in General especially lately because they're you know people getting their Twitter hacked or whatever They want.
Speaker 1: anyone says something was hacked.
Speaker 0: It really means you had terrible password.
Speaker 1: someone guessed your stupid password.
Speaker 1: Yeah You told it to some.
Speaker 1: or you use the same password on multiple sites or you like you clicked Oh off Yes on something stupid and gave permission to some app to use your shit.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Now there are password managers and You probably shouldn't use them because while I don't
Speaker 1: use anything that stores my password even in an encrypted fashion
Speaker 0: now Theoretically a good way to do that would be to have local encryption only of your passwords that are not known to any human in The world.
Speaker 0: sure and the problem is you have to trust the organization that made that software that you run locally, right?
Speaker 1: As soon as you store your password, even if it's encrypted You're basically the whole point of a password the password from something, you know into something you have pretty much.
Speaker 1: So you're basically now you.
Speaker 1: even if you use two-factor auth It's something you have and something else you have and someone else can just steal and take the to have.
Speaker 0: but if you're gonna do Something like that key pass is probably the best one to use because it is not like last pass or any of those things.
Speaker 0: It is just in it a little encrypted database.
Speaker 0: You can put things in and you could you.
Speaker 0: just you keep it and you manage it.
Speaker 0: never sends your shit anywhere Mm-hmm, so you can go into it.
Speaker 0: like you can have a super complex password and if you somehow forget it or like you have a crazy password for how you use that often.
Speaker 0: key pass is so reliable that a lot of Security audit types use it in real organizations and governments use it.
Speaker 1: just use fucking pass phrases.
Speaker 1: They're it's they're easy to remember because just a bunch of words.
Speaker 0: So, you know what I use key pass for.
Speaker 0: I don't put my passwords in it but I put other information that I'd like to be confidential because TrueCrypt kind of died as a project and it's a nice way to Have an encrypted container and the only way to unlock mine is both to type in a passphrase and to plug my yubi key into My computer.
Speaker 1: but I'm saying if you need for passwords.
Speaker 1: just use pass phrases You can remember.
Speaker 1: it's hard to remember like ABC 1 2 XY something capital lowercase weird symbol, right?
Speaker 1: It's hard to remember but it's easy to remember like a whole sentence Right, like the brown the lazy Fox jumped over the dog or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like that's a crazy fucking long password and it's easy as hell to remember.
Speaker 0: How many of you remember the correct horse battery?
Speaker 1: Exactly something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you just use something like that for every different place you log into and You'll be crazy secure.
Speaker 1: No one will ever guess you're really ridiculously long password But you'll remember it without even needing any kind of encryption or any kind of help whatsoever.
Speaker 1: And that's it.
Speaker 1: pass phrases to the king.
Speaker 1: fuck everything else.
Speaker 0: and last but not least the Linux kernel 4 7 was released.
Speaker 0: That's actual tech news according to scout and everyone's talk about all this non tech news.
Speaker 1: It's only news if they did something in that release of significance.
Speaker 0: All right, let's see what was increased.
Speaker 1: What a great news.
Speaker 1: Support for arbitrary number went up.
Speaker 0: support for radion rx 480 GPUs.
Speaker 1: You got one of those.
Speaker 0: No, who cares?
Speaker 0: It's radio.
Speaker 0: It's AMD.
Speaker 0: No one wants those.
Speaker 0: Why do you send video guys?
Speaker 0: Let's see load pin which makes modules load by the kernel or just in files.
Speaker 0: Okay, whatever Generating virtual USB device controllers and USB IP.
Speaker 0: All right Sync file fencing mechanisms used in Android mobile operating systems.
Speaker 0: Berkeley packet filter programs can attach to trace four points schedule till frequency governor to the CPU freak dynamic frequency scaling subsystem.
Speaker 0: None of this matters to 99% of humans.
Speaker 1: Ninety nine point nine nine.
Speaker 1: I'm presenting humans.
Speaker 0: What's funny is the GPU stuff is interesting because that only matters.
Speaker 1: any humans is a lot of humans.
Speaker 0: But the GPU and so like that only matters to people who are running Linux on the desktop and want a GPU To use this GPU stuff on the desktop.
Speaker 1: could be someone somewhere who's using AMD to do like some CUDA processing project or something because they didn't buy in video maybe but I don't know if this driver Necessarily helps with that.
Speaker 1: I don't know either.
Speaker 1: No one cares.
Speaker 1: The one person who has that video card and wants to run Linux on it is really excited.
Speaker 0: Are any of you the person wrote the driver actually you the listener?
Speaker 0: I have a question for you does anything in the Linux for seven kernel in any way?
Speaker 0: Affect you at all.
Speaker 0: If it does I really want to hear from you.
Speaker 1: It might matter to some Android people's, you know, eventually Yeah, maybe in a way they won't realize It's just most good uses of Linux these days are servers not so much desktops.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean Linux runs everything these days.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, it's not running but it's not a desktop.
Speaker 1: It pretty much runs Linux.
Speaker 1: yeah, unless it's an iOS device and You know not just servers like literally every device that isn't a Windows desktop or an Apple devices or legacy device Which is like old Windows is running Linux.
Speaker 1: So, you know the changes of the kernel that affect all those devices But they're invisible to all human beings Except the ones working on.
Speaker 0: but anyway things of the day All right, so I'm just gonna.
Speaker 1: I couldn't actually have any things of the day cuz I've been.
Speaker 1: yeah There weren't really any good things of the day going on.
Speaker 1: so just do a self-indulgent thing of the day the kind of thing that usually I You'd like on YouTube and then don't make a thing of the day cuz I'm like, yeah That's just a thing that I like not a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: But recently like a week ago or so Whereas the alternative press music awards a music award show even crappier than like the Grammys.
Speaker 1: yeah, somehow is that if there's even possible an award show where literally no one cares and Really you won one of these awards.
Speaker 1: No one gives a shit.
Speaker 1: But as award shows are like to do especially musical ones There are performances there and at this award show There is a performance of babymetal on stage with Rob Halford.
Speaker 1: If you don't know who that is That's the Judas Priest guy.
Speaker 1: It's breaking the law.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they broke all the laws.
Speaker 1: So watch this video and see all the laws be broken.
Speaker 1: Nice.
Speaker 1: What's really freaky is You know like in babymetal There's three girls the one who can actually sing and the two that pretty much just dance and make cute noises, right?
Speaker 1: So the two cute noises ones didn't really have a lot to do on this kind of stage.
Speaker 1: So they had them come out with these tiny guitars that were really even more cute.
Speaker 1: and The thing is if you watch the video It looks like they're maybe actually playing them possibly.
Speaker 0: Oh That's interesting.
Speaker 1: I mean, they're probably turned way down on the mixer board so they don't fuck anything up But it really looks like they're playing it.
Speaker 1: You know, usually you can tell like yeah They're just pretending to play which is see the thing is everyone expected them to be pretending to play Video like.
Speaker 1: it almost looks like they're playing and they're actually have little wires coming out going to wireless packs.
Speaker 0: good modern Videos of things like.
Speaker 0: it's especially just a real band where people actually do play their instruments normally.
Speaker 0: But this is live streamed on like Amazon live stream Yeah, so when they're doing a live show that can't be fucked up like, you know Like some bands will do a live show.
Speaker 0: they do a real live show.
Speaker 0: But if you're doing the live show at like the Olympics or something or the halftime They're not gonna risk like something bad happening.
Speaker 0: So usually they'll actually be playing the songs on the instruments.
Speaker 0: They're just not that and music isn't going anyway, right?
Speaker 1: But even if they were doing that the surprise is they know how to play.
Speaker 0: I guess I kind of expected that from them because they seem very earnest.
Speaker 1: I think it's a thing as you know, Japanese people always practicing too hard and putting in the extra effort.
Speaker 0: It depends.
Speaker 0: I've seen multiple J-pop idol Concerts where the person was literally doing the opposite of even pretending to play.
Speaker 0: They're just like kind of banging their hand against the guitar.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: I have seen that as well I think when what's-her-name got her hair stuck in the guitar.
Speaker 1: Oh that whatever her name was.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Otacon concert That was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember who that was.
Speaker 0: So actually surprisingly semi-related my video.
Speaker 1: So whoever made those tiny guitars that are too cute for life.
Speaker 1: Yeah Props to you.
Speaker 0: So if you didn't know this it's actually impossible to tune a piano What?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so No, you can hire people to tune your fucking.
Speaker 1: they can't.
Speaker 0: they can't.
Speaker 0: they can tune your piano and I'm making quote motions But they cannot tune it evenly.
Speaker 0: If some notes are gonna be.
Speaker 1: there's a bunch of individual strings.
Speaker 0: Yes, that's why it can't be tuned.
Speaker 1: each string makes one specific note.
Speaker 0: That that is why the piano cannot be.
Speaker 1: there is a separate string for every key.
Speaker 1: You say that you make every single string.
Speaker 1: that is the correct string at the correct tension.
Speaker 0: So what is the correct string?
Speaker 0: intention Scott?
Speaker 1: Because the problem is you have a little tuner.
Speaker 1: so say this key is this is you know?
Speaker 1: this middle C and you press it and The same hammer hits the string and you say well was that at the frequency of middle C?
Speaker 1: and you know It was a little bit low free.
Speaker 1: so Scott make it tighter.
Speaker 1: so a little bit high frequency I'll make it looser.
Speaker 1: There you go exactly the right frequency.
Speaker 1: when the hammer hit the string that string is in tune.
Speaker 1: you do repeat for every string.
Speaker 0: That's why this video is important.
Speaker 0: So Scott when you watch this video and it's only four minutes long You will find out that you are wrong.
Speaker 1: The strings are not related to each other in any way.
Speaker 1: It is literally just happen to be next to each other.
Speaker 0: with with music and the way music notes work It is impossible to evenly and perfectly tune a piano.
Speaker 1: I think this is a bullshit.
Speaker 1: hooks video.
Speaker 0: uh you do I do okay?
Speaker 1: Incorrect and against all common sense.
Speaker 0: so when you're you could google around for an evenly.
Speaker 1: It should then be also impossible to tune a guitar.
Speaker 1: It's just a piano with a lot less strings.
Speaker 0: uh no guitars can be perfectly tuned then why can't not?
Speaker 1: a piano is the same thing.
Speaker 0: you You should Watch this video.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling this video is gonna be full bullshit.
Speaker 0: So there are different ways to tune a piano and basically no matter what the method I just said is the correct method every method will have some keys will be out of tune.
Speaker 0: Sounds to me like you're now the way around that get a new tuning fork in the old days if you want a piano That is perfectly evenly tuned.
Speaker 0: that piano is only set up to play in basically one key Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: yeah like uh you know what Scott.
Speaker 0: watch the video mm-hmm, okay?
Speaker 0: I've studied music theory.
Speaker 0: I was a musician.
Speaker 0: I'm not a musician anymore, so I don't play my trumpet for shit.
Speaker 0: You've watched this video.
Speaker 0: You cannot tune a piano.
Speaker 0: You're wrong.
Speaker 1: the sound sounds wrong.
Speaker 0: I'll bet you $100.
Speaker 0: This video is not wrong not better than anything.
Speaker 1: cuz what do I know about music?
Speaker 1: But I suspect many of you out there It's just common sense that you can make a string sound a particular frequency when it's hit with a hammer For and you can do that for one string.
Speaker 1: you can do it for as many strings as you need even if you had three Pianos, so I suspect that the listenership view the listener.
Speaker 0: I guess our skits are obviously alities.
Speaker 1: does that not make sense though.
Speaker 0: It does make sense.
Speaker 0: So that's the problem.
Speaker 0: all the listener out there who are Musicians are go are laughing at you and all the people who are not musicians are laughing at me.
Speaker 0: And it is very counterintuitive.
Speaker 0: But this is why when you get a piano tune one string and can tune a thousand strings.
Speaker 0: an expert piano tuner if you care We'll ask you how you want the piano tempered.
Speaker 0: What temperament do you want to give the piano?
Speaker 1: I want every string to sound?
Speaker 1: Exactly the frequency that it is supposed to.
Speaker 0: watch this video, and we'll.
Speaker 0: we'll talk about it again on Wednesday.
Speaker 0: In the moment we are going to be live at PAX West We're doing one panel.
Speaker 0: I forgot when it is so I got to pull up some Saturday our website.
Speaker 0: I think Saturday afternoon or evening or something like that.
Speaker 0: Five ish row crew calm.
Speaker 0: Saturday, September 3rd 5 p.m.. I remember chicken theater the grind.
Speaker 1: So you know at PAX East when you want to go to a theater?
Speaker 1: You just think oh, that's the albatross theater.
Speaker 1: it must be at the top because it's a flying animal yep and it's a. so it must be in the corner because it goes ABCD.
Speaker 1: if you are at PAX West and You hear the name of a theater such as the chicken theater How do you know where it is?
Speaker 0: isn't the first letter the name of the hotel?
Speaker 1: It's in the first.
Speaker 1: that is correct.
Speaker 1: the first letter of the theater means we're in the Convention Center.
Speaker 0: That is correct as opposed to before we were in the hotel.
Speaker 0: That's actually pretty.
Speaker 1: panels that are in the Hyatt begin with H And the ones that are in the Sheraton begin with s and such and such.
Speaker 1: That's how works.
Speaker 0: that is why packs is one of the best-run conventions on earth because they put the thought into making that sort of System.
Speaker 0: it does not hurt people who are too dumb to understand it or who are ignorant of it regardless of their intelligence But it helps people who have the gnosis also.
Speaker 1: We're a guess we're getting free badges to packs yet again meaning we have two badges.
Speaker 1: I have well.
Speaker 1: I have eight badges Friday Saturday Sunday Monday Friday Saturday Sunday Monday, and I got to do something with those.
Speaker 1: we'll figure that out.
Speaker 1: I probably should get money in exchange to them because I could use some money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well We'll sell them at least at face value We're not.
Speaker 1: well you could buy them from me with if you want to do something with them that is free.
Speaker 1: You could buy them from me with patreon money.
Speaker 0: Oh Oh, yeah Maybe we should.
Speaker 0: maybe I should buy them from you with patreon money and give them away.
Speaker 1: There's a markup.
Speaker 0: no markup No mark up.
Speaker 1: It's maybe like 50% mark up, dude We're some more 500% mark.
Speaker 0: we are among the blessed few who don't have to worry about getting tags badges.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna scalp the badges we got.
Speaker 1: I'm the one scalping them to you.
Speaker 0: Yes, you bought them.
Speaker 0: I I failed.
Speaker 0: I tried to buy packs badges because you know I'm always worried too, and I didn't get in in time.
Speaker 0: That's not my fault your bad internet, so I only have a badge because we're a guest again.
Speaker 1: Well, you would have had one of these ones if we.
Speaker 0: the book club book is Oryx and Craig.
Speaker 1: I finished it in like six hours.
Speaker 1: rim didn't even read it.
Speaker 0: yet the next Thursday episode that we do The one that comes next as in the one that comes before We will do our review of Oryx and Craig by Margaret Atwood Probably tomorrow.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna actually post because our website still says the book club is the eye of the world.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna officially update it.
Speaker 1: I also finished uh The great ordeal.
Speaker 0: I'm about to finish it.
Speaker 1: That's a rim always talking about always trying to make fun of me like uh he's so much better at reading.
Speaker 0: you remembered more about Sorewheels fucking friend and the and his dad and Zoe him and all that than I did.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying You know I'm better at reading than rim if I actually read you got a little bit ahead.
Speaker 1: I'm just actually reads more.
Speaker 0: well cuz I didn't read at the beach.
Speaker 0: I said I'd read at the beach.
Speaker 0: you ready to the beach.
Speaker 0: I went.
Speaker 0: ah Yeah, I went I too But I didn't bike.
Speaker 0: Otherwise as you might have noticed geek nights present through 10 episode 15 is up And I have a bonus by the weekend.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna put up a bonus episode episode 15 a much like we did episode I think to a where we were like what the hell is to chew.
Speaker 0: there's gonna be a special Varian version of episode 15 that talks about something different.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm
Speaker 0: Basically, I'm gonna talk about the scene transitions in utenna with a bunch of specific examples And I'm gonna take all the scenes from episode 15 and show all the sort of Kubrick style Nonsense that you see in utenna where like in one scene someone's holding something and then in the next scene There's something sitting in the spot where the person was holding it and that's very much on purpose.
Speaker 0: Whatever, it's good stuff.
Speaker 0: other than that Watch the patreon You could buy our t-shirt.
Speaker 0: don't but hold out because hopefully soon I'll get a licensing deal and you'll be.
Speaker 0: you might be able to buy your very own Officially licensed chicken surprise and ice cream scream t-shirts.
Speaker 1: I'll buy ice cream scream.
Speaker 0: burger brothers is pretty good, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's got two little guys with chef hats.
Speaker 1: I got to represent my full web.
Speaker 0: Actually ice cream sheep scream is good because you know that bright blue Threadless shirt with the lockdowns monster.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So the ice cream scream shirt is that exact same color Because that's the color of ice cream scream.
Speaker 0: Anyway, stay tuned on all that.
Speaker 0: It'll be fun.
Speaker 0: So this issue comes up a lot in tech circles.
Speaker 0: like normal tech people know about this a lot But it's interesting to be aware of the fact that this is a much bigger problem.
Speaker 0: Like tech people say they care about this But the average tech person would not actually take advantage of the right to repair things that they fight for Even though ideologically know they're the right thing.
Speaker 1: It's principle.
Speaker 1: Yeah principle the thing.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna link to one because it's the most.
Speaker 0: it's the most recent one of the hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of articles You can find.
Speaker 0: that will show you the people who are actually really hurt by this problem.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and farmers are a really good example.
Speaker 0: So if you own a tractor, right you might think a tractor is a simple dumb thing.
Speaker 1: But actually it's a motor and some wheels and maybe another motor to spin something.
Speaker 0: and you know Yep, but tractors have very complex gearing because of the kind of stuff they have to do and oftentimes Yeah, it's you know, it's a specifically powerful high torque engine, right?
Speaker 1: It doesn't move real fast, but it can pull a lot of shit real, you know Heavy and but they also usually integrate with very complex mechanisms that they tow.
Speaker 0: The tractor itself you think of a tractor is like it's pulling something around.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's pulling around a giant death robot thresher or something, right?
Speaker 1: Not only is it pulling it It's also spinning things in that you know It's like sort of like my stand mixer right at the front.
Speaker 1: It has that attachment or it's like it's not just mixing It's also got this thing on the front that's turning that you can Attach an ice cream maker a meat grinder to and shit.
Speaker 1: now also tractors like that times a million.
Speaker 0: So unlike a consumer vehicle where there's lots and lots of customers and lots and lots of companies making them Which is what most people talk about when they talk about retro repair Not that many companies make for real tractors.
Speaker 0: That's a specialized thing.
Speaker 1: There's only a few companies in the world that make tractors like John Deere and maybe like caterpillar?
Speaker 1: Do they then they make other kinds of?
Speaker 0: Can't make similar, you know construction devices.
Speaker 1: You know specialized equipment like that is only made by a few companies and because you know Even if there are more companies is only a few that make good ones.
Speaker 0: so like you say you wanted to buy a car and you Learned that from mechanics that that car was real expensive to maintain because mechanics couldn't fix it.
Speaker 0: You might decide to buy a car that didn't have that problem.
Speaker 0: Let's buy this Volkswagen.
Speaker 1: Why is there a huge line to the service department behind?
Speaker 1: Let's not buy one of these.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's buy this kinda and I'll just mess with it myself.
Speaker 0: But if you buy a John Deere tractor like this article is very detailed if you buy the John Deere 8235 are Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: You can't fucking fix anything on it if something goes wrong.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's a motor though shouldn't you just open it up look at the motor and if you know how motor works be able to fix it?
Speaker 0: What do you like what this could?
Speaker 0: so this this article is about a farmer who's fighting for the right to repair his own tractor So it has codes that'll pop up telling you.
Speaker 0: Hey, there's a problem.
Speaker 0: Legally you're not even allowed to look up what that code means because that would violate the DMCA.
Speaker 0: The codes themselves are covered by the DMCA and under copyright You're not allowed to do things like like that.
Speaker 0: the code might mean change a filter.
Speaker 0: now You're probably not even allowed to change the filter Even if you know what the code means because if you do you might void the service contract with John Deere.
Speaker 1: What if you buy one without a service contract, uh, then you probably can't repair it.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: the tractors are expensive.
Speaker 0: They have very complicated sensors and they're basically there's a computer in there like all cars have computers in them.
Speaker 0: now tractors have way more complicated computers and There aren't nearly as many people who are hacking those computers like there are with the car mod community.
Speaker 1: and even then yeah It's not like computer.
Speaker 0: people are buying tractors and say you're a farmer and you buy a super expensive tractor upon which your livelihood Depends.
Speaker 0: you're not gonna start hacking it because if you break it not only might you get sued by John Deere But they might just say well, we're not selling any more tractors and then what buy one for someone else?
Speaker 0: Who?
Speaker 0: there's only so many people who make tractors and they all seem to have this problem and you already lost all your money buying That first one.
Speaker 0: So John Deere very publicly is Against the right to repair.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they want you to pay them every time something breaks.
Speaker 0: John Deere apparently officially said on record in an interview with Wired that giving giving farmers access to the software would quote Make it possible for pirates third-party developers and less innovative competitors to free ride off the creativity unique expression and ingenuity of vehicle software.
Speaker 0: And they're using the DMCA.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell that's the primary tool they're using to f over the farmers Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So this is an issue that I don't know how we're gonna win anything because as you pointed out and I'd forgotten about there was a right to repair bill in New York and The tech companies particularly Apple made sure it didn't pass Mm-hmm, so we have no right to repair our devices, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz the same thing applies right it would it would you know, make it.
Speaker 1: anyone could just open up an old Apple repair business.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which I feel like that should be the case I got there is there are.
Speaker 1: they exist but they would be even better if you know, there weren't these legal restrictions.
Speaker 0: So I guess is there any argument we can make against Repealing this part of the DMCA and letting people repair their own devices?
Speaker 1: You mean an argument like in John Deere's favor?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like.
Speaker 0: is there any argument in Apple's favor?
Speaker 0: or yeah There's favor.
Speaker 1: those companies make more money this way.
Speaker 0: Are is there any non evil argument?
Speaker 1: No, if you buy something isn't the old saying, you know, if you can't fix it, you don't own it, right?
Speaker 1: So It's people wanting are using the DMCA to basically collect rents.
Speaker 1: That's all there is to it.
Speaker 0: Now that that the if you don't if you can't repair you don't own it is a little bit troublesome though in the sense that We're entering a world where there's so much technology that it's basically expected that 99% of all humans will not be able to repair 99% of the things that they own even if there is zero legal restriction.
Speaker 1: I mean even if you go back to the 80s or when I bought a stereo it came with a complete schematic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, did you ever solder your stereo to fix it?
Speaker 1: I never even opened it, right?
Speaker 0: When my cereal broke I did not use the schematic to fix it when we had a compressor for gig nights and one day it Stopped working.
Speaker 0: I had the full schematic I had the full documentation of how it worked and everything and I did not try to repair it.
Speaker 0: I threw it away, right?
Speaker 1: So that's the step number one.
Speaker 1: If you can't repair it You don't own it is even if you're allowed to repair it and you have the information as needed to repair it.
Speaker 1: you need to have these skills and knowledge to actually execute that repair and you know, the Willingness to try to do the repair with a risk of failure, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know if you don't have those things if you don't know how to you know work with an engine You could get a car and like a full blueprint to the car.
Speaker 1: and if you don't know how to do anything You don't have to use a wrench or understand how an engine works.
Speaker 1: You don't really own that car.
Speaker 1: You really you know the mechanic who lives near you has you.
Speaker 1: oh, they own you.
Speaker 1: They own that car really and you have to pay them for the ability to use your car if it ever breaks.
Speaker 0: But at least in that got you over a barrel you can go to any mechanic.
Speaker 1: Yes, you can go to any mechanic.
Speaker 0: There's a wider net so more there's.
Speaker 1: it is better, but you're still being owned and you're not the owner.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that distinction is increasing in principle, but in practicality It's increasingly meaningless.
Speaker 0: because the reality is you can't even expect people to have that capability.
Speaker 0: and also there's a side argument.
Speaker 1: What if You even own yourself if you don't know how to doctor yourself, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah On your own body, I'm gonna defer to other people.
Speaker 0: I'm not dr.
Speaker 0: McNinja I'm not gonna so much.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna undislocate my own jaw.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna relocate my job.
Speaker 1: Doctor own it.
Speaker 0: Doctor owns my jaw.
Speaker 0: Yeah doctor owns most things about my body.
Speaker 0: I mostly own my allergies my nose stuff.
Speaker 0: I know about that.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm But what?
Speaker 0: so let's say we didn't have any of these laws and you were free to fix anything.
Speaker 0: At what point is a company like Apple like within their moral rights to say because you tried to fix this But you're stupid We're not going to value when we're gonna avoid the warranty.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 0: That's fine Yeah, so what if Apple said if you ever try to repair it, we're gonna void your warranty.
Speaker 0: So that means that even if there was no DMCA you would still not actually have the practical Read space writer.
Speaker 1: Well, no because if something is currently under warranty, right?
Speaker 1: So Apple sells you iPhone a month later It breaks.
Speaker 1: you could repair it yourself because with this we're assuming we have the right to repair and we have the schematics We know how to fix it.
Speaker 1: We got you know, Apple's providing service manuals and shit, right?
Speaker 1: But if it's under warranty There's no reason for you to do that because you're gonna get a free fucking repair or replacement.
Speaker 0: All right, wait, so is Apple Obligated in this case to provide the service manuals.
Speaker 1: I Mean if you have the right to repair and in though.
Speaker 0: Well, no, do you have the positive right to repair or the negative right to repair?
Speaker 0: Do you have the right to repair if you don't have the service manual?
Speaker 1: You don't have there even if you have the right to fix it, but no, there's a you don't really have the ability.
Speaker 1: See, it doesn't it's meaningless, but there is a huge no different.
Speaker 0: There is a huge difference between saying you're not allowed to repair it and saying any company that makes something is forced to make Manual a service manual.
Speaker 1: It's different but in in terms of like yes, that's going a bit further But really if you don't make the people give you the service manual.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter if you give people the right to repair they can't repair it because they don't have the fucking service manual.
Speaker 0: So but it does create a market for third-party people who will reverse engineer the service manual which we've seen happen with consumer vehicles.
Speaker 1: They can't but they can't get it exactly right and you're always gonna be left like is that repair place?
Speaker 1: Like got it 100% right because they only have a reverse engineered idea.
Speaker 1: They don't know exactly right and that original place who made the thing still has that.
Speaker 0: What's the line?
Speaker 0: So say I make a video game?
Speaker 0: What's the service manual?
Speaker 1: I'm now obligated to provide to my customers I mean a video game isn't really something that gets repaired what there's a bug.
Speaker 0: keep tribes who doesn't work on my video card.
Speaker 0: Do they have to give me the source code which is the service manual if it has comments in it and then I can repair It myself.
Speaker 0: What's the line?
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying?
Speaker 0: That's why I'm shying far from a positive right to repair because that opens a can of worms that I don't think Humanity is capable of sorting yet.
Speaker 1: Oh I could.
Speaker 1: I'm fine with that.
Speaker 0: Well, I would I guess if we're gonna go with positive rights I'd rather go with like some positive rights.
Speaker 1: I think you can Think you get into a situation where it's like, okay, you made a video game, right?
Speaker 1: You're delivering it.
Speaker 1: There's a bug.
Speaker 1: Are you gonna patch that bug?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got some kind of warranty, right?
Speaker 1: You know, are you gonna give the person a refund?
Speaker 1: or what are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: and if they don't patch it?
Speaker 1: That means they're not maintaining it anymore.
Speaker 1: You could go to if you could go to court and force them to give you the source code Because you have the right to repair and they're refusing to repair it and give you a because
Speaker 0: that would edge a little bit Into the orphan work stuff with copyright where if no one's using this thing or no one can identify who owns it Maybe there should be a way for someone to reclaim it the same way you can reclaim.
Speaker 1: It's all the same issue Yeah, but we're just incapable.
Speaker 0: society is dealing with that issue whatever.
Speaker 0: but I guess if we're gonna if we're gonna focus on practical Realities the practical reality of consumer vehicles is that even though it's technically illegal in a lot of places to reverse engineer this People are doing it and it's almost working itself out.
Speaker 1: I mean, I just saw a YouTube video of There's those people who found the Super PlayStation in their attic or whatever.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, and they brought it to Ben Hector whatever his name is that guy and He totally like got the CD-ROM working again and shit just by figuring it out because he knows so much about Electronics and he had a super didn't edit SNES schematic and the things.
Speaker 1: mostly is Super Nintendo with the CD-ROM.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and he was able to you know, like replace some bad capacitors and you know get stuff going.
Speaker 1: So it's like you can get really far even without any manuals whatsoever.
Speaker 0: So, I guess actually.
Speaker 0: so the one final piece what if you make a dip like Apple?
Speaker 0: This is where I would defend them If you make a device like people used to complain about how you can't swap the batteries out of certain devices Because they're built-in embedded.
Speaker 0: There are situations where making something less Modular or less repairable could make its form factor better.
Speaker 0: Like look at most good laptops.
Speaker 0: I Defy you to do significant repairs on them because they're so embedded and tightly coupled.
Speaker 0: The tight coupling is what made it a good thing.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying you have to make your device Physically easy to repair at that to sacrifice the quality of the device I'm just saying yep You have to provide the in you should you know in an ideal world have to provide the full schematic of this device.
Speaker 1: It's that someone with the not appropriate knowledge and tools could repair it without having to pay the original manufacturer After the warranty is done.
Speaker 0: Thus I propose if nothing else Instead of like cell phones and cars and the things that the right-to-repair Activists usually fight about because those things are pretty abstract to the average person and the issues get pretty complex we should probably focus on the Specific harms to society that matter like farms and tractors.
Speaker 0: I feel like narrow legislation in specific industries like this with captive audiences with rights to repair in those circumstances would break the seal and Normal non techies can understand.
Speaker 0: Well, what do you mean?
Speaker 0: the farmer can't fix his fucking tractor?
Speaker 0: What's that bullshit?
Speaker 0: because that same person cares a lot less about your smartphone?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I think people understand that.
Speaker 1: you know They're upset when their phone breaks and they're upset when they go to the Apple Store and Apple won't help them and then they go To a place that charges a fortune Whereas if this law had passed you could have gone to a place and gotten charged way less than a fortune.
Speaker 0: Yep, when the Apple geniuses didn't want to help you I also do think that law should have passed because skimming what it actually did it was babies first Like.
Speaker 0: it didn't do a lot.
Speaker 1: No, it didn't go nearly far enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it didn't pass either.
Speaker 0: So it's just something to think about.
Speaker 1: it was New York only it wasn't even like the whole country.
Speaker 0: But when you've got when you're a techie who's got a very like I have a lot of real angry opinions about copyright.
Speaker 0: The average person doesn't understand those things.
Speaker 0: You've got to pick specific concrete Understandable examples and advocate for specific Focused practical solutions to those and when enough of those accrete you can then make the general case.
Speaker 0: I think that works a lot better than vaguely agitating for complex things that people don't understand.
Speaker 1: I mean, I only care about repairing shit.
Speaker 1: I don't care about the optimal way to make a law pass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's so.
Speaker 0: that's so you voted for Bernie.
Speaker 0: I guess I voted for Hillary.
Speaker 1: Yet, it's not November.
Speaker 0: would you vote for in the primary?
Speaker 1: I didn't.
Speaker 0: you really didn't vote in the primary.
Speaker 1: not allowed to.
Speaker 0: You're not a Democrat.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm a nothing and you can't change because you know change.
Speaker 0: I Changed way back because I was real pissed that I couldn't vote for Zephyr teach-out because primaries in New York.
Speaker 0: It's literally the only thing that matters in New York.
Speaker 0: So I changed back then to be able to start voting now.
Speaker 0: Hmm That's a separate issue.
Speaker 0: I think it's time to get some food.
Speaker 0: I'm real hungry Hungry for croutons.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: Croutons as I've said many times are just a highly evolved form of cracker.
Speaker 0: again there they are the cracker getting worse.
Speaker 0: They're the cracker that is taken.
Speaker 1: You have a problem.
Speaker 1: It's getting worse.
Speaker 0: I eat croutons because croutons are crackers that have embraced the absolute.
Speaker 0: the patrons for this episode of geek nights in the amount of money that they give us on a continuing basis order are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda dujette James David White Christian coons construction noises.
Speaker 0: my state a comm Sean Hayworth.
Speaker 0: I will Emei scenarios Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: Michelle Garcia Brian Fisher sailor Vista Devin Goodman Iggy kid Matthew Smith kajar tavish and Joe Joe.
Speaker 0: Joe star Tyler Eller Don Schleich Sean Yeager Clinton Walton run from New Zealand.
Speaker 0: Ryan Perrin Drew open lander rear laval Brian sit phoney Rochelle, Montana.
Speaker 0: Finn Eric Silver on bonsai buddy Chris midkiff Chris Knox.
Speaker 0: I paid five dollars and all I got was this lousy shout out Sam Corddry Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: Scott still coughing.
Speaker 0: He's almost at the end of the illness So I can't really.
Speaker 0: we got to do the Q&A is and catch up and all that stuff as soon as he is not Coughing so I can spring it on him at the end of an episode.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, you're gonna see like I said some more videos.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna try to get a ton of video work done this weekend.
Speaker 0: Hopefully I can get the Atari game design panel up - we've recorded it at a bunch of conventions.
Speaker 0: I think I have one good run of it and Stay tuned.
Speaker 0: mag fast put out the call.
Speaker 0: So we're working on our mag fast lineup as well.
Speaker 0: And now I leave you with something You.