Speaker 1: It's Monday, August 8th, 2016!
Speaker 1: I'm Rim, he's Scott, and this is Geek Nights Tonight!
Speaker 1: Specialized peripherals for computers!
Speaker 1: Let's do this!
Speaker 0: Alright, so we took a ferry over to a beachy place, but that was also a bicycle place, which is pretty much the best place.
Speaker 0: Combining two great tastes that taste great together, except, you know, the beachy place.
Speaker 0: The sand was a little eh, and, you know, the water wasn't amazing blue water, but it was actually nice water.
Speaker 1: It was real swimmable water, like it was good beach time.
Speaker 0: Good temperature.
Speaker 1: We saw some Cold War era nukes.
Speaker 0: Yup, so anyway, on the way back, right, we take the ferry, and apparently there's some deal with this ferry, that you can only take it from there to New York City if you used it to go to the beach from New York City in the morning.
Speaker 1: Now, I've used this ferry twice, this was the second time I used it, and I used it with Emily before, because basically before we invited, like, Scott and everyone else to come to this beach.
Speaker 0: Like, if you drive to the beach, and say, let's say you're hanging with your friends in New Jersey, right, and you're a New York person, and you hung out with them all week, and at the end of the week, they drive you to the beach, and then you just want to take the ferry one way back to New York, you know, and your friends drive back home to Jersey, you cannot do this.
Speaker 1: Now, it's interesting, so Emily and I, like I said, we tried this ferry out to go to this beach before we invited other people to make sure, like, it was worth doing, and it was, but way back when we did this, the sign, there was no sign saying anything like that, but now, as I got on the ferry the second time with Scott when we were coming back, there's a bunch of signs on the dock itself, and nowhere else, that say, you can only use this ferry if you came here from Manhattan today, and spent the entire day at Sandy Hook.
Speaker 0: However, that sign... So I couldn't even come on the thing, sleep on the beach, and go back tomorrow.
Speaker 1: No, what's weird is that sign is literally like on the dock, like past where they take tickets, and does not exist anywhere else in the world, or even on the website of the ferry.
Speaker 0: It's also interesting how the ferry is clearly run by a private company, right, and this company charges 30 plus dollars, 30 is like the minimum amount to get on this ferry, we paid 35 because 30 plus a bike fee, but if you get on the later ferry, not the crack of dawn ferry,
Speaker 1: it's
Speaker 0: like 40 something dollars,
Speaker 1: I think it's 47,
Speaker 0: and you add the bike fee, you could pay anywhere between 30 and 52 dollars to ride this ferry.
Speaker 0: So there's like hundreds of people on the ferry, and it runs like three times, so that's like three times a few hundred times 40.
Speaker 0: They're making like 300k almost a day running this ferry.
Speaker 1: And it takes like 40 minutes for the ferry to get there.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, owning a boat is expensive, buying a big boat, it's really big, is expensive, if you make 300k a day, you're profiting on the boat.
Speaker 1: They also sell a bunch of terrible booze for cash on it.
Speaker 0: They sold mad booze on this boat, people were getting Bloody Marys at 8am, but they were selling a decent bagel, decent meaning edible, for a dollar, it was better than a street cart bagel which cost a dollar, it wasn't as good as a real bagel, right, and I bought it for a dollar and they gave me an orange juice, also reasonable, like a dollar.
Speaker 0: fifty two dollars, so alright.
Speaker 1: I'm shocked by that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but this is a privately owned boat, but for some reason when the boat lands at the park, you know, it's a beach and a national park and all this other stuff, the National Park Rangers, federal employees, are managing everything on land and helping the ferry, like with its line and with all this stuff, they're helping the private company out, there are federal employees that federal tax money is being used to pay their salaries, and they're helping out a private ferry company that should, I think, have their own employees managing their own line.
Speaker 0: So just as we're coming up to the ferry to go home, And you know what, there's no one even managing the line on the New York side at all, there's just a big line of New Yorkers.
Speaker 1: So I start telling Scott the story of the last time Emily and I came, and how this crazy guy and his family almost got arrested by these federal park people, because there was some crazy drama.
Speaker 0: They're just park rangers, like Yogi Bears, you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there was some
Speaker 0: crazy drama
Speaker 1: where this guy wanted to park his car there and take the ferry into Manhattan with his family for the weekend and come back and get his car later, and the lady was yelling at him and then she called a whole bunch more cops, like more rangers showed up and surrounded his car and there was this crazy drama, and just as I'm telling this story to Scott, we get interrupted by basically the same situation but escalated.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this lady gets out of a car, I couldn't tell if it was her friend or an Uber or something.
Speaker 0: I suspect it was an Uber, just the way things played out.
Speaker 0: But the car left, the car wasn't there anymore, so she got dropped off, and the ranger's like, "Listen, you can't get on the ferry unless you came here from New York this
Speaker 0: morning.".
Speaker 0: And she flips out, and I'm like, "Oh, crazy
Speaker 0: person.".
Speaker 1: Zero to crazy in zero seconds.
Speaker 1: She starts screaming, "I've got to get to New
Speaker 1: York.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, and she starts running towards the ferry.
Speaker 1: So this ranger, standing in front of her, saying, "You can't come in," she runs past her and bolts toward the ferry.
Speaker 0: It's like, "What do you think's going to happen?
Speaker 0: You're not getting on the
Speaker 0: boat.".
Speaker 1: So the ranger starts yelling for, "I need backup,".
Speaker 1: and then she gets into a radio, and then these other rangers come out, and the woman's running around trying to get away from the rangers, and then three more rangers' cars come up, and one thing leads to another, and she gets fucking arrested, handcuffed, and driven away.
Speaker 0: Now, there were a lot of questions, right?
Speaker 0: One question was somebody said they heard her yelling about her father being sick, so maybe best case scenario, well, not best case for her, but she was on the beach and got a phone call, and then was clever, and was like, "Aha, I can get to New York to see my suddenly sick father really quickly with this ferry,".
Speaker 0: and didn't know the rules, and because was in a bad situation, was freaking out.
Speaker 0: But, yeah, no matter how bad the situation, freaking out is not good.
Speaker 0: You just made shit worse for yourself.
Speaker 1: Freaking out by the police, especially in America.
Speaker 0: Well, they're federal park rangers, I don't even know, and I guess they could arrest you.
Speaker 1: While she was being crazy, she was not being get-arrested crazy.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure what the fuck they arrested her on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't see anything she did.
Speaker 0: that was warrant being arrested.
Speaker 1: She warranted at most being yelled at and told to go away.
Speaker 0: She warranted being yelled at, being made to calm down and explain her deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe being put in the police car.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Maybe if you explained your deal calmly and quietly, maybe the people on the ferry would be like, "Oh shit, yeah, we'll let you on this
Speaker 0: ferry.".
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: meanwhile, while this is going on, another car pulls up and tries to drop some people off at the ferry, and that same police person or park person who had arranged the arrest of this crazy lady runs over and starts yelling at him, "You can't drop people off here.
Speaker 1: This ferry is only for
Speaker 1: people.".
Speaker 1: And it's the same deal.
Speaker 1: They're like really, really aggressively enforcing this rule.
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: meanwhile, there's someone in line next to us who said they got yelled at by the ranger, and I think the ranger has a problem with their communication because the person who was standing in line next to us did arrive by the boat in this morning from New York, and instead of taking the stupid shuttle bus, they had their friends from Jersey pick them up in a car.
Speaker 0: So of course, when they came back to the ferry, they were in a car.
Speaker 0: Even though they didn't break that rule.
Speaker 0: Even though they totally had a right to ride the ferry back to New York, because they came from New York this morning, because they arrived in a car, the ranger was like,
Speaker 0: "Eh.".
Speaker 0: And it's like, I think the ranger needs to, when they approach these cars, be like, "Hi, excuse me, did you come from New York this
Speaker 0: morning?".
Speaker 0: And then give them the what for.
Speaker 1: So we thought before I learned a new piece of information that part of this might have been because there's no ticket office in Sandy Hook.
Speaker 0: No, there were people who lost their tickets and were buying tickets right before they got on the boat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I went on the website.
Speaker 1: Not only that, you are totally allowed to buy tickets on the ferry.
Speaker 1: You can get it on without a ticket and then you buy it just like a train.
Speaker 0: They didn't come and check tickets.
Speaker 0: How would they even know?
Speaker 1: I guess you have to tell them when you try to get on and they do something because the website actually says that specifically.
Speaker 1: I scoured the website.
Speaker 1: That rule that we keep talking about only exists on two signs hidden on the gangplank to get on the ferry in Sandy Hook.
Speaker 0: But was being enforced by federal people quite strictly.
Speaker 1: But that rule is not on the New York side.
Speaker 0: The ferry didn't seem to care, actually.
Speaker 1: It's not on the website.
Speaker 1: In fact, if you go to the ferry's website, as an intelligent human being, I looked at that ferry website and I am confident based on that website that I could drive to Sandy Hook and get on that ferry right there totally legally.
Speaker 1: So the only place this rule exists, the rule that got the crazy lady arrested and seems to cause constant parades of drama is on a printed sign that appeared there only in the last few weeks.
Speaker 1: But my suspicion, my guess, I don't know if you have a different guess, is that this is either the federal people who run the park or the New Jersey people who run the park or whoever is responsible for that pier being, for whatever reason, weird about the fact that this ferry is here and enforcing this rule that no one else wants enforced.
Speaker 0: I think that it's a protectionist racket.
Speaker 0: There are other ways to commute and get from Jersey to New York.
Speaker 0: Like path trains or tunnels with tolls.
Speaker 1: And they don't want you to use this really convenient ferry.
Speaker 0: Those organizations do not want, you know, they basically said, "Okay ferry, we'll let you ferry, but we're not going to let you become a new competing option for people to get from Jersey to New York.
Speaker 0: So you can't let those people do
Speaker 0: this.".
Speaker 1: But the fact that it's federal officers enforcing that rule and that they're enforcing it so aggressively and kind of violently despite the fact that the rule-- And the ferry people didn't care, and they're park rangers.
Speaker 0: They should be warned about keeping the birds on the beach protected or whatever.
Speaker 1: I also wonder if what they're doing is actually legal because that rule doesn't exist anywhere except on one sign after you get on the ferry.
Speaker 0: And because they're federal park rangers, I think only the FBI can go and investigate.
Speaker 0: I don't think-- Who else can you call?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I did a ton of-- You can't call the New Jersey Police Department to say, "Hey, these park rangers are like--".
Speaker 0: And where do they take you?
Speaker 0: Park ranger jail?
Speaker 0: Is that like a wooden hut with a fire outside?
Speaker 1: It's a weird situation.
Speaker 1: It seems to be escalating day by day.
Speaker 0: And I can find-- I only went to this place twice, and it happened both times.
Speaker 1: Yup, multiple times both times.
Speaker 1: Everyone who uses the ferry regularly knows this one park-- And it's the same ranger is super aggressive.
Speaker 0: She basically-- Yeah, she's maybe got some issues also.
Speaker 1: Credit, you escalated the situation by heckling the crazy lady.
Speaker 0: I wasn't involved in the situation.
Speaker 0: I was a spectator.
Speaker 0: No one who was involved in the situation heard my heckling.
Speaker 1: Your heckling was a little loud.
Speaker 1: I would have heckled more quietly in the direction of my audience and not at the crazy lady.
Speaker 0: I had to keep an eye on the-- I can't heckle if I got an eye on the action.
Speaker 0: If I turned around to look at you while heckling, I wouldn't have been having-- I can't make a play-by-play.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at the crowd, right?
Speaker 1: So then later, Scott's getting on the ferry, and he's like, "I hope they let me bring my ice water
Speaker 1: on.".
Speaker 1: And I was like, "Nah, it's a federal
Speaker 1: crime.".
Speaker 0: That was really interesting happening.
Speaker 0: Everything else that was interesting was just stuff that was there, not things that happened.
Speaker 1: Maybe on Thursday, the next Thursday show, we'll talk about it, because we actually got a tour of--.
Speaker 1: For those of you who aren't aware, there was nuclear anti-aircraft-- nuclear anti-aircraft systems in Sandy Hook around New York.
Speaker 0: Anyone who doesn't know the geography, look at Google Maps and look for Sandy Hook near New York City, and you'll see that this is a place where you can defend New York City from pretty much any boat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, before airplanes existed?
Speaker 1: This was like, literally, no boat could get to New York Harbor.
Speaker 0: From the Revolutionary War onwards-- Until the '70s.
Speaker 0: Until the '70s, this little spot was used to defend New York from any kind of attack, mostly by boat, but then eventually also defending from planes.
Speaker 0: But then once planes got too good, it became mostly useless.
Speaker 0: So now there's no more active defenses there.
Speaker 1: When planes got too good, they made the anti-aircraft rocket artillery nuclear.
Speaker 1: So there's nukes.
Speaker 0: And then the Cold War ended, so we don't need anything here anymore.
Speaker 1: I'm frankly really glad those nukes are not there anymore.
Speaker 1: Especially now that I know how they worked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, they were a deterrent, and they did their job.
Speaker 0: No one ever attacked New York City ever.
Speaker 0: It was very interesting that, in fact-- Because of the little things they put on that island, all the artilleries they set up there-- Not just the artillery, but the hydraulic shore batteries and all those things from the 1980s.
Speaker 0: They put many things there, and they were very effective at keeping New York where it is now.
Speaker 1: None of the weapons ever-- A job well done.
Speaker 1: No weapon ever put on that island was used in anger, which is amazing.
Speaker 0: A worthwhile investment.
Speaker 0: I think they might have shot at some boats in the olden days.
Speaker 0: No!
Speaker 1: You didn't get to do the other tours.
Speaker 1: We got tours of all the old batteries.
Speaker 0: They didn't even have to shoot at boats in 1812.
Speaker 1: The Potter battery never used in anger.
Speaker 1: The 9-gun never used in anger.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: The War of 1812, they didn't try to ride up on into New York with their boats?
Speaker 1: I don't think they had those installations there in the early 1800s.
Speaker 0: I thought they were there in the Revolutionary War.
Speaker 1: No, Revolutionary War was other stuff, I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it was good times.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll do some investigative journalism, try to figure out what's up with the Sandy Hook ferry thing.
Speaker 1: Question A-- I thought I was clever.
Speaker 0: Why are the federal park rangers helping the private boat?
Speaker 0: B, why do they have this rule?
Speaker 0: C, why are they enforcing the rule so crazily?
Speaker 1: Does this rule even exist?
Speaker 1: I'm dubious of whether or not this is an arrestable offense.
Speaker 0: Maybe, I don't know.
Speaker 1: If I insisted on getting on the ferry, what could they arrest me for?
Speaker 0: My general advice, though, is in life, there's really no reason to flip out.
Speaker 0: Tell you what, guys-- There are things that are actually so bad in this world that it's like, "Yeah, that's really, really bad.
Speaker 0: That's worthy of flipping out
Speaker 0: about.".
Speaker 0: But don't flip out even then, because flipping out doesn't help anything.
Speaker 1: Scott, you be the park ranger, and I'll be crazy lady, and I'm going to roleplay how I would handle that situation as clever rim.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I just need to get on the ferry, but what's the problem?
Speaker 0: Some rule, you can't get on the ferry unless you came here from New York this morning on the ferry.
Speaker 0: It's a return trip only ferry.
Speaker 1: I did come this morning.
Speaker 1: I took the 8 a.m.
Speaker 1: sea streak or whatever.
Speaker 0: Do you have the other half of your round trip ticket?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's buried somewhere in my wallet.
Speaker 0: Well, show it to me.
Speaker 1: Shit, I can't find it.
Speaker 1: They said I have to buy another one on the ferry if I lost it.
Speaker 0: Okay, because I'm a reasonable human being.
Speaker 1: Or even better, thanks officer, sorry, drive away, wait 10 minutes, leave the car somewhere else, walk to the ferry line from the other side and blend in with the gigantic crowd.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a ways around those things.
Speaker 1: So, in another kind of open it before we get to the news.
Speaker 0: Rent a bicycle, come back, return the rented bicycle, walk up to the...
Speaker 1: Just make a fake receipt for a ferry ticket on your phone and show it to them really quick.
Speaker 1: So, anyway, remember how last week my thing of the day was the entire Nintendo Power Archive on archive.org?
Speaker 0: Is there some other archive on there?
Speaker 1: No, that shit got taken down within 48 hours.
Speaker 1: So, the question of, I wonder how this was legal, the answer was Nintendo hates you and took it down and there is no way to legally see old Nintendo Powers.
Speaker 0: Also, some people made an awesome Metroid 2 remake because Metroid 2 is actually pretty good Metroid, it's different from the other Metroids, but still Metroidy and worth playing.
Speaker 0: But it was only ever a Game Boy game.
Speaker 0: really, I guess you get the Virtual Console version.
Speaker 0: It's not really nice to play, but a lot of people that remade.
Speaker 0: Metroid 2 is like a good PC game, that's the same map, the same game, only smooth and pleasant like a Super Metroid.
Speaker 0: And Nintendo was like, yeah, take that shit down, but you can get the torrents, like people are spreading it wisely.
Speaker 0: Listen, people, when you got something to spread, don't make a fucking website and post it.
Speaker 0: Just make a torrent only and only on Pirate Bay, that's it.
Speaker 0: Torrents only.
Speaker 0: And then there's no one to send a takedown to.
Speaker 0: Fuck yourself, Nintendo.
Speaker 1: In fact, the torrent of all of Nintendo Power would be smaller than like one episode of a TV show.
Speaker 0: Exactly, it's like, don't go posting stuff on a website with a link on a server.
Speaker 0: Just make a torrent only.
Speaker 0: People who are posting stuff on YouTube and get taken down and then they post on Dailymotion, it's like, dude, torrent only.
Speaker 1: Well, no, what the kids do now, and I've watched, I know people who watch shows this way, I don't know why, the audio is sped up like 10% and the stereo channels are like munged and messed up.
Speaker 0: I've seen stuff on YouTube where there's like, most of the video frame on YouTube is taken up by a JPEG and the video is in a smaller frame within that JPEG.
Speaker 1: And the video itself is zoomed in a little bit and twisted a little bit.
Speaker 1: Like, don't watch shows like that.
Speaker 1: Just fucking pirate it at that point, Jesus.
Speaker 1: Like, just go to Pirate Bay.
Speaker 1: If you respect the media enough to pirate it, at least pirate a good copy of it.
Speaker 1: Do you disrespect your own time that much?
Speaker 0: I think it's because a lot of the people posting a lot of this content are trying to make money off of it.
Speaker 0: No one makes money if you pirate something the honorable way.
Speaker 1: But it only gets posted and makes money because people do want to pirate things in this degraded, terrible form.
Speaker 1: Got any news?
Speaker 1: Newsboy?
Speaker 1: You said you had the news.
Speaker 0: Alright, so Edward Snowden made this tweet that was clearly some cryptographic key and then waited a bit and then deleted it and everyone started freaking out.
Speaker 0: Like, oh my god, he's dead.
Speaker 0: Because the truth is he did actually give a bunch of journalists a bunch of these documents that are all encrypted and it's believed that if he dies that they will receive the key to decrypt these documents and then spread them, which is sort of like a great way to tell the world, hey, if you're the person who doesn't like me, don't kill me.
Speaker 0: That would be bad for you.
Speaker 1: Or I got killed, hey everybody, if I actually did have real information, avenge me.
Speaker 0: Right, it's like who knows what.
Speaker 1: There could be anything in there, but it's basically a pretty good- If it was just a picture of dick butt.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty good thing to have existing, to have yourself not be killed when you're a person that many people want dead.
Speaker 1: Yep, you just gotta have blackmail somewhere.
Speaker 0: It's also a good way to keep your information safe and spread it around the world, but not actually spread it, but still in the event of your death.
Speaker 0: For example, I could have a document that has all my passwords in it and I could encrypt it and give it to RIM and then have a system set up to where I have to push this button every day
Speaker 1: and if
Speaker 0: I don't push the button for one day, it'll send the key to RIM so he can encrypt and get all the passwords to everything.
Speaker 1: When I'm getting older, I'm still thinking about setting up a system to publish every email I've ever sent or received into the public domain on the day of my death.
Speaker 0: I think I'm going to do the easy way and just put all my passwords and stuff on a piece of paper.
Speaker 1: And then give it to a lawyer.
Speaker 0: And put it in a safe deposit box and then have the keys somewhere.
Speaker 0: and then if I die, someone will find the keys in my apartment.
Speaker 1: If I do that, I might have the will say, "All the media I ever created is public domain.
Speaker 1: if it is legal to public domain
Speaker 1: it."
Speaker 1: Including all my emails, all my correspondence.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't even care.
Speaker 0: I'd be like, "I'm dead.
Speaker 0: What the fuck do I
Speaker 0: care?".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Whoever can find my keys in my apartment, it's like, you know.
Speaker 1: I hope I'm famous enough to where some day, someone working on their senior thesis at some dumpy school somewhere uses RIM's email archive from 100 years ago to research something stupid.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Right, so he did this.
Speaker 0: And we're pretty sure he's not actually dead.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's just a bunch of people freaking out.
Speaker 1: I didn't see any explanation of it, though.
Speaker 0: I think that basically the reasonable explanation is.
Speaker 0: he needed to give a key to somebody and they needed to know that it was definitely from him.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And rather than, you know, digital signing is hard, but if he tweets it, all right.
Speaker 0: And it doesn't matter if anyone else has the key.
Speaker 0: What are they going to do with it?
Speaker 1: Well, it's important.
Speaker 1: if you need to protect the identity of someone you're sending data to as opposed to the data itself.
Speaker 0: Exactly, right.
Speaker 0: So it's like whoever he was sending this information to, we have no idea because he broadcasted the whole world.
Speaker 1: It might have just been a numbers thing, too.
Speaker 1: It could have been a code saying, "Hey, people do a
Speaker 1: thing.".
Speaker 1: I mean, to this day, number stations exist.
Speaker 1: If you listen to the right radio bands, there's human voices just saying numbers.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: 24/7, just numbers.
Speaker 1: Four, eight, seven, nine.
Speaker 1: And there's a bunch of nerds who obsessively try to figure out what these things are and it's pretty much just spy codes.
Speaker 0: It's just a random number generator to help with your encryption.
Speaker 1: It's coded information, but the idea is that you distribute the information to everyone so that no one can pinpoint who you're sending the information to.
Speaker 1: So we'll see.
Speaker 1: At least Snowden, as a person, if we're talking about that stuff, I respect him deeply and I'm glad that he did what he did and I really wish the United States would pardon him and bring him home.
Speaker 0: I don't know why Obama doesn't just pardon him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pardon him and bring him home and then put him on an agency.
Speaker 0: If I was the president right now, I'd be like, "Oh, Everett Snowden, you are now firing whoever's in charge now.
Speaker 0: You are now in charge of the Department of Homeland Security.
Speaker 0: You're the boss of the whole thing because I know you're not corrupt and evil.
Speaker 0: And by the way, if you find anyone corrupt and evil, let me know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but as opposed to, say, Assange and WikiLeaks, which basically prove that it is, at best, gamergate.
Speaker 1: And at worst, it's just like a right-wing propaganda nonsense machine.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, WikiLeaks started out with an honorable mission of take information that shouldn't be secret.
Speaker 1: Wait, no, it started out with an honorable mission of ethics and journalism.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like take information that's being kept secret that probably shouldn't be or doesn't need to be and make it public.
Speaker 0: And it's like, yeah, we should do a lot of that.
Speaker 1: Except it pretty much only targeted left-wing and Jewish and democratic things.
Speaker 0: Well, it just so happens that the people running it are awful people regardless of what their actual mission is, right?
Speaker 0: It's like my mission could be, you know, save the dolphins, right?
Speaker 0: And on the boat of people who are all out saving the dolphins and cutting fishing nets, everyone on the boat's a Nazi.
Speaker 0: And it just so happens they don't save the Jewish dolphins.
Speaker 0: But, you know, it's still.
Speaker 0: the mission itself is fine.
Speaker 0: If anyone else wants to find, you know...
Speaker 1: Yes, the idea of the mission is fine.
Speaker 1: The entire structure of everyone involved in WikiLeaks is corrupt and irretrievably so.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they released many informations that should have been released.
Speaker 1: There's been a pattern of releasing information.
Speaker 0: They released all those like diplomatic things.
Speaker 0: That was like their big one, right, way back years ago.
Speaker 1: I think part of what might have happened is that the WikiLeaks group sort of tried to like get volunteers to help them out, you know, around the world.
Speaker 0: And of course, yeah, if you ask the internet for volunteers, you know who you're going to get.
Speaker 1: GamerGaty-type Reddit people were primarily the people who needed that call.
Speaker 0: Neckbeard1, Neckbeard2, and Neckbeard3.
Speaker 0: They got nothing better to do.
Speaker 0: They got no lives.
Speaker 0: They got no friends.
Speaker 1: Yup, so steer clear of WikiLeaks.
Speaker 0: And they're way libertarian and way believe in that mission.
Speaker 0: Even more than we do.
Speaker 1: In other news, if you might have noticed, Delta Airlines had an outage supposedly due to a power outage somewhere.
Speaker 0: How could you have an outage from a power outage in the modern times when every data center has like mad diesel generators outside of it?
Speaker 1: Sometimes those things fail or they don't come on right away.
Speaker 0: I've never seen that happen.
Speaker 1: It happens all the time.
Speaker 1: You just don't know shit.
Speaker 0: I've never seen that happen.
Speaker 1: Real data centers have blips in power sometimes.
Speaker 1: Like in a serious outage, sometimes the generators don't come on right away.
Speaker 1: And you get a blip of power.
Speaker 0: Deltacrew.com has never gone down because of power outage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm saying that is way more common than you think.
Speaker 0: Like our crappy website can't even be taken down by power outage.
Speaker 0: How does Delta Airlines get taken down by power outage?
Speaker 1: Well, a system probably got rebooted.
Speaker 1: Maybe a UPS itself died.
Speaker 1: That happens sometimes.
Speaker 1: Like redundant power supply might blow up.
Speaker 1: And then the secondary one doesn't kick in right away.
Speaker 1: So the server just reboots.
Speaker 0: All right, but then it comes right back up.
Speaker 1: No, because your server was shitty.
Speaker 1: Your software was shitty.
Speaker 0: Well, why that's your Delta Airlines?
Speaker 0: That should not be.
Speaker 1: So you, Scott, don't seem to... I guess I've worked with a lot more big iron enterprise stuff.
Speaker 1: For the last decade, there has been a continuous drive to reduce the cost of ops because pretty much no one values the operations mission anymore.
Speaker 1: And the bigger iron something is, like the more important it is, I get the impression that the less valued that role actually is.
Speaker 0: Well, everyone's outsourcing all their shit to Amazon, Google, Facebook, etc.
Speaker 0: Rather than do it themselves, which is actually great.
Speaker 1: It's better than having shitty ops that you run is way worse than the lower SLAs of like outsourcing to Amazon.
Speaker 0: It's like you can actually save a ton of money if you do it yourself, but you need mad, knowledgeable, hardworking people that aren't so cheap.
Speaker 1: So, "Large-scale cancellations are expected today while flights already in the air operating
Speaker 1: normally.".
Speaker 1: Basically, no one could check into flights.
Speaker 1: I guess they couldn't send passenger manifests and things that were required to be sent for planes.
Speaker 1: And basically, because their entire information system globally got effed because this one server or system had an outage somewhere, no one could fly, tens of millions of dollars of damages.
Speaker 0: First of all, they probably have an insurance policy against this kind of thing.
Speaker 1: See, that's the other problem.
Speaker 1: If you insure against outages that could have been prevented by operations, that is way cheaper than having an operations team.
Speaker 0: It's like if you think of the operations thing as insurance, the cost of the operations is more expensive than the insurance premium, and it evens out.
Speaker 1: I worked at IBM.
Speaker 1: And IBM was one of the few companies I've ever encountered, just in terms of all my professional experience, that took this kind of stuff seriously internally.
Speaker 1: And we had a real fucking crack ops team.
Speaker 1: And when I worked for that broker-dealer, that was my first Wall Street job.
Speaker 1: I learned since then that that job, that company, probably had 100 times more operations than any other financial company on earth.
Speaker 1: And most people considered what that company that I worked for did to be way overkill.
Speaker 0: You mean the normal amount of stuff?
Speaker 1: Yeah, what I consider to be baby's first, bare minimum operations, is considered by the majority of companies in the world to be overkill.
Speaker 1: So you should actually be terrified of this, because basically no one has significantly capable operations teams to deal with outages, because clearly Delta underestimated the importance of this system, did not have high availability, did not have a rapid disaster recovery, did not have a break glass system of, "Hey, what if that system goes
Speaker 1: down?".
Speaker 1: "Wouldn't it be a
Speaker 1: disaster?".
Speaker 1: "Is there a procedure we can follow to mitigate that
Speaker 1: damage?"?
Speaker 1: Apparently not.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's weird too, if you look at the very top, right?
Speaker 0: The Googles, the Facebooks, the top tier, that shit really doesn't go down.
Speaker 0: I think way back in the day, I remember a couple times it happened, but only in the most infancies, right?
Speaker 0: Amazon went down once in the 90s or something, right?
Speaker 1: I mean Google Calendar or Gmail has gone down a few times in recent memory, but it was outages...
Speaker 0: It was years ago, it's so rare.
Speaker 1: No, there was an outage like a month or two ago.
Speaker 0: I don't remember that.
Speaker 1: Okay, I remember it, it happened.
Speaker 0: It didn't affect me, but anyway.
Speaker 1: Okay, it affected millions of people.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Just because you don't see things doesn't mean they don't happen.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: But the outage lasted hours, and flights were not grounded because of it.
Speaker 0: Sure, but if you go to the second tier, Delta Airlines for example, or Blizzard Entertainment, you think someone who has systems that handle steam?
Speaker 1: Well what, Blizzard actually almost never has outages.
Speaker 0: They fuck up all the time actually, notably.
Speaker 0: Diablo 2 launch, oh, Diablo 3 launch, oh, their systems are down for days.
Speaker 1: Ah, but you wait a few days and everything's fine.
Speaker 0: But shouldn't their shit be working from the beginning?
Speaker 1: I'm going to tell you straight up, it costs so much to make things work from day one, especially under a high load peak, there's literally no money to be made, there's no reason to ever support that.
Speaker 1: And the real problem is expectations.
Speaker 1: People expect a giant new system launching day one, like Pokemon Go for example, to just work when a billion people hit it.
Speaker 0: It should.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: It's not worth the money.
Speaker 1: You'll make the same money if it takes a few weeks for it to actually start working.
Speaker 0: Not if everyone gets pissed and they decide to not play your thing because you're just broke.
Speaker 1: That never happens.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: And look, even then, Overwatch came under a huge DDoS right after they banned all the cheaters in a sudden wave.
Speaker 0: Huge DDoS.
Speaker 1: And let me tell you, DDoSs, like legit ones, they're actually pretty difficult to mitigate.
Speaker 1: Like, there's a lot of systems that claim to mitigate DDoSs, but they still require a lot of tuning.
Speaker 1: And it's not just like, "Oh, the DDoS has
Speaker 1: stopped.".
Speaker 1: It's more like services degraded for hours, possibly days, as you slowly heuristically tune to avoid the DDoS.
Speaker 0: That's why Cloudflare is actually making tons of money.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Cloudflare is still not perfect.
Speaker 1: And under a severe DDoS, you'll see a similar pattern of service degradation, not outage, but significant degradation.
Speaker 1: And then you slowly reapproach.
Speaker 1: You regress back to the mean.
Speaker 0: But when you use Cloudflare, your stuff doesn't get fucked up.
Speaker 0: It gets absorbed by all of Cloudflare.
Speaker 1: What it is also is that you're paying someone else to do that.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like- It's not free.
Speaker 0: They have a free option, actually.
Speaker 0: They do.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: You want the real one.
Speaker 1: That free option, you should just use it if you can.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 0: But you can pay for the real option.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's not actually that expensive if you're just a little tiny website.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, if you outsource to a company like that, their job is deal with this weird edge case that happens occasionally.
Speaker 1: Most companies, there's no money in dealing with the weird edge case that happens occasionally.
Speaker 1: And most companies, there's no money in having a good operations team because the cost of an outage is still less than the cost of what ... To have a really good operations team, like on Wall Street, you need 20 people like me, and I'm not cheap.
Speaker 1: So, you're better off, or at least a lot of companies feel like they're better off, hiring people who cost- It would cost you many millions of dollars a year.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So instead, hire people who cost a fourth what I cost, and you'll deal with the average outage.
Speaker 1: But in the event of a serious outage, you're fucked, and it takes forever to come back online and huge damages.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: Those huge damages were probably still less.
Speaker 0: Were the huge damages less than the millions a year?
Speaker 1: Yeah, sometimes.
Speaker 1: That's the problem.
Speaker 0: How do you know?
Speaker 1: You don't.
Speaker 0: And what's the insurance company going to charge if you want to pay for protection against?
Speaker 1: I would love to know if and how the damages caused by Delta's issue were covered by insurance because- They might not have been.
Speaker 0: They might have just been like, "Oh, we fucked
Speaker 0: up.".
Speaker 0: In which case, they should have paid the more obvs people and considered their salaries to be insurance premiums.
Speaker 1: Now, I've also seen companies where they decide that the potential damages are a cost of doing business.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And that's actually really common.
Speaker 0: They just work it into the budget.
Speaker 0: They're like, "Oh, part of the budget this year.
Speaker 0: We're going to allocate $2 million to this outage we're going to have.
Speaker 0: that's going to make all our customers upset.
Speaker 0: All
Speaker 0: right.".
Speaker 1: But I'll tell you this.
Speaker 1: Usually these problems, like what Delta had, the general case for this is not a super high tech solution or a serious technical hurdle or problem.
Speaker 1: Really, it just takes having someone who's relatively smart and relatively technical and relatively capable, spend the time to look at what your business does, know what it does, and be able to ask questions like, "So what would happen if that thing went down?
Speaker 1: Could you guys recover from
Speaker 1: that?".
Speaker 1: Oh, you couldn't.
Speaker 1: You don't know what that thing is, do you?
Speaker 1: Things of the day.
Speaker 1: This was a little thing.
Speaker 1: It's a little game where you can load the New York City subway system from various eras, including the planned system for 2025, and you can then modify the New York City subway system by adding and removing stations and lines and-
Speaker 0: I tried this thing and it was so broken, I just gave up in 10 seconds.
Speaker 1: See, you say that, but it worked completely fine for me, and I actually started designing.
Speaker 1: what I thought was ... I started seriously trying to improve the subway system in New York based on my knowledge- From Queens to Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: Actually, only one more, but also extending the seven down, and then having an 11 line- You can now go from Flushing south.
Speaker 1: I had an 11 line that follows Super Express on the seven line, but also connecting across from Astoria into the Bronx, and anyway, but the system- Yeah, Queens to Bronx.
Speaker 0: We need that line.
Speaker 0: Actually, a line there, so the cool thing about- Just have a train go over the tribe of our bridge, like whoosh.
Speaker 1: I was looking at some of those lines, places you could put trains to anyway.
Speaker 1: If you don't live in New York, you don't give any shits about this, but if you do live in New York, this is real fun, but more importantly, it does a cool thing.
Speaker 1: It's actually based on data, and it estimates how the ridership, what effect the changes you were making would have on how many people use the system daily, and it estimates how much a MetroCard would cost if you had to pay for the new system.
Speaker 0: It's actually based on census data, jobs data- Because I'm going to tax cars to pay for it.
Speaker 0: Commuting data- That's my system.
Speaker 1: But it basically, it uses data to show you a pretty interesting overall heuristic analysis of what the changes you propose would do to the system, and I tried it out, like yeah, if you had a bunch of bullshit everywhere, the system just gets way worse.
Speaker 1: It knows, but we could have a really cool subway system if we were just willing to pay for it.
Speaker 0: We could have a really cool everything if we were willing to pay for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you got a thing of the day?
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 0: So this dude, he's biking around, and he's biking around, and he gets up on the sidewalk, and a cop immediately walks out to him.
Speaker 1: Was that a cop or a bobby?
Speaker 0: Bobby walks out to him and says, "Hey, why you got your bike in the sidewalk
Speaker 0: there?".
Speaker 0: And he's like getting ready to give him a ticket, and he says, "This is a little bike path here.
Speaker 0: It goes over the sidewalk to the next
Speaker 0: road.".
Speaker 0: And the bobby looks down and he says, "Oh, I guess it
Speaker 0: does.".
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: It's a good day.
Speaker 1: What a weird ending.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's so unusual.
Speaker 1: That is not how it would go down in the US.
Speaker 1: You'd be lucky if you didn't get shot.
Speaker 0: Pretty much.
Speaker 1: I mean, New York, there's that video of the dude who literally got a ticket for riding his bicycle in the street, which was legal, and the reason he was in the street was because the bike lane was blocked by the car
Speaker 0: of the cop who wrote
Speaker 1: him a ticket for not using the bike lane.
Speaker 0: Which isn't even an offense.
Speaker 1: Even though it's not illegal to not use the bike lane.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: So the cop blocked the bike lane and then wrote him a ticket for legally not using the bike lane.
Speaker 0: This has happened at least once to my knowledge.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And I don't know what to say.
Speaker 1: other than American cops shouldn't have guns.
Speaker 1: Can we just hire Britain to send us their cops?
Speaker 0: They don't have enough of them.
Speaker 0: They don't have a lot of land.
Speaker 1: Why don't we do an exchange program?
Speaker 1: We'll send them a bunch of our cops.
Speaker 0: That's not a bad idea, right?
Speaker 0: It's like how many cops are in London, right?
Speaker 0: Take half of them, move them to New York and we'll send you the same number of our cops to go to London.
Speaker 1: I don't think they want our cops.
Speaker 1: That's the problem.
Speaker 0: No, our cops will have to learn how to be London cops with no guns and then we'll cycle like student exchange program until we've cycled all of them, right?
Speaker 1: What if the problem is the cops that come here might want to start wanting guns?
Speaker 0: Uh, maybe.
Speaker 1: We might make things worse instead of better, depends on it.
Speaker 0: I imagine they will both get quite an education in how shit goes down and you know, there's not really a language barrier and eventually everyone will have cycled.
Speaker 1: So you know, I travel a lot and I want to say, I want to point this kind of an aside.
Speaker 1: There is more of a language barrier than you think because when I am in London, I mean, you're not talking to someone from Wales.
Speaker 0: You're talking to someone from London.
Speaker 1: When I am in London, it is surprising how often at a bar or a restaurant I will order something from the menu and the waiter will not understand me and I have to repeat myself multiple times.
Speaker 0: What if you try fake British accent?
Speaker 1: So I feel like that would just offend people.
Speaker 1: However, I have sort of picked up enough of an Australian accent.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: You think it would offend them.
Speaker 0: yet if you ask an Australian or someone from the UK or an English speaking person anywhere on earth who's not from the US to say, please do an American accent invitation.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's so great.
Speaker 0: They would love to hear your fake British accent.
Speaker 1: In London I haven't because it would have felt weird and also I feel like I couldn't do it.
Speaker 1: I would come off like, I would sound like Monty Python at best.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying is like.
Speaker 0: at the one hand, I feel like if I went to say Scotland and said, they would be like, would they be offended?
Speaker 0: Maybe I shouldn't do that and I probably wouldn't, but at the same time I know that there's someone in Scotland who wants to hear me say, ah, let's talk like Scrooge McDuck and would be so happy to hear me do that.
Speaker 1: When I'm trying to speak French in France, like the last time I was in Paris.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's definitely someone in France who wants me to say, and there's someone in France who if I say that will want to kill me.
Speaker 1: But there was a Frenchman in France who gave me some advice.
Speaker 1: There was a waiter and he was super nice and he was really funny.
Speaker 1: This was the same guy who was pretending not to speak English for this other horrific tourist that I saw on the other part of the restaurant.
Speaker 1: But he suggested to me that when I'm speaking my rudimentary French to imagine a stereotypical French accent and affect it and it would sort of even out the awkwardness of me not speaking French very well and I would sound, it would make it easier for people to understand me and it kind of worked and I, and the same thing worked kind of well in Australia.
Speaker 1: Like when I'm there, I'll sort of just slur my words and draw my vowels and try to not say the letter R and it probably sounds kind of dumb, but at the same time, waiters asked me to repeat myself way less often when I do that.
Speaker 1: Like if I'm like a long black, like I kind of brought out like that.
Speaker 1: No one ever says what, but if I say, yeah, can I have a long black?
Speaker 1: They're like, what, what, what do you want?
Speaker 1: What in the meta moment?
Speaker 1: The booklet book was Oryx and Crake by Margaret Atwood.
Speaker 1: We did the show.
Speaker 1: You should read the book and listen to the show.
Speaker 1: It was a really good book.
Speaker 0: Oh, Oh.
Speaker 0: Do you know the book?
Speaker 0: I forgot to completely forgot to tell you what the book club was.
Speaker 1: What's the new book going to be?
Speaker 1: Is it going to be the mad Adam trilogy?
Speaker 0: No, there's actually two books that can be, I got to pick one of the two.
Speaker 1: Oh, you haven't picked yet.
Speaker 0: I will do so right now.
Speaker 1: So I'll warn you if this book is good, I got a good idea for the next book club.
Speaker 1: If the book you choose is one that I do not approve of, there's a nonfiction book.
Speaker 0: I don't see any reason to disprove of either of these books.
Speaker 1: So I just say it, I got a nonfiction book.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to use.
Speaker 0: There's this one book, right?
Speaker 0: That has been like, apparently this is the hot fantasy thing right now.
Speaker 0: And we know we love the hot.
Speaker 1: We're already reading the prince of nothing.
Speaker 0: No, this is supposed to be the hottest thing.
Speaker 0: It's by some lady from Brooklyn, right?
Speaker 0: It's called the fifth season by NK Jemisin.
Speaker 0: Like this is like the hottest thing right now in the fantasy world, right?
Speaker 0: So we can go with that or the other thing we can go with.
Speaker 0: I bought on Kindle.
Speaker 0: It was so cheap.
Speaker 0: I did not know.
Speaker 0: Actually, let me let me ask for him here, rim.
Speaker 0: Alfred Hitchcock.
Speaker 0: We like him, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm a fan.
Speaker 0: He makes good.
Speaker 0: He made good movies when he was alive.
Speaker 1: They had a really good TV show.
Speaker 0: What was the best movie he made?
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: Like you have to break it down by era.
Speaker 1: I mean, he was quite the best like technically or the one that I think he was quite prolific.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, like I really, really like the lady vanishes.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: What movie he made is Scott's favorite movie.
Speaker 0: Yes, right.
Speaker 0: What is what movie he made is Scott's second favorite Alfred Hitchcock movie.
Speaker 1: Not the birds.
Speaker 1: The 39 steps.
Speaker 0: No, birds is kind of lame.
Speaker 0: I don't like birds.
Speaker 0: I don't know why people like that.
Speaker 1: It's not the man who knew too little or too much or whatever.
Speaker 1: No, I don't know.
Speaker 1: You will pretty much only ever talk about Rear Window.
Speaker 0: No, that's because it's the best movie.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the movie that is the second best Alfred Hitchcock movie is Rebecca.
Speaker 0: Have you seen Rebecca?
Speaker 1: I've never actually seen Rebecca.
Speaker 0: Well, that's fucked up.
Speaker 0: So anyway, uh, Rebecca is like one of the best movies ever made.
Speaker 1: Full disclosure, I've seen more of Hitchcock's like weird, like way early movies.
Speaker 0: Because you watched from that box set.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You don't watch anything else because you're an uncultured heathen.
Speaker 1: Oh, and then I pirated off a complete collection of Hitchcock.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're some uncultured heathen anyway.
Speaker 1: Actually, lately I've been watching a bunch of Alfred Hitchcock Presents.
Speaker 0: Well, fine.
Speaker 0: Watch Rebecca today.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Uh, but I did not know because I'm stupid until maybe like a month ago that Rebecca based on a book, the book is called Rebecca by Daphne du Maurier.
Speaker 1: Maybe I should read the book before I watch the movie because then I'll have the perspective of not tainted by the movie.
Speaker 0: Uh, that would be weird.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: That's a rare opportunity.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling it would be like someone watching Terminator 2 for the first time not having had it spoiled for them.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Um, I don't know how many pages are in the book cause I only have this Kindle version which is ridiculously inexpensive.
Speaker 0: Um, I don't know how long it is, but uh, I assume it's a crazy good book.
Speaker 0: So one or both of these and you know what, whichever one I don't pick, the other one's probably going to be the next one.
Speaker 1: Those are pretty good.
Speaker 1: So I'm going to tell you, I'm not going to do the nonfiction book that I really want to do.
Speaker 1: So you've got to reprieve.
Speaker 1: I always threaten you with Dumas, but I feel like if the choice was, you know, the Count Lecompton Monte Cristo or nonfiction, you'd probably rather like the Count.
Speaker 0: All right, so, so what mood are you in?
Speaker 0: Are you in a mood for, Ooh, there's a, you know, a house and this dude is haunted by, you know, his dead wife or whatever or some kind of fantasy thing that's supposedly so hot right now.
Speaker 1: So I'm actually more in the mood for Rebecca because, all right, so I just read the entire fucking wheel of time.
Speaker 1: You want to learn about trollocs?
Speaker 1: Tell you all about trollocs.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 0: So let's read.
Speaker 1: Fourteen books of trollocs.
Speaker 0: So you have to read Rebecca by Daphne du Maurier, French.
Speaker 0: And then, uh, we will later read the fifth season.
Speaker 0: so you can get on that fifth season now if you really want to.
Speaker 1: But you know, I guess I'll pick a book in between those two.
Speaker 0: I'll probably just read one and then read the other.
Speaker 1: I got a few ideas.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to read the mad Adam trilogy really quick, but I'll read the book club book first and those aren't going to be the book club.
Speaker 1: No, I'm just going to read them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm also going to read it.
Speaker 1: I kind of, I want, especially now that I know I've read more snaps as to what the other two are about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm going to read the other two books, especially because multiple people have said repeatedly that the other two books are both better than Oryx and Craig.
Speaker 1: and then Oryx and Craig is still super good.
Speaker 1: So if it's better than Oryx and Craig, I liked Oryx and Craig, so it's only, everything's coming up Milhouse there.
Speaker 0: Also watch the movie Rebecca, what the fuck is wrong with you?
Speaker 1: I'm going to read the book first.
Speaker 0: That's about enough.
Speaker 0: That's a good idea.
Speaker 1: I've read it.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling this is a movie better than book situation.
Speaker 1: It very much could be.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's not, but that's why I kind of want to see otherwise at PAX West, which is coming up sooner than you think less than a month.
Speaker 1: We were doing on Saturday, September 35 PM in the chicken theater, the grind, our newest lecture, all new market on it, and if it's good, it's the only time we'll do it live probably.
Speaker 0: So you'll see why we won't do it again.
Speaker 1: Well, if we, if we do, I only stopped doing a lecture.
Speaker 1: If the video of it that we get at a particular convention is perfect.
Speaker 0: Like if it's really good, like, well, I'll be using this at magfest and shit, what are you talking about?
Speaker 1: All right, fine.
Speaker 1: It'll be the only time we'll do it at a PAX West.
Speaker 0: That's probably true.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Uh, I'm also going to be a PAX dev and I just looked at the schedule.
Speaker 0: cause the whole schedule Yeah, they put the schedule up.
Speaker 1: There's some real good looking stuff.
Speaker 1: The one I'm most interested in, cause it's relevant to us, I guess the schedule is public knowledge.
Speaker 1: It's one on designing, you know, tabletop games or whatever, but specifically with one purpose, like one goal, one angle, and the angle is if you're going to physically actually print produce the game, like it's different kinds of rules or pieces that maybe make it impossible to publish your game because you don't know how to deal with Chinese factories, all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: So I just make a game cards and cards only.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: It's really easy to get cards.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: I don't have to know anything.
Speaker 0: If I know I'm going to print cards and put them in a box.
Speaker 1: So I need interlocking cubes.
Speaker 1: These cubes have to interlock like puzzle pieces.
Speaker 0: I invented Blockus.
Speaker 0: How am I going to make it?
Speaker 1: And seems like the answer is usually you're not, but they made Blockus.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean they make fucking mousetrap.
Speaker 1: Mousetrap.
Speaker 1: Well, mousetrap never really worked.
Speaker 0: Worked for me.
Speaker 1: I never got the original mousetrap set like the original original one.
Speaker 0: I don't know which one you had.
Speaker 0: The mousetrap I had worked just fine.
Speaker 1: Mine was so old that it was like this ancient thing in my grandma's house.
Speaker 0: I definitely didn't have the oldest available mousetrap that has ever been made, but I had seen mousetraps that were super old and they were not significantly different in design than mine, except mine was made of like cheapo plastic in some parts.
Speaker 1: I wonder if someone's uploaded a 3D print of all the pieces for mousetrap.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you could.
Speaker 1: I'm curious if someone did.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Otherwise.
Speaker 0: I guess you can't 3D print the rubber band or the marble, the metal ball.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, stay tuned for magfest.
Speaker 1: I think hotels went live, so I guess if you need a hotel room, it's probably all sold out and it's too late and you can't go to magfest now.
Speaker 1: I guess badges are on sale, I think.
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: Will be at magfest.
Speaker 1: We filled out the form.
Speaker 1: Will be there doing the same stuff.
Speaker 1: We always do at magfest.
Speaker 1: Magfest is our favorite non-Paxcon.
Speaker 1: It is approaching equal, but different.
Speaker 1: Like if you had to choose between Pax East and magfest, kind of would say magfest.
Speaker 1: But if you had to choose between Pax Prime and magfest, I think Pax Prime still edges it out.
Speaker 1: So we've done a lot of shows on computer components and I think we've covered pretty much everything.
Speaker 1: So there's not much left, so I guess we're going to talk about, and this will be a short show, kind of on purpose, all the weird peripherals, like specialized crap, anything that isn't like a normal thing, like things that you don't automatically buy when you buy a new computer.
Speaker 0: Most people buy a mouse and a keyboard, but there's so many other input devices that are only for specialized purposes, most of which I've never bought or used.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: What have I bought ever?
Speaker 0: I bought- They've got crazy 3D things you can get, and I've seen things in the past that were gimmicks, like finger- Remember the mouse man, the 3D mouse?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the stuff like that.
Speaker 0: There was a thing where you put it on your finger and it said you worked with brain waves, but it didn't really work.
Speaker 0: It was bullshit.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 0: I once bought a keyboard- Toy sticks and game pads, but I mean, that's just common sense, right?
Speaker 1: We don't need to talk about those.
Speaker 1: I bought a long time ago a keyboard extension.
Speaker 1: It was like a thing that you put plugged into your keyboard slot, and then you plug your keyboard into it, and it had some buttons on it, and those buttons, you could map them to be special keys, and I basically used it as a gaming input device, except it barely worked.
Speaker 1: It was a piece of shit.
Speaker 0: I mean, my earliest keyboards, I bought one that had extra buttons on it, but at one point, I was using the Happy Hacking keyboard, which had no numpad, and I wanted a numpad, so I bought this thing that was a numpad and a wireless mouse, wireless numpad mouse combo deal, and it had weird stuff.
Speaker 0: It was also a timer and a clock and a thermometer, it told you the room temperature and all this stuff, and I bought one, it totally worked, and I used it a bunch, and also, I would sometimes just take the wireless mouse part only and use it with a laptop, and it was quite a useful thing when I had it, but now I have no use for that anymore.
Speaker 1: So I guess the only things that we use, that we have a lot of experience with, the only things we've bought in the modern era of computing that really constitutes specialized input, I guess except game pads, but that's one.
Speaker 0: I already said, there's nothing to say about game pads.
Speaker 1: You know what I could say?
Speaker 1: The Steam controller is kind of shitty.
Speaker 0: It's average.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's eh.
Speaker 0: You're probably better off with your PlayStation or Xbox controller plugging into the PC.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: But the two things that both Scott and I have are drawing tablets, or at least Scott has a drawing tablet and I have a drawing tablet, and I have a basically video editing knob.
Speaker 0: Right, and obviously if you're a person who draws, you want to get the fanciest Wacom, maybe even the Cintiq, because like, whoa man, right?
Speaker 0: That's like the best drawing thing there is in the world, but if you can't draw, why the hell would you want one of these things?
Speaker 1: Those are the kinds of tools that are beyond the scope of this episode, because like my giant mixer.
Speaker 0: I've never used one except at a demo station.
Speaker 1: Well look, yes, I've played with them at PAX's.
Speaker 1: That's literally it.
Speaker 1: But like the giant mixer that I'm touching next to my computer.
Speaker 0: It's not a computer peripheral, really.
Speaker 1: Well, it's a weird specialized peripheral for professionals, but you only need it if you have a super specialized ultra professional, like.
Speaker 1: never buy something like that unless you are using that for like a job, because the Cintiq is like that.
Speaker 0: But the cheapo Wacoms tablet, like the cheapest, cheapest one is actually way, way cheap.
Speaker 0: It's like less than a hundred bucks.
Speaker 0: The tiny crappy one.
Speaker 0: And you know what, if you have a computer, it's actually not a bad idea to buy that no matter what.
Speaker 0: Because even if you rarely use it, that one time you want to like do something in MS paint or make a funny drawing or even just using the windows snip tool for a screenshot.
Speaker 1: And then you will like write a note on the screenshot before you send it to someone.
Speaker 0: compared to doing it with the mouse or having to own a tablet.
Speaker 0: It's like an iPad tablet.
Speaker 0: It's so cheap.
Speaker 0: It's like, why not have?
Speaker 0: you could even buy the old version of the crappy one.
Speaker 0: It'll be just fine.
Speaker 0: You can probably get a used one that someone got rid of like 20 bucks.
Speaker 1: So here's what I use mine.
Speaker 0: I have actually the medium level one.
Speaker 0: It's actually pretty good with buttons on the side, because even though I don't draw for photo editing, if you do photo photography stuff, it's way good and useful.
Speaker 0: Like, oh crap, I need to make this person's face brighter and you can do that the mouse or you do it the pen.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: it just makes your life so much easier.
Speaker 0: More comfortable.
Speaker 1: It's like one of the things I do at work and it's inexpensive.
Speaker 0: Only the way the Cintiq ones that are also monitors are expensive, really.
Speaker 1: But I'm a UX designer.
Speaker 1: So one of the things I do is I just draw and I use mischief just like a drawing pad.
Speaker 1: And the cool thing about it is it's just a vector drawing tool with infinite zoom and an infinite canvas.
Speaker 1: So just draw all over it and save it, whatever.
Speaker 0: So I would not waste paper.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So basically, whenever I'm at work, any time I would use paper, I just draw with my tablet instead.
Speaker 0: I stop doodling on paper.
Speaker 0: I doodle on my iPad with a magic pencil.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like I don't keep anything.
Speaker 0: It's like, oh, my God.
Speaker 0: Magic pencils, a ripoff for one hundred bucks.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is.
Speaker 0: It is a super ripoff for one hundred bucks and magic pencil.
Speaker 0: But I've already saved more than one hundred dollars in ink and pens and papers of doodles.
Speaker 1: But the other thing I use them for is that I can make better doodles.
Speaker 1: Most tablet interfaces are also a multi-touch pad like you'd have on a super fancy laptop.
Speaker 1: The use of that is one, if I'm playing like Civ five, actually leaning back, holding that tablet to interact with the game instead of using my mouse way better.
Speaker 1: And also, if I'm playing Civ five on my laptop, no laptop has a good touchpad anymore unless you get a MacBook.
Speaker 1: So I pretty much need that to do anything on my laptop at this point.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, I don't really use it for anything.
Speaker 1: But see, it's a specialized.
Speaker 0: It's so worth the small price paid for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like you pay a nominal fee to have an augmented device next to your mouse for specialized input.
Speaker 0: Like if you have Photoshop installed on your computer or Lightroom installed on your computer, you should have one.
Speaker 0: If not, you know, maybe buy the super cheap one if you can get a discount.
Speaker 0: Otherwise.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: The moment the first time you ever are trying to draw something in the gimp, even if it's something dumb, you should probably just buy one of these things and use it for that forever.
Speaker 0: So you never need to like replace it or as long as you don't break it, it'll be good forever.
Speaker 0: As long as USB is still a thing.
Speaker 1: So this jog wheel I got now.
Speaker 1: originally I was going to go way cheaper.
Speaker 1: I was thinking because all I really was the problem was one day I was using Premiere after an update and they reversed what the mouse wheel does in some of the interfaces.
Speaker 1: And also they changed the way the sensitivity were made up was down and down was up.
Speaker 0: Basically, you can change it in the options preferences.
Speaker 1: You could change it kind of, but not a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: like I couldn't get it back to the way I liked it.
Speaker 1: And even then, my pipeline was not great because you couldn't just adapt to the new way.
Speaker 1: So the problem was my workflow.
Speaker 0: That's what I do.
Speaker 1: My workflow, because I added a lot more video than you, was never super optimal.
Speaker 1: Kind of like how imagine doing your workflows in Lightroom without a tablet.
Speaker 1: Like I use Lightroom.
Speaker 0: I'd be okay if I didn't, you know, sometimes you don't got to draw on a picture.
Speaker 1: But like my, my, uh, my workflows in Premiere or like my workflows in Lightroom are way simple so I don't use it often enough to need the specialized input.
Speaker 1: Like yeah, maybe I'm not as efficient, but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Like you don't need to be more efficient.
Speaker 0: It's not really about the efficiency so much.
Speaker 0: Actually I could be more efficient.
Speaker 0: It's also less pleasant.
Speaker 0: It's when you have to do stuff that's sort of like drawing, right?
Speaker 0: Like I got to brighten up the sky and you got to like drag this gradiated filter or you want, you're poking at someone's face, you're moving all their like zits and shit.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You don't remove natural things like a mole, but you know, someone's got like a zit.
Speaker 0: It's like you got to hit it with the, you know, and like going clicking on the thing is a lot more less pleasant than, you know, going with the pen.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But it's the comfort thing too.
Speaker 1: Like it's less comfortable to do the suboptimal thing.
Speaker 1: But say I only edit video a couple of times a year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: Just adapt.
Speaker 1: It's fine.
Speaker 1: But I edit video almost every day.
Speaker 1: Like I added a lot of video.
Speaker 1: I fuck around premiere all the time.
Speaker 1: So getting the specialized knob, not only did I get around the minor annoyance, how does a knob that turn help with video editing?
Speaker 1: So what you can't do with the mouse is there's two things.
Speaker 1: They're shuttling and there's jogging and they're very different use cases.
Speaker 1: So if I, so one, if I spin the wheel, every clicks like a mouse wheel.
Speaker 1: Every click is one frame.
Speaker 0: I mean my mouse wheel clicks.
Speaker 0: I can do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So if I spin it fast, my mouse wheel does that too.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: If I spin it fast, it does not accelerate or decelerate.
Speaker 1: It is just clicks equals frames by default in premiere.
Speaker 1: In most places, if you spin your mouse wheel real fast, it'll accelerate unless you go in and change a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: And it's not just that the, so your computer doesn't see this wheel as a mouse.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: It sees this wheel as a specialized interface.
Speaker 0: Is it like a game pad as far as windows is concerned?
Speaker 1: It has its own driver.
Speaker 1: It's its own thing.
Speaker 1: So it, so this is the thing is a specialized tool.
Speaker 1: So it has software and the drivers are set up.
Speaker 0: So premiere has special knowledge of this, the way that Photoshop has special knowledge of Wacom tablets.
Speaker 1: Premiere actually has special stuff for jog wheels and shuttles and all these things in general.
Speaker 1: because if you're a super pro, you'll have a giant editing console and it just premiere just says, Oh, you have money.
Speaker 1: Let me just work with that thing.
Speaker 1: This is just the cheap version of that.
Speaker 1: So it's, it's got that one thing like, yeah, your mouse can do that.
Speaker 1: But around the wheel, the, the, the, the wheel where I can do the frame by frame, I have another wheel that I can turn about 80 degrees in either direction.
Speaker 1: Then it stops and it Springs back to center.
Speaker 0: Oh, that kind.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So if you turn it forward a little bit, the move, the video starts playing at a crazy almost like a steering wheel.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And the fast, the more I move it to the right, the faster the video plays and I can go back the same way.
Speaker 1: So thinking about when you're editing, I can be like, all right, Scott's talking.
Speaker 1: I know what he's saying.
Speaker 1: Wait, did I cough?
Speaker 1: And I let go and it stops.
Speaker 1: I go back a little bit like, yep, there's a cough.
Speaker 1: And then I, I switched from that to the frame by frame and I get to the X spot and then I got all these buttons.
Speaker 0: I have to do that, uh, by using the, like I'll control all and shift and different combinations and the arrow keys on the keyboard.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's how I have to do it.
Speaker 1: So see, if I was only editing video and audio occasionally, then yeah, I would just do what Scott did.
Speaker 1: But I do this stuff all the time.
Speaker 1: The same thing works in audition for the audio and also the keys do all the buttons.
Speaker 1: There's a whole array of buttons on the top.
Speaker 0: Well that means you're putting your left hand on this wheel, right?
Speaker 0: And your right hand's on the mouse.
Speaker 0: So you need to be buttons there cause you can't hit any keyboard shortcuts.
Speaker 0: So you need buttons around the wheel just because you, even though you have buttons on your keyboard, you only really need the wheel.
Speaker 0: You can't touch those keyboard buttons.
Speaker 0: You'd have to move your hand.
Speaker 0: Therefore the wheel must come with buttons.
Speaker 0: So same way with the Wacom tablet, it's like, yeah, I bought the Wacom tablet with buttons.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: Because if I have it on my lap and the pen in my right hand, I can't have like my left hand over on the keyboard.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know what the most important button on my tablet is?
Speaker 1: Control Z. Yeah.
Speaker 1: Because literally when I'm actually drawing in a vector thing, it's draw, draw, control Z, draw, draw, control Z, control Z. So yeah, putting your holding, putting your hand on the keyboard every time to control Z. No, I just tap the button on the upper left of my tablet.
Speaker 0: So there's not much more to say.
Speaker 1: I mean, it really just comes down to if you do something occasionally, just use the, use the generic tool.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there's a whole world out there of specialized computer peripheral things that we're not using.
Speaker 1: I mean, but like think of this, if you do, if you, it's a general purpose computer, right?
Speaker 1: So you can do pretty much anything with a mouse and keyboard.
Speaker 1: And unless you have a good reason, you might as well do everything with a mouse and keyboard.
Speaker 1: But like, kind of like how you own some cheap screwdrivers.
Speaker 1: They're pretty generic.
Speaker 1: They work okay.
Speaker 1: You don't need fancy screwdrivers in your house unless you use screwdrivers every day.
Speaker 0: You might need a power one.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But the more you've, the more often you use screwdrivers, the better screwdrivers you should own.
Speaker 1: The more variety of screwdrivers you should own.
Speaker 1: Same thing with the computer.
Speaker 0: So let us know about whatever weird thing you got plugged into your computer.
Speaker 0: that's not normal.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: The
Speaker 1: Patreon patrons for this episode, in order of the amount of money they give us on a continuous basis are Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Nicholas Brandau, Logan Stafford, Heidi McNichol, Amanda Duchette, James David White, Christian Kuhn, Construction Noises, MyStady.com, Sean Hayworth, William Eisenroz, Jeremy Miner, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: Aaron Cerise, Michelle Garcia, Brian Fisher, SailorVista, Ernie Hudson vs.
Speaker 1: The World, Iggy Kidd, Matthew Smith, Don Schleich, Jar Tovish, and Joe Schur, Joe Star, Tyler Eller, Sean Yeager, Sam Cordery, Clinton Walton, Run from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Ray Lavelle, Brian Sivroni, Rochelle Montanona, Finn-Erik Solveraude, Banzai Buddy, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redmond, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: If you didn't notice, I post for at least the patrons above that super line that I'm starting an eight player patrons only Civ 5 game, seven of you and me, and we'll fight it out and I'll video all my turns and I won't necessarily publish those turns, at least not except on a significant delay, because otherwise you guys will just cheat and beat me.
Speaker 1: But if I don't get a full set of eight from the five dollar and up patrons within a few more days, we're getting close but not there yet, I'll open it up to all the patrons and I think it'll be fun.
Speaker 1: Fair warning, based on the people who have already requested to join the game, at least be okay at Civ before you join, otherwise you're just going to be fresh meat for the meat grinder.
Speaker 1: There's some people joining this game who I think are very good at Civ, that's the impression that I get.
Speaker 1: Expect some Rims Rants and Rimly reviews in the near near future as I continue to re-ramp up everything post-plague and post-Connecticon, and also I'm working real hard on editing that Atari game design panel together because I finally have enough good video and enough time and I have that knob.
Speaker 1: So now I leave you with something strange.
Speaker 1: So they've found it again, have they?
Speaker 1: I thought we'd taken care of it.
Speaker 0: The forces of evil are persistent, sir.
Speaker 1: I'm getting too old for this.
Speaker 1: Who have we got lined up to deal with this problem?
Speaker 0: Murphy, sir.
Speaker 1: Oh no, not Murphy.
Speaker 0: Afraid so, sir.
Speaker 1: What about Spade or Marlowe?
Speaker 0: Uh, dead, sir.
Speaker 1: Isn't there anyone else?
Speaker 0: Sorry sir, he's next on the list.
Speaker 1: Well, I suppose we'll have to make do.
Speaker 1: Knowing Murphy, he's going to need help.
Speaker 1: A lot of help.
Speaker 1: I'll check the archives and get back to you, sir.