Speaker 0: It's Tuesday July 5th 2016.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: that was good, and this is geek nights tonight speed runs and other exhibitions of video game prowess.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Kind of feeling roller coasters.
Speaker 0: I've been thinking about roller coasters a lot like that.
Speaker 0: clock hasn't rung in a long time And it's really ringing.
Speaker 1: What okay?
Speaker 0: What I just really want to ride a roller coaster All right, so I'm thinking about going to ride a roller coaster all right, okay?
Speaker 0: You've been very unexcited about pretty much everything lately.
Speaker 0: Are you dying?
Speaker 1: What's there to be excited about?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: it's summer.
Speaker 0: We can buy it.
Speaker 0: stuff's nice.
Speaker 0: I'm doing that all right You're not excited about it.
Speaker 1: What is there to say?
Speaker 0: is there anything you're excited about in the entire world?
Speaker 1: All right, the weather's still good.
Speaker 1: It's gonna sell it for a while.
Speaker 0: Tycho tweeted the other day, and he was like basically it appears that he encountered fascination for the first time.
Speaker 0: hmm and fascination is the thing that's not widely known.
Speaker 0: it was very popular in like the 50s like the late 50s early 60s and By the 70s it was basically gone from all the places that it existed Except cedar point which had one of the first rigs, and it was like a big deal there.
Speaker 0: It was there at cedar point from 1955 until like the 2000s when they finally got rid of it because no one cares about What is actually kind of a shitty game?
Speaker 1: We could just make a fascination if you really wanted one.
Speaker 0: Yeah But you could.
Speaker 1: as long as someone maintains the memory of how the game is played anyone can make one if they ever wanted to.
Speaker 1: Yep actually That would be a good thing for someone to make a digital version of on phones that everyone like.
Speaker 0: it's like oh Yeah, when everyone just fascinates and in fact you want to make it a little engaging like you have to flick the balls up.
Speaker 0: So it's all like that kind of obviously Game to begin with.
Speaker 0: yeah, even though it isn't.
Speaker 0: it's just a random game that you can.
Speaker 1: obviously we'd put lots of randomness into the Engine after you play your dexterity bit basically multiplayer Angry Birds.
Speaker 0: But so this game you know he tweeted about it, and I just remembered that it existed and It can't.
Speaker 0: this is like the second time it had disappeared from my life, and then out of nowhere I bump into it somewhere.
Speaker 1: I didn't wild where they had it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I was some years ago.
Speaker 0: We go to wildwood one year, and I'm like what fascination.
Speaker 0: There's no way and we walk in as totally it.
Speaker 0: so I Can't vouch for the chain of custody.
Speaker 0: But I found a blog that claims That the fat at least some of the fascination set that is in Wildwood was the one they took from cedar point Mmm.
Speaker 0: I can't verify that.
Speaker 0: I don't know how I could verify the head other than trying to call people.
Speaker 0: that could be some investigative journalism, but What I did find is a photo.
Speaker 0: because the building you know if that area of cedar point Was just a really cool area because it was built in the 50s that part The park was already old at that point and they built like this brand new modern pavilion And like this giant convention center and all these buildings and fascination was a part of it, so I found this photo from The 90s.
Speaker 0: it looks like and you can see the fascination building there.
Speaker 0: And I found this other photo from the 50s and you can see that.
Speaker 0: It's literally Clothing.
Speaker 0: the people are wearing Mm-hmm, it's good stuff.
Speaker 0: So I could kind of want to go to see the point like real bad that that I saw that photo when I was like Oh, man, and then I spent like 10 minutes.
Speaker 0: Just looking at pictures of like the Millennium Force.
Speaker 1: So just go I'm thinking about it.
Speaker 0: I think stop you.
Speaker 0: I gotta find a free weekend.
Speaker 0: We had a lot of shit going on.
Speaker 1: You can just go like tomorrow me back in time for kinetic on.
Speaker 0: uh I could except I got shit to do.
Speaker 0: so if I got shit to do for kinetic on don't do that shit Alright.
Speaker 0: anyway got any news because there's actually a lot of gaming news.
Speaker 1: suddenly It is one ginormous gaming news.
Speaker 1: So it's been sort of a half news for a while, right?
Speaker 1: This is one of those news stories or when it first showed up.
Speaker 1: I was like, that's not news.
Speaker 1: I read about that like a month ago.
Speaker 1: Yes that the.
Speaker 1: the non news is that people are basically gambling on eSports using Things in steam to launder the money, right?
Speaker 1: So I think we explained this and we talked about this when it was news to begin with.
Speaker 1: but just to reiterate So you're maybe underage or maybe you're in a you're betting on eSports You're almost definitely under the age of 18 or do not have a credit card or maybe right, you know You.
Speaker 1: for some you want to bet on something that you normally not allowed to bet on sports gambling and you want to bet on?
Speaker 1: eSports like.
Speaker 1: I bet rim is gonna win this counter-strike match or I bet Dago's gonna win this Street, so in other words, you're already a moron, right?
Speaker 1: You're already more on betting on this.
Speaker 1: so You go and you can't use real money for this because you get the shut the fuck down in jail and bad stuffs and a That wants to facilitate that obviously can't do it with real money because even the fan duel and you know draft kings Which are enormous had, you know, bajillions of dollars were advertising all over TV.
Speaker 1: huge companies got shut down, right?
Speaker 1: Because you can't get away with that.
Speaker 1: So what people did is they said all right everyone turn your money into like counter-strike skins will gamble the skins And then you can turn it back into money and it'll be money laundering and it'll totally work.
Speaker 1: and it worked and it still works Today.
Speaker 1: you can do this now.
Speaker 0: That is not the whole story.
Speaker 0: That's just like what I think that's.
Speaker 1: that's the old news.
Speaker 1: That was.
Speaker 1: that's been so.
Speaker 1: we talked about that a long time ago when it started happening and it's not new.
Speaker 1: Here's the new thing.
Speaker 1: So there was a site that was facilitating this sort of gambling.
Speaker 1: Okay, this site was being promoted on certain counter-strike streamers YouTube channels.
Speaker 0: Yep, shouting man, right?
Speaker 1: So obviously if you're a you know counter-strike streamer, that's the kind of sponsor you're gonna get.
Speaker 1: it makes total sense.
Speaker 1: Okay Those YouTube streamers were revealed to have been the owners of that site.
Speaker 1: So this is like it's low.
Speaker 0: What did you say?
Speaker 0: It's like if I ran three-card Monty and I played against my own Three-card Monty in a YouTube stream and I was winning a ton of money.
Speaker 0: because look how fucking great I am at this Isn't it amazing?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: It's basically you should also play this three-card Monty that I don't.
Speaker 1: they didn't reveal the fact that they own this Company, they just pretended like they were being sponsored by it and then they were on stream or on YouTube would you know?
Speaker 1: gamble and Win.
Speaker 1: so it's like if it's like if I went into the Scott casino and you didn't know that I was Scott and I made A video of myself at the roulette table and he just kept landing on my number and I was raking it in.
Speaker 1: I'm like, wow everyone this Scott casino was just sponsoring me, you know, they're paying me to advertise how great they are.
Speaker 1: But look I came here and I'm totally raking it in like at the roulette table.
Speaker 1: Holy shit everyone.
Speaker 1: You got to come down to the Scott casino.
Speaker 1: It's crazy.
Speaker 1: You didn't know that it literally not only was You know me owning the casino, but also that roulette table is rigged.
Speaker 1: And if you come to the Scott casino You're gonna lose all your money and the whole casino is built on top of a giant money laundering ring, right?
Speaker 1: So these guys got caught and revealed.
Speaker 0: now what's a huge fiasco?
Speaker 1: This is one.
Speaker 0: it's almost like another step toward Big boy times with eSports because that's the kind of corruption that you get in real things where there's real money.
Speaker 0: But they're not real big time yet They're little baby money.
Speaker 0: And the reason you know, there's still a little baby money is that this is such a government hasn't?
Speaker 0: first It's such babies.
Speaker 0: first scam like it took what was out of the call.
Speaker 0: someone posted a video like.
Speaker 0: they figured this out.
Speaker 0: It took basically a few minutes of investigative journalism to figure out what was going on.
Speaker 0: Like this was not the best and brightest minds and organized crime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is like a couple steps below Fat Tony.
Speaker 1: Right, but the regulated casinos of the world.
Speaker 1: You should take bets on eSports because apparently people want to make those bets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the people who want to make those bets are Probably dumb young kids and they only have counter-strike skins to bet.
Speaker 1: they don't have money to bet.
Speaker 0: Yep So if you'll take counter-strike skins if I can go to your casino give you a counter-strike skin and get chips and we're gonna talk.
Speaker 1: Also noteworthy that like valve as you know Shut them down to an extent.
Speaker 1: But valve is not like done everything within their power that they could do if they wanted to to shut this down.
Speaker 0: Well, the problem is there's no way to 100% shut this kind of thing down just because unless you remove the markets or skins I'm waiting for the shoe to drop and the government to come after.
Speaker 1: pretty much everyone Who has sort of a currency like steam has steam money that can be exchanged into real money Like even I'm surprised they'd have it in all these years gone after like Second Life money, which can be turned into real money
Speaker 0: I think the only reason they have not enough money
Speaker 1: or Eve online money, which can be turned into real money, right?
Speaker 1: Eventually, the government is gonna cut.
Speaker 1: our governments of the world will go after these things.
Speaker 0: Even if they can't be turned back into real money directly they can still be used for these purposes because they have a value Because there is a market even if that markets entirely within these egos.
Speaker 1: yes, but would you bet a picture of Abraham Lincoln that could get you a bacon egg and cheese sandwich?
Speaker 1: and Even if you won and the winnings were huge you can get a million dollars.
Speaker 1: But those million dollars could only be used to buy pokeballs in Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you would not make that bet because you'd rather have a union.
Speaker 1: five dollars of real money.
Speaker 1: They could be used for anything.
Speaker 1: but the problem is more valuable than a bazillion dollars That can only be used for you worthless counter-strike skins.
Speaker 0: If you made it the other way like in overwatch their skins, right?
Speaker 0: Like there's all this stuff There's no way to trade them with other people.
Speaker 0: You can just get.
Speaker 1: they do that on purpose because they don't want this kind of shit to have.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a one-way valve.
Speaker 0: they come into you and you can't.
Speaker 0: they can't ever go away from you.
Speaker 0: You can't like sell your sweet sick skin to someone.
Speaker 1: Yep, but like the directness of this scam is almost Insulting quote but cover makes money on this right because they make a cut every time you make a you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sell some shit on Steam.
Speaker 0: So wasn't even worse.
Speaker 0: They were from what I read.
Speaker 0: they were going so far as to make fake videos like straight-up Rigged matches as part of all this.
Speaker 1: Like it goes it's not like you're gonna find the server and spectate it and see and watch the match.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like if I made a betting ring, but it's not even the sting.
Speaker 0: remember that world WWF wrestling board game from the late 80s?
Speaker 0: No, well, it came with a VHS tape and maybe I do.
Speaker 0: occasionally in the game You'd both like get a wrestler like I get Hulk Hogan and you get Andre the Giant and then you'd watch Like a part of the VHS tape and you'd see the match and whichever whichever wrestler won you got points.
Speaker 0: It'd be like if I ran a betting ring on that VHS tape.
Speaker 1: Oh, if you haven't seen it the movie the sting it's maybe like I Can't.
Speaker 1: I can't make a ranking right now, but top 50 movies of all time ever buried me.
Speaker 1: It's a real good man the history of human beings.
Speaker 1: So you have to see that it's a necessary movie for all human beings to watch.
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: watch regardless
Speaker 1: of actual rank and
Speaker 0: realize that What they what the characters pull off in in that movie is so far beyond the little baby scam that happened here
Speaker 1: Yep, and even the sting which when you watch it seems like pro mode is not even real close to real pro mode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I guess eSports is starting to come of age.
Speaker 0: But the problem is you're gonna get basically any time like an industry appears like this and gets to a certain level.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of obvious dumb scams that you could do to make a lot of money and no one no one bigger than you Or smarter than you is paying attention enough to stop you.
Speaker 0: Like if you try to do like baby's first scam in like the drug trade or Any of the things that the real mafias in you'll be dead.
Speaker 0: They'll either kill you or they'll take all your money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like and people.
Speaker 1: It's like people who know how three-card money works and go to one and start winning.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what happens when you walk away from the three-card money.
Speaker 1: They come and beat you up and take the money back.
Speaker 1: But here like you're not smart.
Speaker 0: there are.
Speaker 0: no one big is watching this.
Speaker 0: yet So small fry took out smaller fry you got.
Speaker 0: you know There's way more similar level corruption and nonsense going on in this realm.
Speaker 0: the moral of all of this?
Speaker 0: don't bet on eSports.
Speaker 0: It's the dumbest thing you could do don't?
Speaker 1: I mean first of all betting at all is dumb because even if you bet in a regulated Non-cheating place like a real legit casino the house always wins.
Speaker 0: and you know, even if you ever bought a stock I mean, you know It's just a sliding scale.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying just saying.
Speaker 0: But no, you're right.
Speaker 0: Don't go to casinos Don't bet money in casinos.
Speaker 0: if you're gonna bet money at least bet money that you expect.
Speaker 1: if you're going to bet money Bet it in that legit casino and not in some unregulated crazy house.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz look they can just take your money and I'll give you anything back as they fuck you.
Speaker 1: We're not regulated.
Speaker 1: We're just you just gave me money for nothing.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh Yeah, at least in the casino they take your money, but then they give you like free food.
Speaker 1: If the casino doesn't give you money when you give them the chips back like the cops will come and make them do it Right or they get shut.
Speaker 1: this things will happen.
Speaker 1: but if you buy some chips at the you know random you buy some counter jury skins to gamble with and They don't give you money in exchange for skins.
Speaker 1: You're just fucked.
Speaker 1: You're sitting there with a fancy-looking gun and you that's it.
Speaker 0: But it's interesting because they did this shadily to make their money and be semi-legal like they advertise the site like it was an open site but Bitcoin exists, they weren't even big enough fry to just do it like directly with bitcoins.
Speaker 0: Think about that.
Speaker 0: They had to go a step below Bitcoin as their current.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's because their target audience couldn't get bitcoins.
Speaker 1: their target audience though is kids who have time and don't even have credit cards.
Speaker 1: so they can just play counter-strike and Get skins and then bet with them.
Speaker 1: and then literally you see if like you're a kid You have no money.
Speaker 1: So you play counter-strike and you win some skins by playing counter-strike.
Speaker 1: You just earn it with time which you have plenty of and then you turn those.
Speaker 1: you can turn those skins into a bunch of Money to buy steam games if you gamble and win with them as opposed to Grinding even more and steam games are worth way more to kids that age the kids who have so much free time.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's just.
Speaker 0: I don't have a lot of sympathy for the people who are betting on this stuff Because how can you how do you not see this coming?
Speaker 0: But at the same time?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I kind of expecting all this to get shut down and Maybe some of these people go to jail like.
Speaker 0: I don't think so because I don't think it's even big enough time.
Speaker 1: I don't think there's any DA or anything or federal agent or anyone who's even noticed this thing has happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not.
Speaker 1: the Justice Department isn't even like this isn't even like a paper in their office.
Speaker 0: But in a way it's kind of like the scammers who only target load small drug dealers because the small drug dealer can't call the police On you when they were drug deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's kind of the same thing.
Speaker 0: But they're targeting the same kinds of kids who buy games.
Speaker 0: they trade their games in at the electronics boutique Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So in other news, there's an article on Kotaku and it was big in the rounds.
Speaker 0: I kind of feel like I got to talk about it because it it is such a tag is still around.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's part of my news.
Speaker 0: Okay But well actually interestingly when I googled for the thing we just talked about The number one result is a bunch of Kotaku articles.
Speaker 0: Not any other side.
Speaker 0: Whatever it's a true story, uh The other thing not this thing your thing your thing Kotaku is like the number one source when I googled.
Speaker 0: But anyway this thing it's just an op-ed on Kotaku about overwatch, but it was titled overwatch is competitive mode is at odds with the rest of the game.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of thing that someone like us might say in a panel and then try to back it up with some evidence.
Speaker 0: And I saw a lot of people commenting on this.
Speaker 0: But this article is sort of amazing because it's basically Complaining up.
Speaker 0: it's like it.
Speaker 0: it's like you complaining about a banana because it's yellow and it tastes good and You could throw the peel on the ground someone might slip on it.
Speaker 0: and that's funny like Complaining about the thing for being the thing it is and complaining about the thing for the thing for the thing that the thing is supposed to be The.
Speaker 0: so basically the article talks about how overwatch Players have a certain sort of Expectation of the game like you're gonna keep leveling up like you're always progressing That it's not a super serious competition that you can just sort of play for fun that the matchmaking is very individually driven So you can just randomly play with people.
Speaker 0: it'll always be fun, and he's mad that because the competitive mode exists People who are serious about the game Look down on.
Speaker 0: the non-competitive mode is not being the real game.
Speaker 1: What do you care?
Speaker 1: what someone else does?
Speaker 1: you don't like the competitive mode don't play it.
Speaker 1: What does it matter whether it exists or not?
Speaker 0: mad that the people who are in competitive mode if he plays in it?
Speaker 0: That's not even playing.
Speaker 1: That's like if you're playing in the little league and you're mad.
Speaker 1: the Major League Baseball exists.
Speaker 1: It's like you can just not watch it and not pay attention to it.
Speaker 1: Just keep playing a little league game.
Speaker 1: What's the problem?
Speaker 0: yep?
Speaker 0: But he's also like he gets in a pretty specific detail about like how you level up and level up in the normal game But then in the competitive game you might level down like.
Speaker 0: that feels real bad.
Speaker 0: don't suck.
Speaker 0: It feels bad to have an elo ranking.
Speaker 1: if you suck don't play it.
Speaker 1: then yeah, what's the problem?
Speaker 1: I mean this isn't new.
Speaker 1: this is like hundred-year-old news, right?
Speaker 1: It's there are people who are gamers who actually want to compete and test their skills against each other and see who is better.
Speaker 1: But then there's an ender game And you know you think this is a false dichotomy because it's like you're splitting things right down the middle.
Speaker 1: I was like no It's not a false dichotomy at all.
Speaker 1: there are two types of gamers the kinds who want to compete and see who's better and the Just like playing a game and want to just enjoy the act of playing it and just want to feel good all the time and Don't care about testing their skills or seeing who's better than anyone else now.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 0: both kinds of gaming.
Speaker 1: You're totally legitimate right, but what's being mad that the other kind of person exists?
Speaker 1: It's like every one thing if overwatch is only competitive mode now, but it's not so who the fuck cares?
Speaker 0: yeah But it's interesting.
Speaker 0: I've never seen we were talking about this the other day I've never seen an article that was so on the nose of someone basically saying I Really, just want to climb into that Skinner box and never come out right.
Speaker 0: I really just give me that variable reward schedule.
Speaker 1: That's the one thing that really gets me right.
Speaker 1: is like you look And it's like you know you.
Speaker 1: when you imagine a rat in a Skinner box or a person playing an RPG or you know a?
Speaker 1: Candy crush you think ah there's a person they have.
Speaker 1: you know the psych.
Speaker 1: you see the psychology.
Speaker 1: They're like ah they are trapped in this loop of you know Reward and right.
Speaker 1: it's like aha I see what has happened to them.
Speaker 1: But for the person to be you imagine the rat doesn't realize what's going on.
Speaker 1: right the rat is just eating food and doing its thing.
Speaker 1: But for the person to know like I know I'm in a Skinner box.
Speaker 1: I know how a Skinner box works.
Speaker 1: I know everything that's going on here.
Speaker 1: There is no mystery here.
Speaker 1: I see behind the curtain.
Speaker 0: I like what I see behind the curtain, but I see out the window outside the Skinner box And I'm mad that that exists.
Speaker 1: right I am happy to be in the Skinner box.
Speaker 1: I don't want this Skinner box to change how it works.
Speaker 1: I like what's going on behind that curtain.
Speaker 1: I love being in here, but I'm mad that there's a world outside of the Skinner box that has been brought to my attention.
Speaker 0: I mean here's a line from the article.
Speaker 0: This is just.
Speaker 0: this is exquisite.
Speaker 0: So let's say you win a 40-minute match only to find that your skill rating level bar barely budgets.
Speaker 0: That's fucking unsatisfying.
Speaker 0: partially on Because overwatch previously trained us to a. Expect short matches and be expect big rewards after those short matches.
Speaker 1: Look, so don't.
Speaker 1: well first of all don't play competitive mode.
Speaker 1: second.
Speaker 0: What rewards?
Speaker 0: there's no rewards.
Speaker 0: It's just a game.
Speaker 0: you either win or lose.
Speaker 0: you don't level up anything.
Speaker 0: a number goes up.
Speaker 0: that number means literally nothing.
Speaker 1: Oh, it does.
Speaker 1: if you're a person who likes numbers going up But like someone who plays candy crush the only
Speaker 0: thing the numbers ever meant to me is sometimes I see someone who has a really really high number But then they're not good And I just feel bad for them because I know they played way more than me there.
Speaker 1: listen most people Seem to like.
Speaker 1: you know, they even it's it does.
Speaker 1: the weird part is even though they recognize that this number is just a number They still like it And it's like, you know, I feel like once you recognize what's going on, then it doesn't work.
Speaker 1: It shouldn't work on you anymore.
Speaker 0: when you saw through the matrix.
Speaker 0: He didn't immediately go and eat a steak, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know You see the Wizard of Oz behind the curtain and even the fucking dumbass tin man who has no brain.
Speaker 1: Here's the woman.
Speaker 1: no brain, right?
Speaker 1: No, who does do his no brain?
Speaker 1: scarecrow the scarecrow.
Speaker 1: And he sees that the Wizard of Oz is not really this magic hologram thing.
Speaker 1: It's just a dude behind the curtain and even him with no brain is like I was a bunch of horseshit.
Speaker 1: Hey, but meanwhile, this dude is a scarecrow going behind the curtain and say oh, I see it's a guy behind their curtain But don't take my fucking hologram away.
Speaker 1: I'm worshiping this hologram.
Speaker 1: stay the fuck away curtain man.
Speaker 1: Don't turn that shit off Now.
Speaker 0: in general though the people who and like I said people are playing overwatch and seem to not super like competitive mode I've seen a common theme and this is kind of my point here.
Speaker 0: the common theme among most of those people is that they're playing by themselves and They're salty that the matchmaking is not accommodating them that well and that they isn't it like the best matchmaking there is it is.
Speaker 0: but Overwatch was from the very beginning.
Speaker 0: It is a team game.
Speaker 0: It is a team of six versus a team of six.
Speaker 0: It'd be like if I complained that the Detroit Lions are doing crappily even though one of their players is super good Like that player should be ranked up onto a different team.
Speaker 1: That's how all professional sports yeah,
Speaker 0: so The only the only complaints I'm seeing of normal
Speaker 1: basketball where one person can carry the team
Speaker 0: There's this article where someone pointed out the Skinner box from the inside and dared you to take it away from him And then everyone else is just mad about the fact that the game is actually a team game and you really got to play with The team like you got to have five friends.
Speaker 0: or it's not that good of a game.
Speaker 0: That's just like it's like every game the game before it in this vein.
Speaker 0: It's a team game.
Speaker 0: You're playing a team game to win teams.
Speaker 1: If you're really good at a game or believe you're really good at a game and you're sad because you keep losing all the time And you keep blaming it on your team and your name is not Alexander Ovechkin.
Speaker 1: You can go play a tiny-ass violin somewhere.
Speaker 0: So I got one last little news because this kind of happened today and it's just How are people so bad at this?
Speaker 1: Ubisoft which has had problems in the past which is like one of the worst game publishers There is maybe the worst even they're like damn and EA are the two worst game video game publishers of triple-a games.
Speaker 0: It's like on the other end of the spectrum.
Speaker 0: You got Blizzard who was just like by the numbers doing a blizzard.
Speaker 1: is Activision.
Speaker 1: They're not perfect.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're worse than they used to be.
Speaker 0: Yeah But at the same time they're knocking everything that they focus on.
Speaker 1: Game publisher developer.
Speaker 1: that does everything right.
Speaker 0: everything right.
Speaker 1: the small team that made advance Wars That you mean Nintendo and it's not a small team.
Speaker 1: Yeah I guess the Zach Tronics guy who keeps making the programming games.
Speaker 1: Ah, he seems to self publish them.
Speaker 0: Anyway, Ubisoft put out a gamer survey to find out stuff about gamers And the first question it asks is if you're male or female.
Speaker 0: if you say female it immediately ends and says Thank you for taking the time to believe the survey.
Speaker 0: Unfortunately, your profile does not suit our profile for this survey.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So first of all, if you're doing a survey and someone wants to give you free information Yeah, don't turn it away.
Speaker 1: Why would you turn it away?
Speaker 1: - Usually if you're running a certain your survey company, that's what you do You know.
Speaker 1: if you only want to know about like what dudes like and what you know various demographics old people young people You know Americans other people from other countries you do reports on the data you've collected.
Speaker 1: So when you're all done collecting all this data You can just be like select from Survey where gender equals M and you'll only get that data and it doesn't matter whether you collected the other data or not.
Speaker 1: So to filter it out, but also to tell the user you could even let them do the survey and just throw the data away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like I tell the user and but it's free data.
Speaker 1: Why wouldn't you just collect it?
Speaker 1: But especially why would you why would you tell them and create this fiasco?
Speaker 0: Like we know that there's a problem with the how dumb are you women like that's?
Speaker 1: it's like well Ubisoft doesn't?
Speaker 1: Ubisoft is one of the bad publishers who true women poorly now.
Speaker 0: They claimed a little while ago that quote there's a bug a bug.
Speaker 0: There was an error in the setup of the survey Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: It is now resolved and available to everyone.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Apologies for any confusion.
Speaker 1: Yeah Also anyone who's doing fucking surveys Why are you fucking helping Ubisoft by giving them your information?
Speaker 1: stop doing surveys for people.
Speaker 1: The only survey you should be doing is the steam hardware survey.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that one's real important.
Speaker 1: Actually, don't do any other video game related surveys.
Speaker 0: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: I have to because the 4th of July was yesterday at least have one 4th of July themed thing and I Do.
Speaker 1: this is the best tweet somebody celebrating the birth of our nation by blowing up a small part of it.
Speaker 0: This tweet is titled all caps ahem who the fuck lit fireworks in Walmart?
Speaker 1: Why are there?
Speaker 1: I didn't know Walmart sold fireworks.
Speaker 1: I guess if you're in Florida they do Like New York.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay, but someone set an entire fireworks aisle on fire in a Walmart.
Speaker 1: my hero I wonder what the insurance pay out it like.
Speaker 0: I Disapprove of what happened because that's dangerous and property destruction.
Speaker 0: But I approve of the tweet that I got to enjoy this in from.
Speaker 1: it's okay to do it to Walmart.
Speaker 1: fuck them.
Speaker 0: They're not even the worst anymore Like I would they're not.
Speaker 1: it's worse than Walmart.
Speaker 0: So I got a real thing of the day and you just got to see this.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: I tweeted it.
Speaker 0: I retweeted the thing and you should just click in here and see what's going on.
Speaker 1: after three clicks I realized what it was and and then didn't read didn't continue the.
Speaker 0: I followed it to its source And it was kind of worth it.
Speaker 1: You really have no time there.
Speaker 0: It's only like 20 deep.
Speaker 0: like it's not that far I thought it was super deep.
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't as deep as you expect.
Speaker 1: I mean after three I'm like, I haven't got time for this shit.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it was a few clicks in was like Oh, I see what's going on here.
Speaker 1: And then I was like, how far down does the rabbit hole go?
Speaker 0: So you got a thing of the day?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this dude Commits a misdemeanor in this video.
Speaker 1: So crime on film here.
Speaker 1: Watch out.
Speaker 1: So they're at some bridge somewhere.
Speaker 1: I guess it's a car bridge that drives across like a river and He jumps off, but he's not doing the usual which would be bungee jumping or base jumping, right?
Speaker 1: Because you need a you know.
Speaker 1: to span a bridge I guess counts as a span and you the s in base, right?
Speaker 1: No, he's got a rope and is just a rope.
Speaker 1: So you're thinking whoa, that could be dangerous Just a rope.
Speaker 1: you usually you bungee jump with the bungee thing because then you won't die.
Speaker 1: But he jumps off in such a way So as to not bungee and die and yet or spider-man Gwen Stacy yank and die but instead to swing Majestically then.
Speaker 0: therefore part of this video is the face he's making.
Speaker 1: Yeah He's got his GoPro on a stick and he's got it in slow-mo and you can see his friends down at the bottom And I wish you would have kept videoing when the cops came and gave him the ticket.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if I were the cop I would give him the ticket and then I would ask him if I could come back when I Was off duty and do it.
Speaker 1: I would totally do this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this seems great as long as I knew the river was deep enough and someone else did it first.
Speaker 0: It's the kind of thing we did when it when a grown-up, you know I did a lot of reckless things with friends like out in the woods were involving rope swings and jumping off a shit and whatever.
Speaker 0: But I had a very specific rule someone else had to do it and survive before I would do it no matter what it was.
Speaker 1: That's my rule for a lot of things.
Speaker 0: So like cybernetic implants I would do this or replacing my body with a robot body in the moment The book club book was long ago the Wheel of Time the first of the Wheel of Time.
Speaker 0: I finished the 14th book of the Wheel of Time.
Speaker 1: Is that the last one?
Speaker 0: Ah, there's no more Wheel of Time.
Speaker 1: I know you've gone around the whole wheel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're out of time.
Speaker 0: No more time done with time.
Speaker 0: I made my time.
Speaker 0: My time is done.
Speaker 0: Move Randell tour and yeah, so the next book club book will be Oryx and Crake But it's much shorter than even one book of Wheel of Time.
Speaker 1: So even though we've been talking about this book for a long time and not actually doing the episode on it I'm gonna start reading it.
Speaker 0: probably like today I'm gonna start.
Speaker 1: we should be able to do the episode on it like in a couple weeks.
Speaker 0: In fact, if there's a lot of downtime in Connecticut, I might just finish it between traveling to and from Connecticut.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: maybe the thing is it's a race because the next Prince of Nothing book comes out like any day But I have to reread so many princes of nothing.
Speaker 1: So I a couple years ago reread the first trilogy so I don't need to reread that I did But I still have to reread again because I forgot half the proper nouns.
Speaker 0: Uh, I think a lot of them don't matter like you don't really do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what's an Ione?
Speaker 0: They're the ones with the steel masks, right?
Speaker 1: And who are the evil like Sharam?
Speaker 1: know the the the the priests who wear like red and they're totally like evil like the Mafia.
Speaker 1: Oh the the priest the Wizards who are evil.
Speaker 0: That was the one of the Gnostic school or the anagogic schools.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what is that?
Speaker 1: What does the tusks say?
Speaker 0: Oh, no, we don't know what the fucking tough says.
Speaker 1: Who's the guy who hangs out with the tusks?
Speaker 1: Beard guy the priest guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't remember his name the Pope guy.
Speaker 1: basically.
Speaker 0: Well, that's all complicated.
Speaker 0: after what happens in the first series I know but I'm just saying what's his name?
Speaker 0: that matter He's dead.
Speaker 1: Is he dead?
Speaker 1: I don't think he's dead.
Speaker 0: Did you read all the books that came out?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Did I come before you?
Speaker 0: Anyway, a lot of people are dead by the end of the books that were written up to.
Speaker 1: pretty sure that guy's not dead.
Speaker 0: He's dead.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about this after this.
Speaker 0: didn't he die at the end of the stuff the book we just read?
Speaker 1: no You're thinking about different guy.
Speaker 0: Uh maybe.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the prince of nothing is like our favorite fantasy series ever and we've done a bunch of.
Speaker 1: I have to put a huge content warning on.
Speaker 1: yeah Dude, who writes it is like mad Misogynistic.
Speaker 1: yeah the books reflect this.
Speaker 1: The books also have stuff that I probably like.
Speaker 1: if I saw in a movie I might get sick and usually I don't get sick Anything in a movie not even like each of the killer like we have.
Speaker 0: so interestingly Scott wheel of time does similar things later on Like when you start finding out about how compulsion works, it is the prince of nothing compulsion like a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: Oh, in fact, it's kind of worse because it's real bad.
Speaker 0: If you try to take it out of someone's brain anyway.
Speaker 0: anyway Yeah, prince of nothing.
Speaker 1: Is that what the rod of you know, the oath rod?
Speaker 0: the oath rod does stuff like that.
Speaker 0: The oath rod does a lot of bad things to you.
Speaker 0: Okay, this pain involved in the heartache and misery and shortened lifespans and yeah I am it's good bad news.
Speaker 0: But yeah, we really like the prince of nothing series.
Speaker 1: all all caveats notwithstanding it combines philosophy Wizards and history.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it's also a nice sort of sci-fi aliens.
Speaker 1: It's also a sort of mission at least and the bad guy is a sarcophagus inside of a tornado.
Speaker 0: It's got some Tolkien Deconstruction like what would elves really be like like that kind of thing like for real.
Speaker 0: what else be lost?
Speaker 1: some barbarians also.
Speaker 0: Yeah, skill Vandy barbaria.
Speaker 0: It's also a very quotable series track a step.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, so yeah We're gonna read orcs and Craig and we're gonna do a review of it Even though everyone's telling me I should have done the Handmaid's Tale.
Speaker 0: It's more relevant to modern American politics.
Speaker 1: Whatever just read all the.
Speaker 1: just read all this shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got time.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, we're gonna be a kinetic on this weekend Like it's happening.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be there.
Speaker 0: We're running the panels department.
Speaker 0: We're doing some panels as well.
Speaker 0: I forget when they are but we're doing a Anime foreign anime openers on Friday.
Speaker 0: We're doing more foreign anime openers on Saturday.
Speaker 0: We're doing a professional Podcasting and live streaming on Sunday.
Speaker 0: We're doing Atari game design and we're doing writing game rules.
Speaker 0: I think that's it Cuz.
Speaker 0: I just didn't really want to do a lot of panels this year.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, why don't you smart people?
Speaker 0: We know are doing panels.
Speaker 0: We made the panel.
Speaker 0: Well, I made the panel schedule.
Speaker 0: I think it's actually a the best panel schedule this con has ever had in terms of content.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: I'm actually pretty proud of it and if you try to use the website that kinetic on has to let you see that schedule I Highly recommend you complain to them about the fun.
Speaker 0: So the first speedrun I ever saw that sort of made me really realize what the hell that was.
Speaker 0: Was that Mario 3 thing that we saw at our IT?
Speaker 1: This is so long ago.
Speaker 1: It's not any Mario 3 but that you've ever seen.
Speaker 0: basically like earliest days of you.
Speaker 1: it was pretty much just world 8 1. right that you know the final world and It was a more than a 1.
Speaker 0: it was a few bits of world 8.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was a bunch of world 8 and normally I would just like I think a speedrun you'd fly over the p-wing or something.
Speaker 1: But he didn't do that.
Speaker 1: All right, I mean it's an auto scroller But this he's super optimized like jumping on the cannonballs in like a ridiculous way.
Speaker 1: It was like basically a miracle that the person could do this because it turned out a person couldn't do it.
Speaker 0: That at least in that case though.
Speaker 1: I'm sure maybe a person can do it now.
Speaker 0: Yeah but that was a tool assisted speedrun and it was interesting because up until that point when I thought of the like I kind of Had the idea of like a speedrun because it wasn't like gamer.
Speaker 0: pop culture had not really crystallized all these ideas.
Speaker 1: I mean there were people playing video games for speed.
Speaker 1: Metroid told you how long it took for you to beat it and people tried to get faster times.
Speaker 0: people set records.
Speaker 1: Yeah There were very contests.
Speaker 1: there are various games that had time as opposed to score and people you know had always been doing high score attack But people were also doing time attack.
Speaker 1: It just hadn't become a phenomenon until games done quick really made it into a community With you know to event two major events every year one of which is going on right now For some.
Speaker 1: according to rim, we've never done an episode on this.
Speaker 0: I couldn't find an episode on this.
Speaker 1: if we're wrong Blame rim, how does that my fault?
Speaker 1: We've done this episode.
Speaker 0: All right now there was a community for this before a GDQ sort of did its thing, but you kind of had to know and People were still sort of arguing and fighting about like what counted what the terminology was Like.
Speaker 0: how exactly do you measure this?
Speaker 0: which emulators are like legit for it?
Speaker 1: streaming?
Speaker 1: Also made it a big thing because you could see people You know practicing and that made other people get hooked on Practicing and watching other people and it let people share their techniques with each other.
Speaker 1: before that People would have to record and like share videos direct directly with each other.
Speaker 1: that Mario 3 thing We watched was like an mp4.
Speaker 1: We download.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it might have even been an AVI.
Speaker 0: This was like free YouTube days guys.
Speaker 0: So what happened was basically now that there's a community around it live streaming is a thing.
Speaker 0: YouTube exists and the internet exists and everyone has access to it and Anime and gaming and all these conventions are like super easy and widespread.
Speaker 0: It was like the perfect time for an explosion and it got to the point of where people started breaking records That no one ever thought would be broke.
Speaker 1: I mean it really exploded like three or four years ago and it just keeps getting bigger and bigger Constantly every single year.
Speaker 0: every year I look at the schedule of a GDQ and I'm shocked by at least one of the attempts that they're about to make and it's like.
Speaker 1: You think it's like.
Speaker 1: are there really new games they can go after?
Speaker 1: are there really ways They can improve upon the games.
Speaker 1: They're already.
Speaker 1: they're still improving Final Fantasy for speed run Right and then on top of that there's always even for one game.
Speaker 1: There'll be so many different modes.
Speaker 0: any percent hundred percent Blindfolded it's like really into that hundred percent bionic commando in 30 minutes.
Speaker 1: I just watched blindfolded symphony of the night today, holy Crap, it's like.
Speaker 1: are you kidding me?
Speaker 1: This dude couldn't see he had problems in the library buying stuff.
Speaker 1: But the point is is like he still beat symphony of the night without seeing only audio.
Speaker 0: dude I'm not a hundred percent guaranteed to beat it non blindfolded.
Speaker 0: if I have all the time in the world I am I haven't played in a long time.
Speaker 0: I think I might die.
Speaker 0: It's not a hard game now, but I'm sure I die a bunch if I just picks up right now.
Speaker 0: I haven't played a metroidvania in at least three years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, yeah, I might die maybe in the upside-down castle if I sort of rush and don't take it easy.
Speaker 0: But I remember was also interesting about that speedrun that Mario 3 one that we saw.
Speaker 0: that really sort of like got me interested in This.
Speaker 0: that's why I got into the community in those days not doing it.
Speaker 0: I'll never be that good now.
Speaker 0: but like finding them and watching them and learning about them was that it wasn't just a Like Fox only Final Destination style like heavyset mouth breather staring at the screen not saying anything Perfect run doing no extraneous actions.
Speaker 0: This was parkour.
Speaker 0: This was a show.
Speaker 0: This was someone showing off taking risks, right?
Speaker 1: cuz I mean think you had this video game and you have to beat it as fast as you can and You have to do this without hacking the game.
Speaker 1: It's like normally you'd hack the game right or you know, you do something like that But no only by pressing the buttons on the controller and doing nothing else.
Speaker 1: You're not allowed.
Speaker 1: you can push the buttons on the console to like the reset button maybe depending on the rules But you all you can do is push buttons.
Speaker 1: So how can you beat the game faster?
Speaker 1: You think like Mario 1 it's like well hold B and right and jump and don't ever let go of right or B Unless you got to shoot a fireball or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like you know that is that really as fast as you can go and then you start to see things like basic techniques.
Speaker 1: for example in They have the thing where you turn backwards do a back dash and then bring your shield out to cancel the animation.
Speaker 1: so you go and You go really really fast because the back dash is really fast and by canceling it with the shield You can just keep back dashing constantly without you know The sort of ending animation of it and go whoosh much faster than you could run just going forward.
Speaker 1: Yeah, suddenly when you see someone playing Castlevania Symphony tonight, they're always going backwards going And that's like beginner mode of speedrun.
Speaker 0: yep, and then what?
Speaker 0: what this is culminated into?
Speaker 0: and I guess my favorite thing now is that the community is so big that there Can be races with two three four people playing a multi-hour game in a race Sometimes even taking different routes, so you don't even know who's ahead until the end and they finish within seconds of each other.
Speaker 0: Yep, like that is the point that we're in today, and they're optimizing so much to where they're like.
Speaker 1: ah do that You know I'm doing the safety strat.
Speaker 1: It only loses like two seconds versus the.
Speaker 1: you know as she means that when they're not doing the safety strat because it's not AGDQ or SGDQ they do this other thing that is much riskier.
Speaker 1: just to save two seconds They're gonna cuz.
Speaker 0: you know some people are going for the world record like you.
Speaker 1: try over and over those two seconds keep adding up right two seconds here two seconds there.
Speaker 1: suddenly you're a minute faster.
Speaker 0: and But because of the performance aspect of it This is like the generation where AGDQ made this happen by turning it into a performance.
Speaker 0: The tool assisted runs are like their own sort of thing.
Speaker 0: and be like you know I did it a million times and the video you see of his world record is the best of them.
Speaker 0: It's very different when it is a performance where there's a human in front of an audience a giant audience live Performing for
Speaker 1: you right, but the the tool assisted ones are actually really important because even though like you know You might not be impressed with them because a person didn't do it It took a lot of work to make it because a person sat there going through the game frame by frame Figuring out the best way to do
Speaker 0: it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though it didn't take a lot as much skill It took a lot more effort.
Speaker 1: But also by doing those tool assisted speed runs it gives the people doing the by hand real speed runs Something to look at and say aha.
Speaker 1: That's the fastest way.
Speaker 1: Let's see how much of that it's possible for a human to do.
Speaker 1: and there's a lot of like frame perfect things that people can Do very consistently because they're gods.
Speaker 0: Now now I think we were on.
Speaker 0: I was watching one of the earlier ones.
Speaker 0: it was the the most recent link between worlds DS run and Well 3ds and the guy was just sort of talking and he gets at one point where he's like All right, this move coming up.
Speaker 0: I gotta be too almost frame perfect.
Speaker 0: and then they start talking to each other about how many frames they have to input the command and then one of Them laughs and points out something that hey coming up is the other one the frame perfect one be.
Speaker 0: Literally you have to input a control on one specific frame or it fails, right?
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: for people to understand when you program a video game Almost every video game is programmed using this very similar coding structure where you have a loop the main loop and basically The loop starts and a bunch of code gets executed the computers doing math math math math math math math math math math.
Speaker 1: And then when it gets to the very bottom of the loop, it basically has to draw the screen.
Speaker 1: So if your screen is, you know, 1080p's you've got 1080 by you know pixels Right to draw and it basically has to create in memory, you know, which color it goes in all those pixels.
Speaker 1: So this pixels green this pixels blue and so on.
Speaker 1: and then it puts that you know Array of color information to the video card and then it gets drawn on the monitor.
Speaker 1: And if your game is running at say 60 FPS, that is loop has to go all the way through 60 times every second.
Speaker 1: also in this loop is the code that says are they pressing a?
Speaker 1: If they're pressing a make Mario jump if he's on the ground obvious, right, you know, so that code is happening 60 times a second which means in any given second You could press a on the.
Speaker 1: you know, there it's cut into 60 slices Right.
Speaker 1: So 160th.
Speaker 1: if it's a 60 FPS game what every 60th of a second?
Speaker 1: It would be a difference.
Speaker 1: So if you push a on the first 60th or the second 60th It's impossible to push a on anywhere in between.
Speaker 1: that because it's the loop.
Speaker 1: go, you know The loop executes one at a time, right?
Speaker 1: So you have 60 chances every second in a 60 FPS game.
Speaker 1: So if it's a 30 FPS game You have 30 chances every second to press the button and you have to press it on an exact very specific One of those loops like that loop that the tenth one is the one we had to push the button.
Speaker 1: That's how hard this is to do a frame perfect thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So it's it's like oh my god, you know You have you.
Speaker 1: you have one second in the game and on this one like fraction of that second That's when you had to press the button.
Speaker 0: now I guess what also I like.
Speaker 0: but this is sort of a wider point.
Speaker 0: that sort of it's affecting a lot of people who make Content or do streams or anything on the internet.
Speaker 0: but because live streaming has such a strong community now And because these speedrun people are like pushing this art as far as they can already Unless you are like of that caliber like you have to be so good to even warrant anyone watching you at this point.
Speaker 1: well They seem to have like this big community going on and you can go to their website.
Speaker 1: And even though if you were to say start, you know There are always people when I watch this who like oh we got a new guy playing Super Metroid Is he?
Speaker 1: Super Metroid is the most speedrun game?
Speaker 1: But someone will just start doing it and they could.
Speaker 1: they learned everything from the previous people by watching them and they have skills.
Speaker 1: So they like level up and become Just as good if not better than the people already doing it in a short a matter of time because they have skills.
Speaker 1: but there are people with less skills who choose less popular games and Because there's less competition there.
Speaker 1: right and you think you know, how about you pick some weirdo game?
Speaker 0: Well, the best example of this ever watched the speedrun on a GDQ of super pitfall.
Speaker 0: It is hilarious because that game is so bad and so broken and so glitchy and the guy doing the speedrun Knows literally everything there is to know about the game.
Speaker 1: I mean I've seen speedruns on there like people were doing like Lion King and it's like How many.
Speaker 1: and there's like a community of people.
Speaker 1: like it's probably only less than 10 people But it's like they're the Lion King speedrunners.
Speaker 1: Like there's that many people on earth who are like putting effort into playing that game as fast as possible and they send someone to the Multiple people to the games done quick and you watch them play it.
Speaker 1: and it's like wow It only took like 10 people to optimize the hell out of this game.
Speaker 1: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: and it's like so no matter you know, you can get into this it with a lower level of skill because even if you can't Even if you're not the person who can push the button with frame perfect timing You can still contribute in many ways.
Speaker 1: right by simply trying it.
Speaker 1: you can find tricks to help the guy who can execute them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know you can do the top.
Speaker 1: the tool assisted speedrun to figure everything out, you know You can.
Speaker 1: you know There's so many things you can do in this community if you want to if that's your interest.
Speaker 1: The thing is ice is one of those hobbies where I think can only be meaningful if you dedicate a huge amount of time To it like you.
Speaker 1: make it your thing.
Speaker 0: You can't dabble you can't you know.
Speaker 1: Do other too many other hobbies like.
Speaker 1: if you're also like an anime fan and you're making a webcomic you can't be also speedrunning.
Speaker 1: Right, but if you're only speedrunning I notice a lot of the speedrun people speedrun multiple games because once you sort of get the skills of speedrunning You can sort of do a lot of similar games or a lot of games to the same system.
Speaker 1: or you know You can really work yourself up and you know get a huge repertoire and not just concentrate on one game only.
Speaker 0: Yeah I guess my favorite speedruns now are the live Performance ones with good commentary like someone who is kind of talking about the game or doing something interesting while they're playing.
Speaker 0: It's not just the speedrun.
Speaker 1: I like the ones where there's just there are things in the game.
Speaker 1: that is that you dislike don't think of.
Speaker 1: right like a boring One is like just he runs to the right as fast as the game lets him and jumps and everything.
Speaker 0: the more weird stuff like the Final Fantasy 4 one where they like they got the random seed in a certain way and then He knew like what every encounter would be along the way for like hours of this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah any the weirder trick you found the more fascinating thing that you way to speed up this game that you have discovered and That's awesome.
Speaker 1: Er to look at right.
Speaker 1: that makes it more interesting from a spectators perspective.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I do appreciate I think I hate to say this.
Speaker 0: I think the showmanship of a GDQ is Getting to the point where it started surpassing a lot of what the competitive game circuit does Like.
Speaker 0: take your average fighting game tournament versus your average live streamer event last year.
Speaker 0: events tend to have better Production values and better announcing and everything, but it might be a side effect of the fact that there aren't as many Actual events like.
Speaker 1: it's not like a ladder as a charity organization.
Speaker 1: It's not like a profit organization.
Speaker 0: That's you know, yeah, but I'm saying they do a really good job.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it is I know that I know you know I know the people doing it right and they're like the people who do that kind of stuff like at a pax or at another Convention, but that is really good at it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're doing it, you know volunteering because it's you know, they want to help it out.
Speaker 0: So the other thing I'm enjoying lately is the the weird mode stream.
Speaker 0: a lot of speed runs Like the example I came up with that no one's blindfold to p1c Or like mario 2. you're not allowed to run Like that kind of nonsense.
Speaker 0: It's basically gum.
Speaker 0: Take deathmatch, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, you can just make things more interesting, you know blindfolded punch-out, you know started off as like well I can sort of get to Mike Tyson.
Speaker 1: then they were beating Mike Tyson.
Speaker 1: No problem the next year blindfolded, right?
Speaker 1: Now they're doing.
Speaker 1: now the guy just beat blindfolded Symphony in the night, you know, what?
Speaker 1: what's next thing like well blindfolded Super Metroid.
Speaker 0: It's like I don't wait for the point where guys like instead of controller.
Speaker 0: I'm manipulating the wires.
Speaker 0: I've shoved them into my fingers, right?
Speaker 1: The 2p1c is really good.
Speaker 1: We get two people on one controller and so one person's got the arrows another person has the buttons.
Speaker 0: That's really fun Especially when they're still.
Speaker 1: how much do they practice moves, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they practice that much.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like if you both you know think about it.
Speaker 1: if I play this game and I get the perfect muscle memory in my left and right hand and you get the Same exact muscle memory.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right hand We just say your left hand in my right hand and my left hand is right twitching behind my back and your right and switch Behind your back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we just both hands on the 1c and it's impressive.
Speaker 1: but really is it any different, you know That's how they do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel it feels different.
Speaker 0: if use your left hand though, maybe Got anything else to say.
Speaker 0: I think we're petering out here.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: the patrons for this episode of geek nights in order of the amount of money they give us on a continuing basis are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Dujette James David White Christian coons construction noises mystady.com Sean Hayworth William Eisen Rose Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Sailor Vista Devin Goodman Iggy kid Matthew Smith Kajak Tovish and Joshua Joe star Tyler Eller Don Schleit Sean Yeager Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Rera Laval Brian Cidroni Rochelle, Montanona Finn Eric silver on Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Aaron Cerise Chris midgiff Chris Knox Sam Cordery Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: I tried real hard to not laugh during that one.
Speaker 0: you guys I don't know what to say.
Speaker 0: So Connecticut is this weekend.
Speaker 0: I know we've been a little bit behind on like the Q&A.
Speaker 0: partly It's like pulling teeth to Scott to ever do it But also just we've been super crazy busy.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna make it up with a bunch of extra bonus patreon content and extra stuff for you $5 people as well in the near future.
Speaker 0: we might not do a regular geek notes on Thursday, but I think Emily and I might do a roomly review of Fargo season 1 and Fargo season 2.
Speaker 0: I'll probably put one of those at least on the actual like geek nights website as a Thursday episode and the other one will be patrons only just for you guys, but Connecticut is the last significant thing that we had to do.
Speaker 0: that took time out of our lives Other than just like work and doing geek nights.
Speaker 0: So after this weekend things calm down and the patreon is gonna start having a lot more stuff.
Speaker 0: I gotta edit the utennas start uploading those.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of sci-fi videos to upload lots and lots of stuff Atari game design.
Speaker 0: I still have to get together.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna start hitting that cue of all the stuff.
Speaker 0: We haven't done yet.
Speaker 0: and Also, maybe Scott will try to play overwatch, but I suspect you won't.
Speaker 0: So yeah, see you at Connecticut maybe and otherwise I leave you with your moment of kind of the opposite of Zen.
Speaker 1: What should be wrong dear?
Speaker 1: Mine is being creative.
Speaker 0: How do you get the idea?
Speaker 1: Let's try to think creatively.
Speaker 1: when you look at this orange Tell me please.
Speaker 1: What do you see?
Speaker 0: Just a boring old orange.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe to you and not to me.
Speaker 0: I see a silly face Walking along and smiling at me.
Speaker 0: I don't see what you mean because you're not.
Speaker 1: It's not very good at all Not good.