Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, November 2nd, 2016.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym, and this is Geek Nights Tonight, the adventures of Ichabod and Mr.
Speaker 0: Toad, except we're not actually going to talk about the Mr.
Speaker 0: Toad part.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So Scott has some part season tickets to the Rangers, and he brought me along to- Part season.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Rangers tickets are fucking expensive kids.
Speaker 0: So I went to a game, and it was a good hockey game, all told.
Speaker 0: We shut out the St.
Speaker 0: Louis Blues.
Speaker 0: It was kind of awful for them.
Speaker 0: But what was notable is that during the game, they interrupted, like during an stoppage of play, to be like, "Hey guys, guess what's going on in the World Series
Speaker 0: business?".
Speaker 1: They didn't interrupt.
Speaker 1: They do that all the time, and they do it during any play.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, but the content of the interruption was notable because the second time they showed this, it was to show that the already ahead Cubs got a grand slam, and there was basically going to be a Game 7.
Speaker 0: It was only like the second inning.
Speaker 1: I think it was the third inning, but yeah.
Speaker 1: You hit a grand slam in Game 6 of the World Series, and you're the team that's down.
Speaker 1: I mean, team up or down.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: That's legendary.
Speaker 0: Grand slams are not common anyway.
Speaker 1: Legendary.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it's going to come down to a big game.
Speaker 1: It's bad news either way, right?
Speaker 1: Bad news number one.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, the Cubs.
Speaker 1: I don't dislike the Cubs, and it's going to be mad exciting.
Speaker 0: I feel for them.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm a Lions fan.
Speaker 1: It'll be way exciting if they win.
Speaker 1: The problem is that excitement will be short-lived.
Speaker 1: If you look, like the White Sox and the Red Sox recently had similar, not quite as long droughts of winning, but like 70, 80 something, you know, super long droughts and curses, and they broke those curses.
Speaker 1: Now that the curses are over, it's like, now it's meh.
Speaker 1: It's like your legend is gone.
Speaker 1: It's like if I was a Cubs fan, I'd almost, like even if I was a Cubs fan, I'd almost want them to keep losing to maintain this legend.
Speaker 0: I can actually give a relevant bit of info on that situation, that sentiment, because remember when the Lions went winless?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know what?
Speaker 0: You can't have the Lions winning.
Speaker 0: Come on, win a game.
Speaker 0: So win a game.
Speaker 0: Please win a game.
Speaker 0: But when there are only like three games left, I kind of didn't want them to win a game, because if they lost every game but one or two, that would just be a really shitty season and no one would talk about it again.
Speaker 1: But yeah, the season the Lions won no games.
Speaker 0: Going winless, that was legendary.
Speaker 1: Legendary, right?
Speaker 1: It's like there's.
Speaker 1: no, why would you just want to be boring and meh?
Speaker 1: So the Cubs, the only reason anyone cares about the Cubs at all is because they're cursed.
Speaker 1: They just don't win.
Speaker 1: If they suddenly win, it's just like, alright, you're just some other garbage bin.
Speaker 1: Who gives a fuck now?
Speaker 0: I mean, look, back to the future.
Speaker 0: If they were playing against any other team, except maybe the Yankees, right?
Speaker 1: I would, you know, just be like rooting against them.
Speaker 1: Like, no, keep losing.
Speaker 1: But they had to be playing the racist team.
Speaker 1: So it's either the racist team wins or the legend dies.
Speaker 1: There's not a good result that can happen.
Speaker 1: But at least if the legend dies, we'll have a short-term good result of party time.
Speaker 1: But long-term, you know, long and short-term bad results.
Speaker 0: But if the legend continues, I kind of want the curse of the Cubs to last another hundred years.
Speaker 1: Sure, but at the expense of racist team winning?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's a flash in the pan.
Speaker 0: That comes and goes.
Speaker 0: The racist team exists independent of the rest of the spectrum.
Speaker 1: I guess I can hope that if the racist team wins, that, you know, it'll be sort of like the eye of anti-racism Sauron upon them.
Speaker 1: And we can maybe get them to change their fucking team.
Speaker 0: I don't think it will, though.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: I think that's just gonna fester for a while.
Speaker 1: There's at least a small chance, right?
Speaker 1: Because when they have their little parade, there'll be people protesting, hopefully, right?
Speaker 1: I can't go to Cleveland and do that, but someone else can.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is it'll be overshadowed just by, you know, the presidential election and all that nonsense.
Speaker 0: I mean, the KKK just endorsed Trump officially, so...
Speaker 1: That should help you amplify the anti-racism message.
Speaker 0: Except, no, it seems to actually, like, be mobilizing white supremacists to vote, and the election's looking close.
Speaker 1: Well, good, mobilize them so we can find them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if he wins, then they're mobilized and they're kind of mainstream again.
Speaker 1: Good, it'll be easy to get rid of them.
Speaker 0: Uh, the only way it's easy to get rid of them at that point...
Speaker 1: This time, we couldn't do anything about it.
Speaker 1: Now they'll just be visible.
Speaker 1: If they come out with their white hoods, it's like, "Oh, there they
Speaker 1: are.".
Speaker 0: And what are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: Physically attack them?
Speaker 1: I wouldn't really feel bad about bombing a KKK rally.
Speaker 0: You heard it here first, folks.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, like, I'm down with that.
Speaker 0: See, I'll go a step back from that to the "I hate Illinois Nazis" situation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, if I'm in a car and they're in the street, it's just gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but seriously, even though it's right before the election, we're not talking about politics tonight, but for fuck's sake, vote for Clinton.
Speaker 0: Jesus Christ.
Speaker 0: Like, if you don't vote, what the fuck is wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Like, if you don't live in the
Speaker 0: U.S.,
Speaker 0: then yeah, you get a pass.
Speaker 1: I mean, also, you know, I live in New York, so I'm gonna vote, but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but not all of us.
Speaker 0: Some of you live in, like, Pennsylvania or something, guys.
Speaker 0: Like, I know at least one of you lives out there.
Speaker 1: If they're voting for Trump, they're not listening to Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: No, no, but what about people who...
Speaker 1: This is the problem I have.
Speaker 1: It's like, shut up on Twitter.
Speaker 1: There's no one following you who doesn't agree with you.
Speaker 0: I know people.
Speaker 0: There are people who follow us and follow me who are either voting for Jill Stein because they're morons...
Speaker 1: Okay, you're morons.
Speaker 0: ...or voting for Gary Johnson because they're morons... Morons.
Speaker 0: ...or not voting or saying they won't vote because they're morons.
Speaker 1: And they're following you?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And even with you tweeting a thousand times a day, they haven't changed their mind.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to make them feel bad enough to actually vote.
Speaker 1: But your tweeting isn't helping, so shut the fuck up.
Speaker 0: How do you know?
Speaker 0: It might be.
Speaker 1: Apparently, they haven't changed their mind yet after a year of you tweeting nonstop.
Speaker 0: I've convinced people to change votes in the past.
Speaker 0: A small number of votes could matter.
Speaker 0: A couple hundred votes would have made Al Gore president.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Sorry, Scott.
Speaker 0: You used to listen to Obama's podcast.
Speaker 0: You've fallen so far.
Speaker 1: Uh, you've not learned your lesson.
Speaker 1: I learned, right?
Speaker 1: And I elevated above all that fray of garbage.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: You're still doubting the muck.
Speaker 0: No, you're just trying to be a hipster.
Speaker 0: You're like, "Ah, I'm above
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 1: I am above it.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I'm not poisoning my mind listening to people like Donald Trump talk like you are every day.
Speaker 0: Uh, okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you got any news?
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 1: I have some great news, but I also have a geek fight because I'm paying attention to, you know, good stuff in the world, right?
Speaker 1: So, tiny news.
Speaker 1: Very tiny news.
Speaker 1: There's a manga called, and get this, ready for this manga title?
Speaker 1: It's the best manga title ever.
Speaker 1: Delicious in Dungeon.
Speaker 0: Now, I think we mentioned this briefly a while ago.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it's licensed.
Speaker 1: It's gonna come out in English for real, so I'm gonna buy it.
Speaker 0: If you're not sure what it is from the title, Delicious in Dungeon, the cover is a dude wearing fantasy armor and a backpack.
Speaker 0: And in the background, there's like an elf, and there's a dragon poking around the corner.
Speaker 0: And the dude has a sword, a cooking pot, and a spatula.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah.
Speaker 1: So, it's cooking in a dungeon, but it's got recipes and stuff like that, right?
Speaker 1: It's a cooking manga that takes, plus adventuring, fantasy style.
Speaker 1: And you're probably thinking, it's like, oh, I'll get a fantasy adventure where they fight the orcs.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, when they stop to camp, we'll actually learn about cooking, like how to cook delicious food when camping.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: They cook fantasy food, like slime jerky.
Speaker 1: And I think at one point, they take out a golem, and then they grow vegetables on the rocks of the golem.
Speaker 1: And then, right?
Speaker 1: It's not real cooking, it's fantasy cooking also.
Speaker 0: You're gonna find out about if you can cook a slime and eat it, now that's gonna work out for you.
Speaker 1: Like gnoll stew and shit like that.
Speaker 1: But it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: I feel like you can make an entire tabletop RPG based on this exact concept and nothing more.
Speaker 1: They go into the detail of the recipes like they're real.
Speaker 1: And they probably could be real if you replace slime with like some kind of jelly or something.
Speaker 1: But you get the ideas, manga's awesome, it's coming out, so buy it and read it.
Speaker 1: Alright, so Geek Bite.
Speaker 1: I went to see with NotRim, because he was on the other side of the world.
Speaker 1: His movie came out and was translated and licensed and put out.
Speaker 1: I think you can still see it if you hurry up.
Speaker 1: Called Ms.
Speaker 1: Hogusai's Anime Studio IG, which stands for Is Good.
Speaker 0: I'm curious what you think, because what you told me about the movie previously was, it's pretty good, and you left it at that.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's not, you know, I was expecting it.
Speaker 1: So it's about, you know, it's Ms.
Speaker 1: Hogusai.
Speaker 1: It's about Hogusai, you know, the big wave painting.
Speaker 1: It's his daughter, right, who is a real person who we know limited information about.
Speaker 1: And there was a manga based on her life, mostly biographical, plus some fantasy-ness.
Speaker 1: And this movie is based on that manga.
Speaker 1: So it's very sort of like episodic in a way.
Speaker 1: There's a few plot threads, and they really skip between them a lot.
Speaker 1: There's a plot thread of the cute boy in town, and the plot thread of having to paint to make money.
Speaker 1: It's like each of the different sides, you know, the plot thread of the even younger sister who's sick.
Speaker 1: There's all these little plots, and it sort of skips scenes between them very rapidly.
Speaker 1: And some of them don't get fully enough attention on them, and some of them get a lot of attention.
Speaker 1: And then there's a lot of single episodes that don't really connect to anything else, but are really interesting.
Speaker 1: Like the time they go, and there's this Geisha who's got a spirit in something, and they go to take a look at it so they can paint it or whatever, you know.
Speaker 1: You know, cool stuff like that happens.
Speaker 1: So the animation is awesome, and there's a lot of, you know, beautiful scenes.
Speaker 1: The music, while good, I think is out of place.
Speaker 1: They play like rock music and stuff, like right in the opening.
Speaker 1: It opens with rock music, and I'm just sort of like, normally that anachronistic music can work out.
Speaker 1: Like Samurai Champloo, which plays the hip-hop music, but for me at least, it didn't fit.
Speaker 1: I was just like, it's not working for me.
Speaker 1: You should have done something.
Speaker 0: Maybe you're just too primed by watching so much Japanese media that you expect more traditional soundtracks.
Speaker 1: No, because I'm fine with Samurai Champloo or any other crazy soundtrack.
Speaker 1: I think it's rock music.
Speaker 1: It's fine if you use the rock music and then you do stuff in the movie to fit with it, right?
Speaker 1: But they didn't, right?
Speaker 1: It was weird.
Speaker 1: You know, it's an anime.
Speaker 1: It's a movie.
Speaker 1: It's not bad.
Speaker 0: Oh, look, get two times the tickets in three theaters near Long Island City right now.
Speaker 1: It's in the theaters in the U.S.
Speaker 1: in English.
Speaker 1: It's, you know, medium widely distributed-ish.
Speaker 1: You can probably see it at the smaller movie theater near you.
Speaker 1: You might as well.
Speaker 1: Just don't go in and expecting like Satoshi Kon level, right?
Speaker 1: Or Mamoru Hosoda level or Makoto Shinkai level.
Speaker 1: It's like a level below that in terms of, you know, how good a movie it is.
Speaker 1: So, there you go.
Speaker 0: So, in a tiny news, and I'm not going to get too much into it because there aren't enough details to really know, but if you weren't aware, they're making a Sonic the Hedgehog movie and it appears it will be- Is it animated or live action or CG?
Speaker 1: So- Or a combination?
Speaker 0: It is, and this is why I'm worried, a CG live action hybrid.
Speaker 1: So, there's going to be a CG Sonic running around in like the real world?
Speaker 0: And I presume having sex with other Sonic the Hedgehogs.
Speaker 0: And Dr.
Speaker 1: Robotnik's going to be like a guy in a costume?
Speaker 1: And Tim Miller, the Deadpool director- The guy who left the second Deadpool movie or got kicked out?
Speaker 0: Yup, is probably going to be directing it.
Speaker 1: Okay, so he wanted to do a high budget Deadpool and no one on Deadpool but him wanted that.
Speaker 0: So, I guess now they're going to do a high budget Sonic the Hedgehog?
Speaker 0: Right, like.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen any of these stupid superhero movies, but I read the news about him getting kicked off because it was on all the nerd news channels, right?
Speaker 1: So, I guess he went to the high budget Sonic movie.
Speaker 0: I guess this is partly because remember how Sailor Moon came out?
Speaker 0: Because the Sailor Moon anniversaries, they had to do something as they did Crystal.
Speaker 1: 25th anniversary of Sonic seems to be the reason- Is Sega financing this movie?
Speaker 0: Yeah, Sega seems to have a big part of it.
Speaker 0: Sony Pictures, Mars Animation Planet, a wholly owned Sega Sammy holding subsidiary- So, it's a Japanese thing.
Speaker 1: It's Sony and Sega, so it's Japanese.
Speaker 0: It's the people who made the Captain Harlock CG animated film.
Speaker 1: Oh, so it's a Japanese production.
Speaker 1: It's not a Hollywood production, but they got a Hollywood guy to make it for them?
Speaker 0: Directed?
Speaker 0: Maybe Sonic the Hedgehog has just got to be super Deadpool-y?
Speaker 1: But, I mean, if you tell me it's by the Harlock, now I know what we're sort of expecting, right?
Speaker 1: It's that kind of movie.
Speaker 1: It's not going to be some widely distributed in the US blockbuster kind of thing.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: The only thing I have to say about this, because we don't have enough information to really go deep, is that there hasn't been a good Sonic game since Sonic 2.
Speaker 0: Like, Sonic games are just not good.
Speaker 0: Maybe Sonic CD?
Speaker 1: Sonic 3 with Sonic and Knuckles was still good.
Speaker 0: Sonic games were never that good, though.
Speaker 0: And they've been really bad for a long time.
Speaker 0: I feel like Sonic movies and comics are the only way to salvage that character.
Speaker 0: I would not even ever try to make a Sonic game again.
Speaker 1: I could make a Sonic game.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: I'd just make it just like Sonic 2, only longer.
Speaker 0: But Sonic 2 wasn't even that good.
Speaker 0: It was only okay.
Speaker 0: It was okay.
Speaker 1: It's a great game.
Speaker 0: It was an okay game.
Speaker 1: What do you know?
Speaker 0: I played it.
Speaker 0: It wasn't that great.
Speaker 0: It was okay.
Speaker 1: Let's see how good you are, Hattie.
Speaker 1: You probably suck at it.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I beat it.
Speaker 1: You just don't know how to appreciate that flavor of Sonic.
Speaker 0: You've got giant sprites, not a lot of view distance, simple maps, you've got to semi-memorize.
Speaker 1: It had really clever scrolling, actually, the way it could shift left and right and up and down a bit to put Sonic in different parts of the screen so you could see where you were going.
Speaker 1: If you're running really fast to the right, it would push Sonic over to the left so you could see more ahead of you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just Sonic wasn't fast enough.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: He didn't have enough hyper-processing.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: What was my thing of the day?
Speaker 0: I'm not talking about the 2008 Lions series.
Speaker 0: So what was my thing of the day?
Speaker 1: I'll go my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: So this is a video.
Speaker 0: It's a short film.
Speaker 0: It appears it's from Russia and someone has titled it Modern Software Development.
Speaker 0: And it is the saga of someone trying to plug a plug into an outlet that the plug cannot fit into and the method by which they solve their problem.
Speaker 0: And it basically describes how Node.js development works today.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: This whole Node.js thing, I could go off on that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's our Monday episode.
Speaker 0: I said these are web frameworks.
Speaker 1: Just Node?
Speaker 1: Just Why?
Speaker 1: Node.js is Garbage.
Speaker 0: That's a good title.
Speaker 0: It's the next Monday show.
Speaker 1: So this is YouTube.
Speaker 1: I was going to do one YouTube video from this channel, but I'm going to do the whole channel.
Speaker 1: The channel is Psychonomicsp5yckomixxx.
Speaker 1: All caps.
Speaker 1: And what this channel is.
Speaker 1: Do you remember there was like that?
Speaker 1: there was a YouTube channel where the guy was like dubbing over Transformers.
Speaker 1: It's like shockwave.
Speaker 1: You can't shoot shit.
Speaker 0: That is one of the funniest things that exists on the Internet.
Speaker 1: And there was also I don't know if it was the same channel or the different one that had the X-Men.
Speaker 1: It was like, you know, the juggernaut was like, I'm the juggernaut bitch.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It was that.
Speaker 1: This is similar styling.
Speaker 1: But what this is, is basically redubbing unofficial, obviously.
Speaker 0: Created in trial version of Movavi video editor.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But that sort of gives it some charm using the free video editor.
Speaker 1: that adds the overlay of various things, mostly Tunde cats and X-Men in, you know, the beautiful language of Jamaica.
Speaker 1: And this is really awesome because Jamaica is awesome.
Speaker 1: And these are awesome things.
Speaker 1: It's like, dude, you combine.
Speaker 0: Oh, my.
Speaker 0: The lyrics that they used in the opener are written out in the description.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, because for people who, you know, can't understand what they're saying, actually, I can understand it pretty well.
Speaker 1: But, you know, other white people can't.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They need some help.
Speaker 1: And they understand that they're trying to spread, you know, the joy of their language to people through this nerdy medium.
Speaker 1: It's a noble endeavor as well as an entertaining one.
Speaker 0: Good stuff.
Speaker 0: So in the moment, the book club book is Rebecca.
Speaker 0: I'm going to read it real soon.
Speaker 0: We are going to be at Gamer X.
Speaker 1: Hooray.
Speaker 0: Not this weekend.
Speaker 1: Good.
Speaker 0: Not next weekend.
Speaker 0: I think it's the following weekend.
Speaker 0: It is next weekend.
Speaker 0: It's next weekend.
Speaker 1: You're getting close to Thanksgiving.
Speaker 1: There's too many weekends.
Speaker 0: Next weekend, we will be at Gamer X East in New York City, in Manhattan, talking about writing game rules.
Speaker 0: And otherwise, it's just a super awesome LGBT focused and friendly game.
Speaker 1: Our panel is on Sunday, but the con is Saturday, Sunday.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You should go to both days.
Speaker 1: I guess on Saturday we're playing games.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And Sunday we're playing games.
Speaker 1: I get my games together.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, check us out.
Speaker 0: There it is.
Speaker 0: There's our thing.
Speaker 0: Occasionally, the site messes up.
Speaker 0: So it shows.
Speaker 0: the speakers are DeCoster, Rim, Ampersand Quatt, Brandon Ampersand Quatt, and Scott Rubin.
Speaker 0: Good job, Shed.
Speaker 1: Oh, Quatt.
Speaker 1: I see.
Speaker 0: Quatt.
Speaker 1: Their HTML element code.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: How do people still fuck up the Quatt?
Speaker 0: I feel like that's the first thing.
Speaker 0: You just make sure it works on your website.
Speaker 1: Actually, that happens because in their template, they're in their template rendering engine.
Speaker 1: They didn't tell it.
Speaker 1: That's probably in the database, and they didn't mark it as safe, so it's refusing to render it as HTML.
Speaker 1: Instead, it automatically put escape characters and all those things to make them render literally.
Speaker 1: An amateur mistake.
Speaker 0: We're also going to be at MAGFest.
Speaker 0: We're doing, between me and Scott, between five and seven panels.
Speaker 0: And otherwise, it's just four days of gaming and going hot and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: It's going to be good times.
Speaker 1: Play some X-Mon.
Speaker 0: Follow, check out my YouTube channel and Scott's YouTube channel.
Speaker 0: We've both got stuff going on.
Speaker 0: Six player X-Mon.
Speaker 0: And I did read the Fishy story.
Speaker 0: It is on the Patreon if you want to hear the somewhat unnerving tale of Fishy.
Speaker 1: Don't bother with that.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 0: So it was for Halloween, which happened to also be the anniversary of Geek Nights, 11 years running.
Speaker 0: We did the show, and we had a little party where we wanted to watch a horror-ish movie.
Speaker 0: So we watched Attack the Block, which most of the crew had not seen.
Speaker 1: It was in my queue, and now it's out of the queue.
Speaker 1: So all you people who are thinking Scott's queue is not a real thing, it's real.
Speaker 0: It was the second time I've seen it.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty good movie.
Speaker 0: It's not perfect.
Speaker 0: It's got flaws.
Speaker 1: I'm going to say that movie.
Speaker 1: It was a good movie.
Speaker 1: It was entertaining and enjoyable.
Speaker 1: But again, I think the people hyped it up above what it actually was.
Speaker 0: Who hyped it up?
Speaker 0: I remember most people said it's a pretty good horror movie.
Speaker 0: It's better than you expect.
Speaker 1: That's people.
Speaker 0: Who?
Speaker 1: Such as Chase and others on the internet.
Speaker 0: Chase will hype up what he ate for breakfast.
Speaker 1: Everyone who told me about that movie was like, "Oh, it's fucking amazing.
Speaker 0: Chase will tell you that literally any movie is the greatest movie ever.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, many peoples, internet peoples.
Speaker 1: Name another who.
Speaker 1: People on Twitter.
Speaker 0: Who are these people?
Speaker 1: In general, the general sentiment about that movie that was portrayed to me is that it was fucking incredible, and it was good.
Speaker 0: I did not see that anywhere.
Speaker 1: I would show it and promote it to others, but not so crazily.
Speaker 0: I saw people saying it was pretty good, better than I expected, or, "Hey, you should watch this.
Speaker 0: It's not the kind of movie you might think to
Speaker 0: watch.".
Speaker 1: Also, it wasn't the movie I thought it was.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you thought it was ... I know what you were thinking, because we're not going to spoil anything in it, but it escalates to the main thread pretty much right away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I thought it was a different kind of movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It was pretty good, though.
Speaker 0: I liked it, but we're not talking about that today, because before that, in traditional sense, we watched a cartoon, and it was a cartoon that I have not seen.
Speaker 1: That's what you got to do when there's a movie coming on.
Speaker 1: You got to watch the short cartoon before the movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I have not seen this cartoon in its original full format since I was a little, little kid.
Speaker 1: I may have or may not have.
Speaker 1: I've only seen- I remembered that it existed, but I don't remember if I had ever actually seen it in full at any point in my life.
Speaker 0: I have definitely seen it in full.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: I was so young, there was no way I could remember much of it other than vague imagery.
Speaker 0: I remembered every single song.
Speaker 0: Who's that coming down the street?
Speaker 0: I saw- Are they shovels or are they feet?
Speaker 0: I saw this thing- ...
Speaker 1: two days ago.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: I don't remember any songs.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: I remember- Are they shovels or are they feet?
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Can't remember that?
Speaker 1: I remember it because you just said it.
Speaker 1: Before you said that, asked me to name or sing any of the songs, I couldn't.
Speaker 0: I saw it more recently, like middle school, high school, as most kids today I assume see it because Disney would take segments of their older cartoons and embed them in framing stories to make others shit later.
Speaker 1: Right, so people don't realize this, but for a lot of the Disney shorts, like a lot of the legendary type ones that you think of, for example, my favorite Mickey and the Beanstalk, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, okay, they made Mickey and the Beanstalk.
Speaker 1: Where did- Mickey and the Beanstalk's pretty short, right?
Speaker 1: It's not a movie length.
Speaker 1: It's like what, 15 minutes probably?
Speaker 1: I'm just guessing.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's not long, right?
Speaker 1: So where they made this a long ass time ago, right?
Speaker 1: Like the early 20th century, when and where was it released?
Speaker 1: It wasn't put on television.
Speaker 1: It's like they didn't have color TV then, right?
Speaker 1: 29 minutes.
Speaker 1: That's pretty good.
Speaker 1: So it's like if you wanted to see Mickey and the Beanstalk, you didn't go to the movie theater for 29 minutes, right?
Speaker 1: And buy a movie ticket, right?
Speaker 1: How was it released?
Speaker 1: It was released as part of this compilation thing called Fun and Fancy Free.
Speaker 1: You went and bought a ticket to go see Fun and Fancy Free at the movie theater, which was like multiple cartoons, probably like two or three of them.
Speaker 1: And in between the cartoons, there was like narration, live action, puppet show thing to sort of like tie it together somehow.
Speaker 1: And there's a reason no one watches it that way because that shit is scary garbage, right?
Speaker 1: They just cut the cartoons out and released them on VHSs and on television and whatnot individually.
Speaker 1: But the narrator in Mickey and the Beanstalk is the narrator from Fun and Fancy Free.
Speaker 1: So this Ichabod, Mr.
Speaker 1: Crane, whatnot was a similar situation.
Speaker 1: where it was, you went to the movie theater, you bought a ticket and you got multiple Disney shorts together.
Speaker 0: Well, the 11th Walt Disney theatrical animated feature and is the last of the studio's package film era of the 40s following the three Caballeros, which I'm a big fan of as a kid at least.
Speaker 0: Donald's trying to get his freak on with that girl.
Speaker 1: Right, that's what they did before.
Speaker 1: they had the full length animated feature, right?
Speaker 1: Snow White style, right?
Speaker 1: Where it's like 90 minutes, one cartoon.
Speaker 1: Before then, it was the other kind, the package era.
Speaker 1: I guess that's what it's called according to Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Reception, I'm just looking around all the business because I didn't know anything about the history of this particular film.
Speaker 1: Right, so anyway, it's the story of Sleepy Hollow, right?
Speaker 1: There's a dude, Ichabod Crane, he comes to town.
Speaker 1: He's the new school teacher in town.
Speaker 1: He's sort of a weird guy.
Speaker 1: The town is weird.
Speaker 1: And then there's a headless horseman who gets crazy cray with the Halloween action.
Speaker 0: I saw this as a little kid and my memories of it, I remembered all the songs, but it is interesting how different my perception of the story watching it as an adult is compared to as a kid.
Speaker 0: Because as a kid, it was just, "Fuck that bully guy.
Speaker 0: Ichabod Crane is totally the
Speaker 0: hero.".
Speaker 0: And then he got murdered.
Speaker 0: I legit just assumed he got killed by that fucking dude.
Speaker 0: Right, I mean, as a kid, I was aware that it wasn't really the headless horseman, that it was just that jerk.
Speaker 0: And I was also aware that he probably killed Ichabod.
Speaker 0: That's what I thought.
Speaker 1: So not remembering the cartoon very well, right?
Speaker 1: I'd been, you know, most of my exposure to the headless horseman story was just people telling the story.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: Brom Boon's my man.
Speaker 1: And it was told, you know, I'd not read it, like the original, and it was told to me in so many different ways that I didn't really have any clarity on what the real original story actually was, ever.
Speaker 1: Like, if you asked me before we watched it yesterday, it's like, "Tell you the story of the headless
Speaker 1: horseman.".
Speaker 1: I would have been like, "There was a town, and this guy Ichabod Crane comes to town, and then there's an evil headless horseman haunting the town, and it fucks him
Speaker 1: up.".
Speaker 1: Or like, I might have even said, you know, I was actually confused.
Speaker 1: I was like, "Is Ichabod, is he the
Speaker 1: horseman?".
Speaker 1: And he terrorizes the town to get revenge.
Speaker 0: I feel like the headless horseman is a pretty standard and well-known Americana-like story.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it just, in my life, it wasn't told to me in any way that I remembered.
Speaker 0: Right, the only thing as a kid, like this thing's like, "Near the sleepy town of Peekskill, Tarrytown, all that
Speaker 0: business.".
Speaker 0: As a kid, I had no idea this was in New York.
Speaker 1: I literally never even- That's the one thing I did know, because I lived over relatively close.
Speaker 0: I never even considered the idea that there was a place, there was actually a Sleepy Hollow or anything.
Speaker 1: I didn't even really- If Sleepy Hollow had been in Michigan, you wouldn't have felt that way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it was in some other fucking state, so it didn't exist.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it existed for us.
Speaker 0: But then, when I started working at Yonkers, the first time I drove to work on my home, I'm like, "9D Sleepy Hollow, really?
Speaker 0: Is that the Sleepy
Speaker 0: Hollow?".
Speaker 1: Yes, it's the Sleepy Hollow.
Speaker 1: It's not just one of those places that renamed itself to be, you know.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, watching this again as an adult, I really like it a lot, because it's really funny as an adult watching this thing, because Ichabod is kind of a shithead.
Speaker 1: Everyone, there's not really any good people.
Speaker 1: But Bronn Bone- Except the Baker.
Speaker 0: At first, Ichabod's a normal dude, and Bronn Bone's just this awesome hero.
Speaker 0: He's just fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they both start out as being really good.
Speaker 1: At the very beginning, Ichabod, he looks ugly, like a stick person, but he's got skills like Sakamoto, right?
Speaker 1: And Bronn Bone is like Gaston, but he's not an evil Gaston, at least at the very beginning.
Speaker 1: He's just a badass dude in town.
Speaker 0: Pretty sure that this takes place after Sleeping Beauty.
Speaker 0: We're pretty sure that almost every male in this village is one of Gaston's descendants.
Speaker 1: Doesn't Sleeping Beauty take place in Europe?
Speaker 0: I guess he must have made his way over here, because seriously, there's like eight Gastons in this thing.
Speaker 0: And also, wouldn't it be- And then one Uber Gaston.
Speaker 1: Also, wouldn't it be a similar time period?
Speaker 1: Yeah, sure.
Speaker 1: Why does Sleeping Beauty happen?
Speaker 1: I mean, not Sleeping Beauty.
Speaker 1: I mean, Beauty and the Beast.
Speaker 1: Sleeping Beauty definitely happens way before.
Speaker 1: That's like they're living in the castle.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying that Bronn Bone is definitely somehow related to Gaston.
Speaker 1: They definitely have similar personalities and appearances.
Speaker 0: But basically, as an adult just watching this, Ichabod's just educated and self-serving.
Speaker 1: But he's still a bad person.
Speaker 0: He's not that bad, though.
Speaker 0: He's self-serving.
Speaker 1: He's not that bad, but yeah, he's not like a saint.
Speaker 0: I mean, what?
Speaker 0: He's actually teaching those girls how to sing, and they all swoon over him just because he knows stuff.
Speaker 1: But he's teaching them to swing because he wants them to swoon.
Speaker 1: Hey, if you do a bad- He's not teaching them to sing to actually spread cultures.
Speaker 0: If you do a good thing for a bad reason, you still did a good thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't make you a good person, though.
Speaker 0: Who cares if he's a good or bad person?
Speaker 0: He wasn't doing anything wrong.
Speaker 1: You were just arguing about whether he was a good person or not.
Speaker 0: The only bad thing he did is he stole that one pie.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, he bought- He stole a lot of food.
Speaker 1: Also, how did he eat so much and not get fat and be a stick figure?
Speaker 0: Well, because he appears to be literally twice as tall as anyone in this town.
Speaker 1: He was very tall, yeah.
Speaker 0: When they're dancing.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile, Brom Bones, it seems fine.
Speaker 0: But then as soon as he wants to make it with that girl, then he turns into a giant shithead and proceeds to do a bunch of illegal and intimidating things.
Speaker 0: He tries to basically murder Ichabod Crane, and then he does murder Ichabod Crane.
Speaker 1: Also, the girl seems to not- It's like, if you're a kid watching it, you know, you don't see carefully.
Speaker 0: No, as a kid, I just assumed she likes Ichabod, and then she's trying to ruin it.
Speaker 1: But actually, she's just sort of using Ichabod to make the other dude jealous, and she just takes it too far.
Speaker 1: She could have had that dude any time she wanted.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: But only an adult eyeball can see that happening.
Speaker 0: But that's why her and Ichabod would actually be good for each other, because they're both just manipulating other people, and with his mad skills and her mad skills and her father's wealth, because when Ichabod's imagining being with her- They could have run that shit.
Speaker 0: He keeps imagining, like, "Ooh, I'll make out with
Speaker 0: her.".
Speaker 0: But then he imagines, like, it shows her dad sitting there, and he imagines himself wearing all the dad's stuff.
Speaker 0: And our friend Judith is just like, "One day, I'll be
Speaker 0: you.".
Speaker 0: But they would have made a good team, and I wonder if she was feeling that too.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: 'Cause she was a little bit disdainful of Brom Bones' rough and uneducated ways, but I guess she ended up marrying him, so...
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: You know, Ichabod's dead.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure he's- I mean, they show you this, like, denomat, where, like, weird rumors that he went off and married some woman and had all these kids that look just like him, but those are just rumors.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure Brom Bones just fucking killed him, because in the actual chase segment, he is really trying- He's swinging a sword at him violently.
Speaker 0: And we know from an earlier scene that that sword is sharp as fuck.
Speaker 1: And it's surprising, like, how much he swings it without actually hitting him, but here's the thing.
Speaker 1: If he did kill him, he wasn't smart, Brom Bones, right?
Speaker 0: So- No, he left the pumpkin there so that the townsfolk would assume that the Headless Horseman had driven him away, when really, he's buried in a shallow grave right off the side of that road.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Where is this body, right?
Speaker 1: He's not good at hiding the body.
Speaker 1: It would have been found.
Speaker 0: I don't think it would have been found.
Speaker 0: Who's gonna go looking for a body?
Speaker 1: If you put it in a shallow grave, they're gonna smell it.
Speaker 0: Nah, probably not.
Speaker 1: I mean- On that well-traveled road?
Speaker 0: That road looked the opposite of well-traveled.
Speaker 1: It had a bridge on it, therefore it had to have some amount of travel.
Speaker 0: He had all night, too.
Speaker 0: Like, who's looking for him?
Speaker 0: He could have done anything with it.
Speaker 1: Also, apparently you need to go on that road to get from the party barn to the town.
Speaker 1: 'Cause I guess they have their parties way outside town.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: It's right by the water.
Speaker 0: Maybe he just threw the body in the river and it floated away.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Town downstream's not gonna be like, "Hey, is this your
Speaker 0: body?".
Speaker 0: They're just gonna ignore it or bury it themselves.
Speaker 0: They don't care.
Speaker 0: I mean, what would- Maybe it goes into the Hudson.
Speaker 0: I mean, look at where this place is.
Speaker 0: It's gonna end up in, like, New York, that body.
Speaker 1: All I'm gonna say is, you know, the baker is the best person in this whole- I forgot about all the other girls in this thing.
Speaker 1: The singing ones?
Speaker 1: Yeah, because- Well, 'cause they get so much screen time right at the very beginning and then they're gone.
Speaker 0: Except the chubby girl, who's cute, who comes back and is a major weapon that is used between the two guys.
Speaker 1: But she can't dance.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I love how in the background her sound effect is just, "Whoo, whoo, whoo, whoo, whoo,
Speaker 0: whoo.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one in this whole thing talks.
Speaker 1: There's no voice acting.
Speaker 0: It's just Bing Crosby narrating.
Speaker 1: It's all noises and one narrator voiceover and that's it.
Speaker 0: The animation is also pretty superb, actually.
Speaker 1: It's Disney animation, right?
Speaker 1: So it's the same exact Disney animation you get with all other Disney things.
Speaker 0: On Wikipedia, the two lone rivals are invited to the Van Tassel Halloween party where Braum tries to swap a plump woman for Katrina, but comically fails.
Speaker 0: But that scene, I wouldn't laugh out loud other than add my adult observations to this thing until that scene, because it goes on so much longer than you expect it to.
Speaker 1: You should go find the video on YouTube that shows the animation that was reused from or in this, right?
Speaker 1: Because that's what Disney did, is they just animated things once.
Speaker 0: But there's not nearly as much, as far as I can tell, compared to the Robin Hood.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was the Robin Hood Lion King one, right?
Speaker 1: Lion King?
Speaker 1: Not Lion King, Jungle Book.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: The Jungle Book Robin Hood where it's the exact same dance.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Used twice, yeah.
Speaker 0: Half that movie is just- The same exact movie.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I mean, if you are in the mood to watch a short Disney from the olden days, you should watch Mickey and the Beanstalk.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And if you're still in the mood, you should watch something else with Goofy in it.
Speaker 0: Actually, my favorites are still all of the.
Speaker 0: Goofy teaches you how to do a thing, like Goofy goes skiing.
Speaker 1: You should watch some, you know, you should go watch some Donald Duck or some Chip and Dale.
Speaker 1: But you know, this isn't a bad choice.
Speaker 0: This is actually, I'd put it pretty high up there, because it's very demonstrative of what Disney was like in that era.
Speaker 0: And it's a half hour long.
Speaker 0: And if you're really desperate, there's a whole other half hour with the wind in the willows that we just skipped.
Speaker 1: Don't watch that garbage.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I've ever actually seen it.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure as a kid, we never watched it.
Speaker 0: We just watched the Sleepy Hollow one.
Speaker 1: I definitely, I don't remember much, but I remember there was the Mr.
Speaker 1: Toad cartoon, because I saw it.
Speaker 1: Because I was like, you know, this is Mr.
Speaker 1: Toad's wild ride at Disney World.
Speaker 1: And I was like, what the fuck is Mr.
Speaker 1: Toad?
Speaker 1: So then I saw that at some point.
Speaker 1: And I remember just being like, whoa, that is not good.
Speaker 1: I don't remember anything else other than that's not good.
Speaker 0: Alright, so yeah, Bing Crosby did play Ichabod Crane, Brom Bones, and the narrator whenever sound effects were needed.
Speaker 0: Uh, the, let's see, ready, Thaddeus Toad, Mr.
Speaker 0: Winky.
Speaker 0: I'm just looking at all these people here.
Speaker 0: A guy named Pinto Culvig did one role.
Speaker 0: He played Ichabod Crane whenever he was screaming, apparently.
Speaker 1: The scream guy.
Speaker 0: Uh, Pinto Culvig was a vaudeville act.
Speaker 0: Ooh, I found a bunch of Wikipedia pages to read.
Speaker 0: He lived until the late '60s.
Speaker 1: It is a somewhat vaudevillian act, this cartoon here.
Speaker 0: The madcap antics while they're dancing, that would be a good vaudeville stage scene, I guess.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So yeah, this was our Halloween, this and Attack the Block.
Speaker 0: Attack the Block isn't really relevant to Wednesday, but this certainly was.
Speaker 1: Attack the Block is way better than this.
Speaker 0: Aye!
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 0: Definitely is.
Speaker 0: But, I liked this way more than you did for whatever reason.
Speaker 0: Like, I really enjoyed watching this again, partly because I hadn't seen it since I was a little kid.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm just comparing it to Mickey and the Beanstalk, and it's not, it's maybe slightly more than half as good.
Speaker 0: Mickey and the Beanstalk is pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's like A+, what are you talking about?
Speaker 0: Well, you're just obsessed with Goofy and that Jello.
Speaker 1: That's just the best part.
Speaker 1: That's like, that's like the, uh, you know, the platinum frosting on the golden cake.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, the platinum frosting tasted the best, but it's still fucking golden cakes.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons, in order of the amount of money they give us on a continuing basis are... Brian Cedroni, Finn Eric Silveroff, The Rural Juror, Chris Minkin, Chris Knox, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: And a whole shit-ton of people who give less than five dollars a month.
Speaker 0: Seriously, though, uh, Scott Sablazane is aside.
Speaker 0: He is actually voting, and I swear to God, if you don't vote, shit's kind of bad right now.
Speaker 0: And we just gotta hold out and swallow your pride.
Speaker 0: Vote for Hillary Clinton, who is the officially recommended nominee of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: And we'll see you on the flip side.
Speaker 0: But now, I leave you with something that has nothing to do with the election, and is simply fantastic.
Speaker 0: ♪ Maybe Arden, maybe he ain't.
Speaker 1: ♪ ♪.
Speaker 1: Anyway, there's no complaint ♪ ♪ From Ichabod, Ichabod Crane.
Speaker 0: ♪ ♪.
Speaker 0: And though the arrival of the pedagogue gave rise to mixed emotions ♪ ♪ The townspeople all agreed they'd never seen anyone.
Speaker 1: ♪ ♪ Like Ichabod, Ichabod Crane ♪.