Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, December 6th, 2016.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 1: The Jackbox Party Pack 3.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So last week, on Friday, my life changed.
Speaker 1: Uh huh.
Speaker 1: My life changed in a significant way that will impact me for days to come and in fact, impacted me even today.
Speaker 1: Mmhmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is true.
Speaker 1: So, you know how I annoyingly, like, I don't know, like, a lot of, like, super history about the subway.
Speaker 1: Like, I'm not a deep, deep, like, trained nerd.
Speaker 1: But I know, like, a lot about the operational, like, shit of the New York City subway.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, more than normal person because you're a nerd.
Speaker 0: And a nerd, even though a nerd may specialize in one area, any nerd usually knows more about everything than a non-nerd.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: You could go up to, like, if you go to someone who's not a nerd at all or not a geek in any way, shape, or form, it's like they can tell you about, like, that TV show they watch and that's about it.
Speaker 0: But if you go to someone who might be, like, a fighting game nerd and you ask them about some anime, and anime is not their main deal.
Speaker 0: They're not listening to anime podcasts.
Speaker 0: They're not, you know, reading anime news network.
Speaker 0: But they've seen some animes because they're in the fighting game community.
Speaker 0: They know more about animes than just a random person on the street.
Speaker 1: Because, like, the new subway that's coming, right?
Speaker 1: The T?
Speaker 1: The only people I know who even today know that it's called the T are...
Speaker 0: People who pay attention.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically all our friends know and, like, no one normal seems to know that even though that has been, like, on subway maps for over a year at this point.
Speaker 1: But anyway, like, I know, like, I know a lot about the subway and it's usually more annoying to people than practical because I'll bring it up a lot.
Speaker 1: But something happened that affected me about the subway.
Speaker 1: And while it's something I should have anticipated and known, I did not know it and was surprised by it.
Speaker 1: So, you know how they brought the W back, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, normally, what's the difference between the N, Q, R, and W?
Speaker 1: Like, what are they, like, generally, like, what's the differences between them?
Speaker 0: So, the R, once it gets to Queens, goes a different way than the N and W.
Speaker 1: Yup, it does come here, but it goes, like, way off to Queens Plaza and then it goes, like, way out into Queens.
Speaker 0: It goes to Eastern Queens.
Speaker 1: It doesn't go to Scott's.
Speaker 1: It's the one that comes, like, when Scott and I are in Manhattan late at night that I can take home, but kind of just fuck Scott.
Speaker 0: Also, once you get downtown to, like, after Canal Street, I think?
Speaker 1: Yup, Canal Street's the line.
Speaker 0: They all split off into three different ways.
Speaker 1: Yup, well, there's really only two ways now, but...
Speaker 0: There's one that goes even further downtown and there's one that just goes fuck it and goes to Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So, here's the big thing that I didn't think about, 'cause they brought the W back to make up for the fact that the Q don't go to Queens anymore.
Speaker 1: 'Cause the Q's gonna eventually go up the T to 125th Street.
Speaker 1: So, when the W came back, what route does the W follow?
Speaker 0: The W?
Speaker 0: It's local in Manhattan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it goes to Astoria up here.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: But, currently, before the W came back, if I was in here and I want to go to work, 'cause my work is way down by Fulton Street, I pretty much have to transfer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there is no direct way to take the subway to my work.
Speaker 1: I either take the 7 or the N or the Q, in the old days, across to either Times Square.
Speaker 1: I guess I could connect to the F and do some bullshit, but that sucks.
Speaker 1: Or I can go to Grand Central.
Speaker 1: And then I take either the 1, 2, 3, or the 4, 5 downtown to my office.
Speaker 0: Pretty sure the N goes all the way downtown.
Speaker 1: No, it never has.
Speaker 1: The N turns to Canal Street and goes off to Fuck All.
Speaker 0: So, the R goes all the way downtown.
Speaker 1: Yup, but the R doesn't stop at Queensborough Plaza.
Speaker 0: It stops at Queens Plaza, which is right there in the same place, basically.
Speaker 1: No, it takes like 5 minutes to walk there.
Speaker 0: I just walked from the R. It took not 5 minutes.
Speaker 0: It takes almost 5 minutes.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Also, the R, if I go to that subway, yes, the R kinda goes direct to my office.
Speaker 1: It's local the whole way, and it doesn't come that often.
Speaker 0: Also, the R comes super often.
Speaker 0: In fact, the R is the least crowded subway, even though it's older trains, usually.
Speaker 0: Not always, but usually.
Speaker 0: It is the least crowded and most luxurious because it is the least crowded.
Speaker 1: A lot of the R, yeah, so downtown, the R is like crowded nightmare territory.
Speaker 0: Well, it's the least crowded in Queens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, 'cause no one's on it by then, 'cause everyone wants the N.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying.
Speaker 1: So, but, and also, if I go to Queens Plaza, Queensborough Plaza.
Speaker 0: So, you're saying the W, because the W now is back, it takes you from Queens Plaza, Queensborough Plaza, not Queens Plaza.
Speaker 1: Direct to my office.
Speaker 0: Down where, okay, sure.
Speaker 1: So, it stops at Prince Street and City Hall, which, if I just looked at the subway map even once, like, when they said they were bringing the W back, I didn't think about down there, like, 'cause the last time the W existed, I didn't go down there.
Speaker 1: I worked in, like, I worked next to Grand Central.
Speaker 1: I didn't care about those up-down subways on, like, my normal commute.
Speaker 1: And going to Queens Plaza is kind of a dicey thing, because if anything happens, like, if the R's down, what, I can take the super fucking local E, like, all the way, and that takes forever.
Speaker 1: Or I can wait for an M.
Speaker 0: The E is, like, the most express train there is, like, woosh.
Speaker 1: Not if you're going into Manhattan, it stops everywhere.
Speaker 1: It's good if you're going to, like, West 4th Street, or if you're going to, like, the Upper East Side, but otherwise, it's actually not that great.
Speaker 1: And it also gets super crowded, like, crazy crowded.
Speaker 0: Well, 'cause it's super express, it goes everywhere.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So...
Speaker 0: Even goes to the JFK.
Speaker 1: And it's rare that when the subway, like, updates the map, that it actually affects me directly.
Speaker 1: So I'm going, I have to stop at REI to, like, buy some ski boots.
Speaker 1: So I go to City Hall Station, which is right next to my office, and I can take the, usually the R stop there, and only the R. But the R will take any N, I think.
Speaker 1: But it would take me to, uh, Prince Street, where the REI is.
Speaker 0: There's a whole lot of talking for a whole lot of nothing.
Speaker 0: Also, why are you going to REI?
Speaker 1: That's, like, the best sports store.
Speaker 1: Paragon's kind of, like, not great.
Speaker 0: I've heard that, you know, pretty much only lame-os buy sporting goods at department stores.
Speaker 1: Alright, where would you buy ski boots?
Speaker 1: Uh, no.
Speaker 1: Ski boots need to be fitted, like, in person.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 1: There's, buying ski boots on Amazon, or even, like, Zappos or something, would be awful.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I try to, like, temper.
Speaker 1: Most don't fit me that well.
Speaker 0: The special ski store.
Speaker 0: Uh, alright.
Speaker 1: Where are specialized ski stores in New York City?
Speaker 1: Because I've been to almost all of them, and you know what?
Speaker 1: They're all way overpriced, and have really shitty selections.
Speaker 0: Uh, they have a shittier selection than REI.
Speaker 1: REI has an excellent selection of ski boots.
Speaker 1: They also are one of the only places that has good ski services.
Speaker 0: Oh, look.
Speaker 0: There is not only a ski shop.
Speaker 1: What, Emilio's?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: There is a special ski boot shop called Surefoot that has 4.1 out of 5 star rating on Amazon.
Speaker 1: Ooh.
Speaker 1: On Amazon.
Speaker 1: So, can I try them all out?
Speaker 0: I meant on Google reviews, you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is a special ski boot only store.
Speaker 1: Also, Scott.
Speaker 0: That looks really fancy, actually.
Speaker 1: I went there.
Speaker 0: These ski boots have, like, hoses coming out of them.
Speaker 1: You seem to, like, forget how this works.
Speaker 1: I went there, got the experts to explain to me the differences of all these boots, and I tried them all on, and I found the boots I wanted.
Speaker 1: Didn't say I bought them there.
Speaker 1: Also, I got to take my skis there because I bought my skis online and delivered them to the REI because I'm going to have professionals put my bindings on because I just don't want to deal with that crap.
Speaker 1: And, yeah.
Speaker 1: So, now I can take the W direct to work, and the W is the most luxurious train because it goes down to Whitehall.
Speaker 1: So, basically, no one gets on it until, like, 34th Street.
Speaker 1: So, I can sit down in a whole -- I can lay down on a whole row.
Speaker 1: No one will stop me.
Speaker 0: There's almost the same person who would be like, "Ah, fuck them yellow trains.
Speaker 0: Take the
Speaker 0: 7.".
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: If I'm waiting at Queensborough Plaza and a 7 comes first, I'm still taking it because the 7 to the 4-5 is less comfortable but actually still, on average, 4 minutes faster.
Speaker 1: My commute home today took -- exactly all I'm going to take.
Speaker 1: It took 30 -- That's way long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I go downtown.
Speaker 1: The best you can get to downtown, like, the best -- 34 minutes.
Speaker 1: The best possible commute to downtown by Fulton Street if every subway is working like clockwork and you get on the trains immediately is 28 minutes.
Speaker 1: That is the best possible case.
Speaker 1: And that is if you take the N or any yellow train to 59th Street and then catch a 4 or a 5 downtown and you make the connection and there's no one in your way on that stairwell.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: You were making a big deal about some opening bit you had.
Speaker 1: that was apparently fascinating.
Speaker 0: I just can't remember it.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 1: I guess a bird in the hand is better than none in the bush.
Speaker 0: No, because a shit in the hand is worse than empty, clean hands.
Speaker 1: But I was standing there at Prince Street like, "Well, I guess take the fucking R home because fuck
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 1: And then I see the W coming.
Speaker 1: I'm like, "The W!
Speaker 1: You're back!
Speaker 1: You're my
Speaker 1: buddy!".
Speaker 0: He's been back for a while.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I hadn't been to Prince Street since the W came.
Speaker 1: I mean, how often do you go to Prince Street?
Speaker 1: What's the last time you've been to Prince Street?
Speaker 0: Uh... I went to... I went to something.
Speaker 0: What the hell did I go to?
Speaker 1: Was that where you're thinking that it happened?
Speaker 1: At Prince Street?
Speaker 0: On the W?
Speaker 0: Oh, I went to see, uh...
Speaker 1: Babymetal?
Speaker 0: Miss Hokusai.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: With Judalee when you weren't in town and beforehand, because I had a bunch of time, I went to Prince Street first instead of just getting off at Bleecker and then did some stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, because right there is all the good clothing stores, too.
Speaker 1: It's like a Uniqlo and an H&M and everything right there.
Speaker 0: It's where the fancy clothing... It's a clothing shopping district.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And all the other sports stores are there, too, if you don't want to just go to REI.
Speaker 0: You go for like, "Oh my god,
Speaker 0: shopping!".
Speaker 0: "Oh my god, designer
Speaker 0: whatever!".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, occasionally I need new pants or whatever, so I'll go over there.
Speaker 1: I actually need some more Uniqlo pants.
Speaker 0: You can't just buy pants.
Speaker 0: You gotta go to the fancy store.
Speaker 1: Well, I really like Uniqlo jeans.
Speaker 0: You know, there's like a whole bunch of other Uniqlos that are closer.
Speaker 1: But that Uniqlo is right next to my work!
Speaker 1: I can just like stop there on my way home.
Speaker 0: Prince Street is nowhere near your work.
Speaker 0: It's way downtown.
Speaker 0: Prince Street is sort of middle-ish.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I leave work, and I get on the W, and I take it to Prince, buy my shit, get right back on the W, and take it all the way home.
Speaker 0: The real problem is that the flagship Uniqlo at like Fifth Avenue and 57...
Speaker 1: It's always so crowded, like...
Speaker 0: No, it's like the biggest, best one.
Speaker 0: But it is now in the no-go zone.
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: The evil dude in his tower.
Speaker 0: It's in the no-go zone.
Speaker 0: It's right in, you know, Mordor moved in, so it's too close.
Speaker 0: You gotta go to like the 34th Street one now.
Speaker 0: Oh, this isn't Mordor.
Speaker 1: This is like Saruman's tower.
Speaker 1: Like, Saruman's tower is like in the middle of the Shire.
Speaker 1: Like, some fucking hobbit's trying to get his beer.
Speaker 1: It used to be the same place to go, and now you can't go there.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I encountered that not too long ago, because we met Judalee to go to a movie, and they had their car, like, in Manhattan, because it was like late at night.
Speaker 1: So they just drove us home, and everything is fine, and we get to Fifth Avenue, and then all at once we go, "Oh, right.
Speaker 1: Fuck.".
Speaker 1: And then it took us a while.
Speaker 1: Well, we had to go across town, and it was causing traffic problems cross town, because...
Speaker 0: This is why I don't use a car.
Speaker 1: But it was there, and getting home from 84th Street's not always the fastest late at night.
Speaker 1: Alright, got any news?
Speaker 0: Because I got some follow-up news.
Speaker 0: So, it is the 20th anniversary of something you wouldn't think about on a daily basis.
Speaker 1: Windjammers?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Parappa the Rapper.
Speaker 1: Oh, my man.
Speaker 1: Crack, crack, crack the eggs into the bowl.
Speaker 1: M-I-X, the flower into the bowl.
Speaker 0: So, anyway.
Speaker 0: So, this game came out 20 years ago.
Speaker 0: And there was an anime of it a ways back, right?
Speaker 0: But, for the 20th anniversary, it's getting a new fancy re-release on PS4 and maybe other... I think only PS4 probably, but maybe something else.
Speaker 0: And, there's also going to be a new Parappa anime also coming out.
Speaker 1: Ah, Parappa.
Speaker 0: So, it's Parappa time.
Speaker 0: This game is weird.
Speaker 0: It's like 20 years old.
Speaker 0: Like, holy shit, it's old.
Speaker 0: I thought it was dead.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is, you look at modern...
Speaker 0: It's like, it's one of those, like, there's so many of these properties, right, that are like... Someone made the property, it maybe even lasted a while and got sequels or something, and then went away.
Speaker 0: But, it still has.
Speaker 0: people still remember it, but it's gone, right?
Speaker 0: Yup, yup.
Speaker 0: And, some of them, sort of like, have always staying power, right?
Speaker 0: So, something like Voltron, for example, has sort of like this staying power, where it's always around a little bit just to stay alive.
Speaker 0: And, occasionally, gets brought back a bunch.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: But, usually, it's just sort of like in the sleep mode, where like maybe a comic book will come out, maybe, just to keep the property rolling.
Speaker 1: Well, like current Sonic the Hedgehog.
Speaker 0: But, Parappa was one of those ones where no one was... I thought it was just 100% dead dead.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Like, there was no new Parappa anything.
Speaker 1: Like, people too much younger than us, I couldn't even reference it because they would have no idea.
Speaker 0: Right, it's like, I thought it was, you know, there's a lot of those that, like, Viewtiful Joe's one, right?
Speaker 0: It's like back in college days, like, there were multiple games and even an anime.
Speaker 0: But, now, as far as I know, it's dead dead.
Speaker 0: There is no new Viewtiful Joe anything and is unlikely to be in the near future.
Speaker 1: It's also real interesting when you think about the fact that, like, modern rhythm games that aren't dancing games are all basically the exact same game.
Speaker 1: Like, they all just, like, copy, like, they're all just really, in my opinion...
Speaker 0: Except for Dub Wars, which is not like those.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's a lot of, like, weird indie ones on Steam that do something clever.
Speaker 1: But, Parappa, like, not a bad design for that kind of game, considering how old it is.
Speaker 0: Also one of the first.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: 20 years old, right?
Speaker 0: So, yeah, if you Parappa'd back in the day and you have a nostalgia for the rapping and the chopping.
Speaker 0: And putting your eggs in bowls, now is the time to relive that while you can.
Speaker 0: 'Cause I don't know if it'll come back again in a 30, 40, 50 year anniversary.
Speaker 0: 'Cause it's not that big a deal.
Speaker 0: And if you never Parappa'd, now is your chance to Rapa Rapa.
Speaker 0: So... Because you should.
Speaker 1: Do you remember Dale Brown?
Speaker 0: I have no idea what that is.
Speaker 1: Okay, 'cause he has another name.
Speaker 1: He is Hanjo.
Speaker 0: Oh, that guy.
Speaker 1: He's that guy.
Speaker 0: The guy you went on and on about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the guy who was trying to have the lowest possible rank in Overwatch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, uh, respectable.
Speaker 1: So he kept that up and he has a whole team, Team Hanjo.
Speaker 1: And, like, they've continued to aspire to be the very worst.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: And, like, they treat it professionally.
Speaker 0: Why don't they be the worst in some other games to sort of spread out, you know?
Speaker 1: Well, 'cause they're really specializing in this.
Speaker 1: Because the best part is...
Speaker 0: And you've already hit the worst possible rank.
Speaker 0: How much worse can you be?
Speaker 1: No, he hit the first possible rank in Season 1.
Speaker 1: And then they substantially changed how the ranking system worked.
Speaker 1: And Season 2, he eventually hit bottom, but it took a long time.
Speaker 1: He set a record.
Speaker 1: He was, 'cause now there's a whole bunch of Korean players who are always racing him to the bottom.
Speaker 1: He beat everybody.
Speaker 1: He hit a score of one on the first day of Season 3.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 1: He is a pro at this.
Speaker 0: That tells me the ranking system is actually improved.
Speaker 0: If it's downranking him for being so shitty so quickly, it's doing a better job.
Speaker 1: But this article follows up on just, like, the state of that world.
Speaker 1: And apparently, oh, there was such a great quote in here, but they do everything in extremes.
Speaker 1: So their goal is not just to lose, but to be as super fucking amazing and great as possible and still lose.
Speaker 1: I think they set a record in one game for the most kills in one match any player has ever gotten.
Speaker 0: Oh, because they're playing against people who are so shitty.
Speaker 1: They're playing against people who are so bad that they just saw it by accident.
Speaker 0: So it's easy to get all these kills, but then you just ignore the objective.
Speaker 0: Like, if you played Counter-Strike, well, I guess in Counter-Strike, no one comes back to life.
Speaker 0: If it was, I guess, in Quake, only killing matters.
Speaker 0: But if somehow in Counter-Strike you killed everyone on the team except one person, no one on your team died, but you pushed the hostages into the zone and got them rescued even though you're the terrorist and you didn't want them to be rescued.
Speaker 1: So he talks a lot about, like, people he's run into and situations that have occurred through these eras.
Speaker 1: Like, they started spawn camping for a while to see if they could do it because it's real hard to spawn camp in this game.
Speaker 1: Like, even a crappy team can bust out of their spawn.
Speaker 0: Well, you're getting reloads in there and shit because it's like a Team Fortress game, right?
Speaker 1: Like, set up a turret in there if you have to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because it's like Team Fortress.
Speaker 0: A spawn is like an invincible base you can't touch.
Speaker 0: Of course you can get out.
Speaker 1: They found people where they could basically keep them in their spawn forever.
Speaker 1: Like, there's literally no way for them to get out.
Speaker 0: Well, there is a way for them to get out.
Speaker 0: They just...
Speaker 1: No, there's no way for them to get out.
Speaker 1: Learn!
Speaker 1: He's also talked about running into crazy people who he'll keep running into because that bottom barrel, like, there's this person he keeps talking about as, like, the worst Reinhardt in the world.
Speaker 1: But that kid was actually trying to be good.
Speaker 1: Just wasn't.
Speaker 1: And how he watched him.
Speaker 1: eventually, like, slowly start to get better.
Speaker 1: So, the final quote of this article is a quote because he was asked a bunch of direct questions in the interview.
Speaker 1: "I have no plans of ever stopping
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 0: I'm sure he will eventually.
Speaker 0: It'll get un-fun at some point.
Speaker 0: Unless he's one of those obsessive types where, like, he can just focus on it so much.
Speaker 0: In which case, it's kind of sad because we need people like that to focus on something important.
Speaker 0: Imagine if you pointed that amount of effort at something meaningful.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: Not that this is meaningless, but I feel like once you achieve the rank one once, like, you don't need... There's no... Keep doing it over and over doesn't really, you know, add to it, right?
Speaker 0: You're better off doing something else now.
Speaker 0: If he could lose legendarily at other things, I think he could, like, keep coming back more, you know, as a big deal.
Speaker 0: But by concentrating on the one thing only, it only has so much staying power.
Speaker 1: So, after he hit the bottom, he started doing a different experiment.
Speaker 1: He teamed up with that really bad Reinhardt player who I think he described as the worst Reinhardt player ever.
Speaker 1: And tried to team up with him and bring him as high into the ranks as he could.
Speaker 0: Oh, with a different account?
Speaker 1: Same account because he hit bottom.
Speaker 1: He doesn't need to stay there.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: So, once he hits bottom, it's like he won and then he spends the rest of the season experimenting.
Speaker 0: Oh, and then the season resets and he tries to go to the bottom again?
Speaker 0: What if he ended one season at the bottom?
Speaker 0: Wouldn't he start the next season at the bottom?
Speaker 1: No, he'd do ten placement matches at the beginning of every season.
Speaker 0: So, at every season they reset everything?
Speaker 1: I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: I think they seed you a little bit based on your previous rank.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's really interesting because that actually sounds better.
Speaker 0: What Hearthstone does is basically you have to grind to get into the legendary and then it's real ranking.
Speaker 0: But then at the beginning of every season, they basically downrank everyone some amount.
Speaker 0: So, if you were a legend at the end of a season, you're now going to start the season at rank five or seven.
Speaker 0: But if you ended the season at rank sixteen, you're going to start the next season at rank twenty.
Speaker 0: So, they just downrank everyone and force you to grind your way back in.
Speaker 1: So, you'd basically do ten placement matches and all that means is you play in competitive and you don't have a rank.
Speaker 1: And after you do the tenth one, it is like based on your performance in those ten, here's your starting rank.
Speaker 1: Good luck, have fun.
Speaker 0: Oh, so if you significantly improve, all your old games don't matter, only your placement.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're good, you'll start Platinum.
Speaker 1: If you're bad, you'll start Honjo.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day!
Speaker 1: So, I actually also have this issue of Mad Magazine.
Speaker 1: In fact, actually, because my mom and dad are both my families going back, we're independently big fans of Mad Magazine.
Speaker 1: I actually have crates and crates and crates of like...
Speaker 0: Your mom has crates and crates and crates.
Speaker 0: You don't have any.
Speaker 0: You have zero Mad Magazines in this apartment.
Speaker 0: None Mad Magazine.
Speaker 1: Yes, I own a lot of things or have access to a lot of things that are at my mom's giant house.
Speaker 0: Oh, I mean, if you're going to have access, like I have access to almost every book ever written.
Speaker 0: I can just go to the library.
Speaker 1: Do you have physical ones?
Speaker 1: Because the Mad Collection that we have is actually like the earliest Mads on.
Speaker 1: It might be almost a complete set.
Speaker 0: I'm confident that there is a New York library.
Speaker 0: you can go to where they have old magazines they have available.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, it's possible.
Speaker 1: I'll look into it.
Speaker 1: But I'm definitely sure I have this one.
Speaker 1: And basically, Mad Magazine, making fun of board games, posted... They just had this one article that was the rules to a game.
Speaker 1: And I've referenced this game in the past, just kind of offhandedly.
Speaker 1: But I've never really referenced it into detail, but I remember the name and not much else.
Speaker 1: So this brought back a lot of memories.
Speaker 1: The game is called Three Cornered Pitney.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: And...
Speaker 0: Is it like Calvin Ball, basically?
Speaker 1: It is a game that has very specific rules how to play it.
Speaker 1: And all the rules are here on the internet for your enjoyment.
Speaker 1: And I'm going to add slides with some of these to our panel on writing game rules.
Speaker 1: So here's step nine of the game.
Speaker 1: Three Cornered Pitney officially begins when the first player rolls the three dice and subtracts the number on one of them from the combined total shown on the other two.
Speaker 1: A bunch of examples.
Speaker 0: So if I roll six, one, and two, I can subtract one from eight and get seven.
Speaker 0: Or I can subtract two from seven and get five.
Speaker 1: And you keep doing it.
Speaker 0: Or I can subtract six from three and get negative three.
Speaker 1: The player whose point total on the die comes closest to the host telephone number must announce this fact by calling out, quote, "I vouchsafed that the opening Vinmert has herewith
Speaker 1: elapsed.".
Speaker 1: The others realizing it takes only three Vinmerts to make a complete Fenny may respond by either shouting, "I challenge" or "Souls your old
Speaker 1: man.".
Speaker 0: I challenge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I also challenge.
Speaker 1: So this is, it's like Hall, that role playing game you're not supposed to play in board game form.
Speaker 0: All right, so my thing of the day is also related to Parappa the Rappa.
Speaker 0: So in honor of the 20th anniversary of Parappa the Rappa in Japan, the land where it seems like magic land for nerds and that is continues to be true to this day.
Speaker 1: Oh man, I want to go to this.
Speaker 0: They opened up a temporary Parappa the Rappa pop up store.
Speaker 0: I do not know in which part of Japan this is.
Speaker 0: I assume Tokyo or what somebody's big.
Speaker 0: because otherwise, why would you write?
Speaker 0: and you can see on this guy's Twitter account.
Speaker 0: There's other photos of the other parts of this store.
Speaker 0: It's quite elaborate considering what, you know, Parappa the Rappa, but the best part of the store is the dojo, which you can stand in and play Parappa the Rappa.
Speaker 0: I assume that's the remake version that he's playing there and the dojo as you play and chop your onions is quite animated.
Speaker 0: And if this, you know, the only reason I'm not going to this is because it's in Japan and not in New York.
Speaker 1: So Scott, why is Master Onion so good at rapping?
Speaker 0: Uh, good question.
Speaker 1: Because he's a rapscallion.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is great for rap of a man.
Speaker 0: So yeah, uh, reasons to move to Japan plus one.
Speaker 1: In the matter of a moment, the Book Club book is Rebecca.
Speaker 1: I started reading it today because I finished the Mad Adam trilogy, the two following books from Oryx and Craig.
Speaker 0: I actually watched a movie recently that was in the same genre-ish, kind of, and that got me in the mood for reading it and I continued reading it.
Speaker 0: I read like two more chapters than I read previously.
Speaker 0: I should probably finish it real soon.
Speaker 1: Alright, I'll burn through it pretty quick, I think.
Speaker 1: Because now that I have a 28 to 34 minute subway commute that does not involve me having to stand up or transfer trains, I can read a lot more.
Speaker 0: The only thing that got in the way is Pokemon started to get in the way, but then Mario Maker 3DS came and pushed that out of the way.
Speaker 1: That's what you were playing when I came home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm making Marios.
Speaker 0: You're going to see some levels.
Speaker 0: I'm going to make you play.
Speaker 0: I'll plan.
Speaker 0: I got ideas for some excellent, high quality Marios.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, we're going to be at PAX South doing at least one panel on Friday.
Speaker 1: We are going to be at MAGFest doing, between me and Scott, five panels at least.
Speaker 1: Hopefully not more, because that's a lot.
Speaker 1: PAX East will be there, probably, working on those arrangements.
Speaker 1: Stay tuned for all that.
Speaker 1: The Patreon's got a bunch of shit in there.
Speaker 1: Scott's got a bunch of stuff on his YouTube channel, though he hasn't uploaded his cooking show yet.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: YouTube channel's content is a lot of work.
Speaker 0: I got too busy doing other stuff.
Speaker 1: And also, I did pull the trigger.
Speaker 1: I ordered my new gaming PC with the exception of one part that is currently sold out.
Speaker 1: And I'm going to play a bunch of games that I haven't played as soon as I upgrade my PC.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll do it by two weeks from now, so we can talk about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I should be able to order.
Speaker 1: The last thing I needed is that M.2 SSD.
Speaker 0: It was on sale.
Speaker 0: Why'd you buy it when it was on sale?
Speaker 1: It's still on sale.
Speaker 1: When I went to buy the computer before, the 950 was sold out everywhere.
Speaker 1: Unless I wanted the shit-sized 256 gig one, which, no.
Speaker 1: So, then it came back, and it's like 318, 320.
Speaker 1: It's actually cheap.
Speaker 0: It's not cheap, but okay.
Speaker 1: Well, for what it is, for a 512 gigabyte, like, ridiculous SSD.
Speaker 0: Lightning drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like, the first comment when I was looking at it on Newegg was, "Is this storage or is this
Speaker 1: RAM?".
Speaker 0: Well, because it looks like RAM.
Speaker 0: People don't know what M.2 is.
Speaker 0: That's a good question.
Speaker 1: But the 960 came out, and I thought, you know, the 960 just came out.
Speaker 1: How different could they really be?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's gotta be a minor upgrade, right?
Speaker 1: It is actually a structural upgrade.
Speaker 1: It's like the equivalent of, like, going between Skylake and Kaby Lake.
Speaker 1: Like, it's a big deal, and it's cheaper.
Speaker 0: I thought Skylake and Kaby Lake was not gonna be a big difference.
Speaker 1: It is a big difference in some narrow areas, but it's not a big difference in other areas.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: There's actually one difference I heard of.
Speaker 0: I don't know if this is true.
Speaker 0: That, you know, Netflix is gonna add support for 4K videos.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, if you don't have a video card.
Speaker 0: But you need a Kaby Lake to do this, and not a Skylake.
Speaker 0: That's what I heard.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure the truth of that is you need a Kaby Lake and not a Skylake unless you have a real video card.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know how true that is.
Speaker 0: I didn't see enough details.
Speaker 0: That's important info because, like, if I'm buying a new PC, it's like, I just bought a new HDVC just now.
Speaker 1: I don't have any monitor that can display 4K.
Speaker 0: No, but I just bought a new HDVC, and if you tell me it can't do 4K Netflix, then I'm not gonna buy a 4K TV.
Speaker 0: But if it can, then maybe I'll buy one in a year or two.
Speaker 0: Because actually, like, in the past month, 4K support has been added to a lot of things.
Speaker 0: People are only adding the 4K support if you have, like, a certain device and not for you just have a PC.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: We'll see how that goes.
Speaker 0: I assume within a year or two, besides YouTube, which already has 4K support.
Speaker 1: In fact, many Geek Nights panels are uploaded in 4K because you really need to see my pores.
Speaker 0: I'll be able to, you know, there'll be 4Ks for everything, and then I can buy a 4K TV without wasting money.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But the 960 is actually significantly faster and more reliable and cheaper than the 950.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But it's sold out everywhere.
Speaker 1: And the other difference is...
Speaker 0: Just buy two just in case.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm not getting the motherboard that has two.
Speaker 1: That was a little bit excessive.
Speaker 1: If I'm gonna do that, actually, if I need, like, super fast storage, I could just buy a professional PCIe SSD.
Speaker 0: Well, the other thing you could do is get the motherboard that has two slots, buy the one crazy good 960 M2, and then the other slot...
Speaker 1: Put, like, the 950 EVO 2TB.
Speaker 0: No, there was that super cheap Intel M2.
Speaker 0: Oh, forget that!
Speaker 1: So, you know how there's the Pro?
Speaker 0: The thing is, it's not as good as the other ones, but it's still amazing and it's still so cheap.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, no.
Speaker 1: So, right now, Samsung is like the leader in this.
Speaker 0: Well, Samsung has been the king of solid-state storage forever.
Speaker 1: There are the Pro versions and the EVO versions, and the only reason you need Pro is if you, like, really care about reliability, because the Pros have a five-year warranty and are way, way more reliable.
Speaker 1: The EVOs, unless you're doing crazy bullshit 4K stuff like I do, the EVOs are effectively just as fast as the Pros.
Speaker 1: They cost half, and they're less reliable, they only have a three-year warranty, but you can get, like, a 1TB 960 EVO for, like, 500, 600 bucks next year.
Speaker 0: Oh, next year?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm like, "Whoa, I'll buy that right
Speaker 0: now!".
Speaker 1: No, they come out January 1st.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: Like, next year, like, literally next year.
Speaker 0: They already have release dates of these things?
Speaker 1: And also, right now, you can buy a 512GB 850, like, regular SATA 6 EVO for, like, 150 bucks.
Speaker 1: In fact, I saw one as cheap as 113, so SSDs are real cheap right now.
Speaker 1: And if you're not going crazy, they're, like, ridiculous cheap.
Speaker 1: But the Samsung ones are clearly superior.
Speaker 1: So, you guys know, we're a big fan of the original Jackbox party packs.
Speaker 0: Well, pretty much just Drawful.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Drawful is, like, the good one.
Speaker 1: Fibbage would be good, except it doesn't have enough content in it.
Speaker 0: Well, back in the day, right, is, like, when this sort of thing was, like, super rare, you know, the regular ol' -- I think we did an episode on Jackbox already.
Speaker 1: We did.
Speaker 1: I'll link to it.
Speaker 0: But, yeah, pretty much what we said in that episode, right, is, like, back in the day, those old Jackbox -- you know, it wasn't Jackbox, it was just -- You don't know Jack.
Speaker 0: You don't know Jack, and it was a fun party game, but you had to sit around a PC, and everyone had their finger on one letter on the keyboard, and you'd play it like that to buzz in, and it was just trivia, and, you know, it was okay and funny, and it was unique back in those CD-ROM days, but it doesn't hold up that well, even though it's still okay.
Speaker 0: The Jackbox, with their revolutionary usage of your phone to connect to the game that's on the screen, you know, is amazing, and that's what makes it so hot, and Jackbox 1 and 2, you know, had some good games and some not good games.
Speaker 1: 2 was not super worth it.
Speaker 1: Like, 1 was good.
Speaker 1: Like, 1 had Drawful.
Speaker 0: Well, they're not the cheapest, either, so, you know, right?
Speaker 0: But anyway, but the -- you know, Drawful is pretty much the king of games, and then the trivia ones are okay, but they sort of run out of trivia, and it's also not always the best trivias, and that's about it.
Speaker 0: So, now the Jackbox Party Pack 3.
Speaker 0: So, we're like, "Well, I've got to try that
Speaker 0: out.".
Speaker 0: So, we did.
Speaker 1: And the winner, like, the chicken dinner of this game is Quiplash.
Speaker 0: Uh, sort of.
Speaker 1: Well, so, TKO, I don't know how much, like, super -- like, I have a complicated feeling.
Speaker 1: We should just play all together.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about the bad one first.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So, trivia murder party -- This game is garbage.
Speaker 1: It's hot garbage.
Speaker 0: It is the worst.
Speaker 0: Like, I don't know.
Speaker 0: How did this even pass, like, the fun test that they -- Like, do they really enjoy playing this at the Jackbox office?
Speaker 1: So, 1, it's theme, because they're really doubling down, like, every game having, like, a really specific theme.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: But the theme for this one was really sort of, like, a thin veneer, and it was not very, like, well put into what the game was.
Speaker 1: And it was just a shitty trivia game, and the theme was, "You were being tortured and murdered by a serial
Speaker 1: killer.".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Which, I guess, you could go, like, Super Edgelord with it, but they don't.
Speaker 1: It's, like, lame-o dad jokes with a serial killer, like, twist to them.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So, everyone's a little voodoo doll kind of monster thing, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, which are moderately cute, almost.
Speaker 0: You get a trivia question, and I think it's multiple choice, if I remember correctly?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And if you get it wrong, then you're dead?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so everyone who gets it wrong has to play a minigame.
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: And if they don't, and if they get killed in the minigame, they're dead.
Speaker 0: Right, there's a minigame to basically, you know -- and if you win, if you get the trivia question right, you can just avoid the minigame entirely, and you wait while the other people play.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the game goes on.
Speaker 1: Now, the trivia is bad, and pretty much everything about it is bad, but the game goes on until there's only one player left alive.
Speaker 1: And then, much like WarioWare for the GameCube with the spaceships, then that player has to do this trivia challenge to get out before the ghosts of all the dead players catch up to them.
Speaker 1: So, basically, either they win, or they get overtaken, and one of the ghosts wins.
Speaker 0: I was a ghost, and I won.
Speaker 0: You did.
Speaker 1: I wasn't clear on how that part actually worked, playing it.
Speaker 0: The reason I won, even though I was a ghost, is because I got enough trivia questions right when I was alive so that I had a head start-ish in the final race, and then I just did better at the final race to make up for the margin between me and the people who were alive.
Speaker 1: Like, the end bit, like the chase, was almost clever enough to be interesting.
Speaker 0: It's also really slow.
Speaker 0: It's like you're waiting for shit to happen when you play this.
Speaker 1: Like, way more than the other games, and way less funny than even the latest.
Speaker 0: So, don't play Trivia Murder Party.
Speaker 1: Like, don't even play it.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Faking it is the second crappiest one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this game, I guess, had a good idea, a good concept, but a bad execution where it didn't actually work out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the idea is that everyone's playing the game earnestly, and one person is the faker.
Speaker 1: So, it'll be like, it'll show on everyone's phone except one person, "Raise your hand if you've masturbated in the last 48
Speaker 1: hours.".
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So, then it goes, "One, two, three, go," and one person doesn't even know, you know, what they should be doing.
Speaker 1: It just tells them, like, you're the faker.
Speaker 0: It tells them nothing.
Speaker 1: And then, suddenly, like, three of your friends raise their hands and two of them don't, and you have to decide how to fake it so they don't realize you're the faker.
Speaker 0: If you're not the faker, you're trying to figure out who is.
Speaker 0: It's like, did someone raise their hand just because they were trying to follow everyone else?
Speaker 0: Or is there somebody who just, they're either the faker because they didn't raise their hand and they don't know what the hell's going on?
Speaker 1: This is an excellent concept for a game that was implemented so badly.
Speaker 1: it's unplayable.
Speaker 0: Because you're trying to look at the screen and your own phone, but you're also trying to look at the other people in the room, and there's no way for that to physically work.
Speaker 1: I think that could work.
Speaker 0: The problem- That is one problem, though.
Speaker 1: Here's the real problem.
Speaker 1: It wasn't super clear how, like, the game didn't, like, the other games kind of go overboard telling you way too much info about how they work, or are designed to where.
Speaker 1: if you don't know how they work, it's fine.
Speaker 1: This one didn't tell you enough and required you to do the things that you didn't really understand.
Speaker 0: The other thing is I felt like, I couldn't tell what was going on necessarily, but it felt like even though the faker didn't know why they should be doing a thing, I feel like it still told them, "Alright, this is a hand-raising
Speaker 0: round.".
Speaker 1: It did.
Speaker 1: That was the problem.
Speaker 0: Like, it shouldn't tell them it's a hand-raising round or a clapping round or a jumping round or whatever.
Speaker 0: It should tell them absolutely nothing and all of the information should be private on your phone.
Speaker 0: So all the other players get a directive, like- This is a game that doesn't need the central screen at all.
Speaker 0: It should only use phones and then say, "One, two, three, everyone look up.
Speaker 0: One, two, three, everyone do the
Speaker 0: thing.".
Speaker 0: And then the faker doesn't even know what the thing is.
Speaker 0: That's how it should go down.
Speaker 1: Imagine if it was suddenly, like, it just says, "Everyone wearing glasses, take them off right
Speaker 1: now.".
Speaker 0: Like, that would be an amazing game, but this game is- This could be done as a board game with cards that you hand out and people look at in some way.
Speaker 1: You know, it's funny you say that because the next day after we played it, I was kind of sketching out, like, how I would redesign this game and I realized the same thing.
Speaker 0: This game could be- Whereas trivia murder party is just bad trivia, faking it is a good concept that doesn't work so you don't need to actually play it.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: So, so far we're 0 for 2.
Speaker 1: Gaspionage is actually pretty fun, but I feel like it has the same problem that Fibbage does in that it'll run out of content.
Speaker 0: Right, so there's definitely limited content, but this is fun to play a few times and the way it works is they're like, "Okay, what percentage of people have, you know, something, right?
Speaker 0: I don't know, have never seen the ocean, right?
Speaker 0: I just made that
Speaker 0: up.".
Speaker 0: And then one person who's, like, whose turn it is will guess- Publicly.
Speaker 0: Publicly on this pie chart what percentage of people they think have never seen the ocean according to Family Feud survey says, right?
Speaker 0: They'll be like, "Okay, 25% of people on Earth have never seen the
Speaker 0: ocean.".
Speaker 0: Then everyone else says whether that's too high, too low- Way too high.
Speaker 0: Way too high or way too low and whoever's right gets points.
Speaker 0: and if you basically saying way high or way low is doubling down, so if you're wrong when you go way high or way low, you lose stuff, but if you're right when you go way high or way low, you get stuff, so sort of like double or lose, you know, it's bad news or good or great news.
Speaker 0: And then that's pretty much what the game is about, that one thing.
Speaker 1: Yep, but it actually, like, it works pretty well.
Speaker 1: It's moderately fun.
Speaker 0: It's interesting, you know, questions because it's not just, like, a trivia, like, "Do you know this or
Speaker 0: not?".
Speaker 0: It's, like, it's a percentage, so it's a lot like that Wits and Wagers board game, right, where you're sort of betting, like, the trivia question will be a number as the answer and you'll be betting on whether you, you know, what range you think the number is in.
Speaker 0: It's a lot like that.
Speaker 0: It's also got a pretty good theme, like, I like how a lot of these- I feel like Wits and Wagers would be a good game to have just in-jackbox technology, period, yeah.
Speaker 1: So, Quiplash is probably going to be the drawful of this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Quiplash is- there is a- the final game is actually a drawing game.
Speaker 0: Quiplash isn't a drawing game, but it's the best game in the pack.
Speaker 1: Because the final game is great, but that's a very qualified great.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So, Quiplash basically has you- everyone has to answer, like, two little things.
Speaker 1: Like, it'll give you a prompt, like, "A bumper sticker a nudist would
Speaker 1: have.".
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And you come up with something funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so mine was, like, the name of a high-end cat salon, and I wrote, "Per
Speaker 0: Snips.".
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And I got- so that was a great answer.
Speaker 1: Mine- the one that got the most laughs for me was, "I missed my own wedding because,".
Speaker 1: and I wrote, "I was at
Speaker 1: PAX.".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you basically, you know, there's these prompts, you answer them, and then- Right, so even though there's eight people, everyone gets two prompts each, right?
Speaker 0: But there's still only a total of eight prompts because each prompt was given to two different players, at least, right?
Speaker 0: So that way it shows your prompt versus the other person who got the same prompt, and then people vote on whose is better.
Speaker 0: And if you want to get more votes because you- you made the- you basically gave a better, funnier response to the prompt than they did.
Speaker 1: Now, I say it's the drawful because it's the quick jump in and play game.
Speaker 0: And it's not trivia, it's a creative- you know, it's what drawful is, it's a creative competition kind of thing, right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It does not rely on anything other than those questions, those prompts, so you're not going to run out of trivia.
Speaker 1: Like, Fibbage, I've seen the same questions so many times that I pretty much always win if I play Fibbage with strangers.
Speaker 0: The only problem with Quiplash that I had, though other people didn't have it as much as I did, was time.
Speaker 0: I did not have enough time- I felt like- You gotta move quick!
Speaker 0: If I had another minute, I could have come up with, like, two incredible prompt answers.
Speaker 0: But, like, persnips took me all my entire time to think up.
Speaker 0: It was really good.
Speaker 0: And then I had, like, five seconds and I had to push the automatic "put an answer in for me" button because I ran- I was gonna just put in nothing otherwise.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And I didn't like that.
Speaker 0: I wanted to have, like, a lot of time to think about it and come up with something.
Speaker 0: so spice for both prompts.
Speaker 0: I feel like it could also do better by just having everyone do one prompt and then after four rounds, do another prompt.
Speaker 0: Oh, so then you can react to- Right, because you're given one allotment of time to do both prompts.
Speaker 1: That's good, though.
Speaker 1: You gotta think on your feet.
Speaker 0: I wanted to have enough time to do each one separately.
Speaker 1: It's also got the cutest sort of style and theme, like the little avatars are just good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, the visual design of this one is more fun.
Speaker 0: It's just cute little eyeball shapes.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So it's the one that's gonna get the most play, like, at conventions.
Speaker 1: Like, if you look at- 'cause PAXes tend to have Jackbox games, like, out in the open everywhere.
Speaker 1: It's usually Quiplash these days.
Speaker 0: The other thing is, I gotta say, good or bad, all the games in this pack mostly support a ton of players.
Speaker 0: In the other PAX, there were some games that only supported, like, four players.
Speaker 0: I think most of the ones in this pack support eight.
Speaker 1: Only faking it goes up to six.
Speaker 0: I guess that'd be hard to play with too many people.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I think, actually, it'd be better with more people.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But you'd need more rounds to narrow it down.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should just design the board game version.
Speaker 1: That's way easier- that kind of game?
Speaker 1: Way easier to design than the stuff you're working on right now.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: So, the final game.
Speaker 0: And this game is sort of, like, the best game, but not the best game?
Speaker 1: It's the craziest game.
Speaker 1: Like, it's an experience.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it's sort of, like, a high investment thing, 'cause it takes a while and takes a lot of effort.
Speaker 0: But the payoff was, like- like, so the game basically- But we couldn't do it again, 'cause it was such an involved game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like, we didn't know- we didn't even know what was going on.
Speaker 0: It's like you can't play "Axis and Allies" twice, 'cause even if it's so great, 'cause it's such a big deal.
Speaker 0: Not that "Axis and Allies" is great, but just, you know.
Speaker 1: So all the other games kind of, like, really tell you- well, except for faking it, which sucks, like, really tell you- They explain the game before you play.
Speaker 0: This game, you turn it on, and it just has you start playing before you even know what you're supposed to be doing.
Speaker 0: It's like- it says, "Draw something.
Speaker 1: Draw as many things as you can.
Speaker 1: They can be
Speaker 1: anything.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like,
Speaker 0: "Whoa!"
Speaker 0: And even worse- It gives you more drawing tools than the Drawful does.
Speaker 0: You actually- Colors, erasers- Colors, erasing different tools.
Speaker 0: It's like a real paint tool, and it makes you draw a bunch of stuff, and you're like, "Oh,
Speaker 0: fuck.".
Speaker 1: And the art and the style and the theme is, like, crazy.
Speaker 1: It's basically like a- like a Japanese fighting game crossed with a Jap- like a- like a Battle Balls puzzle kind of game.
Speaker 0: Well, it has, um, you know, what are the names of the Japanese spirit monsters?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you can be, like, a Tengu or, yeah, all these- The Umbrella Guy.
Speaker 0: What the hell are the names of those?
Speaker 0: I don't remember all of them.
Speaker 1: I get to see the list of all of them.
Speaker 1: I don't have it up.
Speaker 0: You know, the things that Kitaro deals with.
Speaker 1: Oh, monsters?
Speaker 0: No, there's a name for it.
Speaker 0: That's a Japanese word that I know, but I just can't remember right now.
Speaker 1: Akemono?
Speaker 0: No, that's just the generic word for monster.
Speaker 0: There's a specific word for these coded monsters.
Speaker 0: Yes, that's- you basically- all your characters are yokais, and the styling is very, like, woodblock kaiju kind of styling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but also, like, versus puzzle game and versus fighting game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a crazy awesome style.
Speaker 0: Whoever did the art on this game is the best art of all the games.
Speaker 0: You did a great job.
Speaker 1: But, like, we didn't know what was going on, and the game was just like, "Fuckin' do this now.
Speaker 1: Write as many slogans as you can in a hurry.
Speaker 1: Go, go, go.
Speaker 1: Puff, puff, puff.
Speaker 1: Here's the interlude.
Speaker 1: Blah,
Speaker 1: blah.".
Speaker 0: And then at the end, it kind of all comes together, and basically- It's like it didn't need to tell you what the game was until it got there, which is a great design, actually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I'm actually legit impressed.
Speaker 1: So
Speaker 0: it makes you draw a bunch of pictures for whatever, then it makes you write a bunch of slogans that could go on a t-shirt, okay, and then each player on their screen gets a choice of, like, a few of the pictures that have been drawn by other people, and a few of the slogans that have been written by other people, and you choose a combination of one picture and one slogan to make the best t-shirt you can make amongst all the just raw materials that were just generated, right?
Speaker 0: You combine and make one t-shirt from all the things your friends just made, and then you vote.
Speaker 0: It puts two t-shirts together, and there's a tournament of t-shirts as to which one is the champion, and it's pretty much just like, "All right, t-shirt one, t-shirt two, go,".
Speaker 0: and then it's not a bracketed tournament.
Speaker 0: It's an all-kill tournament, where if you win, you fight the next, you know, challenger, and the first challenger is dead, right?
Speaker 0: And then whoever wins that keeps going.
Speaker 0: Whoever wins that keeps going.
Speaker 1: Now, the actual end result playing this game was kind of off the hook.
Speaker 1: Like, it was legit hilarious.
Speaker 0: Right, and somehow we've just made a bunch of random shit and wrote random slogans, and it made epic t-shirts of epicness.
Speaker 1: I mean, like, one of my favorite ones was just this, like, giant lightning bolt in the sky, like, just fucking killing the stick figure, dude.
Speaker 1: And on the bottom, it's just, "I'm sorry for your loss," and something about that just really clicked with me.
Speaker 0: It was just so good.
Speaker 0: Everything about this is so good.
Speaker 1: So, basically, there are two good games in here.
Speaker 1: One of them is, like, this deep experience.
Speaker 0: Also, because it's on Steam, you can take screenshots, which we did.
Speaker 1: I took a lot of screenshots.
Speaker 1: I'll post them in the thread.
Speaker 0: Make sure you have, when you play the t-shirt one, your keyboard handy to push.
Speaker 0: I forget if it's F11 or F12.
Speaker 1: Because otherwise they're gone forever.
Speaker 0: The Steam screenshot button.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've seen things you people wouldn't believe playing this game.
Speaker 1: So, the only other really unique thing, I mean, if you need a party game, like, this is the kind of game not everyone in your friend group needs to buy, one of you needs to own it.
Speaker 0: Right, I would recommend buying this if, A, you already have the other party pack with Drawful in it.
Speaker 0: B, you already play Drawful a bunch, but you're looking for something fresh, and you play this kind of thing often.
Speaker 0: You have a lot of people over often.
Speaker 0: C, it's on sale.
Speaker 0: It's a bit expensive.
Speaker 0: considering some of the games are just so bad you're never going to play them.
Speaker 0: Like, you're paying for trivia murder party whether you play it or not, so wait for a sale.
Speaker 0: Because the regular retail price, I think it's like $25 or $35.
Speaker 0: It's a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean, I'm paying for SATA Express on my new computer.
Speaker 1: It's not like I'm going to use that nonsense.
Speaker 0: Right, but, you know, I'm just saying, don't spend full price unless this is your number one deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like, if you're the kind of person who runs- If it's on sale, and you already play Drawful a bunch, and you want to play something different a bunch, definitely get Jackbox Party Pack 3 because there's still nothing else out there like it.
Speaker 0: And TKO, and, uh, Quiplash 2, actually, are going to be totally worth it.
Speaker 0: And Gaspionage, you can play once in a while, you know, just to mix things up.
Speaker 0: Ignore the other games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't- you might think, "How bad could the trivia murder party
Speaker 1: be?".
Speaker 1: It is not great.
Speaker 0: But listen, two and a half amazing games for that kind of price, if you play it enough, that's good.
Speaker 1: So, the- I mean, like, if you run- here's a perfect use case for these games.
Speaker 1: If you host parties in hotel rooms at conventions, you put this on in the corner.
Speaker 0: If you are a convention or a club, like, imagine if, like, at the Anime Club back in the day- It would have just been in the club space.
Speaker 1: It would have been more popular than the anime.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying.
Speaker 1: So, this pack also does something interesting in that it is directly designed to be used as live streams on the internet.
Speaker 1: You can have up to 10,000 spectators who can sort of interact with the game, like, vote on good responses and kind of mess around.
Speaker 0: Oh, we should try to do that.
Speaker 0: We should.
Speaker 1: We should live stream playing this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically we can invite, like, some other- because if we're showing the screen, we don't need to be in the same room.
Speaker 0: Can we do it to YouTube or Twitch only?
Speaker 0: Uh, we all- Since it's integrated, right, we might not be able to make it go to YouTube?
Speaker 1: Uh, I think we can make it go to YouTube.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: But otherwise, we'll set up a Twitch.
Speaker 0: Other people, like you listeners, will watch on Twitch.
Speaker 1: I'll tweet, like, the code.
Speaker 0: We'll have eight people at our New Year's party.
Speaker 0: We'll all be playing.
Speaker 0: I'll set the party we'll be playing.
Speaker 0: But all you at home who are sad on New Year's and lonely with nothing better to do than go on Twitch will watch.
Speaker 1: Yup, we can even point a webcam into, like, a fancy stream.
Speaker 0: And you will vicariously enjoy how funny we are and how good at TKO we are, or bad.
Speaker 0: Uh, and that'll be that.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons that order the minor winner of the game with us on a continuing basis are... And Chris Hahn, Rymer, and Thomas And... Literally right after I read all those names, some packages arrived and I got the phone call and I went down and brought them up here.
Speaker 1: The case and the Kraken for my new computer arrived.
Speaker 1: Don't worry, this is my money, not Patreon money.
Speaker 1: All the money that you patrons have donated to Geek Nights are still in a holding queue.
Speaker 1: You will know when we do awesome things with it.
Speaker 1: We're not just, like, putting it into our income.
Speaker 1: It'll be used for specific things that will enhance the Geek Nights experience for all of you out there when the time is right.
Speaker 1: And as Wesley Snipes said, "When it's time, you'll
Speaker 1: know.".
Speaker 1: But you might have noticed I haven't been doing a lot of YouTube videos lately.
Speaker 1: That's partly because I'm waiting for the new computer and then I'm going to explode onto the YouTube scene in ways that you have never seen before.
Speaker 1: But anyway, at this time, in this place, I leave you with...
Speaker 0: Every single day, stress comes in every way.
Speaker 0: I ain't got no time for nobody.
Speaker 1: My style is rich, dope, fat, and rich.
Speaker 1: We'll make a cake today that looks rich.
Speaker 1: Crack, crack, crack the egg into the bowl.
Speaker 1: M-I-X the flour into the bowl.
Speaker 0: Crack, crack, crack the egg into the bowl.
Speaker 0: Baking a cake, yes, means you gotta try.
Speaker 0: I'm doing this for years, but don't ask me why.
Speaker 1: Butter, butter, butter joins the bowl.
Speaker 1: We're making us a cake that you've never... Hi-ya!
Speaker 1: Ta-ta!
Speaker 0: Kick, punch, it's all in the mind.
Speaker 1: If you wanna test me, I'm sure you're finding the things I'll teach ya.
Speaker 1: It's sure to beat ya.
Speaker 1: Nevertheless, you get a lesson from teacher.
Speaker 1: Now kick!
Speaker 0: Kick, kick, kick, punch!
Speaker 1: Punch, punch, punch, punch, punch!
Speaker 1: Jump!
Speaker 1: Chop, chop, chop, chop, chop!
Speaker 1: Block!
Speaker 1: One more now!
Speaker 1: Kick!
Speaker 1: Kick, kick, kick, kick, kick!
Speaker 1: Punch!
Speaker 1: What, what, what, what?
Speaker 1: Jump!
Speaker 1: Chop, chop, chop, chop!
Speaker 1: And block!
Speaker 1: Block, block, block, block!
Speaker 1: Don't get hooky, it's gonna get rocky.
Speaker 1: We gonna move down to the next joke, you know, talk!
Speaker 1: Talk, talk, talk, talk!
Speaker 1: Jump!
Speaker 1: Talk, talk, talk, talk, talk!
Speaker 1: Holes!
Speaker 1: You sound carefully, jump!
Speaker 1: Talk, talk, talk, talk!
Speaker 1: Holes!
Speaker 1: Talk!
Speaker 1: Talk, talk, talk, talk!
Speaker 1: And turn!
Speaker 1: Turn, turn, turn!
Speaker 1: Hm, yeah, I see you're getting better.
Speaker 1: Kick to the limit in order to get an out.
Speaker 1: kick!
Speaker 1: Punch!
Speaker 0: Kick, punch, kick, kick, kick, punch!
Speaker 0: Chop!
Speaker 0: Chop, chop, chop, chop, chop!
Speaker 0: Block!
Speaker 0: Chop!
Speaker 0: Kick!
Speaker 0: Chop, chop, kick, chop, chop, chop!
Speaker 0: Punch!
Speaker 0: Block!
Speaker 0: Gonna get hard enough!
Speaker 0: Duck and jump!
Speaker 0: Duck!
Speaker 0: And boils!