Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, December 14th, 2016.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: And I'm Emily.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights tonight.
Speaker 0: Because Scott's a little baby who won't watch movies that came out within the last 40 or 50 years.
Speaker 0: Emily and I saw Moana and we're reviewing that.
Speaker 0: So for any of you who back us on the Patreon, this is Emily and I semi-regularly review all the stuff we watch and do that Scott just won't consume.
Speaker 0: Like he hasn't seen Zootopia, he hasn't even seen Mad Max actually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I feel like when you recommend stuff, we're like, "Scott, you need to see this movie.
Speaker 1: We saw it without you.
Speaker 1: You should go see
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: He's like, "No.
Speaker 1: No, I don't want
Speaker 1: to.".
Speaker 0: Watch my hurry.
Speaker 1: But it's definitely movie season in our group of friends.
Speaker 1: And part of the reason we've been seeing a lot of movies lately is Judith and Natalie were like, "Eh, let's go see Dr.
Speaker 1: Strange.
Speaker 1: Let's go see
Speaker 1: Moana.".
Speaker 0: Well, she needed to see the movie so she wouldn't feel conflicted about selling fan art about the movie.
Speaker 1: It's research, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, "Let's do
Speaker 1: research.".
Speaker 0: So normally these are just on the Patreon for the Geek Nights Patreon patrons right up there with Rims Rants where I talk about stuff like how I cut my finger open in the dumbest possible way the other day.
Speaker 1: Oh no, did you do a Rims Rant about entering your finger?
Speaker 0: Of course I did.
Speaker 0: There are 17 Rims Rants and like 7 or 8 Rimmly reviews and this one is public.
Speaker 0: But the one we're going to record pretty soon on Dr.
Speaker 0: Strange will be back on the Patreon.
Speaker 0: So if you support Geek Nights on Patreon for even $1, you get all that, not just Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: You're really selling it here.
Speaker 0: Hey, I got a few more pledges recently.
Speaker 1: One of the things that's interesting, I used to be kind of like peeved when I do shows with just you and I because you'd never want to do Thing of the Day and you'd never want to do news.
Speaker 0: You want to do the whole format?
Speaker 0: You got to start with the opening event.
Speaker 0: Then you need to have two main newses and one small news.
Speaker 1: See, I always have a backlog of Things of the Day.
Speaker 1: I mean, they're not usually things I found that day because I don't really browse the internet a lot at work.
Speaker 1: I'm busy animating.
Speaker 1: But like I have all this backlog of shorts.
Speaker 1: I've got like this YouTube playlist that I can pull from.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it's kind of grown on me that since you and I have a different style when we do the show together, it's like instead of following the Rim and Scott format exactly, the Rim and Emily formats a little bit more loose.
Speaker 1: We don't necessarily have to be like, "What happened
Speaker 1: today?".
Speaker 0: I cut my finger open.
Speaker 1: The other good thing about that is that we can take those reviews and put them anytime we want.
Speaker 1: So like if we go on vacation, we can queue up a bunch of episodes and they're not specifically topical.
Speaker 0: My hot take is Moana was super good and you should go see it.
Speaker 1: What's that hot take?
Speaker 0: It's the second best Disney movie in modern history.
Speaker 1: That's like, that's not negative at all.
Speaker 0: Hot take doesn't have to necessarily be negative.
Speaker 1: It just means it's hot.
Speaker 0: Hot off the press.
Speaker 0: Usually, ironically, like hot take.
Speaker 0: Twitter has some issues.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I usually hear it used in the context of saying something vaguely snarky about a piece of media.
Speaker 0: So when I was pulling up the stuff for this, the IMDb has a pretty good rating for Moana so far.
Speaker 0: But the first and featured review is someone who gave it 5 out of 10. and they're like, "The beginning reminded me of Pocahontas, but Pocahontas was a rich tapestry that drew me into this amazing
Speaker 0: world.".
Speaker 0: And Moana was just like a dumb, boring rehash of that.
Speaker 1: Are you serious?
Speaker 1: It had nothing.
Speaker 1: You know, like Avatar was like Pocahontas, right?
Speaker 1: This was not like Pocahontas at all.
Speaker 0: They go on to complain that Moana is bad because it's diverse and Disney's trying to be diverse instead of "telling good
Speaker 0: stories.".
Speaker 1: Oh, wow.
Speaker 0: That is the top review on IMDb right now.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is, I mean, with a movie like this, which takes very heavily from a specific culture's mythology and aesthetic and everything, I think there's definitely going to be a lot of criticism revolving around that.
Speaker 1: Specifically, I've read a few reviews by scholars of Polynesian studies about what the movie got right, what the movie was kind of eh about, what made them mad, what made them happy.
Speaker 0: It seems like the consensus was more positive than negative.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually, on the internet, I've seen some people of Polynesian descent be like, "Oh my god, it was fucking awesome to see my heritage
Speaker 1: represented.".
Speaker 1: And the whole big theme behind the movie is about Polynesian migration.
Speaker 0: And the great pause.
Speaker 1: The great pause.
Speaker 1: Polynesian culture spread throughout the Pacific for like a thousand years and then it stopped.
Speaker 0: I remember with navigation techniques and shipwright techniques that basically were not known to the rest of the world for countless, not millennia, but countless centuries.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like expert sailing culture who had incredible knowledge of the stars and of wayfinding techniques and stuff like that, and built canoes that were fast and very light and versatile.
Speaker 1: And they were able to go throughout the entire ocean pretty much, like from New Zealand to Hawaii to just all these different islands.
Speaker 1: And then evidence of that kind of disappeared for a while and then it started up again.
Speaker 1: And to this day, there's a lot of theories, but nobody really knows why that happened.
Speaker 1: Well, I saw the movie.
Speaker 0: I know exactly what happened.
Speaker 1: Because there was a girl and she had to break the magic spell that was causing the fish to die, so she found a demigod.
Speaker 1: But that, just in general, it definitely was kind of like Kubo.
Speaker 1: in that I feel like even if the movie wasn't necessarily perfect on the front of cultural representation, Disney at least did its due diligence, and so it doesn't smack of appropriation quite as much as some of their earlier efforts.
Speaker 1: Because Disney is like, you know, you want to talk about taking a culture and then dressing it up in like, "Okay, now we're going to make a musical with this culture as the
Speaker 1: setting.".
Speaker 1: And it's not always the most authentic or respectful, perhaps.
Speaker 1: I'm looking at you, Aladdin.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Aladdin.
Speaker 0: Snarky teen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean, Moana definitely, it felt like they were trying to put their effort in to represent Polynesian culture well.
Speaker 1: And at least in the island scenes, I really enjoyed all the different characters in the village and stuff.
Speaker 1: I like the guy who was just like, "Are you sure we can't eat that
Speaker 1: chicken?".
Speaker 0: On that front, you brought up the chicken.
Speaker 0: I really appreciate the fact that that chicken does not talk.
Speaker 0: There are no talking animals in this movie at all.
Speaker 0: And the posters all show the chicken and the pig like, "Okay, there's going to be animal sidekicks like there always
Speaker 0: are.".
Speaker 0: The pig doesn't follow her into the ocean, and the chicken never says a word.
Speaker 0: The animal sidekicks... Maybe other chickens can talk, but that one can't.
Speaker 1: They're more like... Actually, Pocahontas was the same way.
Speaker 1: You know, now that brought up Pocahontas and it's in my mind.
Speaker 0: So, I'll admit something.
Speaker 0: Despite having played the song from it on the Blue Horn a million times, I've never actually seen Pocahontas all the way through.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: I saw The Colors of the Wind, I saw the songs, and I just felt like that movie was not for me.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a bastardization of history, and it's basically Romeo and Juliet.
Speaker 1: Like, hot Indian lady, and John Smith is like this romance novel-looking dude.
Speaker 1: And they had this...
Speaker 0: You mean that she didn't actually marry because she married that other John?
Speaker 1: She was like 12 years old.
Speaker 0: John Rolfe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I mean, actually, I think they made a sequel where she meets John Rolfe or something.
Speaker 1: But I don't think she dies so smallpox in that one.
Speaker 1: Like...
Speaker 0: If they did, it was made for TV.
Speaker 1: I just remember my teacher... I took a class, it was like comparative director series, where they compared... The teacher was a huge Miyazaki scholar.
Speaker 1: He loved the works of Hayao Miyazaki.
Speaker 1: And he also really liked Disney.
Speaker 1: So he did this animation history class comparing the two directors' styles.
Speaker 1: And he was a great teacher.
Speaker 1: I loved him.
Speaker 1: But he was also of First Nations descent, and so he had some pretty choice words to say about the representation in Pocahontas.
Speaker 1: I remember, I didn't watch the movie in his class because I wanted to go to a concert or something.
Speaker 1: And I said, "Can I skip the screening?
Speaker 1: Is that
Speaker 1: okay?".
Speaker 1: And he was like, "Most of the time I'd encourage you to go to the screening, but yeah, this one's a
Speaker 1: mess.".
Speaker 1: I was like,
Speaker 1: "Okay.".
Speaker 0: So since it's still in theaters, honestly, my short review is go see it in the theater in 3D.
Speaker 0: It is designed, much like Mad Max, it is designed for 3D.
Speaker 0: They put a lot of care into making the movie work very well in 3D.
Speaker 1: Just really saturated colors, the environments are just phenomenal.
Speaker 1: There were many scenes in the movie where it was very simple and beautiful.
Speaker 1: You know, like the scene with the stars.
Speaker 1: Most of the movie takes place on a boat.
Speaker 0: Spoilers.
Speaker 1: Well, it's a movie about wayfinding.
Speaker 1: It's about exploring and learning to sail.
Speaker 1: And it's also about finding yourself and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: I'd say meeting your heroes, but it wasn't really her hero.
Speaker 0: And that was kind of a plot point.
Speaker 1: So the whole plot is, she lives on this island and her dad is chief of the village.
Speaker 1: And he's like, she really wants to go in the water.
Speaker 1: Ever since she was a little kid, she's been obsessed with the ocean and always going to the ocean.
Speaker 1: And her dad's like, no, no, come back from the ocean.
Speaker 1: Don't go to the ocean.
Speaker 1: She's like, but the ocean.
Speaker 1: And so he's like, stay on land.
Speaker 1: You've got responsibilities here.
Speaker 1: You know, be responsible, dad, kind of person.
Speaker 1: And so it ends up she has to go save her village because the island's dying and they think it's a curse.
Speaker 1: And the only way to fix the curse is to return the heart.
Speaker 0: But interestingly, no one thinks that except the grandmother who's old enough to remember what's in that cave and all that biz.
Speaker 1: I love the grandmother.
Speaker 1: She was one of my favorite parts of that movie.
Speaker 1: She was also very ocean-y and kind of mystical, but she was funny about it.
Speaker 1: She's like, I'm just the village crazy lady.
Speaker 0: The characters that had speaking lines or that had any sort of prominent part of the movie were just really good characters?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They had complex motivations insofar as they needed them for whatever they were doing in the movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the dad caused conflict.
Speaker 1: Their wills were often at odds, but he was portrayed as this loving, caring father, even though he was like, nope, don't go sailing kind of thing.
Speaker 1: And I loved her relationship with her.
Speaker 1: I mean, with her mom, there was a few good scenes with that, but mostly with her grandmother.
Speaker 1: That relationship was just really sweet and well done.
Speaker 1: So anyway, she has a legend that she's got to go save the island and she braves the ocean to go find Maui, who's like this legendary demigod.
Speaker 1: And yeah, he's not quite what she expected, I think.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's not quite a dick, but he's- He's a trickster for sure.
Speaker 0: There's a little bit of Gaston in there, but then- No, not Gaston.
Speaker 0: He's more like- He's full of himself.
Speaker 1: He's kind of like the genie a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: He's like very egotistical, but he's a little bit like the genie where he has modeling moments, but he's not quite as pop culture- The genie's only modeling because that's a post-apocalyptic society and they've rebuilt- Oh, come on.
Speaker 1: That's silly.
Speaker 1: I don't buy that.
Speaker 1: Look at the evidence.
Speaker 1: Nonsense.
Speaker 1: You could make cases for just about anything.
Speaker 1: Be like- Pokemon ashes in a coma the whole time or whatever.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's canon.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: Nonsense.
Speaker 1: Nonsense, I tell you.
Speaker 1: But Moana, one criticism I did see was that the character of Maui is based on a mythological figure from Polynesian culture.
Speaker 1: And they were like, "Why did they make him so
Speaker 1: doofy?".
Speaker 1: But they also made him kind of badass.
Speaker 1: So he's a combination of doofy and really badass.
Speaker 0: Well, the movie has no- It ties up all of its ends really well.
Speaker 0: Maui is the way he is, but even that ends up being a big part of his character arc and the plot toward the end.
Speaker 0: Not to spoil anything, everything like that in the movie, except possibly the chicken, wraps up in a very heartfelt and meaningful way.
Speaker 1: The chicken wraps up just the way the chicken should wrap up.
Speaker 1: The chicken survives through the whole thing and ends up pecking at rocks just back where he started.
Speaker 0: Okay, the Aladdin thing is checking out more and more.
Speaker 1: Oh, bologna.
Speaker 1: Anyway- This is looking pretty solid.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: I'm going to have to look at this later.
Speaker 1: He's looking at this fan theory that Aladdin was set in this post-apocalypse.
Speaker 0: Look, it's like Adventure Time.
Speaker 0: Look at that.
Speaker 1: But that's the video game.
Speaker 1: What the heck?
Speaker 0: Yeah, video game is canon.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: Anyway, concentrate.
Speaker 1: We're talking about Ocean Voyages here.
Speaker 0: But the movie's just really good and kind of drew me in in a way that I guess recent Disney movies have, but there was a long drought of Disney movies that were not bringing me into them to that level.
Speaker 0: They didn't have these sort of beautiful, expansive, immersive worlds to fill out.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I feel like- Inside Out was pretty superficial.
Speaker 1: That was a Pixar.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: That's the thing that's interesting is I feel like for about a decade, it was like Disney's going down the tubes and Pixar's star is rising.
Speaker 1: But I tell you, I think in the past maybe five years or so, I've found Disney movies to be generally more compelling than the Pixar counterparts.
Speaker 1: Frozen had some issues.
Speaker 1: I enjoyed it anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Frozen was okay.
Speaker 1: No pros and cons.
Speaker 1: Come on.
Speaker 1: It was like Norwegian.
Speaker 1: But, oh, that's one thing I must say for Moana.
Speaker 1: that disappointed me in Frozen.
Speaker 1: that Moana did really well is incorporated traditional music of the setting into the score.
Speaker 0: Frozen was like, "Hey, check out this traditional music.
Speaker 1: That's never coming
Speaker 1: back.".
Speaker 1: And I was like, "Oh, Norwegian Joiking.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's
Speaker 0: semi-people.".
Speaker 0: Nope, the Joiking's gone.
Speaker 0: It's only in the soundtrack.
Speaker 1: No, it's just musical music.
Speaker 1: And this one had a good combination.
Speaker 1: It was like Disney musical music by the guy who did Hamilton, Lin-Manuel Miranda, I guess.
Speaker 0: And if you stay for the credits, one of the songs, one of the good songs in the movie.
Speaker 0: The movie has excellent, excellent music.
Speaker 0: He sings the song over the credits.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it was funny because I feel like the soundtrack, it wasn't like.
Speaker 1: I watched it.
Speaker 1: I was like, "Wow, that had the best score of any Disney movie
Speaker 1: ever.".
Speaker 0: But it got stuck in my head.
Speaker 1: It got stuck in my head hardcore.
Speaker 1: I listened to the soundtrack at work the day after on Spotify.
Speaker 1: And then I was going around humming Maui's song.
Speaker 1: I was humming the song that the crab sings.
Speaker 0: Oh, we'll get to the crab.
Speaker 0: The crab is...
Speaker 1: So this crab monster appears.
Speaker 1: He was your favorite because you love that, what's his name?
Speaker 1: Clements, Jermaine Clements or something.
Speaker 1: Goodbye Moon Man.
Speaker 1: And that's a song that always gets stuck in your head.
Speaker 0: The crab starts singing and immediately all I can think of is it's the Moon Man guy.
Speaker 1: It's the guy from Rick and Morty.
Speaker 1: He played fart in Rick and Morty.
Speaker 1: And he does this voice of this giant crab monster who impersonates.
Speaker 1: He does this kind of David Bowie inspired glam rock number.
Speaker 1: And I was just like, "That sounds really
Speaker 1: familiar.".
Speaker 1: And rim leans over and he's like, "It's the guy from Moon
Speaker 1: Man.".
Speaker 1: I was like, "Oh yeah, I totally see
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 0: As opposed to say Zootopia where there's one song that was memorable and that gets stuck in our heads.
Speaker 1: Zootopia wasn't really a musical.
Speaker 1: It had a very different format.
Speaker 1: This felt more like...
Speaker 0: Zootopia had the same problem that those Marvel movies did where it had a soundtrack that just sort of served its purpose and then one iconic song.
Speaker 1: No, I would say Zootopia is a little bit more unique than the standard action movie.
Speaker 0: I can't place a single melody of any sort from that movie.
Speaker 0: That's super generic.
Speaker 0: That could fit like a hundred movies.
Speaker 0: I got nothing.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, I've been singing three different songs from Moana under my breath constantly since we saw it.
Speaker 1: Yes, Moana's songs really, really stick.
Speaker 1: And also they incorporated like about half the songs incorporated Polynesian vocals in them.
Speaker 1: And I really like that.
Speaker 1: I think it was mostly like Samoan culture.
Speaker 1: But I know they had a lot of New Zealand voice actors like Maori people and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: And I thought that was pretty neat.
Speaker 1: But anyway, music was good.
Speaker 1: But I think the thing, one of my favorite, favorite things about the movie, and this is going to sound really superficial and animatory of me.
Speaker 0: Now the water.
Speaker 1: Oh my God, the shaders in this movie, like the nature stuff was really, really well done.
Speaker 1: Just like it was so colorful and beautiful.
Speaker 1: And it wasn't that it was realistic because that wasn't what made it cool.
Speaker 1: It was that they took the good things of realism and the good things of like artistic expression and like exaggeration and brought them together.
Speaker 1: And it was really, really beautiful.
Speaker 0: I found all these articles where they said that they did a lot of study of their old 2D animation while simultaneously investing, kind of like how they invested in that.
Speaker 0: What was the thing that made the Zootopia characters sort of just...
Speaker 1: It was like motion noise where everything was like, it's kind of like moving holds, where if you have a freeze frame in an animation where the character is not really moving, if you just freeze it, it looks kind of stiff, especially if it's in 3D.
Speaker 1: Like if the character is moving and then they stop moving and then they move again, it really breaks the illusion.
Speaker 1: So they have this kind of, to add visual motion noise to a character's movement.
Speaker 1: It's just like a character will be standing and their fur will be blowing and the trees will be blowing.
Speaker 1: It's like wind and stuff.
Speaker 0: Apparently that was a crazy system they developed.
Speaker 0: And now they extended that with a liquid water and particle system for Moana.
Speaker 1: It's nice to see all their tool development, right?
Speaker 1: Because Zootopia was all about the fur.
Speaker 1: It was about the fur and certain things, like I said, the movement stuff.
Speaker 1: Moana is all about sand and water and the hair.
Speaker 1: I love the hair in Moana.
Speaker 1: She has this big, long, curly hair.
Speaker 0: It swings around and gets stuck in her eyes.
Speaker 1: It swings around and she'll come out of the water and it will be all wet and it will hit her in the face.
Speaker 1: I loved watching the way her clothes and her hair were animated.
Speaker 1: But just as a character, I found her to be a really compelling character.
Speaker 1: Because they didn't make her overly like "tough girl, let's go, punch 'em" kind of thing.
Speaker 1: She was just very determined and pretty smart and adventurous.
Speaker 1: But I don't know, I just thought she was good as a protagonist.
Speaker 0: It's not like "fuck this town, I'm out of
Speaker 0: here.".
Speaker 1: No, she cared a lot about her family and about the people in her village.
Speaker 0: She was pretty close to agreeing and staying to do her job.
Speaker 0: And she was actually pretty okay with it.
Speaker 0: And it wasn't until the thing that grandma showed her, and not to spoil, but basically one of my favorite things ever in anything is precursor technology.
Speaker 0: And that is a big part of this movie.
Speaker 1: The movie was all about "where did our people come
Speaker 1: from?".
Speaker 1: And then she has this revelation like "oh, we weren't always on this
Speaker 1: island.".
Speaker 1: And it's actually a really great scene.
Speaker 1: But also I like how some of the songs, they do the thing like... You never saw Princess and the Frog.
Speaker 0: I do need to see that.
Speaker 1: It's a good movie, but there was this one musical number where it's like the style will switch during a song, and it will be like aping a specific artistic style.
Speaker 1: And this one was like 1920s Jazz Age posters.
Speaker 1: And in Moana, they did a similar thing during Maui's song where it's all like stylized art and it looks like paper cutouts.
Speaker 0: It's beautiful.
Speaker 0: And they don't overuse it.
Speaker 0: They just use it there in that one scene.
Speaker 0: But it's just like... He basically has the powers that the witches have in Madoka and pulls her into this weird animated death world.
Speaker 0: Because he does try to kill her.
Speaker 0: I mean, you're welcome.
Speaker 1: He's such a jerk.
Speaker 1: He's straight up.
Speaker 1: Watch the movie and you'll see there's a point.
Speaker 1: He's like hanging out on this island in this cave.
Speaker 0: He tries to kill her like 20 times.
Speaker 1: He tries to kill the chicken too.
Speaker 1: He's like "I'll fatten you up for
Speaker 1: later.".
Speaker 0: That villager tries to kill the chicken.
Speaker 1: At that point, everybody kind of looks at the chicken and be like "Should we just put it out of its
Speaker 1: misery?".
Speaker 1: And she's like "No!
Speaker 1: He's our special
Speaker 1: chicken!".
Speaker 1: He's like trying to eat a rock.
Speaker 1: But I like how the chicken wasn't too big a part of it.
Speaker 1: It was just kind of like a little bit of comic relief.
Speaker 1: Like look at the cute, dumb animal.
Speaker 1: do a cute, dumb thing.
Speaker 1: But yeah, they have that... It was definitely, again, kind of a buddy thing where at first they don't really get along and then they learn to work together.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I highly recommend you go see this while it's still in the theater.
Speaker 1: But it wasn't a romance for the once.
Speaker 1: That's actually cool.
Speaker 1: The Disney princess did not... It wasn't about finding the prince.
Speaker 1: She had an entirely different motivation and I really liked the resolution of this because to be honest, there wasn't really a villain.
Speaker 1: There were bad guys.
Speaker 1: There were antagonists.
Speaker 1: Like the crab was an antagonist.
Speaker 1: But I wouldn't call anybody particularly villainous.
Speaker 1: There wasn't any overarching thing where somebody was like "Mwahahaha!
Speaker 1: I will thwart you at every
Speaker 1: turn!".
Speaker 1: It was like the majority of the antagonism came from the adventure itself or from two characters kind of dealing with each other and dealing with their past and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Surprisingly subtle little arcs for the very relatively small cast in this movie.
Speaker 0: And just haunting moments like when the ships are going by and she's sort of having her vision of what could be.
Speaker 1: I like that scene.
Speaker 1: I like the scene, like I said, the scene where it was like... You know in the hero's journey to get all film school on you.
Speaker 1: But in the monomyth, there's always the point where the protagonist is kind of down and out before the climax where they have lost space in their self.
Speaker 1: And it's like the belly of the whale, I think it's called in the monomyth.
Speaker 1: But it's like, so they're at their lowest point and they receive some sort of revelation that allows them to go for it.
Speaker 1: That scene in Moana was really, really beautiful and I really liked it.
Speaker 1: And yeah, go see it.
Speaker 1: It's a simple movie but it's definitely, I think, one of Disney's better records.
Speaker 0: Of the recent stuff, I think only Zootopia beats it out on my list.
Speaker 0: It's a solid number two and I think Zootopia only wins partly because of the subject matter and the two main characters.
Speaker 0: It's kind of hard when you don't like... But also, Zootopia dealt with some real shit really in a nuanced way that I did not expect that level of subtlety.
Speaker 1: I liked that their two most recent movies were so different.
Speaker 1: You compare Zootopia and this film and they're both really good but in completely different ways.
Speaker 0: Which don't worry because their next movie is Cars 3.
Speaker 1: That's Pixar, again.
Speaker 0: Disney's next movie, Wreck-It Ralph 2 2018.
Speaker 0: Then Incredibles 2, that's Pixar.
Speaker 1: I mean, I liked Wreck-It Ralph but I don't really think it needs sequel.
Speaker 0: Toy Story 4, that's Pixar.
Speaker 1: God, they're having total sequelitis.
Speaker 0: Frozen 2 is listed here.
Speaker 0: For real?
Speaker 0: For 2021.
Speaker 0: And an untitled Lin-Manuel Miranda, Byron Howard developed Disney animation film is supposedly in the works.
Speaker 0: Okay, then.
Speaker 1: I know that Moana was in the works for a long time.
Speaker 1: They really wanted to do... It's kind of funny because I think it started because they had all the Polynesian stuff at Disney World.
Speaker 1: You know how Disney likes to work with existing properties and themes like Pirates of the Caribbean and stuff?
Speaker 0: We have the Polynesian, you know, the resort, the Polynesian.
Speaker 0: We never did anything and luckily they didn't get that idea until 2016.
Speaker 0: Can you imagine this movie in like 1940?
Speaker 1: Well, I don't think... Well, Disney World hasn't been around since 1940.
Speaker 0: When did they build the Polynesian?
Speaker 1: Then we'll look at what Disney movies they were making.
Speaker 1: I'm assuming it was sometimes in the 60s from the decor of that place.
Speaker 1: It's like, I'd say mid-60s, I'm assuming.
Speaker 1: That's where we had the Tiki Bar.
Speaker 1: That was actually some of my favorite memories from our recent trip to Disney World.
Speaker 1: was hanging out at the Polynesian Resort.
Speaker 1: They have this balcony where it's an outside Tiki Bar and you can see the fireworks.
Speaker 0: You can actually see the Disney castle and the fireworks in the distance.
Speaker 0: They actually played the music and all the stuff for the fireworks right there.
Speaker 0: It was pretty fun.
Speaker 0: It was a bunch of couples and adults like us, surprisingly similar demographic sitting there, all just having cocktails and sort of enjoying Disney from afar.
Speaker 1: And the nice lady let me keep the glowing ice cube from the fancy drink.
Speaker 0: All right, so 1971...
Speaker 1: See, I was right.
Speaker 0: I said late 60s.
Speaker 0: So let's see, we got The Jungle Book, The Aristocrats, Robin Hood, The Rescuers, Fox and the Hounds.
Speaker 1: This is a different movie.
Speaker 1: Fucking and sucking.
Speaker 1: I don't think Disney is in that one.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I kind of think that the development...
Speaker 0: We're right all over in company.
Speaker 0: I always forget that movie exists.
Speaker 1: I like that movie okay.
Speaker 1: It's not great, but it's not terrible.
Speaker 0: It's just, I forget, it never comes to mind.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I feel like, because being in the industry I'm in, I keep a fairly close eye on what Disney's planning, like their development stuff.
Speaker 1: And I know both The Snow Queen, which became Frozen, and a Polynesian princess movie were in the pipeline for many years and it got substantially rewritten.
Speaker 1: And luckily the end result is a really good movie.
Speaker 0: Well, they already had The Tiki Room.
Speaker 0: They can make that movie.
Speaker 0: It'll be Iago and everyone going on an adventure.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, The Parrots.
Speaker 1: That's a song that gets stuck in my head.
Speaker 1: I'm like, no, don't even start with me, buddy.
Speaker 0: I remember they had that one drink at The Polynesian, The Tiki Tiki Tiki Tiki Room.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it could have been really stereotypical.
Speaker 1: And I'm not saying it was without any problems, but I was pretty impressed by the caliber of the movie.
Speaker 1: Good game, Disney.
Speaker 0: But seriously, go see it in 3D while you can, because it will lose... It'll still be a great movie to see, but it'll lose something significant if you don't see it in 3D.
Speaker 1: The depth of the environment.
Speaker 0: It was designed for 3D.
Speaker 0: If you look at the credits, they put a lot of effort and care into the 3D environments.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Now we have to review, let's see, we have to review Dr.
Speaker 1: Strange.
Speaker 1: Dr.
Speaker 1: We've got to review...
Speaker 0: Lupin, Fujiko Mine, we'll do that one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've got to do that one.
Speaker 1: But I really want to drag you to go see the new Harry Potter because I really liked it.
Speaker 0: A bunch of white kids running around.
Speaker 0: It was good, though.
Speaker 1: It was 1920s New York, and it was fun.
Speaker 1: It was like, imagine New York, prohibition era, plus dragons.
Speaker 1: It's great.
Speaker 0: I guess the two, I saw I think three Harry Potter movies, and one of them was like half of the Deathly Hallows or whatever.
Speaker 0: One of them was the bad one with the Phoenix, I think?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the one Chamber of Secrets, which is the weakest of the Harry Potter books.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've not batted too well with Harry Potter movies.
Speaker 1: You're like so anti-Harry Potter.
Speaker 1: It's a great story.
Speaker 0: I can't read those books.
Speaker 1: Blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: Ron said, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: Harry said, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: Harry said, and then a sword fell from the sky into Harry's hands and he accidentally killed the salamander or whatever.
Speaker 1: Salamander.
Speaker 1: I think, I think you should narrow... See, you would be better than that potted Potter.
Speaker 1: You would have been a better like...
Speaker 0: I can get my off-Broadway show.
Speaker 0: Rims summarizes Harry Potter.
Speaker 1: Harry Potter, having read approximately none of it.
Speaker 1: Oh boy.
Speaker 1: Anyway, Disney's, Disney's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Pixar's needs to step up their game a little bit and that's our show.
Speaker 0: And look forward to, I guess, Cars 3 if you're a Pixar fan.
Speaker 1: Okay, one last thing before the end of the show.
Speaker 1: The trailer for Cars 3, right?
Speaker 1: Which we saw before Moana.
Speaker 0: I had heard so much about this trailer.
Speaker 0: What the heck?
Speaker 1: I had heard a little bit.
Speaker 0: It just shows the main car like dying in a car accident and then it's like everything changed and that's it.
Speaker 1: But it doesn't show the car as like the weird car face.
Speaker 1: You just see this computer animated car like flipping over and it's not like stylized all that much.
Speaker 1: It's just like this red NASCAR looking car flipping over and wiping out and it's all like sparks and on fire.
Speaker 1: And I was like, what?
Speaker 1: And then I was like, this is cars?
Speaker 0: Okay, I learned what the deal is.
Speaker 0: Blindsided by a new generation of blazing fast racers, the legendary Lightning McQueen is suddenly pushed out of the sport he loves.
Speaker 0: To get back in the game and lead the help of eager young female race technician Cruz Ramirez with her own plan to win.
Speaker 0: Plus inspiration from the late Doc Hudson.
Speaker 0: It's basically Rocky.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's a comeback story.
Speaker 0: Except he's actually going to win.
Speaker 0: Spoilers, I guess.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Pixar could pull a thing and not have him win.
Speaker 1: They could have him die.
Speaker 0: Then it cuts back to he's just in the hospital hallucinating.
Speaker 0: all of that from the actual accident.
Speaker 0: The end.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Cars just weirds me out because it's like, I have difficulty.
Speaker 1: Like little, little kids love the shit out of that movie.
Speaker 0: Because they have cars.
Speaker 0: They can move them around.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I get that little kids like it and it seems like, but like.
Speaker 0: Cars bothers me on a fundamental level the way that like Rugrats does.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm like, I have trouble immersing myself in that world because like I don't really understand how the world works and why.
Speaker 1: and like.
Speaker 0: How come Angelica can talk to the babies and they understand each other, but like the babies can't talk to the adults, but Angelica can also talk to the adults.
Speaker 1: Well, cause she's a toddler.
Speaker 1: She's halfway between.
Speaker 1: But she fully understands them.
Speaker 1: So did you ever read the book of 101 Dalmatians?
Speaker 0: I don't think I've ever actually read it.
Speaker 0: I think I just.
Speaker 1: It's way better than the Disney movie.
Speaker 1: I really like it.
Speaker 1: It's very British.
Speaker 1: But anyway, there's this one part where Pongo and misses encounter this old sheepdog and this little kid and the old sheepdog is like.
Speaker 1: Hangs out with the little kid and the little kid can kind of talk to the dogs and understand them.
Speaker 1: But he's like in that weird liminal stage between like starting to learn how to talk in people.
Speaker 1: So he's losing the ability to talk in dog.
Speaker 1: And so it's kind of like that scene where it's like when they're little, they can talk to each other, but then they grow up and they lose the ability to talk baby.
Speaker 0: And I think we'll leave it at that.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.