Speaker 0:
Speaker 1: It's Monday October 3rd 2016.
Speaker 1: I'm rim Scott and this is geek nights tonight disposing of old technology.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I was on a boat the other night.
Speaker 1: Yeah on the other side It was one of you know those party boats that you see going up and down the river in New York sometimes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I was on one of those.
Speaker 0: I mean we were on one of those when we went to see the joke Oh concert.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I was also on one of those when Judith had her bachelorette party.
Speaker 0: I mean they seem to be like an in ex relatively inexpensive, but Moderate party situation that you know.
Speaker 0: if you're in New York you're gonna end up on that boat a few times If you're here long enough, I remember one time.
Speaker 1: You know we did.
Speaker 1: we went for Judith's thing.
Speaker 1: We went to the boat.
Speaker 1: our boat was technically a Hall and Oates tribute band boat.
Speaker 0: was there actually a Hall and Oates tribute band On it?
Speaker 1: yes, and they performed for the entire boat ride, and we didn't.
Speaker 0: I mean Hall and Oates isn't bad?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the music was fine But no one gave a shit about them.
Speaker 1: so like the inside of the boat where they were performing was literally empty and everyone was outside in the beautiful weather Listening to the music piped up so they were playing to an empty room.
Speaker 1: I felt a little bad, but and but while we were getting on the Hall and Oates boat I mean I was this weekend.
Speaker 0: I was at like the tiniest Country fair and you know welcome to our country.
Speaker 0: home Local business has a table place.
Speaker 0: yeah There were bands playing to nothing Except like an old person standing there and a kid running around in a circle.
Speaker 1: yeah So uh man bad weather didn't help them when we got on the Holland but Hall and Oates boat way back.
Speaker 1: I remember that as we were getting on our boat There was a boat next to us that was also loading and that boat looked like a much better boat.
Speaker 0: because that boat Boat you listen.
Speaker 0: whenever you get on one of these boats the boat next to you is always.
Speaker 0: in that case unless you're the rich Person with the big is why the rich people who do the yacht thing try to have the biggest yacht And don't like.
Speaker 0: what's the guy's name?
Speaker 0: Paul Allen?
Speaker 0: He always kept trying to make his yacht bigger and bigger and bigger and he'd buy bigger ones That way whenever he was pulling out.
Speaker 0: He wouldn't have like some Bill Gates or someone with a bigger yacht next to him He would always be pulling out in the biggest boat.
Speaker 1: But so basically I remember that time.
Speaker 1: the other boat it was interesting cuz our boat for the Hall and Oates tribute band was Pretty much 90% like white people all dressed the same way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the other boat was no white people and everybody was dressed real fashion nice.
Speaker 1: And the music coming out of that boat sounded like the opposite of Hall and Oates.
Speaker 1: and it was like that boat went off into The distance and we were thinking about jumping for it.
Speaker 0: I would have jumped for it.
Speaker 0: How far how far was a jump?
Speaker 1: so the boat that time it's a parkour on.
Speaker 1: so this other time We're on this boat.
Speaker 0: If you land if there's a party boat and you arrive on that party boat by jumping from an adjacent party boat You're the only officially the life of the party unless you're the party frog.
Speaker 1: So, but I remember when we got back that other boat got back around the same time and There was this weird walk of shame down the gangplank where like every basically normal people were walking off the boat.
Speaker 1: They were fine, but like every 20 or 30 people they were.
Speaker 1: almost invariably It was always a woman wearing like four inch heels who was too drunk to walk Trying to make their way down the gang playing to fall off that gang playing and they're like falling off of each other and it Was like such a thing.
Speaker 1: It was kind of funny.
Speaker 1: But on this other boat, we were on a party boat.
Speaker 1: same deal hanging out.
Speaker 1: There's fine boat time and the boat gets back and we're getting off the boat.
Speaker 1: We get off the boat right away.
Speaker 1: And then as we're standing there waiting for the rest of our friends to all get off the boat the Shame walk of the drunk people was there again.
Speaker 1: and because we stood there while all the drunk people got off the boat I got to see in the fullness of that situation and I think that this happens every time there's a party boat.
Speaker 1: There's a surprising number of people who drink so much on these boats.
Speaker 1: They cannot get off of the boat under their own power.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I don't know what happens to those people after they do get off the boat because the boat is
Speaker 0: long as they don't drive home And they take a subway or a cab because the boat
Speaker 1: people help them get off the boat
Speaker 0: They barf in the back of an uber or something, but they do
Speaker 1: not help them after that point.
Speaker 1: So I watched this one dude stagger down the gang playing like gaining momentum.
Speaker 1: the whole time He gets to the bottom and just kind of keeps going straight and then bumps into the wall That was like 15 feet away from the water Mm-hmm, and then just stands there and does not move.
Speaker 1: and he was still standing there when we left.
Speaker 0: Oh, he's standing.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 1: No, I don't.
Speaker 1: maybe he knocked himself out, but he was just like propped up against the wall.
Speaker 1: I couldn't quite tell that's fine There's a good boat.
Speaker 0: He wasn't moving into the road or something, you know, yeah.
Speaker 0: So I think if like a drunk guy, you know, if you see a drunk person you just ignore them.
Speaker 0: But if you see, you know a drunk person like stumbling about randomly and they're near a road You kind of have to call through on one.
Speaker 1: maybe yeah a couple of times in my life I've steered someone who was drunk away because it's like you don't want to go from walking into the subway track.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you don't want to go near them because they might barf on you or fight you or something.
Speaker 0: But you also you don't want them to die just getting hit by a car because by stumbling into the road.
Speaker 1: Yep So the other thing that happened to me that was kind of interesting is I got this device and I asked you earlier You know, I pointed out I was gonna talk about it.
Speaker 1: It might look like a battery but it's actually a power adapter to charge an LG device of some kind.
Speaker 0: It's a it's a USB charger.
Speaker 0: It has two prongs for power at one end at least in the United States and it has USB hole on the other end.
Speaker 0: It's kind of boring.
Speaker 0: What's what's the big?
Speaker 1: So the prongs are bent quite dramatic.
Speaker 1: The
Speaker 0: prongs are bent out like ears like ones pointing to the left of ones pointing to the right like somebody took pliers and made It this shape to make like a cute little like you were making like you can be a little toy out of it Put two googly eyes on it and draw a little mouth and use some pipe cleaners to make arms and legs and you have like A cute little guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I did take pliers and do that yesterday.
Speaker 1: And that is why I like that.
Speaker 0: Why did you do that?
Speaker 1: So we were watching TV and I'm laying there and I hear this noise like this heavy vibrating buzzing noise like like Like hypnotoad.
Speaker 1: Mmm, so but it's I like.
Speaker 1: I'd heard it off and on throughout the day But there's a lot of construction outside our building.
Speaker 1: So I kind of just chalked it up to that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then I'm sitting there and is like really bothering me Like it's louder than it should be and I saw like I touched the window and like it's not vibrating.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to figure it out.
Speaker 1: so eventually we have this power strip on the couch and there's a USB charger plugged into it and then There's this assortment of like five other one-off USB chargers that I guess people have over the years Plugged into that when they visited and just left there.
Speaker 0: Why don't they use the group charger?
Speaker 1: I don't know like the group charger is there.
Speaker 1: and yet I watch people sit next to it Take their phone out plug into the power strip with a device like this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so whoever left this device here is losing it because I'm throwing it away I just damage it so that no one will use it.
Speaker 1: because I realize eventually because I turn off the power strip the buzzing stops.
Speaker 1: Oh, I turn the power strip back on And I one by one unplug things from it.
Speaker 1: And when I unplug this and held it up to my ear, it was buzzing so loud that you would be surprised.
Speaker 1: And it's continued to buzz because you know, it's there's a coil in here it's there's induction for like 45 seconds.
Speaker 1: Pretty sure there's problems inside of this thing.
Speaker 1: So I damaged it so that no one can use it and I'm going to dispose of it Which is the topic of the show.
Speaker 0: you just missed our disposal opportunity.
Speaker 1: Yeah I disposed of a lot of things that the disposal opportunity and this is gonna go in my bucket until the next disposal opportunity.
Speaker 1: Hmm, I guess I could take it like staples or something like.
Speaker 1: those places will take this stuff.
Speaker 0: Best buy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which anyway got any news.
Speaker 0: What was?
Speaker 0: I don't have any news, but I did acquire an iPhone 7 so let's talk about that, right?
Speaker 0: So my original plan was to get the iPhone 7s which you know, the iPhone 6s came out March.
Speaker 0: So if I could wait until March I get iPhone 7s.
Speaker 0: It's almost Gary almost guaranteed not a hundred percent guaranteed which would be a smaller iPhone, which is nice.
Speaker 1: It's basically the iPhone 5 Small phones because this phone I realized in my my packs prime hoodie.
Speaker 1: There's this little sub pocket within the right main pocket and I there's no like.
Speaker 1: there's nothing that would go in that pocket.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this phone fits in that pocket pocket perfectly.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: My own phone could not go in that pocket.
Speaker 0: So here's the situation though.
Speaker 0: So I go to the Apple store and I'm looking at the iPhone 6s and I'm like, huh?
Speaker 0: You know the iPhone 7s is basically gonna be that only better right?
Speaker 0: Is that is that gonna cut it, right?
Speaker 0: Am I gonna be able to use my iPhone 6 for a few more months and then get this guy?
Speaker 0: Will that be okay?
Speaker 0: and I started to do some researches and while it is great that it's smaller it actually wasn't as much smaller as I remember like I put it next to the iPhone 6 and 7 and it was only like Less than an inch smaller in one dimension and like not even a centimeter smaller in the other dimension and it's actually thicker.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know about the total volume difference but you know, it wasn't that big a deal.
Speaker 0: also You know, I mostly care like the size is like my number one thing I cared about But it's like they're all the second tier priorities Using that iPhone 6s after using an iPhone regular 6 for two years.
Speaker 0: It was like way slow.
Speaker 1: You know that is a trade-off because my you know I have the Xperia z5 compact which I still think is the best Android hardware in the world.
Speaker 1: bar none.
Speaker 0: But Google pixels come in any second.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we'll see how that goes.
Speaker 0: But I don't know if Google pixels gonna be a great phone, but I think it's gonna be a normal phone.
Speaker 0: But I think the advantage is you're gonna get your normal Android with your updates constantly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what's gonna put that ahead of every other Android phone?
Speaker 1: But the only problem with this phone is that the battery lasts two full days like for real.
Speaker 1: But it only does that because it's kind of slow and a little laggy.
Speaker 1: if I turn off all the power saving shit It lasts about as long as a normal iPhone like.
Speaker 1: it lasts about one day.
Speaker 0: and it's way fast And like even though the screen on the iPhone 6s is a retina screen.
Speaker 0: or I mean se not success se.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've been saying success the whole time.
Speaker 0: I mean se the small one.
Speaker 0: Yeah success is the one that's in between the six And the seven.
Speaker 1: well, I've got a z5 C for what it's worth, right?
Speaker 0: but yeah, the SE is the small iPhone and Like everything else about the small iPhone except for the fact that it was small was like worse.
Speaker 0: the camera was worse.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even here does the z5 compacts camera.
Speaker 1: while it's a really good camera.
Speaker 1: Like it's as good as an older screen The screen was worse.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: The screen is only 720p on this thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I was like, uh, like the big version of this phone is better in every way except It's too big to put in my pocket right.
Speaker 0: further compounding My difficulties is that my iPhone 6 while working perfectly and in great condition was having battery issues.
Speaker 1: I think you sabotaged that battery on purpose.
Speaker 0: It was not having battery issues of the sort where the battery was dying.
Speaker 0: quite the opposite The battery was lasting just as long as it ever had.
Speaker 0: but the battery meter that reported how much percentage is left Was all fucked up despite me trying to recalibrate it multiple times.
Speaker 0: So for example, I would I had it at a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: I left the office Like less than an hour later.
Speaker 0: It said like 70% and then like less than an hour by the time I got back to the office It was like 20-something percent that I did use it to make a video but 20% after making like a little Scott's lunch video.
Speaker 0: That's not too much.
Speaker 0: Yeah As soon as I plugged it back into my computer at the office like plug it in do I acknowledge that I've been plugged in?
Speaker 0: The battery meter said 88%.
Speaker 0: I had only actually used 12% of the battery It was.
Speaker 0: I tried to drain it completely once to recalibrate it.
Speaker 0: I was went to bed and it said 1%.
Speaker 0: I woke up and it said 1%.
Speaker 0: It was lunchtime and it still said 1% even though it hadn't been plugged in since the previous evening and Then just about at lunchtime.
Speaker 0: It turned off So it had battery meter issues.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, oh rather than deal with these issues Because I mean you might think well if it's lasting as long and the meter just as 1% you just ignore.
Speaker 1: the probe is the Consequences of the battery hitting zero when you're out and about can be devastating.
Speaker 0: The real consequence is that when the iPhone meter hits 20% it goes in the low power mode and stops doing stuff And then it tries to turn itself off even though it had plenty of power left.
Speaker 0: because the meter is wrong.
Speaker 0: It's doing things based on the meter that are you know getting annoying?
Speaker 1: Yeah, my phone will do that when I hit 10% but I can configure that also to replace the battery would have cost 60 to $80.
Speaker 0: so I'm like, well fuck it.
Speaker 0: Let me just get iPhone 7.
Speaker 0: So the reason I also got the iPhone 7?
Speaker 0: because it was effectively free ish.
Speaker 0: So the reason it was effectively free ish is because Verizon changed their plans.
Speaker 0: I looked at like maybe switch to t-mobile maybe You know whatever but horizon changed their plan to where I was paying for six gigs of data like $100 a month, right?
Speaker 0: I Could change the plan to either eight gigs of data for the same amount of money.
Speaker 0: But they now allow rollover data and I looked at my past history and I was using less than four gigs a month.
Speaker 0: So I went to the four gig a month plan Which is 70 bucks a month like 30 gigs for $30 for four gigs.
Speaker 0: fuck that right.
Speaker 0: and The rollover data should help me in those months that like one month a year where there's two conventions and I go over the limit The rollover data will get me through.
Speaker 0: so I saved 30 bucks a month by switching to the Verizon plan That was smaller.
Speaker 0: and then I got the iPhone upgrade plan Which is get a new iPhone every single year no matter what and all you do is pay 30 something bucks a month.
Speaker 0: So I'm basically paying a hundred bucks a month that I was paying all this time.
Speaker 0: And I just get a new iPhone every year no matter what.
Speaker 0: but the other problem with the small iPhone the SE They don't let you do the upgrade plan with that phone.
Speaker 0: They only let you do it with the big iPhone or the normal iPhone.
Speaker 0: really Yeah, you can't get.
Speaker 0: you can't use the iPhone upgrade plan, which gives you permanent Apple care.
Speaker 0: also with the small iPhone You can only do it with the normal iPhone.
Speaker 1: That's a shame.
Speaker 0: So I got.
Speaker 0: I just said all right fuck it.
Speaker 0: I went into the Apple store and they gave me an iPhone 7 for effectively nothing.
Speaker 1: and I know okay We'll see what I do cuz I got my phone.
Speaker 1: so this phone will last me a while.
Speaker 0: So I just see what's great about the iPhone 7 and you know what?
Speaker 0: Compared to the iPhone 6 the I I mean I've gotten every iPhone.
Speaker 0: that was a major jump.
Speaker 0: I got the iPhone 3G.
Speaker 0: I got the iPhone 4 5 & 6 and now this is the 7 and The like.
Speaker 0: the 3G was way different than the original one The 4 was way different than 3G.
Speaker 0: the 5 was way different than the 4. the 6 was way Different than the 5. the 7 is not that much different than the 6.
Speaker 0: It's like it's it might.
Speaker 0: it's basically like 6s and 6 6s and 7. all might as well be really the same phone.
Speaker 0: The mate like the camera is significantly improved.
Speaker 0: There's no question about that Which is nice, but it's not like game-changing.
Speaker 0: It has the force touch thing where you can push down harder on something to get a context menu Which actually works really well, which is nice.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: The home button is not a physical button.
Speaker 1: tap ticks That's the word for that.
Speaker 0: It has all these tap ticks like the steam controller has and it really feels like you're pushing a home button But it's not a physical mechanism.
Speaker 0: So it's way better.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: I saw the usual pre-complaining of people who were like, oh they're rid of the physical.
Speaker 1: You know the people who complain about those kinds of things complain about a thing before they use it.
Speaker 1: But in this case, I noticed when the iPhone felt weird for about two minutes and now it's.
Speaker 0: I can't go.
Speaker 0: It would feel weird if I went back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when the phone came you literally walk over to me and you're like touch this and I touch the button and it felt pretty Good, but yeah, all those complaints the pre-complaints pretty much disappeared when people actually touched it.
Speaker 0: So it's fine.
Speaker 0: It's a button That's not a real buttons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it works.
Speaker 1: button is coming out.
Speaker 0: The only valid complaint that I can find right is in regards of course to the no headphone hole.
Speaker 0: now People be like, there's no headphone hole DRM.
Speaker 0: and I'm like dudes that while I am anti DRM Just as much as you that is the biggest bullshit I ever heard.
Speaker 0: because they're worried that for example that there's only this lightning output that someone could write code.
Speaker 0: That's like if watching football game on phone don't allow audio out lightning hole.
Speaker 0: You could write code on an old iPhone that says don't allow audio out analog hole.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not any fucking different Because the audio still originates at a digital source and therefore can be controlled by the same DRM regardless of whether there's an analog Output or not.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Because they give you that lightning to analog hole They can't stop you.
Speaker 0: It's like what the you know, right?
Speaker 0: It's it's Different.
Speaker 0: now people I think they analogize because inside an iPhone 6, you know, what's behind that analog hole Effectively a lightning hole.
Speaker 1: Yeah lose a red Any fucking different.
Speaker 1: but so with I think people get confused because with a video like the HTTP nonsense Yeah the deal is if you don't have a trusted chain the analog output meaning the light your human eyes can see is Downgraded in quality.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: and with audio What down great like they're not gonna do the same thing.
Speaker 1: audio is not downgraded.
Speaker 1: It would be one thing isn't copyright?
Speaker 0: It'll be one thing.
Speaker 0: if it was.
Speaker 0: you must use Bluetooth headphones or lightning.
Speaker 0: You cannot use analog headphones.
Speaker 0: we did not make an adapter but no there's an adapter.
Speaker 0: therefore That's a bullshit argument.
Speaker 1: Also audio is Basically trivial to capture like say there was HTTP style.
Speaker 1: crazy DRM down the road.
Speaker 1: in these things Speakers are microphones like the at closing.
Speaker 1: bringing the analog hole back into the digital realm also Has no DRM money.
Speaker 0: you could always do it that way.
Speaker 1: Quality depending on.
Speaker 0: Regardless, there is a valid argument though.
Speaker 0: The valid argument is many people pointed this out.
Speaker 0: There's no headphone hole.
Speaker 0: There's only a lightning hole.
Speaker 0: You can't charge and listen at the same time through the lightning hole.
Speaker 0: You would need Bluetooth or wireless headphones to listen and charge it or a special lightning Special thingy that has an analog hole and a lightning hole so you could charge and listen at the same time.
Speaker 0: But I bought an extra analog hole nine bucks just in case plus I might you know.
Speaker 0: and Yeah, it's not the biggest deal.
Speaker 0: It's slightly annoying.
Speaker 1: I mean the only the only time I could ever see that actually being annoying is That I often fuck around with my phone when I'm flying Yep, and I'm usually also plugged into the USB port on the plane.
Speaker 1: keeping my phone charged while I'm flying.
Speaker 1: I could not do both.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That's still a minor annoyance at best.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Still I honestly though.
Speaker 1: I don't think Switching bought them that much.
Speaker 0: It.
Speaker 0: I think they put the tactic thing where the headphone hole used to be yeah, they could have gotten around that I mean they made.
Speaker 1: it's been all they.
Speaker 1: all they get out of this really is they make it thinner and I guess they Don't have to have a RAM deck in the phone anymore for audio, but they still do because there's two speakers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh, that's another thing.
Speaker 0: Stereo sound because they put a speaker where the headphone hole used to be Yep, and we used to be.
Speaker 0: only the iPad had stereo sound but now the iPhone.
Speaker 1: but any argument that they don't need RAM decks Or anything is bullshit because they still have speakers.
Speaker 1: So there's still something doing that in the iPhone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess you don't need two of them now.
Speaker 0: I don't know three of them.
Speaker 1: I don't know how the iPhone looks internally.
Speaker 0: You can look it up online.
Speaker 0: It's not that excited.
Speaker 0: But yeah iPhone 7 really similar to previous iPhones.
Speaker 0: But you know, it's fine cuz I'm gonna get an iPhone.
Speaker 0: See there's a rumor that next year there won't be an iPhone 7s They'll be an iPhone 8 and they just because they're sucking they're going slower.
Speaker 0: Which is great because I got the upgrade plan.
Speaker 0: So I'll just get it for nothing I'll just get one.
Speaker 0: So it's all good.
Speaker 1: So in other news that was kind of interesting.
Speaker 1: Recently amber alerts and like the all those sorts of things got a lot of press in New York City because there were two separate instances where one an amber alert went out on the Tell everyone in an area with phones Overriding any settings they might have emergency broadcast system and it broadcast an amber alert to basically everyone in New York Which you know 20 ish
Speaker 0: imagine.
Speaker 0: Yeah millions of phones all going Simultaneously, it's just a best.
Speaker 1: you the best part about that I mean, I'm good.
Speaker 1: on one hand just the concept of amber alerts seems like a good thing.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand The odds of me acting on one of those are basically zero.
Speaker 0: I Would love to see the stats on whether an amber alert is actually saved a child or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and aren't there like, you know while I you know Agree that a child that has been kidnapped is bad news and we should do something about that.
Speaker 0: If you're going to alert everybody Literally everybody I think it needs to be even more serious than that Like it needs to be as serious as like holy shit.
Speaker 0: You know a meteor is going to land or holy shits everyone seek shelter.
Speaker 1: Like I was okay with the second time they used it around here when the guy who was trying to do all the bombings They put an alert out saying here's this guy's photo.
Speaker 1: He's armed and dangerous and somewhere in the city.
Speaker 0: Even that is a borderline usage.
Speaker 1: I think that was fine.
Speaker 1: Now if I only think that was fine because they were pretty sure he was in the city They had a photo of him They knew who he was and he was likely dangerous and he was armed and you know that I think that was no K use.
Speaker 0: I think you only should alert literally everybody of something if literally everybody has to take action.
Speaker 1: But that one was easy because everyone basically has looked around like was the guy here?
Speaker 1: It's not like unsolved mysteries where you're an amber alert where the odds are pretty much zero.
Speaker 1: this works Mmm, but the out the the fallout of this was not.
Speaker 1: why did everyone bother me?
Speaker 1: Most people are okay with that alert though with the amber alert Twitter was nothing but to see if people going what the fuck is an amber alert.
Speaker 0: Well, people don't know.
Speaker 1: No, it's a problem.
Speaker 0: That is a problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah Silver alert is just as serious.
Speaker 0: I think as amber alert, right?
Speaker 1: It's like there's an old person you missing.
Speaker 1: So this is you want to make a real cold horrible calculated evil.
Speaker 0: People's lives are more valuable than old people's lives because you could die Anyway in a vacuum between the two.
Speaker 1: a young person's life is worth more, right?
Speaker 0: But is it worth?
Speaker 0: is it the difference between an old person's life and young person's life?
Speaker 0: the difference between?
Speaker 0: Bothering every single person's phone and not I think the line should be is the gap.
Speaker 1: What are the odds that everyone getting this alert will alter the otherwise predicted outcome of this situation?
Speaker 0: Everyone to vote Today vote now, we'll keep alerting your phone until you vote Your phone number.
Speaker 1: in fact until your phone shows up at the polls We're gonna keep alerting you and then your phone is gonna disable itself.
Speaker 1: Yeah You want to alter history with alerts on phones, but the fallout from the terror alert was why is this system?
Speaker 1: So primitive and can't eat.
Speaker 1: It can send 300.
Speaker 1: I think it can only send 90 characters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a pretty shitty system in a world.
Speaker 0: If you look if you already agree that you're gonna use this system Whether we're gonna argue about whether it should or should not be used in which cases it should still be a much better system That is capable of say, you know saying messages out loud for people who are blind or showing pictures of the guy You're looking for or the person you're looking.
Speaker 0: Okay, Scott So a car having links that you can click on in the message that would bring you to more.
Speaker 1: So that was the thing.
Speaker 0: because the terror alert the reason it worked was that or doing better Targeting of exactly which phones it's going to alert and not just everyone in the whole fucking city.
Speaker 1: So all of those 90 characters in the terror one They they used it to link to a website that had a picture of the guy and that's the only reason they caught it Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So a consequence of the fact that we're kind of live streaming geek nights when we make it now A listener just did the research for us.
Speaker 1: according to the amber alert government side There are 261 amber alerts total in the US between January 1st 2006. there were 10 years ago amber alerts.
Speaker 1: Okay in that year 214 children were recovered and 53 of those were directly attributed to the amber alerts being issued.
Speaker 0: If it saved 53 kids a year well That's it.
Speaker 0: You had to quantify how annoying the alert is.
Speaker 0: the car.
Speaker 1: So, you know if it was one kid a year and I don't want to get woken up if it's so effective Should we not be alerting all sorts of fucking other things?
Speaker 1: well maybe but that's again I think the line of whether or not you like
Speaker 0: if you're gonna say the amber alert is effective Then how come we're not using this alert system to say do all sorts of other good But
Speaker 1: like what the line is will this alert one?
Speaker 0: We're either alerting unnecessarily or not alerting enough.
Speaker 0: It's one of the two.
Speaker 1: Yeah but I think the line has to be Will the expected outcome change or be likely to change as a result of this and at what point?
Speaker 0: if we alert too much?
Speaker 0: Will the alerts become less effective because everyone ignores them because you do too much?
Speaker 1: Right, and it's very telling that this is only happened as far as I can tell with this system in New York.
Speaker 1: twice Cuz.
Speaker 1: that's the only two times has ever happened to me.
Speaker 0: I've heard it happened to me a bunch.
Speaker 1: I guess I haven't once because I don't want me to have it and I got it once for flash flooding But it was specific to LIC.
Speaker 0: it happened twice recently and then there was a huge gap But like maybe two years ago going backwards.
Speaker 0: There was like a ton of it happening.
Speaker 0: the only time it was ever useful to me was the Yeah, the hurricanes coming.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna run the subway anymore.
Speaker 0: You better actually go home from this burning con.
Speaker 1: I think that was a good one.
Speaker 1: Even though I literally caught the last subway out of town I think I was on the second last train.
Speaker 1: I know I was on the last because every station the guy ran out of the train Gathered people from like the ticket booths and turned off all the lights and locked a bunch of gates Got back on the train on the train rent.
Speaker 1: So the train ride took forever because it stopped at every station for like five minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mine train did not do that.
Speaker 0: It was the second last year.
Speaker 1: I was real glad I caught that train cuz I realized if I didn't you're walking home in a heart.
Speaker 1: I was gonna walk home in a hurricane over the bridge or I was a travel ban a taxi wasn't gonna take you no, or I was gonna stay in that bar and The people run in.
Speaker 1: the bar stayed after the subway went down and I know for a fact at least one of the bartenders did Not live in Manhattan.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 1: I don't know what that guy did.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'll bet they just stayed at the bar.
Speaker 1: Maybe I would have.
Speaker 1: yeah, why not?
Speaker 1: if they let me we could just kept burning kind of going all night.
Speaker 0: Okay Yeah, I mean it's a hurricane shit like that happened.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: so, you know a toilet works, right?
Speaker 1: Actually, I learned a whole lot about how a toilet works recently How to get rid of that silt in you in the top of your thing.
Speaker 0: I did a whole bunch of research and I made my toilet way awesome by doing if I adjusted the water I learned everything about basic toiletry.
Speaker 1: now I don't know how to fix a fancy Japanese toilet but I know everything about a standard American toilets because one time we had a toilet like Emily did something and messed up a Toilet and I remember like.
Speaker 1: I went through all my troubleshooting steps and I determined that it was unfixable by my time.
Speaker 0: I am now.
Speaker 0: thanks to YouTube I am now an expert on basic American toilet mechanisms and can repair them and know which parts to buy an Amazon and everything.
Speaker 1: So as a complete aside, I am terrified by the people whose houses I visited Where their toilet kind of runs and got a jiggle the handle.
Speaker 0: I know how to fix that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you need to hire a plumber.
Speaker 0: if I come to your house and you have a shitty toilet Just give me permission to make your toilet awesome and we will do that and I'll teach you how a toilet works.
Speaker 0: It'll take like 10 minutes.
Speaker 0: It's real simple.
Speaker 1: Romans figured it out Not naming names, but I'm terrified by the fact that I know people.
Speaker 1: we've visited their house and Later like a year later we visit again and the toilet still has the same problem.
Speaker 0: I mean my toilet had a problem for a while until I sort of realized I can do this.
Speaker 0: It's like it doesn't dawn on you because it's a black box, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's like your whole life.
Speaker 1: Well, if it's black in there, you got real serious problems, right?
Speaker 0: But like your whole life you've called plumbers to fix this thing.
Speaker 0: You'd never imagine it like it's a really simple thing.
Speaker 0: And as long as the toilet itself isn't like smashed or there's something wrong with the pipes or serious problem Well, you can do it yourself so easily.
Speaker 1: It's like babies first unlike other plumbing problems Like I generally don't take you like those use out of tote Like I'm not gonna deal with the pipes just because there's a lot of like.
Speaker 1: if you mess that up There's a lot of consequences.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean the only reason I don't do anything like with pipes is because I'm not strong enough to tighten it and then it'll Leak everywhere.
Speaker 1: Well, also you don't have all the specialized tools like they're like those.
Speaker 0: it's a lot like I could install a faucet, but I'd probably when I first turned on the faucet spray water everywhere and then be like fuck.
Speaker 1: Well, it's just like with cars and bicycles and even skis like the main like a maintenance on a bike.
Speaker 1: Like you can learn all the maintenance even on a fancy bike.
Speaker 0: I mean you can learn all the maintenance on an f1 car to if someone will teach it to you.
Speaker 1: But like bicycles are not that hard, but even I don't do most of that work because I don't own all the specialized tools.
Speaker 0: yeah, like I actually have a Like if you don't have quite a few of the tools But I don't have like the rack.
Speaker 1: to like mount my bike to like read like rejigger my brakes.
Speaker 1: There are ways to yeah But it's way more pain in the ass Like when I was a kid I had the rack.
Speaker 1: I would like mount my bike and work on it and one time I tried to recalibrate all my gears without that rack.
Speaker 1: Fuck that noise.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna pay someone 60 bucks to do it.
Speaker 1: Yep But so do you know about the mechanics of how toilets work in terms of how and why it flushes and why it doesn't smell?
Speaker 1: Yes, so, uh Why would like say you put a brick of gold like a small brick of gold in the bottom of your toilet?
Speaker 1: Would it flush or would it just sit there?
Speaker 0: Is it physically small enough to go through.
Speaker 1: it's physically small enough, but it's real dense and heavy.
Speaker 1: I Mean it's like we're talking ten times heavier denser than your poop.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure how strong the toilet flush is but I have a feeling it's it gets pretty strong and it also depends on how Much water you got in the tank.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you got a big even a little bowl and you flush it It's not gonna be enough right and it depends on the shape of the gold bar also, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so but There are circumstances in which that yes, you could flush some amount of gold.
Speaker 1: That would be surprising Yeah, but it turns out pretty much.
Speaker 1: No anything heavy and dense is just not gonna flush.
Speaker 1: It'll stay in the bottom of the bowl forever.
Speaker 1: Okay, so let's say you proved instead of poop poop.
Speaker 1: You pooped liquid mercury, but in the same volume as your poop.
Speaker 1: and then you tried to flush the total go near mercury.
Speaker 1: But let's say well elemental mercury in your body actually is not that bad for you because it just passes right.
Speaker 0: Okay, wait So we're talking about mercury in a nator to in water.
Speaker 1: you poop mercury in the quantity You normally poop into a normal water toilet and then flush it.
Speaker 1: Will it go out into the sewer system or will it stay in the bottom?
Speaker 1: I Did not know the answer and then I watched this video and I know he's pretty heavy, but it's also a liquid But it doesn't mix with water.
Speaker 0: So it's like this it's a really tough call.
Speaker 1: what if you filled a toilet the top Entirely with mercury and then flushed mercury and then pooped gold and then flushed it with the gold that the water didn't move?
Speaker 1: now Get moved by the mercury with it Like what would happen?
Speaker 0: the mercury would definitely flush and it would be a way stronger flush than with water.
Speaker 0: Would it be enough to move gold?
Speaker 0: What's the?
Speaker 0: I don't forget the atomic number of gold and mercury if you're intrigued by the answers to all these questions?
Speaker 0: My video is titled flushing 240 pounds of mercury if the atomic number of mercury is water.
Speaker 0: if the atomic number of mercury is Bigger than the number for gold.
Speaker 0: I think it would flush the gold.
Speaker 1: It flushes the gold but he fills an entire toilet with mercury.
Speaker 0: But is mercury have more protons than gold does?
Speaker 1: Uh, watch your show.
Speaker 0: Let me look at my periodic table.
Speaker 1: oh, he also flushes a lead bullet and it floats on the mercury and This video is just great.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at a period.
Speaker 1: also, you know the chain that pulls they'll stop her up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it breaks cuz the mercury is too heavy.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah There's a moment where he sticks his hand in the mercury.
Speaker 1: Let's see lead is Now why she's about to stick his hand in the mercury.
Speaker 1: Where is it?
Speaker 0: Don't put your hand in mercury crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's him flushing the toilet.
Speaker 1: This video is pretty good All right, so you got a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I know you're looking up your atomic numbers.
Speaker 0: I Said you might think of the day.
Speaker 0: What was it?
Speaker 0: There it is.
Speaker 0: It's a real simple little Instagram.
Speaker 0: This guy was biking to work yeah in New York on the west side bike path like you do and he's got a camera on his thing like you do and He encounters a real-life Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtle on his bike ride to work because they live in New York.
Speaker 0: That's where they're from And they're like.
Speaker 0: that's a rare sighting.
Speaker 0: that's like seeing like a super camouflaged owl during the day like you.
Speaker 0: don't see that shit right, so The fact that it was caught on video and post on Instagram is like pretty amazing.
Speaker 0: So check it out.
Speaker 1: Yeah So in the meta moment, oh the book club book is Rebecca I'll probably read it on my trip and then we'll do the show right after I get back from Australia.
Speaker 1: Otherwise we had no conventions coming up until Magfest.
Speaker 1: but we will be at mag fest doing whole bunch of panels.
Speaker 1: We're part of the mages group.
Speaker 1: We'll be at all that academic stuff.
Speaker 1: Magfest is awesome.
Speaker 1: We're totally gonna be there.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be awesome as always.
Speaker 1: I also got the video of our most recent panel our packs panel on the grind from PAX West.
Speaker 1: I put the whole thing up on YouTube and actually Because of Atari game design which is also on YouTube now Which had probably a more complex pipeline because I had the camera angles But I also had to sync us actually playing Atari games live and all that stuff I took the time to actually make like a real video pipeline.
Speaker 1: so I can crank out panel video Way faster and higher quality than we've ever done before.
Speaker 1: So at least when we video our panels at PAX is you can expect them on YouTube like right away from now on.
Speaker 1: That is not the case for other conventions because the lighting in the rooms are so bad that usually the video is not worthwhile.
Speaker 1: But at least at PAX is that he was gonna be a real quick.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, yeah follow both means got on YouTube and Other places and I'm gonna be out of town in Australia for the next two weeks.
Speaker 1: So after the winds on me Yeah, after the Wednesday show will be gone for a while Emily and I might record podcasts of our Australia experiences for the patreon.
Speaker 0: But otherwise, I'll do some streaming bits.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna get my stream going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz you know, so geek nights will be on momentary hiatus But we're both making a lot of other content.
Speaker 0: come to my youtube channel instead.
Speaker 1: I'll have part two.
Speaker 1: I'll have more parts of our.
Speaker 1: remember Scott said five series coming up this week as well.
Speaker 1: So also I am reading all of Castlevania to Simon's quest.
Speaker 0: you don't need that the novel ization, but I'm gonna make good content.
Speaker 0: You're paying for that crap content.
Speaker 0: I will give you good free content that you actually want.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure Timothy Bradley grabbed Simon Belmont's dick and then had an orgasm but I'll leave it up.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: This is what you're paying for.
Speaker 1: Are you sure that's what happened?
Speaker 0: So by the way, gold a topic number 79.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Guess what number mercury is?
Speaker 1: Ah Fuck if I know.
Speaker 0: One just one proton more just one.
Speaker 0: and guess where lead is 82. oh man two more protons.
Speaker 0: you got led.
Speaker 0: It's something they're all real close, but so different.
Speaker 0: It's like the bad.
Speaker 0: imagine you got a bar of gold right and you got like a hundred gold atoms.
Speaker 0: You just should add a hundred protons and now you got a hundred mercury atoms.
Speaker 0: It's crazy.
Speaker 0: It's like it just.
Speaker 0: it's insane science.
Speaker 1: So two things that are sort of relevant to the show today is that one on January 1st 2015 New York City at least Passed a law where you cannot throw any of the following things away in the garbage TVs monitors computers laptops small servers printers scanners tablets e-readers mp3 players mice keyboards Video game consoles VCR.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so people don't might not know this but like when I lived in the burbs we had private trash pickup.
Speaker 0: You had that's cuz.
Speaker 1: you lived in a fucked up place.
Speaker 0: You had to pay a private.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of place every time I know and I think those places are all fucked up.
Speaker 1: You know trash is the only way to go.
Speaker 0: I think it's most places in the US but basically you had to pay Somebody who owned a dump truck to come to your house Pick up your trash and then take it to the public dump or disposal place for you Cuz or you could do it yourself if you really wanted to like, you know Use your own truck to bring your trash to the the transfer station or wherever it is, you know You could do that.
Speaker 0: You didn't have to pay someone to do it.
Speaker 0: But there was no town owned dump truck that would come and pick up trash for you.
Speaker 0: in New York City You had the Department of Sanitation which cleans the streets comes and gets the trash pretty much takes care of everything And your taxes pay for it.
Speaker 0: so they can have a law like this because there isn't some private company That's gonna say yeah, I'll take your TV.
Speaker 0: They come into the side of the street and they see a TV sitting there and they say fuck No, and they put a sticker on it.
Speaker 0: And if it's still there you get a fine and you know, you get in trouble.
Speaker 0: So You know because we have this public Department of Sanitation we have laws like this.
Speaker 0: No What you can and cannot throw away.
Speaker 1: it got more complicated because you know complex CFLs replaced incandescent bulbs.
Speaker 0: They got mercury in them shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and now we got LEDs that I'm glad it were short-lived.
Speaker 1: No, I can tell you're kind of oh, it's.
Speaker 1: it seems like it's legal to just throw them away.
Speaker 1: It's just discouraged.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it depends on like where you are.
Speaker 1: I don't throw them away.
Speaker 1: no, even though theoretically residential buildings in New York have to handle that shit.
Speaker 1: like I Took our printer because I could I went to the thing with the e-waste recycling thing and I took all our like.
Speaker 1: all our see.
Speaker 0: If I went I took a lot of stuff there.
Speaker 0: It's like empty propane cans and CFLs.
Speaker 1: Well, I took a backpack filled to the brim with old batteries and CFLs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but It's a lead at his last battery over there.
Speaker 1: I took a lead as a battery over there the one that was in my files.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I took the one that was used to be in my UPS.
Speaker 0: that broke open.
Speaker 1: Oh, I forgot to take the fucking UPS UPS under here.
Speaker 1: my computer's plugged into it, but the battery has been dead for two years.
Speaker 1: I just haven't Extricated.
Speaker 0: I bought a replacement battery for my UPS and Amazon and it's only had to take the battery over there.
Speaker 1: I don't care anymore because I've.
Speaker 1: we've never had a power outage since I moved in.
Speaker 0: Your line has clicked frequently Really yeah, I mean over the years it is never happened.
Speaker 1: in this apart It never even went.
Speaker 0: click click whenever.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've heard it go click click even though the power is still just fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've never had that happen.
Speaker 1: It's also good to have you know, yeah I just don't care anymore because one in the modern era.
Speaker 0: I mean the battery caused less than like 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I'm really gonna buy a $20 power strip.
Speaker 1: I mean what you know, well, I mean I buy like the cheap one.
Speaker 1: I have enough power strips last me my entire life at this point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: but So basically even though I can throw those things away I don't.
Speaker 1: because even if there is theoretically a chain of custody where all the people in that chain will Treat them with the proper respect.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure they'll just get broken open and mercury gets everywhere.
Speaker 1: and I guess I'm a good person.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's another thing in New York.
Speaker 0: Is it any place where you're in a large building?
Speaker 1: right if you're in, you know your large Residential building or even a commercial building most commercial buildings seem to just fucking ignore this.
Speaker 0: What I'm saying is that if you live in your own house and you bring your own trash to the curb if there's any Separation required you're taking care of it, right?
Speaker 0: But if you're in a building It's up to the like.
Speaker 0: the building can just fuck you over.
Speaker 0: You could be spending hours like separating your recycling and separating your paper from your plastic and set me know and then your building I'll just dumps it in the same place.
Speaker 0: because they don't give a shit You know, at least are lazy.
Speaker 1: because one thing is then this is like more in recycling But in general the right way to go is to have the single stream recycling where the recycling stream itself Like downstream from you will separate so you don't have to.
Speaker 1: yeah Because then more people are willing to recycle like in New York.
Speaker 1: They tell you put all plastics in the recycling.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even if they're not recyclable because and I think in New York you can actually recycle all plastics.
Speaker 1: Well, so the secret is a lot of those individual plastics get separated and still landfilled.
Speaker 1: the reason they're separated is that if the technology gets better or if Demand for those plastics changes to make it economically viable instead of telling everyone Okay, now you can recycle number nine, but not number seven.
Speaker 1: They can just they don't have to tell you shit.
Speaker 1: All they do is take the number nine that was going in the garbage and just redirect it at the facilities into the stream.
Speaker 1: Mmm, so like it's a great thing, but my building Handles all the separation of all the other stuff downstairs.
Speaker 1: I see him doing it.
Speaker 1: So I just take all our recyclables in a box to throw it down there and there's someone whose job it is every week to Separate everything out and deal with it.
Speaker 0: I take all my trash and I throw it down the hole and I take anything that's not trash and I separate it and put On the floor in the trash room.
Speaker 1: Oh, we're not allowed to put stuff in the trash room.
Speaker 1: I gotta take it down.
Speaker 0: specifically says like if it's glass if it's recyclable if it's like smelly food Don't throw it down the hole Just put it on the floor in the trash room and then someone will take care of.
Speaker 1: smelly food specifically goes down the hole.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, but the thing is is that I've seen at least once a piece of paper by the front door That was a fine from the sanitation department.
Speaker 0: that said hey you put something that was recyclable in the trash.
Speaker 0: You're getting a fine.
Speaker 0: so I don't know if somebody Tossed paper down the hole or something.
Speaker 1: the only cardboard I throw down the hole because you're not supposed to is Grease-soaked pizza boxes because that's not recyclable.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but it lit off though.
Speaker 0: That's not grease.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah usually is.
Speaker 1: But the other side piece of this is that or every time I build a computer as almost everyone does You get all your components and you get a bunch of extra shit mostly with your case or your motherboard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you get screws you get this parts that you take off like you take off something.
Speaker 0: Maybe you don't have an optical drive anymore, but you used to take off a piece of plastic from the front.
Speaker 0: It's the optical drive could stick out.
Speaker 1: You used to take off like you put your video card.
Speaker 1: you take those little metal shields off the back and in the CI slots Like in the days when you would buy cards for extra functionality, which really don't do anymore except video.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's all sorts of extra cables.
Speaker 0: You don't use like.
Speaker 0: you get 10 sat cables and only use two.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you got a fancy case, it's got like different cages to hold different kinds of drives.
Speaker 0: Evil ties is all those extra bits that don't actually end up in the computer.
Speaker 0: and You know you throw most of it away or recycle most of it But there's still leftover bits that it's like I got to keep these screws.
Speaker 0: What if one day I got to add a PCI card to this computer?
Speaker 0: or what if one day I got a?
Speaker 0: you know?
Speaker 0: Do something here.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna need these screws and you keep them somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yep So I would.
Speaker 1: I have a motherboard box from every computer I've ever built pretty much worth of because I always put in the motherboard Box, it's just like because that's the empty box.
Speaker 1: I happen to have laying there.
Speaker 1: I put all that stuff in a box.
Speaker 0: I have a drawer in my little stack of drawers, but then that stuff.
Speaker 1: the next time I build a computer I take the previous box and I open it and I have it sitting next to me while I'm building the new computer cuz like Hey, maybe I need a part.
Speaker 1: Yeah in my whole life Other than SATA and PETA cables.
Speaker 1: I don't think I have ever Take it apart from that box and used it ever.
Speaker 0: so there's two reasons that you know, I've used stuff from there right.
Speaker 0: number one is I'm doing some upgrade.
Speaker 0: I wish I had it.
Speaker 0: So why I upgraded like the video card in my current desktop?
Speaker 0: Uh, it was a current one or the previous.
Speaker 0: I upgraded a video card at one point and boy was I glad to have that stuff still there not thrown out.
Speaker 0: and two sometimes you need give someone a computer and You know, they're gonna rejigger that whole computer a lot.
Speaker 0: maybe they're gonna mount some drives or unmount some drives and they will be very happy to have the screws that go with that case and The plastic bits that go with that case and the mounting equipment that goes with that case.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they'll be very sad to not have it like.
Speaker 0: wow I want to add a hard drive to this computer But I can't get Scott throughout all the rails that he wasn't using.
Speaker 1: but I decided because I've never used this stuff anymore.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do a purge and when I build my new computer, I'm going to dispose of Every single computer building component that I have that is not used in that new computer.
Speaker 0: I'd keep some.
Speaker 1: all I'm gonna keep is a handful of SATA cables.
Speaker 0: Don't come asking for anything from me.
Speaker 1: I'm confident based on my entire life experience that I will never need anything.
Speaker 0: You'll buy a hard drive You'll want to mount it.
Speaker 0: You won't have a mounting bracket.
Speaker 1: So I be so I'm doing something different with my new computer, too One.
Speaker 1: it's a new computer.
Speaker 1: So it has its own mounting stuff.
Speaker 1: So the case is gonna come with like all the mounting stuff I'll ever need.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna keep the stuff from the new case and throw away everything old.
Speaker 0: What if someone wants to mount something in that old computer?
Speaker 1: I just don't care.
Speaker 1: Also, there's like six hard drives in that computer so you've already got enough stuff in there.
Speaker 0: My new HD PC is great by the way, and the case is even smaller and it's so much faster.
Speaker 0: It's like the best computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my HD PC is like early 2009 circa and it's like a core i3.
Speaker 0: It's really the only thing keeping my current HD PC from being like the best desktop in the universe is that I didn't.
Speaker 0: it only has two RAM slots, so I couldn't load it up to all the way and It can't hold really that many hard drives at all.
Speaker 0: It has like one tiny hard drive.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: So but other than that, it's like incredible.
Speaker 0: It's like it's an i5 or the 1070s.
Speaker 0: So it's great.
Speaker 1: So what I'm very seven years out if these kbla I think I mentioned this if the kbla chips perform as well as people said they are for video.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna get like a Tiny HDPC like one of those little baby Specially built like super tiny computers that has just like and I'm not to drive sticking it into RAM No video card at all.
Speaker 1: No video card at all.
Speaker 1: I don't trust I can play a lot of games on my 2009 era laptop But I'm having a 1070 on.
Speaker 0: the HD PC is so great because like I can play every game Full frames at 1080 with max settings.
Speaker 0: No problem.
Speaker 0: So the other and if I get a 4k TV and like a couple years when they're not bullshit when there's no when there's A reason to have them.
Speaker 0: It'll still be great.
Speaker 1: So what'd you do with the old HDPC?
Speaker 1: because I guess that's the topic of the show cuz I got a debate.
Speaker 0: What is the topic of the show?
Speaker 0: and you know what that is a perfectly good computer.
Speaker 0: It is a is an i3.
Speaker 0: It's not like four gigs of RAM, which isn't as much but I think you could put more in there.
Speaker 0: It's you know, it's got a hard of one terabyte magnetic hard drive Which you could should probably replace in the SSD because it's really slow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it works.
Speaker 0: and it's got an old low-profile ATI video card Which can actually play some games at decent frame rates.
Speaker 0: It just has some trouble with newer things or putting on high settings.
Speaker 0: as long as you keep your settings low Or your resolution low or your frame rates low or your games old.
Speaker 0: It's just fine.
Speaker 1: But do you have a plan?
Speaker 1: What are you gonna do with it?
Speaker 1: plays in there?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just sitting there looking for a home.
Speaker 1: So I think this is a relatively new problem because I realized I was thinking about this in my whole life.
Speaker 0: Maybe I can find a place to donate it.
Speaker 0: Does anyone like know where to donate working computers?
Speaker 1: because I was you know Because I would die wasn't rich.
Speaker 0: thing is the case is actually, you know, it's a really nice, you know HTPC case.
Speaker 0: there's nothing wrong with it.
Speaker 1: It's like worth a lot actually, but computers used to be a lot more unreliable and components would fail a lot more off.
Speaker 0: That's because we were buying AMD computers in that era.
Speaker 0: But also just like Intel computers I've had have always been super reliable.
Speaker 1: But for most of my life I generally only started speccing out and then building a new computer when the old one was dying or dead.
Speaker 1: But nowadays I have to upgrade the computer I'm using because it's not fast enough.
Speaker 1: same with the HTPC.
Speaker 1: same with my laptop.
Speaker 1: Yeah only after six or seven years though Yeah but now I have all these computers like a lot of them that I'm gonna basically have nothing to do with that are 100% fine and they're actually pretty fast.
Speaker 1: They're just not fast enough for me and I'm not sure what to do with like this computer.
Speaker 0: If you're a person who needs an HTPC and you are just gonna watch video Like you're not even gonna play any serious games or you're only gonna play like nice 2d games It could be your desktop.
Speaker 0: You could even play.
Speaker 0: it could be like it could be a great desktop.
Speaker 0: It could be like your ultimate the ultimate HTPC for so many people.
Speaker 0: But just for me, it just.
Speaker 0: I couldn't put a better video card in it because it's a low-profile case.
Speaker 0: Yep, so I replaced it, but it's perfectly awesome for anyone else.
Speaker 1: So in the old old old days if I had a working computer, I always had all these projects.
Speaker 1: So I would immediately turn it into a server of some kind.
Speaker 0: also, you need a Windows license.
Speaker 0: cuz I erased it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna erase it but I would always put like any computer I had that was spare was like, holy shit I have a spare computer.
Speaker 1: What am I gonna do with it?
Speaker 1: And I would just like install software on it and like run the servers on it.
Speaker 1: I just run a counter-strike server Now I just don't bother games don't need that anymore.
Speaker 1: Everything's online and easy.
Speaker 1: Like there's like.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna host a server on files here in the apart.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think an RIT my old computer became a web server and then in beacon the old computer became HTPC and another old computer became DNS DHCP Yep, and yet another old computer was a counter-strike server that I ran for a while that no one use.
Speaker 0: It's like we kept doing stuff with old computers.
Speaker 0: But now I only need two PCs the desktop and the HTPC.
Speaker 0: I don't need any more.
Speaker 1: Yeah and what's interesting is all the other technology because you know in general like like I have all these electronics that are 100% functional and that I use occasionally.
Speaker 1: but I've bought better versions of like.
Speaker 1: we have these fancy microphones.
Speaker 1: we bought right.
Speaker 1: We bought them to upgrade from the old.
Speaker 1: good, but now we have money and we know what we're doing.
Speaker 1: We're getting better microphones microphones those old microphones.
Speaker 1: The sm57s are fine.
Speaker 1: They're literally as good as they were when we bought them.
Speaker 0: We just don't use them Good use them as someone comes over to record.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we need them.
Speaker 0: What about the Radio Shack ones?
Speaker 1: Those I think I just threw away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're so wasteful.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those those were terrible microphones.
Speaker 1: like they were not worth any amount of money.
Speaker 1: in retrospect We were better off with the Logitech.
Speaker 1: because I've listened to the old geek nights I've been remastering them.
Speaker 1: those Radio Shack microphones were worse than the Logitech stick mic because they cost any amount of money and they weren't better.
Speaker 1: But like all the mixers we've gone through a bunch of mixers and I gave away.
Speaker 1: every time we upgraded the geek nights mixer I gave away the previous mixer to someone and They used it.
Speaker 1: as far as I can tell I hope they used it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in fact, I gave the old the last analog mixer the giant one that we used to bring to conventions.
Speaker 1: I gave that to one of our old doorman.
Speaker 1: He's like an aspiring DJ.
Speaker 1: I was like, hey you want this giant mixer?
Speaker 1: and he was like, fuck.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right, go for it, dude.
Speaker 0: So he'll saw it on Craigslist or something.
Speaker 1: I think he was using it.
Speaker 1: I think he wanted to use it.
Speaker 1: good But most of the tech I have seems worthless.
Speaker 1: that even though it's perfectly functional.
Speaker 1: most of it No one would want and I can't come up with good ways to get rid of it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I don't know what to do about that.
Speaker 0: You go on the old list of Craig.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's Facebook just launched a Craigslist competitor today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I'm thinking maybe I'll use that right.
Speaker 0: So actually this happened.
Speaker 1: we could do the geek nights Luke, right?
Speaker 0: So this happened to me today, right?
Speaker 0: So I'm not a big fan of worst buy or the store that is not the best buy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, but I'm trying to get rid of my iPhone 6 cuz I just got the iPhone 7, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just talked about the beginning the show.
Speaker 0: So, you know I could sell it on Craigslist or eBay or something.
Speaker 0: It's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: and this places you can do it online.
Speaker 0: Amazon will give you a gift card, right?
Speaker 0: This website giselle.com and there's some other ones.
Speaker 0: be like mail them your phone.
Speaker 0: They evaluate it They give you a quote you either accept it or they send you your phone back.
Speaker 0: It's a pain in the ass, too.
Speaker 0: so Best Buy apparently You can bring your phone in they'll look at it in the store and give you a gift card.
Speaker 0: and I'm like Well, you know while I don't like worst buy that's really fucking convenient.
Speaker 0: It's right near my work and The GoPro Hero 5 is out and I'm buying one high up.
Speaker 0: So they've got it.
Speaker 0: They've got it in the store today.
Speaker 0: Actually, I'm like, well, they give me the gift card.
Speaker 0: I can just buy it right here.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'd rather buy it on Amazon, but hey, right?
Speaker 0: Why the fuck not?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know turn my iPhone 6 into a GoPro shade something.
Speaker 0: I don't need any more for something.
Speaker 0: I do need great deal.
Speaker 0: What do I care?
Speaker 0: So I was surprised by a great many things at the worst buy.
Speaker 1: Well, I've not been inside a Best Buy in More than five years.
Speaker 0: Yes So the first thing I was very surprised by is that the staff in the cell phone area of the worst buy Were Scarily knowledgeable about phones particularly this this the girl who was like taking care of me.
Speaker 0: It's like everyone kept coming to ask her shit.
Speaker 0: Like this dude was like, hey, is there like a 4g phone?
Speaker 0: that's like less than $100.
Speaker 0: like does this one come in red?
Speaker 0: and like she just knew everything about like every phone ever and She was there.
Speaker 0: and then so after she evaluates my phone for a bit.
Speaker 0: She's like, alright Best Buy is gonna give you like 70 bucks for this and I'm like, that's not so great But it's a not a hassle.
Speaker 1: you took it didn't ya know?
Speaker 0: I was thinking about taking it and then she was like listen Don't take it.
Speaker 1: She like I'll give you 80 bucks for it.
Speaker 0: No, she's like.
Speaker 0: she's like, you know The screen has some scratches on.
Speaker 0: I'm like, yeah, cuz it was my phone for two years.
Speaker 0: It's not a perfect screen It's you know got normal wear and tear on it.
Speaker 0: What's the problem?
Speaker 0: You know, what are you expecting?
Speaker 0: brand new shiny phones from two?
Speaker 0: Years ago, but she's like.
Speaker 0: you could just sell this like anywhere and get way more money for it.
Speaker 0: But I'm like, that's such a pain in the ass, though And she's like, all right Look just go somewhere else and if you really if it's too much of a pain in the ass come back and I'll give you the $75.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the other dude standing next to her was like seriously go use the Giselle calm Like.
Speaker 0: I'm like really?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: It's like they really didn't.
Speaker 0: They were really looking out for the customer and not looking out for Best Buy at all in the cell phone department.
Speaker 1: Well They're not getting paid that much.
Speaker 0: No, but I'm saying is like look it was a real.
Speaker 0: It's a real hassle to get rid of this fucking phone.
Speaker 0: So I did the Amazon thing.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna mail it to Amazon and I checked the box that said listen Amazon if you're gonna give me less money for it Don't give me money.
Speaker 0: Just send it back.
Speaker 0: But hopefully they'll give me Amazon credit for it and it supposedly will be like 200 something dollars.
Speaker 1: So interestingly if they like the phone up until my Nexus 5 Every smartphone I've ever had I replaced it because it broke to the point that it was unusable.
Speaker 0: I wonder how that happened.
Speaker 1: also because you bought not iPhones or Because I Upgraded because the old phone was literally completely obsolete like my palm free or my Nexus S?
Speaker 0: Well all my previous iPhones I see the MA Nexus I think.
Speaker 0: I think I handed down my 3g and my 4 and I what did?
Speaker 0: I think I handed down the 5 to someone Else.
Speaker 1: I gave my Nexus 5 to friends.
Speaker 1: My Nexus 4 I also gave to a friend.
Speaker 1: even though the screens broken the phone works.
Speaker 0: So guys I basically handed down.
Speaker 0: I've only had this is only my fourth iPhone 3g 4 5 6 7 1 2 3 4 5 6.
Speaker 0: This is my fifth iPhone.
Speaker 0: So I've gotten rid of four phones.
Speaker 0: So like my next I think I handed down 3 and did something else.
Speaker 0: at the other one My Nexus S was low.
Speaker 0: No, I handed down 3 and I've got the fourth one.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to get rid of it.
Speaker 1: My Nexus S was both locked to sprint and CDMA only as it was literally worthless.
Speaker 1: my palm free.
Speaker 1: So it sucks.
Speaker 1: But unless you root it Which is a giant pain in the ass Even though that would be a perfectly fine like remote control like it has Wi-Fi like you just use it You can't activate it without connecting to servers that don't exist anymore.
Speaker 1: So unless I root it and I went online and all the ways to root a palm free Involve using shady ass software that if you install that on a computer I think you're a moron you can start in a virtual machine.
Speaker 0: even then Spare computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have a spare computer you could use for such things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, would you like it?
Speaker 1: I don't care enough Me either.
Speaker 0: That's why I just want to get rid of this shit Even.
Speaker 1: I guess the moral is all the all the non like all the technology.
Speaker 1: I have computers and other things.
Speaker 1: I pretty much almost always just give away things that work to friends who have worse things or I throw away And there's pretty much nothing else I do with old technology I get I need.
Speaker 0: there needs to be something better to do with it there because they like this You know Even though if I can't find the friends that need it There's people that need it as someone out there who can make a ton of use out of the HDVC and I just can't find Them and it's too much of a hassle to find them.
Speaker 1: Yeah especially because I remember we were trying to give stuff away in Craigslist, you know a long time ago and like People would email you and just like never respond when you're like, yeah, you can have it just come pick it up.
Speaker 1: Here's your day.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's not easy to get rid of stuff.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to get rid of stuff.
Speaker 0: So Sign up for the geek night's crate.
Speaker 1: I guess You know.
Speaker 0: and the other thing is I'm a ship it to someone.
Speaker 0: the shipping cost is so high because it's big and heavy.
Speaker 1: So that was the thing.
Speaker 1: that was the experiment I did.
Speaker 1: so we had an old pride bought a new.
Speaker 1: we have a real color Laser printer now like a for real one up there like looming over me on the desk And the old printer barely worked and had a lot of problems.
Speaker 1: I was gonna throw it away.
Speaker 1: I wasn't gonna carry it on my bike to the Disposal amnesty thing so I put it downstairs with a regular garbage because our building theoretically will just handle it As an experiment to see if it remained there.
Speaker 1: if they brought it still there, isn't it?
Speaker 1: If they brought it maybe they would bring it back up because it was in a box that our apartment number on it Like.
Speaker 1: maybe they'd bring it up be like, yeah, you can't throw this away.
Speaker 1: I was just curious what would happen to it.
Speaker 1: So what do you think happened to it?
Speaker 0: It's still there.
Speaker 1: No, it's gone.
Speaker 1: Okay, and pretty sure they did it the right way.
Speaker 1: so Mm-hmm Apparently buildings can sign up for a thing where the city will take the eways and deal with it And big apartment buildings seem to just do it because people like us move into them and throw away technology all the time.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Was really happy though because when I went to that end that like throw away your eways.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is a safe disposal event And what they do is they send everyone a piece of paper in the mail.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it says on this this is the day and this is the place to bring your shit.
Speaker 0: Here's the shit you can bring.
Speaker 0: is the shit you can't bring?
Speaker 0: you can do it year-round if you go to like these places But they're way out of the way comes to your neighborhood like once or twice a year, right?
Speaker 0: So I walked over there with my stuff in a bag and just handed it to them and walked away.
Speaker 0: But there was a line of cars down the street.
Speaker 0: Yeah That was with cones and there was a whole teams of people sorting everything like the people I interacted with were real pro.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like.
Speaker 1: he's like so much you got and I was like a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 1: He's like, alright, let's go one by one.
Speaker 1: I was like got a bunch of CFLs and he's like, alright, we'll take those and he took it.
Speaker 0: They didn't even ask me.
Speaker 0: they were just like what you got.
Speaker 0: Alright, see you.
Speaker 0: You're good.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, okay.
Speaker 1: So if someone came up next to me and they were like, so I got a bunch of scrap steel and a Bunch of paint and he was like, alright, I'll deal with the pain Wait here and we're gonna get a got it and they like did a thing.
Speaker 1: But they didn't check IDs of anyone who walked up or biked up and they were very thoroughly Checking the IDs of everyone who drove up.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: Yeah interesting Cuz I went around like I took some pictures like checking it out.
Speaker 1: the line of cars coming into this thing was crazy long.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz they bet it's so hard to get rid of your shit and they have an event like hey everyone all that shit You normally can't get rid of it for free.
Speaker 0: We're just gonna take it off your hands for free.
Speaker 0: All you have to do is bring it to this place.
Speaker 0: and this time you were a resident of New York City and it's like everyone Is like holy shit gotta bring my garbage.
Speaker 1: I saw him turn it away the fuck out of my house with Connecticut plates.
Speaker 1: cuz I stood there.
Speaker 1: really Yeah, Joe from Connecticut to his story drove in that a Connecticut plate and there's a dude and looked like his wife and he had all these pink hands in the Car.
Speaker 0: and but in Connecticut like, you know, my family's in Connecticut There's a transfer station that is open Every fucking day and you can go there everything for free or that there's some things you have to pay.
Speaker 0: We never had to pay when we went there.
Speaker 1: There's a transfer station.
Speaker 1: I remember in upstate New York There was a limit on how much you could bring to them.
Speaker 0: So the transfer station is actually really fun to go to because they have this gigantic trash compactor.
Speaker 0: It looks like something it would be like in a movie at the end like
Speaker 1: at the end of the Brave Little Toaster
Speaker 0: or something We throw the Terminator into it to squish him Yeah, and you can just go over to it and throw your shit right over the edge and then watch it get crushed.
Speaker 0: But certain things you can't throw in there.
Speaker 0: so there's like for example They have a whole shipping container and the shipping container is where you put your computers and your TVs and all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: No, you can go in there and there's mad loot in there.
Speaker 0: We went in there and sure there was like a bunch of old compacts and monitors and CR mostly CRT's.
Speaker 0: But I found like a whole box full of like mad old 90s software and it was like I was like, oh shit CD roms is like there's.
Speaker 0: you can go there and get good shit if you just want.
Speaker 1: You know 90s computer shit You know, I think it might have changed because I remember think there were a bunch of charities like just growing up High fighter on CD roms.
Speaker 1: I remember there are all these charities that would ostensibly take your computer stuff and then like yeah There is a place that does that.
Speaker 0: I have no idea where it is.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it's not in New York.
Speaker 0: It's hard to find it's hard to get your shit, but they would then donate it to like schools and things.
Speaker 1: But I remember the result is that most of those got shut down Because they were basically scams where they would give schools garbage shit old broken computers at least one That wasn't a scam.
Speaker 0: and I remember because I watched the whole video about them and they were smart people like us who were Volunteering in their spare time like taking the good parts out of broken computers and come recombining them to make working computers.
Speaker 1: I think it's time for.
Speaker 1: and they were not selling them for a profit because because specifically we've hit this area For like six years now where computers aren't getting that much faster, and they're basically super durable and invincible.
Speaker 0: I think what's happening is everyone's getting rid of their computers replacing them with phones and tablets and not getting computers.
Speaker 0: So now basically is can everyone but gamers and people have to do real work are getting rid of computers.
Speaker 0: And there's a bunch of free computers out there That could use homes.
Speaker 1: Yep, and I feel like you could put those in schools and do a lot of good Or you could put them in a giant supercomputer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well you can make a bail of cluster.
Speaker 0: I don't think that's the 1996 called.
Speaker 0: It's called Hadoop.
Speaker 1: now This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one, but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek knives in order the amount of money They give us on a continuing basis are Ellen Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette Christian Koontz construction noises Ivy Faye mystady.com Sean Hayworth William Eisen rose Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: James David White Rochelle Montanona Superboy old man Scott is old man.
Speaker 1: Aaron Cerise Brian Fisher sailor vista Jai fried pork Matthew Smith Don Schleich chartavish and Joe sure.
Speaker 1: Joe star Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent or open lender Rerla Val Brian said Roni Finn Eric Silverado the rural juror Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: So as you noticed I am reading the novelization of Castlevania 2 Simon's Quest Created by F dot X dot 9 as part of the world of power series.
Speaker 1: It is a it's quite a special book and I'm reading it to all of the patrons as an audiobook because that's just the kind of thing I'm doing pretty sure in this third chapter that I don't know if it was just a Sex scene from a fanfic and they changed the proper nouns.
Speaker 1: I don't know how this came to be.
Speaker 1: Maybe the guy was trying to be funny and like push the edge or whatever, but pretty sure Timothy Bradley had an orgasm After touching Simon's whip like I don't know how else to read that.
Speaker 1: I really don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean, let's see This is the line.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna read this from this is not me reading the book as I am for the audiobook.
Speaker 1: This is me reading it right now after just recorded this episode of Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Blah blah, where'd you like to go?
Speaker 1: Well, come grab my whip Timothy Bradley.
Speaker 1: Well, it was worth the shot thought Tim anything?
Speaker 1: get away from that walking dynamite truck with biceps in the very least blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: He reached out and grabbed the leather whip.
Speaker 1: it felt as though he'd grabbed a live wire.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he said.
Speaker 1: he felt his hair stand on end.
Speaker 1: energy coursed full throttle through his body.
Speaker 1: a burst Of light zapped through his eyes.
Speaker 1: then everything became a pleasant calm after the silent bang.
Speaker 1: You really shouldn't play around with shocks.
Speaker 1: He told Simon you can electrocute a guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this all takes place in a high school boys room, and I'm pretty sure it was describing an orgasm.
Speaker 1: But anyway now I leave you with something that tastes so good.
Speaker 1: I love the taste of milk max.
Speaker 1: It's a great taste Which is why for the pleasure of a tall tasty glass I do almost anything For the smooth cool goodness of milk.
Speaker 1: I fly to the farthest galaxy for the cold refreshing taste of milk.
Speaker 1: I crawl through the burning wasteland for one satisfying.
Speaker 1: Yummy gulp of milk.
Speaker 1: I'd stretch myself to the limits.
Speaker 1: I do homework.
Speaker 0: max Wow milk.
Speaker 1: it tastes so good.