Speaker 0: It's Monday June 13th 2016.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight talking to your computer.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So you know there are certain things that like become like personal Traditions like something you do every year or something you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got a few of those things.
Speaker 1: you got a few of those things.
Speaker 1: like it's like your thing And you always do it.
Speaker 0: like every year around Emily's birthday We go for some sort of like crazy hike or some sort of like outdoor adventure, okay, so For the past.
Speaker 1: I don't know how many years right either by chance or by intention I have gone to the Big Apple barbecue in Madison Square Park, but this year for so whatever reason It was this weekend, and I don't know about it until it was too late.
Speaker 0: Oh, you don't regather missed enough.
Speaker 0: you missed Christmas.
Speaker 1: I read it and that's where I found out that it happened and they posted after it was already happening.
Speaker 1: Where were you during the week?
Speaker 0: I?
Speaker 1: Skipped it every year, but only because unless you get there early in the day That's what I used did I would bike there at the crack of dawn and eat like ribs and beans like 10 or 11 a.m.
Speaker 1: And like that there's one dude's beans have become like maybe my favorite food.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's that's the desert island food.
Speaker 1: It's a tough run between that and like salt and fat You know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so they have the menus all different now, but that it's always all different.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that scallop is there of course is there and I thought I'd go back to ice cream.
Speaker 0: Uh the ice cream is not going yet next month.
Speaker 0: the ice cream is back.
Speaker 1: I'm going next month then.
Speaker 0: but instead they I got that panna cotta that I never get.
Speaker 0: no I don't know.
Speaker 0: so you know what's under that panna cotta?
Speaker 0: like a half-inch thick sponge cake made primarily with olive oil.
Speaker 1: Okay, holy shit.
Speaker 0: was that probably really bad for me?
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I totally missed it, but the guy who owns the John Brown place is oh that place is the one that's right here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's open a new place in Astoria, so I mean that place is crazy good food especially cornbread.
Speaker 1: Oh my so that doesn't run out of food or have bad Here's here.
Speaker 0: There's two problems in my life right now related to that place.
Speaker 0: one It's right next to the climbing gym that we go to.
Speaker 0: If I walk out of the climbing gym, it's real tempting.
Speaker 0: So think about this.
Speaker 0: you're exercising for like an hour like climbing up while you're hungry, and then you smell Barbecue fucking good barbecue like legit.
Speaker 1: I would just get a cornbread only if I want to hurt.
Speaker 1: You know, I can't eat barbecue that often no matter how much our body wants to also.
Speaker 0: But there's a far more insidious problem.
Speaker 0: when I bike to work my path goes past that place really Wouldn't you?
Speaker 1: just?
Speaker 1: I mean it's going down that street You're not just it shouldn't?
Speaker 1: it usually would be just off to the left.
Speaker 0: no so the going down Vernon.
Speaker 0: The fastest way to get to the Pulaski is to go and then turn right on that Street I think it's 44th and then get on Vernon.
Speaker 0: Yeah And then turn left.
Speaker 1: I would turn right and go alongside the bridge get on Vernon then turn left.
Speaker 0: So there's a shorter way if you just go under the seven train the whole way.
Speaker 0: But there isn't bike lane through a chunk of that and that is like the most agro driver place in Queens.
Speaker 1: I mean if I was going from here what I would do is I would just cut through that Not a road next to the project.
Speaker 0: No, that's too far out of the way.
Speaker 1: That's when they go south on Vernon.
Speaker 0: No, you're better off doing the ant.
Speaker 0: cuz if you go that and that bike path goes straight into the Pulaski.
Speaker 0: Otherwise you've gone out of your way cuz you're coming back from that road later.
Speaker 1: I'm going right and then I'm going south.
Speaker 1: It's not like I'm going north.
Speaker 0: it adds Not insignificant distance whatever.
Speaker 0: I mean I track my rides pretty closely like I know the absolute fastest possible.
Speaker 1: I'm also not in a big hurry to go to work.
Speaker 0: The problem is a real barbecue place.
Speaker 0: They start making the barbecue early in the morning.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it takes all fucking day.
Speaker 1: So The smell is why they run out of food.
Speaker 0: because they didn't put enough in in the morning is perhaps peaking Just as I would buy pest it every morning.
Speaker 0: the smell of barbecue on that street is so powerful That I'll be thinking about it all day.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That's why they run out of food.
Speaker 0: Yes, you know what I did.
Speaker 0: instead and instead of doing the barbecue thing I just like ran 11 miles.
Speaker 1: Hey, hey You want to go eat there right after we're done with this show?
Speaker 1: Actually, I have three blue aprons and I've cooked.
Speaker 1: I got them on Saturday and I've cooked zero of them.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, we have a blue apron I think coming today.
Speaker 0: So we should probably cook that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if it doesn't come to we always have a rule.
Speaker 0: we always.
Speaker 0: you know It's like Matt Cawthon in a Wheel of Time leave it up to chance.
Speaker 0: We'll say things like if the blue apron arrives by the time we're ready to eat then we'll cook it.
Speaker 0: But if it doesn't That's okay.
Speaker 1: The weather was good.
Speaker 1: I went to the park went to a big shop a lot of stuff going on in the city lately actually.
Speaker 0: So I kind of lost track.
Speaker 0: There's several events that I saw and thought I should go to that and then I went to some other event.
Speaker 1: I actually actually worked on a shit talk project a lot of Saturday.
Speaker 0: I worked on one too.
Speaker 0: All right I remember how I said I'm gonna make those that chicken surprise shirt and all the fast food franchise themed t-shirts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you worked on that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the problem is there are Zero high-resolution scans of the actual art.
Speaker 1: Well, we have.
Speaker 1: you were in a game.
Speaker 1: we can just do it ourselves.
Speaker 0: It's very hard to get the game.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna base I've got has it.
Speaker 0: so I'm going to see if Chris will get a will scan.
Speaker 0: if he doesn't I want a scanner.
Speaker 0: I'll just buy him one because they're like $10 and I have actually a way good scanner.
Speaker 1: now because It can.
Speaker 1: I needed one that could scan film negative.
Speaker 0: We have a good scanner, but it's for like big art.
Speaker 0: It's not for like little tiny film things.
Speaker 1: I only use it for films but it can also scan.
Speaker 0: it can also scan paper because a big old flatbed thing, but That I looked at some tentative designs for how the shirt would look and it looks real good.
Speaker 0: So this is definitely gonna happen.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna make a few just so I can buy them myself.
Speaker 1: Hope the guy who made the game doesn't come after you.
Speaker 0: Well, no So you can make a shirt and not make it public so I could just buy it for myself Like miss print a high-quality t-shirt on demand.
Speaker 0: Okay, I can make a lot of shirts Like.
Speaker 0: I still know how I got this account because it looks like it's still invite only from Amazon.
Speaker 0: But if the shirts look good I'm gonna make one for me and I might give one to like Chris or Anthony just as a gift because I feel like that's Appropriate.
Speaker 0: and then the next step is I'm actually gonna try to reach out to the guy and be like look Can I have a licensing agreement to just make these shirts?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll sell them on Amazon.
Speaker 1: I'll give you like half the money Amazon gives me.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what do I give a shit?
Speaker 1: I'll give you all the money Amazon gives me or I'll even be like, you know what?
Speaker 1: I'll sell them at the value where no money comes out and these shirts just exist or I'll charge him at the price you want Them to be charged and give you all the money.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 0: yeah, cuz I just really like that Terrible like.
Speaker 0: there's something about the chicken surprise logo on a bright orange t-shirt that just it just did.
Speaker 0: it warms the cockles of my heart.
Speaker 0: Do you got any news?
Speaker 0: So I know this is a loaded question.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so six minutes before we did the show Dateline 6 p.m.
Speaker 0: 605 p.m.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 1: So we were already thinking earlier in the day man.
Speaker 1: What an easy news for Monday tech show.
Speaker 1: It's Apple Day.
Speaker 1: Thank you Apple for finally having your day on our Monday.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm sure it's happened before but usually it feels like Apple Day is always like the week before We do a Monday show or two weeks.
Speaker 1: We'll do a show on Monday and then Apple Day will be Wednesday and we won't come around again till the week and a half At least once to like we're.
Speaker 0: someone was out of town and we like couldn't do the show for a few weeks.
Speaker 1: There have definitely been cases though where Apple Day was on you guys day But today is one of those days again, and I thought oh what an easy day.
Speaker 1: all this Apple news, right?
Speaker 1: But no six minutes before we did the show an even bigger news appeared.
Speaker 1: that is not tech related, but doesn't matter It's too big to ignore and thankfully it happened before the show and not during the show.
Speaker 1: So we didn't ruin our show like stopping in the middle when someone was reading the internet and saw this news Which we probably would have like.
Speaker 0: there's very little breaking news.
Speaker 0: That is actually breaking news as far as geek nights is concerned.
Speaker 1: I was like this news is so big I had to be like rim.
Speaker 1: you guys sit down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm like Like it's really it's too big and I'm like this is too big.
Speaker 0: did copyright get reformed.
Speaker 1: No, it's not that big Not that big But this news is ginormous.
Speaker 1: You probably know it already unless I mean by the time you're listening to this, right?
Speaker 1: It's been hours already.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you know who we are.
Speaker 0: you can guess what we're about to talk about.
Speaker 1: So one of the most important people right the president, I don't know is he a CEO?
Speaker 1: was was CEO.
Speaker 1: I could look.
Speaker 1: I guess I gave up the whole news already.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna look up his LinkedIn profile and actual title was cuz.
Speaker 0: I didn't even Robert.
Speaker 1: I do not know his middle name.
Speaker 1: He might not even have one coup.
Speaker 1: My grandpa doesn't have a middle name has officially resigned as The person who was in charge of penny arcade.
Speaker 1: He was the president Sure One of the most important people who makes the shit happen that we care about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, he's used the Walt still is but he is still for until I guess mid-july the president of operations And business development.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm for penny arcade Inc.
Speaker 0: and the managing director of Child's Play.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I was.
Speaker 0: I Wonder if he will continue to run Child's Play.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure he's resigned from everything who's going to the beach.
Speaker 0: But I think that the thing specifically said leaving penny arcade, I don't know it didn't.
Speaker 1: I mean it wasn't detailed.
Speaker 0: right to be honest I know a lot of people who are managing directors of charities, which means they literally do nothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you have your name on it, right?
Speaker 1: So what does this mean?
Speaker 0: It's and again, we're not going to speculate on any weird stuff.
Speaker 1: We don't have any information.
Speaker 1: You don't have really.
Speaker 0: yeah Even if we did if we had information you didn't have.
Speaker 0: it's probably something we shouldn't share.
Speaker 1: People who paid money to be in Club PA which we're not in I think they got a Newsletter from him this morning or something and they know more than we do because we're not paying for that shit.
Speaker 1: Yep, and no one shared that online yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it looks like the the official pack site thing just says that in July 15th He's going to step down up.
Speaker 0: Yep from penny arcade and Child's Play.
Speaker 0: Okay, and That's all we know.
Speaker 0: So Generally when this sort of thing happens just in general You know crap.
Speaker 0: Oh basic business.
Speaker 0: There was a drama.
Speaker 1: There's either some sort of internal drama Reason like we're not doing so well lately out with the CEO.
Speaker 1: Let's put a new one in.
Speaker 0: I don't suspect the latter is what happened here And I don't even really suspect the farmers.
Speaker 0: what happened here?
Speaker 0: because penny arcade is a pretty just as an outside observer I mean, you never can know unless you're part of one of these things.
Speaker 0: It looks pretty tight Like I feel like there's enough family feeling and intimacy to where it was.
Speaker 1: I mean, it seems like their growth phase has and oh you mean drama.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think that was drama But it seems like their growth phase has ended and there's sort of been really like in this status quo of hovering and instability For a quite a while
Speaker 0: which is you know, when you look at it They were like a few
Speaker 1: years at least.
Speaker 1: how they pack south is already going into a third year.
Speaker 1: So they're like for the past two or three years.
Speaker 1: They just been sort of doing the same thing not really doing it.
Speaker 0: They hit this sort of like peak momentum where they started expanding paxes rapidly and not just taxes But like their other endeavors like they tried the strip search and they tried You know, I really like strip search, but I don't think that can make enough money.
Speaker 0: They're printing, you know, all kinds of tabletop games and they're you know, and while I love the idea of making tabletop games like that I don't think most of those games were that good or at least they weren't gonna be profitable enough.
Speaker 1: They made all.
Speaker 0: those are video games RPG ones.
Speaker 0: I own them all.
Speaker 0: I don't think I ever really played.
Speaker 0: them played.
Speaker 1: I beat the first one it even played the second one,
Speaker 0: but the in terms of paxes it's interesting because the two main paxes West and East and we'll get back to the fact that it's called West now because it's interesting that they pointedly changed the name to West Kind of ahead of all this.
Speaker 0: So I wonder if that was in a little planning phase.
Speaker 1: I don't think that has anything to do with them resigning No, but well it could in the sense of like.
Speaker 0: they're trying to align paxes to be their own thing and sort of consolidate I don't think.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll see because they've definitely been trying to get more people to go to the other paxes.
Speaker 0: But that's for sure as the world is shown.
Speaker 0: No, everyone wants to go to Pax Prime.
Speaker 0: All the other paxes are second-tier.
Speaker 1: Yeah, imagine if there was like San Diego Comic Con and there was another San Diego Comic Con.
Speaker 1: It's like no one.
Speaker 0: the Milwaukee Comic Con That's the same people and like 80% the same contact content, but it's in Milwaukee.
Speaker 0: Like would you go to Milwaukee?
Speaker 1: Apparently there was room for New York Comic Con, but there's room for East and West packs.
Speaker 1: Yeah I don't think there's room for more than two things in the u.s Cuz all you can do is hit the population center on the West and hit the population center on the East.
Speaker 0: Yeah Because based on the data that I've been able to get access to over the years my suspicion was sort of you too in Chicago Never got big packs.
Speaker 0: prop.
Speaker 0: ex-west seems to have mostly people who are local Or people who have money and just fly to it because it's the big packs and the whole game industry is there.
Speaker 0: Pax East seems to be mostly either game industry, especially East Coast game industry.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know, there's 50 to 70 million people within a short drive of Boston.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so
Speaker 0: everyone on the East Coast goes to that one or at least tries to because even if you can't afford to fly out west like That's within spitting distance
Speaker 1: pack south is like hardly any industry or the the mid-tier and lower industry who can't you know Like
Speaker 0: I'll put it this way This is this is the shocking truth.
Speaker 0: and locals if you die hards if you list it in order of like how much actual impact They have in the industry.
Speaker 0: everyone in the games industry or adjacent to it who goes to pack south in an official capacity We're in we're not in the bottom tenth of that list.
Speaker 0: We're in like the bottom ninth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like Like We're at the bottom of the list as opposed to not being on the list, right?
Speaker 0: But pack south is almost all locals like from Texas like not even from nearby states But like.
Speaker 0: they live in or near San Antonio and drive there for the day.
Speaker 0: Like and tax us is pretty much just people in Asia Pacific and crazy people like us who fly mostly Australians.
Speaker 1: I didn't see you know, how many like Chinese Japanese Philippines.
Speaker 0: I get the impression Just because I've been to I went to a. no I went to the next pack, you know the two packs ausses ago after when Scott didn't.
Speaker 0: you don't see a lot of Antarctic ins there and what you what I saw Was that the I suspect the demographic of people from Asia Pacific who go to packs Australia who are not from Australia?
Speaker 0: Is very close to the demographic of people from Asia Pacific who go to packs prime?
Speaker 0: That is my guess Based on the audience's based on interactions and even people from Western Australia don't go to the Eastern Australian bags.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is so big like it's Melbourne Sydney Brisbane get like that East Coast District and that seems to be the majority.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so packs is can't expand in terms of more packs is unless those packs is like.
Speaker 0: I Hate to say this, but if there were two packs is in Seattle and two packs is in Boston They'd probably bolt they'd probably all four sell out way more than packs south does.
Speaker 0: maybe that's my guess anyway.
Speaker 1: But yeah, Robert cool.
Speaker 1: What's gonna happen to packs?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because not for nothing but even at even as recently as the packs east we just went to like some shit went down like we're like with the Boston police nonsense where they were like scat like checking people's bags and crab like it was kind of a clusterfuck.
Speaker 0: and then we saw Physically Robert Coo walked over there and was looking at it and sort of like frowning and Then a tweet came out that was like we're dealing with this.
Speaker 1: and then it was dealt with and it was from his Twitter account not the penny arcade Twitter account.
Speaker 0: and
Speaker 1: also there was the time there was a hotel block and some packs people couldn't get in their hotel rooms and Because the Oakland Raiders came to town and the hotel gave the rooms to them instead and then Robert Coo Personally went to the hotel and fought with them and got the Oakland Raiders kicked out of the hotel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like sure even if it's somebody else's job to do that.
Speaker 1: Do you think that they will succeed where Robert Coo succeeded?
Speaker 1: I think that another person or any most human beings I can think of like if Mike or Jerry had to go talk to the Hotel, they're not gonna make it happen.
Speaker 1: Right, who do you know in the penny arcade organization that could go to the hotel and make that happen?
Speaker 0: because that sort of Conversation is it's there's.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of factors.
Speaker 0: There's the magic man factor or magic, you know The magic person the someone who just has that combination of gravitas and whatever which is pretty rare.
Speaker 0: There's also the knows enough about the industry business contract law Whatever to be able to actually make the real argument that needs to be made like breach of contract or you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: That's a skill like.
Speaker 0: that's a real difficult thing to do.
Speaker 0: If you don't know it's a skill and knowledge.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: and then third and a personality you've also got to be someone who Understands like packs and like the culture of the convention and its needs.
Speaker 0: there are very few people who have all of those attributes.
Speaker 0: So not like I have a lot of faith in packs because the enforcers do a lot of the like.
Speaker 1: the things that make it Enforce your kid go fight with a hotel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there is a tier of things above the top of the enforcers That are at the level of penny arcade staff that I I hope They find some combination of people who can fill this role effectively because I don't think there's one person who could know.
Speaker 0: That's how much I respect Robert coup.
Speaker 0: in all the years.
Speaker 0: I have either interacted with him or just watched him interact with others.
Speaker 0: So I guess Robert like we salute you.
Speaker 0: Good luck.
Speaker 0: Have fun.
Speaker 0: I hope you are taking a vacation and you enjoy it And we'll keep going to Pax's until they burn into fire.
Speaker 0: I hope they don't.
Speaker 0: I hope Pax's outlive me But they could burn it if I now if somehow I'm not saying this is gonna happen But if somehow Pax's decline I'll do everything I can just to get everyone I know and just start the equivalent spiritual successor.
Speaker 0: Sure That's what I would do.
Speaker 0: That would be my life.
Speaker 0: I would consider quitting a job and then borrowing money to try to make that happen But hopefully it'll not come to that geek night's Expo GNX.
Speaker 0: I Might just go more generic than that Of course just gax Not even just nice arcade expo.
Speaker 0: No just stuff that Nickelodeon.
Speaker 0: It doesn't even stand for anything.
Speaker 0: It's just gax.
Speaker 0: So I guess in actual techno, right?
Speaker 1: So what it was Apple Day like we said before.
Speaker 0: yep It took me.
Speaker 1: this is the worldwide developers conference Which means the Apple only talks about stuff that developers care about not stuff like products that normal people would buy.
Speaker 0: it was Surprisingly hard to without several minutes of googling find a succinct list of the things that they announced.
Speaker 1: well Cuz a tech news site wants to make a whole bunch of stories one for each item that Apple talked about to get you to Most ad impressions.
Speaker 1: I'm clicking on all these separate articles.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I'm not super high level.
Speaker 0: They're really pushing Swift both as like.
Speaker 0: well the super high level.
Speaker 1: they're talking about their four OS's right TV the Mac the iOS and The watch.
Speaker 0: yep now there's no more OS X. there's gonna be what Sierra.
Speaker 1: they called it.
Speaker 1: No, it's Mac OS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they changed it because they had iOS TV OS watch OS and now instead of OS X It's Mac OS which is what it was originally.
Speaker 1: I think they really messed up with OS X because they went with the animal names right away and they kept.
Speaker 1: you know in those Early 2000s they kept incrementing the animal and they never had the balls to just make it OS 11.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I think it's because they never really even even the one.
Speaker 1: if you compare the newest one to the first OS X it still has that same fundamental design of The old Mac OS bar the top right that you know The the top level menus that you even have on like a Mac Plus which I have in my closet.
Speaker 1: But what made it OS X was the taskbar at the bottom and you still have that exact same fucking taskbar at the bottom.
Speaker 1: So it's like it's still OS X. It doesn't seem like it's worthy of an 11 right because they haven't revamped it completely.
Speaker 1: So it they just kept improving or well changing, you know The various apps and adding features in like notifications and spaces and all that, you know, I kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: So I guess that's the reason they never went to 11 with it.
Speaker 1: So I guess now realizing that You know the you can't just keep incrementing the the you know place name while keeping OS X They wanted the symmetry.
Speaker 1: so they went, you know watch OS iOS OS.
Speaker 0: I could cut the other thumb off for symmetry here.
Speaker 1: if they wanted real symmetry symmetry iOS They announced iOS 10, but it's Mac OS Sierra.
Speaker 1: shouldn't iOS also have like names of things and not numbers?
Speaker 1: because you're gonna get like iOS 37 and then it's gonna be weird and It's gonna be.
Speaker 1: you know, the marketing people aren't gonna like that.
Speaker 1: Well, that's for the same reason people don't like they didn't want to do Super Bowl L.
Speaker 0: Is this going to get into the situation that video cards got into for a long time?
Speaker 0: That I think radio and video cards still kind of have this problem like the ATI nonsense that processors have where Users unless they are paying attention don't really know what version of something they're running anymore.
Speaker 1: I think they're gonna you know Either change Mac OS to have a number or they're gonna change all the other ones to have names and it'll be iOS name Watch OS name tv OS name.
Speaker 1: Yeah Mac OS name.
Speaker 0: So they made a big deal about end-to-end encryption and all their privacy stuff.
Speaker 0: And if that whole session seemed to just be a big middle finger to the FBI which props?
Speaker 1: Yeah, except they also gave the FBI like this huge Like olive branch, right?
Speaker 1: While they were announcing all this shit about, you know privacy, which Apple does right?
Speaker 1: It's that's a legit thing and that they've always believed and they're just promoting that fact that they have that belief more than they used to.
Speaker 1: They also made phones way easier to unlock.
Speaker 1: They're like, hey everybody look Half the new features.
Speaker 1: they like not half but a large number of the new features they announced especially in iOS.
Speaker 1: We're like Check all this stuff that you can do without having to go through the pain in the ass of unlocking your phone.
Speaker 0: It's like really that's such a pain in the ass with my fingerprint sensor.
Speaker 0: or Oh Android said that forever I can run like fucking almost any widget I want.
Speaker 1: but that's also a bad idea.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'll just send a password reset email to Scott and then I got his phone.
Speaker 1: I can't unlock it.
Speaker 1: But oh I can see the password reset email on the home screen screen And then I reset his email.
Speaker 1: now, I got everything and then you know, they also announced a feature That was like a pretty quick thing.
Speaker 1: They're like, oh you could unlock your Mac if you're wearing your iWatch.
Speaker 1: Oh great.
Speaker 1: So now it's not something I know and it's not something I know and something I have.
Speaker 1: it's the worst of all situations.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not the worst which is the worst locked the worst by something I and other people also know.
Speaker 1: Well, the worst is unlocked completely all the time, but it's just something you have.
Speaker 1: you just put your iWatch near your Mac and unlocks.
Speaker 1: It's like great.
Speaker 1: So now the FBI is happy day.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh just take someone's watch and unlock The whole point of multi-factor authentication that there are multiple factors, right?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna have to now like I'm a next iPhone or when the OS gets updated go through all the settings to make sure that Like I turn off lock screen notifications.
Speaker 1: for like all these apps that are important like I can't have lock screen notifications for inbox because of emails will show up and I got to make sure that like you can't do any fucking shit.
Speaker 1: Well, my phone is locked like reply.
Speaker 0: they were like check it out.
Speaker 1: You can reply to text while the phone is locked and I'm like, that's fucking great Right.
Speaker 1: It's like now it takes my lock phone and starts messaging people with it without having to unlock it.
Speaker 0: Literally the whole point of locking the phone Is that if you set your phone on the table and you walk away for a second people can't fuck up your shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at least they have the feature if someone tries to unlock it too many times it erases itself.
Speaker 1: But seriously, I just like.
Speaker 1: I'm sure the settings will allow you to make it right.
Speaker 1: But they kept promoting all this stuff like look how easy it is to unlock or look at all you can do without Unlocking and I'm like that's not privacy.
Speaker 0: But what I also don't get is that all those things Have been an Android for a long time.
Speaker 0: They're just all.
Speaker 1: you can turn them all on like everything Apple does is.
Speaker 1: some is something someone else has done for a long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what Apple's history in the 80s.
Speaker 1: We got a GUI guys.
Speaker 1: You mean the GUI you stole from Xerox?
Speaker 1: No, no, we got a GUI before I can.
Speaker 1: it's you know, like even less than in this decade.
Speaker 1: They're like check it out virtual desktops.
Speaker 1: You mean the virtual desktops I had in Unix.
Speaker 1: and like the 80s and 90s those virtual desktops you acted like you invented them.
Speaker 1: So, oh, we got an mp3 player.
Speaker 1: You mean like the one that I just saw over there.
Speaker 1: It's like the iPod wasn't the first mp3 player.
Speaker 0: So they made a giant update to iMessage.
Speaker 1: But we got a smartphone you mean like the palm trio.
Speaker 0: I don't understand who uses iMessage on purpose for it being iMessage.
Speaker 1: Well, I think there are people who don't use hangouts right and all they do is text their friends.
Speaker 0: Yep Well, you don't understand these people who text me like never ever text me.
Speaker 1: I text you and a hangout isn't gonna work for some reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like if you're at a convention and like data services aren't working.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who knows?
Speaker 1: but anyway So or someone?
Speaker 1: I don't know their hangout.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you tell how would I ever know someone's phone number?
Speaker 0: But not their email.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you get in the habit of texting all the time.
Speaker 1: It is using the messages app as your primary messaging app Yeah, and all your.
Speaker 1: you can use it to text you and all you're doing is texting people.
Speaker 1: But your friends have iPhones.
Speaker 1: You don't even realize your iMessaging them and the only way you know is because the messages are blue instead of green.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it doesn't.
Speaker 1: even if you pay for text, it doesn't cost you anything.
Speaker 1: but who pays for not unlimited text?
Speaker 1: But you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but all this stuff to add all these fancy features to where if you're iMessaging You can do all this crazy shit.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 0: What worries me is because Google is pushing their thing.
Speaker 0: That's gonna come out later alo, which is basically androids equivalent of iMessage and They've stated very clearly that it will not have a desktop equivalent.
Speaker 0: So What they haven't said yet is whether or not it'll interoperate with hangouts.
Speaker 0: Like will it just be a front-end hangouts or is it its own stupid thing like iMessage?
Speaker 0: because if it's its own stupid thing It's at least the iPhone.
Speaker 0: people who use iMessage for this purpose are those kinds of people.
Speaker 0: Android people don't do that crap.
Speaker 0: So it'll just be a useless app You can.
Speaker 1: actually people don't realize if you use iChat on your Mac you can iMessage.
Speaker 1: So if you're like with if you have a whole bunch of Apple friends, you can all use iMessage.
Speaker 0: Oh and on your desktop coming in iOS 10 voicemail transcription the thing I've had for like six years.
Speaker 0: Google boys.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Also, it'll detect spam calls.
Speaker 0: I already have a spam blocker on my phone - thanks.
Speaker 0: Yep Home automation with home kit.
Speaker 0: They well the way.
Speaker 0: Announcements about updates they may affect.
Speaker 1: they made API's.
Speaker 1: there's an app that comes with the phone called like home, right?
Speaker 1: And basically they were.
Speaker 1: you would if you got like a some let's say you bought home automation lights and a home automation Thermostat.
Speaker 1: they each of those things that have their own app like you'd have a nest app or something right or a Philips LED light bulb App.
Speaker 1: but basically they made API's so that instead of having to make your own separate fucking app when you're a company that makes a home Automation device you just makes an app that integrates with the home kit app.
Speaker 1: So now the person can control all their home automation products.
Speaker 1: That with from one app instead of from a hundred different problem is.
Speaker 0: I've looked into a lot of different home automation stuff because I Can think of use cases?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not worth it.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing.
Speaker 1: and especially if I had a house definitely but not in an apartment But even in a house I can reach the light switch from wherever I am even in in a house.
Speaker 0: Most of the home automation hardware that I've seen out there is hot garbage with zero security.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah
Speaker 0: that like even if you come up with cool ways to use it and even if you ignore all the problems like the Bugs I saw with the nest stuff where you just literally can't set your thermostat cuz fuck you It's just none of this stuff really works that well like we're.
Speaker 0: VR is more here than that home automation is Like.
Speaker 1: they're about the same.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 0: VR is way more here than home automation Because VR is the equivalent of the people who bought open GL video cards back when there was one game that used it Like hobbyists, but even the people who are super hobbyists about home automation Find that they can't actually use this shit, and it doesn't integrate.
Speaker 1: well And I know there are people who have home automation shit that works like opening their garage door with their phone Opening their house door with their phone changing the lights of their phone.
Speaker 0: Yeah No Look at all this light stuff.
Speaker 0: like the companies have just deprecated an API and just like bricked all the existing Hardware that was out there the nest stuff barely works.
Speaker 0: all these light bulb things have problems.
Speaker 0: There's fights over the standards.
Speaker 1: I'm sure but the people are into it.
Speaker 1: have the good ones that work?
Speaker 0: No, but from what I gather it's not.
Speaker 0: we're into it.
Speaker 0: Not all of them are pretty surprising number of problems on a regular basis.
Speaker 1: hmm I think I mean it can't be that hard to make a good one.
Speaker 1: I should just do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's really the case.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of low-hanging fruit companies making really bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one's buying that you got by the good shit If you're in the home if you're into that you're hanging out in the home automation Subreddit and stuff and like you know what the good stuff is right Apple music is redesigned No one cares.
Speaker 1: So a lot of the announcements that they made also are Siri related which is what our main topic is gonna be about.
Speaker 1: yeah, so let's just hold off on that.
Speaker 0: well hold off on that indeed.
Speaker 1: But yeah They didn't announce new Mac books knew that and nothing you could buy was announced.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: the other big Announcement that I was I was like I was sitting through the whole thing and I'm like nothing Nothing, I care about nothing.
Speaker 1: I care about.
Speaker 1: so here's something I do care about.
Speaker 1: Small thing you can used to be an iPhone.
Speaker 1: a lot of the apps you couldn't delete because they came with iOS.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I remember the iPhone kids complaining right, so I didn't really give a shit.
Speaker 1: I just shoved them in a folder on the second screen and never looked at.
Speaker 0: delete them now.
Speaker 1: But some people are OCD and like they have to delete the app.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: They got some fucking problems, right?
Speaker 1: They got to delete that shit.
Speaker 0: I mean I would really like to.
Speaker 0: there's one Xperia icon.
Speaker 0: I can't delete Whatever.
Speaker 1: so the reason there's actually an okay somewhat decent reason for having undeletable apps Some of them anyway.
Speaker 1: so for example the messages app right the one that protects messages.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's possible for example that like you would be in I don't know a website and the website would have a phone number on it And you would want to touch that phone number in order to call or text.
Speaker 1: So if they let you delete the phone or messages app that would be wouldn't unit you.
Speaker 1: basically there's integrations there.
Speaker 1: Right if they deleted this?
Speaker 1: if they let you delete Safari because you wanted to use Chrome It's like well What if you delete Safari and don't have Chrome or don't even have a browser or Chrome doesn't update like back in the day?
Speaker 1: It's like you click on a link in.
Speaker 1: if someone sends you in Hangouts, and you can't open it.
Speaker 1: It's like you would break your phone.
Speaker 0: basically remember back in the day when they're all the kind of BS lawsuits against Microsoft saying you Can't bundle Internet Explorer with Windows.
Speaker 1: It's like then what do I do when I have a brand new computer?
Speaker 1: I need a browser.
Speaker 0: Yeah, how can I download Chrome?
Speaker 1: yes?
Speaker 0: Anyway, so don't you get.
Speaker 1: there are certain apps that you still aren't able to delete But a lot of the apps that didn't have that kind of integration where you they were basically undeletable are now going to be able to be deleted in the next iOS for example like the compass or You know the reminders app or like it's kind of garbage that like you might not be using.
Speaker 1: you know the You know whatever.
Speaker 1: so that's that's an okay news.
Speaker 1: and other news is that they made a new free app And I was getting.
Speaker 1: when they started announcing it I was like oh my god.
Speaker 1: finally.
Speaker 1: finally But no it wasn't what I thought it was gonna be.
Speaker 1: so they're like they want people to let.
Speaker 1: they talked.
Speaker 1: They started talking about Swift their programming language.
Speaker 1: They made and hyping it up way more than it deserves.
Speaker 0: They're really pushing it to be a general-purpose language.
Speaker 1: It's not bad language, but you know they're hyping it up.
Speaker 1: Apple always does that.
Speaker 1: they talk about how great Everything is when it's not as great as they say it is.
Speaker 1: I mean you can have a fun time.
Speaker 1: go and look at old keynotes.
Speaker 1: So they hype something up for being so great that is now a dead product or no longer exists But anyway, so hyping up Swift.
Speaker 1: They're like.
Speaker 1: you know we're making a thing where you can code Swift on iPad.
Speaker 1: I'm like yes, finally you don't need a stupid Mac with Xcode to make an app.
Speaker 1: You can just make an app for iOS on an iOS device.
Speaker 1: It's a miracle.
Speaker 1: It's the greatest yes But that's not what they did.
Speaker 1: They basically made an app which seems like a perfectly decent app for learning to program Swift like a kids kind of thing basically a Modern day.
Speaker 0: the heading for this thing is just called literally teaching kids to code right.
Speaker 1: It's you know it's like a modern-day logo like when I had the little turtle.
Speaker 1: kids today are gonna have this which is great.
Speaker 1: It's totally great.
Speaker 1: kids need this because they don't have the turtle anymore And I don't think the turtle would get kids excited these days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I. we grew up at the end of the era where the turtle could cause any excitement.
Speaker 0: you draw boobs with it Once and then you're done.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and like you know in the late 80s.
Speaker 1: You know me coding with the turtle It's like that was.
Speaker 1: that was it right, but now this is a turtle for the kids today.
Speaker 1: It's great that they made this But it doesn't let you make an app and get it in the App Store, and it doesn't let you make it.
Speaker 1: it's not Xcode it's not Xcode for iOS.
Speaker 1: and My co-worker was like oh, they can't make that.
Speaker 1: and I'm like why couldn't they make it.
Speaker 1: They're like.
Speaker 1: well here is three Arguments that I countered and he said oh, I guess you're right.
Speaker 1: so first argument was well How are you gonna type, and I'm like dude it supports Bluetooth keyboards?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like oh, okay, and the other argument was but how can how can it like compile like Xcode is like this huge program?
Speaker 1: How can it possibly compile a program?
Speaker 1: And I'm like an Apple to compiles a program to run on itself.
Speaker 1: I'm like your computer right there compiles a program that runs on itself.
Speaker 1: It's like any computer can since it doesn't run on vacuum tubes pretty much Can run.
Speaker 1: it can compile a program that then runs on itself.
Speaker 0: as an aside actually vacuum tubes are coming back For audio amplifiers no for processing.
Speaker 0: obviously save this for Some.
Speaker 0: Monday you have a vacuum tube smaller than a transistor Yeah, so vacuum tubes have use cases to replace transistors in certain situations.
Speaker 1: Whatever anyway a little tiny vacuum tubes Yeah, and then he's like the Xcode is such a big giant application They don't want to.
Speaker 1: you know maintain that.
Speaker 1: I'm like.
Speaker 1: you don't have to maintain it.
Speaker 1: you make something completely different.
Speaker 1: You just call it Xcode or mobile Xcode or something and then you make it only develop iOS apps.
Speaker 1: It doesn't need to be able to make Mac apps.
Speaker 1: Yep, or it all needs to be able to make iOS.
Speaker 0: and maybe I mean frankly if I could run either net either native Adobe applications or Like the steam games that were run on my regular old non video accelerated laptop.
Speaker 0: now I would own like three laughs three iPads, but that'll never happen.
Speaker 0: So I bet they're almost useless to me.
Speaker 1: I've had is perfectly fine.
Speaker 1: I don't need a laptop.
Speaker 0: It is what 90% of what I use my laptop for is Running Adobe software.
Speaker 0: I run these.
Speaker 1: I run the mobile Adobe software.
Speaker 1: I never found it.
Speaker 1: I've never found that I've needed the full one.
Speaker 0: Have you Edit a panel video.
Speaker 1: I don't do that on the go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do that sitting on my desk at home.
Speaker 0: I do that on my laptop.
Speaker 1: No interest in doing it on the go.
Speaker 0: either I do it on the go or playing some.
Speaker 1: I bet I could still do it with mobile Adobe from here, dude I would defy you to do that.
Speaker 1: I just don't place it five on the go either.
Speaker 0: I place it five on the go and overwatch runs totally fine on my laptop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're the only one left.
Speaker 1: I'll be like the last man on earth walking around while everyone else is plenty hooked in and play overwatch And then my glasses that I don't need will break while I'm sitting in front of the library.
Speaker 0: It's totally an aside, I know I bring this up a lot but seriously I Cannot believe that overwatch is actually the successor to weapons factory Like I never thought that would actually ever.
Speaker 1: next gaming show.
Speaker 1: we can talk about all these e3 announcements like the new quake.
Speaker 0: What was this?
Speaker 0: someone tweeted and they were like, wow, you three has a lot of announcements.
Speaker 0: There's shoot man There's walk man.
Speaker 0: There's puzzle man and jump man.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: Yep things of the day.
Speaker 0: so This is a lecture.
Speaker 1: You've been trying to use this thing a day for like weeks.
Speaker 0: So the little backstory I learned a Compared to an average person I learned a lot about elevators about four or five years ago because I was so butter about Connecticut and anime Boston's main hotels having magfest.
Speaker 0: We didn't stay we didn't have to use that elevators.
Speaker 0: I didn't care about the elevator party, right?
Speaker 1: but but we were at conventions in hotels a lot and there are many times where there's too many people who overload the elevators.
Speaker 1: and obviously there's a capacity limit that elevators have depending how many shafts.
Speaker 1: yup, but It was obvious the elevators are running sub optimally.
Speaker 1: They would be completely full and they would keep stopping to let more people on.
Speaker 1: and I got mad all sorts of other stupid shit.
Speaker 0: So I started learning about elevators to figure out like is this solvable?
Speaker 0: And the answer was pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, just reprogram the fucking elevator right?
Speaker 0: It's not even that hard.
Speaker 1: but people don't program elevators at places that like don't have such incredible Elevator traffic or it's not?
Speaker 1: you know, like some hotel that's got like four elevator shafts.
Speaker 1: It's like how often is that hotel so crowded?
Speaker 0: like what is the nerd gonna not go to his convention?
Speaker 1: No, he's just gonna bitch every day on Sunday and not realize they just they just put the elevators in default mode And the hotel staff are taking service elevators.
Speaker 1: They don't even give a crap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the smart people are also taking service elevators.
Speaker 0: But a lot of people like to think they can hack Elevators now.
Speaker 0: Yes, you could like you could reprogram the elevators all sorts of crazy stuff with it but most people who say they think they can hack an elevator are full of utter shit are Spreading urban legends and just all this sort of nonsense.
Speaker 0: Now I learned as much as I could learn just on my own about elevator.
Speaker 1: main urban legend I've heard I don't know how true it is is hold the number you want to go to and closed door at the same time.
Speaker 0: That's never been true.
Speaker 1: So some elevators it will express no no elevators.
Speaker 0: Will it do that?
Speaker 0: Boom the urban legend denied the best case for that is there are some elevators where if you do that It'll still stop on every floor.
Speaker 0: that had a floor call, but it just won't open the door But it'll stop at the floor.
Speaker 0: Anyway, not saving you any time.
Speaker 0: The door just won't open.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, so This is a lecture better.
Speaker 1: Hope it opens at your destination.
Speaker 0: This is you know, we talked about like we go to cons But we don't go to that many panels at cons anymore because very few Pat like an anime con Unless it's like Mike tool or Daryl Surratt, like no one's gonna tell me anything.
Speaker 0: I don't already know.
Speaker 1: man Maybe someone would but you don't care that more.
Speaker 0: they're gonna tell me something I don't know But they're gonna mumble it through 50 unrelated minutes of like rambling Sonic the Hedgehog fanfic or whatever like.
Speaker 0: they're not good presenters.
Speaker 0: But this right here is a panel from a convention.
Speaker 0: if you want a prototype for the kind of panel that I like to go To at a con it is this one.
Speaker 0: It was called Elevator hacking from the pit to the penthouse.
Speaker 0: I believe it was given at a Def Con a couple years ago and They very pointedly gave this panel on Sunday at the end of the con because the panel is two hours of yo-dog.
Speaker 0: Here's how elevators work and how to fucking hack them.
Speaker 1: So if they gave it to the beginning of the con the elevators would have been fucked up for the whole con.
Speaker 1: It's actually a Def Con.
Speaker 0: So some of these things I knew.
Speaker 0: so Scott have you ever seen riot mode in an elevator?
Speaker 0: Riot mode riot mode.
Speaker 0: No, Ella's many elevators have riots mode.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I thought I knew what riot mode did.
Speaker 0: I was wrong now.
Speaker 0: I actually know a riot mode does.
Speaker 0: I also know how it's distinct from executive mode and all these crazy mode.
Speaker 1: executive mode.
Speaker 1: the only mode I know about is regular mode and Fire departments here mode go directly to the floor.
Speaker 1: We tell you to know.
Speaker 0: So what do you think fire mode does?
Speaker 0: I knew a little more about it because I got my dad So usually my grandfather fireman.
Speaker 1: usually when there's a fire in a building all the elevators would go to the bottom and open the doors.
Speaker 0: All right, that's that's phase one, right?
Speaker 1: It's phase one and then it no one will be able to use them Except if they have the fireman key.
Speaker 1: and when the fireman goes in there with the fireman key He can manually control the elevator and go directly to the floor.
Speaker 1: They want and open and close the doors by you know, whenever they want essentially.
Speaker 0: Yes, that's phase two and then that's it.
Speaker 1: So and then they hopefully put the fire out before it becomes an issue.
Speaker 0: Some buildings either don't have the alarm systems hooked into the elevator directly.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: in New York you have to in a big if your building's big enough, right?
Speaker 0: Or if you have the fireman key if you go to that slot on the outside of the elevators Just put your key in and twist it It'll come to the bottom and open up all the depending on the building.
Speaker 0: Maybe all the elevators in the building will come to the bottom.
Speaker 0: probably now if they're not connected to each other and the talks about This then maybe only certain banks will come down.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's a lot of buildings like express elevator, right?
Speaker 1: There's a lot of buildings like really big ones or like they tell you to use the stairs.
Speaker 1: It's like dude I'm on floor 83 if I use the stairs, I am so fucked.
Speaker 0: So this lecture not only it's about 20% like actually like legit specific ways to hack Elevators.
Speaker 0: the rest of it is just explaining how elevators work and it's just.
Speaker 0: it is a Fascinating lecture like Sim tower.
Speaker 1: You'll learn all the same shit.
Speaker 0: Uh, so do you know the history of Sim tower, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, Sim tower was actually basically a real simulator application for tall buildings.
Speaker 0: it was a Japanese thing for us to optimize elevators and shit and They turned it into a game because it was just fun.
Speaker 1: and then it wasn't even made by Max's made by.
Speaker 1: it was a Japanese Game called the tower.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they rebranded Sim tower released in the US But for real like this places him to.
Speaker 0: this is two hours.
Speaker 0: like you will be shocked at how fascinating this lecture on how elevators work is and give you basically the gist of it is if you care about security an Elevator is unless it is secured Elsewhere like before you even get to the elevator And then later is just a shaft or a stairway that goes to every floor of your building.
Speaker 0: That is not locked Pretty much.
Speaker 0: So you gotta think of the day I do.
Speaker 1: it's just a quick thing of the day because I couldn't find anything.
Speaker 1: So basically it's a little thing.
Speaker 1: It's like how to turn any cat in the Totoro and you just cut out this little paper thing and you put it on the Back of the cat and it's just pointing out how like the back of a cat's head is Totoro shaped.
Speaker 1: So you put this the white thing.
Speaker 1: You put the white thing on the back of the cat.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: And you could just turn any cat into a Totoro.
Speaker 0: if any of you own cats you have to send us a picture of you.
Speaker 1: So you can see all these tweets here of people who did it and took a cute picture.
Speaker 1: so You know, I think that they went to the trouble of cutting out the eyes.
Speaker 1: But I think you could just use a little reinforcement to use for three ring binders.
Speaker 1: I was about to suggest the same thing and it would be sticky already and you wouldn't have to like spray post-it glue on it or anything.
Speaker 1: So how to make your own Cat into a Totoro.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: This is real good.
Speaker 1: And if your cat makes a good pose, it'll be an even funnier picture like that middle one.
Speaker 0: You would all better do this to your cats If you have a cat.
Speaker 1: you had to do this in the meta moment.
Speaker 0: kinetic ons coming up.
Speaker 0: in less than a month We'll be there.
Speaker 0: We're doing two of our, you know, foreign anime opener panels.
Speaker 0: We're doing writing game rules Which is a kind of new lecture for us.
Speaker 0: There's a riff on an older lecture.
Speaker 0: They're.
Speaker 0: hopefully we'll also be doing a bags.
Speaker 0: We might do it a couple other things But we can't do a lot even though we're actually some of the highest in demand panelists at the show.
Speaker 0: We we run the panels department so we can't actually spend all our time doing panels.
Speaker 0: We got to sit at a desk and get a hotel.
Speaker 0: I do have a hotel.
Speaker 0: It's kind of far away But it's our transportation.
Speaker 0: I booked Amtrak.
Speaker 0: Well, it's an Amtrak or Megabus.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you take Megabus.
Speaker 1: I'll do something else.
Speaker 0: Megabus or Amtrak a walk or you can rent a car.
Speaker 0: I'm not renting a car and paying to park it in Hartford.
Speaker 0: No, I Did that once.
Speaker 0: that was way too much money?
Speaker 0: No, I'll show.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you what Amtrak's were on.
Speaker 0: I'm going Thursday night and coming back Sunday night.
Speaker 0: I'm not sticking around.
Speaker 0: I just don't care.
Speaker 1: No, I'm not sick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, uh otherwise Pax Prime will be doing hopefully at least one or two panels there and The Patriots going strong.
Speaker 0: somebody and I'm not.
Speaker 0: I might thank you personally if this shows out to be legit just Donated $50 a month to us.
Speaker 1: What the fuck is wrong with them?
Speaker 0: So I'll see.
Speaker 1: if that's like a whole video game every month that you could buy a brand new one Why is geek nights worth that much to you?
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: and if you're so rich that you can afford that Why don't you pay me enough money so I don't go to work cuz that'd be a lot more than $50 a month.
Speaker 1: But they're so rich if they can afford 50 a month on something.
Speaker 1: That's stupid.
Speaker 0: I can afford $50 a month.
Speaker 0: I'm something that I think if it turns out to be legit I'm gonna donate $50 a month be to either Neil Cicierega or Crash Course.
Speaker 1: That's way too much money for either of those.
Speaker 0: I respect both of those institutions so much.
Speaker 1: if I was mega rich though I would just pay Neil Cicierega like a zillion dollars.
Speaker 0: No, dude, if I was super rich, I would hire Neil Cicierega to be my court barred.
Speaker 0: Sure like full stop.
Speaker 0: I would just be like I just go to him every morning and be like today.
Speaker 0: I would like to hear the song.
Speaker 1: Right, he'd write for you the cantarega tales.
Speaker 0: I want pump up the jam set to the tune of time after time.
Speaker 0: Okay, actually legit want that.
Speaker 0: Okay running through my head.
Speaker 1: It barely works anyway It's not working for me.
Speaker 0: So people make a bit interesting.
Speaker 0: people make a big deal about how much they like Siri Except they notice any except they seem to only make a big deal about it If they're fake people showing you how Siri works online or in advertisements.
Speaker 1: The only time like I'm in New York City There's iPhones everywhere and the only time I ever see Siri being used is at an Apple keynote.
Speaker 1: I never see anyone use it in person.
Speaker 0: I have seen someone use it in person only and when I say only I mean literally 100% of the times I have ever seen someone use Siri out loud in public.
Speaker 0: in New York.
Speaker 0: They were showing someone else what Siri is.
Speaker 0: They were not actually earnestly using it, right?
Speaker 1: But meanwhile, so, you know, I've seen a couple people have claimed.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen them use it But they claim to use Siri often.
Speaker 1: It's like a few.
Speaker 1: there's a few diamonds in the rough out there.
Speaker 1: We just keep I don't know if they're diamonds, but there's few people out there.
Speaker 1: a few bad eggs Use Siri a whole bunch, but also I have a co-worker who use claims and I believe him.
Speaker 1: I don't see why I'd lie.
Speaker 1: He's got the Amazon The echo the echo and he says he uses that like a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: But it's like I would use something like an echo way more than I would use something on my phone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can see that but I think he's in a situation.
Speaker 1: It's like perfect for it.
Speaker 1: Like because the Amazon echo it's like if you don't have I have other stuff.
Speaker 1: So it's like I have a sound system.
Speaker 1: if I didn't have one then that would make sense, right?
Speaker 1: It's like it can't control my existing sound system.
Speaker 1: It just is a sound system and home automation is there.
Speaker 0: I can't be like Echo.
Speaker 0: turn the temperature down turn the lights up close the blinds, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I think you know the biggest thing is like.
Speaker 1: so the main idea here is that you control something by talking to it and There are occasions where I find myself wanting to do this.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, so pretty much only two times.
Speaker 0: One use case is I am biking and I want to respond to a text when I was wearing Google Glass That's well, that's my number one.
Speaker 1: It's not even Google Glass Like I see on my watch.
Speaker 1: there's something there and I just want to either say like hang up or you know Quick text reply or something without having to stop biking except I don't stop biking.
Speaker 0: I just reach over because I have the pebble with the physical buttons.
Speaker 1: Like I could push the physical button too, but I can't do everything I want to do.
Speaker 1: You can do a lot more with the voice, right?
Speaker 0: Oh true.
Speaker 0: So well like, you know, the Google like reply fuck you I'm not coming to your birthday.
Speaker 1: Also, if I talk if I talk while I'm biking that's not really a big deal.
Speaker 1: But will it work if I talk along biking with the wind and everything?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: So with Google Glass it did like scarily.
Speaker 0: Well, it was actually yeah, Google Glass worked.
Speaker 0: I never had a problem talking to but that was only kid was on my face with the watch.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna like let go and like hold my watch up to my mouth to talk into it.
Speaker 1: No, it's got to be able to hear me from where I am.
Speaker 0: cuz I can only do that of going slow.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you get like.
Speaker 0: if you bike like at a high speed You can't let go with one hand or if you bump into something you're dead Right.
Speaker 1: The other time is I want to do.
Speaker 1: it is when I'm hold when I my hands are busy Right and not cooking.
Speaker 0: so I'm like I'm cooking and I think I'm knee-deep in a bunch of raw chicken.
Speaker 0: I want to be like set.
Speaker 1: I don't want to touch the phone with my dirty hand.
Speaker 1: I want to say set five-minute timer.
Speaker 1: There's actually Apple commercial cookie monster did this and he's like, yeah He's like said cookie time.
Speaker 0: I want to do things like said cookie timer Set oven preheat oven to 450 which can't do another great use which I don't have.
Speaker 0: how long do I cook this for again?
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's another situation that isn't doesn't pertain to me but pertains to people who can't use their hands.
Speaker 1: Well for whatever disability reason.
Speaker 0: that's that's like the best possible use case, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like you're missing an arm and you're using one to hold something and you're just like, you know Hey, dude, scary cuz like with Google Glass again while I never used it except maybe you got a hook or something.
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: except to show off like I would owe when you're hanging out at dinner when we were in glass all the time I'd be like God like, you know, hey Google whatever and I just ask it a Google query Like how many people live in Singapore and I get the
Speaker 1: answer.
Speaker 1: So it's not that these things are useless and it's good that they're making them better.
Speaker 1: But personally, I'm not talking to my fucking phone in public ever.
Speaker 0: It's not happening like there's no use case.
Speaker 1: and if someone else did and it's like you think oh But if someone else did it like you're worried Like someone's gonna like look at you weird and something and it's like I would if I was one.
Speaker 1: someone else is doing it.
Speaker 1: I'd give them the side.
Speaker 1: I I'd give them big side.
Speaker 1: I maybe your side.
Speaker 0: I know you're.
Speaker 0: you don't talk.
Speaker 0: In fact, you're talking to someone else.
Speaker 0: if you're talking not to a person and you're not on a Bluetooth headset.
Speaker 0: I assume you're crazy.
Speaker 1: I mean even if I'm on the subway early in the morning and Like anyone says anything it's like oh my god.
Speaker 1: It's rush hour in the morning.
Speaker 1: Shut the fuck up.
Speaker 1: Yep Oh my god, do you want to die?
Speaker 1: Surprised this homeless guy who's trying to sleep isn't stabbing you right now.
Speaker 1: And if he was I wouldn't do anything.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't push the red button.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'd Brett push the red button after a minute.
Speaker 0: It's funny you bring that up cuz I got a rims-renz for the patreon about that sort of topic.
Speaker 1: That's someone pushed the red button.
Speaker 0: No, no, it's just the whole.
Speaker 0: so, you know in New York Like there's a certain timber of voice like a certain like quality where you hear someone's voice in the distance And you say not turning my back or whatever that is.
Speaker 0: Hey, yep But I noticed the other day that I have an aggressive thing to say to you, yep I noticed that people who live in New York immediately turn to assess the threat and tourists don't seem to react to it right away.
Speaker 0: I noticed that yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that's the totally aside, but I want this technology to get better.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's I just disabled Siri.
Speaker 1: They're like we had Siri on the Mac.
Speaker 1: now It's like it's like dude.
Speaker 1: None of these announcements mean anything because if I get any device that has Siri I am disabling it immediately.
Speaker 1: And you know what the number one reason I disable it immediately Even though I do have occasional uses for it Like there's a couple times rum got my hands full of dough and I really want to set the timer enough Like if I have my hands right?
Speaker 0: Oh, I haven't set it up I can't make.
Speaker 1: I have Siri disabled and I can't use it and I'm disappointed.
Speaker 1: I can't lie I'm disappointed at that moment, but when I had Siri enabled, you know, and I wasn't really using it It kept activating constantly and I'm like, oh my god get the fuck like it kept turning on and being like dude Hello, and I'm like
Speaker 0: why go
Speaker 1: away.
Speaker 1: I'm not trying to use you now.
Speaker 1: You have accidentally enabled yourself and tried to listen to me when I don't want you here and that happened constantly.
Speaker 0: Well every time I'm going to do the kinds of thing I could do with Siri I'm either holding my phone.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I can only imagine like sitting there work doing real work on your Mac and like you're just working and then Siri pops up.
Speaker 1: It's like hello.
Speaker 1: What do you want?
Speaker 1: And I'm like go fuck away.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I'm disabling you so hard.
Speaker 1: uninstall.
Speaker 0: So it comes down to because the voice recognition is really good like the technology is there like yeah No, it's fine.
Speaker 1: Like even now like my back end of it just keeps getting better like crazy fast better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, neural networks are a big part of that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know the deep learning and whatnots, right?
Speaker 0: But the output of what it does is still like.
Speaker 0: someone needs to do a lot of like real UX effort into making the experience for the use cases that actually would matter to normal people Which I think just comes down to.
Speaker 0: I am cooking Like that use case.
Speaker 0: like you said the Cookie Monster set a timer.
Speaker 0: It has to also know what I'm cooking Like.
Speaker 0: the recipe has to be like easy to put in so I can like ask it questions about the thing I'm cooking right now and has to just work immediately all the time while I'm cooking because if it can't answer the question I'm asking I gotta wash all the rotten chicken off my hands or the raw chicken Hopefully it's not rotten and then I gotta go to my phone and futz with it.
Speaker 0: And at that point a hundred percent of my utility was already gone.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, it's pretty much really good for things that take one step Like what's the score the hockey game or give me directions or but anything requires multiple steps and like decisions It's like they always use examples of like apps for like restaurant reservations and shit, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like, okay, Siri find me a restaurant.
Speaker 1: Okay, get one that has a gluten-free option for my friend.
Speaker 1: So okay get one that has this table for seven.
Speaker 1: Okay, you know it's like.
Speaker 0: thing is even even if you're at a computer in this neighborhood Like you're at a computer on Yelp or on the internet.
Speaker 0: That's still a really hard problem to solve.
Speaker 1: Clicking on like, you know anything takes multiple steps and becomes real work.
Speaker 1: suddenly the voice thing is he's useless and it's like you just need to click or touch until it has that sort of semantic context.
Speaker 0: or I can be like Siri.
Speaker 0: how hot like?
Speaker 0: how hot do I have to make this chicken to not make me sick?
Speaker 0: and serious bonds like cook it to This temperature for this amount of time?
Speaker 1: and there's a lot of cotton, you know There's a lot of things where it's like, you know a simple search it can do right like.
Speaker 1: what's the news today?
Speaker 1: Whatever the headlines but it's like it doesn't.
Speaker 1: usually I'm doing a complex search like I get to a street in this police activity And it's like man.
Speaker 1: I know I can search Twitter and do the exact searches in this way And maybe I'll find the info I want to be like.
Speaker 1: I can't be like.
Speaker 1: can I be like?
Speaker 1: search Twitter for?
Speaker 1: tweets and this you know It's like suddenly.
Speaker 1: it's a complex query and I don't know if Siri can do that unless it gets to the point where I can Be like Siri.
Speaker 0: what's going on at 42nd Street?
Speaker 1: Yeah Right and it knows that you're thinking, you know asking about something that's happening right now And you know and it's not just gonna be like Oh 42nd Street.
Speaker 1: Well, this is a tourist there Street is in Manhattan.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: no, I want you to tell me that like.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah Somebody shot someone or there's of the water main broke or something like that.
Speaker 0: Yep anyway, so It's it's just.
Speaker 0: it's very rare that you see this situation because usually it's people want to do something With the technology but the technology like the back end
Speaker 1: I really wonder like are the Apple people like using Siri all the time Like if I go to the Apple offices everyone walking around talking to their phone like a fucking weirdo.
Speaker 0: So remember we got Google Glass.
Speaker 0: like I was in Google's office and I was there for a bunch of other reasons Like I've been in Google's offices a few times.
Speaker 1: I've been there.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But even at the era when like they made everyone wear glass Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I did not hear at any point any human being say the words.
Speaker 0: Okay glass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brand ok for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights in order of the amount of money that they give us in a continuing basis are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brandau Heidi McNichol Amanda douche at James David white.
Speaker 0: Christian Please close parenthesis.
Speaker 0: coons my stage calm.
Speaker 0: Sean Hayworth William isen rose Jeremy minor Spartacus Spartacus Spartacus Iggy kid Matthew Smith kajar tavish and Joshua Joe star Tyler Eller Don Schleich Sean Yeager Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Robert Lee Ryan Perrin drew open letter.
Speaker 0: Raoul of Al Brian said Roni Rochelle, Monta, Nona Finn Eric silver odd and the infinite sadness.
Speaker 0: Aaron Cerise Chris midkiff Chris Knox flame dark fire Sam Corddry Daniel Redmond Chris hadad Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Han.
Speaker 0: I Think I'm getting pretty good at going down that list But I think it's only because I've said all your names at least many of you so many times that there's sort of a rhythm To it.
Speaker 0: I overheard in the background out of the studio.
Speaker 0: Emily's sort of partially memorized this list Just cuz I yell it so often to her microphone.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah, if any of you open the game fast food franchise Not just Chris and you would be so kind as to scan at least like the main game elements and send them to me.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna make that t-shirt even if I don't get a license to sell the t-shirt or like legitimately put it out there.
Speaker 0: I'm at least making it for myself and I'd be willing to open it up in a limited time just for people who wanted to have these What I think are going to be amazing t-shirts.
Speaker 0: So let me know and now I leave you with something odd.