Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, October 5th, 2016.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we're talking about Mob Psycho 100.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I'm coming home today.
Speaker 0: And first, as I'm going down to get on the 7 train, there's a lot of yelling going on down there.
Speaker 0: Like I hear...
Speaker 1: On your way to work?
Speaker 0: On the way home from work.
Speaker 0: Just now.
Speaker 1: That makes more sense.
Speaker 0: I hear people yelling.
Speaker 0: And it was the, like, "Ah, ah, ah," kind of like, "Something's going on down there
Speaker 0: trouble.".
Speaker 0: And all the New Yorkers are kind of, like, crocking the heads.
Speaker 0: They're going down the stairs, like, ready to just turn around and walk back up those stairs.
Speaker 1: But maybe there's a spectacle to look at.
Speaker 0: It's a bunch of drunk guys in Mets jerseys.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So then...
Speaker 1: It's a little early.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's super crowded.
Speaker 1: The game's not for a couple hours.
Speaker 0: So meanwhile, also, on that ramp that goes down toward the 7 from the 4-5, there's usually the people selling various foods that I would never buy, because those things are probably just full of hepatitis.
Speaker 0: But there's also all the people selling bootleg DVDs and bootleg Blu-rays.
Speaker 0: They were all gone today.
Speaker 0: Instead, there were two different people selling bootleg Mets jerseys.
Speaker 1: Hey, not a bad deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Depending on the construction.
Speaker 0: And the one guy who is obviously a hobo is holding up these obviously bootleg Mets jerseys, and he's like, "Listen, if they win the World Series, they're going to really wish you bought this from me, you sons of
Speaker 0: bitches.".
Speaker 0: And that's his schwiel.
Speaker 0: That's what he's selling.
Speaker 1: We're so far away from the World Series.
Speaker 1: So let me... See, I bet you don't know how baseball playoffs work.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: So here's what I know about baseball.
Speaker 0: Here's what I know about baseball.
Speaker 0: A business contact I have who knows that I'm from Detroit, I hadn't seen him in a while, and I saw him.
Speaker 0: And the first thing he said to me was, "It's a shame about the
Speaker 0: Tigers.".
Speaker 0: So that's about what I know the state.
Speaker 1: Here's how the baseball playoffs work, right?
Speaker 0: And I know the Mets are still in it because of these drunk guys.
Speaker 1: There's a National League and an American League.
Speaker 0: And they have slightly different rules.
Speaker 0: I do know that.
Speaker 1: Slightly different rules, and they're divided in half, right?
Speaker 1: So when you do play during the regular season since the '90s, they added some interleague play.
Speaker 1: It used to be that you didn't play teams in the other league unless it was the World Series at all, right?
Speaker 1: Like during the '80s.
Speaker 1: You didn't play the team in the American League ever unless it was the World Series.
Speaker 1: But now, you do play them a bit during the regular season, but in the playoffs, you don't.
Speaker 1: And at the end of the playoffs, you have one American League team and one National League team, and they go to the World Series, and that's the winner, right?
Speaker 1: So each league has three divisions, right?
Speaker 1: East, west, and central.
Speaker 1: So you have the winner of each division goes to the playoffs, but that is hard in an elimination bracket to have three and three.
Speaker 0: so there's a wild card, right?
Speaker 1: Unless you give someone the bye.
Speaker 1: So to make four and four, they take the team with the best record.
Speaker 1: that wasn't a division winner, and they get in too.
Speaker 0: I think as a kid, in all sports that have wild card slots, that was the thing that confused me the most until an adult explained it.
Speaker 1: So it's basically the team with the best record that didn't actually win.
Speaker 1: their division gets in.
Speaker 1: So in the Mets division, the National League East, the Washington Nationals have the best record, except they have the second best record in the National League, so they won the division.
Speaker 1: But it could be that because they split it up in divisions, there's a lot of situations where it's not fair.
Speaker 1: You were second best in your division, but the God team was in your division, and meanwhile, some shit team wins the central division, and now you're not in the playoffs, and they are, so that's why they have a wild card.
Speaker 1: But more recently, they added a different rule where basically instead of taking the team with the best record that didn't win their division, they take the two teams with the best record that didn't win their division, and they play one game of baseball.
Speaker 0: So that's the crazy game that's happening tonight?
Speaker 1: It is the wild card game, and if you win the wild card game, you go to the real playoffs against the best team.
Speaker 0: I almost wish hockey did that.
Speaker 1: You go to the real playoffs as the bottom seed, and if you lose the wild card game, your season is over.
Speaker 1: So the Mets, with one game remaining in the regular season, secured the wild card game home team home field advantage.
Speaker 1: So the last game of the regular season, they just didn't give a fuck.
Speaker 1: So as
Speaker 0: a result, not only all this, but on my train today, the train stopped at court square, and then the conductor kept yelling at these jackasses to get out of the way of the door as all these Mets fans would hold the
Speaker 1: door open for further Mets fans.
Speaker 1: I looked at tickets for tonight's game, right?
Speaker 1: This one game elimination.
Speaker 0: What, 1,200 bucks?
Speaker 0: That's my guess.
Speaker 1: No, but it was 500 for the nosebleeds.
Speaker 0: So probably 1,200 for a decency.
Speaker 1: I'm sure, whatever, but yes, I didn't go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's fine.
Speaker 1: But it's not for a while.
Speaker 1: Why would you go to the stadium this early?
Speaker 0: The MTA, at 4.45 p.m.
Speaker 0: today, tweeted, "New York Mets win World Series," and they had a nice picture of it.
Speaker 1: The World Series is like a month away.
Speaker 0: And they said, "Basically, looking forward to when we get to light up our bridges in orange and blue.
Speaker 0: Let's go,
Speaker 0: Mets!".
Speaker 1: So -- Last year, at least, we were in the World Series.
Speaker 1: This year, we could be done today.
Speaker 1: Today could be the end.
Speaker 0: Why would you take that?
Speaker 0: The MTA has announced that the Mets will win the World Series.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess we're not going to.
Speaker 0: Thanks, MTA.
Speaker 1: We're probably going to lose today because of you.
Speaker 0: So, in other news, it's actually kind of a big deal.
Speaker 0: Adventure time.
Speaker 1: Oh, speaking of which, right?
Speaker 1: So we're playing against the San Francisco Giants.
Speaker 1: The San Francisco Giants won the World Series in 2010.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: And 2014.
Speaker 0: So why are they fighting for the wild card slot now?
Speaker 1: They won it in 2010, 2012, and 2014.
Speaker 0: You're looking at the pattern.
Speaker 1: And it is currently 2016.
Speaker 0: Baseball has a lot more superstitious patterns than any other sport, as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: But that's not some superstition.
Speaker 1: That happened.
Speaker 1: They won it, the World Series, the whole thing, in 2010, 2012, and 2014.
Speaker 1: And it is currently 2016.
Speaker 1: And we are playing them today in a single elimination game.
Speaker 1: So, MTA, you're not helping.
Speaker 0: Well, they tweeted at 444, which is an even number.
Speaker 1: That doesn't mean anything.
Speaker 0: But this is actually kind of bigger news because for a long time, Adventure Time's just been going on forever.
Speaker 1: And-- Not forever.
Speaker 1: It started like after we graduated college.
Speaker 0: Which is a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, the show isn't that old.
Speaker 1: I found the episode-- The Simpsons started when I was in elementary school.
Speaker 1: Adventure Time is effectively a brand new fucking show.
Speaker 0: We're talking about The Simpsons.
Speaker 0: I start, but I've watched-- The Simpsons, I only watched about 12 seasons worth.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, Adventure Time, as far as I'm concerned, is a new fucking show.
Speaker 0: But, yeah, I watched The Simpsons from my parents, got us to watch The Tracy-- Because we watched The Tracy Ullman Show.
Speaker 0: That was the thing we watched as a family.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: To this day, I don't know who Tracy Ullman is.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Is that a person who still does anything?
Speaker 1: Is that a person who's alive?
Speaker 0: I do not know anything about the current state of Tracy Ullman.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure she's still alive.
Speaker 1: I never knew who it was.
Speaker 1: I just knew that The Tracy Ullman Show was the show that had The Simpsons bit.
Speaker 0: I think she's still alive.
Speaker 1: What does she do?
Speaker 0: Let's see what she's doing.
Speaker 0: Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what she looks like.
Speaker 0: Oh, nope.
Speaker 0: She-- Yeah, born.
Speaker 0: Not dead.
Speaker 0: Still acting, looks like.
Speaker 1: In what?
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't know if I saw her on the street.
Speaker 0: Other appearances, stage credits, music videos, filmography.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: Uh, she's a guest presenter and have I got news for you.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the hell that is.
Speaker 0: She has a new show called Tracy Ullman's Show, apparently.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: I should check that out.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Uh, she's in How I Met Your Mother, which people talk about, but I think that show's garbage.
Speaker 1: I know that's a TV sitcom, so I assume it's garbage.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: I assume it's basically Friends 2.
Speaker 1: The last thing she was on that I remember was-- Wow.
Speaker 0: Now, Ally McBeal is the last thing I knew she did.
Speaker 1: I know that's another garbage TV sitcom.
Speaker 1: I don't know anything about it, though.
Speaker 0: But it was garbage TV in an era when that's all you got.
Speaker 0: Like, there wasn't much non-garbage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there wasn't really.
Speaker 0: As opposed to How I Met Your Mother, which is still that same garbage TV.
Speaker 0: It'd be like if Seinfeld was made today.
Speaker 0: You wouldn't even look at it.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah.
Speaker 0: I guess she's still doing stuff.
Speaker 0: Good for her.
Speaker 0: Cool.
Speaker 0: But, uh, Adventure Time, I was speculating a lot, because Finn's, you know, as a character, has been growing.
Speaker 0: Like, as the show went on, 'cause the actor got older, they just had him get older, and the tone of the show kept changing.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't think it's because the actor got older, but, you know, it just sort of works out that way.
Speaker 0: It might have been a little bit on purpose, 'cause his voice was changing.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, that probably was, that was probably, you know, a concern.
Speaker 1: But, you know, the fact, they could have easily said, "We want Finn to stay a
Speaker 1: kid."
Speaker 1: That's our creative decision, and made that happen, if they wanted to.
Speaker 0: But the fact that they didn't, and that they had him, kept getting older, and they went through, like, all these different eras.
Speaker 1: I think it's also a wise business decision, 'cause your audience is getting older.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: If you have a kid's show, right, you know, it's real quick.
Speaker 1: It's like, okay, some fifth graders watching the show, and then you've done the show for five years, and now they're in high school.
Speaker 1: So, if the show hasn't changed from being a show for elementary school kids, to a show for high school kids, and you haven't been able to get new elementary school kids into it, your show's dead.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: But, because of this, and, you know, you can see, too, because the tone of the show, like, season one.
Speaker 1: Like Pokemon, right?
Speaker 1: Pokemon manages to somehow keep the people in, but also get the new ones, right?
Speaker 1: Well, 'cause Pokemon has this-- But if you just have your audience that you're serving and is aging, you need to advance.
Speaker 0: Pokemon has increasing tier--.
Speaker 0: Pokemon does what, for some reason, no anime con can do.
Speaker 0: It provides stuff for the young kid with the kid brain, who's like,
Speaker 0: "Yay!".
Speaker 0: It provides stuff for the young kid with the still kid brain, who thinks he's too sophisticated for that kid shit, 'cause Pokemon's still there for him.
Speaker 0: It's got stuff for the college kids, it's got the video games, the adults with the nostalgia, and the IV training, and the EV training.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not something nothing else does, it just-- I'm just saying, anime cons don't do it.
Speaker 1: It's for all ages.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anime cons are not for all ages.
Speaker 0: Pokemon's one of the few things that says it's for all ages, and actually is, as opposed to-- There's a lot of things that are, they're just, you know-- A lot of things that say they're for all ages are actually for little kids only.
Speaker 1: It's just, I think what it is, is that things that are all ages are, that are truly all ages, are the hardest kinds of things to make.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: 'Cause imagine something that entertains-- The easiest kind of thing to make is something that is adults only, because basically the taste of your audience doesn't really move.
Speaker 1: If someone goes from 30 and they're 60 now, if they've been watching it for 30 years, you can just keep doing the same exact thing, 'cause they're not really changing as much as--.
Speaker 1: But if someone changes their age from like 10 to 16, only six years, more changes in that person's desires for media than the 30 years of 30 to 60.
Speaker 0: But it fit that the show, Adventure Time at least, sort of grew up with its audience on-- I mean, it obviously kind of went on purpose at one point, 'cause it started with like, yay kids stuff, and it got into increasingly complex and dire shit as he got older, and then it dealt with a lot of weird sex and adolescence issues and family issues and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: And I'd speculated for a long time that if the show didn't end, it was possible that it could have been like for better or for worse, where 30 years from now, Finn's 46, and the show just kept going.
Speaker 1: I think there's a limit to how far they can take it.
Speaker 0: I don't know if there is, but the problem is, every further bit that you take it requires an exponentially higher level of artistic care without fucking it up.
Speaker 0: So eventually you hit this slope where it's really hard to go higher.
Speaker 0: That's why Seinfeld ended, because in the era the slope was good, so if Seinfeld had kept going to today, that would not be a good show.
Speaker 1: I mean, when anything ages, right, there's a certain limit that you can take it to, right?
Speaker 1: So for example, a rock band, right, is like, yeah, there's still, like, Aerosmith is still playing, but it's like, really?
Speaker 1: There's like a point at which it's like, you're too old now, the show's not great anymore.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, Aerosmith cover bands continue to do their thing forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the music itself doesn't get old, right, because it's the same song, but it's like the people in the band, right?
Speaker 1: And you can see the biggest example of that if you watch some idol group or something, right, is like, they're in schoolgirl uniforms, like, dancing, and it's like, when they get to be 30, they can't do it that long, because it doesn't work anymore.
Speaker 0: And meanwhile, look at The Simpsons, which is probably going to be America's most enduring television cultural icon ever.
Speaker 0: It's basically Artur Ayman.
Speaker 1: Bart's still in the same class.
Speaker 0: But notice how that show, even in the first, like, ten seasons, went through many different eras with different styles of comedy.
Speaker 0: There's like four or five different versions of Homer, ranging from actually evil and malicious to mentally challenged.
Speaker 0: And, like, you can pick out eras of The Simpsons, and eventually they expanded increasingly into all the side characters.
Speaker 0: They brought Sideshow Bob back, like, 15 times.
Speaker 1: Is that really that many times?
Speaker 0: I found, because we've been watching old Simpsons.
Speaker 1: I think, you know, because I was watching in the Sideshow Bob era, where, like, he would come back and it'd be, like, a new episode, right?
Speaker 0: Like, the Kate Fear one was probably the best one, though.
Speaker 1: But it's like, I think there was a time, it was, like, maybe, like, the fourth time or fifth time he came back, and it was, like, that was supposed to be the true.
Speaker 1: last time he came back.
Speaker 1: And it was for-- Dude, at what point-- There was a point at which, like, he didn't come back again for a long time.
Speaker 1: Well, because he was in jail with his family, and he was crazy.
Speaker 1: It's like that one was really the last one.
Speaker 0: But he came back in an episode where, I guess, he augmented his DNA with animal powers.
Speaker 1: I did not see that one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw a clip, because I was looking up recent Simpsons.
Speaker 0: But it's just going to keep going, I think.
Speaker 0: And that's because they're willing to, like, they change up the show a lot.
Speaker 0: But unlike Adventure Time, The Simpsons does not need to maintain a serious artistic continuity.
Speaker 0: It just needs to maintain a certain baseline level of humor.
Speaker 1: All right, so I got you-- Adventure Time's ending, great.
Speaker 1: I got a bunch of tiny newses, ready?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Tiny news number one.
Speaker 1: The Garbage New York Comic-Con is this weekend, I think?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: There's probably going to be a bunch of Wednesday news coming out of it that we're going to tell you about two weeks from now.
Speaker 0: I'm definitely not going to New York Comic-Con.
Speaker 1: But Rin won't be here two weeks from now, I don't think.
Speaker 1: So you're going to have to wait even longer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm flying to Sydney on Monday, and then I'll be back two Mondays later.
Speaker 1: So just read the internet for that news.
Speaker 1: Okay, second tiny news.
Speaker 1: Showing, I think, for like one night, or like-- It's a very limited engagement of Shin Gojira, also known as Gojira Resurgence, the live-action Godzilla movie that is made by Hideaki Anno.
Speaker 1: It looks like it's an amazing Godzilla movie, better than the other new one that came out recently in America.
Speaker 0: I would go see it.
Speaker 1: Based on the trailer alone, it looks like Evangelion only replaced the Avas with Godzilla.
Speaker 1: There's only one of them, and there's just a military only to fight it back, and not like another monster or something.
Speaker 1: It's like you watch the trailer, and it's like there are shots from Evangelion in the trailer, only with things changed and live-action.
Speaker 1: Even the glass shatters in the way he draws glass shattering.
Speaker 1: Anyway, also, Ms.
Speaker 1: Hogusai, new anime movie, is going to have a much less limited run that you can go see starting like two weeks from now or so.
Speaker 1: It's already had some preview screenings and whatnot.
Speaker 0: I mean, if you live in New York, you can see stuff like this pretty easy.
Speaker 1: The Makoto Shinkai movie, not screening in the U.S.
Speaker 1: yet, as far as I know, but apparently it's making big money in Japan, more money than I think any Makoto Shinkai movie has made previously, and more money than many, many other Japanese movies.
Speaker 0: Is that Kimi no Wa, that one?
Speaker 1: I don't know, the newest one.
Speaker 1: It's in Japanese theaters now.
Speaker 0: Your name, yeah.
Speaker 1: There's tons of, basically it's movie season in the anime world.
Speaker 1: Even though there's a new anime TV season, I looked at the chart, and even though we're not doing our thing, because it's not Anime Boston right now, I saw almost nothing on that chart.
Speaker 1: Like cancel your Crunchyroll, turn it back on next year, because there's nothing to see.
Speaker 0: I got to catch up on stuff that we reviewed or that looked good that I just haven't watched all the way through yet.
Speaker 1: If that's your situation.
Speaker 1: But right now, I got my Hulu on, because South Park.
Speaker 0: South Park.
Speaker 0: Hulu is basically pay for South Park.
Speaker 1: Well, there's also old movies to watch, but it's like, man, last year, you're watching South Park, and you're like, goddamn, how do they keep upping the whatever?
Speaker 1: They upped it even more.
Speaker 1: How could they do it?
Speaker 0: Scott, remember South Park?
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: Oh man, remember Adventure Time?
Speaker 1: Remember the Simpsons, when it was still good?
Speaker 0: Well, I think we'll be talking about South Park on the show at some point.
Speaker 1: We might have to do a South Park season review episode or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much from the last season onward, like as soon as, like, does she know she's an ad?
Speaker 0: Like the show just kicked into super gear.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: And it kind of started with the episode where Stan grew up, and everything looked like shit.
Speaker 0: That was the beginning of that.
Speaker 0: So, speaking of how, you know, we're not going to New York Comic Con, because, like, no lie, it sucks.
Speaker 0: Like, we live here.
Speaker 0: It's not worth going to.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like an anti-convention.
Speaker 0: There is going to be a new New York Anime Convention.
Speaker 0: that is not the New York Anime Festival, which was run by and then thrown into the ground by the Reed Expositions of New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: So now, Left Field Media, which looks like it's going to be pretty good, we'll see, has an all-star cast on the back end of the kinds of people who run conventions.
Speaker 1: It's sponsored by all the American anime companies, and they've managed to rent out the Javits, which is not easy to do.
Speaker 0: And they're launching November 17th through 19th, 2017, so next year, Anime NYC.
Speaker 0: And I can guarantee we will be there doing panels.
Speaker 1: So it seems like, you know, I'm going to go, but it's like, are they trying to make something good, or are they trying to make Anime Expo of the East?
Speaker 0: So, I know there's things I can't talk about, because I independently, a bunch of people who work for this convention reached out to me separately, like, "Oh, hey, by the way, this is where I ended
Speaker 0: up.".
Speaker 0: So, that's why I say it's an all-star cast of people who know what the fuck they're doing.
Speaker 1: They're half the people, like people that we know, because that's how it is.
Speaker 1: And there are other anime conventions in New York.
Speaker 1: There's actually one recently in a hotel.
Speaker 1: It was really dumpy.
Speaker 0: I was going to submit panels, and I forgot.
Speaker 1: It had almost no guests or anything that I've ever heard of.
Speaker 1: But I walked out of my office one day, because the hotel is like two blocks from my office, and a cosplayer walked by, and I was like, "That looks really
Speaker 1: familiar.".
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Oh, right, I remember.
Speaker 1: There's that really garbagey con in a hotel near my
Speaker 1: office.".
Speaker 1: Now, I think this one will succeed, and the main reason-- This is a real convention.
Speaker 0: Even when the New York Comic-Con ruined the New York Anime Festival, and just kind of relegated to that weird ghetto, a lot of people went to the New York Comic-Con just for that.
Speaker 1: So, if this is the closest likelihood-- But will they have a marketing budget where it will get enough people to come in, but they didn't spend so much money on marketing that they can pay the Javits bill?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it looks like it's backed by real company and everything, but if ever there will be an anime convention that gets run the way PAX is run, this is the closest thing to it.
Speaker 0: So, either this is going to be the PAX of anime cons, or it's possible it'll be an anime expo of the East, and we'll go to the first one and never go back.
Speaker 1: Sure, but I think what we can do is if all of us anime-type peoples who are good and make good anime-con stuffs all come to this con and support it and make it happen, this is our chance.
Speaker 1: We can make the con good.
Speaker 1: We don't have to completely stand back and say, "Is this con gonna be
Speaker 1: good?".
Speaker 1: We can try to make it good with our token efforts.
Speaker 0: Like, I gotta whisper in the right ears to make sure that if we're gonna do panels, Anime World Order is gonna--.
Speaker 0: Let's just put in a moderate effort to try to make it good.
Speaker 0: Like, get him to take my tool and get my hotel room and come in.
Speaker 1: And if it still sucks, then alright, fuck it.
Speaker 1: But, you know, for one year, for one con, for a con that's in town and we're easy to get to because it's in New York City, the center of the world-- Country World.
Speaker 0: Funimation, Viz, Kinokuniya are the four main sponsors so far.
Speaker 0: So, every company that cares about anime and manga in the
Speaker 0: U.S.--
Speaker 0: Leftfield Media founder Greg Tapalian and Leftfield Media's head of content, Peter Tatara, are organizing the convention.
Speaker 0: Oh, good, I'd say, yeah, they're both formally affiliated with ReadPop, New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, these people know what's up.
Speaker 0: But, anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So, a while ago, 'cause Halloween's coming up and drone technology got pretty good, I posited that this might be the Halloween of skeleton drone pranks.
Speaker 1: Sounds good to me.
Speaker 0: Now, I feel like the perfect form of a skeleton drone prank is-- Wouldn't it be easier to do a ghost, though?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the skull-- You basically put an umbrella over the--.
Speaker 1: Would that still be able to fly with an umbrella?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, basically, my ideal prank is you have a light foam skull, a really good-looking one, and you hang it from a string in the bottom of a drone.
Speaker 1: You fly up-- You make the drone all black.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And you have a glowy skull from the bottom of it, and you fly the drone around, and it looks like a-- And you need some LEDs--.
Speaker 1: It looks like a skull that's floating around.
Speaker 0: It needs some LED lights, like little ones.
Speaker 1: And you put some noise-making, so it sounds like--.
Speaker 0: But, basically, yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: But what you do, here's to make a key.
Speaker 0: It's gotta fly up to a second or third or higher story window.
Speaker 0: Bonus points in an apartment building if you're, like, six or seven stories up, because, think of this, if you're-- Think of this, if I'm in my apartment, and I'm asleep, and I'm over, we're pretty high up, and suddenly I hear something tapping on the window of a skyscraper, and I hear a weird noise-- There you go.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna get up, I'll blur you out.
Speaker 1: Here's the problem, as a drone makes noise, I think you need to dangle the skeleton from, like, a somewhat, like, fishing line.
Speaker 0: Oh, the skull's gotta dangle, like, ten feet.
Speaker 1: So the drone can be higher, where the person won't necessarily hear it or notice it, and the skeleton can be free-swinging.
Speaker 0: But, I mean, the seven train's right out there.
Speaker 0: In a building like this, the windows do not let sound through, but if you tap them, you'll hear it.
Speaker 1: Well, also, it's mad illegal to fly drones almost anywhere in the city.
Speaker 0: I am not concerned with the legality of my skull drone prank.
Speaker 1: Uh, but I-- This is the only reason I have not gotten into drone as a hobby, because I live in pretty much the only place where that's an illegal hobby.
Speaker 1: Yeah, same-- If I moved out to the sticks, I'd probably buy some drones.
Speaker 0: Similar reason why, as much as I like model rockets, I don't make model rockets anymore.
Speaker 1: There is a Kickstarter, though, for--.
Speaker 1: Remember the Vortex football?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: It was basically a football with wings on the back.
Speaker 1: It would be-- It was easy to throw it in a spiral.
Speaker 1: They basically made this thing.
Speaker 1: that's like a vortex, and you shove your GoPro in the front, and then you throw it.
Speaker 0: I saw that.
Speaker 1: And that's great, because there's nowhere.
Speaker 1: that's, you know, illegal.
Speaker 0: You could use that on a ski slope.
Speaker 1: You could use it anywhere, pretty much.
Speaker 1: So, uh, it's a lot of money, though, for a piece of foam.
Speaker 0: But that's the key.
Speaker 1: You've got to-- Which is why I didn't buy it, but it'd be really cool, like, you know, to throw it at certain places with, like, a large crowd.
Speaker 1: Like, you go to PAX tabletop, throw it, have your friend catch it, and you get a good shot.
Speaker 0: No, you'll get this video of someone catching it and running away with your camera.
Speaker 1: You throw it to your friend.
Speaker 0: Uh-oh.
Speaker 0: Someone intercepts.
Speaker 0: [laughter] Drone camera interception.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I hope you're going for some height so you can get a good-- But just imagine that.
Speaker 0: You're in a skyscraper.
Speaker 0: You hear something tapping on the window.
Speaker 0: You open the blend, and there's a skull swinging forward at your face out the window.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty good.
Speaker 0: So, this person-- I was looking around.
Speaker 0: This is the best drone skeleton prank to date.
Speaker 1: And the way they got-- Is it up to our expectations, or is it just--.
Speaker 0: So, the way they did it is they put the skull on top of the drone, and they have the eyes light up, and the drone noise kind of makes it sound like it's screaming.
Speaker 0: And then they hung all these streamers down.
Speaker 0: so it looks like this giant thing that's floating and-- Don't the streamers get caught in the blades?
Speaker 0: Uh, no, it actually works pretty well.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: And it works--.
Speaker 1: I can see the wind from the blades is blowing the streamers.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's pretty good.
Speaker 0: And think, it looks creepy.
Speaker 0: Like, look, people are walking, and suddenly it comes around the corner.
Speaker 1: [laughter] But it's obviously a drone is the problem.
Speaker 0: It is obviously a drone after your first reaction.
Speaker 0: So, you go,
Speaker 0: "Whoa!"
Speaker 0: and freak out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's not scaring people, like, really.
Speaker 1: That's just sort of like jump out, go,
Speaker 1: "Boo!"
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 0: If you put the-- No, it's got two levels.
Speaker 1: If you had the drone way up high, and the skeleton on a string way down low, the effect would be floating fucking skeleton hole.
Speaker 1: It would be a double effect, right?
Speaker 1: You could surprise them, and then, "Oh, my--".
Speaker 1: There's no way you would know what is going on.
Speaker 1: First, your brain would be surprised, and then your brain would register.
Speaker 1: There is no explanation for what I'm seeing in front of me, other than floating skeleton with no seemingly human thing attached to it.
Speaker 1: It would be a really good magic trick that fools you, the way a magician cuts someone in half, and your brain is totally fooled.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's got to be a good knife for flying.
Speaker 0: So, this is the best I've seen anyone do yet.
Speaker 1: So, all of you out there-- Step it up to the level which we describe, people who are allowed to have drones.
Speaker 0: Don't get arrested, and I didn't tell you to do this.
Speaker 0: I got nothing to do with you.
Speaker 0: if you get in trouble, but do it.
Speaker 1: Go for it.
Speaker 1: A better thing of the day.
Speaker 1: So, remember the last time I had a thing of the day about how to smash the garlics?
Speaker 0: That was pretty good.
Speaker 0: I remember that.
Speaker 1: I remember.
Speaker 1: Here is something else garlic-related.
Speaker 1: Rem, do you know what aioli is?
Speaker 0: I know what aioli is.
Speaker 0: It's the thing that is on the best of the burgers that I get at the fancy places.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: Do you know how to make aioli?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: I imagine you'd use a grind of a bunch of garlic.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: So, apparently most places that say they're giving you aioli, and most recipes, even Blue Apron-- I did a Blue Apron recipe once that had me make aioli.
Speaker 1: Almost all aioli that you will get in the United States, or in most places, period, is pretty much just mayonnaise with garlic smashed up and mixed together, right?
Speaker 1: With maybe something else, like salt and pepper, who knows what, right?
Speaker 1: But mostly it's mayonnaise plus garlic.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: I don't like mayonnaise, but that is actually quite delicious.
Speaker 1: No one's gonna complain about that.
Speaker 1: No one's saying it tastes bad.
Speaker 1: But actually, if you are a pedant or a food snob, that is not aioli.
Speaker 1: That is not what aioli actually is.
Speaker 1: That is just garlic mayonnaise.
Speaker 1: Real aioli is nothing but oil and garlic emulsified and such.
Speaker 1: So the way to make it is-- I see what he's doing here.
Speaker 1: You take some garlic, and you mortar and pestle it, and then you add, you know, a little salt, which helps smash the garlic and also get the flavor out.
Speaker 1: And then you add the oil, and you smash it some more.
Speaker 0: I've got some oil.
Speaker 0: And you keep adding oil and smashing-- I've got some garlic.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Garlic oil.
Speaker 1: You keep adding oil and smashing and oil and smashing so that, you know, if you add oil to oil at once, you'll get the oil separating from the garlic, and then you've ruined it.
Speaker 1: You have to add a little bit at a time so that all the oil emulsifies into the paste, and that's the real aioli.
Speaker 1: So I had to go on Amazon and buy a mortar and pestle.
Speaker 1: They're pretty cheap.
Speaker 0: I've got a real nice one that we use occasionally.
Speaker 1: This one that I saw on Amazon, there was quite a few to choose from, and they all had high ratings, so they were all effectively perfect.
Speaker 0: It's hard to fuck up a mortar and pestle.
Speaker 1: But the one that I picked was a really good one that is, like, ceramic.
Speaker 1: The stone ones you think are, like, the better ones, but actually the stone ones, even though they're nice and heavy and get the job done, some of them will, like, release, you know, chalk into the food.
Speaker 1: In very small amounts, you won't even notice.
Speaker 1: It's not a real concern.
Speaker 1: But there were some ceramic ones, and the reason I like the ceramic one better is it had rubber grippies, so they don't move around on you.
Speaker 1: And they were the same price, so who cares?
Speaker 1: So I bought one on Amazon.
Speaker 1: I'm going to make some real aiolis and put it on some delicious meats.
Speaker 1: But here's a video showing you how to do this, and there you go.
Speaker 1: You learned something about foods.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: In a moment, the Book Club book is Rebecca.
Speaker 0: Rebecca.
Speaker 0: And I did a little -- I was just -- I kept looking at it.
Speaker 0: I figured out.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: Now I'm going to read the book, and then we'll do the review of it.
Speaker 0: But I watched some clips from the movie "Rebecca," just a couple of clips from this, like, Hitchcock thing, and I'm pretty sure I figured out why my kid brain conflated the two movies together.
Speaker 0: There are a large number of extremely superficial similarities if your kid brain is looking at the movie from the shallowest perspective.
Speaker 0: But otherwise, I'm going to be in Australia for the next two weeks, and Emily and I will be recording stuff while I'm there, and then we'll resume Geek Night as soon as I get back.
Speaker 1: I'm going to make a bunch of content because I got nothing else to do, so I'm going to make mad videos and shit.
Speaker 0: Unfortunately, I'm not there for PAX.
Speaker 0: I'm there for this other unrelated thing, and I'm flying home right before PAX, Why wouldn't you stay there for the PAX?
Speaker 0: Because I would have had to stay for a whole 'nother week in between, and I would have been gone for over a month in the end.
Speaker 0: I would have been gone for one month, and it's real hard to disrupt your adult life for an entire month.
Speaker 1: Also, I think the visa that I had, was it 90 days?
Speaker 1: I forget if the automatic sign-up online visa was long enough for that.
Speaker 0: I sign up for the business one online, but I can stay there for three months.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's plenty of time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's plenty of time.
Speaker 0: But also, our video from our most recent PAX panel, Grinding, is up on the YouTube-y.
Speaker 1: And not the mortar and pestle kind.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: Well, I used that image from South Park of them grinding up in World of Warcraft, so that kind of grinding.
Speaker 0: And we're going to be at MagFest doing a whole bunch of panels.
Speaker 0: We're still sorting all that out, but we will be there.
Speaker 0: And PAX South, pretty much going to say we're going to be there at this point.
Speaker 0: I mean...
Speaker 1: I just bought plane tickets.
Speaker 1: We won't know... So if they don't accept my panel, and I already have a hotel and a plane ticket to go to San Antonio, so I'm sure I can buy a PAX South ticket second-hand, worst-case scenario.
Speaker 0: It'll be real weird if we go to a PAX and don't do a panel.
Speaker 1: I highly doubt.
Speaker 1: That's never happened.
Speaker 1: We were worried they wouldn't accept our prime panel, and they did.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure we're going to safely get our South panel accepted.
Speaker 1: Dude, I just...
Speaker 0: I can't ever... I never assume these things.
Speaker 1: I don't assume, but I'm like 90% sure.
Speaker 1: I'm not... I'm secure enough that I do not feel like I have to buy a PAX South ticket.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: We also got to bring Dune there and play a high-stakes game of Dune, meaning we got to really learn the expert rules.
Speaker 1: We're going to bring lots of good stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm not playing baby Dune.
Speaker 0: I'm done with no baby mode.
Speaker 1: I'm done with baby mode on every game ever.
Speaker 0: But we have to play Dune with the full rules at least once before we go to this PAX.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: Because we've never played it with the real rules.
Speaker 1: And yet, four more people who are willing to sit there for that amount of time.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Working on it.
Speaker 1: And are serious gamers.
Speaker 0: So we needed a Wednesday show to do, and there's a bunch of anime I'm going to watch all the way through, but I've just been busy.
Speaker 0: I'm probably going to catch up on a lot of that when I'm traveling.
Speaker 0: But a lot of people, at least in my Twitter feed, have been talking about Mob Psycho 100.
Speaker 1: So I did not... I had not heard of the show.
Speaker 1: I had not seen anything about the show.
Speaker 1: I knew nothing.
Speaker 1: I didn't see a hype like I did when there was, say, like Madoka going on.
Speaker 1: But that was because I just didn't realize those tweets were about this show.
Speaker 1: There was a whole meme going on taking the character from this show and redrawing different situations from other media with him instead of whatever.
Speaker 1: And I did not realize that's what this was.
Speaker 0: That's why it was sort of... It was weird because I was like...
Speaker 1: But actually, I have to say, knowing the character now makes the meme less funny.
Speaker 1: It was funnier when I just knew that it was a character from an anime.
Speaker 1: And now that I know about that character, that meme is less funny to me.
Speaker 1: But I'm glad now.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen that meme in like a week.
Speaker 1: Well, because we moved on to that... I won't have any unfunny tweets in my feed.
Speaker 1: I got the maximum enjoyment from the meme.
Speaker 0: But if you were talking about Mob Psycho, I saw it all over the place.
Speaker 0: I guess Scott did too and just didn't realize it.
Speaker 1: Well, I only saw that meme.
Speaker 1: I didn't see anything else about it.
Speaker 0: And then I realized it's based on a webcomic by the same guy who did One Punch Man.
Speaker 1: So the guy who made One Punch Man made a not-so-good-looking webcomic.
Speaker 1: Still better than I can draw.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: And then One Punch Man, the real manga, is still written by him, but drawn by someone better at drawing.
Speaker 1: And then the anime by people who are even better, because they can animate.
Speaker 1: But he made a different webcomic, the original guy, called Mob Psycho 100.
Speaker 1: And this is an anime based on that.
Speaker 1: I don't think there is a better drawn manga version of Mob Psycho 100.
Speaker 1: There might be.
Speaker 0: I think there is, actually.
Speaker 1: Oh, there is?
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: I saw some people talking about the manga.
Speaker 0: I assume they refer to a real remade manga, not just the webcomic.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 0: I don't actually know.
Speaker 1: So Rym was like, "Watch
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 1: So then I remembered this morning, I hadn't watched it, so I watched it right before I went to work.
Speaker 0: I also watched one episode.
Speaker 1: I only watched one episode.
Speaker 1: And I don't know if one episode is enough to review.
Speaker 1: I mean, you could say it's not enough to review any show, but I'm not reviewing the whole show.
Speaker 1: But it's based on the preview to episode two.
Speaker 1: I don't think this show is going to have formulaic episodes where they're all the same.
Speaker 1: So I don't know if I'm going to... I'm only going to judge this first episode.
Speaker 1: I can't judge anything else.
Speaker 1: It's not one of those shows where it's like, "Ah, I can tell there's a shounen fighting show, and every episode is going to be the same
Speaker 1: deal.".
Speaker 1: You know, the first episode is just setting things up.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: What struck me, though, is that it started, and this will sound kind of weird, but it starts kind of in media res in this weird action scene that's not really explained, and then it sort of reveals implicitly later what it's actually about.
Speaker 0: But it was really colorful in a way that I don't often see.
Speaker 0: The action was just really stark, bright, vibrant colors.
Speaker 1: Well, I think what it is is the designs of the monsters and the spirits that they're fighting, the bad guys, basically, are really unique and interesting.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: They're not quite as good as the Monika ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They're still like the witches, but they're still really good, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, even just... You know, anime actually has a history of having lots of unique monsters and have Pokemons, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like this is yet another example of that done well, where all the bad guys are unique and different and really cool-looking.
Speaker 0: All the normal characters are, too.
Speaker 0: True to this style, every character has a very, very unique character design.
Speaker 1: But they all have the characteristic, you know, bottom half of a circle eyeballs that are unique to the one-punch man guy.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But the story basically is about this kid Mob, and it basically means, like...
Speaker 1: They told us his real name, but apparently that doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: The descriptions say straight up that that is a term for background characters.
Speaker 1: Interesting.
Speaker 0: That is used, apparently, in anime, but it means like background character, effectively.
Speaker 1: Oh, like mobs, like an MMO.
Speaker 1: I guess.
Speaker 0: I'm not actually sure.
Speaker 1: Like farming mobs.
Speaker 0: But he's a, quote, "He's a boy who will explode if his emotional capacity reaches
Speaker 0: 100%.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I don't know how they quantify that, but I guess they do.
Speaker 0: But what's interesting is you watch the first episode and there's a point where there's like the eye-catch.
Speaker 0: It shows the... And it basically shows what his number is now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it keeps showing his numbers.
Speaker 1: And I imagine... Is someone there with a scouter, like, showing you?
Speaker 0: There are only...
Speaker 1: Is that 99,000?
Speaker 0: And in the opening, like, set, it basically shows him as a psychic demon entity fighting increasingly dire monsters in this crazy psychic world.
Speaker 1: But being so powerful that he just beats them all, no problem.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And the numbers keep going up.
Speaker 1: And when it gets to 100, he explodes.
Speaker 1: It's like, whoa, and destroys everything.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So you know what the opening theme's title is?
Speaker 1: So the key is it's like a video game where you have to, like, make sure you hit 100 when there's a monster nearby that's so strong you couldn't beat it and it gets beat by the explosion and then you're back to zero and you're good.
Speaker 0: Maybe, or maybe it ends the world.
Speaker 0: But you don't want to offend the gods by having a number too high.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: But you know what the name of the opening theme is?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Nice.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Nice, okay.
Speaker 0: So there's only two ways the show can go.
Speaker 0: Either the number goes up and down every episode based on what happens.
Speaker 1: It's only gone up as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: Or the number keeps going up and then if it keeps going up, there's only two ways the show can go.
Speaker 0: Either it never hits 100 in the show until the very end or it hits it halfway through and the show goes way off the rails.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: you know he's going to explode when it hits 100.
Speaker 1: They, like, reveal that right away.
Speaker 1: It's not like some mystery, like, "What happens when it hits
Speaker 1: 100?"
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: It's like in the title of the show is the number 100.
Speaker 1: They show you the number.
Speaker 1: They show you it hitting 100 and exploding.
Speaker 1: So it's just like, when and where is he going to be at that point?
Speaker 1: and what does the explosion mean in the real world versus, like, the spirit world where it just killed all the bad guys near him.
Speaker 0: Yep, and we already know from the first episode that all these spirits are legit dangerous to regular people.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, some of them are more good or evil, but they're all really powerful and dangerous and are totally real.
Speaker 0: And I like his sidekick because basically there's this other guy who pretends to be a sidekick.
Speaker 1: It's like they tell you that Mob is the protagonist of this show, but based on episode one, he's not.
Speaker 1: It's really this other guy.
Speaker 0: And the other guy is a sidekick investigator.
Speaker 1: What's his name?
Speaker 0: I don't even remember.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: But he sucks.
Speaker 1: Is it Reigen or something like that?
Speaker 1: Something like that.
Speaker 1: I could be wrong.
Speaker 1: Probably wrong.
Speaker 0: He either is not sidekick or is barely sidekick.
Speaker 0: What was the guy in Gatekeepers who didn't have any powers?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but basically he's just a con artist.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 0: He's sort of a con artist, but at the same time, he knows this shit is real.
Speaker 0: Like this is a world where there's a Uri Geller type who's totally faking it.
Speaker 0: But demons and spirits are real.
Speaker 0: He does know that.
Speaker 1: So he has knowledge, right?
Speaker 1: He's not stupid.
Speaker 1: He's just sort of mildly malicious, right?
Speaker 1: It's like he does.
Speaker 0: He's just trying to make a buck in this crazy world.
Speaker 1: He's trying to make money, but he's not completely a coward.
Speaker 1: He goes in and throws salt ineffectively at these monsters.
Speaker 0: I love when he's like, "Now I'll
Speaker 0: attack."
Speaker 0: And he does his special attack and it does the fist of the North Star cutaway.
Speaker 1: I mean, he is somewhat cowardly.
Speaker 1: He's like, "Hey, you go fight this
Speaker 1: monster.".
Speaker 1: But he's not completely cowardly, like he's running away and shit.
Speaker 0: Well, like when the kid throws up the shield and defeats the boss demon.
Speaker 0: And I like how the demon was just a boss.
Speaker 1: He's the boss.
Speaker 0: But right there, he realizes immediately how the kid put up the shield.
Speaker 0: And then he just totally acts like a super badass in front of the demon.
Speaker 0: Like, "Yeah, don't fuck with
Speaker 0: me.".
Speaker 1: And he's not 100% evil.
Speaker 1: He's ripping people off and making them pay him a bunch of money.
Speaker 1: But he is actually trying to fight the demons.
Speaker 1: And giving the kid only a little bit of money.
Speaker 1: Probably when the kid deserves more of the money.
Speaker 0: He's doing what any corporation would do.
Speaker 1: But he is legitimately trying to go and help.
Speaker 1: He wants to get rid of the demons and help the people.
Speaker 1: And also what he's selling.
Speaker 1: And he's also being really comedic.
Speaker 1: It's weird, right?
Speaker 1: Because you know how I always complain about that character?
Speaker 1: My example is always the John Goodman from Big Lebowski.
Speaker 1: Where it's like that guy who's just so... You know, and it's like that's...
Speaker 0: Like if they were real and in the room with you, you would want to stab them in the throat.
Speaker 1: It's like they just need to be stabbed in the throat.
Speaker 1: This guy is really weird.
Speaker 1: Because this character of this guy, he's half that.
Speaker 1: But he's half actually funny.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like usually the characters in comedies these days are 100% that guy that I can't stand and it's not funny.
Speaker 1: But this guy, he's only... Like half the time I'm like... Like when he's ripping... When he's hitting the kid like a few hundred yens, I'm like, "Oh you
Speaker 1: motherfucker.".
Speaker 1: But then, he does something actually funny.
Speaker 0: And I'm like...
Speaker 1: So I only half hate him and half like him.
Speaker 0: But I love his attack because he's like, "My whatever salt
Speaker 0: attack.".
Speaker 0: And then it's like, "That was one of his special
Speaker 0: attacks.".
Speaker 0: He just violently throws salt all around.
Speaker 1: Now here's the thing that I thought was really... I actually laughed at a lot.
Speaker 1: Is that the first Spirit guy is like, "It only works if you have purified
Speaker 1: salt.".
Speaker 1: Not grocery store salt.
Speaker 1: And then it was funny again because he does like a salt punch where he fills his fist with... And the demon is like,
Speaker 1: "Ahh!"
Speaker 1: "Oh, that didn't
Speaker 1: hurt.".
Speaker 1: But the thing is... Why didn't he just go get some purified... If purified salt works, why don't you get some purified salt?
Speaker 0: Because he kind of sucks.
Speaker 1: Get some purified salt.
Speaker 1: If you were just told that it works, why don't you get some?
Speaker 1: But he's basically conning Mob also.
Speaker 1: And it's like you can't tell... Mob isn't stupid, but he is.
Speaker 1: He has bad grades in school and shit.
Speaker 1: He's not that smart.
Speaker 0: He's like below average at everything.
Speaker 1: He's bad at school, but that doesn't... But he's not stupid.
Speaker 0: He's not a stupid person.
Speaker 1: He's just not good at school.
Speaker 1: So does he realize he's being conned or not?
Speaker 1: It's like...
Speaker 0: Is Avash the stampede thing?
Speaker 0: Does he know what he's doing?
Speaker 1: Is he doing this just because this guy will conveniently call him to where the spirits are?
Speaker 0: And also, I like how the guy... The guy's obviously acting like he knows way more than he does and that he's a super psychic.
Speaker 1: But he knows stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but he acts like the kid will point things out where he's wrong.
Speaker 0: And he is legit good as a character, in character, at deflecting that the way that, say, I would if I was lying to someone.
Speaker 1: I was just about to say, rim style, and that's the half of him that I hate.
Speaker 0: But it works!
Speaker 1: That's the hateful half.
Speaker 0: Usually when a show does something like that, it's not like no one would fall for that shit.
Speaker 0: But he does it right.
Speaker 0: He's lying the way a real liar would lie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he has... He has some chrismas and powers of some kind.
Speaker 1: He's not just this completely useless guy who's just like an annoying leech, right?
Speaker 1: He has some use.
Speaker 0: And also, you know, he's not actually even ripping off the people he's selling to, because he's very clear.
Speaker 0: For this small fee, he doesn't charge a lot.
Speaker 0: He'll reduce the spirit activity by some percent, and like 20% is the best he can hope for.
Speaker 0: I'll bet that his service before he had Mob was about that effective.
Speaker 1: Well, I think what he does a lot that they sort of imply but don't show is that people come in to his business, and their problem isn't actually a spirit, and he pretends to beat the spirit and takes their money and rips them off.
Speaker 1: And he only calls Mob when he shows up at the scene, and there actually are real spirits there.
Speaker 1: So that's his evil part, right?
Speaker 0: Because it might also be that...
Speaker 1: He basically just sells nonsense to people.
Speaker 0: Because when the monsters come, he's just like, "Well, there's
Speaker 0: one.".
Speaker 1: Like, imagine if the Ghostbusters show up, and there's a Slimer there.
Speaker 1: So they fucking catch it, and they charge you money.
Speaker 1: But if you call them and you just think there's a ghost and there's a loud noise, imagine if they put on an act where they caught a ghost and then took your money.
Speaker 1: That's what this guy does in his spirit.
Speaker 1: You know, he just doesn't call Mob for those jobs.
Speaker 1: Now, the animation is great.
Speaker 0: Like, the fighting and the monsters and everything.
Speaker 0: Like, I like this show a lot, and it was legit funny.
Speaker 1: It's modern, good, decent animations.
Speaker 1: I think the best part about it, like I already said, though, is the character designs, especially on the monsters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but also the people.
Speaker 0: Like, I'm looking at Crunchyroll the rest of the episodes.
Speaker 0: Like, there's Milhouse, just has a blockhead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's the designs and also the expressions.
Speaker 1: But the actual drawing quality is... it's okay.
Speaker 0: It's above average, I'd say.
Speaker 0: It's modern.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, average is bad.
Speaker 0: The color scheme and the action is really well done.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's alright.
Speaker 1: It's not a fucking masterpiece.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna watch a bunch more episodes, and if it stays good through the first four, then I'm just gonna watch the whole thing.
Speaker 1: It's like, I could watch more.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't mind watching more, but I don't have a super strong... I only have a slight desire to watch more, right?
Speaker 1: Like, I kinda wanna watch more, but if there's like five shows to watch, it's not gonna jump the queue or anything.
Speaker 0: I had a pretty strong desire to watch episode two just because I laughed a lot at episode one.
Speaker 1: Well, I have a slightly greater desire just to see episode two and maybe not three, because the preview for episode two made it seem like it wasn't gonna be a formulaic show.
Speaker 0: Also, there are only twelve episodes.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's good.
Speaker 1: So it felt like it was gonna be formulaic.
Speaker 1: Like, each episode, there's a spirit and they deal with it, right?
Speaker 1: But if it breaks that formula and the episodes do something different, then I would wanna watch it a lot more.
Speaker 0: I mean, the next episode is doubts about youth.
Speaker 0: Episode four is idiots only event.
Speaker 0: There's a cult or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it looks like it escalates.
Speaker 1: Right, so I guess being written by the one-punch guy, you sorta have to compare it to one-punch man, because there are some similarities, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, the kid is a one-punch psychic.
Speaker 1: Right, the kid is one-punch... He's basically one-punching the spirits.
Speaker 1: He's so strong, the spirits can't even compete with him, right?
Speaker 1: But, even though you have this really powerful character who's kinda quiet, the fact that he's so powerful isn't, you know, a plot point, isn't the key motivation, the way one-punch man's, you know, Cy Thomas' key motivation is the fact that he's so powerful, right?
Speaker 1: And also, you know, the Genos character, you know, the secondary character in one-punch man, it's like, you know, he's got a thing going on, but he's less of a character than the con artist in Mob Psycho is.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, Mob Psycho really is the sort of duality of these two characters, whereas one-punch man is like Cy Thomas and Genos is definitely a second fiddle.
Speaker 1: This is two equal fiddles going on.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna give the show a big chance and I'll keep watching it until I get bored.
Speaker 0: Twelve episodes, I'll probably watch the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: I don't wanna say this is, I can't say yet that this is a must-watch scenario, but it's like, look, this anime season is pretty bad, so if you've already seen all the old animes and you wanna watch a new anime, this is the newest anime I've seen that I haven't seen all of that, you know, I
Speaker 0: haven't already told you to watch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like, of the new animes that I have not seen all of, this is the newest and best yet, so why not?
Speaker 1: Twelve episodes, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yup, I got the C-rollo watching.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights in order of the amount of money they give us on the continuing basis are Ellen Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Nicholas Brando, Heidi McNichol, Amanda Duchette, Christian Koontz, Construction Noises, Ivy Faye, MyStady.com, William Eisendrills, Jeremy Biner, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: James David White, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, Old Man Scott Is Old Man, Aaron Cerise, Brian Fisher, Sailor Vister, Jai Fried Pork, Matthew Smith, Don Schleich, Shartavishan, Joshua Joestar, Tyler Eller, Sean Yeager, Sam Cordry, Clinton Walton, Wren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Ray LaValle, Brian Cedroni, Finn Eric Silveraude, The Rural Juror, Chris Minkiff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: I know I'm going to be in Australia, but don't worry, I'm going to be making a bunch of content while I'm there.
Speaker 0: I'm going to try to queue up a bunch of stuff to release while I'm there, while I'm still here in the States.
Speaker 0: And after that, then things will calm down again through the holidays, and we're going to keep trying to make more content.
Speaker 0: A bunch of the Patreon things are going to start coming out and increasing frequency.
Speaker 0: And don't forget that I'm reading all of Castlevania 2, the novelization Simon's Quest by FX9.
Speaker 0: But anyway, now I leave you with this.
Speaker 0: Wake up!
Speaker 1: So let's just say...
Speaker 0: Oh, well I hate to be a bummer, I brought you here to bring me... How about you know those brothers?
Speaker 0: Oh, it's their names.
Speaker 0: Oh yes, Mario and Luigi, just the sound of them makes me queasy, I love them.
Speaker 0: Take that monkey wrench, I'll play my own game.
Speaker 0: Princess Toad!
Speaker 0: You're so misguided!
Speaker 1: I've never been found the one who's a faggot, and this one does make good Mario weight!
Speaker 0: Oh, I can't wait.
Speaker 0: Ignorance is blessed.
Speaker 0: With my magic book I'll shower those clumsy lizards with my power until Dinosaur Land is nothing but fossil fuel.
Speaker 0: My only problem with these spells is that I know not what they tell, so every hex leaves me perplexed and all I want are those plumbing fools.
Speaker 0: Princess Toad!
Speaker 0: You're not so clever!