Speaker 1: It's Tuesday October 25th 2016.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We are back.
Speaker 1: We're bad and it's time to talk about civilization.
Speaker 1: 6.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I was as I said in Australia for a couple weeks on a trip to a much less fun convention than packs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know you're in Australia.
Speaker 0: It was warm here.
Speaker 1: now as soon as you get back woman's cold Yep, but the one thing that's going for me is the back wall.
Speaker 1: I don't need you know what's going on in Australia like the height of spring.
Speaker 1: So Sydney smelled like nothing but flowers like it was just amazing there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was smelled pretty good here too.
Speaker 0: The Sun was out It was like 70 80 degrees and then you got back and now it's 50 40 degrees.
Speaker 1: yeah, but basically I got two Springs and I got to my mountain biking and like all the biz and then I had to Home because I couldn't justify staying in Australia for two more weeks just to go to packs.
Speaker 1: Why not cuz I had shit to do like in my real life Never mind work stuff, and I didn't want to blow two weeks of vacation.
Speaker 1: I only get 25 days of vacation.
Speaker 1: I don't want to blow at all.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I'm back and I'm missing packs off.
Speaker 1: So I think what I think my plan I don't know if you want to do it or not is just I'll start starting next year I'll go back to packs off and I'm gonna try to go every other year.
Speaker 1: 2018.
Speaker 0: we already decided we're gonna go to essence and in 2018.
Speaker 1: We also decided we're gonna start our own con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah February though.
Speaker 1: That's that doesn't.
Speaker 1: that's literally not in the way of anything.
Speaker 1: We do better get started right now.
Speaker 1: I've been working on it.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 1: I've been talking to people working on the find a place.
Speaker 0: Then we the rest of the work is that place in Brooklyn's looking pretty good.
Speaker 0: Actually, I thought you said they didn't pick up The phone they did.
Speaker 1: now they actually got back to me.
Speaker 1: Okay, I got some initial talkings.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to get an indicative quote Which is the only thing table rental or they gonna call someone else because all I really need is Tables and then maybe AV rental.
Speaker 1: Yep tables AV and maybe like a couple of screens and things like that comes from the AV rent?
Speaker 1: No, no, not not.
Speaker 1: projection screens blocking one area off from another area screens.
Speaker 1: You don't want just one big room.
Speaker 1: That's all that always feels.
Speaker 0: remember that usually comes at the table rental.
Speaker 1: Remember anime next.
Speaker 1: how weird it felt was just big one giant open room of nonsense.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm sure they have dividers built into the walls also.
Speaker 1: Yeah So anyway, that's all that's all going good.
Speaker 1: But we're finally back and we got to be real careful not to blow our entire load of new stuff.
Speaker 0: That's all right.
Speaker 0: We don't.
Speaker 0: usually you know, I look I thought back and I look back.
Speaker 0: We don't blow our load of stuff.
Speaker 0: What happens is we forget stuff just forget everything.
Speaker 0: So the first time we do a show we have things you remembered, you know from like.
Speaker 0: like you can only remember a few days Back, so right now we haven't done a show but I can remember more of my life than a few days back Like something.
Speaker 0: we something that happened like two days after the last show.
Speaker 0: we did like.
Speaker 0: there's probably something great and we just forgot it.
Speaker 1: well The most reliable way to ensure that we don't do a show on something is for one of us to say that's a great idea for the next n-day show.
Speaker 1: That guarantees we will not talk about it for at least two or three years.
Speaker 0: write it down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got a Google Keep and the only good idea we've got that we have definitely not forgotten is one that requires some work.
Speaker 1: So we haven't done it yet.
Speaker 1: You know what that idea was.
Speaker 1: It's a Thursday idea.
Speaker 1: Things of the day the all things of the day show.
Speaker 1: the best of the plan is will each come to the table with our Ten?
Speaker 1: from all the things it has to be the rule is has to be a thing of the day that you yourself Used on a previous geek night.
Speaker 0: that's still around that still exists.
Speaker 1: And then but if the link is broken, but you find it again, that's okay.
Speaker 1: Like the tapestry generator is up again In fact, it keeps going down.
Speaker 1: and whenever it comes back the video of our beyond D&D panel where we lamented that it's gone People keep commenting there linking to when it comes back.
Speaker 1: So that is how I keep finding it.
Speaker 1: So in the tiniest news and relevant to my trip One thing I did on the trip is cuz at my laptop is I played an entire game of Civ 5 on One of the flights like start to finish.
Speaker 1: No one of course against the AI is like I always do.
Speaker 0: and the hardest difficulty no fuck deity mode.
Speaker 1: It's not fun Emperor.
Speaker 1: it's yeah, I play.
Speaker 1: I pretty much always play King or Emperor depending on what kind of game I'm looking for.
Speaker 0: I can win King Rarely, really.
Speaker 1: I win King a hundred percent of the time no matter what like.
Speaker 1: it's not even a question of.
Speaker 1: the question is only Which sieve do I pick and how do I choose to win?
Speaker 1: Assuming eight player continents normal speed Emperor I win about.
Speaker 1: I want to say 45 percent of the time Unless I play one of my go-to saves like Portugal agrees.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I could win ever.
Speaker 0: I'd have to like try But yeah I'm like afraid to try it cuz like I'll just get killed right away.
Speaker 1: It sucks because the AI just gets crazy cheat and the only way to win at all is to hyper optimize like you're literally like optimizing for Individual great people and calculating how many turns they'll take for you to get them and that kind of nonsense
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 1: so but we'll get to that because I played.
Speaker 1: basically I am like peeking my sieve.
Speaker 1: five play Just as sieve six came out.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I've got three remaining giant multiplayer robot games going opposite five And I think that big game is to five that I played against the AI's on the flights Will be my last single players to five game.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna run out all my sieve five GM ours because they're all really good and After that ends that's gonna be the end of it.
Speaker 1: But my news is that there was a tweet from the giant multiplayer robot People saying that initial testing against the civilization six hot seat save file Confirms that they will very likely be able to provide the exact same service for sieve six.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 1: That's real good because the initial reports I've not tried it yet of Because we did not test this so we can't talk about it in our actual show on sieve six.
Speaker 1: so it coats in the news section of the show is That it works fine in that it works as well as the sieve five.
Speaker 1: one should have worked meaning It doesn't just crash like it did in sieve five like it actually works But it's still not good.
Speaker 1: sieve has never had good multiplayer and giant multiplayer robot is the only way to reliably play Asynchronous multiplayer of a civilization game in the world.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much the only way to do it.
Speaker 1: So my news is I will be able to continue doing it as soon as it is stable And I know enough about sieve six to not be a dumb moron at it.
Speaker 1: I think I'm gonna start a sieve six giant multiplayer robot game, and we'll all play it together.
Speaker 0: I think the one problem with all sieves, but it's you know.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's better or worse in sieve six But is that there are certain things in sieve six like that you can build or do and the bonus for doing them Is that it curries you favor with or against?
Speaker 0: the AI opponents yeah get right.
Speaker 1: so the problem with sieve five is that the the Diplomacy against a eyes was just like you could just game it heavily Right and now.
Speaker 0: so for example in sieve six you might want to like put a bunch of Envoys to a particular city-state, but if another empire has a bunch of envoys there And you out envoy them they get pissed and it's like the penalty for doing that.
Speaker 0: yeah against real people that penalty is gone.
Speaker 0: And I guess the balance of the game.
Speaker 0: They don't change the rules when you're playing multiplayer for a single and they need to Account for the fact that there are no a eyes involved.
Speaker 1: so having played it's interesting.
Speaker 1: We'll get to it in the main show, but having played a lot of multiplayer sieve five and sieve four and also having played a lot of single-player the Sieve six is has a lot more ways to interact with the a eyes like way way way more
Speaker 0: tons more
Speaker 1: and they're so Integral to the game that I don't know how that's gonna play out.
Speaker 1: actually.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean there are sieves that got mad at me because I chose a different government than them.
Speaker 0: right But if you're playing multiplayer, and I choose monarchy, and you choose something else you don't give a fuck that I chose mine I think.
Speaker 1: ah but in sieve five when the Ideologies come out you care a lot because if other people like say someone picks your ideology versus someone else's that could alter the balance Of tourism output and really fuck you.
Speaker 1: so choosing an ideology if you're not one of the people who really starts one is Actually a really big deal mechanically, but you know.
Speaker 1: Anyway, like I literally have already threatened a specific person.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about some knots of sieve five.
Speaker 1: I'm playing where.
Speaker 1: if they don't choose my ideology I'm going to immediately declare war on them, so let's talk about some non sieve.
Speaker 0: so this game came out Called really bad chess.
Speaker 0: It's for I don't know if it's for other mobile platform.
Speaker 1: I start I've really bad at shit into Google and the first thing I recommended was really bad chest pain Really bad.
Speaker 0: chess is on iOS.
Speaker 0: I don't know what else it's on.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it's on something else And basically it's chess and there's like a daily board and a weekly board and you can just play ranked mode And you I don't know if you can play multiplayer.
Speaker 0: Maybe looks like it's only iOS.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: That's a shame for anyone who has bad phone.
Speaker 0: So the thing really bad chess is that it just gives you random pieces in your front and back row And it also gives the other guy random pieces in the front and back row.
Speaker 1: oh my god I'm looking at the board on their page.
Speaker 1: white has one two three four queens down there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all night you all.
Speaker 0: I mean sometimes sometimes you always have one king.
Speaker 0: the whole top row is Knights.
Speaker 0: You always have one king.
Speaker 0: you know what else is Knights?
Speaker 0: Two more people yeah, so I mean you know you ten nights You always have one king in the back row, but you know it's really crazy even crazier.
Speaker 0: They're just having a ton of Queens or stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah having pawns in the back row Pawn starting in the back row is fucking great.
Speaker 1: Do they get to move?
Speaker 1: can they move two or three?
Speaker 1: How does that work?
Speaker 0: I'd haven't been able to get someone out of their way.
Speaker 1: Can I on pass on from back there?
Speaker 1: cuz that could be pretty good.
Speaker 0: I think you might be able to.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: it's pretty crazy.
Speaker 0: I really want to play this right, so it's pretty good.
Speaker 0: The thing is it's really bad And I'm really bad at it.
Speaker 0: like my rank is just keep going down like they'll be boards.
Speaker 0: I've got like five Queens, and the other guys got maybe some bishops and Knights, and I lose like I can't No, it's interesting or like I'll move one piece and it like check and like what the fuck cuz like.
Speaker 0: I can't see everything That's going on cuz I got too much shit, so think about fairy chests.
Speaker 1: That's the same thing.
Speaker 1: chess masters They want an interesting game will change the rules of chess so that all the patterns and all the right.
Speaker 0: But they just shuffle up the pieces.
Speaker 0: They don't bring out eight Queens.
Speaker 1: I Feel like being better at chess like really better just not you were.
Speaker 0: so it's not going to help you with this because in Real chests if you're good at it You've memorized patterns.
Speaker 0: and here there's no patterns to memorize all you can what all you can do in This is evaluate moves individually like all right.
Speaker 0: I'll move that knight there Then he'll kill it then I'll kill that and he'll kill that right.
Speaker 0: you're on that level again that beginner level And you can't if you can think more than three moves ahead.
Speaker 0: in this you are a genius level or too much effort level.
Speaker 1: so Anecdotally when I was in high school I knew someone a kid who was a legit like chess master.
Speaker 1: like he was like super pro at chess.
Speaker 1: He played in real tournaments and no one to play chess.
Speaker 1: I would always play chess with him because no one else would.
Speaker 1: I never beat him ever like and I never even came close to beating him.
Speaker 1: But what would reliably happen is that he would take a bunch of my pieces and once I was kind of crippled I could hold out or press him pretty well for a surprisingly long time.
Speaker 1: Once you have less pieces, it's easier to figure out what the fuck to do Exactly, I could start calculating out and also he would tell me several times that I did something dumb and weird.
Speaker 1: But it was so dumb and weird that he wasn't actually sure how to deal with it so until he got the game back into a normal state.
Speaker 0: Right, so it's like he thought about three moves ahead But you made a weird move and now everything he thought about ahead of time is gone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now the move was to start from scratch again.
Speaker 1: The move was always still bad like I did something bad for me reliably But it would take him a while to figure out why it was bad Like what he could do to make it worse for me and end the game.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I'll be good or bad at this because I'm worse at chess than you.
Speaker 1: with a few times we play.
Speaker 1: I don't think I ever.
Speaker 1: I'd only beat you like once or twice ever.
Speaker 0: I'm real.
Speaker 0: I'm really bad at this.
Speaker 1: I'm not good at chess.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: we should play this together.
Speaker 0: I don't know if we can.
Speaker 1: I guess it's just a I we could.
Speaker 1: we could Roll dice and randomize a chess board and play a game.
Speaker 0: Oh, you can't play it on my iPad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm getting an iPad soon the new iPad Pro.
Speaker 1: well like whatever the next iPad comes out up I just get one early next year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I need an iDevice of some kind.
Speaker 1: So yeah in other news probably the biggest gaming news, and we'll probably be doing a whole show about this once It's out and there's more details, but Nintendo switch was announced.
Speaker 1: Everyone already realized that the controller looks like a puppy yeah like a puppy face Two seconds after the video came out.
Speaker 1: uh I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm both excited and Disdainful and they cancel out to me.
Speaker 0: being ambivalent I mean look I didn't get a Wii U, but not getting a Wii U. I didn't miss much where there was the height of Mario maker, which was Mario maker is coming out for 3ds.
Speaker 0: I already pre-ordered it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this holiday season is coming.
Speaker 1: I feel like the fervor in the hype and like the 3ds isn't dead.
Speaker 0: you still got Pokemon And you got Mario maker coming out for 3ds.
Speaker 1: I feel like Mario maker is not at like people people who already played it or done with it because it turned into.
Speaker 1: the only Thing anyone cares about now is crazy kaizo or automation maps like no one cares.
Speaker 0: I don't care about that.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna make Mario levels, and I don't need anyone else to you know.
Speaker 1: I think I think that'll be fun for about a month, and then you'll never touch it again.
Speaker 0: I mean what DS 3ds game do I play for more than a month?
Speaker 0: That's advanced wars for the regular DS month is pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah Splatoon I feel like is also a ship that has sailed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it's whatever right, but the point is is that There was like no Zelda game for the Wii U.
Speaker 1: I have not enjoyed most Zelda games that have come out since I've played every real Zelda game there is.
Speaker 1: I didn't even finish Twilight Princess.
Speaker 1: I kind of got bored with it.
Speaker 0: the point is I was right to skip the Wii U And I'm gonna get me some NX and play some Nintendo games, and you know that's how I do.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I will like.
Speaker 1: if I do I mean, I don't know the things I like.
Speaker 1: the things I have liked about Nintendo franchises in recent memory are Maybe one Zelda game on a portable console replaying old advanced wars.
Speaker 0: I'm saying is that if you bring you know your 3ds to you know say PAX And you're sitting in line right you got to get everyone with the wireless shit, and you don't have the game.
Speaker 1: The problem was that was so easy except at an actual gaming convention.
Speaker 1: It never worked because of all the Wi-Fi interference.
Speaker 1: right and to No one would ever play smash with me because most of you suck at it and didn't want to get beaten by me And the few of us who are good at it didn't want to play with me because they would just crush me.
Speaker 1: And now I play smash.
Speaker 0: so now what we'll do is we'll take the switch put it on the floor And just hand out little controllers and everyone play.
Speaker 1: I don't think that'll happen.
Speaker 0: I think that's definitely gonna happen.
Speaker 1: I think it'll.
Speaker 0: I think we actually have a problem because PAX East is like right after the switch comes out.
Speaker 0: It's like they're easy.
Speaker 0: the same month is that at PAX East you're gonna have too many switches.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be like everyone's gonna put their switch down and you're gonna be like Sitting in line like you know.
Speaker 0: these switches everywhere.
Speaker 1: I guess I'm honestly just not that confident in Nintendo's first party games being that good on it like.
Speaker 1: that's my biggest worry.
Speaker 1: Hmm like nay, what's what's a really good recent first-party game that you would play?
Speaker 1: not that was generally popular, but that you would have liked Mario maker all right.
Speaker 1: How long got any more anything else?
Speaker 0: I mean, that's why I skipped the Wii U.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm just not that confident in those first party game development anymore.
Speaker 1: I'm coming to appeal to someone like me.
Speaker 0: I guess I'm confident that all the shit that was not on the Wii U Right has been being held back and is gonna come out on the switch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean like Mario Kart on the Wii U.
Speaker 0: They're gonna come out with a paper Mario.
Speaker 1: I played it a lot actually and I played it just on other people's we use and I played it in Comparison to the 3ds one and the 3ds one.
Speaker 1: I think is actually objectively just a better Mario card if not for the snaking.
Speaker 1: There's no the 3ds one Yeah, not the DS one.
Speaker 0: I mean yeah the portable games.
Speaker 0: I've always been more on with the portable Nintendo games.
Speaker 1: right and remember Mario Literally ruined like it's only Nintendo.
Speaker 0: There's a list of Nintendo systems that I have owned ready.
Speaker 0: I know an NES a game you've been a wee which are three console.
Speaker 1: Well, you didn't notice any s and you own one.
Speaker 1: No really yeah.
Speaker 0: But I owned a Game Boy Color a GBA Ds a three right every single.
Speaker 0: you know handheld Right.
Speaker 1: see I skipped the Game Boy Color, but I had a Game Boy and a Game Gear, and then my next one was the GBA.
Speaker 0: My brother had the Game Boy, and then I got the Game Boy Color.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's when I had money.
Speaker 1: yeah We'll see I'm just I'm not that excited about it Especially because a lot of the initial marketing in the initial discussions was talking about again all this like set-top box HTTPS Functionality which from a Nintendo console means it'll be way shittier than any other option in that regard.
Speaker 0: I mean, I have an HTTPS.
Speaker 0: I don't need any of that exactly nor all that.
Speaker 1: It worries me that they even talk about it like.
Speaker 1: I feel like Nintendo in this modern era.
Speaker 1: It needs to give up on that ship like that ship.
Speaker 1: It's not that it's sailed.
Speaker 1: It's that it's sinking.
Speaker 0: No, the reason he's the reason you don't give up on that ship.
Speaker 1: right because no Nintendo will never make one that floats.
Speaker 1: They're incapable of doing it.
Speaker 0: it doesn't have to flow just has to do something right.
Speaker 0: because You're thinking like oh someone's got this big home entertainment center And you think they're gonna choose the switch over like their Roku or their cable box or their actual HDBC.
Speaker 0: It's like no no they're not gonna do that right.
Speaker 0: the reason you put those features on there is because up in the kids bedroom Where the switch is right there ain't no Roku in there right.
Speaker 0: there ain't no HDBC.
Speaker 1: in there The kids bedroom.
Speaker 1: he probably doesn't even have a TV or he probably just has his portable stuff and Not even a computer because kids don't use them anymore.
Speaker 1: He's got a tablet.
Speaker 0: I think you're just detached from.
Speaker 0: you know suburban family house life?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: we gotta ask them to suburban house people.
Speaker 0: pretty sure once your kid is old enough to have a Nintendo switch They got a TV in their room.
Speaker 1: my sample size is messed up because most of the people I know Who live that lifestyle are?
Speaker 1: The HD PC types who know better mm-hmm, so I don't know.
Speaker 0: Also, they don't have children old enough to or they don't have children or have children.
Speaker 1: Here's a problem.
Speaker 1: those people right that you described those people.
Speaker 1: yeah They have more than one kid.
Speaker 1: which kids bedroom does the switch sit in?
Speaker 0: Hopefully you know neither one.
Speaker 1: it's gonna have to sit in the living room or the den because the family room.
Speaker 0: Maybe you get two docks moved around.
Speaker 0: Oh If you're rich enough Kids have their own bedrooms, maybe you can be rich enough that they have their own switches.
Speaker 0: no Go, I don't think your kids are in the same bedroom because you're not rich.
Speaker 1: I feel like the people who on average have two bedrooms because that's actually pretty easy to do in modern suburbia.
Speaker 0: They're still not going to switch a room cost a lot more than a video.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't modern houses got.
Speaker 1: if you have you have a four corner house.
Speaker 1: They're almost all two bedroom now.
Speaker 1: well two bedroom plus master bedroom.
Speaker 0: so three bedroom I mean a game console cost less than a room.
Speaker 1: I feel like the kinds of people who are even gonna buy a Nintendo switch and live in suburbia have two bedrooms plus master bedroom.
Speaker 1: I feel like that's the thing.
Speaker 1: people who only have one bedroom and two kids one bedroom for two kids Probably not buying a new game console.
Speaker 0: point is it might as well add HD PC features.
Speaker 0: it's a computer.
Speaker 0: everything is a computer.
Speaker 1: Watching Netflix like I watch I've seen people try to watch Netflix on a Wii.
Speaker 1: Didn't was not great.
Speaker 0: No a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: It's not great But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: so Scott you remember the bear in the shinin.
Speaker 1: No Really the one of the weirdest most unexplained scenes in The Shining.
Speaker 0: I mean I don't remember every scene for that movie Where he's talked like the ghost bartender, and there's the scene where he cuts through the door with the eggs.
Speaker 1: So remember when cuz the wife like never sees the the monsters, right?
Speaker 1: It's like the kid sees the ghosts and the dad sees the ghost But she doesn't right.
Speaker 1: so there's one ghost that she sees at one point when she's running away from him And she looks in this door And there's the good-looking rich old guy getting sucked off by a fat older guy in a bear costume with his butt hanging out.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm you remember that?
Speaker 0: no you really don't remember that.
Speaker 1: no I'll try to find a screenshot of it.
Speaker 1: this scene.
Speaker 0: I don't see it because your head is in the way right there.
Speaker 1: bear guy Remember that?
Speaker 1: He was getting a blowjob barely Vaguely.
Speaker 1: so Apparently cuz I never thought about this scene other than scary ghost like something something because I hadn't read the book.
Speaker 1: I've actually never read the book nope.
Speaker 0: So in the make it make it your book club thing.
Speaker 1: so this is a scene that was in the book But in the book it was different and the dude was wearing a dog costume.
Speaker 0: Maybe they just didn't have a dog costume?
Speaker 1: no so Kubrick would bait like.
Speaker 1: it was crazy Crazy attentive to that kind of detail and as many people have pointed out over the years He would never have made that mistake if he included an unexplained scene from the book Without giving all the other scenes that give it context in the movie.
Speaker 1: He would not have fucked up and made it a bear by accident mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so the question was What the hell with this scene all right?
Speaker 1: And this is a video that actually in very well researched well documented detail Explains the most likely story with the scene.
Speaker 0: the movie's not that old couldn't you ask.
Speaker 0: I mean Kubrick's dead But he won't.
Speaker 1: no one involved will answer like no they did.
Speaker 1: and actually apparently he was famous for Specifically with The Shining not explaining things.
Speaker 0: you couldn't just ask the guy who was wearing the bear suit they weren't told Put on this bear suit and suck this guy up As far as I can tell yeah, and you say yes.
Speaker 1: So you want to know what the what the pretty like for real explanation probably is all right.
Speaker 1: Jack Nicholson was molesting the kid and That's the backstory of the whole movie And her revelation of figuring this out.
Speaker 1: And there's a lot of good reasons why this is the case and I found a bunch of essays going into it in detail.
Speaker 1: But this because none of you are gonna read essays.
Speaker 1: I know none of you read essays So you can all watch this four and a half minute YouTube video that will probably convince you that that is the reason.
Speaker 1: That's the story behind the bear.
Speaker 0: I mean you could probably get gather that as a possibility even without the bear.
Speaker 1: uh Yeah, but the bear motif is used in all the scenes like literally every scene that reinforces the.
Speaker 1: he is molesting his Kid and him and the kid both have these ghosts and demons and the wife doesn't see him because she's like not involved.
Speaker 1: and this Scene represents her coming to the realization that she married a psychopath Because that's literally saying she's running away from him when he's got the axe.
Speaker 0: You know no bear no TV Something.
Speaker 1: This video is just like.
Speaker 1: it's very succinct for how Complexive an analysis it is and he even has ever.
Speaker 1: there's even further evidence that there was a deleted scene Where the kid where there's a very prominent bear that touches on this real close Mmm, so yeah, that's my thing of the day right?
Speaker 0: It's not unless frightening unless Halloween Related.
Speaker 0: so slot car racing.
Speaker 0: you know where they put the car on the track and all you can do is make you go fast Or go slow because I was real into that as a kid and you would you know you would get one.
Speaker 1: You'd set it up once you'd play for you hold the thing down It would fly off the track and you say what's this bullshit, right?
Speaker 0: You'd play with it a little bit.
Speaker 0: Then you play with it one more time when you remember that you had it And then you never play with it again.
Speaker 1: And then I always tried to be competitive.
Speaker 0: you didn't have an expensive one.
Speaker 0: you had a cheapo one from Toys R Us and it Really worked.
Speaker 1: they also because of the way the paddles that were shaped like guns usually worked.
Speaker 1: They would always smell like ozone when they were running like always mm-hmm anyway, so You know.
Speaker 0: apparently that's like a hobby that you can get into if they know and there's pros and such.
Speaker 0: And I had never you know thought about.
Speaker 0: I knew that it was a thing But I never thought about it too hard or cared about it too much, but here's some video of a world championship a while's back And Wow Okay, this video is some people have put in way too much effort into playing this at a very high level And now you can witness it, and you never need to see it again.
Speaker 1: You know we talked like we've done lectures about like eSports and how like games have to have good expectation.
Speaker 0: This is like if you've said that your car goes flying off the track.
Speaker 0: well Yeah for the pros it also goes flying off the track pretty much constantly yep.
Speaker 1: Well now like the people who go off the track you can see like well they lost that's over obviously But you know it still happens.
Speaker 0: It's not like you know.
Speaker 0: They're so good.
Speaker 1: But I guess like we make fun of dota for having like bad spectator heuristics watch this video Watch what this is like.
Speaker 0: Yeah, tell me who's in first Tell me anything.
Speaker 1: It's literally.
Speaker 1: And then it just stops and everyone just walks over to pick up their cars.
Speaker 0: The noise I guess I think it's you know not just the control of the car But also the making of the car.
Speaker 0: I think is a lot of the hobby.
Speaker 1: yeah But the skill of it is literally just f1 racing Except the only thing you have one finger was your speed.
Speaker 0: one finger f1 racing with.
Speaker 1: no It's just gas and brake and nothing else you have.
Speaker 1: no you can't.
Speaker 1: you don't have to steer just gas and brake.
Speaker 1: yep And turns out even gas and brake is real hard like if you went to this track and took one of these cars and tried To drive it around.
Speaker 1: it would fly off the first turn would fly off immediately, or you'd be going like like stop and start Maybe start a fire.
Speaker 0: pretty much exactly what would happen if you drove a real f1 car.
Speaker 0: you'd either go fast So fast you killed yourself in the first turn or go so slow the car didn't work.
Speaker 1: Yep the car Just catch fire.
Speaker 0: well f1 cars Don't work unless you go fast enough because you won't get enough heat into the brakes And then you won't be able to stop.
Speaker 0: no It's you know.
Speaker 0: so it's like you have to go a certain speed also and get the car warmed up or else it doesn't go.
Speaker 1: So I've randomly Recently learned a lot about.
Speaker 1: this is kind of obscure, but in World War two like planes on aircraft carriers It was a real hard to warm him up.
Speaker 1: like you had to run him on the deck for a long time Or they literally just couldn't take off or would just explode.
Speaker 0: you gotta get it cuz.
Speaker 1: Think the reason was just like f1.
Speaker 1: when you take off you basically have to go from idle to full Throttle and hold it there.
Speaker 1: so if you do that on an unwarmed up engine it would just explode.
Speaker 0: well cuz it has to do With oil.
Speaker 0: right it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like okay.
Speaker 0: also rotary engines right, but it's like all right.
Speaker 0: We need the oil to be liquidy and Lubricating so that the metal parts can move without exploding the turbines of the pistons or whatever they are.
Speaker 1: Yep, and in a complicated rotary engine you also have to get it distributed around the engine.
Speaker 0: So we put some oil in there And if the oil is nice and liquidy and lubricating at like room temperature Then when you get your engine be it f1 or you know f15 it turns into fire it turns into fire.
Speaker 0: So you need oil that's basically solid at room temperature Basically, and then you got to get it warmed up.
Speaker 0: You know to the.
Speaker 0: you know cuz it needs to be nice and liquidy and normal at F-15 jet engine temperature, which is much much hotter.
Speaker 0: so at regular room temperature.
Speaker 0: It's not going anywhere.
Speaker 0: So you need you know.
Speaker 1: yeah, well these are old propeller planes, and it was.
Speaker 1: it's all just kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: I'm reading this really really Kind of book that you would never want to read, but it's about the details of some aircraft carrier stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't need to know that it's pretty interesting.
Speaker 1: the best part about it Is there's this dude.
Speaker 0: if we ever end up on an aircraft carrier in some sort of post-apocalyptic situation bring a copy with you.
Speaker 1: Here's here's remember remember the Russian space program asides his rims.
Speaker 1: World War two Pacific war aside There's this dude in the Battle of Midway from the Japanese side right and he had to fly a recon plane out to look for American ships and then fly back.
Speaker 0: you didn't just get shot down.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, so I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think he survived the war.
Speaker 1: at least he survived this battle, but The situation he was in is he went out and he ended up getting airborne like an hour late And he also went the wrong direction.
Speaker 1: good job, so he gets out there and eventually he's like guys.
Speaker 1: I see like ten American ships over here and the commanders are like other aircraft curves What kind of ships?
Speaker 1: and he basically doesn't know and can't give these good answers?
Speaker 1: So they're like well stay out there and keep an eye on him and let us know if you think there's an aircraft carrier.
Speaker 1: and then the Battle of Midway happens and Periodically throughout the entire battle he kept radioing back saying basically yeah getting low on fuel out here Can I come back in?
Speaker 1: and it appears that the Japanese commanders kept forgetting about him?
Speaker 1: So he'd radio in and they'd be like oh no But there's a report and he'd report and then they'd be like yeah stay out there and keep watching and he'd be like Okay, and he kept radioing back because then they'd forget he was out there.
Speaker 1: and Eventually he radios back like yeah, I'm basically out of fuel.
Speaker 1: I'm coming back, and they're like who are you again?
Speaker 1: Where are you?
Speaker 1: No?
Speaker 1: You're not stay out there.
Speaker 1: We need you out there, and he's like yes I will stay out here and then exactly one minute later.
Speaker 1: He radios back and says something to the effect of fuck it I'm coming home And I don't know what happened.
Speaker 1: the history books don't know anything about this guy after this point.
Speaker 0: How do they know this?
Speaker 1: Radio logs.
Speaker 0: someone's recording all this.
Speaker 1: yeah There are detailed logs of like everything that was said over the radios for most of these battles in World War two.
Speaker 0: That's interesting.
Speaker 1: There's yeah, that's it.
Speaker 1: There's there's interesting stuff in this book.
Speaker 0: We should go read aim chat logs to the 90s and see if this is.
Speaker 1: I've got some old chat logs that could be a reading on the patreon.
Speaker 1: Anyway in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: We are going to be at doing a panel writing game rules at gamer X East Which is in New York City November 12th and 13th, so it's a gaming con you do not.
Speaker 1: it is a LGBT focused gaming con But that just means that it is a friendly environment to that like.
Speaker 1: it is encouraging of that and as a result You know just might be a lot less agro and a lot more chill than say the average gaming con or a lot more party.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it is just an awesome gaming con.
Speaker 1: you do not have to be gay to go to this con A homo you just have to not be a homophobe.
Speaker 0: yes, you would have a bad time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there is no GG here There's only good game.
Speaker 1: So this con is just awesome, and it's out in a play.
Speaker 1: You know it's far away, so we don't go to it, but gamer X has an East Coast version.
Speaker 1: now It looks like they're kick-starting out Australia version - I mean it's right here in New York.
Speaker 0: Why not go over there?
Speaker 0: It'll take me five minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you live in New York like seriously just go to this con.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be two days of us playing tabletop, so go over there.
Speaker 0: I'll play some games.
Speaker 1: I'll come home yep, but we'll be doing one panel at it.
Speaker 1: We're doing writing game rules, but because it's a smallish con and the panel rooms are not that big I'm gonna be very clear.
Speaker 1: if you have seen us do this panel before do not come to this con To see this panel.
Speaker 0: you should not come to this con just to see us.
Speaker 1: But if you've already seen us talk about writing game rules Don't go to this panel because literally the rooms not gonna be that big.
Speaker 1: I'd rather someone who doesn't know who we are See the panel.
Speaker 1: so yeah if you come to this panel And I recognize you and I know that you've already seen it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna throw some shade at you probably in the panel Which we're good at that.
Speaker 1: Yeah gamer X. We're gonna be there.
Speaker 1: we're gonna be a magfest as well on a bunch of panels January 5th through 8th down in the DC's and I'm assuming we're gonna be a peck south Magfest you should go to even if we're not there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even if you live in like I don't know The Sahara Desert you should find your way to magfest.
Speaker 1: magfest is a con like Pax's that is worth flying to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's worth going to you know good luck.
Speaker 0: It's already too late if you're not already planned start planning for magfest 2018 at this point.
Speaker 1: guys seriously And the book club is of course still Rebecca And the other book club the scout doesn't want to do on the rise of Nazism in the Weimar Republic the geek nights politics book Club.
Speaker 1: we're gonna record our podcast as soon as I can get Andrew to respond to an.
Speaker 0: I am.
Speaker 1: So if you read that book the episodes coming if you didn't read that book you don't.
Speaker 1: It's a really good book.
Speaker 1: read Rebecca Rebecca's really sure.
Speaker 0: I read like a few chapters And then I stopped because I was doing all the stuff.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna read it soon because I'm almost done with this other nonfiction book I'm reading where I learned about private first class.
Speaker 1: I think he's first class.
Speaker 1: you say anyway private Amari is garbage.
Speaker 1: private Amari is the dude.
Speaker 0: so I read nonfiction all day on the internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is reading a nonfiction history book that is well-written is a far cry from reading Nonfiction on the internet just because it's well-written, but it's not relevant to my life.
Speaker 0: Fiction is it could be.
Speaker 1: actually it very much could be.
Speaker 0: really something that happened in some war is relevant to my non-war existence.
Speaker 1: You know what is relevant to?
Speaker 1: distribution of your carrier decks in Civ 5.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I'm good.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: You know you're real bad at that.
Speaker 1: I expect Otherwise.
Speaker 1: we got the patreon Scott's YouTube channel and my youtube channel.
Speaker 1: both have tons of content coming in.
Speaker 1: I'm editing a video right now poorly and we are live streaming geek nights even though that was a patreon goal that we have not Reached.
Speaker 1: I'm doing it anyway.
Speaker 1: I'm just not gonna do it all the time necessarily.
Speaker 1: so this episode That's good.
Speaker 0: people are not giving her money.
Speaker 0: He's getting desperate.
Speaker 1: Okay money.
Speaker 1: We're well over $300 a month in the patreon.
Speaker 0: Give me that money then.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm paying 150 a month for the stupid forum.
Speaker 1: I could put some of the money toward the forum.
Speaker 0: just give me 150 a month.
Speaker 1: Maybe I will if you but then you have to Stop trash-talking the patreon.
Speaker 1: no because the patreon will be directly funding us.
Speaker 0: I'll just delete the form then.
Speaker 1: oh See state if you have opinions.
Speaker 1: actually this kind of an important meta vanilla forums kind of suck now But they're still the best forums out there.
Speaker 1: there aren't other forums.
Speaker 1: We are not sure what to do And we're earnestly like trying to figure out a better solution because we want a forum.
Speaker 0: Well I want to use the discord thingy But the discord thingy is not like.
Speaker 0: if they something happens to them then what we lose everything.
Speaker 0: It's a forum.
Speaker 0: everything is saved.
Speaker 0: like I have a backup of the forum database.
Speaker 0: It's safe.
Speaker 0: You know we can't get fucked.
Speaker 1: Even if it all disappears the data could be put on the internet and mind and we could use it for stuff.
Speaker 0: right we move Everyone our community to a discord chat.
Speaker 0: it'll be way active and have an.
Speaker 0: I assume it'll be way active and everyone have a party Time in there.
Speaker 0: to be great, but it's different forms.
Speaker 1: It's a different form of interaction and then it goes.
Speaker 0: and then if something happens to it It's like well We just lost everything guys.
Speaker 1: and you might already be thinking but rim and Scott why not both?
Speaker 1: that doesn't work.
Speaker 0: if you have a forum And I have a discord no one will go in the forum.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the forum would just die.
Speaker 1: and if you're saying if you think well just let the forum die I don't think you understand the horrifying degree of Google juice that forum has.
Speaker 0: there is all we don't have to let.
Speaker 0: we can just Keep it up in like read-only mode yeah, but but even
Speaker 1: then like there's a lot in there And I want to put
Speaker 0: it 11 years of typing
Speaker 1: 11 years of typing and the forum used to be a lot more Active in the early days, so
Speaker 0: I just think I think people aren't into forums these days.
Speaker 1: Well, I get the impression a lot of people read the forum, but very but like a tenth of them posts.
Speaker 1: That's the impression.
Speaker 1: I get just based on
Speaker 0: I can I can look at numbers and find out yeah,
Speaker 1: but anyway Seriously like if you have suggestions You want things you have input you just anything about how to have our geek nights community outside of the podcast continue Posting the forum about it because we're earnestly to start deciding what to do all the way up to and including.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should quit our jobs and write an actual good forum because apparently no one else is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you pay me enough money.
Speaker 1: Yeah There is a goal in the patreon that would.
Speaker 1: we would both quit our jobs and just do geek night stuff Which would include writing the forum tons of money.
Speaker 1: 12 grand a month I think is what we said it at need more than that.
Speaker 1: that way I think 12 grand a month would cover both of our living expenses.
Speaker 0: so the forum has like a hundred and something.
Speaker 0: Users, I don't know if that's how that's measured.
Speaker 0: is it active users.
Speaker 1: I think that's only active users.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't even know because we have all those old accounts of like.
Speaker 1: Killarney hasn't posted in a long time Hungry Joe.
Speaker 1: I don't think I've seen him around.
Speaker 0: I can't really tell how to read this.
Speaker 0: It's like did we only have 11 users in a single day, that's not much yeah.
Speaker 1: But then again because it's public you know I logged in or in the past month.
Speaker 0: We've had 1.3 million pageviews, which is You know yeah It's a twenty six thousand comments Goddamn, that's all.
Speaker 1: that is more than all the tweets.
Speaker 1: I've ever tweeted But no that's had.
Speaker 1: Oh, I think that's actually half as many as all the tweets.
Speaker 1: I've ever tweeted.
Speaker 0: I have 2170 comments you have 2056 comments and the third place is Cherbo with 1045 comments.
Speaker 1: So yeah, where were?
Speaker 1: that's something we're actively working on in geek nights.
Speaker 1: It will do a whole like meta show on it at some point.
Speaker 1: so Civilization six I wasn't.
Speaker 0: it was you know it was a brand new game.
Speaker 0: It just came out.
Speaker 0: usually I wait for the game of the year edition, but I said you know what?
Speaker 0: Everywhere I just fuck it.
Speaker 0: I'll just play it.
Speaker 1: I bought it while I was in Australia.
Speaker 1: I Wanted to play it on the plane home because guess what it's system requirements not bad.
Speaker 1: It'll run fine on my old Lenovo x230.
Speaker 1: The only problem was I would have to download like 15 gigabytes in Australia.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: They don't have 15 gigabytes there.
Speaker 1: no In fact the nice hotel.
Speaker 1: I was staying in unless I paid a lot more money only gave us a gigabyte a day.
Speaker 1: So I'd wait till I got home, that's why I was playing Civ 5.
Speaker 0: great reason not to live there.
Speaker 1: uh yeah Well if Trump gets elected would think it might.
Speaker 1: it might be a wash we could head out there.
Speaker 0: This better places to go where I can go to Tropical Island.
Speaker 1: yeah, tropical island Scott have a lot of problems.
Speaker 1: You're not thinking about like what.
Speaker 1: internet's not great there either, but I have bananas.
Speaker 1: There's bananas in Australia Sand.
Speaker 1: there's some of the best beaches in the world in Australia Swimmable year-round.
Speaker 0: the swimmable year-round on the tropical island.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just got like Brisbane But there's Australians the tropical island diseases.
Speaker 0: I'd rather have a disease then Poison you're dead from some animal.
Speaker 1: I have spent actually uh I was counting up just all my trips for Australia.
Speaker 1: I've spent like two months there.
Speaker 1: I've never gotten poisoned.
Speaker 0: You got lucky.
Speaker 1: I got the shits once on Manly, but that was from a Mexican restaurant.
Speaker 1: That's probably the worst thing that ever happened to me that Other than the time I punched myself in the face.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what there isn't in Australia Mexican food.
Speaker 0: Well, we tried it when.
Speaker 1: yeah, I've tried it three times ever.
Speaker 1: I have decided it is impossible to get it.
Speaker 0: Why don't we?
Speaker 0: You know find some Mexican people and fund them.
Speaker 1: Get like a fancy Mexican restaurant like put it inside.
Speaker 0: Let's just go over to like cafe my and be like, hey you want to open up in Australia Cafe my.
Speaker 1: I'm so hungry right now.
Speaker 1: This is gonna be hard.
Speaker 1: to the rest of the podcast.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty hungry But yeah, so sieve six.
Speaker 1: that my biggest fear because we talked about this not that long ago Was that sieve six would do what sieve five and sieve four did because sieve four and especially sieve five when they came out.
Speaker 1: We're garbage games.
Speaker 1: Sit five especially like when it first came out like.
Speaker 1: it was revolutionary and all these changes.
Speaker 1: But the game was kind of simplistic and it really just like it was just this kind of simple Optimization problem and it just wasn't fun.
Speaker 1: There was very little depth and sieve five was literally not worth playing.
Speaker 1: We all stopped playing it.
Speaker 0: It's so weird.
Speaker 0: There's even six sieves.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah sieve two was like the only one and sieve three was about the day came out.
Speaker 0: It was man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's probably the worst one.
Speaker 1: sieve three is definitely the worst worst one.
Speaker 0: sieve four once it got expanded one is the second worst one.
Speaker 1: yeah Sieve four was good Once it had expansions.
Speaker 1: sieve five.
Speaker 1: sieve five before the expansions might be the third worst one.
Speaker 1: But once brave new world came out sieve five was the best sieve that had ever been made.
Speaker 1: like far and away.
Speaker 1: It's just so good.
Speaker 1: I mean it's telling them.
Speaker 0: He doesn't have the cheating mode though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I don't really care about that anymore.
Speaker 0: to cheating mode I play.
Speaker 0: I've still probably played sieve two more than any other sieves.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you played it kind of weird.
Speaker 1: You played it with kid brain.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all the enemy all the enemy says also you can you cannot beat that.
Speaker 0: DaVinci's workshop video and music.
Speaker 1: Also, you always play the game the same way.
Speaker 1: DaVinci's workshop upgrades all your all your workers to engineers and all your Everything automatically in for free.
Speaker 0: it was the best That was.
Speaker 1: that was.
Speaker 0: that's why I basically had to rush it and if I didn't get it I'd quit cuz I didn't want to manage upgrading all my guys.
Speaker 1: I also quit if I didn't get the pyramids because of the pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: bill granaries everywhere.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, think about powerful shit was just like free granary fucking everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah And back then grant imagine something in sieve four five or six was just like free granary everywhere and granary did what aqueducts do now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I know sieve six is a huge evolution with substantial changes.
Speaker 1: But unlike sieve five which started over and started, baby Sieve six day one is as complicated if not more complicated than sieve five fully expanded.
Speaker 0: It's so weird because in the one hand it is more complicated much more complicated to the point at which Like I have a hard time knowing to do on my turn Watch my stream and like I played it blind literally last night for the first time.
Speaker 1: So I click on something and I'm like envoys.
Speaker 1: the fuck is that?
Speaker 1: wait are there two science tracks?
Speaker 1: Oh I have a mix-and-match government, right?
Speaker 0: So the thing is is that even though it's more complicated each Individual system and all these details of the game have actually been made much more elegant.
Speaker 0: So, you know it can consider this like in sieve In sieve five if like happiness and there's like global happiness and local happiness.
Speaker 0: And now you can ignore local happiness unless you really sucked at the guy, but I'm saying it's confusing It's not.
Speaker 0: you're not a hundred percent sure how every detail of this system works.
Speaker 1: unless I was I'm literally 100% sure how happiness works in sieve five.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm not so.
Speaker 1: anyway, it's real simple.
Speaker 1: You have a non happiness number.
Speaker 1: that is driven by population number of cities.
Speaker 1: There's a few other things that'll drive it.
Speaker 1: you have a happiness number.
Speaker 1: The difference between the two is all that matters.
Speaker 0: if it hits negative ten you're fucked Right, but this happiness affects like so many things.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't.
Speaker 1: it affects them all in trivial ways tiny tiny minuses of percent to military effectiveness while you're unhappy if you had negative ten like partisans and shit start coming out.
Speaker 1: if it's Positive then your cities grow faster.
Speaker 1: if it's negative your cities basically stop growing.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes, I can't remember all that shit.
Speaker 0: Anyway, really straight six.
Speaker 0: I don't have to remember all that shit.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 1: you have this housing system.
Speaker 0: It's so much amenities system, right?
Speaker 0: It's so much simpler this housing and this amenities and if you have enough amenities your people are happy And if you don't have enough amenities your people are unhappy.
Speaker 1: You also you have is if you have extra amenities like people grow faster.
Speaker 0: If you have enough houses Then your people can.
Speaker 0: you can grow your city.
Speaker 0: the population can increase to fill those houses.
Speaker 0: If you don't have enough houses the population of the city doesn't grow.
Speaker 0: that is Complicated than happiness and said five it's but I can understand the rules much more simply.
Speaker 0: It's my straight forward.
Speaker 1: I am actually really shocked by the what you're expressing here because I think no I Agreed with everything you were saying until you said that the CIF five system was complicated.
Speaker 0: It is complicated.
Speaker 0: Here's another example.
Speaker 1: It's way simpler than sieve sixes, right?
Speaker 1: Here's another example But it's way simpler.
Speaker 0: It's not simpler.
Speaker 0: So it is simpler.
Speaker 0: and sieve five.
Speaker 0: There's all sorts of things where there's like exceptions to the rules, right?
Speaker 0: So what?
Speaker 0: So for example, like oh if you work a marble then you get this ability to make wonders.
Speaker 1: That is literally the only one.
Speaker 0: there's lots of other weird little exception like why?
Speaker 0: Oh if you you know, alright see you when you Start this, you know a thing of what's it called?
Speaker 0: I can't remember the name like if you start tradition You get this and then each thing in tradition gives you something and then when you finish tradition Then you get another thing that's just listed on the page.
Speaker 1: when you pick them all the words are there.
Speaker 1: It's real simple, right?
Speaker 0: But it's much simpler now.
Speaker 0: It's like oh we have the system for science like this tech tree.
Speaker 0: Let's just make another tree for culture that works exactly the same way.
Speaker 0: So you don't have to remember these two different systems.
Speaker 0: It's just you the system you already know how to use.
Speaker 0: We're just gonna reuse that same system again.
Speaker 1: Now that is where I agree with you.
Speaker 1: and while it is more complex in some cases It is also more elegant right and there's no that you don't have to like complain with Yokohama that board game.
Speaker 1: It's more complex, but it is not elegant in its complexity.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm You know, so it's basically what other things.
Speaker 0: oh so city-states, right?
Speaker 0: So in Civ 5 like city-state influence is like the points are going up the points are going down.
Speaker 0: You the points always go down.
Speaker 0: you have to like do stuff to make them go down.
Speaker 1: remind them like hey We're your friends.
Speaker 0: We have to do stuff to make them go down less Right and you do stuff to boost it.
Speaker 0: and now it was also money and curry fail.
Speaker 1: It was I'm gonna say a very simple system and it would but it was way more complex than Civ.
Speaker 0: Could you calculate like on hand like how much influence you were gonna have like how much gold?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it totally just told you in the screen.
Speaker 0: It's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: No now it's much simpler.
Speaker 0: It's like oh you are an industrial city-state if I give you argue.
Speaker 1: It's not simpler.
Speaker 1: It's just more Abstracted and as a result they can add more complexity to what it did.
Speaker 0: I give you an envoy and now I get this bonus.
Speaker 0: I give me three envoys I get this bonus at six envoys I get another bonus and if I give you more envoys than anyone else I get a super bonus.
Speaker 1: That is literally how the olden worked except it was points instead of envoys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you couldn't like.
Speaker 0: it was very hard to give points.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like a direct.
Speaker 0: you now have a point that you can give.
Speaker 0: it was like, you know Oh, I had to kill a barbarian and now you like me.
Speaker 1: It was a separate system where they would give you quests you could fulfill which they still do.
Speaker 0: Quest the quest give you the envoys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: It's a. it's a more elegant system that allows city-states to have much more complex interactions Even than what Civ 5 did.
Speaker 1: but Civ 5 because it was already a different system Even though it was a simple system.
Speaker 1: every simple but different system you add drastically decreases the elegance of the whole game meaning City-states couldn't be more complex or the game would be too stupid and too complex to fiddly.
Speaker 0: Systems in Civ 6 are much more explicit right?
Speaker 0: Like I have given this envoy to this city-state ding right in Civ 5.
Speaker 0: It's like you got some info.
Speaker 0: they like you less than they did.
Speaker 0: yes No, it was like you got 45 influence because of X.
Speaker 1: It's just a less granular system as Final Fantasy 1 hit points instead of Final Fantasy 10 hit points It was.
Speaker 0: it was not as easy.
Speaker 1: It is amazing that I can agree with your overall point but disagree with pretty much every example you get.
Speaker 0: Anyway, another good example right is like
Speaker 1: Well here look the boosts like the in spray all that stuff the boosting system in the trees The fact that it is identical between the two
Speaker 0: yeah,
Speaker 1: but that means that the things that trigger them can be Crazily varied like so basically the way this works is if you don't have something in a tree yet Everything in a tree much like the board game Attica if any of you remember that one has the condition you can meet.
Speaker 1: that will basically get you a boost to that thing up to 75% of its total completion.
Speaker 1: and the UX does a good job, you know, like when I did my live stream I was actually looking at it and I was like, I'll bet this is how
Speaker 0: you can tell for yeah from the tech the tech Culture trees with the boosts you can tell immediately how it works just by looking at it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't need anyone to explain it to you.
Speaker 1: If you have a modicum of intelligence and you're familiar with board games, like you'll just figure it out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Because it's the same system for both trees and for the entirety of every tree and the city-states use a similar system, too.
Speaker 1: It comes down to every one of them have a crazy goal.
Speaker 1: It's like one of them will say make three mines.
Speaker 1: another one will say Fight against this particular kind of units more than end times.
Speaker 0: I had one that was like kill three things using Ranged attacks or something like that.
Speaker 1: I had one like my slingers fought a barbarian a bunch of times and then it was like yeah Slingers suck and you realize this.
Speaker 1: and now you have a boost to researching archery.
Speaker 1: But they can be crazy like that glory to roam.
Speaker 1: crazy because the underlying system is 100% consistent and it's the same system across all these other systems.
Speaker 0: like the same mechanic is used in multiple systems Here's the biggest and best changes from previous sibs, right?
Speaker 0: The number one best change of all is the workers.
Speaker 0: Ah, so I as soon as they told me the workers were like limited use and then they go away.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh Thank you so much.
Speaker 1: There are two kinds of people who read the initial news before we had access to the game that said workers are expendable.
Speaker 1: Half of the people were like Scott and said thank God and half the people were like me and said oh no having visions of Final Fantasy legends.
Speaker 1: but 100% of the people who had my initial thought when they actually played the game said oh, I see what's going on Brilliant, right?
Speaker 0: so when old sieve games you'd make a worker which kind of sucked and took a long time and Then the worker would go around working and you'd have to build roads one hex at a time Remember older games you were using.
Speaker 1: settlers were the same thing, right?
Speaker 0: You would build improvements on every single spot of your territory that you could write that you could afford to anyway.
Speaker 0: It was this really tedious thing you had to do you to automate your workers because it was such a pain in the ass You would.
Speaker 0: you would build more workers.
Speaker 0: But then eventually after you had done working you have all these workers around and you're like they're costing you maintenance money.
Speaker 0: So you want to get rid of them?
Speaker 0: This is why you.
Speaker 0: but if you got rid of them Then you'd be in trouble because you discover railroad and now suddenly you need an army of workers to upgrade all your roads.
Speaker 1: That's why you're bad at sieve.
Speaker 1: You you know how many you need depending how big your sieve is generally and you leave them on auto Because they'll go around and get new resources and when you have a war you bring an army corps of engineers along.
Speaker 1: You've got like four workers following the army building roads and forts along the way to maintain your supply.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the way it works now is much better.
Speaker 0: You bought.
Speaker 0: you build a builder not a worker.
Speaker 1: a builder and he can upgrade anything.
Speaker 1: You can build him real easy life Like it takes a few turns which also means him getting attacked by a barbarian is not the devastating blow.
Speaker 1: It once was right.
Speaker 0: Also, then you tell him to build something.
Speaker 0: He builds it immediately like BAM one.
Speaker 0: It's done.
Speaker 0: He doesn't sit there working on it.
Speaker 0: You're like keep a military unit defending him like mmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we got to take five turns to build this farm.
Speaker 0: It's like no farm done got it But you know what he doesn't build roads.
Speaker 1: roads are an automated abstracted system.
Speaker 0: now Thank you, Jesus and the yes, so you don't have to nothing tedious with these guys, right?
Speaker 0: You pretty much send them to the bonus resources and go build build build done.
Speaker 0: Now as and then when you get more bonus resources you build another builder.
Speaker 1: now, here's another example.
Speaker 0: It gives you a reason to build more builders later in the game and not just once at the beginning and then never again.
Speaker 1: Here is another example of adding Interesting complexity and being able to do so because you've otherwise made a system more elegant and abstracted The workers because they're so much simpler for a lot of different resources.
Speaker 1: You have two options Mm-hmm, you can improve it which is like building a mine.
Speaker 0: Cut that shit down which is like you used to be able to chop down forests and sieve But now you can chop down fucking you can over you can like over fish and now there's no more whales.
Speaker 1: But you got a fuck ton of gears along the way.
Speaker 0: some people actually I was watching some people play who didn't you know?
Speaker 0: And they did that by accident cut down their corn by accident.
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: This is like oops I cut down my corn.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you could.
Speaker 1: you can basically strip mine if you want which is super interesting.
Speaker 1: The reason I think they added that is that the city's take up multiple hexes now and use cities now.
Speaker 1: have Regular buildings and districts right?
Speaker 0: You're not just using these workers like improve every single hex of your city like a lot of the hexes in your.
Speaker 0: you're only really improving the bonus places and maybe a couple extra farms or something and The rest of the hexes in your city territory are being filled in with those Theater district or an encampment or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there's districts and there's buildings, mm-hmm and Not to get into all the details of how that works Obviously because this is just our initial thoughts based on like a small number of hours of play.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty neat system and I can see why everyone is like There's a lot of strategy now and thinking that goes into where you're gonna position things, right?
Speaker 0: So I had a thing that was like if you your holy site gets plus one faith for every adjacent tundra.
Speaker 0: So it's like oh shit I guess I'm putting my holy site up.
Speaker 0: I better build a city with a good holy site spot and you got a city over there.
Speaker 0: It's not even near a tundra.
Speaker 0: You don't even bother building a holy site.
Speaker 1: I kind of ignored the water thing when I first started playing.
Speaker 1: so I'm gonna build my second city and I see this great Spot like by classic Civ heuristics.
Speaker 1: I see this spot and I'm like, this is the god spot.
Speaker 1: This will literally be the best city I've ever built in any civilization game ever.
Speaker 1: I put it there and then like ten turns later It's like yo dawg.
Speaker 1: this city's out of housing and then I realized that that city is Nowhere near fresh water.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and water is the big deal.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you need some water.
Speaker 0: build some aqueduct.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the aqueduct gives you mad houses.
Speaker 1: Yeah and if you go the thing is the Own district.
Speaker 1: the aqueduct only maxes out if it bridges the gap between your city and the water Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, it only gives you like two I think.
Speaker 0: I Thought it gives you less if you already have water.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: I think it has to reach water though.
Speaker 0: Anyway, like it is you need aqueduct or it has to get to like a mountain or something you build in one, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like when you build that encampment and like your city has oh, that's oh, I love this, right?
Speaker 0: So in old Civ games when you built walls Oh, yeah walls were basically like a thing you only built when there was a war on your doorstep and there were a pain in the ass and Didn't do anything but defend you.
Speaker 1: or in Civ 5 there were three levels of walls.
Speaker 1: There was walls castle and I think Arsenal.
Speaker 0: There's still levels of walls in Civ 6.
Speaker 0: No, but in Civ 5 the levels were like real non-granular Sure, but now if you don't build walls your city does not have a built-in ranged attack.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also ancient walls power is.
Speaker 1: now your city can attack things.
Speaker 0: Also, if you don't have the wall your city is basically completely defenseless.
Speaker 0: We'll just get squished by like one guy like old.
Speaker 0: It's like they made you so defenseless without the wall that you remember that even though the wall only Defends you it's like you need the wall.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: the wall went from something that like I only build it when is a war on My doorstep to something I build in like every city That's anywhere near a bad guy or as even any remote chance of any who are being Built it just to stop barbarians
Speaker 1: less ye children.
Speaker 1: forget every sieve up till five.
Speaker 1: if a city didn't have a unit in it Boop, just take it up doesn't matter how big the city is.
Speaker 1: You know if your capital is gone because boop.
Speaker 1: So five fix that by making cities super dangerous in their own right.
Speaker 0: see why.
Speaker 0: build a wall.
Speaker 1: Six took a step halfway back and the walls are way more granular.
Speaker 1: You can build Ancient wall.
Speaker 0: Yeah ancient walls usually gets you through, you know for a while.
Speaker 1: But similarly like in traditional sieve the first range unit you get is Archer.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: Yeah They give you an earlier range unit and then archery.
Speaker 0: do you have to?
Speaker 0: just if you want archers you have to discover archery on Its own.
Speaker 0: all it does is give you archers.
Speaker 0: It's like oh, it's like.
Speaker 0: you really don't want to research it But once you upgrade a bunch of slingers to archers, you're so happy.
Speaker 0: Yeah Everybody because they can actually shoot two hexes not just one worthless hex.
Speaker 0: Yep So there's one other thing they changed that I noticed that was quite significant.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's just me imagining it but I'm pretty sure this is real.
Speaker 0: Is that there's a lot more rock-paper-scissors with the units?
Speaker 0: So for example, usually in old sieves combined arms are necessary.
Speaker 0: if one through five I would build spear man and spear man would be like your main melee guy.
Speaker 0: He would defend your city.
Speaker 0: He could attack.
Speaker 0: he was pretty much, you know, it was a really strong Basic, you know unit that you would use in the early mid ish game.
Speaker 0: turn into pike man Whatever and he would do like all your stuff and he was hard to kill no matter what.
Speaker 0: now the spear man Spearman fucks up the chariots and he fucks up the horses.
Speaker 0: if you send a warrior to attack a spear man That warrior will now fuck the spear man up big time.
Speaker 0: Like a spear man has to run.
Speaker 0: if a warriors coming and if a swordsman coming spear man really got it run away.
Speaker 0: They're in deep fucking shit, right now this same thing, but it works the same way if you got an archer, right?
Speaker 0: And they got a warrior.
Speaker 0: that warrior better not be two hexes away because they're getting shot down now.
Speaker 1: This is kind of dangerous for humans that play against me.
Speaker 0: specifically There's a lot of rock-paper-scissors going on with these units and we're before and there's no unit that's like strong Just generally strong on its own.
Speaker 1: I'd say unless you're just so technologically advanced that they can't say There's a lot more advanced wars, but really there's a lot more Fire emblem going on and also they added support units and Escorts.
Speaker 1: so you can like combine similar units together and I can't figure out how to use the battering ram But I think you'd put it into a support unit and it makes all those.
Speaker 1: I also did better.
Speaker 0: I also fucked up using the siege engine, but I successfully used the catapult and man that catapult takes the walls down Like I shot a catapult at an ancient wall and it like did 40% damage to it.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh shit, son.
Speaker 1: But the the effect of all this is that Civ 5 by make by forcing the hexes and the one unit per space And all these changes individual decisions mattered more than they did in previous Civ games
Speaker 0: and it's like you can actually think about all these decisions because they're Much more abstracted and there's a lot more of them to make.
Speaker 1: Civ 6 has like 10 times more decisions than Civ 5 and they all Either matter a lot in the short term or matter a lot in the long term.
Speaker 1: like no decision you make Doesn't matter in Civ 6 as far as I can see and everything is more upfront.
Speaker 0: There's like there's.
Speaker 0: no there's nothing like a decision that you didn't realize you are making because it's hidden somewhere.
Speaker 0: It's like everything is up and in your face like choose civics now choose science now.
Speaker 0: Right receive five would only do that for certain things like choose the science and move your units.
Speaker 0: There's other things.
Speaker 0: it wouldn't even bother you now, it's like everything.
Speaker 0: it bothers you about everything.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 0: there's no decision that you didn't make because you were ignoring like city-states or something.
Speaker 1: One other thing I noticed that was a nice change just for me personally.
Speaker 1: Is that a kind of overriding theme of Civ 5?
Speaker 1: was that?
Speaker 1: Expanding and settling and conquering too fast.
Speaker 1: There was a really powerful Disincentive to doing that even if you were the.
Speaker 0: oh, yeah Six settle away just like so.
Speaker 1: Every single sieve other than five has been fucking settle if you see a good spot.
Speaker 1: Let's go for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I was the opposite of that Civ 6 went back because I feel like Everyone kind of wanted that back.
Speaker 0: there is one Limitation on that that I figured out by reading the rules very carefully.
Speaker 1: That's what I have not read the civil opedia at all yet.
Speaker 0: So, let's say you if you send up a builder and he builds on some mercury which is surprisingly a luxury good right that luxury good gives you four amenities that will be distributed to the cities that need amenities the most.
Speaker 0: and So if you have five cities One of them isn't getting any mercury.
Speaker 0: So you need actually a lot of luxury goods to support a lot of cities or else you won't have enough amenities for everyone.
Speaker 0: And oh you think just like old Sims you just build a Coliseum everywhere.
Speaker 0: it's like no no No, the Coliseum is now a wonder.
Speaker 0: get fucked.
Speaker 0: If you don't have the Coliseum you're in deep shit.
Speaker 0: But if you do have the Coliseum you got more amenities than you know to do with.
Speaker 0: everyone else can get fucked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Mean Civ 5 was similar.
Speaker 1: But again, the system now is consistent with the other systems amenities, right?
Speaker 0: But the point is similar.
Speaker 0: the point is if you expand too much you need lots and lots of amenities to cut But you don't need anything else right?
Speaker 0: because each city can have plenty of housing and be fun, you know Yeah But yeah You can.
Speaker 0: you can definitely expand and conquer much more freely like you could in the old days not be worried about like oh no Unhappiness from too much population or oh no unhappiness from too many cities.
Speaker 0: It's like no no I'm happy.
Speaker 0: only reason you would have unhappiness is not enough amenities per city And it's a lot easier to think about in your head.
Speaker 0: Like do I have enough amenity points for all these cities?
Speaker 0: Yes, it's like.
Speaker 0: do I have enough food to feed my people in Agricola?
Speaker 0: It's the same thing.
Speaker 1: Though what I noticed is that the result of all these changes too is that there's a lot more uniqueness.
Speaker 1: So like in Civ 5 if you have cities The only thing that'll differentiate cities from other cities other than their size is is it more production focused or?
Speaker 1: Culture focused?
Speaker 1: is it on the sea or not on this?
Speaker 0: Yeah Now you have.
Speaker 0: now you have a culture city have a religion city like every city having everything, you know It's sort of everything is super unique and every city-state is Specifically unique in what it and you can't have a hundred wonders in one city because they've got a hundred hexes.
Speaker 0: You got to put the wonder on a hex.
Speaker 0: No, you got to put everything on a hex somewhere, right?
Speaker 0: Now this let's talk about the problems of the games.
Speaker 0: the problem number one The biggest problem is the UI has some issues.
Speaker 0: Yeah has some good parts a lot of good parts But also some issues.
Speaker 0: one issue for example is like at least for me unit control is like a problem A lot of times.
Speaker 0: anybody like this unit has not moved yet.
Speaker 0: So I'll click on that unit and then it like doesn't let me move it.
Speaker 0: It doesn't let me move it like or so part of that is.
Speaker 1: I figured out they change movement rules In every save up to this point.
Speaker 1: say you have three movement and you're on rough terrain.
Speaker 1: It doesn't count the train you're on when you start to move.
Speaker 1: But and you can sort of cheat with that like go over a river at the end of your movements at the beginning And there's all this stuff you could do it sort of always round it up in the new sieve.
Speaker 1: It effectively always rounds down.
Speaker 1: So you'll often not have enough movement.
Speaker 1: It'll say you have a couple movement left, but it always rounds against you.
Speaker 1: So you end up not moving where you expected Hmm.
Speaker 0: Oh one other thing that forgot.
Speaker 0: that's good for unit promotions.
Speaker 0: you heal when you promote but you can't move that turn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like promoting is a discrete action, which is really nice.
Speaker 0: I like it better this way.
Speaker 0: So anyway other other bad things about sieve six.
Speaker 1: so perhaps I can never figure out what to click on and have these interfaces.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so for example a lot of things don't stand out enough like in like scooby-doo like in scooby-doo when you watch us You know There's always like they're running and they're going between all the doors in the hallway with that gag.
Speaker 0: that's in every single episode and you can always tell like when something's gonna be Animated because it's on the cell and not on the background and it looks different.
Speaker 0: it stands out in this sieve six.
Speaker 0: I can't even tell when I found what did they rename it to the tribal village which used to be the room?
Speaker 1: Three when I was playing it and I didn't grab them because I didn't realize what they were.
Speaker 0: yet in Sieve every other sieve game ever.
Speaker 1: It's like oh my god.
Speaker 0: There's a hut on this hex.
Speaker 0: touch it and sieve six.
Speaker 0: It's like it tells you but it doesn't tell you loud enough and clear enough.
Speaker 1: Like you can't see it It's like or even worse at a glance the the like the fog of war and it looks really cool.
Speaker 0: It looks it's really beautiful, but it's hard to see what's going on.
Speaker 1: Can't tell without thinking about it if it's territory.
Speaker 1: I haven't explored or territory I'm just not looking at.
Speaker 0: yeah, and it's like even if you use the strategic view, which is like the 2d board game view It's really hard to tell what's going on because there's so much stuff in these hexes.
Speaker 0: Like you got a district and you got a resource and you got it.
Speaker 0: It's like you cannot see what is happening on all these hexes.
Speaker 0: It doesn't let you zoom in or out or make hex.
Speaker 0: I wish I could we even just I wish I could make hexes bigger.
Speaker 1: It's like a you know, see all the stuff that's in them more clear Just in the UX like the buttons and they never shine enough or pop enough to remind you like.
Speaker 1: this is the thing to click On.
Speaker 1: so I literally kept trying to figure out.
Speaker 1: I could not figure out how to assign an envoy to a city-state.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because it's a little left and right arrow.
Speaker 1: It's these ornate looking arrows that look like accents just like wedge down to the side of this icon.
Speaker 1: Yep, and that the interface is rife with that.
Speaker 1: like it's.
Speaker 1: it could be a good UX but the UI is just not obvious or intuitive or Visible or like it has deep deep problems.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's definitely a lot of things going on that are not so hot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the mini-map is like impossible to use.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't zoom out enough, which instead five was kind of okay.
Speaker 0: But if you do zoom out You won't be able to tell what's going on because you just be a mess of like it'll be like a pile of junk.
Speaker 0: You can't tell what's happening.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's none of the hexes are clear enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just everything is kind of cluttered and I guess I'm just gonna have to get used to it.
Speaker 0: No, like there isn't really a city screen anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like a little.
Speaker 0: there's a little thing in the bottom right and then you have to click on this button and that'll open a Big thing on the left that has way too much fucking information in it.
Speaker 0: Right when all I really want to see is just how many do I have enough amenities and do I have enough housing?
Speaker 0: All this other info in there that I ignore because I don't know what the hell it means or if
Speaker 1: I want to see my People or any of that stuff is like all these extra sub buttons
Speaker 0: and I can't like push left and right to like scroll through My cities I can't get if I don't know if it exists and I just can't find it.
Speaker 0: I can't find like a unit list anywhere.
Speaker 0: I want cuz like I want to upgrade all of my you know slingers to archers this turn.
Speaker 0: I just discovered archery and I haven't moved them yet.
Speaker 0: And I know I've got a bunch of money.
Speaker 0: I can't just like go through them all.
Speaker 1: one and it's like it's not a Civ 5 did a much better job of having Screens that show you the information you actually want in an intuitive manner.
Speaker 0: They did add some stuff to help with the management of a ton of units though.
Speaker 0: You can group units together into core and then later in the game into armies.
Speaker 1: and you can also like with settlers.
Speaker 1: You can have an escort.
Speaker 0: Yeah the at your link two guys together and then you just move them all at once.
Speaker 0: It makes things a lot easier.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't have to be like, oh shit I move my settlers you far my warrior can't catch.
Speaker 1: So they also did something clever in Civ 5 with cities while the city UI is garbage in Civ 6. in Civ 5 You could manually assign your dudes or you could check a focus.
Speaker 1: So you could say like focus on culture focus on gold focused on production focus on great people focus on science.
Speaker 1: Civ 6 does this so much better But it doesn't tell you it's doing it unless you really like you notice because the UI is again garbage.
Speaker 1: It shows all those same things.
Speaker 1: if you click on one It highlights it and says focus on this.
Speaker 1: if you click on another it focuses on both.
Speaker 1: So you can say focus on and things and it'll tune the city toward those things.
Speaker 1: Obviously the more you pick the less full focus you'll get.
Speaker 1: but you could say Focus on food and gears and forget everything else.
Speaker 1: You can also click on something and say avoid this And you can combine the two.
Speaker 1: so you can say fuck religion really go hard on science Really go hard on food and let everything else be default.
Speaker 1: That's real clever and cool, but it is a bad UI and it's not obvious.
Speaker 1: That's what it's doing.
Speaker 0: So one thing that's good and bad I found is the great peoples.
Speaker 0: So you get great people play.
Speaker 1: I did not realize until I read something that those are individual great people.
Speaker 1: you're all fighting over.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is crazy.
Speaker 0: So you get great people points and you get enough great people points.
Speaker 0: You can buy a great people and it's like it's almost a lot like a board game where there's a bunch of great people Available face up like tickets a ride and it's like
Speaker 1: I got
Speaker 0: him and now that one is mine And he does something different than every other great Scientist that you could get.
Speaker 0: and then they draw a new great scientist from the virtual deck who is now the face-up great Scientist and the next person was enough points to get.
Speaker 0: great scientists can get him or her or whatever.
Speaker 0: So It's like a drafting board game to get the currently available Great person and you're like racing to get enough points.
Speaker 0: if it's one you like and if it's one you don't like you can Pass and wait for the next one or whatever to get one that you do like.
Speaker 0: The problem I have with the grand.
Speaker 0: that's really fun, you know a board game like a mechanic.
Speaker 0: it's easier to understand.
Speaker 0: It's unique.
Speaker 0: the great people do specific things.
Speaker 0: It's more flavorful, you know It's easier to understand like progress towards great person because you can look at that screen, you know The heart.
Speaker 0: the problem is is that a lot of the great in Civ 5 The great people had like multi purposes a lot of the time and you could always do something with a great person.
Speaker 0: It was very rarely a time we have they always.
Speaker 1: they always had a long-term option than a short-term option, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you have a great engineer and you didn't have something you want.
Speaker 0: It's like insta build.
Speaker 0: you could just build like the factory.
Speaker 0: you could build the Manufactory and you could get a use out of the great person.
Speaker 0: no matter what You know, you got a great artist for example, and you didn't have a slot for a great work of art.
Speaker 0: You could send the artist to another civilization to mess with them, right?
Speaker 0: You know There's always something you could do with a great person.
Speaker 0: now a lot of times like I got a great scientist When I was playing and to activate this great scientist ability.
Speaker 0: I needed a holy site.
Speaker 0: I didn't have a holy site.
Speaker 0: I didn't know how to make a holy site.
Speaker 0: I It was.
Speaker 0: I did and there was nothing else a great scientist could do.
Speaker 0: it was useless unless you had a holy site to activate His ability.
Speaker 0: he just did nothing except take up a space on the board and clutter up my UI more with this little beaker symbol Yep, and it's like if I get a great person no matter what else is true about my civilization I should be able to do something with them.
Speaker 0: Suboptimal is fine.
Speaker 0: It should be more than nothing because I spent my great people points and you know even if You know, it's like yeah, you could tell me I should have skipped and waited for the next great person to come along.
Speaker 0: But it's like like why did I earn all those great people points for right?
Speaker 0: I want something now.
Speaker 0: I don't want to wait for something else and let someone else have that thing, you know Yep.
Speaker 0: So I guess in the I ended up there a lot of times where I wasn't able to get enough slots to use.
Speaker 0: I like Tons of great artists and writers and there was nothing I could bill.
Speaker 0: I had already built everything to give me slots to get a great art slots and writing slots.
Speaker 0: I had libraries and shit.
Speaker 0: I needed more slots and I didn't have enough.
Speaker 0: I had way more great people than slots.
Speaker 0: Nothing to do now, this is not a review because we've played so I've played it for like Days, I've never even gotten past like the Renaissance.
Speaker 1: Yep So we'll obviously review the game later, but this is the first time in the 11 years We've been doing gig nights that a sieved a new sieve game came out and was immediately full on.
Speaker 1: So Sieve five we could basically review.
Speaker 0: three was pre geek nights We were at RIT and four.
Speaker 1: four was early geek nights five was mid and six is now so four and five we could review pretty much fully Shortly after they came out and then review again when the expansions came out.
Speaker 1: This one is full on right away.
Speaker 1: It's gonna take me like a month of playing it to have a full sense of if I'm gonna 100% migrate to this one or If sieve five is still got a lot of staying power.
Speaker 0: for me it depends on how much they patch right because I think you know, they know it's not perfect and we'll see what kind of fixes and changes come through and if they make things better or worse or any.
Speaker 1: and also mad props to them for taking the Aggressive approach of not going back to baby mode.
Speaker 1: They basically said fuck it and started with brave new world.
Speaker 1: So they introduced a lot of stuff in a hurry in a new game, which could put off players.
Speaker 1: I'm really curious to see how the reception goes.
Speaker 0: Well, they currently I believe.
Speaker 0: I read somewhere that the maximum Simultaneous players of sieve six on Steam at one time has already beaten sieve fives record for that same statistic.
Speaker 0: You know I believe that partly because it's like at launch everyone starts playing sieve six how many people are playing all at once?
Speaker 0: X number?
Speaker 0: Sieve five has never reached that number that high for simultaneous players all at once.
Speaker 1: It might partly be that it's getting to be especially in the States the time of the year when you'll sit at home and play A game like this for four hours.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's cold.
Speaker 1: Yep This was the proper time to release this game.
Speaker 0: I think Everything's getting released now.
Speaker 0: It's really so.
Speaker 1: yeah expect a much deeper review in like a month.
Speaker 1: and Also, I can't say anything about multiplayer because I have no idea how this will work.
Speaker 1: multiplayer It'll be a while before I can arrange multiplayer to play it in earnest and Frankly as much as I love single-player sieve five And probably sieve six.
Speaker 1: The only staying power for any sieve game I have now is multiplayer.
Speaker 1: There's something about playing against a human on the other side, but it'll be a long time before I can review that.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons in order of the amount of money.
Speaker 1: Give us them a continuing basis are Ellen Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Nicholas Brando, Heidi McNichol, Amanda Duchette, Christian Koontz, Construction Noises, Ivy Faye, MySadie.com, William Eisendrills, Jeremy Miner, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn, Shervin Von Horl, Iggy Kid, Rare Lavelle, James David White, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, Irish Wristwatch, Aaron Cerise, Brian Fisher, Sailor Vista, Jai Fried Pork, Matthew Smith, Don Schleich, Char Tovish and Joshua Joerster, Tyler Eller, Sean Yeager, Sam Cordery, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Booskerry Lander, Brian Sidroni, Finn Eric Silverrod, The Rural Juror, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redmond, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be back.
Speaker 1: I have no updates here.
Speaker 1: Expect the patreon to start exploding again now that I'm back and creating content and We have really no travel coming up.
Speaker 1: other than I mean gamer X is in New York.
Speaker 1: So nothing to tell magfest of note, so expect a whole bunch of stuff and we'll leave it at that for now.
Speaker 1: So I leave you with something.
Speaker 1: The game will raise a brief You should realize.