Speaker 0: It's Thursday October 27th 2016.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight timepieces.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: You know we haven't really complained about the weather in a while because they got to the point where we don't.
Speaker 0: we complain about the weather every day because we see in summer we're usually like oh, it's great and We're biking to work or at least biking around in the winter.
Speaker 0: And there's that middle area where it's too cold to bike even though it's still bike season And then we veg about it.
Speaker 0: I gotta tell you today is the shittiest day.
Speaker 0: We've had yet It's not snowing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd rather it be snowing though.
Speaker 0: This is just like that rainy miserable.
Speaker 0: I do not like rain because rain means I can't bike.
Speaker 0: Yeah, thunderstorms good.
Speaker 0: summer thunderstorm is good.
Speaker 0: winter thunderstorm is good.
Speaker 0: fall thunderstorm is just miserable.
Speaker 0: spring thunderstorm is also miserable.
Speaker 1: Stay inside.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess it's good that her raining is fun.
Speaker 0: I guess it's good that I want to go outside, but I guess just the weather.
Speaker 1: I don't want to go outside when it's 50 degrees out.
Speaker 1: I want it to be 90 degrees and degrees is fine if it's not raining.
Speaker 0: That's bike weather.
Speaker 0: It's really cold You're I don't know.
Speaker 0: What's how you've gotten so old so quickly.
Speaker 1: It's really cold.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Hey your head and see how cold you are.
Speaker 0: so now I'm here for a reason.
Speaker 0: So uh because I was in Australia.
Speaker 1: This is now I think someplace where it's warm now.
Speaker 0: actually it was spring it was getting warm But it was 87 one day.
Speaker 0: so we went swimming and you know what I mean.
Speaker 1: But the thing is during that period when you were in Australia It was there was an unusually warm period in New York for a few days.
Speaker 0: I know I'm a little bit salty about that.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's kind of like remember we went to the first pack sauce And it was kind of cold and rainy the whole time.
Speaker 0: there was one warm day like when the first day We're like wow Melvin's pretty great even in the kind of endo winter and then the next day.
Speaker 0: It was like no fuck you Remember that last day of packs like everyone every attendee was huddled around those heaters.
Speaker 1: yeah, like standing like trying to play games on top of me, but I mean we were close to Antarctica than we've ever been ever.
Speaker 1: and You think no matter what time of year it is it should be cold When you're that close to Antarctica, but no surprisingly warm considering it was winter there, and we were close to Antarctica.
Speaker 1: So like it's early spring it makes me wonder like if I go to the place in Antarctica That's closest to like the south of Australia.
Speaker 1: Is that like a warmish, Antarctica?
Speaker 1: Is it like only probably slightly below freezing there and not the negative a zillion, and I guess think of it this way we were.
Speaker 0: you know we're standing by Bondi Beach and Think about how cold the water is in.
Speaker 0: like Wildwood in the middle of summer.
Speaker 0: It's still like a shock when you get into it.
Speaker 0: You kind of just like err and deal with it.
Speaker 1: It's not actually see.
Speaker 1: that thing is that water isn't actually that cold if you put a thermometer in it.
Speaker 1: It's just that you're so hot you feel it relatively In the warm water it feels like it's burning.
Speaker 0: so actually no I had so until a couple years ago.
Speaker 0: I never thought to do this.
Speaker 0: like we just pick around like we go to Wildwood randomly and just go swimming Randomly, and I wouldn't even know like if the water is gonna be good or whatever till we got in it.
Speaker 0: but I started actually looking at charts and knowing how warm water is gonna be and Realize that number didn't mean anything to me.
Speaker 0: And then I did a bunch of more reading to figure out what temperatures of beach water feel good or bad And like what the lines are.
Speaker 0: now I kind of know and I'll say this the water in New Jersey in early summer is cold as Fuck.
Speaker 0: it is colder than the spring.
Speaker 0: the early spring not colder than space.
Speaker 0: It's colder than the early spring water in Sydney.
Speaker 0: early spring water in Sydney was like Warmer than you would expect New Jersey water except at the very end of summer, so it was good times, but the thing I did while we were there is once again, I rented a car and drove around a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: and because I don't drive that often in the US anymore and Actually a lot of the times I've driven long distances in the last couple years have been in Australia It didn't feel as weird as it's felt in the past.
Speaker 0: in fact It felt kind of normal.
Speaker 0: and the only thing I couldn't do is parallel park.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I could I might have been able to but why even try?
Speaker 0: yeah We were in this little town, and we you know we're driving in and Emily's like wow You just drove like it was nothing and I was like yeah I'm getting used to it though she was startled by.
Speaker 0: she'd never encountered one of those European style roundabouts before And she was doing the thing that you were doing when we remember we drove down to Phillip Island where I was like Yell.
Speaker 0: if it looks like I'm going into the wrong lane Or if a car's coming or something you know in case I miss something like I start to turn the wrong way on the freeway So that's all working fine.
Speaker 0: but then we come to this roundabout and I just turned left into it, and there's a car fucking coming from like this other way because it's a roundabout and Emily's like And I'm just like.
Speaker 0: you've never been to a roundabout before have you mm-hmm?
Speaker 0: so uh but anyway after having done this When I came back to the States, and I was walking in New York the next day I Kind of looked at the street And I saw cars and it looked super fucking weird to have the drivers on the left side.
Speaker 0: My brain just had locked driving in as be on the wrong side.
Speaker 0: because I think Every time I've driven so much in Australia lately like over the last couple years and whenever I'm driving in Australia I'm doing the Seinfeld thing of thinking don't die don't die and concentrating really hard the entire time I think I messed my brain up.
Speaker 0: So I think I want to make sure a few weeks go by before I drive again in the US or I might just go the wrong way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what's up?
Speaker 0: What's up in Scotland?
Speaker 0: Yesterday I went to oh yeah, we ate your bread.
Speaker 0: It was really good.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: It was that bread was over proofed and flat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what though it had a real good crust.
Speaker 1: yeah, well anyway, so Yesterday they had a city bike communities planning meeting.
Speaker 0: oh Did you go to?
Speaker 0: it?
Speaker 0: was that like community board like you're?
Speaker 1: no It wasn't a community board meeting right it was a meeting for our community board Area which I'm not sure if you're in or not.
Speaker 1: if you are you're on like the very southern edge of it Which is community board one don't think we are I'm sure either in one or two.
Speaker 0: I'm in one think I'm in two.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna double check anyway But it was at the beer garden, which is like two minutes from my house by walking.
Speaker 1: So I go to the beer garden and the way it worked was you waited and they had a bunch of tables and they put you at a table with some random people.
Speaker 1: and then you're looking at basically the New York City bike map and They give you the city bike presentation Which is like 20 minutes.
Speaker 1: this guy talking to you and like with a book and he's the city bike employee And there's also a Department of Transportation employee And you listen to him tell you all about city bike and he talks about it Like you never heard of it before because
Speaker 0: I saw on Gothamist.
Speaker 0: They were like a story is getting it.
Speaker 1: Here's the map right and then they go.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Now we're gonna do the exercise.
Speaker 0: Oh, look it literally I'm in one.
Speaker 0: it ends at Queensborough Plaza.
Speaker 1: So you could have come anyway could have come.
Speaker 0: I always thought I was into.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I know this now the same one I am anyway, so you then they flip over the other map and the other map has like this, you know outline around the Community board zone.
Speaker 1: they're like city bikes only going in this inside here end of story.
Speaker 1: and then they're like city bike has to go either on public property Property that has to.
Speaker 1: it has to be somewhere that's accessible 24/7.
Speaker 1: We can't put it in like a park that closes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and it could even be on private property, you know, as long as the person who owns it is chill.
Speaker 1: You know stuff like that, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah And then on the map there's a grid and they're like there's gonna be one dock Per square on the grid and they were like figure out where the dots you go.
Speaker 1: in the square There's little symbols that are either squares or triangles and a square means like it's gonna be on The road and a triangle means on the sidewalk or something like that of like the possible locations for a dock in that square Huh?
Speaker 1: and if you like one of the locations you put a little green thingy and if you don't like one of the locations you put a red thingy and then you have a piece of paper and you write down like the code for the spot you picked and Then an explanation like don't put it there.
Speaker 1: That's in the middle of a crazy seven-way intersection and people won't be able to get to the bike and if they do they'll just die Like I'm afraid to even walk over to where you'd put that little symbol.
Speaker 1: And then the other and then you put one in somewhere else and you're like put it here.
Speaker 1: That's a piece of road that no one drives on and you could totally just close it and cars wouldn't even know Because they don't drive there and you spend like 20 minutes putting little flaggies on the map, but then you go home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I saw the like.
Speaker 0: I was reading the Gothamist article and they were just talking about how Everyone's really excited about the city bike and pretty much everyone.
Speaker 1: everyone who I sat with at my little table It's like six people I guess per table.
Speaker 1: Everyone I sat with was a pro bike person.
Speaker 0: The thing is what happened?
Speaker 1: there was not any no old people who were like and cars were there.
Speaker 0: They'll be at the community board meeting complaining as soon as they start seeing those city bike docks appear.
Speaker 1: They had their chance to come and put red flags like the city bike people and the dot people were like.
Speaker 1: Yay, look at all these green flags.
Speaker 1: Everyone's putting on all these things.
Speaker 1: It's like no red flags anywhere.
Speaker 1: We know it's like.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh, I guess yeah, that makes sense, right?
Speaker 1: Someone who's you know, pro city bike is gonna be going.
Speaker 1: Oh, you should put one here.
Speaker 1: You should put one there and someone who's all cars gonna be like don't put it here Don't you know?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll put it here.
Speaker 1: That's in front of my apartment.
Speaker 1: I mean that video I saw was this old man They're not gonna be like, oh, yes, you should put one here.
Speaker 0: He was Screaming at the community board person like standing up just screaming.
Speaker 0: You could see spit flying out about how dangerous bikes are and how they shouldn't allow them in the city.
Speaker 1: Sure, cuz you know bikes kill so many people and Nobody Never been hit by car.
Speaker 0: the people who get hit by cars might actually die on their bike.
Speaker 0: So maybe it's the bikes fault.
Speaker 1: See the thing is in New York if you kill someone with a car you totally get away with it pretty much.
Speaker 1: So we should find those people who are in the cars.
Speaker 1: Yes, they're anti-bike and pro car.
Speaker 1: We should just get a car and run them over.
Speaker 0: It should be easy because they have not illegal.
Speaker 1: They're so afraid It's not illegal.
Speaker 1: Nothing happens to you.
Speaker 1: If you hit someone with a car It's totally legal.
Speaker 1: as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 0: They're so afraid of bikes because they think they'll get hit by and they must be bad at walking.
Speaker 0: It'd probably be real easy to have plausible deniability just to run them down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just like oh he came out from between those two parked cars that I wouldn't be parking there.
Speaker 1: I would have seen him if it was a city bike dock.
Speaker 1: there You can see anyone standing next to one of those.
Speaker 1: but ah geeks not coming out from between two cars I mean, he's hiding big planning public murders since 2005.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying if there's someone you don't like wait for them to take a trip to New York and then run them over You will probably get away with it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna absolutely get us unless you're black.
Speaker 1: Well, not white.
Speaker 1: you can also another color.
Speaker 1: but the other thing is the police will investigate it.
Speaker 1: So if they see like, huh?
Speaker 1: This person who was hit is Scott and they have a strong connection to this person who hit them named rim.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what had?
Speaker 1: this doesn't seem like just a car ax.
Speaker 0: what's this radio show where they're talking about murdering people with cars?
Speaker 1: Right, they'll actually look into it.
Speaker 1: if it's like, you know someone you're related to which is why you need it marks But it looks like he was accelerating not breaking.
Speaker 1: Yeah You need like the.
Speaker 1: you know The the hitman with no relation to the victim.
Speaker 0: What city would be more perfect for strangers on a train?
Speaker 0: You you set it up to where you see another biker on the train and you pass each other notes of who to run over With your bikes.
Speaker 1: you need a car person to do the murdering.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I guess none of us have cars.
Speaker 1: You know what, you know we could do zip car.
Speaker 1: No, we set up a Car share.
Speaker 1: know the uber of murder.
Speaker 1: Hire a literal uber and the uber guy gets a notice and either it's to bring someone somewhere deliver some food or run someone over.
Speaker 0: It's funny because it's uber.
Speaker 0: it's uber but for murder, but it's also literally uber.
Speaker 1: You go on your app you go to uber and you say this person lives around here.
Speaker 1: Here's a picture.
Speaker 1: hit them if you can.
Speaker 1: You'll get paid X dollars, you know escrow with the uber app.
Speaker 1: Yep So prove to me they're dead when I see the notice of.
Speaker 1: you know They're dead.
Speaker 1: then you'll get the money.
Speaker 0: in actual news.
Speaker 0: We do have to mourn something and this isn't technology.
Speaker 0: while it uses technology It is just a service as they think you can use.
Speaker 0: but if you live under a rock you might not realize that vine is Dying Twitter is dying and vine is the first piece of the Twitter that got killed.
Speaker 0: The thing is if Twitter made them no money Twitter has so many users and there's nothing else like it.
Speaker 0: You can't.
Speaker 0: it'd be really hard to make something like it unless you just made it exactly.
Speaker 1: I have an idea.
Speaker 1: if
Speaker 0: it gets low and I'll
Speaker 1: tell you after the show
Speaker 0: Yeah If it gets low enough
Speaker 1: to kill the whole show if I talk about it
Speaker 0: if it gets low enough It would be entirely possible for some rich people to just buy it and run it at breakeven forever.
Speaker 1: You know if it gets low enough remember those guys who are running the meridian 59.
Speaker 0: Yeah The users all buy it.
Speaker 0: make it a co-op.
Speaker 1: we could do something like that's.
Speaker 0: I've been thinking about that a lot.
Speaker 1: I got a better idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll save it for after the show.
Speaker 0: do a show on it on Monday.
Speaker 1: There's no reason to do a show on it.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: people see We just did a short show on uber for murder, but it's uber.
Speaker 1: So I think that's all there was to say about that.
Speaker 0: but vine is dead.
Speaker 0: The moral is social networks can die kids.
Speaker 0: a lot of you're too young to remember palace Chad or aim or ICQ or all these things that are dead just because.
Speaker 1: well, there was there was.
Speaker 1: see the thing is people remember myspace.
Speaker 1: That's like the old one that you know died right the first one that got killed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you think oh why nobody Remembers the sort of in-between ones.
Speaker 1: the things of like the friend stir all the stirs how you Named company and the or cut and there was like a bunch of other ones that I don't remember because no one remembers them.
Speaker 1: I just remember they existed.
Speaker 1: there was a.
Speaker 0: but also it's real different because back then Not many people use social networks like not many people used internet.
Speaker 1: It's because in though the reason that all of those didn't work out is because people didn't have smartphones at that time Yep, but even then to the people who use like myspace like Twitter like that here without smartphones is just like what is it?
Speaker 1: It's nothing.
Speaker 0: Yep, you were they were technically savvy.
Speaker 0: So if a network was shutting down they could move their shit and just kind of deal with it.
Speaker 0: It would suck.
Speaker 0: but like up myspace is dead live journals dead.
Speaker 0: I better move my shit somewhere, but now Everybody uses stuff.
Speaker 0: So like people who have made basically careers putting stuff on vine.
Speaker 0: I fucked.
Speaker 1: well They're gonna let you download your vines.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz you those people to have a way They're not just turning it off right away.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I mean, I guess you can download them all upload them YouTube.
Speaker 1: The thing is is people are like they try to sell things and if they can't sell them they shut them down.
Speaker 1: It's like dude like You could.
Speaker 1: just why not just open source or you can find someone in the community who will.
Speaker 0: I have been on the other side Of that.
Speaker 1: we'll just take it for free and run it.
Speaker 0: I have been on the other side of that.
Speaker 1: Give it away or sell it for like.
Speaker 0: I can't talk about the details of this.
Speaker 1: if you sell it for more than zero dollars No, like even one dollar you would be more than zero dollar.
Speaker 1: Nope
Speaker 0: the legal due diligence alone cost so much more than you expect that Open source and something can cost a lot more than just not
Speaker 1: even just open source Just like give it someone giving
Speaker 0: it away even because if there is any Code or any art of any type that is licensed in any particular way Lawyers have to make sure that those are all transferable and reassignable and that costs a lot of money.
Speaker 1: It's just like make a trust to hold it.
Speaker 0: Even then you might not be able to transfer to that trust.
Speaker 0: It gets real complicated in a hurry and also if you're shutting it down You might be a dick and not want anyone else to get a competitive advantage based on all the hard work and money you lost.
Speaker 0: That's usually not the real reason but I've heard that Express before.
Speaker 0: that's like I Tried real hard.
Speaker 1: I wrote this book and I don't want anyone that didn't sell.
Speaker 1: well, and I don't want anything to read it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna burn every copy.
Speaker 0: Here's the example I can probably talk about because it's been so long.
Speaker 0: Cuz you know, I used to work at IBM and while I was not on like the legal side or the business side or anything like that We used OS 2 in my department.
Speaker 0: So I actually had like installers for continued releases of OS 2 after it was dead to the public.
Speaker 1: So there was some employee there who is still working on OS 2 as late as the 2000s like I was patching it.
Speaker 0: I was someone who knew how to wrote write code and knew their way around the OS 2 code my Parting gift and could patch it the parting gift My department gave to me when I quit IBM and moved on to other things in like 2000.
Speaker 0: When did I quit?
Speaker 0: 2007.
Speaker 1: it was late 2000.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then they gave me the last Installer of the last build of OS 2 which had come out that year and they were that was the last one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they actually were ending it.
Speaker 1: So the people who had wrote the patch for that Quit.
Speaker 0: so I have the install discs for the most up-to-date OS 2 you can get.
Speaker 1: What does it run on x86?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think so.
Speaker 0: It's just a bunch of CDs.
Speaker 1: It has to run on a. I mean It.
Speaker 1: can it run on a modern PC that has EFI?
Speaker 0: you probably not.
Speaker 0: You'd have to do some stuff.
Speaker 1: You need a motherboard with a BIOS and like what?
Speaker 1: What does it even support?
Speaker 1: like what hardware do you need to run it?
Speaker 0: virtual box or DOS box?
Speaker 1: I guess you can run in virtual box.
Speaker 1: That makes sense.
Speaker 0: but so I as much as I could actually campaigned and like got meetings with people even though I was just like a lowly dude and Like this department that I was in department like 68 DD.
Speaker 0: They don't even number departments that way anymore.
Speaker 0: but I advocated as much as I could at every level had access to for them to open source it or give it away like how you Weren't you were working in like a factory?
Speaker 1: What connection did you have to like the oh the oh the operating system writing?
Speaker 1: development group one.
Speaker 0: it's companies that are that big have formal protocols for everything you can imagine like if you have a if you have a grievance with the way the CEOs run in things there is a Byzantine process by which your grievance can get to that person's desk And I followed every one of the cuz.
Speaker 0: I had nothing to do like I was.
Speaker 1: So you read the employee handbook I did like.
Speaker 0: I went through everything I could do the one with the literal eyeball literal bumblebee.
Speaker 0: The answers I got back basically came down to the Licensing of some of the libraries and some of the stuff and people who like companies that co-wrote code together.
Speaker 0: it would be Literally impossible.
Speaker 1: you have the CD.
Speaker 1: So why don't we just put I don't have the source code.
Speaker 0: I have the install.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: We can just at least put it on bit torrent and no one would know where it came from.
Speaker 0: Let me wait long enough until this podcast episode has fallen into distant memory because I really don't want to get sued by IBM.
Speaker 1: How would they know it was you?
Speaker 1: Well, I know for a fact that some my old co-workers listen to the show Right, but I mean it would just be like oh on Pirate Bay you can get OS - where did that come from?
Speaker 1: In fact, they come from anywhere.
Speaker 0: Oh except and then what believe me the people in that apartment probably still have that OS - running somewhere.
Speaker 0: Someone can't?
Speaker 0: someone?
Speaker 0: there are attendees of Connecticut who are children of people I worked with who come to Connecticut.
Speaker 1: We should try to get it running in a virtual box and stream that and sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually that could be.
Speaker 0: That gives me an idea for some patreon content.
Speaker 1: Let's just play with OS - wow this thing sucks you can't do anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what apps what software can this?
Speaker 1: is there even for this?
Speaker 0: actually Scott?
Speaker 0: That's a whole idea for a YouTube channel.
Speaker 0: You just run old computers.
Speaker 0: There's a whole stream.
Speaker 1: It's just a big guy does that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the whole stream would be Can we actually entertain ourselves with this?
Speaker 0: Like we're not gonna explore how it works.
Speaker 1: You can entertain yourself.
Speaker 1: We can entertain yourselves for weeks of my apple 2gs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the magic plus would be harder We would because I don't have enough equipment to make it go.
Speaker 0: god I used to entertain myself just by watching like Encarta encyclopedia videos.
Speaker 0: There were two seconds long.
Speaker 1: Encarta tiny is like you had a 640 by 480 screen and that was high-res.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and in a little box on that screen We're talking like 64 by 48 right with Encarta on the CD It's by four was like a 10 second clip at best from Star Wars and that was great.
Speaker 0: Yep So, uh in remembrance of vine, I'm just gonna link to this.
Speaker 1: It's a verge article that has basically a managed to an animated gif on a CD.
Speaker 1: Rob that took five minutes to load But an audio.
Speaker 0: this is just in memoriam to vine because I miss it.
Speaker 0: and My secondary thing of the day is my favorite vine of all time ever Hands-down the best vine ever in my opinion and that is my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: And I'm just saying that now because now it's time for Things of the day.
Speaker 1: How about that?
Speaker 0: So yeah, I worked out.
Speaker 1: you ever shred some paper and a paper shredder.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah In fact, I brought a paper shredder to our IT and then I threw it away because I never needed it for anything And it was stupid.
Speaker 1: I actually have a file cabinet where I put all my important papers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and but the thing is it got full and then I looked in there and I realized a lot of those papers not so important.
Speaker 0: You know the last time I thought to do that and some of them that are important I could just scan and get rid of row most of my papers away as I get him cuz I just don't give a fuck anymore.
Speaker 1: But I get no papers anymore, I'm like 99.9% of papers, I don't like I get no mail I just do everything digitally, but I went in there and I was like, is there anything in here?
Speaker 0: I can throw away.
Speaker 0: and it was all like titles to cars I'd owned in the past and like my birth certificate.
Speaker 0: You all you need that my originals just in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway, so I got a shredder at Amazon.
Speaker 1: I started shredding stuff.
Speaker 1: and the way a shredder works You know it turns the paper the little bits if you get a bullshit one real old.
Speaker 0: Did you get the ones that get a strip shredder or a cross shredder, right?
Speaker 1: You know anyway.
Speaker 1: But the point is it has all these basically like metal discs that are really close to each other and have weird shapes on them and are really sharp and The paper gets caught in between them.
Speaker 1: and they're also like sort of like, you know at angles to each other.
Speaker 1: So a piece of paper gets caught in there and it can't escape.
Speaker 1: It just gets pulled through by the clever shape and the motor is strong enough.
Speaker 1: that paper is not escaping It's going through but it's also getting cut as it goes through and a bunch of bits come out and it's like, oh, alright.
Speaker 1: So what if you took that same idea of a shredder and you just went big?
Speaker 1: real big Way big and you just made those metal discs eat out of bigger metal and harder metal?
Speaker 1: You could shred just about anything and yes.
Speaker 1: Yes, you can.
Speaker 1: here is a shredder so big?
Speaker 1: They just put a car in it and the car gets shredded.
Speaker 0: I like how they put the.
Speaker 1: you might be thinking like, uh, you know a car being shredded, right?
Speaker 1: It's like the body of the car is like this really weak-ass metal.
Speaker 1: It's kind of thin, you know, once the engine block gets in there, it's gonna like get jammed.
Speaker 1: It's like no Like.
Speaker 0: I put it in feet first.
Speaker 0: So eventually the engine is like pushed out the front and then eaten.
Speaker 1: Yep spoilers It's you mean you don't need to knowing what happens does not ruin seeing it happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's no twist at the end the car doesn't just come out.
Speaker 0: I guess you're a reverse it.
Speaker 0: it would look like an awesome nanotech machine.
Speaker 1: that makes it actually be surprisingly bad at shredding paper Because a piece of paper would probably just make it through unscathed.
Speaker 1: Yep, or just slightly pressed.
Speaker 0: There's an extreme sport.
Speaker 0: you have two people and you dance on top of one of these things.
Speaker 1: You have two people fight on top fight on top of this thing Two people get up on it you turn it on and they fight and if anyone survives they win.
Speaker 0: So My actual thing of the day because a vine is not enough to be a thing of the day is Just this little video and you might recognize our friend Neil Cisarega in it And it's just really short and cute and Scott and I both found it independently and watch it a while ago and laughed at it.
Speaker 0: It's titled simply friend or foe.
Speaker 0: I Got this But anyway in the meta moment the book club book is Rebecca I'm gonna read it real soon.
Speaker 0: I'm almost done with that shattered sword book about the Battle of Midway.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 1: I guess I will continue reading it tonight because I only read like a few chapters and then stuff.
Speaker 0: So remember I was talking yesterday about the last show we did about private Amari in Tony's number four Plane and we kept forgetting about him.
Speaker 0: So You responded to this.
Speaker 1: I talked about this at length.
Speaker 1: I don't know the words you just said were basically just Who flew the the scouting plane out?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah the what you just said did not bring that to mind.
Speaker 0: so I'm further in the book and there's a point where like the battles way progressed and like way later on and like I have to carriers are sunk and all this nonsense is going on and The author is like.
Speaker 0: so, you know cruiser whatever.
Speaker 0: Tony was instructed to send out its scouts to try to whatever Tony number four took off.
Speaker 0: and then parentheses It's like presumably still with our hapless private Atari.
Speaker 0: So I still don't know if he survived but I'm pretty sure he did.
Speaker 0: I really want to find out.
Speaker 1: Oh, you think he got back fueled and took off again?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they're not sure.
Speaker 1: but the plane the same.
Speaker 0: He went out again.
Speaker 1: the same plane went out again, but they don't know who took off.
Speaker 1: Yeah in it the second time, but he got back.
Speaker 1: Yep So he got back and the plane fueled and re and took off again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he may not have been the pilot on the second launch.
Speaker 0: apparently He fucked up a bunch again on the second flight too, so he might not have been that good.
Speaker 1: So, I mean whoever was on the second flight possibly not him fucked up.
Speaker 0: So maybe the plane wasn't him or someone else gave a report back.
Speaker 0: They were like, yeah I cited five American cruisers and five American aircraft carriers.
Speaker 0: I point out there were not five American aircraft carriers in that ocean.
Speaker 1: we're that five American have cares in the world.
Speaker 0: at that time if you count the one that was sinking but hadn't sunk yet and The one that was in Europe at the time I didn't know that any of them had ever sunk ever.
Speaker 0: We lost a bunch of aircraft carriers.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Do you know how much you know about World War two in the Pacific?
Speaker 1: There were boat wars.
Speaker 0: We won.
Speaker 0: Rough history.
Speaker 0: Can you name any battles from the Pacific war?
Speaker 1: Midway.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: That's the one I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: Yorktown got fucked up in that battle and so did the entire Carrier task force of the Japanese Kido Butai.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Those are the people who attack Pearl Harbor.
Speaker 1: I Mean as far as wars go, you know, I've always considered the details of individual battles to be material only need or Worth knowing for war nerds and military fanboys who are basically the same thing, but Scott I'm not a war nerd.
Speaker 1: I am in fact anti-war nerd.
Speaker 0: I guess there's some.
Speaker 0: there's some utility in my mind to the broad strokes of history and understanding what happened and occasionally zooming very far in to wars and non-wars just to get a sense of the actual complexity of real life in different areas in history.
Speaker 1: Like that material is best used for making excellent movies.
Speaker 0: I think you can make a really for example any comic book about.
Speaker 1: well, they're like they're like 20 movies I just thought of that are pretty much just zoom in on war.
Speaker 1: Yeah Does boot does boots?
Speaker 1: a real good movie probably the best one of those?
Speaker 0: Or the books like all quiet on the Western Front though.
Speaker 1: That was bridge over River.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also zoom in on war Hogan's heroes.
Speaker 1: No Also, that's not a movie.
Speaker 0: I know But this is different because it's very Technical and detailed about things you wouldn't think about.
Speaker 0: like the dude is researching like based on all these ships logs The this account of the battle is actually provably bullshit.
Speaker 0: And here's our best reconstruction of what actually happened in this moment.
Speaker 0: deliberately Yeah, so anyway What else we got?
Speaker 1: we're gonna be at gamer X East spelled the G a y em er X?
Speaker 0: Yep, as in and for a good reason.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is an LGBT focused and friendly gaming convention.
Speaker 1: It's just a gaming con.
Speaker 1: It just happens to be fabulous.
Speaker 1: Everyone's welcome much more fabulous than facts, which is not unfabulous But significantly less so than gamer X.
Speaker 0: gamer X is pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: They have multiple events.
Speaker 0: This is the first one in New York and we're gonna be there doing a panel and otherwise We're just gonna be playing games cuz it's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean why not go play game if there's a gaming convention in Manhattan?
Speaker 1: in Manhattan 40 bucks right fucking there for two days.
Speaker 1: Why would I not go there and play games?
Speaker 0: Yeah So, uh, we're also gonna be a magfest which is coming up in January.
Speaker 1: There's a gaming convention in DC for four days non-stop.
Speaker 1: Why would I not go there and play packs?
Speaker 0: Prime the biggest packs at least the best packs shuts down at midnight.
Speaker 0: Magfest does not shut down.
Speaker 1: Magfest is the only convention that is so fabulous as to have 4 a.m Dig dug.
Speaker 0: Magfest is the only convention in recorded history where you think to yourself, you know what?
Speaker 0: I'll stay up till 3 30 in the morning and then I'll go play DDR when it's not crowded.
Speaker 0: So the thing is you find that the DDR machines are more crowded at 3 30 a.m Than they were at 11 p.m See even though magfest is four days the Thursday.
Speaker 1: It doesn't really get rolling yet, right?
Speaker 1: So think early Thursday isn't a day you could technically do stuff like.
Speaker 1: games aren't even set up yet.
Speaker 1: It's only good if you go straight into tabletop or just tabletop and then Sunday people get the hell out Right away in the morning.
Speaker 1: like you can still play games on that Sunday afternoon, but not really tearing shit down.
Speaker 1: You basically got to either leave When you add up all those hours.
Speaker 1: since it's 24/7 the Thursday night that Friday night the Saturday night that are in a hundred percent full-on mode It's actually longer than it would a four-day con would be if it was only, you know, if it shut down.
Speaker 1: No, no I think our real trouble is that we always leave as more total active hours Even though the early Thursday in late Sunday hours The convention is technically open.
Speaker 1: if you subtract those you still have more total active hours.
Speaker 0: If we had left later or earlier on Sunday every year, we'd always be better off We leave with but because if you stay later or until the next day Like you can just go into the arcade and it's pretty empty like late on Sunday before they shut it down.
Speaker 0: You can do a whole bunch of stuff But if you check out and you're trying to catch a train or a bus, you've got too much momentum.
Speaker 0: You can't actually like go and you get home way late And then you have to wake up the next day and go to work and if you leave super early You're leaving the con but that arcade still rocking and you feel kind of bad about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there isn't a good time to leave.
Speaker 1: magfest on Sunday.
Speaker 1: There's like this very short window I think like basically stay eat lunch and leave or stay leave and eat lunch at wherever you're going.
Speaker 1: Yep I don't know.
Speaker 0: So otherwise Subscribe to my youtube channel and Scott's YouTube channel.
Speaker 0: We're both doing a ton of stuff.
Speaker 1: I videoed Baking with Scott.
Speaker 1: It's probably gonna be a bad video, but I guess I have to edit it because otherwise Why did I video it?
Speaker 0: You know what you should get for that editing?
Speaker 0: What are these video editing knobs?
Speaker 1: I don't need the knob.
Speaker 0: Yeah What did you start editing?
Speaker 0: a lot of video.
Speaker 0: that knob is indispensable.
Speaker 1: I think I'll be fine with my mouse if you want that knob.
Speaker 0: if you if you decide I don't want knob I'll buy it for you with the patreon money.
Speaker 1: I don't need enough.
Speaker 0: It's free.
Speaker 1: Why don't you buy me some hockey tickets with the patreon money?
Speaker 0: I'm I buy.
Speaker 0: I'll pay you with regular money for the hockey ticket.
Speaker 0: I'm taking from here for Tuesday.
Speaker 1: Fine, but you know if you just gave me the money then we could just go to all the games free effectively.
Speaker 0: I'm not wasting our patreon money on things that don't turn into stuff for geek nights.
Speaker 1: I could talk.
Speaker 1: we could start doing episodes of geek nights on hockey.
Speaker 0: We kids do that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we could probably do a live stream podcast.
Speaker 1: You can make a hole.
Speaker 1: they could make a New York Rangers.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there are New York Rangers fan podcasts.
Speaker 1: We can make another one get season tickets.
Speaker 1: We've got every fucking home game and do a show on each one.
Speaker 0: Ah, that's actually not a terrible idea.
Speaker 0: You mean Emily too?
Speaker 0: Cuz Emily actually has gone way beyond me and hockey knowledge.
Speaker 0: She pays way more attention to players that I don't care about and then later on she's like, yeah, look how he developed.
Speaker 0: I'm like what we just traded for him.
Speaker 0: How did you know who he was?
Speaker 0: He played for like the Sabres.
Speaker 1: I just read Rangers read it.
Speaker 1: So I know yeah That's that's the that's the amount of knowledge.
Speaker 1: I'm willing to put into it.
Speaker 0: Yeah effort.
Speaker 0: So timepieces, I got watches.
Speaker 0: I used to wear.
Speaker 0: So not only did I wear a watch I wore a watch all the time.
Speaker 0: They're like elementary school all the way up through the end of middle school.
Speaker 0: I wore a watch like every single day no matter what I Replace them over time.
Speaker 0: I'd get fancier watches or less fancy watches always analog except one brief period right a digital watch.
Speaker 0: I realized that they all kind of suck.
Speaker 0: back then I went back to analog.
Speaker 1: so I learned how to tell time The same way that everyone on earth should learn how to tell time which is with the official Mickey Mouse watch Where one of the hands has a little circle on it.
Speaker 1: that goes, you know, and it's got the red wristband Yes, Mickey's arms going around.
Speaker 0: I learned with a Care Bears alarm clock that was so loud when the alarm went off that My parents had to disable the alarm to prevent damage.
Speaker 1: My alarm clocks are just boring digital ones with red numbers or whatever.
Speaker 1: But at one point my mom bought from the JC penny catalog the Super Mario alarm clock.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, I had the two bells on the top and our hands went around.
Speaker 1: so we go to the JC penny pickup counter to get it cuz that's how it was in the days before Amazon and It was just broken.
Speaker 1: like you we opened it and it didn't work.
Speaker 1: So he said hey, it doesn't work get another one.
Speaker 1: So we had to go home and then they called us and we're like, okay We got another one and we went back and that one was also just broken and it wasn't like a little bit broken.
Speaker 1: It was like it just didn't go like it wasn't like.
Speaker 1: oh, we forgot the batteries.
Speaker 1: It was like no like the hands aren't even on the thing and it's like it's like somebody just smashed it.
Speaker 1: Basically batteries batteries mine was actually a wind-up, but it's like yeah It just we couldn't get a working one.
Speaker 1: So he gave up.
Speaker 1: so I never had a mario alarm clock.
Speaker 0: So throughout most of my life up until the end of middle school Especially in middle school.
Speaker 0: I was actually kind of I was not obsessed But I always wanted to know exactly what time it was and I would use that knowledge for a very specific Effect throughout my life.
Speaker 0: Like I was extremely punctual and I mean, I've always been punctual, but it didn't need watches to do that No, but like I would try to be like I would literally try to show up like at a class the second the bell rang.
Speaker 0: No, I didn't like the exact second.
Speaker 1: I just I just be.
Speaker 1: you know, I just don't want to be late, right?
Speaker 1: As long I don't care if I'm early.
Speaker 1: thing is a lot of times in life.
Speaker 1: I'm too early.
Speaker 0: No usually be in high school.
Speaker 0: I shifted to that.
Speaker 0: I started showing up to things like an hour early.
Speaker 1: The reason I'm so early to a lot of things is because I finished doing one thing and the next thing is coming up.
Speaker 1: This happens a lot that something's after work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I get out of work at 5 and I have a thing.
Speaker 1: It's at 630.
Speaker 0: So what are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: sit in the Starbucks doing nothing?
Speaker 1: So it's like okay I go and I eat dinner and I you know I take my time with it and then I go to the place and what else we have to do and then I'm early.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the reason I'm super early to things.
Speaker 1: but I mean if I'm just going to something, you know I show up still slightly early because I don't want to be late ever.
Speaker 0: but there's a big difference between now and when I Was in middle school because now I have an infinite entertainment device in my pocket at all times.
Speaker 0: Middle school, I mean you had bupkis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had a gameboy But one I couldn't bring that to school like they wouldn't let you and even if I did the batteries don't last that long.
Speaker 1: A lot of Pokemon in high school.
Speaker 1: I don't know your problem was.
Speaker 0: well middle school.
Speaker 0: They wouldn't let us bring him.
Speaker 1: Pokemon didn't exist when I was in middle school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it was a different time You understand so I hope so.
Speaker 0: I wanted to maximize my fun time in life so I wanted to never be early or late to anything ever.
Speaker 0: and I there was a trick I would pull once per class per so I guess per quarter per year throughout all of middle school of
Speaker 1: Stand up
Speaker 0: and start walking toward the door while class is still going and just as the teachers like where are you the bell rings?
Speaker 0: Just as I walk out the door.
Speaker 0: That was like my move because it was like for middle school kids.
Speaker 0: That's like a mic drop and the only way I was able to do this was I I had always made try to watch with The second
Speaker 1: hand
Speaker 0: and what I would do is at the beginning every month when I came into class I would pause my watch at the exact time The bell was like the bell would ring officially and I would with the second hand on the 12 And I would start it right when the bell rang because the bells were digitally controlled in the school and were basically a hundred percent Consistent.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So my watch wasn't 100% tied to the school Which as I recall was three minutes ahead of real time.
Speaker 1: So you're talking about punctuality.
Speaker 1: You're not talking about the actual watches.
Speaker 0: Oh the watch.
Speaker 0: I had to have a second hander.
Speaker 0: that wouldn't have worked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean those are specifics of watches, right?
Speaker 0: So that's the only reason I wore the fucking watch.
Speaker 1: It was a big deal, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know if people people are old enough to remember this But like it was a big deal when Timex came into existence Yeah, like I don't know how it might have been an older company But like specifically the Iron Man watch was like this hot trend for like a long period in like I guess the 90s.
Speaker 1: It was like a big deal this Iron Man watch and there was just something about it Like it was super waterproof.
Speaker 1: And if you look at it today, it's kind of ugly.
Speaker 1: And of these two big buttons on the front.
Speaker 1: So it did like all these functions like stop while I had a built-in stopwatch Right and a built, you know built in all kinds of extra stuff.
Speaker 1: Mostly it was just the stopwatch was built in to also your wristwatch, which I remember this is It wasn't really a common thing before then right you had like expensive Casio calculator watch and that was about it.
Speaker 1: Yep Indigo technology the indigo was also a big deal.
Speaker 1: I think it was the first watch or the backlight right like you could.
Speaker 1: it was it, you know Even though it was a LCD screen.
Speaker 1: It wasn't the black with the red numbers It was the white with the black and you could even though usually you couldn't see those in the dark.
Speaker 1: But here you finally have a blacklight on it Which didn't exist until then as far as I know now part of that I had one of those indigo Iron Man watches.
Speaker 1: I think I had two or three of them and I just kept losing them because it's Uncomfortable to wear a watch.
Speaker 1: it is annoying for at least for me Yeah, but no matter how fancy a nice watch band or how well sized it is or anything like that It's even even this pebble watch or haven't lost.
Speaker 1: It's still uncomfortable to wear it.
Speaker 1: It's worth dealing with that slight very slight discomfort to not have to take my phone out of my pocket.
Speaker 0: So in those days before cell phones if you wanted to be not late to things You pretty much had to wear a watch because there was no other way to know what time it was.
Speaker 0: in most places Like in the mall, there's a clock somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's like one clock in the mall somewhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like every classroom had one clock on the wall.
Speaker 1: Also at the clock store they had them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were.
Speaker 0: they were wrong though They'd always just be like pointed up left and up right maybe almost always.
Speaker 0: They're never actually running on time.
Speaker 0: in the clock store.
Speaker 0: I mean before cell phones you had to have a watch to know what time it was and knowing what time it was was real important because if Like you didn't show up on time Your friends couldn't call you.
Speaker 0: it's not like there was any way to find out what happened to you until the next day like everything Was fucked so precise timekeeping everyone had to have a watch like.
Speaker 0: I remember specifically a couple times we were like at senior point and Like with a bunch of friends and I'd be like, yeah, so let's all ride rides or whatever.
Speaker 0: We'll split up and let's meet at 1130 and get lunch.
Speaker 0: And then we noticed that one of our friends didn't have a watch and we were like if you don't show up We're not fucking waiting for you.
Speaker 0: And of course, they didn't show up.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Didn't know that it was 1130.
Speaker 0: I mean, what do you?
Speaker 0: how would you know?
Speaker 0: The clocks are not that common in society anymore?
Speaker 1: I mean, well cuz you know watches, you know historically speaking right going back to like sundials You couldn't even move them and then they were like clockwork which you couldn't move those either.
Speaker 1: But they were big and central.
Speaker 1: see wherever you were in town You could look up and hopefully see one.
Speaker 1: but it's like what a water clock It's like, you know fancy, you know watches were like pocket watches like a luxurious expensive item for much of history and to some extent still carry that legacy of you know being a special expensive thing like not everyone like Watches weren't democratized or everyone could get them until you know why like the middle of the 20th century, maybe
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not gonna posit a date cuz I'm not really sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean in digital watches definitely didn't exist then right?
Speaker 0: It's like Yeah, so in high school I Sort of shifted cuz one.
Speaker 0: my watches would get beaten the shit out of because I wore them all the time no matter what and they'd like bang into stuff and get scratched.
Speaker 0: I keep replacing them and I also decided in high school suddenly like in the middle of ninth grade I didn't actually want to know what time it was all the time Cuz.
Speaker 0: I didn't want to have that like moment that I remember I'd be sitting in class.
Speaker 0: I'm bored I just want to leave and I look down and I know that there's three minutes and 28 seconds before this class ends and that's That clock just starts going slower and slower and slower.
Speaker 1: You know a clock is the same as a pot of water, right?
Speaker 1: You know you look at it the slower it boils.
Speaker 0: So I started wearing pocket watches in high school because I still needed to know what time it was Because you still you know, we're nerdy but you still had not evicted all of your trilby wearing This.
Speaker 0: actually it wasn't.
Speaker 0: so I didn't wear my pocket watch out.
Speaker 0: It was actually I ended up.
Speaker 0: I had a chain pocket watch I'd wear with like suits, which I still have and I still wear those but only with suits.
Speaker 0: But I didn't wear a chain pocket watch on my jeans.
Speaker 0: I just got a watch.
Speaker 1: I just want to remind people that the rim that I met Yeah, the first time in my life was a person who is a wearing a cowboy wearing a silly hat.
Speaker 1: How boy boots a trench duster?
Speaker 0: a trench coat was a duster.
Speaker 1: He basically looked like grit from advanced war.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had a silly mustache full-on Brigadier General mustache right out of World War one.
Speaker 0: Alright, that is the the person who my school picture was me holding a sword, right?
Speaker 1: If you saw this person today a base as gamer game in all over him.
Speaker 0: I said no, there's a big difference.
Speaker 0: I was not fat sure Nor was I greasy.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's also a fat greasy guy out there who's saying I did not wear the trilby.
Speaker 0: But here's the thing with the pocket watch.
Speaker 0: what I did.
Speaker 0: because even in middle school like in high school I was like, well really I don't really pocket watch chain with jeans.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I got a pocket watch key fob.
Speaker 0: Then I could.
Speaker 0: so it was on my keys to my car.
Speaker 0: cuz I had a car.
Speaker 0: cuz Driver's license is 16.
Speaker 0: So that was my pocket watch.
Speaker 0: so I can always know what time it was.
Speaker 0: Cuz I had a watch on me But I didn't.
Speaker 0: I had to actively do a thing to like pull it out of my pocket open it up to look at it To see that time.
Speaker 0: so I didn't have the watch Constantly reminding me how slow my life was moving.
Speaker 0: Cuz back then again no smartphone.
Speaker 0: So I'd get bored like it's.
Speaker 0: it's kind of funny that there was a time in my life When boredom was a possibility.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you like gotta go to the doctor with your parents and the Gameboy batteries run out What are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: You're gonna flip through Reader's Digest, but that's horrible.
Speaker 0: Then you're gonna sit there.
Speaker 1: All the Dodgers and dentists I went to when I was a kid were like, you know pediatric dentists and pediatric doctors.
Speaker 0: Oh, so they had that.
Speaker 0: what's that kid magazine?
Speaker 1: No highlights.
Speaker 1: Yeah I had a description of highlights, but I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: even when I was older like middle school In the waiting rooms were like fucking Genesis things that had like five games in them.
Speaker 1: Whoa You know at the orthodontist you would grant there was a stack of Gameboys and you would grab one.
Speaker 1: you when you went to go Sit down and you just play Metroid 2 while they worked on your teeth, man I didn't have any of that.
Speaker 1: it cost more money to do Rich but I mean everyone in town went to it.
Speaker 1: But it was.
Speaker 1: you know, it was still a mostly white suburb less white than yours, but still mostly no.
Speaker 0: But I guess that was the choice I made with timepieces of.
Speaker 0: I needed to be able to look at the time But I didn't want to have to look at the time.
Speaker 0: and with a watch if you wear a watch You're gonna keep looking at it whether you want to or not.
Speaker 0: It's just gonna happen Mmm, so that was why I used a pocket watch for a long time.
Speaker 1: So the thing with watches is like for a long period of time like I lost those time X's, right?
Speaker 1: I just gave up on watches and I didn't care anymore.
Speaker 1: and then I got phones and I'm like, oh just look at the phone I don't need I don't need a watch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was anti watch for that for this long day.
Speaker 0: I got a cell phone.
Speaker 0: I literally threw away the only watch I still owned other than my pocket watches that I only wear with suits.
Speaker 1: I was so like.
Speaker 1: I still respected like watchmaking and clockmaking as a as a nerdy and valuable thing.
Speaker 1: Right, you know.
Speaker 1: but in terms of like, you know This is like a watch culture of like people collecting watches and people like I have a really expensive watch.
Speaker 1: Look how awesome I am gold.
Speaker 0: why I was at a.
Speaker 1: look at my Rolex.
Speaker 1: Look at my Tag Heuer watch, you know Status.
Speaker 0: I was at a an event.
Speaker 0: This is like three years ago enormous watch.
Speaker 0: that's like weighing my arm down with a bunch of rich British people and like business people.
Speaker 0: and I watched two old two older white guys and a younger white guy and the younger white guy
Speaker 1: No watch measuring content was
Speaker 0: talking some shit like like sort of poking fun at the older white guys because their company wasn't doing so well and
Speaker 1: Basically,
Speaker 0: yeah, like they're talking to each other and having this like kind of
Speaker 1: Company's not doing so
Speaker 0: well, is it?
Speaker 0: that's kind of the conversation.
Speaker 0: they were happy Wow what asshole.
Speaker 0: and then the one white dude who is being had the shade being thrown at him who was who'd kind of Instigated it because he had started by saying like hey, we were thinking about buying you guys
Speaker 1: Mmm,
Speaker 0: so dude literally like pulls up his hand looks his watch and says this watch cost $80,000.
Speaker 0: Said those words All right.
Speaker 0: And then the other guy pulls up his watch and he and he's like this is a and he said like some name of a designer And they literally had a watch measuring contest and I was laughing.
Speaker 1: I literally he's basically one guy was like, you know, my company goes out of business.
Speaker 1: I'm still rich I don't give a fuck and the other guys like I'm even richer.
Speaker 0: So I've got to the point now where I appreciate The craft of making watches but anyone I ever meet who is wearing a non smart watch That is not a cheap watch.
Speaker 0: I Kind it's like a reverse status symbol.
Speaker 0: Like when I see it, I kind of assume by default that they're kind of a douchey upper-middle-class Richie person, right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: it's so weird.
Speaker 1: It's like just like watch means douche.
Speaker 1: Watches went from being right.
Speaker 1: this thing that only certain people could have To a thing that's like a practical thing.
Speaker 1: everyone can tell time like the Iron Man watch times, right?
Speaker 1: But still it was always a status symbol even then Rolex Rolex, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but now It's like to the point where there's so many watches like you're.
Speaker 1: you're if you have a watch Like.
Speaker 1: it says so much about you Right, which watch you have?
Speaker 1: You know to the point at which like there's specific like there's so many models of watch and somehow they keep making all of them There's a watch.
Speaker 1: I read this really fascinating story this particular Casio watch that terrorists used to make bombs.
Speaker 0: I know the exact article you're talking about.
Speaker 1: you can just buy this watch for like 10 bucks on Amazon.
Speaker 1: It's like you can have it but it's like, you know They will look it like if you have the watch you could be Suspected of being a terrorist because those are the people have that watch.
Speaker 1: but like there's a picture of Obama wearing this one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: and it's like kind of want to buy that watch now Even though it's just a boring old Casio digital watch that tells time and doesn't do anything else.
Speaker 0: Well, then you're buying a piece of jewelry.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: It's not even yeah, but it's still jewelry.
Speaker 0: jewelry is just an outward expression of your inner proteins But it's like.
Speaker 1: I looked at it and it's like I don't need that.
Speaker 1: I have a smart watch.
Speaker 1: What's?
Speaker 1: why even why even waste the $10 to get one?
Speaker 1: just you know, just because it's kind of cool.
Speaker 1: and then it's like.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's also like the Casio calculator watch.
Speaker 1: It's like that's so nerdy.
Speaker 1: That's like the nerd status symbols Like you could just get one of those right?
Speaker 1: No problem.
Speaker 1: But like I don't need that either.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: The real status symbol was in fifth grade the kid who had the watch that had Legend of Zelda on it.
Speaker 1: I could play legend.
Speaker 1: really really really really really crappy Legend of Zelda like.
Speaker 0: These were like the bad versions of tiger LCD games.
Speaker 1: It was a tiger LCD game that was so small it would go on your wrist and like I'd Like we would like at recess like he would.
Speaker 1: you know, I want to see.
Speaker 0: I want to see a GDQ speed runs of tiger LCD games.
Speaker 1: I think he's done.
Speaker 1: Oh a GDQ.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I thought you met.
Speaker 0: You did those kind of done with a VGN.
Speaker 1: Yeah me too guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but a GDQ.
Speaker 1: Yes speed run those.
Speaker 1: I don't think I'm gonna be and they're generally high score deals.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we got a look at the room.
Speaker 0: There's got to be one.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, there's.
Speaker 1: you can beat the Aladdin one.
Speaker 1: We had that's beatable.
Speaker 0: There's got to be one.
Speaker 0: the whole interesting.
Speaker 1: they could do it during awful games done quick Maybe but yeah, you can beat some of them for sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty much.
Speaker 1: Just do the same thing over and over again till it's over man.
Speaker 0: I remember that was a status symbol.
Speaker 1: as a sonic one You can beat dad like bosses those watches and also the tiger else.
Speaker 0: these in general were status symbols among the dumb kids and Everyone else like had an NES at home and knew better.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, I mean we had NES at home, but how you couldn't have any us at school?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we didn't play Zelda at his desk.
Speaker 0: I wasn't stupid.
Speaker 0: I saw those things like wow, that's not.
Speaker 0: I'd rather play those little plastic things.
Speaker 0: We have the steel ball bearings.
Speaker 0: You shoot them around.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sure.
Speaker 1: Well, you're at school.
Speaker 1: So I'll take it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, that's why I have my watch.
Speaker 0: so I could show up to class Exactly when the bell rang to not waste even a second of my life.
Speaker 0: So in high school when I started here in the pocket watch what I started doing Unrelatedly is cuz you know, I don't want to be late to things.
Speaker 0: I started showing up to stuff like an hour early and like I just go into the place and just fall asleep And then people would kind of wake me up naturally when they showed up to do the thing.
Speaker 0: So I sort of got this reputation like in high school.
Speaker 0: like that we'd have a band trip or like a tournament or something and People would show up at the school like up like ten minutes for the things gonna start like get this shit together And they'd reliably find me like in the back room asleep on top of a bunch of drawers.
Speaker 1: Didn't you just leave where you were before An hour later and show up on time
Speaker 0: because it was always between the other thing I was doing just like we have now in New York Like it wasn't enough time to go home and play
Speaker 1: it wasn't like you were at home.
Speaker 0: No, it was like I'm out doing something.
Speaker 0: that thing ends.
Speaker 0: There's two hours before the thing at the school starts it.
Speaker 0: What am I gonna do for an hour at home?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That's not enough time to play any video.
Speaker 1: That's a general problem in life.
Speaker 1: Not a watch specific problem Yeah, so so actual why you know, not just watches.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about like the you know clocks.
Speaker 0: my favorite wall clock we ever had was that momo wall clock that we bought.
Speaker 0: it broke.
Speaker 1: Yeah finally You could replace that.
Speaker 1: the thing is with that is I went online and I looked at Amazon and I could get Replacement clock mechanisms for like a dollar right a ton.
Speaker 1: They need a sack of them, right?
Speaker 1: They're so cheap and it would have fit.
Speaker 1: the problem is the the mechanism has a stick coming out that spins Right and the more hands you have on the watch the clock you need a longer stick and the longer The hands on the clock are.
Speaker 1: you need a longer stick.
Speaker 1: that cuz it's harder to turn.
Speaker 1: a long thing, right?
Speaker 1: It's a lever right?
Speaker 1: You know, you need a stronger clock mechanism to turn bigger hands.
Speaker 1: I Could not find a clock medicine mechanism that had the us, you know an axle that matched the one that was in the clock.
Speaker 1: I found the same mechanism, but I couldn't find the same axle so I couldn't replace the mechanism.
Speaker 0: So I just bought a different clock Yeah from the Muji store I used to be a big fan of like those weird artistic like.
Speaker 0: it is technically a wall clock and shows time But also is a cool mechanism of some kind.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see those things like.
Speaker 1: it's cool to look at them like binary clocks and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: But if I can't glance at it and know what time it is in a fraction of a second It's not a good clock.
Speaker 1: So fuck it.
Speaker 1: I'm not actually gonna buy it or put it in my apartment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and once it once my last cool wall clock died I just haven't ever replaced a wall clock my alarm clock.
Speaker 1: Do you want to try?
Speaker 1: you want the momma clog?
Speaker 1: You can go for it.
Speaker 0: I was thinking about giving it Emily's dad.
Speaker 0: He might fix it.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's so easy to fix if you could just find the exact same mechanism.
Speaker 1: But you could just swap it like it even pops out like you don't even need to glue or screw or anything.
Speaker 0: It's so simple, but so my alarm clock in the bedroom, which I don't even use anymore because smartphones replaced alarm clocks, too.
Speaker 0: I Have the same one I had since fifth grade.
Speaker 0: Wow, it's white.
Speaker 0: It's got red LCD in it and that's it.
Speaker 1: It's just I had a clear one with a red LCD in it, and I don't know if it broke or not.
Speaker 1: I think I replaced it with a generic Radio Shack one at some point.
Speaker 1: I think I used that in college.
Speaker 0: So I have a crazy story about then.
Speaker 1: nowadays what I would happen is I don't think that one ever broke but there was a The like a kit where you could you know solder together your own clock with this cool tube the ice tube.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I don't think they make that kit anymore, but I'd made that kit and because I made it myself it's a little flaky it's at the time it tells a little slow and Sometimes it fritzes out if you push the buttons on it too fast.
Speaker 1: that but it still works and tells time.
Speaker 1: it looks really cool.
Speaker 1: So that's what I have next to my bed even though I hardly I. basically it's like why have it there?
Speaker 1: because I've got my iPad and my iPhone and my All right there, and I use the alarm in my iPad.
Speaker 1: I don't use the alarm the only time I ever.
Speaker 1: the reason it's right there is because I can Open my eyes and see the time and close my eyes that having to like reach and shake something or anything like that.
Speaker 0: So I use mine whenever there is a you have to wake up situation as opposed to day-to-day.
Speaker 1: if I have to wake up I'll just set the alarm on my iPhone and my iPad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'll do.
Speaker 0: I'll do phone and That thing also.
Speaker 0: I will use that thing for like 20 years.
Speaker 0: It's invincible.
Speaker 1: I'll also stop using if I really need to wake up.
Speaker 1: I'll change my alarm.
Speaker 1: noise to caramel dancing.
Speaker 0: That's the key to this day.
Speaker 0: the sound that that white alarm clock makes the deep deep deep haunts my dreams.
Speaker 0: That's all.
Speaker 0: that sound never means good things.
Speaker 0: It means get up.
Speaker 0: It's 4/30 time to get up for eighth grade.
Speaker 1: Why did you get up at 4/30?
Speaker 0: because I had to leave because I had to be at the school at 6 Because that's when jazz band was cuz.
Speaker 0: jazz band started before school.
Speaker 1: Oh It took you an hour and a half to get this.
Speaker 0: So I actually I had.
Speaker 0: so I had to leave the house at 540 in the morning.
Speaker 1: But you don't to wake up a fourth or you can wake up.
Speaker 0: it like takes me in my life.
Speaker 0: It takes me about an hour to get going in the morning.
Speaker 0: when I wake up I tie it's an hour between when the alarm goes off and when I'm out the door.
Speaker 1: I would get up in like 15 minutes and put my clothes on and go.
Speaker 1: I got long.
Speaker 0: I got a hairy and a mess with even now anyway, but uh In terms of other timepieces the part the only problem because I don't have any wall clocks anywhere It'll probably never have one again.
Speaker 0: I like bare walls actually or very simple accent.
Speaker 1: I need to have a wall clock.
Speaker 1: I need to basically be able to look and see what time it is.
Speaker 1: And if I'm like, even if I'm using my HD PC, the time is in the corner.
Speaker 1: It's so small You can't see that from the cat a widget on your desktop.
Speaker 1: No, I just look to the right boop.
Speaker 1: There it is.
Speaker 0: So from the from the the couch in the living room I can see the microwaves clock the ovens clock, which is separate.
Speaker 1: My oven my apartment is in such a way that the ovens clock is like Yeah blocked by this little tiny half wall bit.
Speaker 0: that tiny wall is there I can picture in my head.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can see if I'm in the kitchen.
Speaker 0: I use that right though Most people who come over can't see it from there because they can't see.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell I don't think to look There.
Speaker 0: yeah, I think the look there but I live here so I'm gonna used to that.
Speaker 0: and there's also a clock on the rice cooker and I think that's all the clocks other than also every computer monitor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I get two monitors here It's on the bottom right of both monitors.
Speaker 0: so I just see clocks all the time.
Speaker 1: the kind of clock that people don't think about these days because they used to be the Most important and are now or not as important are the public clocks, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you used to like used to be back in the day.
Speaker 1: Like you think about your car has a clock in it right in the dashboard.
Speaker 1: That didn't used to have most cars we had.
Speaker 1: I think one of them had an analog clock in it.
Speaker 1: Most cars we had didn't have a clock.
Speaker 0: until you know much later every car I owned at a clock in it.
Speaker 0: every car I can remember had a clock in it.
Speaker 1: Not every good.
Speaker 1: I've had car a lot of cars.
Speaker 0: in the early part The great station wagon with the eight-track player might not have had a clock.
Speaker 1: I can't picture it in my head But that's why when you drove down the road all the banks had the time and temperature on their sign Because the bank had enough money to do that.
Speaker 1: Whereas, you know other places didn't.
Speaker 0: what I'm amazed by This happened to me actually two days ago.
Speaker 1: That's why you go to the train station this big amazing clocks there because it used to be back in the day.
Speaker 1: you'd go to the train station and That was the only clock anyone had there except maybe the train conductors had like pocket watches and that was it.
Speaker 0: So I've run into this a lot lately.
Speaker 0: Like I've noticed it but Strangers on the street asking me or other people what time it is.
Speaker 0: I've noticed that with increasing frequency over the last few years.
Speaker 1: There was a scam that I read about I don't know if it was true could miss one of those urban legends.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that somebody would ask you what time it was to get you to take out your phone and then grab your phone and run.
Speaker 1: That's a really good scam Right because it's like you might be walking down the road and you don't have your phone out so they can't snatch it.
Speaker 1: So they go.
Speaker 1: hey, man, you know, what time is it?
Speaker 1: So not only you're Standing still now, right?
Speaker 1: You're not walking.
Speaker 1: you're walking with your phone and they cut.
Speaker 1: they try to follow you.
Speaker 1: It's like some more obvious, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you're stopped.
Speaker 1: you take your phone out and you're looking at the phone and not at them And they grab the phone and run and you have to.
Speaker 1: you have.
Speaker 1: they already ran it They're already running.
Speaker 1: you, you know, they got a head start on you.
Speaker 1: What I saw survey, I don't know if that's ever actually happened.
Speaker 0: I saw a video a while ago.
Speaker 0: I just remembered very clearly.
Speaker 0: It's a short video.
Speaker 0: It looks like it's from a surveillance camera and it's in like.
Speaker 0: it's like I might be in Japan I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Speaker 0: but basically you see like a really crowded train station all these people walking around and then one person just walks up to another person who's looking at their phone and taps him on the shoulder and they turn around and he Reaches out and like gingerly while making eye candidate takes his phone out of his hand like takes the stranger's phone out of his hand and then just turns around and walks off into the crowd.
Speaker 0: and then the guys like Wait, what?
Speaker 0: I think he tries to react but the guys lost in the crowd and it's over.
Speaker 0: He's got his phone and I feel like that would work.
Speaker 1: Take pockets have skills and the thing is, you know, if you see that you see like pickpockets like do magic.
Speaker 1: You know, they do it for like entertainment purposes.
Speaker 1: It's like if they wanted to they could just totally loot everybody.
Speaker 0: Maybe they do.
Speaker 0: 20s are missing from every other wallet there.
Speaker 1: I mean You know some people have enough money.
Speaker 1: like if you if you like I have a bunch of ones in my bag.
Speaker 1: If you took some I wouldn't.
Speaker 1: I don't how many are in there.
Speaker 0: Right, I guess depends how much money you have to the more money you have the less you notice small amounts of money.
Speaker 1: What happens to me is like when I go and get money?
Speaker 1: I know how much I have and then like I'll buy something like I'll buy say something that's like five bucks with my 20 And I'll buy something else is five bucks of the 20 but the change increasingly unreliably gets.
Speaker 1: I don't match money.
Speaker 1: I have any more.
Speaker 1: So if you stole five dollars from me I wouldn't notice because I didn't know how much.
Speaker 1: I was not constantly counting how much there is At all times.
Speaker 0: but it is just weird that I've noticed a lot of people asking me what time it is on the street in The subway and this people have these people holding smartphones asking for directions.
Speaker 0: that happened to me yesterday.
Speaker 0: Literally dude outside of Queensborough Plaza is walking looking at a smartphone and he's like, hey, can anyone tell me where?
Speaker 0: Saying some like Institute or something, but he's looking at he's holding his smartphone and looking at it.
Speaker 0: How How do these people I guess that's what the where the undecided voters are.
Speaker 0: So, uh, the only other the only change in timepieces is that I started wearing watches again because of smart watches.
Speaker 0: And the only reason is I didn't actually care about the time thing.
Speaker 0: I cared about all the other features of smartphones.
Speaker 0: But since the screens on all the time anyway, and it might as well show me the time might as well.
Speaker 0: but it's funny how I really think of my smartwatch as Primarily notifications and the time on it is just this like minor side effect.
Speaker 0: It's like the fact that there's a clock in the bottom right of my monitor.
Speaker 1: I actually look at the thing I look at the most is the date.
Speaker 1: Yep And also that I have the temperature on mine.
Speaker 1: So I look at it before like I go outside.
Speaker 0: Yep That's pretty much how I use mine.
Speaker 1: I use the time on it a lot less because I get my time from other places.
Speaker 1: But the up thing I'll be sitting on the couch and wearing a watch and I look at the the analog clock on the wall.
Speaker 0: so the only significant change to the timekeeping timepiece aspect of my smartwatch is that Because it is basically just another screen for my smartphone It always shows the right time even when I land after a long flight into a different time zone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean back in the day, you know They had a time of clocks But even people didn't have access to them and you could buy ones that like synchronize with radio.
Speaker 1: You still can dude, you know, those are expensive and not worth it.
Speaker 0: When was the last time?
Speaker 0: in a modern action movie peep a bunch of characters synchronize their clocks for the heist, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know Used to be like clock.
Speaker 1: every everyone's watch was off whether it was digital or analog.
Speaker 1: It was off by a little bit It was slow or fast and every once in a while Like you'd have to adjust it by like a minute or two.
Speaker 1: how anal you were I'm
Speaker 0: not even joking whenever we went to Cedar Point or an amusement park But if you see your point was the way we went to we would literally all might mean all my friends would get off the bus When we got to the park and then we'd all stand in a circle and synchronize our watches before we dispersed Like that was a real
Speaker 1: thing.
Speaker 1: Like you could think you're on time and actually be five minutes late because your watch is five minutes different than someone else's watch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you kids will never experience this.
Speaker 0: No You will never Literally get a group of friends in a circle and synchronize your watches before never show up somewhere and people be like why are you?
Speaker 1: Ten minutes late?
Speaker 1: and this is like this happened to me in my life back in the day.
Speaker 1: Like yeah, why are you ten minutes late?
Speaker 1: I'm on time.
Speaker 1: What are you talking about?
Speaker 1: And they look at their watch and it's just we don't know who's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you need some other like, you know, you didn't.
Speaker 1: you couldn't go to time gov and settle it.
Speaker 1: Yeah In fact, I remember on occasion.
Speaker 1: You'd have to like you'd we call that phone number.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you pick up the phone and you would actually dial this number and they would say the time is.
Speaker 1: you can still do this Today, I don't know what the number is.
Speaker 0: Occasionally what we did in our house is someone's chore like once a month We took turns just like every household chore was called was take your watch out call that number Make sure your watch is perfect and then check all the clocks in the house And make them all match because they didn't match at
Speaker 1: all daylight savings.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: No, cuz daily saving is easy.
Speaker 0: You don't need to call.
Speaker 1: No, but that's a good time because you're a member to do it.
Speaker 0: then there's a good time.
Speaker 0: Also daylight saving you could fuck it up back then like you could forget.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you just wake up your no clock would update itself.
Speaker 0: You would wake up and just show up to school an hour late or you're standing at the bus stop and you're like Where is everybody if you listen to the radio?
Speaker 1: That's you know, the radio would be like.
Speaker 1: the time is yup such and such.
Speaker 0: More than once in my life Me or someone I knew Was late miss the bus to school because they didn't do daylight saving time.
Speaker 0: Hmm, I think we've exhausted timepieces.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know I'm sure if you want to know more about like watches and clocks you could find some watch nerds.
Speaker 0: if you want depth on a Topic watch this watch nose.
Speaker 1: Yeah watch nerdery.
Speaker 1: That is not the variety.
Speaker 1: That's like collecting and caring about watches being expensive But the kind.
Speaker 1: that's like caring about how well watches are made or like, you know The art and craft of making awesome timepieces.
Speaker 0: find a YouTube channel By the kind of per.
Speaker 1: really I really respect that nerdery a lot But it's not for me.
Speaker 0: find a YouTube channel by the kind of person that dr.
Speaker 0: Manhattan was before he became a superhero.
Speaker 0: exactly This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night
Speaker 0: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brenna Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette Christian coons construction noises Ivy Faye my stady comm William Isen rose Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Shervin on Horrell Iggy kid rural of L James David White Michelle, Montañana Superboy Irish Wristwatch Aaron Cerise Brian Fisher sailor Vista Jai fried pork Matthew Smith Don Schleich chartavish and Joshiro Joe star Tyler Eller Shawn Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Renford, New Zealand Ryan Perrin booze scared you Lander Brian Cidroni Finn Eric Silver on the rural juror Chris mint give Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Starting to pick our production back up two episodes this week We're gonna keep pressing strong.
Speaker 0: the Q&A is will resume in earnest now that we're fully back and everything's coming along as I said before and Stay tuned for some extra Special patreon content.
Speaker 0: Emily and I have watched a bunch of movies.
Speaker 0: We're gonna do a rimbly review of Australia as a continent and a bunch of stuff is gonna be coming in the very near future.
Speaker 0: And now I leave you with something predictably terrifying.
Speaker 1: Oh Oh Now all we need is a little dance music.
Speaker 0: I got my non-stop bebop.