Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, November 8th, 2016, I'm Rym, I'm Scott, and this is Geek Nights Tonight, Uwe Rosenberg's Patchwork.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So it's election day, which means that my Twitter is going to go back to mostly normal most likely, and you guys can unmute me probably.
Speaker 0: Hooray!
Speaker 0: But, I would say, God, Jesus Christ, vote, but there's no way you're going to listen to this and still have the opportunity to vote because it's going to be over.
Speaker 0: In fact, during the course of the show, it's likely we'll find out how the election went.
Speaker 1: Hopefully, people listening to this don't live in the United States.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but basically- I know a lot of them don't.
Speaker 0: If you're nervous about the U.S.
Speaker 0: election- I'm not.
Speaker 0: The one thing I can tell you out there is that you probably don't have to stay up all night because Trump, there's a bunch of states that he has to win or it's over.
Speaker 0: Clinton, basically, is the default winner unless Trump wins all of those states.
Speaker 0: One of those is Florida, and Florida's polls close in like 20 minutes as of when we're doing the show right now.
Speaker 1: It takes a while to count, though.
Speaker 0: But they already counted six million of them because six million people did early voting.
Speaker 0: That's more people than voted in total in the 2000 election.
Speaker 0: Turnout is high, which means- Turnout is way- I had to wait.
Speaker 1: Turnout high means very bad if you're a backwards Neanderthal.
Speaker 0: If your party is the party of white supremacy- Most people aren't.
Speaker 0: And seriously, I've never had to wait in line to vote in all the years I've lived in New York City.
Speaker 1: I've never had to wait and vote for my entire life, and that includes today.
Speaker 1: I went to the polling place I've been to for eight years.
Speaker 1: It's the eighth time I've been there, this public school, and I go- You don't vote in the primaries?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: You really should.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: You could've voted for Zephyr Teachout.
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: I couldn't have because I'm not registered to vote.
Speaker 0: You're not a Democrat?
Speaker 0: If you live in New York and you're not a Democrat, that's just dumb.
Speaker 1: I'm a nothing.
Speaker 0: You should be a Democrat.
Speaker 1: It's not worth it.
Speaker 0: It's worth it because voting in the primaries is all that matters for the local stuff.
Speaker 1: I go to the school to vote, and there's a little line at the door to get into the elementary school gymnasium.
Speaker 1: It's always fun to go in the elementary school gymnasium because when I was in school- They felt so big, right?
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: When I was in school, in elementary school, our elementary school used to be the middle school.
Speaker 1: The gym was enormous, especially if you're an elementary school kid, right?
Speaker 1: And then the middle school I went to used to be the high school, so I always had a real full-size gymnasium.
Speaker 1: I was never in a elementary school gymnasium in a building that was made to be an elementary school until I voted at this place.
Speaker 1: It's like P.S.
Speaker 1: something.
Speaker 1: It's an elementary school gym.
Speaker 1: It's a gym with a basketball court, and it's not small.
Speaker 1: It's not really tiny, but it's like, "Man, I could just dunk in there," and I'm 5'11" and I cannot jump.
Speaker 0: We're also in a school.
Speaker 0: We're like the newcomer's high school over here.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's where you're going.
Speaker 1: That's big, though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it's big.
Speaker 1: That's real big.
Speaker 0: The voting always happens in an auditorium that has all these old chairs in it, like these antique-looking chairs.
Speaker 1: All the chairs were full.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot of room in that auditorium for people unless they're sitting in chairs.
Speaker 1: They don't use the gym or whatever?
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: So, I think it's because this room has a lot of direct-to-the-outside access.
Speaker 1: Are you voting on the stage or something?
Speaker 0: Just about.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: So, Emily and I show up way early in the morning, and there is a crazy line of people inside.
Speaker 0: Two districts vote in that place, and there's two crazy lines that are overflowing and filling up the seats, and apparently because of Fire Code, they can't have people standing behind the seats.
Speaker 0: So, people had to sit.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you, having been a PACS enforcer, having done convention, like back-end stuff for a long time, I have a pretty good idea of how lines work in general, but one thing that you have to realize is that when you work at even a shittily-run convention, you're dealing with people who at least understand the concept of a line.
Speaker 0: When you're dealing with the general public, all bets are off, and they did not have enough polling workers.
Speaker 0: They basically had one person.
Speaker 1: You could have been a polling worker.
Speaker 0: I had to go to work.
Speaker 0: There is one person whose job was to manage both of these lines, and they couldn't have people standing, so Emily actually was explaining to her how to do the pod bays, because it was going crazy.
Speaker 0: People were yelling at each other.
Speaker 0: There was bad feelings and a bad situation brewing in there.
Speaker 0: It was early.
Speaker 1: People were yelling at each other because of line waiting?
Speaker 0: It was mostly old men claiming that people cut in front of them, or she'd come and yell at everyone to sit down but wouldn't explain where or how to sit down or how to get back in the line, so it just turned into this giant mob.
Speaker 0: Emily started explaining to the poll worker how to do the pod bay doors.
Speaker 1: That's not helping.
Speaker 0: Actually, it did.
Speaker 0: She did the pod bay doors, and it started working okay.
Speaker 0: The only problem was she needed more people.
Speaker 0: It looks like they eventually called the cops, and then a whole bunch of cops came and started managing the line inside.
Speaker 0: We were there a long goddamn time.
Speaker 0: I was way late to work.
Speaker 1: I showed up, and for the first ... I've never had a line at this place ever in my life.
Speaker 1: I've always walked into a mostly empty room with a few old people, signed my signature in a book next to an older signature of mine, and then filled out a bubble sheet and shoved it in a machine and went to work.
Speaker 0: Oh shit, a bunch of people were shot at a voting place.
Speaker 0: That's what people are talking about.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: In ... Okay.
Speaker 1: Some crazy place.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: In Azusa.
Speaker 1: I don't know where the fuck that is.
Speaker 1: Alaska?
Speaker 0: LA Times.
Speaker 0: This doesn't tell me where.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I go in there, and there's a little tiny line to actually get in the gym, and I'm like, "Oh, all
Speaker 1: right.".
Speaker 1: I'm expecting when I turn the little corner and go in the gym that it's going to be that old big empty room that I've been in seven times before.
Speaker 1: I turn the corner, look in the gym, and there's a whole bunch of people in a bunch of lines, and I'm like, "What's going on?
Speaker 1: I've never seen this many people in this voting here in my whole
Speaker 1: life.".
Speaker 1: I go and I look for my district, because it's like a table for each district.
Speaker 1: You have to sign your name in the book, and then they give you your ballot to go fill out, and I go, and there's a big long line for the first table, and a big long line for the second table, and a big long line for the third table, like all the way across the other side of the gym.
Speaker 0: But the fourth one was just fine.
Speaker 1: The fourth table, Scott's table, like three people.
Speaker 1: We go sign, sign, sign, ballot, ballot, ballot, shoved it in the machine, went to work.
Speaker 1: No problem.
Speaker 1: So the moral of the story is be me.
Speaker 1: My computers always work.
Speaker 1: I don't have to wait in line for voting.
Speaker 0: No, you don't.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: You live in a district where either nobody votes or nobody wakes up in the morning.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, just be me.
Speaker 1: My advice is still correct.
Speaker 0: As best as I can tell what's going on, there's a heavily armed dude who shot a bunch of people near a polling place and is still on the loose, so that might mess up some election results in wherever this is.
Speaker 1: Do the people vote already?
Speaker 0: No, voting's still open.
Speaker 1: I mean, do the people he shot vote already?
Speaker 0: It's not clear.
Speaker 0: This is literally like just happened.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you what, even though I live in New York and my vote really doesn't matter very much, if someone shot me at a voting place, I'd like crawl in to finish my ballot.
Speaker 1: If somebody shot me when I was still voting, that ballot is going in the machine before I go to the hospital.
Speaker 0: So someone tweeted something and I know, and it was just an interesting thing and they were like, how do the astronauts vote?
Speaker 0: And there was a process for that.
Speaker 1: I've read about that story four years ago and I read that story eight years ago.
Speaker 1: I feel like I also read that story 12 and 16 years ago.
Speaker 1: I think I've heard that story enough times.
Speaker 0: All right, how do astronauts vote?
Speaker 1: Well, they fill out this thing before they go in space.
Speaker 1: It's like the absentee space voting thingy.
Speaker 1: And then they basically, if there's a delivery that goes at a good time and the ballot's already figured out, they'll include a ballot in there for them.
Speaker 1: But otherwise, they just vote digitally and sign a thing and affirm over the space telephone who they're voting for.
Speaker 0: This was just a regular mass shooting.
Speaker 0: It wasn't specifically targeting the polls.
Speaker 0: It just was like right next to the poll, apparently.
Speaker 1: But was it a crazy person who is politically motivated?
Speaker 0: No, it looks like it looks like a run of the mill mass shooting in America.
Speaker 1: You don't say.
Speaker 1: Looks like a typical day when people are craziest.
Speaker 1: Some crazy person got even crazier than you.
Speaker 0: There's so many mass shootings in the US that odds were there was going to be one somewhere in the US today.
Speaker 0: So that appears to be it.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: We're not reporting on this because I'm going on Twitter and an L.A.
Speaker 0: Times article that is not that up to date.
Speaker 1: That's not.
Speaker 1: We don't report on those even when we have.
Speaker 0: Don't come to us for news.
Speaker 0: Never mind the fact that by the time you listen to this, you'll already know what happened.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't even bother mentioning because what's the point?
Speaker 0: I was just really interested in what's going on there.
Speaker 1: It's not very interesting.
Speaker 0: I could have been really interesting.
Speaker 1: By spreading that kind of reporting on the kind of information, it makes it happen more.
Speaker 0: There's actually no evidence of that.
Speaker 1: There's evidence.
Speaker 0: No, there's not.
Speaker 0: Are you saying that we should have censorship of the press?
Speaker 1: No, I'm not.
Speaker 0: So what are you saying then?
Speaker 0: What are you saying?
Speaker 1: I'm saying that.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: doesn't vote in primaries.
Speaker 1: The government shouldn't say press don't report on mass shootings, right?
Speaker 1: Because that'll make more of them.
Speaker 0: So you just want to have a giant press conspiracy to not report on a significant problem that happens in the US?
Speaker 0: Because then the narrative would be, well, there aren't mass shootings, so I guess we don't need to regulate guns.
Speaker 1: No, that's not should be the narrative either.
Speaker 1: The narrative should be they try to report on mass shootings and nobody watches that bullshit and this.
Speaker 1: they don't get ratings for it, so they stop reporting on it.
Speaker 0: That's not how that's going to work.
Speaker 1: That's you know, I do my part by not paying attention to the shitty news to discourage them from.
Speaker 1: No, you just disengage it.
Speaker 0: There was a young Scott Rubin, 2005, who talked endlessly about Barack Obama and how excited he was.
Speaker 1: That Scott became a smarter Scott.
Speaker 1: If you in fact, if you did not grow and learn and become a better person on the radio, the same shitty person he was in the year 2000, whatever you can, Scott is now an adult and rim is still some college kid, some dumb ass.
Speaker 0: But if you listen to the geek nights, Patreon with the beta episodes, you can hear Scott being so excited about Obama and talking about Scott, new specific shit about Tom delay and indictment hearings.
Speaker 1: I know specifically shit now.
Speaker 1: I just don't talk about it because I don't think, you know, specific shit anymore.
Speaker 1: I know more than, you know, I don't think you do pay attention to the shit that matters and not some mass shootings.
Speaker 0: But anyway, if you're worried about staying up late, the polls in Florida close real soon.
Speaker 0: And basically if any one of those states like Ohio or Florida goes Clinton, you just go to bed because it's over.
Speaker 0: Like it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: There's almost no way he can win after that.
Speaker 0: So you can go to sleep, wake up in the morning and not panic all night waiting for like Iowa's last district to report its last ballot or whatever.
Speaker 0: So anyway, I got any gaming news is like this weekend.
Speaker 1: for some reason.
Speaker 1: this past weekend, which I guess is like the first weekend in November or second weekend, I remember whatever every year for the past few years has turned into like the gaming extravaganza weekend.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it is, but this weekend has the fantasy flight games world championship, which if you don't know is when you've got the net runner world championship, the X wing world championship and a bunch of other games, no one gives a fuck about at the same, they're made by the same company, right?
Speaker 1: It's also Blizzcon for some reason has been on the same weekend this many years in a row.
Speaker 0: I was watching the overwatch championships at work.
Speaker 1: You get your overwatch championship, your hearthstone championship, you know, all the blizzard games.
Speaker 1: And also because it's Blizzcon, all the blizzard news.
Speaker 1: So we got tons of news to talk about blizzard stuff.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And also this year it happened to also be PAX Australia, which we didn't go to, but which meant that I could stay home and watching Twitch.
Speaker 1: I was actually two windowing, three windowing Twitch at some times.
Speaker 1: It's so sad though.
Speaker 1: I didn't have to really go to three windows too often because of the time zones of PAX Aus.
Speaker 1: PAX Aus didn't really conflict with the Blizzcon and the fantasy flight stuff, which are in the US.
Speaker 0: It's so weird not being in a PAX because we go to all the PAXs and until now I had, I've been to one more PAX in Scott.
Speaker 0: So I went to two of the PAX Australia's.
Speaker 1: I only went to the first one.
Speaker 0: This year, just being at home and then seeing those tweets, like I'm on my way to PAX.
Speaker 0: Hey guys.
Speaker 1: Cookie Brigade tweets are the worst ones.
Speaker 0: It's Thursday.
Speaker 1: It's like, hey guys, come to tabletop and get cookies.
Speaker 1: And usually when I see that tweet, I'm very soon after eating the cookie.
Speaker 1: And that time I didn't get a cookie.
Speaker 1: Like days after I saw that tweet.
Speaker 0: You're like, go outside and try to buy a cookie at whatever deli's open.
Speaker 1: It's not shaped like a mushroom.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure going to PAX Aus next year, we'll see what happens, but anyway, uh, so tons of stuff happens.
Speaker 1: So let's go down the list of most important things.
Speaker 0: The most, most important thing is actually just, well, a news about, you know, related to all these overwatch championships and all this nonsense.
Speaker 1: What is that news?
Speaker 0: Blizzard is going to have a professional, a professional overwatch league, which is not news.
Speaker 1: That's like, of course, I'm surprised it doesn't already exist.
Speaker 1: Already.
Speaker 0: They're not going to use all the, all the existing traditional kind of bullshitty ways that these leagues go together.
Speaker 0: They're going to have permanent city based teams, real goddamn adult sport.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you what I'd have never played overwatch even one second.
Speaker 1: I have only really showed like.
Speaker 1: you would actually only know what it looks like.
Speaker 1: Barely.
Speaker 1: I don't even know how to play.
Speaker 1: But if you tell me, if you tell me that the New York fuckers doesn't even need to be at the garden.
Speaker 0: The New York fuck sores are playing against the bar play center, the Washington butt faces.
Speaker 1: If there's the New York city somethings and they're playing overwatch, right?
Speaker 1: Whatever their team name is, as long as it's not like, you know, racist, right?
Speaker 1: I'm buying season fucking tickets and learning at least how to watch overwatch.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: So it's got literally, it's just like buying a Jersey factory.
Speaker 0: It's kept its CTF just good.
Speaker 1: Like it's just, yeah, I mean, I'm pretty sure I could figure it out in like five minutes, but I, you know, to enjoy watching it, I had to learn some specific stuff though.
Speaker 1: Like, Oh shit, he went and picked that character.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: He picked me.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: He just released a new character, which is fucking me up.
Speaker 1: But I mean, that's not any different than like watching a hockey game and being like offsides.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: There goes Vessi.
Speaker 1: It'll take me probably 10 minutes.
Speaker 0: Like knowing who Vessi is.
Speaker 1: And hopefully they will play some other games too, because that would make it even better to go watch.
Speaker 1: Cause like if I could go down there after work, you know, my season ticket and watch the New York, whatever they are, is play like some overwatch and then play some kind of strike and then play some something else.
Speaker 0: But there's a much more important thing.
Speaker 0: I mean, this is a, for real professionalization of esports, they're going to launch Q3 of.
Speaker 0: So they got, they're setting all this up, but city-based teams does something that we haven't seen hitherto in that.
Speaker 1: Makes me actually care about the team.
Speaker 0: City-based teams imply local city-based infrastructure imply normalizing problems that plague other formats like lag and regional stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean like the way hockey works is you mostly play people in your local region and then you occasionally go out and do away games far away and like sort of cross.
Speaker 1: They're going to have, they're going to have divisions like, Oh, we won the division.
Speaker 1: We made the playoffs.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: But they also, this article, at least that I found, talked a lot about how most other, most people either use a complicated fan nonsense system or a grind system, or they do use a relegation system, which the article points out.
Speaker 1: Relegation systems are okay.
Speaker 1: It works for English soccer.
Speaker 0: So I never thought about that much, but this article makes a pretty good point that in general, outside of the very specific soccer fandom in specific parts of the world, relegation systems confuse people and turn them away from sports.
Speaker 0: And if they become fans of a team that gets knocked out of the league, they usually don't attach to another team.
Speaker 0: They're just done.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing, the reason the relegation system works in English soccer is number one.
Speaker 1: in the premier league, there are certain teams that have so much money and are so good it, even though they theoretically like arsenal could theoretically be relegated if they really stunk it up for a bunch of years in a row or something, I don't know the exact, how bad you have to be to be relegated, but it's theoretically possible that some enormous team could be relegated if they really shit, right?
Speaker 1: But that will never happen because they have so much money and good players just keep playing for them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Quote, while relegation and promotion make for good drama, they also lead to instability that can frustrate or scare away team owners.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: That's the thing is that, you know, that if you own, like, are you going to buy, uh, you know, buy the New York Rangers, like the Cleveland Browns, if there's a relegation in the NFL would have been relegated already.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: These Philadelphia 76ers would have been relegated, but they have this huge history.
Speaker 1: So it's like, you don't want to buy a, you know, Philadelphia 76ers, if they could be relegated.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But this also means there will be e-sports related, legit careers in a bunch of cities, as opposed to concentrated in the few areas where e-sports is run.
Speaker 0: now, you don't have to work for Blizzard anymore.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe you will, cause they're running the league, but you could work for the New York Fox.
Speaker 1: I hope that the league is a league.
Speaker 1: the same way, like the NFL is a league, technically a nonprofit, but it's really just a, an organization that exists at behest of the team owners.
Speaker 1: And then I could go work, I could go to get a job for the New York e-sport team, whatever it is.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Like I, you know, a team like that, there are so many jobs to be had from usher and hot dog guy at the arena, which you actually work for the arena then.
Speaker 1: But like for the team, there's so many jobs as trainers, there's coaches, there's tech.
Speaker 1: people is, is, you know, marketing, think about Seinfeld, right?
Speaker 1: George Costanza's job with, you know, there's the social media, there's like just, you have an enormous number of people that work for a team and I would totally apply it to get a job.
Speaker 0: I am all about this.
Speaker 1: I don't even care what the job is.
Speaker 1: I'll be the hot dog guy.
Speaker 0: The other thing that's very interesting, you know, you can be the cheer, you can be the mascot.
Speaker 0: So I'll be cosplayers with this game.
Speaker 1: Hopefully that'd be great.
Speaker 1: But there's, you can go get the Statue of Liberty guy from a time of score.
Speaker 0: The other way they're going to depart from most of these other e-sports is that there's going to be a season and there's going to be a lengthy off season just like real sports.
Speaker 0: And apparently that was based off feedback from, uh, the industry, the players, potential owners, pretty much everyone was like, yeah, we need an off season.
Speaker 0: Jesus.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I mean the, the, we talked recently about the MBA owners that bought, you know, e-sports teams and they're basically like, yeah, that's what they're doing too with their lol or whatever games they're playing.
Speaker 0: Oh, this is a really good quote.
Speaker 0: Nobody talks about what the prize pool is for the world cup or the super bowl.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So Blizzard continues to be like the, just on the bleeding edge of doing all this stuff the right way.
Speaker 0: And it's interesting that this, they're only doing this for Overwatch.
Speaker 0: Like they're still running heroes of the storm with a promotion relegation system.
Speaker 0: Like every one of their e-sports is run completely differently.
Speaker 1: They're going to, they're going to obviously going to try this out, see if it works best.
Speaker 1: And if so, they're probably going to move everything over.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they'll move everything.
Speaker 0: I feel like some of them like Hearthstone probably works well the way it is now because Hearthstone is an individual game.
Speaker 1: So I feel like you want to manage that the way you manage tennis or golf.
Speaker 1: You don't want to, it's not a team thing, right?
Speaker 1: You don't have owners in golf, right?
Speaker 1: You're just an individual with your own sponsors and your own, you know, or thing.
Speaker 0: But anyway, rather than try to tell you all the pertinent details, I'm going to link to this polygon article that is probably the best in-depth look at what they're actually doing.
Speaker 0: But this is the biggest gaming news of like the decade.
Speaker 1: Other minor e-sport news.
Speaker 1: There was a low event.
Speaker 1: And at the low event was basically they took the top ranked ladder players.
Speaker 1: So not pro players, just people sitting at home playing, but the best ones.
Speaker 1: And they brought them to an event to play with pros to see if they were good enough to be pros.
Speaker 1: And there's a list of requirements they had to meet.
Speaker 1: And if they met them, they would be pros then.
Speaker 1: You know, teams could draft.
Speaker 1: It was like an NFL combine kind of deal, right?
Speaker 1: Or a draft sort of thing.
Speaker 1: And the best player there is North America.
Speaker 1: only because North America is weak.
Speaker 1: So it needed the help is North America thing, the best player there.
Speaker 1: He was a player who played a role on the team that is like a desperately needed role.
Speaker 1: Like no one plays that role.
Speaker 1: Like, man, we really need a running back.
Speaker 1: And he is a running back.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh shit, there are not a lot of running backs.
Speaker 1: We got one in Overwatch.
Speaker 0: You need one really good Genji, right?
Speaker 1: So he's like the number one guy at that.
Speaker 1: And he was the number one overall.
Speaker 1: He was like, so good.
Speaker 1: And they're like, oh man, we want to sign you up.
Speaker 1: But the last requirement was basically you have to have a good behavior record, no shitheads.
Speaker 1: And they looked at his low history.
Speaker 1: Turns out he was a toxic player piece of shit.
Speaker 1: So they said, go fuck yourself.
Speaker 1: If you can't play, even though you were like the best, get lost.
Speaker 1: And that's awesome.
Speaker 1: I think like even the real, the real sports, right?
Speaker 1: It's like plenty of shitheads in the NFL, NHL, NBA, Major League Baseball.
Speaker 1: And they get to, even if they do something really awful, like go to jail for dogfighting, Michael Vick.
Speaker 1: They let him come right back afterwards.
Speaker 0: Imagine if the NFL was like, no domestic violence charges, you're done.
Speaker 1: And it's like, while I agree that, you know, it's like you served your time, you should be allowed back into society.
Speaker 1: I don't agree with that box, like on job applications, like have you ever been a felon, right?
Speaker 1: There are certain things you should not be able to do, right?
Speaker 1: Like be a public figure, celebrity type person.
Speaker 1: You should just be like, okay, you can have a life, but you can't be rich, famous celebrity because you're a scumbag.
Speaker 0: We're not going to let you do that.
Speaker 1: Well, I suspect, I'm not a lawyer, that's not legal advice, that- Especially not in a position where like you are a role model, public figure type thing.
Speaker 0: If your job involves being a celebrity effectively, pretty sure you can discriminate based on public opinion of you.
Speaker 1: Right, yeah.
Speaker 0: And Blizzard has been like, I report people, like if someone says anything even close to being racist in any Overwatch game, I just report them immediately.
Speaker 0: And I tell them I report them and they usually get mad and say more report worthy things.
Speaker 0: And everyone else on the team will usually also report them.
Speaker 0: It looks like they just fucking take your game away, ban you from Overwatch for life.
Speaker 0: Like they do not fuck around.
Speaker 1: Like if I was hiring someone to be a software developer- I look at their Twitter.
Speaker 0: And it turned out that they were like- I see some Pepe the Froyo over at Twitter.
Speaker 1: Well, no, let's say it turned out that they like, they killed somebody.
Speaker 1: Like they're a felon, but they got out of jail.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 1: Like I talked to their probation officer and I, you know, I just checked it out.
Speaker 1: I'm not, you know, I didn't, I didn't put the checkbox on the job application, but I'm still doing a background check because that's how I do, right?
Speaker 1: And I just find this out, but I interview them and they're a stable individual.
Speaker 1: And, you know, like, and if they know their shit and they're better than the other applicants that know when they're shit for this job, I'm gonna hire them.
Speaker 1: But if that job is say, I don't know, uh, to be like my developer relations person who has to go around, you know, talking to people, I'm like, yeah, murder.
Speaker 1: Can't have that job, right?
Speaker 1: To the face of my company.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But you can totally have a high paying job writing code.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: Uh, tons of other news is going around a lot.
Speaker 0: I mean, I watched the overall championships.
Speaker 0: It was just kind of amazing.
Speaker 0: Uh, the commentation was pretty pro packs.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 1: Megathon finale was basically VR, wild west dueling of some kind.
Speaker 1: From what I could tell, uh, I didn't actually see what game it was specifically.
Speaker 0: I just, but it was a notable megathon for a reason that I've, I've been, every year I root for this to happen.
Speaker 0: And this is the first time it happened.
Speaker 1: Not only was it too, we've been predicting VR for a while.
Speaker 0: But not only was it two women in the omega finale, but a woman who won the omega finale, it took long enough.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: I'm very happy with that outcome.
Speaker 0: I haven't actually watched the omega yet.
Speaker 1: I just saw screenshots.
Speaker 1: I didn't see in photos.
Speaker 1: I didn't watch the video of it or figure out any of that stuff.
Speaker 0: What sucks is I was literally in Australia and came home like a week before packs.
Speaker 1: The person who won the net runner world championship last year and the year before did not win it this year.
Speaker 1: They didn't even make the cut.
Speaker 1: Uh, so, so I watched, but I mean, if you care about net runner, you're just going to get all the info on your own.
Speaker 1: You don't need to meet to waste podcast time on that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Don't get news from us.
Speaker 0: Get commentary.
Speaker 1: It's a good time to play net runners though.
Speaker 1: There's going to be rotation like pretty soon and new cards are coming that are exciting and old cards are going to go away.
Speaker 1: So we're going to like reach the limit.
Speaker 1: We're like, this is the amount of money it costs to buy all net runner cards period.
Speaker 1: And that number won't really go up ever again once we hit that rotation time.
Speaker 1: And I hear there, there's a rumor they're also going to redo the core set a little bit.
Speaker 1: So, and that should really help make the game a lot better.
Speaker 0: So, so I watch the, uh, wow.
Speaker 0: Arena championship stuff they were doing.
Speaker 0: It was like this pregame thing.
Speaker 1: Uh, that's like, I didn't even, why did they even do that?
Speaker 1: I was just, why is that even a thing?
Speaker 0: Because I watched a lot of their other streams and heroes of the storm and, uh, Overwatch.
Speaker 0: The commutation was pretty good and that should be it.
Speaker 0: Like games.
Speaker 0: I don't know that well.
Speaker 0: at good commentary and games I knew that well, like also had good commentary.
Speaker 0: But the commutation on wow.
Speaker 0: Arena was nothing but made up words.
Speaker 0: I could not tell.
Speaker 0: I like, they kept saying this word that I assumed was the name of one of the players, but then it was not.
Speaker 0: And I couldn't figure out what the fuck they were talking about.
Speaker 0: And it's like, you couldn't follow it.
Speaker 0: Like I, that is the opposite of an e-sport that thing.
Speaker 1: The Hearthstone commentary is actually really, really good.
Speaker 1: The only problem with it is that if you don't know the names of cards, it will sound like gobbledygook.
Speaker 1: It's like, other than that, it's like, they're speaking perfect English.
Speaker 1: It's just, they referred to cards by name.
Speaker 1: Like, oh no, he's playing Ragnaros the Firelord.
Speaker 1: What's going to happen?
Speaker 1: They don't, occasionally someone will say, ah, this is what Ragnaros the Firelord does, but not frequently.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But that's about the level I want.
Speaker 0: Cause I feel like if I'm, well, really, I feel like the right way to do this in the future.
Speaker 0: And I feel like you could do this with traditional sports too, is there's always two commentary tracks.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: There's, you can pick between the, I'm a casual viewer of this.
Speaker 0: And I know what's going on.
Speaker 1: And not just English and Spanish.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But the Netrunner actually, they had, you know, commentary on the Netrunner World Championships from, you know, the FFG staff and some other people.
Speaker 1: And sometimes they had people on there who didn't know the game that well.
Speaker 1: And that was annoying.
Speaker 1: And some, and the thing is even the people who did know the game really well, were really trying to talk intentionally, trying to explain everything as if the person watching was a new player, like explaining every card.
Speaker 1: It's like, that would be like, if you're watching a hockey game and someone goes offsides and they, you know, it's like, they just say offsides.
Speaker 1: Imagine if they're like offsides.
Speaker 1: Ah, that means he went over the blue line before the, I would just beat my face into the wall.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So that it's like, imagine if they said that like multiple times, after you would go off with the four check, a four check is when, right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you can't do that either.
Speaker 1: It doesn't work.
Speaker 1: You need to give people some amount of, you know, Puck is a hard wooden object made of rubber.
Speaker 0: Hard rubber objects.
Speaker 1: Oh, he got calls for tripping.
Speaker 1: That means it's just like, oh my God.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like only explain the complicated rules that even someone who knows how to play the game.
Speaker 0: You're only going to have one commentary track.
Speaker 0: You do it the way American football does it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: American football shows you what you think is American football.
Speaker 1: Even people who are football fans, even the kind of football fan who doesn't understand football that much.
Speaker 1: And he's just like the drunken football fan.
Speaker 1: Even they like the commentary less.
Speaker 1: John Madden was a big deal.
Speaker 1: And his name is on Madden football because when he would talk, we'd commentate the football games, right?
Speaker 1: He would talk about them on a, not, you know, the coaches high, super high level, but in a higher level than every day, people could even think about it.
Speaker 1: He would also be drawn the X's and O's and he'd teach you how the game of football.
Speaker 0: He'd reach down to you who don't know that much about football and elevate you a little bit.
Speaker 0: He wouldn't just leave you down there.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: And nowadays you didn't even see anyone using the telestrator anymore.
Speaker 1: The telestrator like does not exist in modern NFL broadcasting whatsoever.
Speaker 1: He brought it, he made it a thing and they got rid of it.
Speaker 0: I saw it on a Rangers game the other night talking about lines.
Speaker 1: But the only time they use the telestrator now is if you're watching like NFL network and there's not a game going on.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know, a special show where they're talking about like strategies and things.
Speaker 1: You can watch some of those videos on like nfl.com/whatever video or something like that.
Speaker 1: And cause you know, if you don't have NFL network cause you don't pay for cable cause you're a smart person, but during the actual games, they eliminated all of that.
Speaker 1: They've dumbed it down to an extraordinary level and it's not good.
Speaker 0: So this is our idea.
Speaker 0: Blizzard, you're doing everything right.
Speaker 0: My suggestion is if you can pull it off two commentary streams for every game.
Speaker 1: Every e-sport do that.
Speaker 0: Every non-sport do that.
Speaker 0: No one else is capable at this point.
Speaker 1: Every sport, multiple commentaries to choose from.
Speaker 1: And also every sport.
Speaker 1: Let me listen to the radio announcers synchronized on the TV.
Speaker 1: I hate your TV announcers.
Speaker 1: They suck except MSG used to be an app that did that, but it doesn't.
Speaker 1: We would delay the radio broadcast.
Speaker 1: It would, you know, you take an am radio and it would delay and you could match it up with your TV, but that doesn't work anymore.
Speaker 0: But uh, anyway, all the, all the specific news is that we could talk about.
Speaker 0: They'll trickle in as we have commentary in the next several episodes of geek nights.
Speaker 0: You can just go read about all this stuff.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So if you're not familiar with, uh, Reddit, it has the concept of subreddits and some subreddits, the only reason Reddit works is because it has subreddits.
Speaker 1: You don't have to go to the bad subreddits.
Speaker 1: You can just stay in the good parts and ignore the shit parts.
Speaker 0: But the interesting thing about subreddits is they get shockingly specific.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: That's the other reason that they work, right?
Speaker 0: Is like, if you're a fan of say, I don't know, Harry Potter, right?
Speaker 1: Well, you're probably not, if you're like the Harry Potter fanfic writing type, you're probably not going to get along with.
Speaker 1: say my brother.
Speaker 1: My brother is a huge Harry Potter fan.
Speaker 1: He was reading Harry Potter before.
Speaker 1: it was a thing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And he'll tell you that.
Speaker 1: And he's read every book and seen every movie.
Speaker 1: But if you showed him a fan fiction, he'd be like, get the fuck away from me.
Speaker 1: What the fuck is that?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But you know, he doesn't want to hang out with them.
Speaker 1: So slash R slash Harry Potter is not for him.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Or maybe it is.
Speaker 1: And slash R slash Harry fic is for someone else.
Speaker 0: So this is a subreddit dedicated solely to not just the Pokemon executor, but the Aeolian version of the Pokemon executor.
Speaker 1: I didn't know there was a different version of exec.
Speaker 0: You haven't looked at the new Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Well, also, executor is a really garbage Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Fuck him.
Speaker 0: You know, he's one of the Pokemon I would use because he's great.
Speaker 1: Like execute an executor.
Speaker 1: That's like.
Speaker 1: that's like one of the worst Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, if I was ranking Pokemon, especially like, I mean, it's an old Pokemon to style wise.
Speaker 0: They're great.
Speaker 0: The problem is they suck at being Pokemon.
Speaker 1: I don't care when I'm ranking Pokemon.
Speaker 1: I do not care about their effectiveness in pokey battle.
Speaker 0: That is like.
Speaker 0: that is not like.
Speaker 1: that is not a concern for me whatsoever.
Speaker 1: The only thing that I'm concerned with is their visual appearance and general stylings.
Speaker 1: And executor, despite being an old Pokemon, that is much better than, say, many of the modern pile of razorblades.
Speaker 1: Pokemons is probably like the worst Pokemon.
Speaker 1: that isn't a pile of razorblades.
Speaker 0: Executor.
Speaker 0: I think he's a great guy.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you have to go look at this subreddit.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good subreddit.
Speaker 0: Like it's not what you're expecting, but in a way it should be what you like.
Speaker 0: When you see it, you'll realize that this is exactly what you should have expected.
Speaker 0: And it's going strong.
Speaker 1: Nice.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 1: The problem is if you subscribe to the subreddit and get the highest rated posts on your Reddit homepage.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's not very effective.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: You've got to go to it directly.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: This Arthur one.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So if you are old like us and you used or saw or knew about AOL back in the day when that was what Internet was.
Speaker 0: I never had AOL.
Speaker 0: I use the free CD, the free discs.
Speaker 0: I would sign into AOL online to do bad shit.
Speaker 0: I shouldn't have been doing.
Speaker 1: I would sign into AOL, minimize it and open up Netscape Navigator is a thing you could do anyway.
Speaker 0: Red Prodigy Internet and wow.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So you would, uh, you know, when you signed into AOL, you had to open the AOL app, right?
Speaker 1: Cause that was how you dialed in.
Speaker 1: You couldn't just dial in with your regular old, you know, modem, you know, you know, TTLs, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So it would open up and it would check your AOL email.
Speaker 1: And if you had it, you would say welcome.
Speaker 1: And then if you had mail, it would say you've got mail.
Speaker 1: And this was such a big cultural phenomenon that there was even like a movie about it.
Speaker 0: And, you know, yeah, that movie real bad.
Speaker 1: There's a whole.
Speaker 1: it was a big deal back then in the 90s, late 90s.
Speaker 1: And then it disappeared once AOL disappeared.
Speaker 1: But, you know, but there's a certain generation of people where that will be a thing for them forever.
Speaker 1: And I wonder, were there things like that for even older generations that are now gone?
Speaker 1: I would like to know about them.
Speaker 1: Old people, please tell me what is the, you got mail of your generation that has now been lost.
Speaker 0: Probably where's the beef.
Speaker 1: That's I know that one though.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Uh, send me your YouTube links.
Speaker 1: Uh, anyway, the guy who's the voice actor who said you've got mail, right?
Speaker 1: He's come back into, you know, 15 minutes of fame here.
Speaker 0: Nice John St.
Speaker 0: John style.
Speaker 1: You know, every once in a while this guy appears.
Speaker 1: He's not like a forgotten sad figure, right?
Speaker 1: He's, you know, he gets his, you know, recurring like, oh, there's that guy again once in a while.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: He's sort of on the same level as like the guy who does the Mario voices.
Speaker 1: But apparently he's getting less work than the guy who does the Mario voices because he is currently at least partial part of the time working, driving an Uber.
Speaker 1: I hate Uber.
Speaker 1: I've never ridden in one and I never will because that company is evil.
Speaker 1: But someone got in an Uber and this guy was driving it and he was totally happy and chill to say you've got mail for them.
Speaker 1: And that's awesome.
Speaker 1: So I like this guy, even though he's working for some shit company part of his time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'll never blame the people who work for Uber.
Speaker 0: I'll only blame the people who work in corporate.
Speaker 1: I don't blame, listen, I don't even blame people who take Ubers cause there's people who were like, they need Uber.
Speaker 0: Like if you were in a place, I blame people who live in New York city and are traveling in the parts of New York city that actually have cabs against Uber.
Speaker 1: I've know, for example, disabled people who live in a place where like a cab isn't going to come get them.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know, even Uber gives them trouble.
Speaker 1: Like the Uber will say that they'll like handicap accessible and they won't or like they'll see them and drive past and shit.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it's one of the, or I've seen people where like they live in a suburb where cars are a thing.
Speaker 1: And they just drive everywhere.
Speaker 1: A cab isn't going to come by their house.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And you know, to get a cab to come to your house is like a huge pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: The Uber is the best option.
Speaker 1: And there'll be a situation where like they need a car because maybe like, you know, they have to, they're going to get a cancer treatment or something and they're going to be mad dizzy and messed up on chemo and they got to get home from the cancer treatment place.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And there's no, like, that's the best.
Speaker 1: It's amazing that for all these situations like that, you know, a grandma, everything is great about Uber, the founders of the company.
Speaker 1: But the company is just awful and horrendous.
Speaker 0: So I got a second tiny thing of the day.
Speaker 0: This is the best tweet of 2016.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Jill Stein with 0.6% of the vote sticking to her guns and going for a homeopathic victory.
Speaker 1: That's a funny joke, but it's not the best tweet of 2016.
Speaker 0: Find me a better tweet.
Speaker 1: I'll check my favorite tweets.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure I could find a better one from today.
Speaker 0: There's the guy who brought his rabbit to vote with him.
Speaker 0: That was pretty good.
Speaker 1: That's just cute.
Speaker 1: You mean cute tweets aren't the greatest tweets, right?
Speaker 1: Or are they?
Speaker 0: Anyway, in the meta moment, the book club book is Rebecca.
Speaker 0: I'm going to read it real soon because I finished that World War II book I was reading.
Speaker 0: Are you reading it?
Speaker 0: or if you're not resumed it yet?
Speaker 1: Soon.
Speaker 0: I feel like as soon as one of us starts reading it, we're both going to finish it in, like, a couple days and we'll do the book club show.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, check out my YouTube channel and Scott's YouTube channel.
Speaker 0: I've been uploading more and more stuff to the Patreon as I spin it back up.
Speaker 0: Now that we're back from Australia, I'm going to continue reading Simon's Quest, Castlevania II, the Worlds of Power novelization by FX9, where it's weirdly sexualized and it's creeping me out as an adult reading this book.
Speaker 0: I worry that all the rest of them are similar.
Speaker 0: If you didn't vote and you live in America, I guess you're a bad person.
Speaker 1: You're over the age of 18.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you could have voted in America and you didn't, probably a bad person.
Speaker 0: Unless you might have an excuse.
Speaker 0: You might have been shot by that guy or whatever, but if not, probably should have voted.
Speaker 1: Now, I'm not saying this is best tweet of 2016.
Speaker 1: I just scrolled down through my liked tweets to find a tweet that was better than the one you just mentioned.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So here's one from nine days ago.
Speaker 1: Someone posted this early in the morning when they had to get up early and it's Sailor Moon pulling the covers overhead in a little gif.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: I know that.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: And right above that is a tweet that's actually text.
Speaker 1: So it's a real tweet.
Speaker 1: If Marvel wanted to capture that fading young male audience, they would bring back Ghost Rider, a skeleton, which rides a motorcycle on fire.
Speaker 1: And I wholeheartedly agree.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much.
Speaker 1: the only thing good about Ghost Rider is that he is a skeleton on a motorcycle who is on fire.
Speaker 1: And we need more of those because Inferno Cop and Ghost Rider are the only two I know of.
Speaker 1: Give me more.
Speaker 1: The end.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: And don't give me that like human Ghost Rider fighting crime on the streets.
Speaker 1: Bullshit, right?
Speaker 1: The real Ghost Rider goes into literal hell.
Speaker 1: It's like a doom situation.
Speaker 1: That's the Ghost Rider.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: I got some good Ghost Rider comics that are really best tweets.
Speaker 1: Imagine if Doom Guy was a skeleton on a motorcycle on fire.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of game that when I was in high school, I would have played the shit out of.
Speaker 0: You did.
Speaker 1: It was called Doom.
Speaker 0: And Doom 2.
Speaker 1: You just shot rockets at skeleton heads on fire coming at you.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So Uwe Rosenberg, we're a fan of his games.
Speaker 1: He's a, you know, somewhat legendary board game maker of games like Agricola and such.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: Agricola, Le Havre, Glass Road, which I haven't played yet.
Speaker 0: Everyone's telling me to play.
Speaker 1: Caverna.
Speaker 0: Which I do not enjoy.
Speaker 1: You played Caverna?
Speaker 0: I learned how to play it.
Speaker 1: Caverna.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I learned.
Speaker 1: I was taught how to play Caverna.
Speaker 1: Because you don't say I'm going to a cavern.
Speaker 1: Well, you can say I'm going down to the cavern and it's a cavern.
Speaker 0: But you don't, you don't buy a crystal yet.
Speaker 0: The game is called Crystalis.
Speaker 1: Some people buy crystal.
Speaker 0: You're going to call it a crystal?
Speaker 0: Crystalis?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying.
Speaker 0: It's not crystal with a K. Anyway, A Feast for Odin is the one that everyone's talking about recently.
Speaker 1: That's a hot new game I haven't played, know nothing about.
Speaker 0: Everyone who's mentioned it to me said, quote, I'm paraphrasing all of the things they said together, it's an Uwe Rosenberg game.
Speaker 1: I definitely want to have a feast with my bro Odin.
Speaker 1: There's no question about that.
Speaker 0: I think it's the one that has a really big box.
Speaker 0: Like you were taking pictures of dropping the box on things.
Speaker 0: That might be a heavy box.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, Odin's a hungry man.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: A hungry god.
Speaker 0: But a possibly overlooked small game that he did in 2014.
Speaker 0: It's not overlooked.
Speaker 0: I've never actually played it until today.
Speaker 0: I didn't play it until recently.
Speaker 1: So there's a game called Patchwork.
Speaker 1: It's a two player game.
Speaker 1: And I knew this game was hot because when I was working in the PAX library multiple years in a row, right, this game would be coming in and out and in and out as soon as it came in and went out.
Speaker 1: People wanted this game.
Speaker 1: We only had like one copy, which I think maybe felt like it had a higher demand than it deserved because it was a low supply situation.
Speaker 1: If we had more copies, you probably wouldn't have that problem.
Speaker 1: But anyway, two player game.
Speaker 1: I knew it was hot.
Speaker 1: I've seen it in stores.
Speaker 1: And recently the iOS app was on super sale, like way discounted.
Speaker 1: So I bought it.
Speaker 1: I learned how to play using the app.
Speaker 1: Today, I read the rules PDF, and it turns out the app taught me how to play exactly one hundred percent correctly.
Speaker 1: The app has an amazing user interface with very few flaws.
Speaker 1: Rim read the rules, which are really short.
Speaker 1: So he learned how to play.
Speaker 1: We played twice.
Speaker 1: I completely destroyed rim both times because I've been practicing playing this on the app for like a few weeks.
Speaker 0: And I literally never played it before.
Speaker 1: And you didn't try very hard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I wasn't going to spend the time to really look at all the potential pieces.
Speaker 1: But even if you had tried very hard and learned to play, you played it a lot.
Speaker 1: I mean, the margin of victory by which I destroyed you even in the second game was so vast.
Speaker 1: I think that, you know, even if you practice this for a while, I would still be better than you.
Speaker 0: I will play this game enough to prove you wrong on that.
Speaker 1: At least I think you could make it close.
Speaker 1: I do not think that you could beat me on any consistent basis.
Speaker 1: There is the tiniest amount.
Speaker 1: There's not that much going on in this game of luck in terms of who goes first, which could matter.
Speaker 1: And if two players are truly equal, depending on the piece distribution, first player could determine winner in like a small percentage of games.
Speaker 1: And that's about it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So here's how the game works.
Speaker 1: You're trying to make a quilt.
Speaker 1: And the best quilt wins with big old like extended Tetris pieces.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like block is right.
Speaker 1: There's a set of pieces and it's the same set of pieces for every game.
Speaker 1: And some pieces are going to go to player one and some pieces are going to end up with player two and some places are going to end up with nobody.
Speaker 1: And you're making a quilt.
Speaker 1: And at the end of the game, best quilt wins.
Speaker 1: And here's how it works on your little board where you make a quilt, which is a nine by nine board.
Speaker 1: Every empty square left at the end of the game is minus two points.
Speaker 1: So it's eighty one nine times nine times two.
Speaker 1: Eighty one times two is one hundred and sixty four hundred sixty two.
Speaker 1: You can have negative one hundred sixty two at the end of the game if you don't put any pieces down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's not going to happen.
Speaker 1: Also, you then get one point for every button you have.
Speaker 1: A button is like this currency and you start with five.
Speaker 1: And then as you get a certain number of incomes as the game goes on and the incomes are equal to the number of buttons that are in your quilt already.
Speaker 1: So certain pieces in your quilt have buttons sewn onto them.
Speaker 1: And those pieces will generate currency for you every time you pass a currency spot on the track.
Speaker 1: And the track is this timing track.
Speaker 1: So basically that archaeologist game.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So the timing track is whenever you add a piece to your quilt, it takes time to sew it on.
Speaker 1: So you get these hourglasses.
Speaker 1: And when you got to the end of the game, right, is.
Speaker 1: you spent so many hourglasses that your piece moves off the edge of the boards.
Speaker 1: You can think of it as everyone starts the game with X hourglasses and they're a currency that you're spending.
Speaker 1: And as you spend more of them, right, you cross certain checkpoints and does get your income points.
Speaker 1: And you're also these little one by one squares that you can get by moving faster than the other player around the track.
Speaker 1: So if you spend a lot of time and get high hourglass pieces that you move faster, which is good and also bad.
Speaker 0: Which is interesting because the game is it's one of those rare games that has two very different currencies and pretty disparate.
Speaker 0: Like the ranges range from like one hourglass to what's the highest hourglass on that?
Speaker 1: I've seen sixes.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And the button costs range from like one to ten.
Speaker 1: There was a zero piece that you can get.
Speaker 1: No buttons whatsoever.
Speaker 0: So as a result, the game has a lot of sort of play within a very narrow band.
Speaker 0: The rules are simple and there's a narrow space in which to make your decisions.
Speaker 0: But there's a surprising amount of play within that space, right?
Speaker 0: That's the best way I can describe the first few times I played this.
Speaker 1: I thought the game was problematic and that it was a snowball game.
Speaker 1: If you got pieces early that had a lot of buttons on them, then you would get a big income early, right?
Speaker 1: Like if you think about it, if you got a piece in your quilt with one button on it right at the beginning of the game, you actually just netted one button per income phase.
Speaker 0: And buttons are not only the currency of the game, but they're points at the end.
Speaker 1: So there's a set number of income times.
Speaker 1: You're only going to get income X number of times.
Speaker 1: I forget how many.
Speaker 1: It's like seven or eight times or something like that.
Speaker 1: So if you got one button right at the beginning of the game, right?
Speaker 1: That's huge.
Speaker 1: If you get two buttons right at the beginning of the game, that's really huge.
Speaker 1: Like you're getting two times eight, that's 16 buttons that you're getting.
Speaker 1: If you cross that first income phase without any buttons in your quilt, think about how much that comes out to at the end, right?
Speaker 1: It's all right.
Speaker 1: So I thought that the way to win this game was to get a bunch of buttons in your quilt early at any cost to get huge income, to buy amazing pieces, to have tons of buttons and just fill your quilt in as best you can.
Speaker 1: And then at the end of the game, we're going to win with a big fistful of buttons.
Speaker 1: And that is true to some extent, right?
Speaker 1: If you do get a bunch of buttons early, you will have a big income and it will snowball and you'll have a good score.
Speaker 1: Generally, that is, however, I was afraid it was, but it wasn't.
Speaker 1: You cannot like guarantee and lock in a win that way.
Speaker 1: It's not somebody else can have a lower income.
Speaker 1: It's only a two player game.
Speaker 1: They can have a lower income and play more efficiently and fill in their quilt better.
Speaker 1: And as long as they have some kind of good enough income, they can beat you out.
Speaker 0: If you can't fill in your whole quilt because you moved so fast and sort of like how in someone else might be getting a bunch of pieces and setting up their stuff really well.
Speaker 0: But you've been accumulating the right numbers in this giant hand.
Speaker 0: And then you have a turn where you're like, I want that tile, that tile and that tile.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It happens.
Speaker 1: It also be situations where it's like, OK, you spent ten buttons and bought a piece of three buttons on it and it filled in a whole bunch of your quilt really nicely.
Speaker 1: That's great.
Speaker 1: I bought a piece that cost one button and that means I'm still got nine buttons left.
Speaker 1: That's like that's nine buttons.
Speaker 1: I didn't spend that you spent.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So even though my income is less, I actually got more buttons than you because I'm just holding on to them.
Speaker 1: I have a moderate income and I'm buying bargain basement pieces that are really effective.
Speaker 1: Whereas you are Uncle Moneybags over there with your big sack of buttons.
Speaker 1: You spent them all on the Mercedes piece and the, you know, the Ferrari piece.
Speaker 1: And now you broke son.
Speaker 0: Guess who wins now with these two currencies?
Speaker 0: Think of it this way.
Speaker 0: You've got one currency that is victory points and you you get them as income and you spend them to buy pieces that may or may not provide more income.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The other currency is a fixed one where there's only a certain number of spaces you can move in the entire game.
Speaker 0: So there's one currency where you can only go down and it's worth bupkis at the end.
Speaker 0: You're always going to hit zero.
Speaker 1: But at the very end of the game and the very last piece you take, it doesn't matter how many you take.
Speaker 1: So if you've got like one hourglass left, you're going to cross.
Speaker 1: you're at the next to last space on the board.
Speaker 1: As soon as you take a patch and add it to your quilt, it will be game over for you because you will cross the finish line.
Speaker 1: You can take a piece that has like theoretically like a thousand hourglasses on it because they let you do that.
Speaker 1: So you actually it's a variable number in that you don't have to cross the finish line exactly.
Speaker 1: You can benefit quite a lot by squeaking your way up to the finish line and then taking a piece that has like eight hourglasses on it.
Speaker 0: Now, so I mean, in the end, I mean, I'm probably going to buy the game, but I've been collecting.
Speaker 0: I put it in the same class as Lost Cities and the morals game, the mushroom game.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of games that are like little two battle lines.
Speaker 1: They come in the flat square box.
Speaker 0: That aligns with Kinesia, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's one of those ones and it's a good one of those ones.
Speaker 1: It keeps getting checked out of, you know, the PAX library constantly.
Speaker 0: And it's pretty short.
Speaker 0: It's quick.
Speaker 0: It's really quick to learn.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of play in terms of skill and like you can just sort of play it like you're not going to play it out unless you really start memorizing build patterns.
Speaker 1: You start memory like you could really overanalyze it for like weeks on my phone and I'm still playing it occasionally.
Speaker 0: It's a good pooping game, I think.
Speaker 1: Yeah, good pooping game.
Speaker 1: I think the best thing about this game is that, you know, even compared to something like Lost Cities, it is way more accessible even to not board game people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it would take me five minutes to explain this game to someone who's never played a board game before.
Speaker 1: You can get anyone to play this game and the theme is even accessible.
Speaker 0: Lost Cities requires me to explain a whole bunch of math repeatedly and people still don't get it.
Speaker 1: Right, but the quilt building part, you know, the theme of quilt building is totally chill with everyone, right?
Speaker 1: No one's opposed to quilt making.
Speaker 0: No one's offended by quilts.
Speaker 1: And then it's totally Tetris piece putting together, which is literally the most popular game that you want to play.
Speaker 1: So if you just say, hey, you know, it's like block us, right?
Speaker 1: You can just get anyone to play this.
Speaker 1: And the fact that it's fast and also two player, you know, you don't need to get this whole group of nerds together to make it happen.
Speaker 1: You can just open it up with one person and teach them to play and go.
Speaker 1: I think it's like a super good entry way.
Speaker 1: If you need to get one person into board gaming as a hobby.
Speaker 1: This is like maybe the best game you can get.
Speaker 0: And in general, these games.
Speaker 1: I can't think of another two player one that's as good at that.
Speaker 1: You need
Speaker 0: to bring a few of them anytime you go to a gaming kind of like a PAX, because you're always going to be in a situation where three of your friends are in the middle of a tabletop game and there's and then you're sitting there just waiting for them to finish and another person walks up and you need to keep them in your orbit until the next five player game.
Speaker 1: Get the app on the iPad.
Speaker 1: It's even because then the setup is way faster.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I think I would prefer to play with physical pieces because then they're all out all the time.
Speaker 1: So the app's credit, it lets you scroll around and see all the pieces.
Speaker 0: And when you're zoomed in, it shows you a representation of everything that's left.
Speaker 1: It's like it really lets you look at all the information and it's like.
Speaker 0: The app does as good a job as it can do.
Speaker 0: And it's like 90% there.
Speaker 1: It's like one of the best board game apps I've had ever.
Speaker 0: That's why I'm not complaining about this.
Speaker 1: iPad helps.
Speaker 1: But listen, I play on my phone, no problem.
Speaker 0: But I would prefer it physically just because of the way I play games with extent information like the pieces.
Speaker 1: If I could see being able to see everything at once and not having to scroll to like remember what I just looked at, it would be very helpful.
Speaker 1: But I mean, you're not going to make that happen.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: It's a trade off.
Speaker 0: You can get that holistic extent information experience by playing it physically.
Speaker 0: But then you have to do all the stuff that the game just sort of handles, like counting out the income will slow the game down.
Speaker 1: It's like, OK, what's my income?
Speaker 1: That could suck.
Speaker 0: But it's a good game.
Speaker 0: I'm probably going to buy it.
Speaker 0: I'll add it to my bag of tiny games.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: The Patreon patrons in this episode of Geek Nights in order of the amount of money they earn.
Speaker 0: Chris Minke, Chris Knox, Daniel Redmond, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: You guys are just making this hard for me.
Speaker 0: The anxiety I have trying to say these names and not fuck them up.
Speaker 0: I am real glad that I did not commit to saying all the rest of these names of all the people who are either only given a dollar or actually there's some people who give a lot of money, but just don't want me to say their name.
Speaker 0: That's that's cool, I guess.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I hope you voted and now I leave you with something great.
Speaker 0: I'm laughing for real right now.