Speaker 0: It's Monday, October 31st, 2016.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights tonight on literally the 11th anniversary of the launch of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: We're talking about the great DDoS that lasted about a day and Rym missed because I was in Australia.
Speaker 1: That didn't even last a day.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So yeah, we've been doing this for 11 years, pretty much non-stop.
Speaker 0: It's kind of weird.
Speaker 1: An arbitrary number?
Speaker 1: I mean, was it weird the last episode we did?
Speaker 1: This episode's only a few days newer than that one.
Speaker 0: No, that wasn't weird, but this is weird.
Speaker 1: And the 10th anniversary is also weird.
Speaker 1: Because an arbitrary number has passed, suddenly weirdness enters.
Speaker 0: Have you ever celebrated a birthday?
Speaker 1: What if we used the hexadecimal system instead of the decimal system?
Speaker 0: Ah, but we don't.
Speaker 1: Would it have been weird when we did Show FFF as opposed to- You know why it's weird?
Speaker 0: Because when we started Geek Nights in 2005, a bunch of other people also started podcasts.
Speaker 0: And most of those people are no longer podcasting.
Speaker 0: It is weird.
Speaker 1: What if we were on a different planet that orbited the sun faster or slower, right?
Speaker 1: Just because the Earth went around the sun almost exactly X number of times, right?
Speaker 1: Even then, it still would have been weird because pretty much everyone we knew who started a podcast in those early days of podcasting- If Geek Nights was on Mars, this would be like our, I don't know, Mars goes around the sun a lot slower and farther.
Speaker 0: Have you ever celebrated a birthday?
Speaker 0: Ever?
Speaker 1: Only when I was small.
Speaker 1: Only because I got presents.
Speaker 0: So now you don't celebrate birthdays anymore?
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 0: No?
Speaker 0: Not at all?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: I really don't respect birthdays very much.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: You ever celebrate a holiday?
Speaker 0: What about MagFest?
Speaker 0: That's every year.
Speaker 0: You celebrate that once a year.
Speaker 1: It's not just some arbitrary number.
Speaker 0: It's just an arbitrary day.
Speaker 0: Arbitrary atoms go to an arbitrary place to move arbitrary wooden cubes around.
Speaker 1: No, not at all.
Speaker 0: How is it not arbitrary?
Speaker 1: The universe is there, they're arbitrary and meaningless.
Speaker 1: Because on a birthday, you're basically having a party and the only reason you're having the party is because some arbitrary thing happened.
Speaker 1: MagFest is like,
Speaker 1: "Oh.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, that arbitrary thing being, "I was
Speaker 0: born.".
Speaker 1: You're not making a reason to party.
Speaker 1: You're literally just saying, "Fuck it, it's party time and everybody
Speaker 1: parties.".
Speaker 0: What is a party?
Speaker 0: but just a miserable arrangement of atoms in an arbitrary configuration caused by the causal chain stretching forth from the Big Bang?
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's the 11th anniversary of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: And what's funny about this is that if you're a patron of our Patreon where I've been uploading the hitherto unreleased beta episodes of Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: So if you're a dumb person.
Speaker 0: So the one I just uploaded was actually pretty- It was very loose with your monies.
Speaker 0: Was actually pretty funny.
Speaker 0: I did real- there's a commentary in the upload of the episode.
Speaker 0: But one, the episode was actually pretty good, which was weird because most of those things were terrible.
Speaker 1: Wasn't it like episode four or something?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It was also the last time we used the Logitech stick mic ever.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: At the very, very end of the show.
Speaker 1: So then we went to buy Radio Shack mics?
Speaker 0: We plugged the Radio Shack mic directly into my line in and yelled into it.
Speaker 0: And I yelled, "Jack
Speaker 0: Thompson."
Speaker 0: And then there's a long pause and then you said one word.
Speaker 0: Can you guess what that word was?
Speaker 1: Fear?
Speaker 1: Penis.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: But the funny thing is that the microphone actually sounded way worse at first.
Speaker 0: It took us a while still.
Speaker 0: Those microphones were the worst.
Speaker 0: But the other really funny thing in that episode was that I started talking about how the Red Wings are having a really good season.
Speaker 0: And it was around this time, so pretty early in the season.
Speaker 1: I don't think they won the Stanley Cup.
Speaker 0: So this was the year after the lockout and some rules changes.
Speaker 0: So I was making this argument that the old offensive teams are back.
Speaker 0: The trap is dead.
Speaker 0: You're going to see the Red Wings.
Speaker 0: This is going to be a good year for us.
Speaker 0: You give me this whole long thing about how this is bullshit and I'm being overly optimistic.
Speaker 0: And sure enough, the Red Wings won the president's trophy that year.
Speaker 0: So I was right.
Speaker 1: They didn't win the whole thing?
Speaker 0: No, they lost the Stanley Cup.
Speaker 0: Do you remember who won the Stanley Cup then?
Speaker 1: Eleven years ago?
Speaker 1: What year was this?
Speaker 1: 2005? 2005, 2006.
Speaker 0: Because there was no 2005 Stanley Cup.
Speaker 0: Because of the lockout.
Speaker 0: 2006.
Speaker 1: So it was the lockout year and then the next year.
Speaker 0: It's the next year and there were some rules changes as I recall as well.
Speaker 1: So the Red Wings didn't win.
Speaker 1: So it wasn't a team in the West.
Speaker 0: Scott, it's the president's trophy.
Speaker 0: If you win the president's trophy, you're not going to win the cup guaranteed.
Speaker 1: No, I'm saying it had to be a team in the East because it wasn't the Red Wings who were in the West.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 0: I think it was the Hurricanes actually.
Speaker 1: It sounds right.
Speaker 1: They were good at one point, I remember.
Speaker 1: There was definitely a time where they won and were good for a short period before they got sucky again and stayed sucky.
Speaker 0: Oh, I typed 2006 Hurricanes.
Speaker 0: It's telling me only about actual Hurricanes and not the hockey team.
Speaker 1: Well, then maybe it's not the right one if that's not what you're about.
Speaker 0: NHL.
Speaker 0: Uh, Stanley Cup Finals.
Speaker 0: Stanley Cup Finals location.
Speaker 0: Stanley game four.
Speaker 0: Rostro's Hurricanes.
Speaker 0: The Hurricanes won the Stanley Cup in 2006.
Speaker 0: But if you Google for 2006 Hurricanes, you do not get this.
Speaker 0: You get real Hurricanes.
Speaker 1: You know, the Carolina Hurricanes used to be the Hartford Whalers.
Speaker 0: You know who they were playing against in the final?
Speaker 0: The Edmonton Oilers.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, there are only a few NHL teams that were never good, like Arizona.
Speaker 0: The Blues.
Speaker 1: The Blues are good.
Speaker 1: What are you talking about?
Speaker 1: The Blues have been good.
Speaker 0: Yes, that is true.
Speaker 1: Recently and also long ago.
Speaker 0: Who has never, never, never been good?
Speaker 0: Arizona.
Speaker 0: Have the Sabres ever, they're pretty young, have the Sabres ever been good?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: When?
Speaker 1: There was a time where they were good.
Speaker 0: Best Buffalo Sabres season ever.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: List of Buffalo Sabres seasons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was going to say, you should just look up the list.
Speaker 0: I'll look this up later.
Speaker 0: Lost, lost, lost.
Speaker 0: It looks like they made it to the playoffs a few times.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so, uh, yeah, if you're a patron, you'll get to listen to that beta episode, which is hitherto never been released.
Speaker 0: And the other weird thing about it is Scott talks a lot about politics and Karl Rove and how excited he is about Obama and how he's listened to Obama's podcast.
Speaker 0: It's a different time.
Speaker 1: I don't remember ever listening to Obama's podcast.
Speaker 0: Not only did you listen to Obama's podcast, but you constantly bothered me because I didn't listen to it yet.
Speaker 1: You were like... Well, maybe that'll teach you.
Speaker 1: Everyone should listen to Obama's podcast and you'll realize there's no point.
Speaker 0: I hope Obama starts the podcast up again after he's out of the presidency.
Speaker 1: I hope anyone who has ever been a political leader in the world of insignificant power or wealth makes a podcast.
Speaker 1: Because notice, right, that in terms of like voices you hear in the public, it's usually not the powerful, intelligent people on earth do not communicate with the general public openly or often.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, it's kind of like how we were only ones.
Speaker 1: The only ones who do that are typically like, you know, assholes and evil people.
Speaker 0: There was a conversation in the forum where we were like, "Yeah, you gotta go to Reddit for like your specialized community
Speaker 0: stuff.".
Speaker 0: And people were saying that, "Oh, there's...".
Speaker 0: Like, generally it came about that forums about things out there in the world that aren't on Reddit tend to be super provincial and have bad knowledge because anyone who actually has, for reals, professional or semi-professional skill and pretty much anything tends to just do that thing professionally.
Speaker 1: That's mostly true.
Speaker 1: However, there are, for certain things on earth, there are certain forums or communities have gathered.
Speaker 1: For example, I know that like emergency room staff and like, you know, medical professionals, there's like a secret-ish forum somewhere.
Speaker 1: It may have been a thing of the day once where like...
Speaker 0: I was.
Speaker 0: I remember that thing actually.
Speaker 1: Where they gather.
Speaker 1: Also magicians, there's some forum for magicians somewhere.
Speaker 0: How do you know?
Speaker 0: It might be a trick.
Speaker 1: Possibly, but like, you know, magicians and illusionists, there's a community for them.
Speaker 1: that's somewhere on the internet that like you have to know to get in some... You know, there's various, there's like a handful of ivory towers out there for certain things, but most things, no.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, I guess that's just how it goes.
Speaker 0: But I do want Obama to start a podcast.
Speaker 0: I would listen to that.
Speaker 1: I think he's got better things to do.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's been some hints just from some interviews I've seen him give recently that he's pretty much just waiting to be out of the White House and then he's going to... I think he said something to the effect of...
Speaker 1: He's still the president.
Speaker 1: You can still do stuff.
Speaker 1: Do stuff.
Speaker 0: He said something to the effect of, "I'm going to express what I'm actually
Speaker 0: thinking.".
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Go for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 0: So, you got any news?
Speaker 1: Well, it's Apple Week, so... Usually Apple Day happens like right as we're doing a Monday show, but this time it happened like a few days before.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But that's okay.
Speaker 0: And right on the heels of that Microsoft Surface workstation whatever announcement.
Speaker 1: It's Surface whatever it's called.
Speaker 0: I would consider buying one of those if it weren't for the fact that I also play games and I want a 1080 instead of a 980M, but that's a pretty solid for real professional workstation there with that monitor.
Speaker 1: It's okay.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's hard to get good monitors like that in general.
Speaker 1: The iMac still has a better screen.
Speaker 1: The iMac has way more pixels.
Speaker 1: The iMac just has a wider aspect ratio, right?
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so yeah, Apple announced mostly their MacBook, some useless Apple TV nonsense, but pretty much the MacBook is the news, right?
Speaker 1: So what did they do on the MacBook?
Speaker 1: Everyone was waiting for this, myself included, because like at work, I got a Lenovo like X220.
Speaker 1: It's way old, right?
Speaker 1: But actually there's nothing wrong with it, right?
Speaker 1: It's got the built-in Intel video card thing, which is all you need if you're not doing anything 3D ever, which is I'm at work.
Speaker 1: I'm using SSH, right?
Speaker 1: I don't need Nvidia or ATI, anything, right?
Speaker 1: Even like a 1050 is too much for work.
Speaker 1: It's got an i7.
Speaker 1: It's got SSDs.
Speaker 1: It's got, you know, eight gigs of RAM.
Speaker 1: I can plug my mouse.
Speaker 0: Eight gigs of RAM.
Speaker 0: My laptop from 2009 has eight gigs of RAM.
Speaker 1: That's mostly my problem, right?
Speaker 1: Because I'm using Virtual Box and stuff, I need 16 or 32, but the laptop cannot hold that much.
Speaker 1: It's already full.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, well, the new MacBook is coming.
Speaker 1: It'll probably be, you know, not only be able to have 16 or 32 gigs of RAM, but will be way better than this.
Speaker 1: And I can just switch to that and it'll be fine.
Speaker 0: But no, the general consensus is that the new MacBooks are not significantly more powerful than the old MacBooks.
Speaker 1: No, I mean, that was the big thing, right?
Speaker 1: Is they did a bunch of usual controversial Apple stuff, right?
Speaker 1: They got rid of all the ports except for four USB-C/Thunderbolt ports.
Speaker 0: Which, as many people have already pointed out, four is not enough for the average professional in a creative space.
Speaker 1: Right, so if you're the kind of person who's just taking this thing and walking around town with it, right, that's not really a big deal because, like, yeah, you're going to need a dongle to, like, connect your iPhone to it or, you know, whatever, but you're not really going to plug to or dongle to connect your SD card from your camera.
Speaker 1: But really, you're not going to do too much of that if you're really using it as a notebook.
Speaker 1: But if you're using it at a desk, which a lot of people do, you know, they take their MacBook to work, it's at a desk most of the time plugged into stuff.
Speaker 1: They even showed, demoed and promoted LG making this monitor.
Speaker 1: because, again, if they truly have given up on making standalone cinema displays, even though they're stupid, if they sold 5K cinema displays, I would pay a lot of money, I would just buy them.
Speaker 1: Even for a thousand dollars, people would buy them, but I guess they're saying buy LG's monitor instead.
Speaker 1: So they're showing you that you should take the MacBook and sit down at a desk with this LG monitor plugged into it.
Speaker 1: But then, in the picture they show promoting this, you see just, like, a MacBook next to this monitor.
Speaker 1: They're not showing you the reality, which is you're going to have 10 million dongles in, like, a hub and all this crazy stuff connected to it in this big mess, right?
Speaker 1: They concentrate so much on making the device itself have less holes and be elegant.
Speaker 1: But in real life, what ends up happening is if you have a PC that has a million crazy holes in the back where it's ugly, you have neatly placed wires in the back and nothing in the front.
Speaker 1: And your desk actually looks, as a whole, ends up looking more beautiful than it does if you have a Mac and some sort of, you know, jungle of snakes and dongles all over the place.
Speaker 1: But anyway, Apple has always done that.
Speaker 1: They just did it more extreme.
Speaker 1: And that's really what this MacBook is about.
Speaker 1: It's the trend that Apple has always had for the past X years, according to the Mac, but taken to the extreme, right?
Speaker 1: They've always overcharged you for RAM and storage compared to, like, just buying it from Newegg.
Speaker 1: But now, it's even worse.
Speaker 1: We've waited so long between this MacBook and the last MacBook, the biggest gap, yet it was the smallest incremental upgrade, the biggest price increase, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, for the cost of an upper-end one of these, I could build a goddamn supercomputer.
Speaker 1: So, I went and I'm like, "Maybe I can convince IT to let me just build a
Speaker 1: computer.".
Speaker 1: And I went on Newegg and I'm like-- That's what I did in my office.
Speaker 0: I built a thousand dollar computer at work.
Speaker 0: It's a tiny god.
Speaker 1: I went on Newegg and I'm like, "All right, can I make a work
Speaker 1: computer?".
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Okay, work computer doesn't need a video card.
Speaker 1: I need the tiniest case.
Speaker 1: I need an ITX motherboard with an Intel built-in whatever, right?
Speaker 1: The i5 that has the Intel built-in video card thing, right?
Speaker 1: I need a power supply that fits in the tiny case, 32 gigs of RAM, an SSD.
Speaker 1: That's it?
Speaker 1: I don't think I need anything else, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I work-- A case, a power supply, a CPU.
Speaker 0: I need virtualization because I run a whole bunch of VMs.
Speaker 1: Case, power supply, CPU, one drive, RAM sticks.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Did I forget anything?
Speaker 1: No, for my-- I guess I could put a really-- If I really wanted to, I could spend like $150 and put the weakest Nvidia 1050 video card in there just because it's going to be so cheap.
Speaker 1: So I did this and it only costs like $1100.
Speaker 1: And it's basically a god-- But it's not thin.
Speaker 1: It was actually crazy thin.
Speaker 1: It's not as thin as a MacBook.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But it was crazy thin.
Speaker 1: It was the tiniest case I could find.
Speaker 1: It has a special something SX power supply that's really thin and modular and whatever.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't even know who tweeted it, but they said something like, "The MacBook is revolutionary as a 2012 era gaming
Speaker 0: laptop.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they don't realize that like, "Hey, sure, the Mac is only 10% of your business
Speaker 1: now.".
Speaker 1: But you haven't updated your stupid black Mac Pro trash can since you announced it.
Speaker 0: Yup, and that thing was underpowered when it was launched.
Speaker 1: And you're selling it for $5,000, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You said for $5,000, I wouldn't even know what to spend the last like 800 bucks on building a computer.
Speaker 1: I already got four 1080s in here, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: That's already like a raid of SSDs inside of it, like two terabyte SSDs.
Speaker 1: I've said this and you can go back to old geek nights and I'll be saying the same thing.
Speaker 1: Why don't they just do X?
Speaker 1: They would destroy the entire industry.
Speaker 1: And X is either A, they could just let you sideload apps on the iPhone.
Speaker 1: Android would die immediately.
Speaker 1: It would just be like, "Oh, why use Android now?
Speaker 1: The iPhone is now open.
Speaker 1: We can install any, we can make any software and avoid the app store game
Speaker 1: over.".
Speaker 1: It would just, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, sure, they'd make a little less money selling apps in the app store, but who gives a shit?
Speaker 1: Your competition would be gone.
Speaker 1: Every person with an Android phone, when those phones got old, would buy an iPhone because there's no other choice.
Speaker 0: Half the market for Android phones is people who want to spend like 100 bucks on a phone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can get the iPhone SE.
Speaker 0: That's more than 100 bucks.
Speaker 1: Not the old one.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the other thing they could do is just make a Mac.
Speaker 1: that's like godly, right?
Speaker 1: You could even charge more for it, right?
Speaker 1: You could sell $3,000 worth of hardware for $4,000 or $4,500, right?
Speaker 1: And if it was actually high spec, people wouldn't be complaining.
Speaker 1: If you put a fucking 1080 in there with your 5K screen and 32 gigs of RAM and the best i7 and just max it the fuck out, no one's gonna be like, "Oh,
Speaker 1: $4,000.".
Speaker 1: They're gonna be like, "Well, okay, this would normally be $3,000 if I bought it and built a
Speaker 1: PC.".
Speaker 1: But I'm getting it as a Mac with its amazing engineering and its Apple care and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: It still has the best screen and the best touchpad, right?
Speaker 0: The people who actually care about using this in a professional capacity, only a tiny percentage of them, because this is already a tiny percentage of the market, only a tiny percentage of the people who even buy a MacBook actually need even a baby powerful computer.
Speaker 0: They don't use it for anything except checking their email and maybe some light Photoshop or whatever.
Speaker 1: That's not the Mac Pro, right?
Speaker 1: If you're just doing the light email, you get the iPad, right?
Speaker 0: Nah, usually those people, corporations are very unwilling to buy iPads for their employees.
Speaker 0: They still want a computer.
Speaker 1: If you watch the presentation, they are promoting this as something you would, you know, they don't show people using it to do spreadsheets, right?
Speaker 1: They show people using the MacBook Pro to edit videos, to edit photos in a professional capacity, right?
Speaker 1: They have Adobe on stage, right?
Speaker 1: This is what the MacBook Pro is for.
Speaker 1: That's why it has the word Pro on it and it's not good enough.
Speaker 1: It's a piece of garbage.
Speaker 1: Anyone who actually needs to edit video can't get by with this thing because it's so weak ass, right?
Speaker 1: And it costs more than the alternative.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm saying the market is so small of the people who actually use these things for those purposes.
Speaker 0: I think most people who buy MacBook Pros don't actually use that power that they have, as minimal as it is.
Speaker 1: But here's what's going to happen is all these people who, you know, now are using Macs, like web developers all use Macs.
Speaker 1: The next time it comes around, they're going to be like, well, I guess I'm not getting a Mac just because it's so weak.
Speaker 1: And then when the developers leave, they're going to lose, you know, you can't make it.
Speaker 1: People are only going to have like a Mac lying around for when they need to write an iPhone app or something like that.
Speaker 1: You know, they're going to lose all the support of the community if people actually make shit.
Speaker 1: And that's going to have a negative sort of downwards effect on the rest of everything, right?
Speaker 0: At the same time, I feel like a lot of people who buy Macs already don't really understand that much about the Deepin.
Speaker 0: Like they don't know that much about hardware because they bought a Mac already, like a MacBook Pro.
Speaker 0: They've never been the most powerful laptops.
Speaker 1: But they've been powerful enough, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like if you bought the last generation MacBook.
Speaker 0: I feel like for web developers whose companies just buy these things for them.
Speaker 0: anyway, this is still powerful.
Speaker 1: If you look at the last generation MacBook, it's like, yeah, it was, you know, you could have gotten, you could have always gotten, right?
Speaker 1: A better PC for the same money, but it wasn't so much more money and it was still pretty good at the time, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, OK, that's like a top of the line laptop, basically.
Speaker 1: And you're getting the touch pad in the screen.
Speaker 1: So it's like, yeah, you spend a little bit extra money, but you're getting your money's worth ish, losing a bit extra.
Speaker 1: And they overcharge you on the RAM.
Speaker 1: But hey, it's ECC RAM, which PCs can't even use these days, right?
Speaker 1: But now it's just like, wow, you're just pissing away a thousand dollars for nothing.
Speaker 0: Well, it's thin.
Speaker 0: That's the thing.
Speaker 0: It's super thin.
Speaker 0: There's a point at which, you know, it's like, I still much prefer my old Lenovo because while it's not like an inch thick, but you know what?
Speaker 0: It's small in every other dimension.
Speaker 1: I like thinness and smallness, right?
Speaker 1: If you get the 13 inch MacBook, it's it's smaller and thinner than your Lenovo.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Which is great.
Speaker 1: I love that part.
Speaker 1: But there's a point at which it's like the thinner.
Speaker 1: the extra thinness isn't really any big improvement.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like I'd rather, you know, the regular the previous MacBook size, even, you know, the first all aluminum unibody MacBook was kind of thick.
Speaker 1: It was like, you know, a little under an inch, maybe, you know, by today's standards, it was thick.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like that's still thin enough.
Speaker 1: No one's going to complain about that.
Speaker 1: And if you made it that thick and you loaded it up with like a 10.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: No one's going to give a fuck that it's only three quarters of an inch and not as thin as a sheet of paper.
Speaker 0: I think it's just hard for Apple internally to justify investing in the creator side of things much, because that is a relatively small market compared to the.
Speaker 0: I just use an iPad and look at shit model.
Speaker 0: iPads are way easier for them to sell.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, what's going to happen is all the people who do creative type things like Photoshop and whatnot will move to PCs and they'll be using like their semi custom sandbenders.
Speaker 1: Adobe will stop making like Photoshop for Mac some years, five to, you know, however many years from now.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, people stop.
Speaker 1: all professional creators will stop using it and then they'll won't be tools for the Mac.
Speaker 1: There are all these all the trickle down things that developers and creative people make.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Won't be going down to the Mac consumers and the Mac will become a less attractive platform for consumers as well as professional.
Speaker 0: Also, I noticed that in certain areas, there's a big overlap between gamers and creatives.
Speaker 0: And very few people, I think, are going to get a super expensive Mac for their work life and build a giant gaming PC for the gaming aspect of their life.
Speaker 0: So if you're already a gamer, then you have a super powerful creator workstation at your desktop.
Speaker 0: And if you're already a creator who has used as a Mac, you'd have to buy an entirely separate thousand plus dollar computer to play games because no one makes games on Macs anymore.
Speaker 0: Because not that many people have Macs anymore who play games.
Speaker 1: So, you know, even though initially might only make, you know, a very small number of people upset over the long haul.
Speaker 1: if they don't fix it, it's going to hurt the rest of the environment of Apple.
Speaker 1: People who can code aren't buying Macs.
Speaker 1: Therefore, they're not writing software for Macs and iPhones.
Speaker 0: Well, we famously, and I had to pay out on a bet because I made a bet publicly on Geeknet as many years ago where we argued that Apple was going to end the actual PC style Macs and move to basically just iPads and like shitbooks.
Speaker 0: And they actually didn't.
Speaker 0: And they're still making this stuff.
Speaker 0: But as we've seen here, as this whole news is about, they're barely making them.
Speaker 0: Like a minimum effort.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's intentional.
Speaker 1: Maybe they want the Mac to sell.
Speaker 1: So like if they just cut the Mac off.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Like if they just came out the other day and said, all right, no more Macs for not making money on it.
Speaker 1: Such a small part of our business.
Speaker 1: Fuck it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Then people would be like crazy up in arms.
Speaker 1: But this way they can go.
Speaker 1: And so, you know, a year or two from now, I'd be like, look, we try our best investors to update this Mac and get it to sell.
Speaker 1: You know, and no one bought it and we're losing money on it.
Speaker 1: So now we're justified in ending it.
Speaker 1: And people won't be upset because they won't be Mac users anymore to be upset.
Speaker 1: Everyone will have abandoned the platform already.
Speaker 1: They have to abandon it first, then they can cut it off.
Speaker 1: You can't cut it off and force everyone away from it.
Speaker 0: So in other news, just kind of slightly relevant to the main bit today, but attack vectors for devices like phones or computers or your Internet of Things nonsense.
Speaker 1: Isn't this the main bit?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: So there is an attack vector.
Speaker 0: I think I've mentioned this offhandedly on a couple of big nights, but we haven't really talked about it in depth.
Speaker 0: But there's a lot of apps you can install on your phone that get permission to use your microphone.
Speaker 0: You don't think much about it.
Speaker 1: I know it was.
Speaker 1: if something asked for like GPS, I'm like, I usually just think, do I need this app to know my GPS?
Speaker 1: What is it going to use it for?
Speaker 1: For example, I put the Ticketmaster app and it was like, I want to use a GPS.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, oh, you're going to look for concerts like nearby.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But like if you install some other app, like this is a notepad.
Speaker 1: What are you using the GPS for?
Speaker 1: No, no, you can't.
Speaker 0: It wants access to all your files.
Speaker 0: It wants root on the phone.
Speaker 1: In fact, uninstall because you asked.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: So one interesting attack factor that someone demonstrated a proof of concept for a while ago was that I think accelerometer data is not protected.
Speaker 0: Like any app can get it no matter what.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one gives a shit.
Speaker 0: So someone wrote a clever app that can figure out exactly where in New York City you are pretty accurately.
Speaker 0: If you use the subway at all, it can figure out based on timing and motion with increasing accuracy the longer you're on the subway, exactly what station you're at.
Speaker 1: Interesting.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: How did they do that?
Speaker 0: Because every like different trains and different subways, like there's particular events along the way.
Speaker 0: So if you get enough data, you can sort of just do some.
Speaker 1: But I mean, so they so they collected data originally, like they rode the end train back.
Speaker 0: They collected a bunch of data.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: This is what the vibrations look like on the end train to look for patterns on particular trains, particular stations, particular.
Speaker 1: build up the data first.
Speaker 1: You can just do it from nothing.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like in Britain, how you can use the hum of the mains in the background to identify the time that a video or some audio was recorded.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Similar thing.
Speaker 0: But I mean, that's just.
Speaker 0: that was obviously an academic proof of concept, but basically there's this thing that's been going on for a while where phone apps will listen for sounds in the background that are transmitted subaudibly or inaudibly or high frequency by TVs and screens so that they can figure out like, oh, he's watching the Rangers game right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Or he saw this ad.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So that stuff is not because it's all like private companies doing it.
Speaker 1: And other than the number one company that does it is Shazam, which is why if I need to Shazam some song, I install Shazam, do it and uninstall Shazam.
Speaker 1: So that's like the.
Speaker 1: it's the most advertising like thing.
Speaker 1: That's how they make all their money.
Speaker 0: So there are demonstrable ways to use this as an attack vector.
Speaker 0: And there is, as far as this is an article linking some of the basics of this, there seems to be no rigor into the security of the APIs that look at and respond to this, the sound data.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You can you say no, you don't have mic permission.
Speaker 1: It's on you.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But you might be able to do it other ways.
Speaker 0: What if, you know, if a webcam is plugged into something, if you get access to sound data.
Speaker 1: Well, unplug my webcam for not using it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But this is an attack vector that is very poorly understood and basically no one is looking at it.
Speaker 0: And it's and apparently there's a lot of moves toward using this kind of communication with Internet of Things type stuff because it's really convenient and just works.
Speaker 0: So this is an attack vector that no one's looking at.
Speaker 0: That's probably going to bite us in the butt later.
Speaker 1: Just saying bite me in the butt.
Speaker 1: We'll say I get some hidden microphone.
Speaker 0: You might there might be a device that has a microphone.
Speaker 0: you don't realize.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's you could.
Speaker 1: that would be a real attack vector.
Speaker 1: You sell someone hardware that is hardware in it that they don't know is even in it.
Speaker 0: Or you sell someone.
Speaker 0: I couldn't find the article again.
Speaker 1: You don't know your refrigerator has a camera in it because it's so small and it's in like this tiny hole in the door.
Speaker 1: And now they're spying on you and sending video to the Internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Who's going to even bother trying to figure that out?
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: That doesn't even have to be something at the refrigerator manufacturer.
Speaker 1: That could be someone in a Best Buy installing those in the fridge doors.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They could just do it.
Speaker 0: So someone demonstrated.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to take off the article, but they bought a webcam.
Speaker 0: This happened a couple of times, but there's a really good in-depth story about it.
Speaker 0: Someone bought these webcams like set them up in your house for security and they decided they sucked.
Speaker 0: So they returned them.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: Then like a couple months later, they got an email that was like activity was detected on webcam number four.
Speaker 0: And they were like, what?
Speaker 0: And sure enough, they logged into their account and they could see some other dude's house.
Speaker 1: It was a cloud backed webcam security thing.
Speaker 1: Like most of those things are regular old Logitech webcam security cloud one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Most of those things have problems like that.
Speaker 0: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: So it's an annual tradition on Fark and I'm going to link to two of them just for your reference.
Speaker 1: Oh, Fark.
Speaker 0: I am a big fan of scary stories.
Speaker 0: Now I'm not saying that I believe in ghosts.
Speaker 0: I'm saying that ghostly cool stories are really good.
Speaker 1: I like them if they're actual scary like, but that's pretty rare.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Now my best- I like a good ghost story.
Speaker 1: It's just hard to come by.
Speaker 0: The best source of pretty good ghost stories- I prefer skeleton story.
Speaker 0: Is Fark because every year there's an annual tradition of having a thread where everyone tells scary stories and it's about one third people where something mundane happened to them, but they kind of wigged out for no reason.
Speaker 0: One third weird shit where even the person is like, yeah, pretty sure it wasn't ghosts, but it was a weird freaky thing that I still can't explain.
Speaker 0: And they tell their story and one third people just writing short fiction.
Speaker 0: That's usually pretty good.
Speaker 0: My favorite one of all time is a real story about Fishy.
Speaker 0: Basically it was a dude who- That he knows real.
Speaker 0: No, so the story is- Just comment on Fark.
Speaker 0: So the story is basically- Is it on Snopes?
Speaker 0: I will read the story to the patrons on Patreon as a spooky story.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't pay for that.
Speaker 1: Go to Fark and read it.
Speaker 0: The story is basically- Or don't?
Speaker 1: because who cares?
Speaker 0: A kid growing up, he had some mental issues and basically, you know, some kids will have an imaginary friend?
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: So we had an imaginary friend.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: And just the way the imaginary friend presented in his life is just really unnerving.
Speaker 0: And he just tells the story of like what it was like as a kid, just having this imaginary friend that he kind of couldn't make go away.
Speaker 0: And then when he grew up, like one day it disappeared.
Speaker 0: That was the end of it.
Speaker 0: But it's just really- It's unnerving in ways that-.
Speaker 1: Oh, so the guy who had the imaginary kid is writing the thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he wrote the thing.
Speaker 1: He was like- Or pretending to right now.
Speaker 0: He was like, so guys- It's a first person story.
Speaker 0: Yes, this is what it was like for me with Fishy.
Speaker 0: Growing up with Fishy.
Speaker 1: Okay, so you know how in the olden days, like the 70s and the 80s, comedians would all be like, black men do this, white men do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was the thing.
Speaker 1: That was like the Richard Pryor bit, right?
Speaker 1: Now Scott's bit is police men do this, firemen do that.
Speaker 0: That's like my dad when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: There's a reason firemen come home to their families happy.
Speaker 1: If you go on New York Police Department Twitter, on any given day, you're more than likely to see some post that's like, "There's been an incident.
Speaker 1: We shot somebody.
Speaker 1: News
Speaker 1: coming.".
Speaker 1: Well, if you go on Fire Department Twitter, which I only realized was a thing somewhat more recently, it's like, "Hey, we saved someone.
Speaker 1: Check it
Speaker 1: out.".
Speaker 1: So, you know, usually they save people all the time, you know, usually for medical reasons, right?
Speaker 1: Like, someone will have like, I think the biggest thing they do actually is when some people have heroin overdoses and they go and they jab them with the whatever it's called, right?
Speaker 1: That's like the thing they do the most more than fighting fires.
Speaker 1: But there was a fire, a pretty big fire.
Speaker 1: This apartment building was way on fire.
Speaker 1: Six alarm fire, which means six different fire departments came there, right?
Speaker 1: That's what that means.
Speaker 0: That is what that means.
Speaker 1: People don't know that.
Speaker 1: They're just like,
Speaker 1: "What?".
Speaker 1: You know, they only know about that when they're talking about like chili.
Speaker 1: Like, it's a five alarm chili.
Speaker 1: What does that mean?
Speaker 1: It means you need to call five fire departments to put out the fire.
Speaker 0: That means you need to find five toilets.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Five ladders, five hoses, you know.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so there's a six alarm crazy apartment fire and someone was trapped.
Speaker 1: And this person was in a situation where they pretty much had two choices, which was A, burn.
Speaker 1: Not a good choice.
Speaker 1: B, jump out the window.
Speaker 1: And he was pretty high up, so not a good choice.
Speaker 1: And normally you think, "Oh, well, the firemen would rescue them with like, you know, put the lights
Speaker 1: on.".
Speaker 1: Ladders up to the window, you know, walk up there, take them out of the window, walk down, right?
Speaker 1: Or jump and land in a parachute thing like in Dumbo, whatever.
Speaker 1: But you're imagining, you know, like when you see firemen in movies or TV shows or, you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: And, you know, the window that's burning is like facing the street in New York City.
Speaker 1: That's not how it is.
Speaker 1: You could get a lot of situations like you're trapped between a fire and a window and out the window is like an alley.
Speaker 1: And there's no way the fire truck's getting anywhere near that.
Speaker 1: So what they do, and it's sort of obvious and it's exactly what it sounds like.
Speaker 1: It's the roof rope rescue.
Speaker 1: They practice this apparently all the goddamn time.
Speaker 0: The triple R.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they practice this apparently all the goddamn time because obviously you're going to need it in New York City, which is where they use the ladder to go on the roof.
Speaker 1: They use a rope.
Speaker 1: They repel down the side of the building.
Speaker 1: You grab onto the fireman or a fire, you know, fighter.
Speaker 1: And then they repel to the bottom of the building with you.
Speaker 1: And then you run the fuck away.
Speaker 1: And that's what they do.
Speaker 1: It's exactly what it sounds like.
Speaker 1: But they do it.
Speaker 1: And because they practice so much, it totally worked.
Speaker 1: And they saved this person and did not shoot them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There's a lottery.
Speaker 0: The FDNY is notable too, because it and the Detroit fire department are basically the only two fire departments that engage in a lot of rescue techniques that are actually really dangerous to the firemen themselves.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: This is not, you know, even though.
Speaker 0: Most other fire departments in the entire United States don't do a lot of the things that the FDNY.
Speaker 1: I can't emphasize enough like how much they practice this, which is why they were able to execute it without also getting burned horribly themselves.
Speaker 1: If you're in somewhere like a suburb with a volunteer fire department.
Speaker 0: What they're going to do.
Speaker 1: You need to be roof rope rescued.
Speaker 1: You are probably in deep shit because those volunteers have not practiced it.
Speaker 1: Like it's not their only job.
Speaker 0: But if you live in suburbia, you probably live in a little McMansion or a two story house.
Speaker 0: You can just jump out the window.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's unlikely that you would be in a situation where you, you know.
Speaker 0: But outside of a very small number of municipalities in the US, firemen will primarily just try to prevent the house next door from catching fire.
Speaker 0: If there's a big fire.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, the book club book is still Rebecca.
Speaker 0: I'm going to read it real soon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I will.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'll just blow through it.
Speaker 0: I'm almost done with that World War Two book I'm reading, which goddamn was Yamamoto kind of a shithead.
Speaker 0: But for reasons you wouldn't expect.
Speaker 0: But we are going to be the next convention.
Speaker 0: red is actually Saturday and Sunday, November 12th and 13th.
Speaker 1: That's way soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Gamer X as a game.
Speaker 1: How come we didn't know about this more in advance?
Speaker 0: Well, I knew about it about a month ago when I reached out to them saying, hey, you want some.
Speaker 1: That's pretty late for getting to a convention, but we're there.
Speaker 0: So.
Speaker 0: So we're going to be there.
Speaker 1: It's right around the corner playing games two days.
Speaker 0: But on Sunday, November 13th at three thirty p.m.
Speaker 1: So the end of the convention, basically.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We are going to be doing us in at the end.
Speaker 0: We're going to be doing an updated version of our talk on writing game rules.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, if you live in New York City, you should totally go to.
Speaker 0: this is two days of gaming.
Speaker 1: Why wouldn't you?
Speaker 0: It's like a legit gaming con with legit panels.
Speaker 1: I should tell the net runner people.
Speaker 1: We get some net runner going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And also looking through the list of speakers who are going to be at this thing, there's some highly hidden people here.
Speaker 0: Like, I'm actually kind of surprised and happy that they're letting us do a talk.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So if nothing else, it's just a legit gaming con.
Speaker 0: We're also going to be at Magfest.
Speaker 0: It's too soon to do the roar.
Speaker 0: It's coming.
Speaker 0: I'm saving it.
Speaker 0: Save my laser.
Speaker 0: Between me and Scott.
Speaker 1: Can you hear it over there?
Speaker 1: It's like two months away.
Speaker 0: You can hear it in the distance.
Speaker 0: By God, is that Magfest?
Speaker 1: It's coming.
Speaker 0: Between Scott and I, we're going to be on like seven goddamn panels.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at the schedule.
Speaker 0: There's some good stuff coming.
Speaker 0: Can't talk about it yet because they haven't published the schedule yet.
Speaker 0: But we're going to be doing two or three of our standard lectures, and the rest is going to be me on panels.
Speaker 0: Like, actual panels, as in people talking about a topic where there's more than just me and Scott.
Speaker 0: And I don't know the questions in advance.
Speaker 0: Scott doesn't want to be on any of those panels.
Speaker 0: He'll just be doing the lectures.
Speaker 1: Why would I do a panel when I could play Dig Day?
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll have a thing where, if you beat Scott at Dig Day, you get a prize.
Speaker 0: Oh, we could do a standing... We should definitely do some sort of Geek Nights meetup or whatever at Magfest.
Speaker 0: Like, pick a time to all hang out and do a dumb tournament on some arcade machine.
Speaker 1: I could make a in-person tournament, like a four-game sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, the top ex-finishers of game one, you know.
Speaker 1: Like a little mini, you know, Pro Megathon.
Speaker 0: We've got to find a listener who is good at one of these games to be the mini-boss so they can play people for like three days and then present the four finalists to us.
Speaker 1: Well, high score games are the best because people can just post their high scores.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: So basically, every time you beat the high score...
Speaker 1: And then we get to a final showdown.
Speaker 0: ...tweet it at Scott being like, "Hey, I beat your Dig Dug score, and then we've got to go over there and beat it
Speaker 0: again.".
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That could work.
Speaker 0: Stay tuned.
Speaker 0: We'll sort that out.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, Geek Nights is on Patreon.
Speaker 0: There's stuff in there.
Speaker 0: I'm reading to you, like an audiobook, the entirety of Castlevania II, Simon's Quest, the worlds of power novelization of that game.
Speaker 0: It is weirdly erotic is how I'm going to describe this book.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, Scott is busting out on his YouTube channel.
Speaker 0: I'm continuing to put stuff up on my YouTube channel.
Speaker 1: I realize something, though.
Speaker 1: I have a problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 1: Is that, you know, I don't need your little knob.
Speaker 1: Lack of knob...
Speaker 0: The knob would speed you up more than you think.
Speaker 1: I am not slowing down because the knob, you know, I'm slowing down.
Speaker 1: Rendering?
Speaker 1: No, I just really hate editing things.
Speaker 1: I really like taking photos and taking videos.
Speaker 1: I really do not like, it's like, it's not fun to use Premiere.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like work.
Speaker 1: It sucks.
Speaker 1: I don't want to do it.
Speaker 0: I don't like videoing things.
Speaker 0: I'm good at editing things.
Speaker 1: If somebody else wants to edit videos for me, I can send you so much video footage.
Speaker 1: You could turn into awesome YouTube videos and you would get mad.
Speaker 1: I'll give you money.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to be that guy who gives you exposure.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then I can reduce my Creative Cloud subscription to just the Photoshop Lightroom one and stop paying for Premiere.
Speaker 0: I would do it, but I don't think you want to pay my rates.
Speaker 1: Well, you also do a really shitty job with like, really lame looking fonts that look like some, you know, three-year-old.
Speaker 0: Oh, I would subcontract out infographics and motion graphics.
Speaker 0: That's a separate thing.
Speaker 1: Like your title card is just like...
Speaker 0: You're talking about just audio editing, video editing, that kind of stuff?
Speaker 0: I charge $2.30 an hour.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: So I was in Australia for a couple of weeks and everything was fine.
Speaker 0: And Scott messaged me.
Speaker 1: Well, because of the time zones, I'd pretty much like, you know, if something, you know, above the bar happened in the United States, I would message him assuming he was sleeping and figured I would wake up the next day with a response.
Speaker 0: And you'd scoop everybody.
Speaker 0: And this happened multiple times because actually newsworthy things kept happening.
Speaker 0: And one of those things...
Speaker 1: Well, you were gone for two weeks.
Speaker 1: I assume at least a few newsworthy things would happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The only thing I was sad about is I didn't get to watch the debate live because it was.
Speaker 0: It ended up being at noon on a weekday and I was literally at a meeting for work during it.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: But I watched all these things go down over Twitter except this one because no one in the US could tweet.
Speaker 0: So I couldn't see, like all I could see was the tweet stream of people like coming back online from this massive internet outage, which was actually just a DNS outage.
Speaker 0: And no one knows how to get around basic DNS problems apparently.
Speaker 1: Well, okay.
Speaker 1: So let me tell you.
Speaker 1: So I woke up in the morning.
Speaker 1: I tried to go to our forum and it doesn't work.
Speaker 1: It says, like, can't find server.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, what?
Speaker 1: I'm like, is vanilla having a problem?
Speaker 1: So I tried to go to some other sites and some of them work and some of them don't.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, that's weird.
Speaker 1: So, you know, there are other sites that aren't working, but there are some sites that are working.
Speaker 1: What's the difference?
Speaker 1: So I'm like, all right.
Speaker 1: Step one, dig our forum.
Speaker 1: And it's a. I'm using Google's, you know, DNS servers.
Speaker 1: Eight, eight, eight, eight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: And it says, nope, can't find no IP for that.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, oh, that doesn't sound right.
Speaker 1: But wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I was able.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like.
Speaker 1: I couldn't contact the DNS server.
Speaker 1: The DNS server said, I don't know what IP that is.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, why don't you know?
Speaker 1: So I check with the registrar and everything is kosher.
Speaker 1: So I didn't fuck anything up.
Speaker 1: No one stole our domain or anything.
Speaker 0: Those things can happen.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Like even to smart people.
Speaker 1: Even though I secured it way good.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So then I'm like, all right, what else is going on?
Speaker 1: So I dig some other domains that are working and I get IPs back.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, OK, so the Google DNS server is actually working just fine.
Speaker 1: It must be something upstream is not in.
Speaker 1: the hierarchy is messed up.
Speaker 1: And I knew it was a DNS problem.
Speaker 1: So I start go to Twitter because whenever there's a problem that's like super fast, you're not going to find news on Google News for like another hour.
Speaker 1: You got to go to Twitter.
Speaker 0: But Twitter's got nothing.
Speaker 1: It was one of the things that were down.
Speaker 1: So I don't know where to search now.
Speaker 0: You know what sucks?
Speaker 0: In the old days, like if we were still at RIT, we'd all get into an IRC or something or like Napster chat.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So I start.
Speaker 1: I basically go around to news sites until I find something that's up.
Speaker 1: Reddit was having trouble.
Speaker 1: I found some some news source and it was like, yeah, big time DDoS attack against DYN DNS.
Speaker 0: DYN DNS provides DNS to a lot of people.
Speaker 0: because remember, DNS is just this framework.
Speaker 0: The only like the only official DNS servers are the 13 root servers that say, yo, internet that way.
Speaker 1: So it's like, yeah, it's like, sure.
Speaker 1: All DNS does is let us use names for servers instead of IP addresses.
Speaker 1: If I remember the IP address to the forum, I could have just typed it in and gone there.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But who fucking remembers the IP address?
Speaker 0: Well, you know what?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: The Internet would totally work without DNS if everyone remembered and hard coded IP addresses like.
Speaker 1: you have to remember that Google is one, two, three, four, whatever it is.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's not one, two, three, four.
Speaker 1: It's like the whole point of names.
Speaker 0: And the old days was that humans, you know, you would remember names, which is funny.
Speaker 0: because now like we got to don't anymore like DNS is not used the way it was used in the early days.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like DNS names now are just soft links pointers to where the real thing is.
Speaker 0: So the real thing can move and they're the tie to your SSL certificate.
Speaker 0: Like those are the only things that it's really used for in the modern era.
Speaker 0: So like these extra top level, we've talked about DNS.
Speaker 0: I don't want to get too into that, but, uh, the funny thing is if we were still living in beacon when this would happen, when this happened, we would have been fine because back then we ran our own DNS server with caching.
Speaker 1: Someone wrote this great article that was like, Hey everybody, this should teach you a lesson.
Speaker 1: I know that none of you were going to read this and learn this lesson or change what you're doing.
Speaker 1: You're going to still do things the wrong way, but everyone is setting their DNS TTL is way too short.
Speaker 1: You got to Jack them up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But why do you set it so short?
Speaker 0: You don't change that often.
Speaker 1: People set their TTLs short so that when it is time to change, they can change it and have the change happen really quickly.
Speaker 1: Whereas if you set your DNS TTL to something reasonable, like a day, eight hours, something like that, then if you need to change to different server infrastructure and move your DNS, you have to wait eight fucking hours to do this changeover thing.
Speaker 1: It's just like, it sucks at that one moment.
Speaker 1: So just to make your life more convenient, that one rare time you actually have to do something, you basically throw away the, you know, you're basically telling every DNS server on earth, Hey, don't remember my IP address for very long, right?
Speaker 1: You know, just throw it out after a few minutes and then look it up again.
Speaker 1: And what this does is a, if shit goes down, all these DNS servers around the earth, forget your IP address and have to ask for it again.
Speaker 1: And if you're down, you're down.
Speaker 1: And to, uh, it creates a lot of bandwidth.
Speaker 1: There's all these extra DNS requests now going farther up the hierarchy of the DNS infrastructure that could make their way all the way up to root and back down.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They could have just hit like a server, you know, for example, you know, if I ask what, you know, I'm asking Google's DNS, but let's say you, most of you are using your IP ISPs, DNS, like you're asking time Warner or charter or whoever.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So, or Verizon on my iPhone, like you're using Verizon, right?
Speaker 1: So it would just ask Verizon and get an answer.
Speaker 1: But if my TTL is five minutes, five minutes later, Verizon is going to have to ask my DNS provider for the IP again.
Speaker 1: Whereas if I would have just told Verizon, Hey, remember that shit for like a day, it would only ask my server once a day for every Verizon user.
Speaker 0: Now around this is what I would do in the past when I used to administer to this sort of thing.
Speaker 0: is I would set up granted.
Speaker 0: This is an older time, like shit's moved fast, but I would have pretty long TTLs, but I would set it shorts in advance of coming changes.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But if you know you're doing some sort of release and you're really clever and well-organized, you can set it short a day in advance.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Or well, far enough in advance, like two weeks in advance.
Speaker 1: Then after, you know, it's good set, you know, and you're stable with the new environment, set it long again.
Speaker 0: Now here's the trouble.
Speaker 0: Some people set it short for failover disaster recovery ways so that they can quickly redirect in a failover, which you literally cannot schedule.
Speaker 0: But if you care about uptime that much, you should have dynamic IPs to begin with.
Speaker 0: Like there are not dynamic IPs in the classic sense.
Speaker 0: You should have, there are special IPs you can get that you can sort of reroute on the fly, even on the Internet or like within your organization, you can get layer three switches that perform like switches.
Speaker 1: But Amazon, Amazon Web Services has elastic IPs where if one of your servers, you can buy basically an IP address and point it at a server.
Speaker 1: And now that server has that IP.
Speaker 1: And if that server completely sets on fire, you need to make a new server.
Speaker 1: You can move that IP to the new server.
Speaker 1: So
Speaker 0: one thing I'm going to do, because I'm going to have a spare computer soon when I fairly soon start upgrading all my biz is I'm probably gonna start running a local DNS server again with caching, because that actually is a big performance boost, especially if you're accessing sites where DNS queries are slow and it would have protected you from.
Speaker 1: But if you if you override the TTLs that they send you with, you know, your own longer TTL, you could end up in situations where if something happens to them, you think they're down and you go to is up dot me and they go, oh, no, they're up.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And you're like, oh, shit.
Speaker 1: And you got to flush your DNS cache.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I could put I could run a squid proxy, too, and just go double.
Speaker 1: That's you know, then you're getting websites that aren't even update.
Speaker 1: You're getting like an old version of the news because it hasn't been updated yet.
Speaker 0: Because I want to do it just because I haven't.
Speaker 0: I haven't run that kind of structure in a long time.
Speaker 0: So I want to see what the current state of it is.
Speaker 0: If there's anything clever I can do, it's I couldn't do in the past.
Speaker 1: You know, the best thing you can do with it is you can offload ad blocking off of your own computer to the computer and you can do ad blocking.
Speaker 1: That's even better than, you know, for example, like if you know there's a certain ad server, you can just block all traffic to it.
Speaker 1: And now it doesn't matter what browser you're using or like if you're using a phone or any any.
Speaker 1: every single device on your network will not have that ad server completely blocked because you blocked it at this sort of proxy level.
Speaker 0: So what actually happened here, as best we can tell, is it was a simple.
Speaker 1: Still don't know who did it or why.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I read some evidence that it's probably some script kiddies who took advantage of things that may have been placed by state sponsored actors because the mirror, the Mirai malware.
Speaker 1: So I heard about the tools.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So we don't know the user of the.
Speaker 0: that's the one that the source code got leaked recently.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: We don't know the user of the tools or the motivation for using them to attack DineDNS specifically, but we do know that the tool was like made open source recently.
Speaker 1: And usually what happens is somebody will you know, people who are like the real black cats of the world will make evil tools.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But since they made those evil tools, if they use them now, they can sort of be found by like the intelligence community is like, ah, this is the tool that was used.
Speaker 1: It must have been rim made that tool.
Speaker 1: So what you do is while you're still anonymous, you sort of make your tool open source.
Speaker 1: So plausibly anyone could have used it.
Speaker 1: And now when you use it, you know, they don't know who it was.
Speaker 1: It could have been anyone because it's some open source tool.
Speaker 1: Now, the malware itself is nothing special, except that I imagine if like you make it you had a gun and you're going to shoot somebody.
Speaker 1: But if you do that, they're like, aha, this was the gun used in the murder and it's got fingerprints on it.
Speaker 1: Like, shoot.
Speaker 1: So you make a billion infinity identical guns and hand them out to everybody.
Speaker 1: And now it could have been any one of us.
Speaker 1: Everyone has that gun.
Speaker 0: So in the old days, malware like this, when you activated a botnet because the machines that had this were bought, they're part of a botnet effectively, they would themselves initiate the DDoS, however it was run.
Speaker 0: That is old style.
Speaker 0: This botnet is a meta command and control layer that would, when activated, itself go out and activate a giant legion of even dumber bots.
Speaker 0: And it appears that those bots were almost entirely Internet of Things nonsense, fridges and DVRs and cameras and shit.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So people are using PCs less and less these days.
Speaker 0: So this actually reduced the effectiveness of bots.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: There's still lots of PCs out there.
Speaker 1: I'm sure you can make a nice botnet out of Chinese PCs or whatever, but, you know, and people are going to things like Windows 10, they're upgrading, they're using OS X more and such.
Speaker 1: So there are less vulnerable PCs in the wild to make a bot to, you know, infest and make a botnet.
Speaker 0: I mean, how many people actually pirate Adobe software to join that botnet?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's a large number, but it's not that many.
Speaker 1: It's not as many as it used to be.
Speaker 0: It's not as many as the traffic that goes to the sites you're trying to DDoS on a normal basis.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And not only that, but it's like if you attack PCs, there's not so many users of them.
Speaker 1: You know, they're not even a good target, even though you do like.
Speaker 1: the thing that's nice about attacking PCs is that they're really powerful.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, if you get one PC, that's as good as getting like six phones.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so people have phones and tablets now and those are actually also if they're running, you know, modern Android, iOS, you know, they're kind of hard to infect.
Speaker 0: You got to go out of your way to get infections on these devices.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, you can, you know, you know, the security patches for them usually come out pretty quick.
Speaker 1: And while there are various vulnerabilities, there's always those like pwn to own events.
Speaker 1: Usually you have to like have access to the device to own it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like something that you can get through the lock screen.
Speaker 0: or if they visit a shady website and do a thing or the speakers are running and then they get that sound gap thing I talked about earlier.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like it's really it's.
Speaker 1: you know, it's not easy to make a botnet out of iPads.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's pretty tricky.
Speaker 1: So what do you make a botnet out of these days?
Speaker 1: And that is devices that are Internet connected.
Speaker 1: that aren't people don't realize.
Speaker 0: So think about your like shit ass router that you get with your Internet service provider like five or six years ago.
Speaker 1: They never updated the firmware on it ever.
Speaker 0: It came with the default username and my password.
Speaker 1: Even my fancy router hasn't had a firmware update in.
Speaker 1: I don't even know when.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Now think about if you go on Amazon and buy some random TiVo knockoff and just plug it into your home Internet and it just works.
Speaker 0: Well, you don't know what the fuck's running on that or what it's doing.
Speaker 0: How would you even know if it was compromised?
Speaker 0: At least your computer might run slow.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And let's say you go to the store and you buy like, you know, some home Internet security device.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So these kinds of devices that people make, they're using it.
Speaker 1: You know, how do you make something like this?
Speaker 1: There's certain features you want, like maybe a garage door opener for your house.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: So say you want to control that garage door opener from your phone.
Speaker 0: That's a cool thing to sell to someone.
Speaker 0: Either the phone has to connect directly to it, which is not going to work, which it does.
Speaker 1: It could work, but it's just too difficult to make that work.
Speaker 0: So even if they did make it work, it would be just as insecure.
Speaker 0: What you're to run jetty in there, have some Apache running on.
Speaker 0: But like there'd be a server that no one updates.
Speaker 1: You'd have to have like a whole computer in your garage door opener.
Speaker 0: That's fancy that no one's going to be.
Speaker 1: the person in their car has to know how to connect to it with Wi-Fi or with Bluetooth or something complicated.
Speaker 1: And there's like a whole process they have to go through.
Speaker 1: And that's not going to work.
Speaker 1: You need a situation where the person pushes a button and the door opens.
Speaker 1: And it's simple.
Speaker 1: And the only way to do that architecturally is to say, OK, the garage door opener connects to the Internet with Wi-Fi, their phone connects to our server.
Speaker 1: They visit a Web page on our server.
Speaker 1: They log in, they press a button, and then we connect to the.
Speaker 1: we know who it is.
Speaker 1: So we know it's garage door opener.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: So we connect to the garage door opener of the Internet and open it.
Speaker 0: Now, there's nothing wrong with this in theory.
Speaker 0: I mean, you could make that possibly secure, just some SSL and basic security principles.
Speaker 1: There's a way to make it secure.
Speaker 0: But usually it's all clear text like like security is not even the last concern when they make these devices.
Speaker 0: It is not thought about at all.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Think about a college project.
Speaker 0: We have to write an app to do something like this.
Speaker 0: You send a clear text, not even a password.
Speaker 0: You just send a command and you get the act back and then you submit the code and get your B. That is what's running on these devices.
Speaker 1: So now you have an evil bot and the evil bot just goes around the Internet looking at IP addresses, trying to figure out what device is at that IP address, what what's it running, what's it doing?
Speaker 1: So it goes around the Internet.
Speaker 1: It's just hitting stuff, you know, pinging and ponging and whatever.
Speaker 1: And it says, oh, here's an IP address and there's a device here.
Speaker 1: What kind of device is this?
Speaker 1: Let me scan all the ports.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's a Sonmai Technologies DVR.
Speaker 0: Well, I know the hard coded username and password for that.
Speaker 1: Let me try to log into this DVR.
Speaker 1: Oh, look, I've logged into this DVR.
Speaker 1: I'm not even a real person.
Speaker 1: I'm just searching the Internet for things.
Speaker 1: And this is one of the things that I'm pre-programmed to know about.
Speaker 1: I have now connected to it.
Speaker 1: I have full access to it.
Speaker 1: I will install this software on it and it will continue to do its DVR thing until such a time as I tell it to attack DynDNS.
Speaker 0: I saw multiple people I know who are smart when the DDS happened afterward.
Speaker 0: They did things like start doing a packet capture of their Internet traffic egress and seeing, wow, 60 megabits a second coming out of my DVR.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All those smart TVs that people buy because they have like Netflix built in.
Speaker 1: They don't to buy.
Speaker 0: My TV has a network and ethernet port on the side of it is never getting plugged in, never getting plugged into anything ever.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So it's like, yeah.
Speaker 1: If that phone doesn't keep getting that TV, doesn't get updated with security updates and such.
Speaker 1: And, you know, it's like they wrote software for it once they shipped it.
Speaker 1: They were done with it.
Speaker 1: They don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, the only TVs that update are the ones that are updating to show you ads in the menus.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm only getting hits.
Speaker 1: I get monitors, not TVs.
Speaker 1: But anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Someone just take over your TV and you're watching TV.
Speaker 1: But meanwhile, the TV itself is attacking, sending spam or something.
Speaker 1: You don't even know.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And I don't know when this I mean, this is the technology exists for this all to work fine.
Speaker 0: It's just the consumers of these devices, at least a consumer of a PC or a tablet or something else, has some level of understanding as to what that device is capable of.
Speaker 0: But when they buy like a garage door opener, they do not make the leap to this is a computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So they don't even know there could be a problem.
Speaker 1: They're selling fridges at the Home Depot and those fridges have Android running on them.
Speaker 1: And no one really pays attention.
Speaker 1: And, you know, people get upset if their Android phone doesn't get updated to the newest candy, whatever it is, kick cats or, you know, jujubes or whatever the fuck.
Speaker 1: But you don't care of a shit about updating the Android on your fridge.
Speaker 0: So back it up to the actual response as a human to the DDoS.
Speaker 1: And now your fridge is spying on someone's email.
Speaker 0: Even if you had your caching DNS, a lot of the services you might have tried to access were failing anyway because internally they relied on DNS as well.
Speaker 0: And a lot of time that internal DNS has the exact same problems, the extra like a lot of Linux servers.
Speaker 0: If you set up a Linux server and you just kind of slapdash about it and you don't put like at least a reference to localhost or your own IP address or something in your host file, usually that's there by default.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's easy to fuck that up.
Speaker 1: or how could you fuck that?
Speaker 0: I have witnessed more than once overly clever admins saying, why would I have an entry for this in my home?
Speaker 1: And removing pretty sure in Ubuntu, actually, if you don't, it does it by default.
Speaker 1: It does it by default.
Speaker 1: And if you don't have the hostname entry in the host file, when you do certain things like sudo, it'll be like, hey, yep, why don't you have this?
Speaker 0: A lot of Linux like certain software, like in the boot sequence even, it'll just wait forever and eventually time out on stuff because it tries to initialize something that needs localhost or needs IP access before the DNS stuff activates and actually starts looking stuff up.
Speaker 0: But the only solution to that is like the best practice is if you run a real network, even though you want stuff to be dynamic, if you have like a critical front end web server that accesses a critical back end database server, you should have fucking host name, host files pointing directly at those internal IPs on the servers and you just have scripts that change those in the event of a failover.
Speaker 0: You also use the also.
Speaker 1: that gets you a lot of performance improvement because you're saving all this DNS traffic.
Speaker 0: That does.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you what I used to do with this complex system involving some middleware, some TibRV.
Speaker 0: And we found that just by putting with no other changes, just by putting standard host files that had all the core systems internal to our network in those host files, we got like a 10 percent performance improvement.
Speaker 1: If there's a website that you visit like crazy often, like say Google.com, it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like if you do a dig for Google.com, you're going to get a ton of IPs back and it changes pretty frequently based on where you are.
Speaker 0: There's load balancing and all this kind of stuff that goes on.
Speaker 1: But odds are, if you pick just a Google IP that like you got when you're at your house, that IP is going to keep working for quite a long time.
Speaker 1: If you just put it in your host file, you're going to have a much faster Google.com for until it stops working.
Speaker 0: In fact, way back, remember when there was a lot of trouble in New York years ago with YouTube like not working?
Speaker 1: I don't do that though.
Speaker 1: I'm too lazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But remember, YouTube like wouldn't work that well.
Speaker 0: Like you get the first 10 seconds of a video and then you couldn't watch the rest of it.
Speaker 1: That was a short period of time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It was messed up.
Speaker 0: While that existed, if you were clever, you could use host files to force your usage of YouTube from like beyond the caching servers to the back end to only use the nodes that were probably working.
Speaker 0: And that made the YouTube situation better.
Speaker 0: And then it broke everything later because, you know, that stuff changes.
Speaker 0: But, you know, I mean, it's, you know, those files are something that you should use because they're a powerful weapon.
Speaker 0: But also remember that you use them.
Speaker 1: The DNS failover is a good strategy, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, you have your DNS, you know, look and you could even do geo stuff these days where it's like, aha, this user who's asking for the IP address of front recruit dot com, they are in New York.
Speaker 1: So I will tell them this answer.
Speaker 1: Oh, this person is in Bulgaria.
Speaker 1: I will tell them a different answer because I have a different Web server in that part of the world and it will be faster for them.
Speaker 0: or like put your SSL up on Cloudflare and use that.
Speaker 1: The Cloudflare does.
Speaker 1: That's one of the things Cloudflare can do.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Cloudflare is actually pretty good.
Speaker 1: Amazon Route 53 can also do this.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So many things that can do this.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like it's like a standard feature these days.
Speaker 1: But, you know, or it's like, oh, the DNS server will say, aha, this server is down.
Speaker 1: I will tell them the IP address of a server that is up instead.
Speaker 1: But if your TTL is really long, that kind of feature doesn't work because the person, you know, the server goes down, they try to visit it.
Speaker 1: They get the cached IP address, which is the IP of the server that's down.
Speaker 1: And they see that you're down and they never.
Speaker 1: they never ask you for the new IP address till the TTL is over.
Speaker 1: And if your TTL is like eight hours, you're going to be down for if you don't bring that server back up at the same IP, you're going to be down for eight hours for that person, even if you're up for other people who aren't caching the DNS as long.
Speaker 0: So what are the takeaways from this?
Speaker 0: to kind of wrap up the show, put a nice little bow on it, be done because I'm kind of hungry other than the fact that the Internet of Things is is the Internet of shit right now and you really just should not use any of those devices.
Speaker 1: or unless you are an expert or if your only choice is to get a device that has these features disabled and do not use them and do not connect your device with Wi-Fi or Ethernet to the Internet, use it without connecting it.
Speaker 1: And if that's not possible, find a different device that will work.
Speaker 1: I think you can't.
Speaker 0: I think the consumer side of it just can't be dealt with.
Speaker 0: So I feel like.
Speaker 0: I feel like the government actually should have the capacity to force those nodes offline.
Speaker 0: Like if your house is issuing a video as fuck you, that's a good thing.
Speaker 1: Also, I think the government should be able to force companies that make devices to either a issue software updates or be forced them to release their code to the public so that somebody can fix them.
Speaker 1: If you're not going to update the software and your Internet connected like that, you know, they regulate.
Speaker 1: the FCC is like, hey, you can't interfere or, you know, must accept all interference, the same kind of regulation.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You must update to be secure.
Speaker 1: If a vulnerability is found that is affecting the whole Internet, you're interfering.
Speaker 1: Your device is illegally interfering.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Or B, you must at least open source it so that somebody else can, you know.
Speaker 0: But I'm OK.
Speaker 0: I'm totally OK with counter strikes disabling these devices remotely.
Speaker 0: And if consumers complain, well, they can take it up with the company they bought the garbage from.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And if that company doesn't exist anymore.
Speaker 0: And in terms of the impact of the Internet, it's so.
Speaker 1: it's so cyberpunk.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: The garage door openers, they're hacking.
Speaker 0: I used to have garage door openers.
Speaker 0: I was in middle school.
Speaker 1: My restaurant is down.
Speaker 1: I can't pay.
Speaker 1: I lost all my money.
Speaker 0: I went around because garage door openers usually like when I was a kid, there'd be like two or three or maybe if you were fancy.
Speaker 1: Oh, the thermostat stole my money from a bank account.
Speaker 0: I will realize that I really happens.
Speaker 0: I will raise the temperature of your apartment by one degree Fahrenheit every hour until you give me a Bitcoin.
Speaker 1: Listen, that's a real world thing.
Speaker 0: That there's a proof of concept.
Speaker 0: Someone wrote that malware.
Speaker 0: It exists.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: This isn't something that, you know, it is something out of a novel, but also for reals.
Speaker 1: Absolutely.
Speaker 1: For real.
Speaker 1: For reals.
Speaker 1: Earth.
Speaker 1: Not some fantasy world of Snow Crash, but also some fantasy world.
Speaker 0: But luckily, the impact to the U.S.
Speaker 0: Internet was negligible.
Speaker 0: Everything was back up pretty quick.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, you know, when something that big goes down, the top men are on the top men top.
Speaker 0: I have been on the other side of those sort of situations in the past, like when I used to work at IBM.
Speaker 1: You're not top.
Speaker 0: No, but I was.
Speaker 1: I was like you're at best mid.
Speaker 0: I have been in like response teams to stuff like this.
Speaker 0: And usually the answer is you just kind of sit there and monitor it and either sort of manually start to figure out ways to identify the bad traffic and block it.
Speaker 0: or you say, fuck it, pull the cord and wait for real top men to deal with it.
Speaker 1: I always that's always my solution to everything is like, hey, I'm paying people at like the real places like Amazon or whatever.
Speaker 1: They'll fix it and they'll let me know.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: I don't have to do shit.
Speaker 1: I got nothing to do with it.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rym and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights in order the amount of money they give you to make bases are Ellen Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Nicholas Brando, Heidi McNichol, Amanda Duchette, Christian Koons, Construction Noises, Ivy Faye, MyStacy.com, William Eisneros, Jeremy Miner, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: Chris Hahn and Thomas Reimer.
Speaker 0: You fucker.
Speaker 0: Sharon Van Hor, Leaky Kid, Rare Lavell, James David White, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, Irish Wristwatch, Aaron Cerise, Brian Fisher, Sailor Vister, Jai Friedpork, Matthew Smith, Don Schleich, Jarth Tovjian, Joshua Joestar, Teller, Ella Shenjager, Sam Cordry, Clinton Walton, Run From New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Booz, Scared Yalander, Brian Sidroni, Finn Eric Silveroff, The Rural Juror, Chris Minkoff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: I can't believe it's the 11th anniversary of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: We've been doing this for a fucking long time.
Speaker 0: We have like 1100 episodes up.
Speaker 0: We've done 40 panels at PAX's.
Speaker 0: And so what I leave you with is I'm actually going to read for you right now the slightly unnerving story of Fishy from Fark.
Speaker 0: The story was originally posted on Fark by the user Quexy, Q W E X Y. Psychosis or ghost story?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: When I was little, probably about four or five years old, I had an imaginary friend, I think.
Speaker 0: It was yellow and about four feet tall, taller than me at the time, bipedal and had oversized eyes that always looked straight ahead.
Speaker 0: otherwise, relatively human and naked.
Speaker 0: I called the thing fishy.
Speaker 0: The weirdest thing, though, it was that it scared the hell out of me.
Speaker 0: I didn't want anything to do with it.
Speaker 0: And I couldn't imagine as a child that it was coming from inside my head.
Speaker 0: It walked or more like skated along on the walls in the rooms of our house and apparently could not leave those surfaces.
Speaker 0: I knew that if I played outside, it could only follow me to the limits of the garage.
Speaker 0: It always followed me, too, even though I often told it not to.
Speaker 0: I had difficulty concentrating on drawing things or reading because fishy was always standing somewhere on the wall, looking over my shoulder.
Speaker 0: It did not ever sit down.
Speaker 0: It didn't ever have facial expressions and it never made any noise.
Speaker 0: The only times I ever interacted with fishy when I was sick in the middle of the night or when I woke up panicked from nightmares.
Speaker 0: Those times, if I looked at it intently, fishy would methodically start drifting along the wall toward my parents bedroom, around the corner, out the door, down the hall.
Speaker 0: As soon as it was out of sight, I start calling for my mom, as in, "Mom, I'm going to
Speaker 0: barf.".
Speaker 0: And she drove quickly, "God bless you, Mom," to help me through it.
Speaker 0: Fishy would come back, though, as soon as I'd recovered.
Speaker 0: Then it would stare at me for the rest of the night, two days or longer, staring then in the direction of my parents room.
Speaker 0: It finally vanished when my sister was born in 1992.
Speaker 0: I was almost eight years old by then and I'd been ignoring fishy for about a year, but not so much that I didn't notice.
Speaker 0: he learned to fly off the wall and visit the floor from time to time.
Speaker 0: There was one instance in the last two months of fishiness when I saw it at someone else's house, a new home that friends of mine, two sisters were moving into.
Speaker 0: Their father walked into the room and we were there playing with the moving boxes.
Speaker 0: he'd given us one another, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: And in the darkened laundry room behind me, or behind him, filling the entire doorway at many times its normal size was fishy, staring down at the father's back.
Speaker 0: It wasn't scary so much as irritating.
Speaker 0: We moved away from there less than a year later.