Speaker 0: It's Thursday, June 29th, 2016.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight The Lost Village anime that well, it's an anime.
Speaker 0: All right Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well, it was about that time of year.
Speaker 0: so I Started doing the thing that I do every few months and I changed all my passwords and I had a few like shit accounts that I hadn't really bothered with for a while.
Speaker 0: So I basically did the password Two-factor everything refresh off everything I got, you know to be honest Like I keep bothering other people about like their passwords and you haven't changed your passwords in years.
Speaker 1: Have you all the ones that have two-factor?
Speaker 1: I trust the two-factor too much and I don't change the passwords that often but they are really really good password Yep, so actually what I did is I because you know what?
Speaker 0: I usually do that the best when I have it.
Speaker 1: also I am very good.
Speaker 1: I have a different password for everything as do I there's.
Speaker 1: no there's no two things that have the same unless they're really stupid.
Speaker 1: Right, like I don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: But yeah like I let's see I have I have two or three stupid throwaway passwords that I use for like literally Garbage account on a website because I have to log in to see you sound like a post and I'll never go to it Exactly.
Speaker 0: Yep, or like shitto forum or whatever.
Speaker 0: But the one interesting thing is that whenever I do this and you're right as much as I talk about like me too Like change your passwords all the time and all that.
Speaker 0: I don't change my passwords that off.
Speaker 1: I should go through and change them all though.
Speaker 0: It was about time because there's been like the longer you wait.
Speaker 0: There's like this accretion of hashes.
Speaker 1: I want to switch to pass phrases because they're easier to remember and even more secure but some websites don't let you pass phrase.
Speaker 0: So here's the problem.
Speaker 0: I ran into.
Speaker 0: actually I wanted to do the thing that I used to do when I was young.
Speaker 0: I stopped doing because it was a pain and I wanted to do it again.
Speaker 0: And what I stopped doing was my passwords were very very long But they were and they were pretty similar to each other But they had some differences that I could figure out that no one else obviously could.
Speaker 0: So it's like a really good password and every site has a unique password.
Speaker 0: But the problem was everyone started adding password complexity rules and everyone had different bullshitty rules.
Speaker 0: So like some sites are like it has to have a number in a letter.
Speaker 0: some sites are like it has to have a number And the number can't be the first or the last Character.
Speaker 0: and some sites like gotta have a special character, but other sites won't let you put in special characters.
Speaker 0: So I literally could not make a password that would match all the sites that I use.
Speaker 0: so I have a bullshitty password for a few things mostly like health insurance and all those things because those are like my Government stuff like New York State tax stuff for the old gig nights sales tax thing Because they literally like their password.
Speaker 0: rules are like it can't be less than six characters But it can't be more than eight characters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're very.
Speaker 1: the thing is nowadays.
Speaker 1: They're actually very few Sites that have this problem right like I think like certain credit card and banks still have the stupid Requirement and almost every government site right but most wet like Twitter and all modern websites Google Passphrase work.
Speaker 1: so my recommendation for passphrases is there's a thing called dice where and basically dice where is a bunch of tables In different languages and you roll dice and that picks words and you pick some number of words And that's your passphrase.
Speaker 1: so for example.
Speaker 1: I'm at rempeh us.
Speaker 1: Which is the basically the dice where website yeah?
Speaker 1: And I'm push the button to generate a six word dice where a passphrase.
Speaker 1: so my passphrase is Mac Alpha RT as in the letter R the letter T earl as in the earl of something Basin fort.
Speaker 1: so Mac alpha RT earl basin for you could remember that because you're only remembering six things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you type that like maybe ten times It'll be quit pretty well stuck in your brain and according to the math here It will take four millennia for modern computers to figure that one out Even without any capitals and numbers or anything.
Speaker 0: so basically what I have is a passphrase But it's salted with a bunch of different things that I'll know What those things would be for any given website or account.
Speaker 1: it's not even necessary if you just use the past the dice where?
Speaker 0: But then it's the same password for everything or you have to memorize.
Speaker 0: you memorize a bunch of different passphrases But there if they're completely different.
Speaker 0: I would not bother because I have like I counted because I did this I have 34 unique accounts on shit online that I care about in some fashion I think.
Speaker 1: at least though for the Google I think the past.
Speaker 0: oh no Google my Google password changes monthly and holy shit is it like one crazy-ass password?
Speaker 0: And I have the two-factor Google's.
Speaker 0: more important than anything like that is literally someone gets your Gmail.
Speaker 1: they got your everything yep.
Speaker 0: So I actually I bought so part of this was cool.
Speaker 0: I checked all the websites I had accounts on to see if they've added support for two-factor since the last time I checked and a lot of people have.
Speaker 0: so I have two-factor now on Amazon on patreon a bunch of other things.
Speaker 0: It's notable.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of site like Newegg doesn't have it But Amazon does.
Speaker 1: the other problem is that a lot of the mobile devices?
Speaker 1: It just sucks to type in a fucking long password.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah That is actually why I used a. my passphrase is a little more complex than what you.
Speaker 0: it's not all words It's more kind of gibberish II nonsense that I just know.
Speaker 0: it's also.
Speaker 1: That's another reason though that the lowercase full passphrase is good because on mobile It's a lot easier to type that because you don't have to stop and like press shift and find some weird character or something.
Speaker 0: yep, but I also bought a YubiKey because I was checking some stuff out and Mine's like the first or second it won't work with anything.
Speaker 0: It doesn't work, but the new one is great because there's a new standard you to you to F or Fido.
Speaker 0: So what that means is anything.
Speaker 0: that was anything that you would normally do Google off with like that to TP stuff.
Speaker 0: If they support it.
Speaker 0: Then if you have a Chrome browser at least or if you use the NFC want to use it with your phone It with your phone you can use it to where your Google off Just shows you the code.
Speaker 0: It can't calculate the code unless you put the key next to your phone.
Speaker 0: It's basically three.
Speaker 1: So Google all the Google off app knows about the YubiKey.
Speaker 0: Yes, the Google off app will use a YubiKey Neo.
Speaker 0: So the Google off Apple run on iPhone or Android only Android only because iPhones Fucking suck and don't let you'd write any software on them.
Speaker 0: Apparently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't do the NFC.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I saw like I checked it out because I found someone who had one.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: but the problem is most sites won't support the YubiKey stuff even though they do support Google off, but Google now supports it natively.
Speaker 0: so if you don't want to do the phone thing You can buy a cheap YubiKey.
Speaker 0: It's just a Fido only one and it'll work with any number of accounts and you can just use it as your second factor Instead of a phone.
Speaker 0: and if you set both up you can set it up to use either/or.
Speaker 0: So the YubiKey could basically replace that sheet of paper with your 10 one-time codes that you encrypted and hid somewhere.
Speaker 1: Get to hide your YubiKey somewhere.
Speaker 0: My YubiKey is always on me.
Speaker 0: And so is my phone.
Speaker 0: so And even if I lose them remember it's two factor they still got to know my password.
Speaker 0: so then Independently, I was like, you know what my work finance what our companies should use this everywhere.
Speaker 0: So I go to go to people like everyone.
Speaker 0: you're fucking setting this up or I'm cutting off your access to shit.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 0: God did certain people like really resist doing this or refused to until I told him you won't get your email anymore.
Speaker 0: Like really didn't want to do it.
Speaker 0: One of them had a blackberry and they were like, well the Google auth doesn't work.
Speaker 0: and I was like, I don't care There's an app on the blackberry and if there isn't buy a real phone.
Speaker 0: Oh But what was very interesting is that the old people were not resisting.
Speaker 0: it was the young people who were resisting younger than me.
Speaker 0: interesting then their passwords all appear to be garbage because I was paying attention when I was setting up lives forcing people to do it and I guess cuz I did IT like baby IT like long long ago like when I worked at RIT.
Speaker 0: and You sort of get this instinct to not see passwords when people type them because people suck at typing.
Speaker 0: so bad that you will know Everyone's password unless you consciously avoid it.
Speaker 0: and I'd rather not even know the past.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the IT guys in my work whenever you type a password they always turn around.
Speaker 0: Yep Like I got real good.
Speaker 1: I would do the same thing, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah the problem is if you were bad like you could you can know anyone's password just by watching them because people suck at this.
Speaker 0: but While I did not see what their passwords were I saw that their passwords were very short and did not involve the spacebar or the shift key.
Speaker 0: So Yeah, so that's what I've been doing.
Speaker 0: I highly recommend if you are out there listening to Geek Nights do two-factor.
Speaker 0: if nothing else do two-factor on your gmail Because that is the thing that can fuck you more than any other account that could be compromised.
Speaker 1: Do you want to have any like actual Wednesday shit?
Speaker 0: Got any Wednesday news only I could only find because I think we are in fact the second longest running anime podcast in the world.
Speaker 0: That's great.
Speaker 0: So the only anime world order started like a month before us But we have more anime episodes than they have episodes.
Speaker 1: the only The only Wednesday ish news that I could find is that one of our Geek night's favorite comic creators.
Speaker 1: Jeff Lemire has a new comic coming.
Speaker 0: I didn't even finish the last several descender.
Speaker 1: No, I just enders still coming out.
Speaker 0: I know I haven't even come up with them.
Speaker 1: Anyway, um drill is a killer.
Speaker 1: So the new comment, I mean it's only the issue.
Speaker 1: I'm not buying it because I'm just waiting for the trade.
Speaker 1: It's coming from Dark Horse.
Speaker 1: It's black hammer.
Speaker 1: So it's a superhero thing.
Speaker 0: I guess but black hammer.
Speaker 1: All right, and it says Once they were heroes, but that age has long since passed.
Speaker 1: So I guess they're washed up or heroes or something.
Speaker 0: It could be Watchmen It could be the Black Order or whatever that vanished from existence by a multiversal crisis Space bullshit.
Speaker 1: It sounds like some DC garbage.
Speaker 0: It's a Dark Horse comic, but it could also be some in call garbage.
Speaker 1: Right, so that's already that part that beginning part and the alternate art cover looks like old DC corny garbage.
Speaker 1: I'm not interested in.
Speaker 1: but then the description goes on.
Speaker 1: it names all the heroes Whatever now lead simple lives in a timeless farming town.
Speaker 0: It's the town for the anime.
Speaker 0: We're reviewing today.
Speaker 1: Yes, even as they try to find their way home trouble has a unique way whatever.
Speaker 1: so it's like oh this is sort of like, you know old-school superheroes, but in a Modern and you know sort of a mystery anime type setting situation of like whoa What the fuck is going on.
Speaker 1: mystery, you know, so lost village plus You know washed up superheroes.
Speaker 0: yes Superman space nonsense all that biz Justice League.
Speaker 0: I mean Lemire pretty much.
Speaker 0: I'll check out.
Speaker 1: I don't think he's ever written a comic that I did not like reading.
Speaker 0: I'll read the first trade if anything he does unless he starts out betraying me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so well who knows there might be some betrayal.
Speaker 1: I don't even know like what it's called Black Hammer.
Speaker 1: It's like dude the title alone.
Speaker 1: I don't even need the description.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like mouse guard who's like home run with the black eggs.
Speaker 1: Yeah You can hit a lot farther home run with a black hammer than you can with the eggs.
Speaker 0: that black axe lived up to everything it should have lived up to - so in The today it looks like it was New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: get your badge day.
Speaker 1: and did everyone have a profile set up?
Speaker 0: Apparently everyone did like.
Speaker 0: I trolled around a little bit on social media networks.
Speaker 0: There didn't seem to be that many people who were confused.
Speaker 1: Well people who had social media accounts weren't confused.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what about the normies?
Speaker 0: I care not.
Speaker 0: the basics do not care anymore because the reality is.
Speaker 0: there was a time when fan conventions And that's why my news is not the comic-con badge situation because everyone's flipping out.
Speaker 0: I think they're already all sold out like no badges That many people made profiles to sell out.
Speaker 0: Wow there is not that much overlap between the people who go to Paxes and the people who go to New York Comic Con because no one in my social media was really complaining about this.
Speaker 0: it's like this whole other set of people and They were all making like you think like the people who complain about packs at least have been to a lot of paxes and conventions.
Speaker 0: So when they complain like while they're wrong about their solutions, they're like several steps beyond babies.
Speaker 0: first Why can't I get a badge?
Speaker 0: Like they at least are like what if they do a lottery like they've come up with all these crazy ideas like they know the basics of the situation.
Speaker 0: The comic-con people are like baby birds Like they're like it's the fucking scalpers.
Speaker 0: Oh my god the scouts.
Speaker 1: No, dude It's not as far as scalping for this than any convention ever with New York City.
Speaker 0: people go there for a day.
Speaker 0: There are like 60 million people who can get there as a day trip if they want.
Speaker 0: there are not 60 million badges for sale.
Speaker 0: But so people have you know that that all happened?
Speaker 0: it was interesting to watch that go down But my news is actually from April because it's tangentially related.
Speaker 0: So basically New York Comic Con in the old days was a free-for-all and kind of a shit show Like we went every year either as guests.
Speaker 1: Well the Attempted to go the first year.
Speaker 1: I didn't go but I walked past it.
Speaker 0: That was the one the fire marshal shut down.
Speaker 1: I wanted to see what the deal was on the first year.
Speaker 1: So I walked past it and saw crazy lines going out the building and no one getting in.
Speaker 1: and the second year I went for like a night after work on Friday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just to see you and it was.
Speaker 1: that's all the time I needed but it's worth telling.
Speaker 1: and then like the third and fourth Years, I went went for a day each and that was it.
Speaker 0: I went to every Yeah, and I went to a lot of the New York comic cons.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah There was a New York comic-con slash anime festival where I went like only for like Sunday morning to see Makoto Shinkai.
Speaker 0: I think that was the year I did panels But you didn't like.
Speaker 0: you just didn't care didn't even want to go.
Speaker 1: I got in Sunday I went in we saw a Makoto Shinkai's movie and then left and but he's got a new movie coming.
Speaker 1: by the way That's another news.
Speaker 1: Makoto Shinkai has a new movie and when I saw the screen capture slash poster for it I thought it was just an old Makoto Shinkai.
Speaker 0: I saw it in the distance on Scott's tablet.
Speaker 0: I was like isn't that place promised in early days or whatever?
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like.
Speaker 1: did someone did someone ripping off Makoto Shinkai?
Speaker 0: Movie it's coming but in the old days like for many many years New York comic-con was not that well attended.
Speaker 0: more importantly like if you went to the panels area No one went to panels at all and the panels were all like nothing But you could just get free badges like we.
Speaker 0: I've never in my life paid for a New York comic-con near to anime festival badge.
Speaker 0: Yet I went to a ton of them and we did not perform at all of them.
Speaker 0: Basically, I would just go walk in not even pre-reg and look at every booth and leave now.
Speaker 0: But without a badge I would go up I'd go to like the reg area and I'd be like, I'm a professional I'd like to get a professional badge
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 0: I would just talk to humans until eventually they handed me this golden badge that got me in Like even before the lot like they let me in early like people would do like.
Speaker 0: I basically do whatever I wanted and I did This every year.
Speaker 0: I always had either a professional badge or a press badge or a guest slash presenter badge.
Speaker 0: The badges were different every year.
Speaker 0: So the news was for this year a lot of people on the internet and by people.
Speaker 0: These are people who have pretensions of being journalists or being in the entertainment industry.
Speaker 0: But the reality is a lot of them are smaller time than geek nights.
Speaker 1: Okay,
Speaker 0: so they were all complaining that New York comic-con wouldn't let them get professional badges because New York comic-con over the last few years Finally tightened up that ship and doesn't give a professional badge to some guy who walks in and says yeah I do a podcast on anime And oh my god are people
Speaker 1: freaking out about
Speaker 0: this?
Speaker 1: and What are the qualifications you need?
Speaker 0: so they don't tell you?
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell that's a problem.
Speaker 0: They'd be that you submit your resume and they approve you.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so quote, please provide a detailed description of your current daily duties as it relates to the pop culture industry.
Speaker 1: So did these people submit their applications?
Speaker 0: that appears they all did and of course they were rejected.
Speaker 0: Okay, what do you have to accomplish by attending New York comic-con as a professional?
Speaker 0: Please explain how you will integrate what you experience into your profession.
Speaker 0: Please provide and this is the one that no one can answer Please provide the names titles and email addresses of three professional contacts.
Speaker 0: We can contact for a professional reference.
Speaker 0: So and also even professional badges, they're not free anymore.
Speaker 0: you got to pay pay less and you get in even though it's full Mmm, so I was sort of watching everyone just freaking out about this and then in my social media.
Speaker 1: But if you're actually a professional you should be able to do that really easily.
Speaker 1: So there's only reason to freak out is if you're not a professional now.
Speaker 0: in the old days They had some rules that they published about like how many hits your site had to get or whatever to get those badges.
Speaker 0: But I'll tell you what.
Speaker 0: even back then geek nights qualified like one year.
Speaker 0: I literally took our Libsyn stats Printed them brought them with me because the thing said like bring three business cards bring like evidence of your websites traffic and all this stuff.
Speaker 0: and I brought it all with me and I handed to the lady and she looked at it and she Was like good because we were way above the standard.
Speaker 0: and I read this was I don't remember what year this was But it was the year I went on Emily's birthday in the morning and then I just left because there's nothing to do.
Speaker 0: And then yeah, but is that someone's birthday soon, uh, yeah, okay October.
Speaker 0: But I remember while I was handing my paperwork over at the stall next to me was this dude And he claimed to work for some anime journalism outfit.
Speaker 0: I didn't recognize him obviously and He was basically trying to explain to the lady why he didn't have business cards and it was just make them dude.
Speaker 0: It was obvious that he had never had a business card In his entire life.
Speaker 1: not like you have to do something.
Speaker 1: they make business cards.
Speaker 1: You can print them at moo.com or even vista print for your money.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's so cheap.
Speaker 0: the lady was given.
Speaker 0: the look on her face was like kid.
Speaker 0: You couldn't even just like fake it and get a free one from staples.
Speaker 1: Yeah You could go to.
Speaker 1: you can go to stables and print like 10 business cards on one sheet and cut him with a scissor Like you couldn't even fake it kid.
Speaker 0: So and but he's not even saying like oh, I don't have business cards.
Speaker 0: He was literally like telling the sob story about how like his business cards didn't arrive because of something happened.
Speaker 0: But he's got to cover the event for your website your professional.
Speaker 1: Why were you ordering business cards at the last second?
Speaker 1: Shouldn't you've had them because you've been in the business.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I don't have a lot of sympathy for the people who are cut out because one if You were cut out and you can't get a professional badge You probably had no business being a professional in New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: But more importantly you probably don't even need to go to New York Comic Con Because what are you going to do there except be a fan like the new?
Speaker 0: the journalists cover the shit out of this car but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: so This is something, you know black right like the color black.
Speaker 0: Yes, well, this is darker than black.
Speaker 1: Oh that that new material.
Speaker 0: That's a black.
Speaker 1: I saw that.
Speaker 0: so That's the only 10.
Speaker 1: you can't even tell what shape it is because the light all absorbs into it.
Speaker 1: So yeah, you had to feel it to see what shape it is.
Speaker 0: So it's kind of cool.
Speaker 0: So this is a really good video one size show You should watch in general because if you even if you're like a short attention fish baby fish kid loud on the internet.
Speaker 0: Their videos are like a couple minutes long and they tell you they give you a lot of real science information in a hurry.
Speaker 0: But basically in this video they talk about what vantablack is.
Speaker 0: it's darker than black.
Speaker 0: It's way darker than that and not darker than black.
Speaker 1: It's it's just the most light absorbing material We've made.
Speaker 1: it absorbs like it only reflects like point.
Speaker 1: Oh something percent of light.
Speaker 1: So it's not completely black like black of space But it's it's so.
Speaker 1: it's so black that effectively a human can't see it.
Speaker 1: You just look at it and it looks like there's just like a hole in space and you can't.
Speaker 1: Cameras can't see you can't tell what shape it is.
Speaker 1: I mean people can see better than cameras.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well in some ways but not unless you have an ultra ultra ultra HDR camera.
Speaker 0: But this might you might seem like okay, whatever they can coat the insides of telescopes.
Speaker 0: You need to see this shit because when you see it It kind of breaks your brain a little bit.
Speaker 1: Because you can't because the light doesn't reflect it doesn't have a shape or three-dimensional shape.
Speaker 1: It looks like there's just a hole in space from all sides.
Speaker 0: It's a two-dimensional shape as far as your brain is concerned and human brains really have never experienced that before.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, like it's not something we've ever experienced ever until recently.
Speaker 1: It's like if you had a hole in it and your arm was coming out through the hole.
Speaker 1: It would look like this arm was just like dissing behind like whoa Oh Yep, some sort of trippy stoner LSD animation shit yep, but it real it's not fake it real.
Speaker 0: this video is really cool and talks about it and I only brought it up because I always make fun of that anime darker than black And I had to reference it at some point.
Speaker 1: how many episode how much darker than black have you seen?
Speaker 0: One episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah What happened in that episode?
Speaker 0: there was a wall on the outside of the fucking city or something and There's a bunch of proper nouns of people talking about like wow the walls there But there's all right.
Speaker 1: anyone who's actually seen darker than black Tell me how rim is doesn't remember anything about the show.
Speaker 0: and then aren't there the demon guys Who their power like they could.
Speaker 0: you can get a power like a thing will happen with a contract But then the contract makes you do something weird like all I remember is supernatural dudes fighting on a roof.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they like like you'll get the demon power, but then you have to break your finger or you get the demon power But then you have to like dump out a bunch of sand and count all the grains.
Speaker 1: Anyway,
Speaker 0: anyway that show I'm gonna continue to make fun of it because that one girl in the back and anime Boston when I referenced it a lot of People didn't even get the reference, but that one girl started laughing So hard, I feel like I feel like I hit her with the arrow of comedy if no one else.
Speaker 0: Anyway in the Madam Argus you got a thing today.
Speaker 1: Oh, that wasn't the black thing wasn't your news.
Speaker 1: It was thing a day.
Speaker 0: We're in things of the day.
Speaker 1: I said, okay anyway things Of the day I wasn't paying attention things No one gives a shit.
Speaker 1: so Last year the Mets were very good much better than the Mets usually are.
Speaker 1: this baseball We're talking about.
Speaker 0: you went to a World Series.
Speaker 1: There was a World Series in New York And it wasn't in the Bronx.
Speaker 0: like you were there and the Mets were there.
Speaker 1: that hasn't happened since the year 2000 when the entire World Series is played.
Speaker 1: Anyway and the met you know.
Speaker 1: so you know we didn't win, but hey we can't complain about that.
Speaker 1: That doesn't come very often.
Speaker 0: Yeah like one of my favorite things to say about the Red Wings They have.
Speaker 0: they've lost more Stanley Cup championships like final rounds than any team in the NHL.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: so anyway This year the Mets ain't bad.
Speaker 1: like usual They're not the worst, but they're like in second place, and they're you know they're losing to the first-place team.
Speaker 1: They lost like 11 to 4 the other day.
Speaker 1: Right this is expected.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna lose by a little and you know plenty of people.
Speaker 1: you know who are Mets fans Mostly talk about how bad the Mets are but for some reason this video despite being pretty old yet Also despite how old it is still has Citi Field and not Shea Stadium in it Which makes me feel even older.
Speaker 0: 2010 was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah Someone made this really funny video about how bad the Mets are And I for some reason I didn't discover this video until like a week or two ago.
Speaker 0: It captures all the beauty of like a public access commercial right down to the production and like yeah It's it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: You could just apply the same formula to many other bad things And it would be equally funny, but we got it first so deal with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah In the moment the book club books gonna be Oryx and Craig by Margaret Atwood, but there's a problem.
Speaker 0: So I just finished.
Speaker 0: Basically the entire Wheel of Time went around.
Speaker 1: the whole wheel went around the whole wheel.
Speaker 0: Actually I went outside the wheel whoa And you know what.
Speaker 0: it would be plausible to say that the prince of nothing happens in the same world.
Speaker 1: I mean look isn't it one of those ones you could say anything happens in the same world uh?
Speaker 1: It's pretty specific though like there's korai And such was there a spaceship that crashed that bad guys come out of it.
Speaker 0: Uh so it is implied that some people may have fled that planet to avoid the dark one and just went to another.
Speaker 1: And so the plants and nothing is the planet they went to.
Speaker 1: yeah Evil demons.
Speaker 1: because remember the prince of nothing.
Speaker 1: is there a sarcophagus in a tornado.
Speaker 0: Ah there is in the outside Outside of the Wheel of Time.
Speaker 0: that's where the dark one is and it's real similar to the outside of the Prince of Nothing And the outside fucking sucks, and you don't want it to get in.
Speaker 1: but is the dark one a sarcophagus of the tornado?
Speaker 0: yeah, but I don't think he made it into the world or maybe the sarcophagus tornado might have been in the third age anyway.
Speaker 0: The one thing you would appreciate about the end of this book is that your complaint about every fantasy book even the prince of nothing Is that the whole time there's all these references to like the old king?
Speaker 0: yeah like the crazy bad?
Speaker 1: Therian the crazy badass.
Speaker 0: if you skip all the other books the Wheel of Time and just read the last one Every single character who is still alive is now a crazy bad leveled up to be like Arthur Hawkwing is like goddamn guys like holy shit, so Arthur Hawkwing is like a chump.
Speaker 0: compare their Hawkwing is there?
Speaker 1: well They blow the horn and he shows up right.
Speaker 0: yeah And he look he walks on me.
Speaker 0: a little spoiler are they blowing the horn?
Speaker 1: like every five minutes?
Speaker 0: He basically walks over to Matt Cawthon, and he's like son Good job.
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 0: But it is literally everyone casting hundredth level spells going crazy bail fire.
Speaker 0: we got anti bail fire.
Speaker 1: Shit son.
Speaker 0: like everything you think every crazy bullshit ancient king thing that you think could happen it happens at one point.
Speaker 0: You're like why don't they just make gateways to lava.
Speaker 0: Yeah fucking gateways to lava all over the place.
Speaker 0: It's it's worth the payoff.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: I don't know if anyone else.
Speaker 0: you necessarily read all these books.
Speaker 0: the payoff of the last book?
Speaker 0: No, just tell me uh There's a lot going on every level of every crazy level that only care about certain parts.
Speaker 0: all right The second most powerful wizard in the world, maybe the third most powerful on the girls side Picks up.
Speaker 0: she basically when chaos strikes.
Speaker 0: you know that storeroom where there's all the like angry.
Speaker 0: Oh that no one will touch in the basement.
Speaker 0: She just goes down there And she's like what's the fucking strongest one we've got?
Speaker 0: and she pulls out Vora's rod.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or his rod is like almost as powerful as Kalindor, and she's like fuck I don't know.
Speaker 1: two statues with the balls.
Speaker 0: no Kalindor is the sword that's not a sword all right that showed in Chi.
Speaker 0: I think that's what it is.
Speaker 0: is the two statues It's not that powerful ran destroyed those.
Speaker 0: he was like.
Speaker 0: you know what those things we and play God.
Speaker 0: Let's just not use those.
Speaker 0: good job.
Speaker 0: I feel like there's a better way to handle that but I digress.
Speaker 1: I would.
Speaker 1: I mean I'm sad that he didn't play God though.
Speaker 0: Uh actually you get a flashback and find out what happens if you play God.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's good.
Speaker 0: That's why the taint is there.
Speaker 0: all right But that's not the problem.
Speaker 0: the problem is that Just as I finish that and I'm about to start reading Oryx and Crake The new our Scott backer books like about gonna come out in like the next week or two it's that soon.
Speaker 0: It's like it's actually happening.
Speaker 1: It's not a joke it appears to be.
Speaker 1: actually have not a tease.
Speaker 0: So we might delay Oryx and Crake and have to do a show on the new Prince of Nothing book It's got are gonna read it pretty much like I gotta reread some old friends of nothing verse.
Speaker 0: I gotta reread at least parts of the white luck warrior because not a hundred.
Speaker 1: I forgot how to take the shortest path I'm taking like a slightly less suboptimal path here like how am I gonna get across the step?
Speaker 0: I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Speaker 0: Regarding the fetus that was the key to that door.
Speaker 0: and what's behind that door?
Speaker 1: I don't remember a single word that is written on the tusk other than the fact that it's written on the time.
Speaker 0: Also something weird happened in the other book with the korai where memora like looked at it And then she like went through it in her brain.
Speaker 1: I do remember This fucking dragon and that's always.
Speaker 1: the good part of any fantasy novel is when the dragon shows up.
Speaker 0: that dragon is Actually one of my favorite characters in the entire story because the conversation that dragon has where they came in is like son Welcome to earth.
Speaker 1: So I am the last one.
Speaker 0: So anyway, we did watch some.
Speaker 0: oh, yeah, we're gonna be a kinetic on.
Speaker 0: uh fucking next weekend Here, I'm gonna pull up our panel schedule because I made the entire panel schedule.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna log into the group take system.
Speaker 1: I still gotta make the staff schedule.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you do and no one sent me their whatever their schedule they want.
Speaker 1: So I'm just putting I guess they don't care.
Speaker 0: I mean all you have to do because I did all the other work in the department.
Speaker 0: All you have to do is make sure everyone in our department who deserves a hotel room has one Has a schedule someone else taking care of the hotel stone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you're responsible for it.
Speaker 0: You think you're some emails about that?
Speaker 1: I'll just ask them and be like, hey what happened with the hotel?
Speaker 0: Just make sure that happens because I ain't if if some bullshit goes down people even with you if a guest just like where's My panel room they come to me.
Speaker 0: if a guest is like, where's my hotel?
Speaker 0: I guess they're gonna come to me too.
Speaker 0: So we have split the duties of who goes who goes on to over this shit.
Speaker 0: But I'm gonna link to the actual panel schedule.
Speaker 0: It's live.
Speaker 0: It's not on the real kinetic on site.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna even get into why that is.
Speaker 0: It's on a different side.
Speaker 0: And also if you dislike the fonts on the thing, I'm linking to.
Speaker 0: by all means complain to kinetic on about it.
Speaker 0: We didn't do it, please complain to kinetic on about that font.
Speaker 0: it is it's a font.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: I've been looking at fonts a lot.
Speaker 0: It's not Helvetica.
Speaker 0: It's a font.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, I did find a really good font to use for printing.
Speaker 0: You know like packs is the banner that has like the panel schedule on each room.
Speaker 0: I Was trying to figure out what fonts to use for that because it's actually kind of a complex problem.
Speaker 1: There's a new feature in the newest Photoshop typekit.
Speaker 1: No, cuz if you use typekit, yeah, but typekit isn't isn't a new feature?
Speaker 1: No, but like using type you search for a font and you get it, whatever.
Speaker 1: So the new feature is that you'll see you have a photo and in the photo, there's some letters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can select the letters.
Speaker 1: Oh shit Photoshop will tell you what the fuck fun it is.
Speaker 0: Oh shit I'm gonna find for everything.
Speaker 1: It'll also search Typekit and find a similar fun.
Speaker 0: Oh, I did not know about that feature.
Speaker 1: That's a brand new feature.
Speaker 1: Yes, this is why you pay for Photoshop you anti subscription morons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even without that you pay for Adobe, right?
Speaker 0: So I needed a font.
Speaker 0: I did cuz monospace fonts are just garbage.
Speaker 0: I need it But I did I wanted except the ones for program.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but there's on a poster.
Speaker 1: You know, why the fuck would you use a monospace on a poster?
Speaker 0: however for a schedule poster what you want is a font that has a narrow width and a thick width and You want the numbers to not be monospace or the letters do not be monospace to a real kerning.
Speaker 0: But you want the numbers to be monospace so you can use them to have a nice lined up schedule.
Speaker 1: You know just use a monospace font for the numbers.
Speaker 1: You don't use the same font for both.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I tried that.
Speaker 0: but I was looking around.
Speaker 0: monospace fonts All kind of look like shit and most of them have really bad zeros.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz the zeros usually have it.
Speaker 1: That's why a lot of them have a lot of variations like, you know dot no dot slash no slash.
Speaker 1: Yep, because they know you might be programming and you need to see the zeros are different from the O's but you might not be Programming.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I digress the schedule is pretty good.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of pretty good-looking panels.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz the con ends at 9 so you're able to cut out all the shitty panels.
Speaker 1: Sorry shitty panels.
Speaker 0: Yep I also had to cut out a lot of good panels because we probably had double the submissions we've ever had Despite the fact that we have like 30% fewer spaces to put them.
Speaker 0: So I rejected like a lot of good stuff alongside the really bad good put on the waitlist.
Speaker 1: Okay, someone bails.
Speaker 0: we're doing like four or five panels.
Speaker 0: We can't do a lot because Well, two of them are anime openers from around the world good and more Anime openers from around the world.
Speaker 1: and you said you rejected a good panel for that.
Speaker 0: That's actually really popular.
Speaker 0: Whatever people like really like that stuff.
Speaker 0: Also the panel I would have put in instead would be like Charles Dunbar's anime opener panels but he is not attending this year because I was.
Speaker 0: I unfortunately cannot give hotel rooms or Real accommodation to professionals like.
Speaker 0: I can't get people shit.
Speaker 0: the most I can get you is a badge.
Speaker 0: So anyone that the other guest departments won't bring I can't bring them because I can't give them money or anything.
Speaker 0: That's a shame, but that's not my mandate.
Speaker 0: I don't want a bigger mandate.
Speaker 0: kinetic guns coming.
Speaker 0: We're doing those.
Speaker 0: We're doing writing game rules, which is a variant on a panel that we did before that.
Speaker 0: We're probably gonna do at PAX Prime.
Speaker 0: I think I'm putting in an overwatch panel that if Scott doesn't want to do it.
Speaker 0: I'll just do it.
Speaker 1: I don't know anything about other than oh, it's an FPS Blizzard made.
Speaker 1: It's like Team Fortress, but more skills want to be on the panel anyway.
Speaker 1: Everyone I know plays it constantly and I don't.
Speaker 0: so you'll be on the panel you be the hater or at least the.
Speaker 1: I've already Said everything.
Speaker 0: I have to say you should be playing this game Scott.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't play netrunner.
Speaker 0: Uh This is way better than netrunner.
Speaker 0: I doubt that Scott remember how we felt when we played tribes like remember that era That's somehow.
Speaker 1: why do I know?
Speaker 1: it's not tribes.
Speaker 1: There's no way.
Speaker 0: no It's not.
Speaker 1: tribes doesn't even have vehicles.
Speaker 0: But remember the feel of like you come home and you just log into tribes and all your friends are already playing tribes and you Join a gameplay tribes.
Speaker 0: I get that every night.
Speaker 0: Right now half our friends.
Speaker 0: Lisa just messaged me like are you playing like?
Speaker 0: she wants me to play right now?
Speaker 1: good So I could actually have a life because all you people who you play in this game and I'll be doing stuff Everyone's playing.
Speaker 0: Oh good 13 messages of people who want to play right now.
Speaker 1: I'm good Tells me it's a good idea not to do that.
Speaker 0: But yeah, Connecticut will be there.
Speaker 0: pecs prime will be there.
Speaker 0: I hope we'll have panels, but I can't say yes We will until we get the confirmation.
Speaker 0: I would never assume pecs dev I'll be there if nothing else because I'm just going as an attendee if I even if I don't have panel.
Speaker 0: That's all the better.
Speaker 0: Patreon t-shirts.
Speaker 0: a bunch of you bought t-shirts.
Speaker 0: suddenly like a whole bunch you just bought t-shirts.
Speaker 0: So cool I guess what the fuck.
Speaker 0: I got some designs for new t-shirts.
Speaker 0: So the new t-shirts that might be coming our chicken surprise.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay I got a really good Concept that I'm gonna work with Emily to kind of flesh out.
Speaker 0: There's a picture of a really excited dog and a really not excited dog That's been making the rounds because everyone's kind of like, oh, it's from and Scott.
Speaker 1: So you're the only one who make in the round.
Speaker 0: No, it gets tweeted at me kind of regularly.
Speaker 0: You've seen those dogs, right?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I kind of want to make a t-shirt.
Speaker 1: doesn't someone own that photo?
Speaker 0: No, I want to make a t-shirt that is inspired by that those dogs and us in some fashion.
Speaker 0: A stylized photo stylized design, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm coming up with it.
Speaker 0: But I'm doing chicken surprise first because goddamn do I want that chicken surprise shirt?
Speaker 0: So when we did our panel at anime Boston our annual panel judge anime by its cover one of the anime we judged By its cover was the lost village and we said, oh this looks like it has an interesting concept.
Speaker 1: It looks like it's sort of got one of those like scenario situations like nine doors nine.
Speaker 0: Whatever is nine something?
Speaker 1: You know the things that they saw
Speaker 0: doors nine dogs
Speaker 1: a lot of Japanese and Asian You know in all mediums books movies, you know, especially, you know I think the oldest one I remember is like battle royale where you get a bunch of varied characters and they get somehow get stuck Separated from society in an
Speaker 0: oddly specific predicament
Speaker 1: right in a in a scenario with a bunch of rules and Or mysteries and is something supernatural or something sinister.
Speaker 0: now This is a common trope outside of anime Like there's a bunch of like.
Speaker 0: if you go to Netflix just go through random movies.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of like American movies that you don't even remember that are this exact same thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just in anime.
Speaker 0: There seems to be an acceleration of these over the last five or six years.
Speaker 1: Also, you know video games visual novel type thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just nine nine.
Speaker 0: Whatever's is the one I always think of.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the sequel to that but virtues last reward, but when we reviewed it We also said it kind of had a bokurano vibe.
Speaker 0: We weren't sure if it would be like this because bokurano is basically one of those ones.
Speaker 1: only good, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know these kids they're not completely separated from society in that one.
Speaker 1: It's actually that's what make bokurano cool is that they sort of aren't separated from society.
Speaker 1: I like they go to like the military like yeah, like they go to the cops right away Yeah, well right away ish.
Speaker 0: But yeah, basically they go as right away as you could like you can understand why someone would but it's still.
Speaker 1: it's silly group Of varied characters that get into a predicament with a lot of specific rules Governing the scenario that they have to navigate and horrors and supernatural and you know, so sinister.
Speaker 0: They got to watch the whole thing.
Speaker 0: I've seen the first five episodes.
Speaker 0: I watched up to what I would only go in to describe no real spoilers as The the giant stuffed kappa with a real human face also in it like it's a half.
Speaker 0: It's half penguin half face, but like photo of a real person not even like drawn.
Speaker 1: Yeah the supernatural thing.
Speaker 1: but uh You don't need to watch anymore.
Speaker 0: You're good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was gonna ask you should I finish it?
Speaker 1: I'll tell you everything you need to know if you tell me more time.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing from the first.
Speaker 0: this is another situation.
Speaker 0: this happens to us kind of often where the first episode of a show Makes it look like it's gonna be real good.
Speaker 1: So the first episode of this show makes it look like about 80% good, right?
Speaker 1: It sets you up in the scenario.
Speaker 1: These people are found on the internet about this hidden village.
Speaker 1: They're on a bus that they rented and like a tour group to go find it on an adventure.
Speaker 0: The bus is weird and they're sinister undertones, right?
Speaker 1: They all want to escape their lives for some reasons.
Speaker 1: You got to learn about each character.
Speaker 1: The only thing about the first episode which holds true for the rest of the show Is that you know, you have a bunch of varied characters.
Speaker 0: I always say a bunch.
Speaker 0: It's not like a normal anime.
Speaker 0: It's not like 9 or 10.
Speaker 1: It's like 30 20 or 30.
Speaker 1: There are 30 people.
Speaker 0: There's a lot plus all the new characters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so but do you know the trope of these shows is like introduce all the characters give the Backstories and then the writing always seems to come down to well.
Speaker 0: these five are together.
Speaker 0: So let's consult our sheet of their personalities and have them interact in a superficial way like those characters would interact.
Speaker 0: This show takes that to such an extreme that after the first episode I actually thought that this show is gonna be like what Nodeshiko was to.
Speaker 0: robot shows Gonna be like this is taking the piss out of the genre.
Speaker 0: But as I started watching more I worry that that is an unintentional side effect of the really bad writing.
Speaker 1: Yeah so the characters a lot of the characters are really really shallow and One-dimensional and really caricatures.
Speaker 1: almost yeah.
Speaker 1: Like, you know some of them get episodes that like explain their backstory and sort of give a reason for they're so dumb Like the surly guy.
Speaker 0: his backstory is I was doing an IT project and something went wrong Vaguely and I got chewed out by my bosses because of it and therefore why I want to run away from society.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that's why you think I have this personality of being angry at everything like you think we're joking.
Speaker 0: That is literally it.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's a really shallow and not you know complex or interesting.
Speaker 1: and what makes it worse is that even though they show?
Speaker 1: Some of the characters pasts and the reasons for the way they are They the way they act is really exaggerated and hyperbolic Which is okay in some senses.
Speaker 0: cuz like one of them love piano love piano love love pond love pond.
Speaker 1: Her backstory is like, you know, pretty serious.
Speaker 1: Did you see her backstory?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: All right, whatever.
Speaker 1: So her backstory is pretty serious and explains why the way she is, but basically all she does is be like execute people.
Speaker 0: He committed a crime.
Speaker 1: we should execute that guy and she's literally like hysterically screams Execute him execute him execute him constantly.
Speaker 0: I know at least the show follows through on that because like in the third episode She does fucking try to murder someone.
Speaker 1: right but it's like just a basically a nut.
Speaker 0: She's just like Frantic not and only one who I don't think is a nut is lion.
Speaker 1: Anyway, and the other thing is that she they don't develop right further.
Speaker 1: It's like we learn love ponds backstory.
Speaker 0: They're all dead they're all dead.
Speaker 1: this is the afterlife no, but we see that she's fucked up now But then she doesn't change after that really very much at all only very slightly The only characters that have any development are like the few main ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah And you know what the main ones suck right.
Speaker 1: the main ones because that's the thing that happens in so many stories especially anime is the more main the character is the more Genero they are.
Speaker 1: because I there's some idea that writers have that the main character needs to be more relatable.
Speaker 0: the best example of this Ever is new to what I do.
Speaker 0: No, no, it's a bunch of great characters everywhere And then the main character is literally this vague masked dude with no history.
Speaker 1: I think Fullmetal Alchemist is my favorite example because you have all these awesome characters like Hughes and Mustang and shit and Meanwhile, the main characters are like the twins are like the most boring.
Speaker 0: It's like they have some personality they have some.
Speaker 1: they're not.
Speaker 0: nothings right but it's like no.
Speaker 0: It's just like you pretend you're that guy But it's like, you know, I wish that the.
Speaker 1: they weren't even in it and it was about the.
Speaker 1: you know The other awesome, but like main kid number one.
Speaker 0: So again, if you watch just the first episode the show looks like it's gonna be so great cuz it.
Speaker 1: it looks like it's gonna Be okay.
Speaker 0: Well, it looks like it's gonna be great in this like nadeshko as deconstructive like the character intros Like it's almost like a parody because literally the bus driver is kind of crazy and like everything's weird.
Speaker 1: The bus driver is actually the most normal person sinister, but he has issues too obviously.
Speaker 0: Not the bus driver the like the sugar bleeder?
Speaker 0: Oh, no, he's not but all the characters are like super into it.
Speaker 1: He's like he's like a Mormon type.
Speaker 0: They one by one introduced themselves and tell you their backstory or at least tell you something about themselves and that scene goes on for like 10 minutes as Pretty much the whole first episode.
Speaker 0: and that was great because some of the characters had like all this anime nonsense.
Speaker 0: Some of them were obviously crazy like the one kids like I'm Jack and wouldn't talk anymore.
Speaker 1: But and then there's the other Jack who's dressed like a pirate or something.
Speaker 0: Jack and Jack.
Speaker 0: the characters keep confusing this but actually it's Jack and Judgeness.
Speaker 0: and just saying those words in Japanese they sound similar But it's Jack and Judgeness and these two characters keep fighting about how they have the same name and his bullshit like oh my god You stole my OC.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the characters are just so Stereotypical that the first episode.
Speaker 0: I really believe that this show was taking that concept of.
Speaker 0: we've got nine characters the mysterious Backstories and just saying fuck it.
Speaker 0: We got I don't know 30 and One of them's like literally just got guns.
Speaker 0: One of them is like literally a demon.
Speaker 0: Let's just fucking go nuts.
Speaker 0: I thought that's what the show was gonna be.
Speaker 0: Mmm the fact that the show is actually just badly written and trying to do this They do find a mysterious village.
Speaker 1: That's Mysterious right because it's empty but it's not like it.
Speaker 1: nothing's destroyed.
Speaker 1: it's just like it looks like the people have recently departed and left everything there and It's like what's going on here?
Speaker 1: And then as they stay there and sort of try to start a new life, you know of Solitude one by one characters scream and freak out for no reason at nothing.
Speaker 1: people disappear People, you know discover weird things people go off into the woods and shit happens, but it's also dumb which again I. but it alternates as you would expect between Characters sitting around discussing things like a lot in a very Death Note kind of way.
Speaker 1: Oh, imagine if L was a bunch of characters like oh is that person up isn't up to no good?
Speaker 1: No, that person's up to no good.
Speaker 1: Oh that but that person went into the woods and did and that person wants to leave and that person does again.
Speaker 0: why?
Speaker 0: I thought it was gonna be a parody.
Speaker 0: because And then stuff happens and then they talk again and it's like The stuff that happens was like really dumb and they were all overreacting pretty much every time up until Overact about everything but to the argue like the discussions.
Speaker 1: Why don't you tell us you must be no good?
Speaker 0: the discussions they had were so dumb and fake Like our group of friends playing mafia sounds more together than these kids.
Speaker 1: Yes It was like.
Speaker 0: it's like a bad game Like at one point I can't start singing a song and there's someone else is like That's not the lyrics aren't the lyrics?
Speaker 0: this?
Speaker 0: and then some other kids like I thought the lyrics were this and that's what they have This discussion about that just as seriously as well.
Speaker 0: So-and-so was murdered.
Speaker 0: So who could have done it?
Speaker 0: Well, so-and-so was somewhere else.
Speaker 1: you were like.
Speaker 1: you were the last person to see them.
Speaker 1: What happened?
Speaker 1: and we're gonna torture you and make you tell us the best one is the paper-rock-scissors.
Speaker 0: They start arguing for like five minutes about how paper-rock-scissors works.
Speaker 0: Yeah so all those things led me to believe that this is a parody and if it is if at least from the first couple episodes if This is a parody of that kind of show.
Speaker 0: No, it's brilliant No, but as you have just informed me one appears it was released on April Fool's Day.
Speaker 1: I didn't know about that.
Speaker 0: That's when it started airing.
Speaker 1: So even better, but I mean baby metals album came out in April first.
Speaker 0: But if this show is actually seriously going to try to for real This show is terrible and I'm not gonna watch anymore.
Speaker 1: you don't need to watch anymore.
Speaker 1: So they do resolve and explain everything.
Speaker 0: is it dumb?
Speaker 1: It's a supernatural explanation as a guest But it doesn't.
Speaker 1: there's no.
Speaker 1: like Climax or like satisfying resolution is just sort of like it goes out with like a whimper like yeah Here's the only question I have.
Speaker 0: is lion the only smart one?
Speaker 1: lions barely a character like a side.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's why I think lions the smartest one because lion seem personality seems to be sitting there.
Speaker 1: Yeah lion and then like that that there's like a group of line and like two or three strong girl strong girl lion Strong girl and like two other people there's you know, they're still around I think in the last episode.
Speaker 1: They're on screen for like all right Does the guy they're like?
Speaker 1: they're like the least.
Speaker 1: there's some they're amongst the least crazy people.
Speaker 0: does the rapey guy from the first episode who disappears die?
Speaker 1: rapey guy is He's still missing.
Speaker 0: when I stopped why I know he is.
Speaker 1: he is only half as rapey as you think and he is not dead.
Speaker 1: Okay But and he only comes back in like one episode Fat guy has to die.
Speaker 0: cuz fat guy literally just eats food all the time and bitches about food.
Speaker 1: lazy fat guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he basically all he's just lazy fat guy to the end.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: There's nothing else going on with him.
Speaker 1: He's just sort of like.
Speaker 1: they're like up.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: He's a background character.
Speaker 1: There's something to be said for the same thing with like the two people who are all like super in love same deal.
Speaker 0: Wow Those two reminded they're like.
Speaker 1: they're like nothing throwaway characters.
Speaker 1: They were like in the show.
Speaker 0: They were like shit-tier versions of the two characters from.
Speaker 1: it would have been something if they gave every character a full Episode to explain their backstory the way they gave some of the characters.
Speaker 1: But it's like love.
Speaker 1: fun isn't any more of an important character than any of them fat guy or in love people or anything but for some reason they gave her an old episode to explain her shit and Some of the other characters.
Speaker 1: they didn't.
Speaker 1: but she has maybe even less impact on the story than they do.
Speaker 0: It's just like just from the first episode.
Speaker 0: like I guess.
Speaker 0: my advice to all of you as anime fans watch the first episode Because like watch it don't watch any more of the show.
Speaker 0: Pretend it was a parody of these kinds of shows and you'll get a lot out of it.
Speaker 0: I think man, maybe the first episode is really good.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like Kazunoyo Jimbo.
Speaker 0: You watch the first episode.
Speaker 1: This isn't like the worst anime ever.
Speaker 1: It's just not really worth your time even for 13 episodes unless you're really hard up for some anime.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 0: maybe you can make.
Speaker 1: At least it's not perverted or you know, it doesn't have any of those kinds of problems.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, it's I guess it's animated Normally, what if you just cut out every scene where either nothing happens or a character says their catchphrase?
Speaker 0: How long would the show be?
Speaker 1: Maybe 25% shorter than it is.
Speaker 0: So that means a lot of like.
Speaker 0: alright in the fourth episode I'll just spoil it and one like they're like they have this stupid plan they like split up because some of them gonna go back to the bus and I don't know why they think that's gonna work.
Speaker 0: is The bus like fell off a cliff and like isn't?
Speaker 1: for some reason the bus keeps working and never runs out of gas or anything.
Speaker 1: It never runs out of gas and never fill it But it just keeps running whenever they need it like whenever the bus keeps doing stuff But it's in.
Speaker 1: it's in the show straight to the end the.
Speaker 0: but then like they're half the group is like fuck this We're out which when they split into two groups It was obviously like smart kids on that team dumb kids on the stay behind team.
Speaker 0: But the smart kids start numbering the trees like walking away and that's the kind of thing that happens in this kind of show.
Speaker 0: So they're numbering the trees on the map.
Speaker 1: They get to tree like 91 and then they get to tree eight.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So They got back to the campsite pretty quick.
Speaker 0: So it couldn't have been that Someone tricked them by putting an eight there way out on the map, but the map match the.
Speaker 0: so was it just a supernatural thing?
Speaker 0: Because it didn't make sense.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, I mean I'd have to explain the whole show which I don't mind doing but people get mad.
Speaker 1: So whatever and I want to go home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't even care.
Speaker 0: actually It's interesting like some dumb shows like I'll watch the end cuz I gotta know.
Speaker 0: but like Part of the reason I kept going was like I really wanted to know and it was taking me longer to figure out But I don't want to know.
Speaker 1: read 15 books badly.
Speaker 0: It took me like like I read a bunch of Wikipedia pages to spoil the wheel of time and it was so hard to piece It all together from that.
Speaker 0: It was literally faster to read the books.
Speaker 0: But with this show I just Watch the first episode.
Speaker 0: I really think you should watch the first episode to at least see what I mean.
Speaker 1: I mean, you don't need to watch that just watch Boker on.
Speaker 0: Oh instead the first episode was interest like the fact that all the characters were like their screen names and Every one of them was like a different kind of that guy from the internet.
Speaker 0: and Yeah, whatever the show has got bad and I'm not gonna watch any more of it.
Speaker 0: We said the show was gonna be good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was.
Speaker 1: it was.
Speaker 1: it was better than most the other shows out there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I feel like of the shows.
Speaker 1: we said we're going to be like it's like a C. This was the big plus maybe C - so far of every show we had in your mood Pre-reviewed.
Speaker 0: this has been the biggest gap between what we expected and what we got.
Speaker 1: I didn't say I never.
Speaker 1: I never said it was gonna be like so good.
Speaker 0: I said I have potential which we said had a lot of potential but it fell so far short of that potential.
Speaker 1: I mean it fell short of expectations, but only slightly.
Speaker 1: Yeah Expectation wasn't that high.
Speaker 1: my expectation was B and it got a C.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but C gets you already into like Armageddon territory.
Speaker 0: So It's better than harm again, actually, I think harm again might be like a B minus.
Speaker 0: I'm again might be more entertaining in certain scenario Like this gets less entertaining every minute that it goes on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't come to the show for entertainment value.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna get that.
Speaker 0: Yeah now I've now.
Speaker 0: I started scrolling through reviews and the people who say it's great Clearly haven't seen a lot of anime.
Speaker 0: and the people who say it's bad or no Sorry, the people who say it's great either haven't seen a lot of anime or they're basically saying it's a shitty B Movie that goes on forever.
Speaker 0: if you like shitty B movies You'll love the shit out of it does have that kind of feel like and you'll enjoy it.
Speaker 0: if you're literally in it to see How bad the script is written?
Speaker 1: Yeah which it has that kind of feel for sure like I've enjoyed things on that level before.
Speaker 0: so I can see that a poorly paced B Movie.
Speaker 0: the people who say it's bad seem to be split between people who say they don't get it And there's nothing not to get if you don't get it.
Speaker 1: It's a isn't a show.
Speaker 1: it spells it all out for you and near the end They just tell you everything literally and the anime news network forums.
Speaker 0: like in the episode 5 I found a thread where like the giant Kappa gets revealed.
Speaker 1: It's not a Kappa.
Speaker 1: It's a half penguin half person.
Speaker 0: But it's got the bald-headed Kappa looking thing on it.
Speaker 1: It's nice.
Speaker 1: No capper.
Speaker 0: So it's a penguin.
Speaker 1: It's half stuffed penguin half person.
Speaker 0: because at first I thought it was a penguin, but then I saw the bald head thing.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh, I guess it's just bald and a Japanese guy with like a thin mustache coming in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever like a photo of him.
Speaker 0: But like in the fourth episode they go into the train track tunnel and I'm like alright tunnels a big deal.
Speaker 0: But then the kid the one girl the guys that got the flashlight.
Speaker 0: He's like, oh my god There's some crazy shit.
Speaker 0: and then they all scream and run away without saying what it is.
Speaker 0: But then when they get back to camp, they're like it was a giant like main character.
Speaker 0: Yeah the that's not.
Speaker 0: that is literally The second.
Speaker 0: to last thing I would have expected them to have seen screamed and run away from.
Speaker 0: on my list was number one train.
Speaker 0: Number two ghost train.
Speaker 1: ghost train would have made the show great.
Speaker 0: Yeah Number three the bear monster.
Speaker 1: that would have been great.
Speaker 0: to number four like mirrors of all the other kids.
Speaker 0: But at near the bottom of the list was things like actual Freddy Krueger black dynamite Evangelion but black dynamite.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like literally it's Hideaki Anno.
Speaker 0: like he is a character in the show now But right at the bottom that's blue blazes.
Speaker 0: You should watch that right at the very bottom down there is a bigger version of one of the characters four meters tall.
Speaker 0: give or take Whatever.
Speaker 0: don't watch this show.
Speaker 0: Just watch the free stuff.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: the patrons for this episode of geek nights in Decreasing amount of money that they send us on a continuing basis are Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Nicholas Brando, Heidi McNichol, Amanda Duchette, James David White, Christian Koontz, construction noises, mystady.com, Sean Hayworth, William Isenbroughs, Jeremy Miner, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn, Devin Goodman, Iggy Kid, Matthew Smith, Kshar Tavashin, Joshua Joestar, Tyler Eller, Don Schleig, Sean Yeager, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Robert Lee, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Rare Lavelle, Brian Cidroni, Rochelle Montanona, Finn, Eric Silverard, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn, Erin Cerise, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, Flame Darkfire, and me, Dio Sam Cordery, Daniel Redmond, Shawn Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Speaker 0: It's like pulling teeth to get Scott to do the Q&A episodes.
Speaker 0: We were gonna record the Q&A for the previous month now But we had to edit the show at the normal time instead of going late Partly because one of our bunnies is a little sick and we got to do some medicine and take care of him.
Speaker 0: So that that's the reason for the delay.
Speaker 0: But what I'm gonna do for the June Q&A Partly because I just want to see this happen once is I'm gonna open it up to all the patrons.
Speaker 0: But they'll only have like a couple days to submit their questions.
Speaker 0: But I will make sure that anyone who is a $5 or above patron Your questions get asked first and then we'll let all the plebs and we'll make it clear who's the plebs.
Speaker 0: You guys still get your privilege, but don't worry.
Speaker 0: Generally, you've got to be at that tier to answer ask questions normally.
Speaker 0: but that's sort of a Throwout to all the people who give us a dollar because honestly I'd rather see a world where all our listeners give us a dollar and Nobody gives us more than a dollar because that would actually be a lot of money and we could do stuff with it Otherwise, the only other update is that the money has not been spent on anything yet.
Speaker 0: I haven't even taken it from patreon.
Speaker 0: it's just sitting there waiting for its project and The potential projects are coming and doing a big show at PAX Australia.
Speaker 0: I'm talking to some people about that Potentially buying a significant amount of further equipment to start really cranking out videos or Straight up starting a small gaming convention in downstate New York like for real a two-day convention.
Speaker 0: The way it would work would be pretty much to start it was Saturday and Sunday.
Speaker 0: only Saturday would be sort of an open gaming thing.
Speaker 0: There'd be a keynote like one sort of like keynote like so we do like an intro thing.
Speaker 0: There'd be a keynote from someone kind of serious and then it would just be open gaming and tournaments all day Probably like one tabletop area in one video game in area and then Sunday would be the same convention.
Speaker 0: But it's a curated event.
Speaker 0: an example of the kind of curated event.
Speaker 0: We would do would be like burning con.
Speaker 0: So basically it would be like an example.
Speaker 0: con would be Saturday's the game day Sunday for everyone who's still in for it for that.
Speaker 0: It would be like a one-day version of burning con.
Speaker 0: That's what we're looking at doing and there's a chance.
Speaker 0: We'll use the patreon money to do the groundwork to make that happen.
Speaker 0: So stay tuned.
Speaker 0: We're working on it.
Speaker 0: We got to make sure Connecticut happens before we do our own con, but stay tuned for real.
Speaker 0: But anyway now I leave you with something odd With But your head gets done You.